<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1179244824" ordinal="31" title="AMERICAN VETERANS DISABLED FOR LIFE COMMEMORATIVE COIN ACT">
  <speaking speaker="400282" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="634">H.R. 634</bill>) to require the Secretary of the Treasury to mint coins in commemoration of veterans who become disabled for life while serving in the Armed Forces of the United States, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Kansas (Mr. Moore) and the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Roskam) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400282" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members have 5 legislative days within which to revise and extend their remarks on this legislation and to insert any other material.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Kansas?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400282" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, this legislation that we are considering today is a simple, straightforward bill that would take a small but important step to recognize and honor the more than 3 million American veterans currently living with disabilities as a result of their sacrifice and service in our United States Armed Forces. In fact, of 26 million American veterans today, nearly one in 10 embody the physical cost of their service in permanent disability.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While there are many other steps that Congress should take to improve the lives of disabled veterans, by passing this bipartisan legislation today, which I have introduced with my friend and colleague, Mr. Kirk of Illinois, we hope to honor and show our gratitude for their sacrifice and the toll this has taken on their lives. Specifically, Madam Speaker, this legislation provides for the design, manufacture and sale of special commemorative silver coins and authorizes special surcharges  on these coins to be contributed toward the construction of a memorial to disabled veterans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The American Veterans Disabled for Life Memorial will occupy an impressive 2-acre site located just southwest of the Rayburn House Office Building adjacent to the National Mall within full view of the United States Capitol. The memorial will embody America's lasting gratitude for the men and women whose lives are forever changed in their service to our country. It will also serve as an important reminder to Members of Congress of the human cost of war and the need to support our veterans. We  must never forget the sacrifices these American heroes made and continue to make in order to promote a better world for our fellow citizens.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Building this long overdue memorial is something we need to do and should do as Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I include the following letter exchange for the RECORD:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>COMMITTEE ON WAYS AND MEANS,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington, DC, May 2, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR BARNEY: I am writing regarding <bill type="h" number="634">H.R. 634</bill>, the American Veterans Disabled for Life Commemorative Coin Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As you know, the Committee on Ways and Means maintains jurisdiction over bills that raise revenue. <bill type="h" number="634">H.R. 634</bill> contains a provision that establishes a surcharge for the sale of commemorative coins that are minted under the bill, and thus falls within the jurisdiction of the Committee on Ways and Means.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, as part of our ongoing understanding regarding commemorative coin bills and in order to expedite this bill for floor consideration, the Committee will forgo action. This is being done with the understanding that it does not in any way prejudice the Committee with respect to the appointment of conferees or its jurisdictional prerogatives on this bill or similar legislation in the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would appreciate your response to this letter, confirming this understanding with respect to <bill type="h" number="634">H.R. 634</bill>, and would ask that a copy of our exchange of letters on this matter be included in the RECORD.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Charles B. Rangel,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>COMMITTEE ON FINANCIAL SERVICES,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington, DC, May 2, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR CHARLIE: I am writing in response to your letter regarding <bill type="h" number="634">H.R. 634</bill>, the "American Veterans Disabled for Life Commemorative Coin Act," which was introduced in the House and referred to the Committee on Financial Services on January 23, 2007. It is my  expectation that this bill will be scheduled for floor consideration in the near future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I wish to confirm our mutual understanding on this bill. As you know, section 7 of the bill establishes a surcharge for the sale of commemorative coins that are minted under the bill. I acknowledge your committee's jurisdictional interest in such surcharges as revenue matters. However, I appreciate your willingness to forego committee action on <bill type="h" number="634">H.R. 634</bill> in order to allow the bill to come to the floor expeditiously. I agree that your decision to forego further action on this bill will not prejudice  the Committee on Ways and Means with respect to its jurisdictional prerogatives on this or similar legislation. I would support your request for conferees on those provisions within your jurisdiction should this bill be the subject of a House-Senate conference.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I will include this exchange of letters in the CONGRESSIONAL RECORD when this bill is considered by the House. Thank you again for your assistance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Barney Frank,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412202" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I rise today in strong support of <bill type="h" number="634">H.R. 634</bill>, the American Veterans Disabled for Life Commemorative Coin Act introduced by Mr. Moore and by my colleague from Illinois (Mr. Kirk).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, occasionally we disagree on the floor of this great Chamber, and we heard some of those disagreements aired a couple of minutes ago, but now there can be no disagreement about the goals of this legislation, honoring the heroes who have been grievously injured in the defense of this country, in defense of liberty, in defense of democracy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are plenty of monuments, as well there ought to be, for those who gave their lives for those causes, but I know of no monument to those who lived, but whose lives were drastically altered, whose bodies were broken, but whose spirits are still strong. But now they will have their own monument, and it is only right, Madam Speaker.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This memorial will be for the World War II vet who came back without a hand, the Korean War vet who uses a wheelchair, the Vietnam vet who uses the white cane of the blind, and for the veterans of the conflicts in the gulf, who came back to us forever changed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 2000, Congress approved the building of the American Veterans Disabled for Life Memorial. It will be a $65 million privately funded memorial just west of the Rayburn Building, across from the Botanic Garden and in full view of the Capitol. The Commission of Fine Arts and the National Capital Planning Commission approved the conceptual design in 2004 and reaffirmed it in 2006.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The memorial will express our Nation's gratitude to those who paid the terrible cost of defending freedom. It represents the values of duty, of courage and of sacrifice that are the lifeblood of American democracy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge Members, staff and the rest of the country to look at the Web site of the memorial at avdlm.org.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>About half of the money for construction already has been raised, and this legislation, through surcharges on the sale of silver one-dollar coins to be issued by the U.S. Mint in 2010, could raise another $3.5 million to be used for construction or to maintain the dramatic memorial.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I am glad to be one of more than 300 Members of Congress who have cosponsored this bill, which is supported by the VFW, the American Legion, the DAV, and thousands of veterans and veteran organizations across the Nation who have contributed to the memorial's creation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I ask for the immediate passage of <bill type="h" number="634">H.R. 634</bill> and urge all Members to support it.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400282" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412202" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield 5 minutes to the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Kirk), the sponsor of the bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400222" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, there are over 50 million Americans who have worn our country's uniform, and over 20 million are alive today. Among them there are 3 million Americans who are disabled from wounds in battle. Thanks to advances in military medicine, soldiers who once died of their wounds are now surviving and they return from battle with broken bodies, but not broken spirits. It is that spirit of men and women that we honor today. This Moore-Kirk bill will help raise funds for a memorial to disabled  American veterans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to particularly thank my bipartisan partner in this effort, Representative Dennis Moore of Kansas. We formed a bond and a partnership to pass this bill first authored by Representative Sue Kelly of New York. Mr. Moore and I worked many weeks to get over 290 cosponsors, Republicans and Democrats, to make sure this bill could come to the floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 2000, Congress authorized the construction of the Americans Veterans Disabled for Life Memorial just south of the Rayburn Building within sight of the U.S. Capitol. Last December, President Bush signed into law a bill transferring control of the land for the memorial from the District of Columbia to the National Park Service. Now, the American Veterans Disabled for Life Memorial Foundation needs to raise approximately $65 million to cover the cost of construction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our bill today will authorize the Secretary of the Treasury to mint commemorative silver dollars to be sold with a surcharge that will help the American Veterans Disabled for Life Memorial Foundation to raise the money it needs for this memorial. Not only will these coins be collectors' items, but they will benefit this worthy cause.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Earlier this year, I had the privilege of meeting with an extraordinary young man, Sergeant Bryan Anderson of Rolling Meadows, Illinois. Bryan's story is, unfortunately, all too common for our soldiers in Iraq, but his spirit is uncommon, and his attitude sets him apart from the average person.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>You see, Bryan lost both legs and an arm to a roadside bomb in Iraq. He jokes that he would have lost both arms if he hadn't been smoking when the bomb detonated. His sense of humor and determination are clearly apparent in the interview that he gave to Esquire Magazine in January. In it he said, "This wound does not define me. It may be how I look on the outside, but it is not who I am. I guess you could remember me easily as being a triple amputee, but that's not who I am. It has nothing to  do with who I am. I have always been the same person."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Bryan is a self-described "adrenalin junkie" who hopes one day to become a Hollywood stuntman. Since his appearances on the cover of Esquire, he has had numerous opportunities to use his story for the gain of this legislation, often being baited to say if he has any political affiliation or asked what he thinks about the war. Each time he refuses to take the bait. He says he doesn't want to talk about politics. But he is always willing and excited to talk about the American Veterans Disabled  for Life Memorial.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington has legions of professional advocates who make a living convincing people to see issues from their point of view, but none of them compare to Bryan Anderson. With Bryan, what you see is what you get, an American veteran with an inspirational story that has dedicated a good portion of his life to seeing that this memorial be built, not just for himself, but for 3 million disabled American veterans, and for everyone to remember the sacrifices that they have made.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Bryan is a genuine man that you may one day meet. I hope passage of this legislation brings us closer to a day when Bryan returns to Capitol Hill to see the memorial that he helped to build.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With more than 3 million disabled American veterans in the United States, it is fitting that we construct a memorial in Washington, D.C., within sight of this Capitol. It is my hope that my colleagues will answer Bryan Anderson's call to action and support this legislation to make this memorial a reality.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With that, I just want to once again thank my colleague from Kansas (Mr. Moore) for an outstanding partnership and a great bipartisan victory today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400282" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I want to again thank my colleague from Illinois (Mr. Kirk) for the wonderful display of bipartisanship here. I wish we could set an example and hope we set an example for all of our colleagues here to work on other matters together.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield 2 minutes to the gentleman from Michigan (Mr. Stupak).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400391" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, let me compliment the sponsors of this bill, Mr. Moore from Kansas and Mr. Kirk from Illinois. I am down here on another bill, but I felt compelled to say a few words, if I may, on this piece of legislation, which really honors American disabled veterans with this commemorative coin. This will help us raise the money to build this monument, which is long overdue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Whether you are talking about my father-in-law, Ken Olsen, up in Escanaba, who was disabled in World War II, or the recent disabled members of our Armed Forces coming back from Afghanistan and Iraq, I think we can all personally relate to different stories.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, Derek Gagne, who spent quite a bit of time at Walter Reed Army Hospital, is coming back to the upper peninsula of Michigan, where family and friends will be waiting to greet him home. Unfortunately, as Derek has left his bed at Walter Reed for an amputation he had to have because of injuries sustained in Iraq, unfortunately, that bed is being taken by another member from my district who also was wounded in Iraq.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We talk about our disabled veterans and we honor them throughout our time, especially in the summer months through the Memorial Day and 4th of July and all the holidays we celebrate in parades and ceremonies like that, but it is time that we have the memorial here in Washington, so those of us who make decisions on war understand that it is more than just sending an army here or there, but that there is consequences of it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>Whether the injury is an amputation or a closed-head injury, which we are seeing so much of in the war in Iraq, each and every injury serves to remind us of the horrors of war but also that these men and women and their families and their spouses deserve our utmost respect.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I am very pleased to see this memorial start to take on more and more life, to become a reality. And the work of Mr. Moore and Mr. Kirk will certainly help bring forth this memorial. I am very honored to not only cosponsor <bill type="h" number="634">H.R. 634</bill>, but also to support the American Veterans Disabled for Life Commemorative Coin Act.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412202" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400282" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Kansas (Mr. Moore) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="634">H.R. 634</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400282" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this question will be postponed.</chair>
</record>
