<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1194973204" ordinal="42" title="HONORING SAN JOSE STATE UNIVERSITY FOR ITS 150 YEARS OF COMMITMENT TO PUBLIC HIGHER EDUCATION">
  <narrative>HONORING SAN JOSE STATE UNIVERSITY FOR ITS 150 YEARS OF COMMITMENT TO PUBLIC HIGHER EDUCATION -- (House of Representatives - November 13, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H13816]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400031" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution (<bill type="hr" number="365">H. Res. 365</bill>) honoring San Jose State University for its 150 years of commitment to public higher education, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the resolution.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the resolution is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="hr" number="365">H. Res. 365</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas 2007 commemorates the sesquicentennial year that San Jos&#xE9; State University was first established in 1857 as Minns Evening Normal School to train teachers for the growing population of California;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the success of the Minns Evening Normal School in San Francisco led to an Act enacted by the California Legislature on May 2, 1862, providing for the establishment of the first California State Normal School in 1862 and thus beginning a new era for education in the State of California: the first State-wide program of free instruction in preparing teachers and prospective teachers;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas from these beginnings as the oldest public, four-year institution of higher education in California, San Jos&#xE9; State University has matured into a comprehensive university, offering bachelor's and master's degrees in 134 programs;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas San Jos&#xE9; State University is the flagship school of the California State University system, which uses the 1857 founding date as part of its own heritage as noted on its official seal;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas California State University, the largest public system of higher learning in the United States, is recognized for its long-term commitment to affordable, accessible, and high-quality education;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas San Jos&#xE9; State University is the region's largest university and the third largest public-sector employer with 30,000 students and 4,000 employees;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas San Jos&#xE9; State University-related spending in the San Francisco Bay Area is an estimated $479 million, generating a total impact of $829 million on the region's economy, sustaining 11,000 jobs, and generating $48 million annually in tax revenue;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas San Jos&#xE9; State University has contributed to the rich economic life and culture of the State of California by providing nearly 7,000 graduates into the workforce each year;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas San Jos&#xE9; State University's most prized tradition is a commitment to enriching the lives of its students by transmitting knowledge and providing them with the skills to apply what they have learned into the service of our society;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas San Jos&#xE9; State University ranks tenth in the Nation's top public universities in the total number of minority graduates--African Americans, Latinos, Asian Americans, and Pacific Islanders, with bachelor's degrees across all disciplines;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas San Jos&#xE9; State University has conferred bachelor's degrees in business management and the health professions to more Asian Americans and Pacific Islanders than any other college or university in the Nation;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas San Jos&#xE9; State University is among the top 35 colleges and universities in terms of the number of bachelor's and master's degrees conferred to Latino students and is therefore a recognized leader in graduating minority students;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas San Jos&#xE9; State University's faculty contribute to the quality of life in the Nation by their active engagement in scholarship, research, technological innovation, community service, and the arts; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas San Jos&#xE9; State University is an active partner with educational institutions, industries, and communities to enhance the quality of education, research, development, and community service for the State of California: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the House of Representatives honors San Jos&#xE9; State University for its 150 years of commitment to public higher education.</narrative>
  <narrative>Amend the title so as to read: "Resolution honoring San Jos&#xE9; State University for its 150 years of commitment to public higher education.".</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from New York (Mr. Bishop) and the gentleman from New York (Mr. Kuhl) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from New York (Mr. Bishop).</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400031" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I request 5 legislative days during which Members may insert material relevant to <bill type="hr" number="365">H. Res. 365</bill> into the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from New York?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400031" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise today in recognition of the 150th anniversary of San Jose State University. San Jose State University was established in 1857 as Minns Evening Normal School, for the sole purpose of training teachers, as California's population grew. As California's population has grown, San Jose State has grown into the largest university in the region with an enrollment of more than 30,000 students. The school has also expanded its programs to offer 134 bachelor's or master's degrees.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>San Jose State is an extremely diverse school, with an enrollment of 23 percent of its students being Asian, 15 percent of its students being Hispanic, and 5 percent of its students being African American. This diversity has also led San Jose State to rank 10th in the Nation in total number of graduating minorities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I am glad to see another outstanding educational institution continuing to serve all those who wish to advance their education. I would like to thank and congratulate my colleague, Mr. Honda, for bringing this resolution to the attention of the House of Representatives. I urge my colleagues to resoundingly pass this resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400642" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise in support of House Resolution 365, honoring San Jose State University for its 150 years of commitment to public higher education. I would like to thank my good friend, Mr. Honda, for introducing the resolution, and certainly my friend from New York for managing the bill on the floor tonight and recognizing the important role San Jose State University plays in educating the citizens of California and many other States and nations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>San Jose State University was founded as a California State Normal School by the California legislature on May 4, 1857, and is the oldest public university in California. The California State Normal School was itself derived from the Minns Evening Normal School, which was also known as the San Francisco Normal School. Led by Principal George W. Minns, the San Francisco Normal School trained elementary teachers as part of that city's high  school system  from 1857 to their professional development and personal growth.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Silicon Valley firms are constantly seeking San Jose State University students for internships, summer work programs, and research and development. For a century and a half, San Jose State University faculty and staff has prepared its students for roles as leaders and highly productive professionals and citizens in society.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is no better way of understanding San Jose State University's economic impact than simply visiting any Silicon Valley workplace, whether it is a tech company, government office, a hospital, or classroom, many of the people you will meet have ties to San Jose State University. In fact, San Jose State University has sent nearly 300,000 graduates into the workforce since it was founded in 1857, and I am honored to stand here today in support of this resolution and would say to my fellow colleagues:  I would like you to support and congratulate San Jose State University's Don W. Kassing and all of the faculty and staff as well as San Jose State University students and alumni. I wish them continued success, and I ask my colleagues to support this resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400031" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 3 minutes to Ms. Zoe Lofgren of California.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400245" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I join in the recognition of San Jose State on its 150th anniversary. I am proud that San Jose State is located in the 16th Congressional District which I represent in San Jose, California, as has been mentioned. It is the Silicon Valley university. More than 300,000 graduates of San Jose State have gone into Silicon Valley, and it is the largest source of engineering talent, of computer science and business graduates, for Silicon Valley.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>San Jose State is ranked eighth among the top ten colleges and universities offering bachelor's and master's degrees in the western region, with its 134 programs. It is also known for its innovative partnerships, including a first-ever, I think in the country, partnership with the City of San Jose to have a joint university-city public library, a joint venture with the National Hispanic University for joint degrees, and most recently a joint venture with a historically black college in Mississippi  for joint issuance of Ph.D.'s in engineering.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am proud to represent San Jose State. We had to decide who would introduce this resolution. And although the university is in the 16th District, the author, my friend, Congressman MIKE HONDA, is an alumni of the university, so we deferred to him to take the lead on this introduction. I want to thank him for doing so. This is an important event for those of us in Silicon Valley, and especially the 16th District.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400031" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 2 minutes to the gentleman from California (Mr. Honda).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400185" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of <bill type="h" number="365">H.R. 365</bill>, recognizing the 150th anniversary of my alma mater, San Jose State University in California.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I'd like to thank Representatives LOFGREN, ESHOO, FARR, Chairman Miller, and Ranking Member McKeon of the Education and Labor Committee, and additional cosponsors of <bill type="h" number="365">H.R. 365</bill>, for the support of this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For a century and a half, San Jose State has provided affordable access to quality education. Founded in 1857, it is the oldest public institution of higher education on the west coast. From its beginnings as a normal school to train teachers for the developing frontier, the campus has matured into a comprehensive university, offering bachelor's and master's degrees in 134 programs, including 69 bachelor's degrees with 81 concentrations, and 65 master's degrees with 29 concentrations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the western region, San Jose State is ranked among the top 10 colleges and universities offering bachelors and masters degrees. San Jose State is part of the California State University System, the Nation's largest public university system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Noteworthy in this sesquicentennial year of celebration is the fact San Jose State is the largest public 4-year university in Silicon Valley with over 32,000 students and 4,000 faculty and staff members. The university awards more than 4,200 bachelors degrees and 2,400 masters degrees each academic year. Since its founding, the university has sent nearly 300,000 graduates into the workforce. These graduates continue to make significant contributions to the region's rich economy and culture.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The history of San Jose State is very unique. The university traces its origins to Minns Evening Normal School, established in San Francisco in 1857 by George W. Minns and other dedicated educational leaders to address the shortage of qualified teachers for the new State of California. In 1862, the school became California State Normal School by action of the State legislature. Although initial enrollments were low, demand for teacher training shot up when California instituted free public education  for every child, paid for with property taxes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The years of growth and expansion at the new location in San Jose State downtown, the first alumni association was formed in 1873. The determination of California leaders to support teacher training was evident when a fire destroyed the normal school building in 1880. In 1921, the control of the school passed from its board of trustees to the State Department of Education.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As the 20th century came to a close, San Jose State University has developed into a thriving comprehensive university known for "powering Silicon Valley."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I just want to close by recognizing the current president, Don W. Kassing, for all the work he is doing to make San Jose State University one of the great, great higher education institutions in the United States, melding itself with the National Hispanic University and also providing students and intellectual power to NASA Ames and the other Silicon Valley enterprises in Silicon Valley.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>San Jos&#xE9; State ranks among the nation's top universities for its academics and ethnic diversity. The university has ranked 10th in the nation for the total number of minority graduates (African Americans, Asian Americans, Native Americans and Hispanics with bachelor's degrees) across all disciplines. San Jos&#xE9; State University has conferred bachelor's degrees in business management and the health professions to more Asian Americans than any other college or university in the nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Noteworthy also is the fact that San Jos&#xE9; State is Silicon Valley's largest university and fourth largest public-sector employer. Its 154-acre campus is in downtown San Jos&#xE9;, the nation's 10th largest city and home to many leading technology companies, including Adobe, Cisco Systems, and E-Bay.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The history of San Jos&#xE9; State is very unique. The university traces its origins to Minns' Evening Normal School, established in San Francisco in 1857 by George W. Minns and other dedicated educational leaders, to address the shortage of qualified teachers for the new state of California. In 1862, the school became the California State Normal School by action of the state legislature. Although initial enrollments were low, demand for teacher training shot up when California instituted free  public education for every child, paid for with property taxes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An earthquake in 1868 and the challenges of San Francisco's rapid growth spurred school leaders to consider a more stable location for the new school. Several cities vied for the honor; the nod went to the town of San Jos&#xE9;, then a thriving community of 9,089. State Superintendent O.P. Fitzgerald characterized San Jos&#xE9; as meeting every requirement: "The climate is unsurpassed, the place is large enough to furnish all needed facilities ..... the people are intelligent, hospitable and  moral." In 1870, the trustees selected a tract of land near local transit called Washington Square from among several sites offered by the city. School leaders moved the college and its 150 students to this 27-acre campus in 1871.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Years of growth and expansion at the new location followed; the school added more students, faculty, coursework and facilities. The first alumni association was formed in 1873. The determination of California leaders to support teacher training was evident when a fire destroyed the normal school building in 1880. The legislature promptly provided $150,000 to rebuild. By 1887, the San Jos&#xE9; State Normal School had an enrollment of 800, highest in the nation except for New York City and Philadelphia.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1921, control of the school passed from its board of trustees to the State Department of Education and it became known as San Jos&#xE9; State Teachers College. Under the leadership of Thomas W. MacQuarrie, who was  named president in 1927, there was significant growth and expansion of the curriculum, including the first program for college-trained police officers in the nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1932, the San Jos&#xE9; State College Corporation was formed, the forerunner of today's San Jos&#xE9; State University Research Foundation, which for the past 75 years has partnered with the University to manage externally funded research and education-related activities that are so integral to the University's mission. The campus gained university status and became part of the California State University system in the 1970s. In 1990, student enrollment topped 30,000 and by 1993, the campus  reached cultural pluralism, with no ethnic majority.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As the 20th century came to a close, San Jos&#xE9; State University had developed into a thriving comprehensive university known for "powering Silicon Valley" with the high numbers of graduates who went to work there. Fruitful partnerships with area firms also made possible new programs and laboratories, as well as ALL internships, summer research and scholarships. A unique partnership with the city of San Jos&#xE9; resulted in the construction and opening of the nation's first joint city-university  library.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 2006, President Don W. Kassing accepted the largest single private donation to the university in its history, a $10 million gift from alumni Sally and Donald Lucas to create a new graduate school of business. One year later, during this sesquicentennial year, $15 million was given by alumnus Charles W. Davidson for the SJSU's College of Engineering, which ties for the largest single private donation in California State University history. Building upon its tradition as a teacher's college,  the university also received a donation of $10 million from alumna Connie L. Lurie for the College of Education.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Having receiving both my Undergraduate and Graduate degrees from San Jos&#xE9; State University I personally attest to the University's academic rigor and integrity. San Jos&#xE9; State University continues to be a driving force in educating our future leaders and in developing collaborative partnerships with educational institutions, industries, and communities to enhance the quality of education, research, development, and community service for the State of California.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also want to recognize the current president, Don W. Kassing, for all he is doing to make San Jos&#xE9; State University one of the great, great higher education institutions in the United States, and we all look forward to the next 150 years.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400031" topic="">
    <paragraph>We have no additional speakers.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400642" topic="">
    <paragraph>I have no additional speakers on this side. I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400031" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from New York (Mr. Bishop) that the House suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, <bill type="hr" number="365">H. Res. 365</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the resolution, as amended, was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The title was amended so as to read: "Resolution honoring San Jose State University for its 150 years of commitment to public higher education.".</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
