<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1211212804" ordinal="36" title="MOTORCYCLE SAFETY AWARENESS MONTH">
  <narrative>MOTORCYCLE SAFETY AWARENESS MONTH -- (House of Representatives - May 19, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H4100]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412200" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution (<bill type="hr" number="339">H. Res. 339</bill>) supporting the goals of Motorcycle Safety Awareness Month, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the resolution.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the resolution is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="hr" number="339">H. Res. 339</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas approximately 7,000,000 motorcyclists ride on our Nation's roads and highways to commute, travel, and recreate;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas motorcycles are a valuable component of the transportation mix;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas motorcycles are fuel-efficient and decrease congestion while having little impact on our Nation's transportation infrastructure;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the United States is the world leader in motorcycle safety, promoting education, licensing, use of protective gear, and motorcycle awareness;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the motorcycling community is committed to decreasing motorcycle crashes through licensing, training, education, enforcement, personal responsibility, and increased public awareness;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, according to a comprehensive study conducted on motorcycle crash causation in the United States the "Motorcycle Accident Cause Factors and Identification of Countermeasures" (Hurt Report), in approximately two-thirds of fatal car-motorcycle crashes, the driver of the car was at fault; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas motorcycle awareness is beneficial to all road users and will help to decrease car-motorcycle crashes;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas May is designated as "Motorcycle Safety Awareness Month"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas National Highway Traffic Safety Administration promotes Motorcycle Safety Awareness Month to encourage riders to always wear helmets and other protective gear, never drink and ride, be properly licensed, and get training and to remind all riders and motorists to always share the road: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the House of Representatives--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) recognizes the contribution motorcycles make to the transportation mix;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) encourages all road users to be more aware of motorcycles and motorcyclists' safety;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) encourages all riders to receive appropriate training and practice safe riding skills; and</narrative>
  <narrative> (4) supports the goals of Motorcycle Safety Awareness Month.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from Hawaii (Ms. Hirono) and the gentleman from Wisconsin (Mr. Petri) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentlewoman from Hawaii.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412200" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days within which to revise and extend their remarks, and to include extraneous material on <bill type="hr" number="339">H. Res. 339</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from Hawaii?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412200" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise in strong support of <bill type="hr" number="339">H. Res. 339</bill>, a resolution that supports the goals of Motorcycle Safety Awareness Month, and that brings much needed attention to motorcycle safety on our Nation's roadways. I thank the gentleman from Texas (Mr. Burgess) and the gentlewoman from Arizona (Ms. Giffords) for bringing this important issue to the forefront.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As spring arrives, our highways and rural roads will once again see a large increase in motorcycle traffic across the country. Motorcycles make up a valuable component of the transportation network in our Nation, with over 6.2 million registered motorcycles in the United States in 2006. These numbers continue to grow in each year as registrations increase by over 60 percent from 1998 to 2005.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With gas prices approximating $4 per gallon, motorcyclists benefit from the significant advantage they hold in fuel efficiency over drivers. However, this increasingly popular mode of transportation also requires greater attention to the safety concerns associated with riding. Because of their smaller size, motorcyclists are often hidden in a vehicle's blind spot. Public awareness of motorcycle safety benefits everyone that uses our Nation's roadways, not just motorcyclists, because it can lead  to a decrease in car-motorcycle crashes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the statistics on motorcycle fatalities and injuries each year further illustrate the importance of public awareness and the need for greater education of all roadway users. Per vehicle mile traveled, motorcyclists are approximately 37 times more likely than passenger car occupants to die in a motor vehicle traffic crash and eight times more likely to be injured. In 2006, motorcycle rider fatalities increased for the ninth straight year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>According to NHTSA, between 1996 and 2006 there were 35,546 motorcyclist fatalities, and 708,000 motorcyclist injuries on U.S. roadways. In 2006, there were 4,810 motorcycle fatalities and 88,000 injuries, up from 2,161 fatalities and 55,000 injuries in 1996.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Throughout Motorcycle Safety Awareness Month, riders are encouraged to become educated on the importance of following the rules of the roadway, being alert to other drivers, and always wearing protective gear, such as a helmet. NHTSA estimates that helmets saved 1,658 motorcyclists' lives in 2006, and that 752 more lives could have been saved if the motorcyclists involved in fatal nonhelmeted crashes had worn helmets.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, as these statistics illustrate, increased awareness of motorcycle safety is an important and urgent need in this country. We cannot allow thousands of riders to die each year on our Nation's highways. Motorcycle Safety Awareness Month helps to decrease motorcycle crashes through licensing, rider training, education, enforcement, personal responsibility, and increased public awareness.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman from Texas (Mr. Burgess) and the gentlewoman from Arizona (Ms. Giffords) for introducing this resolution, and urge my colleagues to support its passage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400318" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of House Resolution 339, which was introduced by our colleague, Representative Michael Burgess from Texas. The resolution expresses support for the goals of Motorcycle Safety Awareness Month.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Each May during Motorcycle Safety Awareness Month, State agencies and motorcycle organizations across our country conduct a variety of activities to remind all riders and motorcyclists to share the road. These activities also encourage riders to wear protective gear, never drink and ride, be properly licensed, and receive proper training. All of these important messages help motorcyclists and other motorists get ready for the busy riding season ahead.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In approximately two-thirds of fatal car versus motorcycle crashes, the driver of the car has been found to be at fault. Motorcycle Safety Awareness Month will help drivers of cars, trucks, and motorcycles remember that they must consider other users of the road as they use their own vehicles.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Additionally, this resolution recognizes the transportation benefits associated with motorcycling. Specifically, motorcycles are fuel efficient and decrease congestion while having little impact on our Nation's transportation infrastructure. I support this resolution, and I hope it brings attention to motorcycle safety across our Nation's highways as well as the benefits associated with motorcycling. Mr. Speaker, I urge all my colleagues to support this resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in strong support of <bill type="hr" number="339">H. Res. 339</bill>, as amended, a resolution that supports the goals of Motorcycle Safety Awareness Month and that brings much needed attention to motorcycle safety on our nation's roadways. I want to thank the gentleman from Texas (Mr. BURGESS) and the gentlewoman from Arizona (Ms. GIFFORDS) for bringing this important issue to the forefront.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With warmer weather arriving, our nation's highways will once again experience a large increase in motorcycle traffic across the country. Motorcycles represent a valuable component of the transportation network in our nation. In 2005 there were over 6.2 million registered motorcycles in the United States. Motorcycles continue to grow in popularity each year with registrations increasing by over 60 percent from 1998 to 2005.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Motorcycles are a fuel-efficient and congestion-decreasing mode of transportation and are a valuable component of our transportation system. This increasingly popular mode of transportation also requires greater attention to the safety concerns associated with riding. Because of their smaller size, motorcyclists are often hidden in a vehicle's blind spot. Public awareness of motorcycle safety benefits everyone that uses our nation's roadways, not just motorcyclists, because it can lead to a decrease  in car-motorcycle crashes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The statistics on motorcycle fatalities and injuries each year further illustrate the importance of public awareness and the need for greater education of all roadway users. In 2006, motorcycle rider fatalities increased for the ninth straight year. According to the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration ("NHTSA"), between 1996 and 2006, there were 35,546 motorcyclist fatalities and 708,000 motorcyclist injuries on U.S. roadways. In 2006 there were 4,810 motorcycle fatalities and 88,000  injuries, up from 2,161 fatalities and 55,000 injuries in 1996.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Per vehicle mile traveled, motorcyclists are approximately 37 times more likely than passenger car occupants to die in a motor vehicle traffic crash and 8 times more likely to be injured. Further, an estimated 137,000 motorcyclists have been killed since the enactment of the Highway Safety and National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act of 1966. A NHTSA-funded study--the "Motorcycle Accident Cause Factors and Identification of Countermeasures Study"--found that in approximately two-thirds  of fatal car-motorcycle crashes, the driver of the car was at fault.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Throughout Motorcycle Safety Awareness Month, riders are encouraged to become educated on the importance of following the rules of the roadway, being alert to other drivers, and always wearing protective gear such as a helmet. NHTSA estimates that helmets saved 1,658 motorcyclists' lives in 2006, and that 752 more lives could have been saved if the motorcyclists involved in fatal non-helmeted crashes had worn helmets.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, these striking statistics paint a very clear portrait of the need to decrease motorcycle crashes through licensing, rider training, education, enforcement, personal responsibility, and increased public awareness.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to join me in agreeing to the resolution, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412188" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, in my home state of Arizona we have 150,000 registered motorcycles.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With over 300 days of sunshine in our state every year, you can imagine why so many Arizonans choose to ride their bikes!</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are many other reasons why motorcycles are so popular, but one explanation is simple economics: the rising cost of gas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Motorcycles offer a more fuel efficient--and cheaper way--of getting around.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On average, motorcycles can get between 40 and 75 miles per gallon of gas. And even as gasoline prices are hovering near $3.75 a gallon in many parts of the country, motorcycle riders can fill up for less. According to the U.S. Department of Transportation, motorcycles consume 56 percent less fuel per mile traveled.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many people are now taking the plunge to own and ride a motorcycle regularly. Over the past decade, U.S. motorcycle sales have more than tripled. They are growing in popularity as a fun and fuel-efficient alternative.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a member of the House Science and Technology Committee, I am committed to working with all my constituents and colleagues in Congress to move our country forward and continue our tradition of international leadership on environmental Issues.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And I am proud that, as a motorcyclist for over 20 years, I am leaving a smaller footprint on our earth by just riding my bike.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But, I do have concerns about road safety and that drivers sharing the road with me aren't looking out for my well-being. That is why I introduced House Resolution 399, recognizing the importance of motorcycles and supporting the goals of "Motorcycle Safety Awareness Month."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Motorcycles have a higher rate of fatal accidents than automobiles. U.S. Department of Transportation data for 2005 shows that for motorcycles, 75 fatal crashes occur per 100,000 registered vehicles--four times higher than for cars.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="hr" number="399">H. Res. 399</bill> encourages riders to always wear helmets and other protective gear, to never drink and ride, and to be properly licensed and trained. It also serves as a reminder to all riders and motorists to always share the road respectfully.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These are important messages for all road users and timely information for motorcyclists in many areas of the country gearing up for the upcoming riding season.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I, for one, am ready to dust off my boots, grab my helmet, and get on the road!</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Happy "Motorcycle Safety Awareness Month."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400318" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412200" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from Hawaii (Ms. Hirono) that the House suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, <bill type="hr" number="339">H. Res. 339</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400318" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I object to the vote on the ground that a quorum is not present and make the point of order that a quorum is not present.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this motion will be postponed.</chair>
  <chair>The point of no quorum is considered withdrawn.</chair>
</record>
