<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1173286803" ordinal="35" title="WATER QUALITY INVESTMENT ACT OF 2007">
  <chair> Pursuant to House Resolution 214 and rule XVIII, the Chair declares the House in the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for the further consideration of the bill, <bill type="h" number="569">H.R. 569</bill>.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> When the Committee of the Whole rose earlier today, amendment No. 2 printed in the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Congressional Record by the gentleman from California (Mr. Rohrabacher) had been disposed of.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> There being no further amendments, the question is on the committee amendment in the nature of a substitute, as amended.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400644" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>In the current form, I am.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will report the motion to recommit.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> The gentleman from North Carolina is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400644" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this motion to recommit would reinforce existing Federal law by making it clear that none of the funds authorized in this act would be used for lobbying or to retain lobbyists in order to attempt to influence Federal, State or local governments or officials within said governments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This motion to recommit is an insurance policy that guarantees this bill won't be a kickback to K Street. This majority was elected on ending the K Street Project. In House Resolution 6, section 202, they changed rule XXIII to ensure that the K Street Project is ended.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If those words on opening day are to become a reality, I encourage the majority to support this motion to recommit that ensures that a K Street-type project would not be further propagated in this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is a simple principle here; put plainly, I am asking the Members of the House to follow their own rules set up on opening day. From time to time, it is important to challenge Congress's words by calling them to action. And if this new majority is to live by the words they set up by opening day, then they should support this motion to recommit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to yield to my colleague from Georgia, Congressman Price.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I thank the gentleman for yielding, and I thank him for his simple motion to recommit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This really is a simple motion to recommit. What it says is that the money that is authorized and appropriated should go for its intended purposes. It would expand upon existing law by specifically prohibiting Federal funds from being used to pay for membership in any association or organization. It is important to make clear that the funds should only be used for the purposes intended by Congress, mainly the construction of facilities and infrastructure to treat combined sewer overflows.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, while associations and organizations can sometimes provide very meaningful opportunities for collaboration and knowledge dissemination, it would not be appropriate to use scarce, hard-earned Federal taxpayer dollars to pay for membership in such associations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I don't know if my colleagues are aware of this, but some of these dues in these associations and organizations run up to $48,000 to $50,000 a year. Certainly, hard-earned taxpayer money should not go for that purpose. So, in the spirit of responsible spending and to decrease the abuse of hard-earned taxpayer dollars, I urge the adoption of this motion to recommit.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400644" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Reclaiming my time, I would like to in particular talk to my 13 colleagues on the Democrat side, Mr. Speaker, and they realize that a motion to recommit is not a procedural motion; it is actually policy. And when those 13 Democrats voted for the recommit on the card check legislation, they said clearly they understand the underlying policy in a motion to recommit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are talking policy here today, Mr. Speaker. In this House, if the Democrat majority was truly elected and is committed to severing the link between legislation and lobbyists, they will vote for this motion to recommit. This motion to recommit is a gut check for Congress, especially the new Members of this body who have not been here before this last election cycle. It is gut check time for them, for them to explain to their constituents that they like the idea of limiting lobbyists' influence,  and whether or not they are willing to fulfill that vote here on the House floor today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This truly is an insurance policy that guarantees this bill won't simply be a kickback to K Street by this new majority.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise to speak on the motion to recommit.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is the gentleman opposed to the motion?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>No. I seek to speak on the motion.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from Minnesota is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the operative provision of <bill type="h" number="569">H.R. 569</bill>, section 221, provides, "The administrator may make grants to States for the purpose of providing grants to a municipality or municipal entity for planning, design and construction of treatment works to intercept, transport, control or treat municipal combined sewer overflows and sanitary sewer overflows." It says nothing about paying lobbyists, retaining a lobbyist or influencing Federal, State or local government entity or officer.  But if the gentleman is concerned that somehow money might be diverted in that, we are fully prepared to accept the amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the previous question is ordered on the motion to recommit.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400644" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I demand a recorded vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 and 9 of rule XX, this 15-minute vote on the motion to recommit will be followed by 5-minute votes on the question of passing the bill and on suspending the rules and passing <bill type="h" number="710">H.R. 710</bill>.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, pursuant to the instructions of the House on the motion to recommit, I report the bill, <bill type="h" number="569">H.R. 569</bill>, back to the House with an amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will report the amendment.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> The question is on the amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 5-minute vote.</chair>
</record>
