<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1170262802" ordinal="24" title="FURTHER CONTINUING APPROPRIATIONS, FISCAL YEAR 2007">
  <speaking speaker="400300" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, pursuant to House Resolution 116, I call up the joint resolution (<bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill>) making further continuing appropriations for the fiscal year 2007, and for other purposes, and ask for its immediate consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the joint resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I demand the question of consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from Georgia demands the question of consideration. Under clause 3 of rule XVI, the question is: Will the House now consider the joint resolution?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400300" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I demand a recorded vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask for a division on that vote, Mr. Speaker.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> A recorded vote has already been ordered. The vote will proceed. Members will record their vote by electronic device. It will be a 15-minute vote.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400196" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to reconsider the vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion to table the motion to reconsider.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400196" topic="MOTION TO TABLE OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I demand a recorded vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400644" topic="POINT OF ORDER">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise to make a point of order.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman will state his point of order.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400644" topic="POINT OF ORDER">
    <paragraph>Under the new House rules, there is an anti-earmark rule that governs the House, which the rule governing this bill does not waive that rule of the House; and sections of this legislation actually go forward and violate that anti-earmark legislation. Therefore, I rise to make a point of order against <bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill>, as title I, section 101(a)(2), violates rule XXI, clause 9, of the House rules, stating, "There shall be no Member-directed earmarks," which this legislation does possess.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Does any Member wish to be heard?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400300" topic="POINT OF ORDER">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would simply note that on page H988 of the Congressional Record there is listed the following statement:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under clause 9(a) of rule XXI, lists or statements on congressional earmarks, limited tax benefits or limited tariff benefits are submitted as follows offered by myself: <bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill> making further continuing appropriations for fiscal year 2007, and for other purposes, does not contain any congressional earmarks, limited tax benefits, or limited tariff benefits as defined in clause 9(d), 9(e), or 9(f) of rule XXI.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400644" topic="POINT OF ORDER">
    <paragraph>Will the gentleman yield?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400300" topic="POINT OF ORDER">
    <paragraph>No.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400644" topic="POINT OF ORDER">
    <paragraph>The gentleman will not yield for the question.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> On a point of order there is no yielding. The chair will hear each Member in turn. Does the gentleman from North Carolina wish to be heard on his point of order?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400644" topic="POINT OF ORDER">
    <paragraph>Yes. I wish to speak further.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400644" topic="POINT OF ORDER">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the gentleman is stating, simply because legislation states that there are no earmarks, that you can contain thousands of earmarks after that statement. It defies logic and defies reason.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And, furthermore, your section explaining that there shall be no congressional earmarks is further on in the legislation. Therefore, it is not operational over the violation that I am stating in section 101. Therefore, under the legislation here, it is not operational. Therefore, it is a very crafty way, and I have got to compliment the gentleman for putting together a very crafty piece of legislation to try to slip this by. But under these House rules, this is a clear violation of the anti-earmarking  provision that is very important to the rules of debate, even when the minority is not able to offer any amendments, even when the minority has no other means of removing congressional earmarks.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman will restrict himself to the point of order.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400300" topic="POINT OF ORDER">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask for a ruling from the Chair.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Under clause 9(a) of rule XXI, it is not in order to consider an unreported bill or joint resolution unless the chairman of each committee of initial referral has caused to be printed in the Congressional Record a list of congressional  earmarks, limited tax benefits, or limited tariff benefits contained in the measure, or a statement that the measure contains no such earmarks or benefits.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400644" topic="POINT OF ORDER">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I appeal the ruling of the Chair.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion to table.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400644" topic="MOTION TO TABLE OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Division. I ask for a division vote, Mr. Speaker.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400300" topic="MOTION TO TABLE OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask for the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400644" topic="MOTION TO TABLE OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Wait a second, Mr. Speaker. I asked for a division vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Under the Constitution, the yeas and nays have precedence over a request for a division.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400644" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRIES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, parliamentary inquiry.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman will state his parliamentary inquiry.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400644" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRIES">
    <paragraph>We just had a vote on this floor about rule XXI, section 9. Just for clarification, for the body's purposes going forward with this new rule, in essence, this is the parliamentary inquiry, if I may state it. The summary of rule XXI, section 9 is that as long as the legislation states that there are no earmarks, there may be thousands of earmarks within that legislation, but only operationally must the legislation include text that states that there are no earmarks. Is that  the ruling of the Chair? I would be happy to give the Speaker numerous examples of earmarks in this.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Chair does not respond to hypothetical questions raised under the guise of a parliamentary inquiry.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400644" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRIES">
    <paragraph>Further parliamentary inquiry then.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman will state his parliamentary inquiry.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400644" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRIES">
    <paragraph>Rule XXI, section 9, states that a bill or joint resolution reported by a committee, unless the report includes a list of congressional earmarks, limited tax benefits, limited tariff benefits in the bill or in the report and the name of any Member, Delegate or Resident Commissioner who submits a request to the committee for each respective item included in such list or a statement that the proposition contains no congressional earmarks, limited tax benefits or limited tariff  benefits. Does this legislation state that and conform to rule XXI, section 9?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Chair previously ruled on that question, and the House sustained the Chair by tabling an appeal.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400644" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRIES">
    <paragraph>Further parliamentary inquiry. Operationally, may a committee Chair simply sign and attest to the Parliamentarian that there are no earmarks within said legislation?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Chair will not render advisory opinions. That is not a proper parliamentary inquiry.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400644" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRIES">
    <paragraph>Further parliamentary inquiry.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Does the gentleman have a proper parliamentary inquiry?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400644" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRIES">
    <paragraph>I appreciate the Speaker operating in such an unbiased way. It is very kind of you.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> If the gentleman will refrain for a moment, the Chair is operating under the precedents and rules of the House of Representatives and properly respecting those rules. So, if the gentleman has a proper parliamentary inquiry, he would please state it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400644" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRIES">
    <paragraph>Parliamentary inquiry, Mr. Speaker. What is an earmark? Under House rules, what is an earmark?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman has again not stated a proper parliamentary inquiry.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400300" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRIES">
    <paragraph>I thank the Speaker. Mr. Speaker, I yield myself 2 minutes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I simply want to thank Janet Airis and her staff at the CBO scoring unit; Ira Forstater and Nadia Soree and the entire staff at the Legislative Council; and certainly, most of all, the staff of the Appropriations Committee, both majority and minority, both Senate and House, especially Rob Nabors and David Reich.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a bill that needs to pass so that everyone who is reliant upon programs contained therein understands what the rules of the game will be for the remainder of the fiscal year. I urge passage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400239" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRIES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today to do something that I have never done before, and that is to oppose House passage of an appropriations bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My friends on the other side of the aisle, and I use the term "friends" sincerely, have produced an 8-month omnibus spending bill that appropriates $463.5 billion. It is legislation that few have seen, which cannot be amended in any way, and that will pass this House after only 1 hour of debate. It is the first omnibus spending bill that I have seen during my time in Congress written and considered without the input of the chairman or ranking members of any appropriations subcommittee, without  the input of any Republican or Democratic subcommittee members, without the benefit of a full Appropriations Committee markup, without the standard three days for circulating the bill to committee members before markup, without the standard 3 days for circulating the bill to all House Members after full committee consideration, without any prior debate whatsoever, and without the opportunity to offer even one amendment on the House floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I do not fault my friend, Mr. Obey, the chairman of the Appropriations Committee, for he is doing what he is asked to be done by his leadership. He is in the position today because of the former Senate majority leader's complete failure to schedule and pass the fiscal year 2007 appropriations bills. The House and the Senate Appropriations Committee did their work last year, and Mr. Obey and I worked very closely in attempting to see it was fully completed. The Senate leadership  did not.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As the former chairman of the committee, I know that Mr. Obey feels strongly about maintaining regular order and passing other appropriations bills. I can vividly recall a conversation Mr. Obey had with me shortly after I became chairman when he suggested that perhaps I would be the last chairman of the Appropriations Committee because of the breakdown of regular order.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I looked to his comments and have taken them to heart because I committed to him and to our Members that we would pass our spending bills in regular order, and the 2 years I served as chairman we did.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, my fear is that Mr. Obey may be the last chairman of the Appropriations Committee because of the very concern he expressed to me, the breakdown of that regular order. Shutting both Republicans and Democrats out of the legislative process is a highly, highly unusual circumstance, but that is exactly what has occurred.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Both Republicans and Democrats are being denied a full and open debate on this legislation that will spend, as I suggested earlier, $463.5 billion, roughly one-half of the annual Federal budget.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Speaker Pelosi and Leader HOYER, both former members of the Appropriations Committee, know that our process is very open and a collaborative one. Historically, appropriations bills are brought to the floor under an open rule to encourage debate and create better legislation. Our spending bills reflect not just the will of the Appropriations Committee but, indeed, the will of the entire bipartisan House. It is not uncommon to have hours and hours of debate and more than 100 Democrat  or Republican amendments offered on a single spending bill. That is, until today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The House will debate this legislation today for 1 hour. Not one amendment has been made in order. The Senate, that is, the other body, on the other hand, will have the opportunity to debate the legislation for up to 15 days and with the potential for an unlimited number of amendments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>Let me repeat, it is important that the Members hear that. One hour of debate in the House with no amendments, 15 days of debate in the Senate with potentially unlimited amendments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Speaker Pelosi has vowed to run the House in a more open, democratic and inclusive way. A spirit of bipartisanship, she said, would prevail in the people's House. That pledge was put on the shelf so the new majority could complete their first 100 hours agenda.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The new majority then promised that business would soon return to regular order with plenty of opportunity for Democrats and Republicans to participate in the democratic process. Members of the House, Democrats and Republicans, are still waiting for the Speaker to keep her word.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In closing, I would suggest that our country would be better served by extending for a full year the clean continuing resolution the House and Senate passed in December. That legislation, a mere 19 pages long, contained no gimmicks, no policy changes, and did not reward or punish agencies indiscriminately, as is done in this 137-page package.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This omnibus spending bill before us today totally disregards the once proud tradition of regular order within the House Appropriations Committee and violates the longstanding bipartisan customs of the people's House. I urge that my colleagues join me in a "no" vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400300" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRIES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield to the gentleman from Texas (Mr. Lampson) for a unanimous consent request.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Mr. LAMPSON asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400229" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRIES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the Energy Policy Act of 2005 which was signed by the President in August of 2005, included four directed spending programs that will each make a significant positive contribution to the security and reliability of the energy supply and infrastructure of this Nation. The Energy Policy Act authorized these programs with full funding so that they could be implemented as soon as possible. It should be made clear that it is the intent of the Continuing Resolution to remove  any impediments that may have arisen to the timely implementation of the four Energy Policy Act provisions--Section 105, the Energy Saving Performance Contracts; Section 384, Coastal Impact Assistance; Section 999, Ultra-deepwater and Unconventional Onshore</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400300" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRIES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself 12 minutes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on Monday, the President will submit to the Congress his new budget. It would be kind of nice if we had disposed of his last year's budget request before the President brings  his new budget forward, because I believe that he is entitled to start the year with a clean slate, and I think we are entitled to start the year with a clean slate as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, we cannot do that because of the failures of the last Congress. This resolution represents the last remaining legislation that must be passed in order to clean up the mess left to us by the last Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, we all know the story. Last year, the House debated and passed every single appropriation bill except the Labor, Health, Education bill. That was held up because of the now-well-known division between the two parties on the minimum wage and also because moderate Republicans in this House, led by people like Mr. Castle and others, were demanding that the Republican leadership add at least $3 billion to the Labor, Health, Education appropriation bill in order to get their votes on  the Republican budget resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The then chairman, Mr. Lewis from California, my good friend, specifically said on the House floor that the reason the Congress was not allowed to finish its work is because the Senate majority leader, Senator Frist, shielded the Senate from any painful votes on appropriations before the election. Then, after the election, the majority party walked away from their responsibility to finish the budget, and they left us to clean up the mess as they walked out the door.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When we considered the CR under which we are now operating, I specifically said from this place on the House floor that I would make any substantive compromise that was necessary and I would make any procedural compromise that was necessary in order to enable the then majority Republicans to finish the bills on their watch, on their terms. I said I was willing to recognize that they still controlled the Congress and so they had a right to have Republican priorities reflected in those bills, even  if I disagreed with those priorities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But I also warned that if they did not live up to their responsibilities to pass the budget, then they would forfeit their right to complain and whine about how we went about cleaning up their leftover jobs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So when it became apparent that they would not meet their responsibilities, Senator Byrd and I announced that we would proceed by doing two things. We announced, first of all, that we would provide no congressional earmarks. We told anybody who had an earmark in a 2007 bill that if they wanted it considered in the following fiscal year they would need to present it under the reform process, which we were in the process of putting together; and we announced at that time that we intended  to cut earmarks by 50 percent in comparison to the 2007 bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The second thing that we announced is that we would take the 2006 continuing resolution and make whatever adjustments were necessary in order to avoid shutdowns of agencies or layoffs or furloughs and in order to recognize priorities that we thought people had on both sides of the aisle. That is what we did.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In this bill, we started with the fiscal 2006 base. We then cut or rescinded $9- to $10 billion, almost $10 billion, in items that we thought could be cut or rescinded. We cut over 60 programs. We generated $10 billion or so in savings, and we added that to the $7 billion that still remained within the Republican budget resolution cap, and then we allocated that money on the basis of what we thought were better priorities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, the gentleman from California says we should have just stuck with the existing 2006 continuing resolution. We could have done that. If we had, we would not have been able to add $3.6 billion in veterans' health care, which we have done in this bill, which is our number one priority. We would not have been able to add $1.2 billion in defense health, which we add in this bill. We would not have been able to add $500 million for basic housing allowances for our military, and we would not have  been able to add the $1 billion that we added for BRAC, the base closing operations. We would also not have been able to add the $216 million that we added to the FBI budget at the request of the administration.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In education, two weeks ago, when the Democratic Party brought to this House floor a proposition to lower interest rates on student loans, we were told, "oh, that is just tokenism. What you ought to do is add to the Pell Grants."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is what we have done. We added enough to the Pell Grant program to allow an increase in the maximum grant of $260. We wouldn't have been able to do that either if we had followed Mr. Lewis' suggestion and simply stuck to the CR under which we are now operating.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to that, we added $250 million to Title I and $100 million to Head Start so we could end the decline in enrollment in that program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the area of science, we were asked by a number of Members on the Republican side of the aisle in this House, and on our side, plus the Senate on both sides, to add money for NIH. Members did not like the fact that, under the alternative, we were going to lose at least 500 medical grants in cancer research, heart disease, Alzheimer's and the rest.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have not met a single constituent who said, "Hey, OBEY, I think you ought to save money by cutting cancer research grants." We added $620 million to reverse the decline in the number of research grants at NIH, and we added some additional funds to the National Science Foundation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We added some additional money to energy conservation and energy research programs, in addition to which we provided a $200 million add-on for the Clean Water Revolving Fund. There isn't a small community in this country that doesn't need some help with clean water.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We added $100 million for park maintenance, and we added $90 million for firefighting.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We also were requested by the administration to provide at least the amount that they asked for the global AIDS program and to combat malaria and TB. So we added $1.4 billion to do that, and we added $146 million to prevent the Social Security Administration from having a 10-day furlough for their employees. That is what we did.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We also provided a suspension of all earmarks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, I want to make clear a lot of the earmarks that we suspended are perfectly defensible. They accomplish laudatory public purposes. I think it is sad that we haven't been able to fund them. But the fact is that it became apparent to me that the earmarking process had been so discredited by the Cunningham case and by other cases that we have no choice but to start over. So we wanted to clear the decks, clean up the process, and start over.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ninety-nine percent of the Members of this House on both sides of the aisle have immense integrity. They don't ask the Congress for things that are illegitimate, but it is that 1 percent that has fouled the nest for everybody else. So we are trying to clean up the nest so that we can approach next year with a clean start and so that we will have a process so that both parties will know what earmarks the other party is putting into the bills.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want the minority to be fully cognizant of whatever earmarks the majority puts in the bills, and I want us to be fully cognizant of the other earmarks you put in the bills. That is the only way we can protect the integrity of this institution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So we are being criticized in some quarters because we are being told, "Well, when you eliminated the earmarks, you should also have eliminated the money in those programs." We didn't do that for one very simple reason. We didn't want to reduce the amount of money in the COPS program, for instance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What we are doing, by eliminating earmarks, and let's be clear about it, we are not saving a dime by eliminating earmarks. But what we are doing is transferring the power to decide where that money goes from the congressional branch to the executive branch. I don't like that, but it is a price I am willing to pay to clean up the system. What that means is that the administration will have much more authority than normal to decide where money goes, whether it is in the Army Corps of Engineers  program or COPS or you name it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would simply say, we may have made some wrong choices. Undoubtedly, we did. But the process was this.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For 3 1/2  weeks our staffs worked 7 days a week round the clock, and they negotiated with the Senate, Republican  and Democratic staff alike. The Republican staff was invited to every meeting that took place. If they attended or didn't, that was up to them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Whenever the staff could not reach agreement, the Members were brought in order to argue it up. If you don't think that occurred, talk to Mr. Visclosky, talk to Senator Domenici, talk about the arguments they had on the Energy and Water bill, and there are countless other examples.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are now in a situation in which we have to move on. We may have made some wrong choices, but at least, in contrast to last year, we made those choices, we made them. They may not be popular, but they were necessary so that we can turn the page, get on the next year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill is the functional equivalent of a conference report. All of the appropriation bills that were not completed action on last year, this is what they look like. This is what they look like. This is a continuing resolution that we are producing today in order to direct where the spending in these bills ought to go.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, you may say you don't think it fits the traditional definition of a continuing resolution. Either you can have an automatic continuing resolution, or you can have a thinking man's continuing resolution. I don't think that we were obligated to lock ourselves into the 2006 numbers, because that would have prevented us from providing the initiatives that I talked about for veterans, for education and the like.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a responsible document. Nothing was sneaked in. Everybody knows what is in this package. All the staff knows.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would urge an "aye" vote for the bill so that, come Monday, we can deal with the President's new budget, rather than continuing to deal with the spilt milk of yesterday's majority.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400239" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRIES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 3 minutes to my colleague, the ranking member of the Homeland Security Subcommittee of Appropriations (Mr. Rogers of Kentucky).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400340" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRIES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I am sad to say that this is a sad day for the U.S. House.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Why do I say that? Well, Mr. Speaker, the power of the purse is the most important power of the Congress. James Madison called the power of the purse "the most complete and effectual weapon with which any constitution can arm the immediate representatives of the people."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The power of the purse of the Congress is exercised through its Appropriations Committee and the appropriations process that is longstanding in this body.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, we are throwing out that procedure. We are saying in this bill that all of the work that has gone on in the hearings, hundreds of hearings, hours and hundreds of hours of testimony that we have taken in the various subcommittee hearings from the administration, from outside witnesses, from Members of Congress, the Senate and so on, all of those hearings are being disregarded and thrown out. The testimony from the agency and the department heads and the Inspectors General and all of the  people that are in the executive branch that are in charge of keeping track of the money, the GAO reports, budget reports, policy expert reports, all of those are being tossed out in favor of the judgment of two Members of the Congress, one from the House, one from the Senate. The bill before us is the product of two people, one from the House, one from the Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>All of the debate that took place on the House floor on these individual bills as they came before this body, and Members expressed their views, offered amendments, had some won, some lost, but nevertheless, the process worked. That is being thrown out.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These bills were chock full of reporting requirements of oversight provisions, congressional controls, money closely tied to results from the administration. The bills were carefully crafted in an open process, input from every Member, and all 10 of the 11 bills passed through the House gained widespread bipartisan support. Legislation we can be proud of. And yet we are throwing that out.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bipartisan work, we are throwing it away. This annual process we call the appropriations process is being discarded. We are cutting the purse strings, blindly handing over the money to the executive branch with no leverage, no new oversight of nearly half of the Federal discretionary budget.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The new majority, Mr. Speaker, has been very righteous in saying it will conduct much more oversight than the previous Congress. And yet this so-called CR completely abdicates the majority's responsibilities as conducting any oversight. Just give the money to the executive branch. Spend it as you please. We don't care. That is what we are saying.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And, Mr. Speaker, I don't like it.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400300" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRIES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself 1 minute.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the gentleman talks about how we should have stuck with the bills that they produced last year. There is only one problem. They couldn't convince their Republican brethren in the Senate to buy them. And so we had to try something else.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I can't help it that the majority party did not meet its responsibilities to pass these appropriations because you had an internal fight within the Republican Party. But now the responsibility is passed to us, and at least we are producing a proposal which can pass both Houses. That is more than can be said for the work product of the last Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I now yield 2 minutes to the gentleman from Texas (Mr. Edwards).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400118" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRIES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I heard the term "abdication of responsibility" used. I consider abdication of responsibility only passing two out of 13 appropriation bills last year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today is a good day for America's veterans. As someone who has fought hard for veterans over the years, I want to applaud Chairman Obey and Democratic leaders for placing such a high priority on veterans in this resolution. It is the right thing to do. Our veterans fought for our country, and now it is time for us to stand up for them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, though, since October 1 of last year, for the last 4 months, VA health care has been woefully underfunded. Why? Because those who are arguing against this resolution today failed to pass for the entire year the 2007 VA appropriations bill when they were in charge of this House and the other body, continued underfunding that put veterans health care seriously at risk.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>VA medical care in this resolution has increased by $3.6 billion. That means $300 million each month once this resolution becomes law, helping to provide better health care for our men and women who have served our country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me personalize what those numbers mean to our veterans. Without the vital funding increase in this resolution, millions of veterans could see their health care services reduced. Hundreds of thousands of veterans could have to wait in line longer, perhaps months longer, to get the medical services they need and they deserve. Tens of thousands of veterans might not even receive any medical care at all from the VA without this resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A vote for this resolution is a vote to respect our veterans. It says we will not only respect our veterans with our words. We will respect them with our deeds. Our veterans deserve no less. Vote "yes" for our veterans by voting "yes" for this resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400239" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRIES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 2 minutes to the gentleman from Virginia (Mr. Wolf).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400435" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRIES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I thank Mr. Lewis for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise in opposition to the resolution. And let me just stipulate it probably has a lot of very good things in it. But when I was chairman of two different subcommittees, we always had complete consultation, and if what I am saying is not accurate, those Members should come down here and attack me for it, complete consultation before we sent the bills out. And what I am concerned about is the precedent that we are establishing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have a resolution to put the Congress on record in support of the Iraq Study Group. Now, am I going to be foreclosed from offering that resolution? Here is a group of men and women, Baker and Hamilton, who spent 8 months. It was one of these evil earmarks that you hear all about it. Am I going to be foreclosed from offering the Baker-Hamilton solution to the  problem? The administration doesn't like it. Probably Members on both sides of the aisle don't  like it. But am I going to be foreclosed? Here is a group that spent 8 months looking at this. And Jim Baker is a good man and Lee Hamilton is a good man. They were bipartisan. Chuck Robb; Bill Perry; Leon Panetta, who served over here; and Ed Meese. Based on what we are seeing here now, I will be foreclosed. Any resolution that comes from this side of the aisle is automatically foreclosed. We have watched it for the whole month of January.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So let me just say I am sure, Mr. Obey, this is probably a lot of good stuff. But we on the minority side have to be treated the way we should be. Do unto others as you would have them do unto you.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, the test will be with my resolution, and there are only two of us on it, GILCHREST and myself. Will I be foreclosed by the Rules Committee in 2 weeks from my resolution that puts the Congress on record in support of the Baker-Hamilton Commission? Ten people, five Republicans, five Democrats, spent more time looking at this issue of Iraq than this Congress has, than the Republican Party has and the Democratic Party has. And based on what is taking place so far today, I will be foreclosed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And I hope I am not foreclosed because when you are in the minority and you don't have that opportunity to offer amendments, then, frankly, you are being cut out of the process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in opposition to this resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a continuing resolution like no other that I have seen before. It is an omnibus appropriations bill that will fund nearly one-half of the federal government for fiscal year 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When I was Chairman of the Science, State, Justice Subcommittee, we had in-depth discussions and consultations with our Ranking and minority members. On our committee we worked in a bi-partisan manner. The precedent that this CR is setting troubles me.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have a resolution supporting the recommendations of the recently released Iraq Study Group, also known as the Baker-Hamilton report.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Based on this CR process with its closed rule and no committee debate, does this mean that I am going to be foreclosed from offering the resolution?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The chairman of the Appropriations Committee has been quoted saying that most of the negotiations on the CR were conducted by staff. While we have terrific staff on both sides of the aisle, this is not the way this institution is supposed to operate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The resolution before the House includes $31.2 billion for the State, Foreign Operations accounts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is an increase of $1 billion dollars over the Fiscal Year 2006 level.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am in no way criticizing the Gentlelady from New York, but I did not meet with the chairwoman of the subcommittee to discuss the CR. I know she is fair and reaches out across the aisle, and perhaps her hands were tied in this unfair process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To be candid, there are some positive aspects of the State, Foreign Operations chapter. One is the full funding of the president's request for Global HIV/AIDS. This funding will provide life saving drugs to thousands of people infected with HIV/AIDS and will meet President Bush's goal of treating 2 million people, preventing 7 million new infections, and caring for 10 million people by 2009.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, another $50 million is provided for the African Union's Mission in Sudan, and another $113 million for United Nations' international peacekeeping.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But, these funding increases had to result in decreases elsewhere. The president's 2007 Budget request included $3.2 billion for the Economic Support Fund, the continuing resolution cuts $746 million from the request, and is $148 million below the 2006 enacted level. A reduction of this magnitude will affect the Administration's ability to carry out critical foreign policy priorities, including democracy, infrastructure, and economic development programs in Iraq.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The president's 2007 Request included an increase of $709 million for stability and reconstruction programs in Iraq, these programs are essential to improving the safety of our troops in the country. Yet, the majority directed that there be no mention of funding for anything related to Iraq in the resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This process is not the way the House's business should be conducted. I urge members to vote against this measure to make a statement about the way this entire process has been handled.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400300" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRIES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 2 minutes to the gentlewoman from New York (Mrs. Lowey).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400246" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRIES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I just want to say to my good friend, my colleague, Mr. Wolf, I look forward to working closely with you. And as you may know, or I am surprised if you don't know, my staff was working with your staff every single step of the way, and your input and the input of your staff was invaluable. So we can have further discussions. Thank you very much.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And I want to commend Chairman Obey and all the staff on both sides of the aisle, because we worked on the bill together, for their tireless work.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is a shame, frankly, that the Republican leadership of the 109th Congress failed to finish its work on the fiscal year 2007 appropriations bills, leaving vital programs in the lurch.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And while this bill is the result of the Republicans' abdication of duty in the 109th Congress, it is a fair, balanced, and bipartisan attempt to continue essential government programs and services and address critical priorities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Specifically, this joint resolution provides a total of $4.55 billion for global HIV/AIDS and TB, almost $300 million above the President's fiscal year 2007 request, including $724 million for the Global Fund. We have also increased PEPFAR funding by $75 million over the President's request to put hundreds of thousands more people on lifesaving medications.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to keeping the momentum in our HIV/AIDS initiatives, the joint resolution also addresses the ongoing genocide in Darfur, Sudan. Two-and-a-half years after Congress declared the atrocities to be genocide, violence continues unabated. This bill provides $50 million in additional funds for the only peacekeepers on the ground, the African Union forces.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Additionally, this bill meets our commitment for Israel and Egypt as requested for fiscal year 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And, finally, having just returned from Afghanistan, I do believe there is still a glimmer of hope that our assistance can make a positive impact there. I am pleased that the joint resolution provides over $1 billion for reconstruction programs, counternarcotics and other priorities. And I urge my colleagues to join me in supporting this joint resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400239" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRIES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 3 minutes to the ranking member of our Transportation Subcommittee of Appropriations (Mr. Knollenberg).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400225" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRIES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in opposition to <bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill> as it is currently written.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The CR includes authorization language that will change the formula for distributing section 8 housing assistance that will cut funding from 31 States and 1,227 PHAs, permanently.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I make no bones about this. Both in my State of Michigan, in Detroit and in Pontiac, PHAs in the State of Michigan as a whole would be severely impacted by the language in this bill. But I am just one of many Members, 31 States, who are impacted by this legislation, by this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask why are we doing this now? There is no need to make the change now. There is no urgent situation that needs fixing. Under the current system, every PHA would have received an increase that fully covers the cost of running their section 8 program. No one gets cut; no one gets hurt.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This language has one impact. It creates instability and uncertainty by creating a new set of winners and losers every year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And in their very first budget, the new majority would cut $460 million for 1,227 PHAs from what would have been provided if the program had been left alone. A complete list of the PHAs being impacted has been made available for all Members to review.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And this is not a one-time sweep, by the way, of so-called excess funds. The losses being imposed on the PHAs with this language are permanent losses, not just for this year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is not the system that we worked so hard to develop. Where stability and uncertainty has been the order of the day, we are now having disruption and uncertainty.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The principal claim by the supporters of this provision is that there are excess funds in PHAs that can be redistributed to other entities so that more families can be served. But that is not what the people who run the program say. Of the nearly $29 billion in funds that has been provided to the PHAs over the last 2 years, only 2.5 percent is  actually deemed excess. Two-and-a-half percent. That hardly seems like a crisis to me.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>To take away those funds permanently from those areas and the families that could be served is not the solution. Getting the funds spent on families in those areas by those PHAs is the right solution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is clear from the language in the bill that the majority has no real certainty on what this provision is going to do. They have set aside $100 million of the funds for unanticipated outcomes. But there will be no doubt about the outcome, and $100 million is a drop in the bucket.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, according to the Department, the top 10 PHAs, including New York City, L.A. County, L.A. City, Sacramento, Dallas, Cook County, Miami/Dade, and San Diego County, will be cut $132 million alone; and that leaves $328 million, or 70 percent, of the destruction being caused in smaller PHAs throughout the country untouched.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, the majority has argued that the administration is proposing the same change in 2008 and 2009. No one has seen the HUD budget. We have very conflicting information coming through. Regardless of what is wrong, I would urge all Members on both sides of the aisle with those PHAs that will be impacted like mine, 31, I strongly suggest they look at all of these losses; and I strongly oppose this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400239" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRIES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield for the purpose of making a unanimous consent request to the gentlewoman from Illinois (Mrs. Biggert).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Mrs. BIGGERT asked and was given permission to revise and extend her remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400027" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRIES">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I support provisions in this resolution that provide funding for roads and transit, Pell Grants, Special Education, NCLB, veterans' healthcare and scientific research at places like NIH and Argonne National Laboratory.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, I do not support a provision in this bill that will slash housing assistance for hundreds of families and seniors in my district and for thousands more nationwide.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is unfortunate that the leadership and appropriators on the other side of the aisle decided that it was OK to completely rewrite the funding formula for the disbursement of Section 8 housing funds in this bill without consulting with the authorizing committee, Financial Services. The last time I checked, authorizing on an appropriations bill is against the House rules. But of course, the rule for this bill denies us any opportunity to raise a point of order, or amend the bill. At least during  previous Republican-led Congresses, our leadership had the courtesy to allow Democrats to offer amendments and points of order and followed rules that reflect a truly democratic process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, I must point out that the other side of the aisle still has a chance to do this the right way. As the new Ranking Member of the Financial Services Housing Subcommittee, I am perfectly happy to work with the majority to craft a comprehensive, bipartisan Section 8 reform package that will provide stability and predictability for our public housing authorities and those whom they serve.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My constituents are not well served by this abrupt and drastic change in the formula, and I would warn my colleagues from Illinois to look closely at the new numbers for their districts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Chicago suburbs are hit hard by this new formula. Each housing authority in all three counties of my Congressional district will receive a funding cut this year. The housing authority in Cook County will lose $8 million, Joliet will lose $1.1 million, Aurora and DuPage County will lose over a million dollars.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These are not just dollars; these are families and seniors who are being hurt here. With this bill's proposed cuts to Section 8 housing funding, more than 100 families in DuPage County, about 150 in Will County, and thousands across the country will be kicked to the curb in 2007. This is unacceptable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am disappointed by the thoughtlessness of those on the other side of the aisle who determined the new formula and numbers in this bill. I urge my colleagues to alert their constituents who will become homeless this year about this fly-by-night formula change that our dear colleagues have brought to the floor today. I invite the Democratic leadership to explain to the neediest citizens in the suburbs of Chicago and in communities across our Nation why they won't have a roof over their heads  in 2007. This is no way to start the New Year.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400300" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRIES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, may I ask how much time remains on both sides.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from Wisconsin has 12 minutes. The gentleman from California has 16.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400239" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRIES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 2 minutes to the gentleman from New Jersey (Mr. Frelinghuysen).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400142" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRIES">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this joint resolution includes important increases above the fiscal year 2006 level for programs that are truly necessary in our Commerce Justice Appropriations Subcommittee. I appreciate the inclusion of increased funding for FBI counterterrorism and intelligence and for the cost of conducting a timely and accurate focus on our next census.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Also included are important increases for basic scientific research, an additional $335 million for the National Science Foundation research, which will set the groundwork for new technologies that will spark innovation and ensure our competitiveness.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I am very concerned, however, about funding for drug enforcement. Funding is included in this resolution to maintain the current rate of operations for every Department of Justice entity except the Drug Enforcement Agency. The funding for the DEA will result in a loss of over 160 agents and deep cuts to the Mobile Enforcement Team program, the DEA's primary tool to fight meth and violent drug crime at the State and municipal levels.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With violent crime on the rise and many communities dealing with methamphetamine, that crisis, this is the wrong time to retreat on funding for the DEA. For this and many other reasons I rise to oppose this resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400300" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRIES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 2 minutes to the distinguished gentleman from Massachusetts, the chairman of the Financial Services Committee (Mr. Frank).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400140" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRIES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, when I hear some of my Republican colleagues leap to the defense of section 8, I can only compare that to learning that Ahmadinejad had applied for membership in B'nai Brith. We have been trying to defend section 8 against assault for some time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One form of the assault has been formulaic rules that prevent all of the money that is appropriated from being spent. Because there is a lot of support for section 8, the administration has been unhappy when we have voted here more money than they have asked for. So they have had a series of formulaic restrictions that keep us from getting it all spent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I will note, by the way, that the particular change here that the committee has recommended is supported by the National Association of Housing and Redevelopment Officials, the Council of Large Public Housing Authorities, and the Public Housing Authorities Directors Association. That is, all of those who administer section 8 through their organizations endorse it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Here is the way it has worked. There were formulas put in there that kept some agencies from spending money which they received. That is, many agencies were given money that could not be spent and had not been spent that came out of the hide of agencies that needed to spend more. What this bill does is to make sure that every appropriation is spent; and as to those agencies that might be losing an allocation, in every case they are losing money that they had not been able to spend because they  did not have the legal authority to do it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill guarantees, and we will be here to make good on that guarantee, that any agencies that can say, well, we are not getting the same allocation that we got before, they will have reserves available to them on which they can draw. So we can guarantee that no one will be unable to serve everyone they are now serving.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What it does mean is that money which this formula has prevented from being spent in some agencies will now be spent. We will not give some agencies more than they can spend and some less. We will even it out.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And I stress again that the reserves will be available, and that is why every one of the agencies in this country that spends money on section 8, all of the public housing authorities have explicitly supported this particular change.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>AUTHORITIES,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington, DC, January 31, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dear Mr. Chairman: The Council of Large Public Housing Authorities (CLPHA) represents 60 of the nation's largest housing authorities that own and manage 40 percent of the nation's public housing and administer over 30 percent of the Housing Choice Voucher program. We are writing to support the FY 2007 Joint Resolution in the House of Representatives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>CLPHA greatly appreciates the inclusion of an additional $300 million for Public Housing Operating Fund in the legislation and the $487 million increase in the Housing Choice Voucher account. The increase in operating funds is a good start in addressing the chronic under-funding of public housing programs. Public housing is still significantly under-funded and we look forward to working with Congress to provide full funding for public housing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>CLPHA commends the House for unraveling the complicated and inefficient funding system HUD has imposed on housing authorities since 2004. By adopting a formula. that bases funding on the most recent 12 months of leasing and cost data the House action will guarantee funding for all vouchers in use. The increase in funds, combined with the change in how these funds are distributed ensure that housing authorities do not have to reduce the number of families they currently serve.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, in order to effectively transition to this new formula, housing authorities need access to currently allocated funds to help them to offset losses and to increase leasing levels in their communities. Congress must protect these funds and prohibit HUD from recapturing them for either punitive reasons or to meet a rescission target.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thank you again for supporting public and assisted housing programs. We look forward to working with you on these most important issues.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sunia Zaterman,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DIRECTORS ASSOCIATION,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington, DC, January 31, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR MR. CHAIRMAN: PHADA represents the professional administrators of almost 1,900 local housing authorities from all over the United States. I am writing in regard to the FY 2007 Joint Resolution the House of Representatives will soon consider.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>PHADA supports and appreciates the inclusion of $300 million more in operating funds included in the legislation. The summary accompanying the resolution notes that this increase still leaves HAs with a significant shortfall in FY 2007. Still, the measure is a welcome step in the right direction. PHADA wants to work with you and your Senate colleagues on future efforts to bring public housing funding up to more adequate levels.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>PHADA also supports the Housing Choice Voice (HCV) funding and formula in the legislation. The association has long supported a more rational voucher formula based on actual leasing and voucher costs. Your bill establishes the inception of such a policy. Recent experience demonstrates that the Bush Administration's "snapshot" voucher formula has not been successful. Inefficiencies in that formula have over-funded some housing agencies and underfunded others. Moving to a formula based on actual  voucher lease up and costs distributes funding to agencies as it is actually being used and thus guarantees funding for all vouchers in use. Importantly, the bill also includes $100 million to protect housing agencies and residents that might otherwise be harmed during the transition to the new formula.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thank you again for your support of public and assisted housing programs. PHADA looks forward to working with you on the implementation of this legislation and during the FY 2008 budget process that begins next week.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Timothy G. Kaiser,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>AND REDEVELOPMENT OFFICIALS,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington DC, January 31, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR CHAIRMEN AND RANKING MEMBERS: I am writing to express the strong support of the National Association of Housing and Redevelopment Officials (NAHRO) for the Section 8 Tenant-Based Rental Assistance voucher- renewal formula included in <bill type="hj" number="20">H. J. Res. 20</bill>. Formed in 1933, with more than 22,000 agency and individual members, NAHRO is the nation's oldest and largest nonprofit organization composed of local agencies and officials engaged in creating and maintaining affordable housing opportunities.  NAHRO members are responsible for administering more than 80 percent of all Section 8 Housing Choice vouchers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This revision to the voucher distributional formula is a long-overdue correction of a policy that has simply proven not to work. Prior to the adoption of the current law policy in 2004, the voucher program was highly successful in serving families it was charged to assist. The funding policies in place provided the incentives and stability necessary for agencies to efficiently administer the program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since the current law formula was instituted in 2004, this highly-successful program has lost well over 100,000 vouchers, and by some estimates are as many as 150,000 vouchers, due to inefficiencies in the formula. In contrast, <bill type="hj" number="20">H. J. Res. 20</bill> will provide all agencies sufficient funding to continue assisting the same number of families served in FY 2006, and some may be able to make some progress toward restoring lost vouchers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Newspapers across the country have chronicled the numbers of families whose assistance was abruptly terminated or denied, dismissed from waiting lists, or for whom rent burdens have increased since 2004. The loss of assistance for these tens of thousands of families has not been due to a shortage of funding provided by Congress. In fact, Congress appropriated sufficient funding each year to support these families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These dramatic losses are, in fact, due to the inefficiency of tbe formula in place since 2004. The current formula bases funding to each agency upon an outdated and unrepresentative "snapshot" of data from three months in 2004. As a result, it has distributed more money to some agencies than necessary to serve 100 percent of their authorized families, while at the same time, deeply cutting other agencies, forcing them to reduce the number of families served. The depth of the inefficiency has  grown with time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The revised formula contained in H J Res. 20, as written, will ensure that all public housing agencies will receive at least the amount necessary to serve the number of families served in their voucher programs in 2006, plus inflation. These agencies will not lose funding needed to maintain their programs at the levels existing in 2006, and some may be able to make progress in restoring lost vouchers. In addition, agencies have access to a $100 million adjustment pool for any agency tbat has  increased need due to unforeseen circumstances or any hardship caused by the transition to the new formula.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The net result is a more accurate formula than the one in use from 2004 through 2006. This formula will utilize tbe funding provided more efficiently than the previous formula, assisting a larger number of families with the appropriated amounts than would occur under the previous formula.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Detractors opposing formula revision have unfortunately relied on data that provides a misleading picture of the impact of the revised formula. This is because the data focus solely on the amounts distributed to each community rather than on the efficiency with which those dollars will be used to serve eligible families. Because the current formula is based on outdated "snapshot" information, much of the funding cited as a "net loss" under the H J Res. 20 formula is actually in excess of  the amounts needed to serve 100 percent of those agencies' authorized families in 2007. These are funds that would be distributed but could not be used by agencies to serve families if the present formula were retained. Therefore, the data do not provide an accurate picture of the families served by those dollars, the most important measure of success for this program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The agency-by-agcncy listing in the data does not show the half of all agencies who receive less funding under the current formula than under H J Res. 20. For these agencies, the consequences of loss of dollars under the current formula will have a real and severe impact on the number of families they can serve. The H J Res. 20 formula is based on the amount necessary to continue serving the number of families presently assisted, Failing to enact it would mean that these agencies will not receive  the funds necessary to serve families in place last year and perhaps make some progress in restoring lost vouchers,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We do not dispute that there is much unmet need for housing assistance across the country. However, providing some agencies with funding above 100 percent of their authorized vouchers while others continue to lose assistance for families in place last year is not a sound national policy. Instead, it is an inefficient use of taxpayers' dollars that needlessly leaves thousands of families unassisted.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In sum, we congratulate you on your willingness to correct in this voucher funding policy. Repairing the damage done to this program over the past three years will take time. The funding policy provided by H J Res. 20 is a good step in that direction. With continued funding support from Congress for both vouchers and the administrative funds necessary to help families find housing, and  efficient funding policies, we can set this critical program back  on its former path of success and restore the number of vouchers lost in recent years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Please feel free to contact me if you have any questions about this information</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Saul N. Ramirez, Jr.,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>POLICY PRIORITIES,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington, DC, January 30, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR CONGRESSMAN OBEY: I am writing to state our strong support for the provisions relating to "Section 8" Housing Choice Vouchers in <bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill>, the Joint Funding Resolution for Fiscal Year 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Section 8 vouchers are the leading source of federal housing assistance, and provide access to affordable housing for approximately two million low-income households, including working families with children, the elderly, and people with disabilities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill> fully funds the President's request for voucher renewals, by providing the $487 million above the FY 2006 level that the President has said is needed to maintain the program. In a bill where resources were very constrained, this is a notable achievement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Even more important, however, the bill makes a badly needed change in the formula used to allocate funding among the 2400 state and local housing agencies that administer the voucher program. For the past three years, voucher funding has been distributed under a highly flawed and inefficient formula. This formula relies on outdated data about housing trends, and has been providing many agencies with more funds than they can use, while others have had to make significant cuts. In all, a staggering  150,000 vouchers have been lost since 2004.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill> would ensure that the funding for each voucher in use in 2006 is renewed, by basing agencies' funding on their actual leasing rates and costs in the prior year. This simple but critical reform would stem the tide of voucher cuts, and restore badly needed stability to the program, at no additional cost to the federal government. By contrast, had the formula not been altered, thousands of vouchers in use in 2006 would have been in jeopardy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I commend you and Members of the Committee for including this provision in the bill, and would urge others to support your efforts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Robert Greenstein,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>HOUSING COALITION,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington, DC, January 31, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR REPRESENTATIVE: The National Low Income Housing Coalition urges you to support <bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill>, the joint funding resolution that will fund the federal government for the remainder of FY07. The bill provides necessary program increases and policy changes to critical low income housing programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In particular, I want to call to your attention the provisions that will make important improvements to the Department of Housing and Urban Development's housing choice voucher program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 2004, HUD and Congress changed the formula for distribution of housing choice voucher funds to the 2600 public housing agencies that manage the program. This was done as a cost-cutting measure. Unfortunately, this change resulted in a system that has proved to be inefficient and wasteful, while at the same time reducing the number of vouchers available to many communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under this new distribution formula, many public housing authorities were forced to reduce the number of families that were served by vouchers. As a result, there has been a loss of 150,000 vouchers since 2004, which could have assisted the large number of families on waiting lists for affordable housing across the country. At the same time, some public housing agencies received funding allocations that were higher than their funding needs and these funds went unused,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress has the opportunity to remedy this problem by adopting the new formula included in <bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill>. In 2006, this formula was included in legislation (<bill type="h" number="5443">H.R. 5443</bill>) approved by the House Financial Service Committee and in the Senate FY07 Transportation, Treasury, the Judiciary and Housing and Urban Development appropriations bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The change allocates funding in FY07 based on each housing agency's most recent twelve month period of voucher leasing and cost data, rather than a three-month snapshot in 2004 that is current measure. The National Low Income Housing Coalition strongly supports this formula change.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We also thank the appropriators for including the President's FY07 request for voucher funding in the joint funding resolution. If both the formula change and the funding increase are enacted, no public housing authority will have to make cuts to their voucher programs in 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thank you for considering our views.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>SHEILA CROWLEY, MSW, PhD.,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>ASSOCIATION,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington, DC, January 31, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR REPRESENTATIVE OLVER: The members of the National Leased Housing Association have reviewed Joint Resolution 20 with regard to funding for the Department of Housing and Urban Development and are writing to share our perspectives on the Section 8 programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, we commend both the House and Senate for their efforts to provide adequate funding for the "Section 8 Housing Choice Voucher" program and for the renewals of Section 8 project-based contracts. These programs are critical to the provision of affordable housing to 3.5 million households. We are also pleased that the Joint Resolution addressed the expiration of HUD's restructuring authority under the Mark to Market program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Further, we applaud you for addressing how vouchers are allocated to local communities. We believe that the approach taken in the Joint Resolution, which bases agencies' budgets on their leasing costs from the most recent 12 months, is sound and will lead to the most efficient and stable results for recipients, administrators, owners and other stakeholders. In the last three years, we have learned through experience that basing voucher funding on outdated information from a potentially unrepresentative  three-month period, leaves many housing agencies without the resources needed to meet current commitments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, the rigid funding formula of the past few years have left current voucher holders vulnerable; minimized the ability of PHAs to utilize the vouchers authorized by Congress; exacerbated concerns that it is not prudent to lend or invest private capital in affordable housing; reduced housing choice for voucher holders; and inhibited new construction and rehabilitation of additional low income units.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By allocating funding based on the realities of the local marketplace, the Joint Resolution formula will avoid these problems, and ensure that scarce federal resources are directed where they are most needed to support current commitments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Denise B. Muha,</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400239" topic="NATIONAL LEASED HOUSING">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 2 minutes to the gentlewoman from Texas (Ms. Granger).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400157" topic="NATIONAL LEASED HOUSING">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this bill before us eliminates $3.1 billion that would support the plan, approved by this Congress, to reposition our military forces throughout the world, a plan that is integral to our strategy to win the war on terror.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The cut in funding of over $3 billion has been termed devastating by Army officials. It eliminates the support for our military and their families, may I remind us, in a time of war.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me give you a specific example. Fourteen thousand troops and their families, including 4,000 children, are scheduled to reposition from Germany back to the States. Cutting funding for support for this plan leaves our senior military leaders with the Hobson's choice of either moving just a few units or moving our servicemembers and their families on the bases with inadequate infrastructure and training facilities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It prevents soldiers from having the type of training facilities they need to prepare for war. It will create an uncertainty about whether their children are able to attend adequate schools. It puts in jeopardy medical treatment facilities that our military members and their families deserve access to and can force our troops into temporary housing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, we are at war. Are we willing to cut support for those who fight this war? I say no, and I will vote "no." This bill shortchanges our troops and their families and inhibits our ability to train and prepare our troops and our Nation for future attacks.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400300" topic="NATIONAL LEASED HOUSING">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself 15 seconds.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, it is not correct that we are cutting BRAC. We are increasing BRAC $1 billion above the existing levels in the continuing resolution under which we are operating today. We will deal with the additional requests for BRAC in the supplemental, and you can bet that they will get all of their money. But we are adding $1 billion to BRAC. We are not cutting.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400239" topic="NATIONAL LEASED HOUSING">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 3 minutes to the gentleman from Ohio (Mr. Hobson).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400180" topic="NATIONAL LEASED HOUSING">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, we would not be in this unfortunate situation if our colleagues in the Senate had actually passed their bill. The House fulfilled its appropriation responsibilities; the other body did not.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have no problem with my majority colleague on the subcommittee, the distinguished chairman from Indiana. He has involved the minority in the process, treated us fairly, and attempted to protect our interests.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, the ground rules established to this resolution disadvantage the House greatly in the negotiations with the Senate. The process adopted by the majority has undermined the ability of the subcommittee to negotiate a good CR and strip out Senate pork. There are a number of significant funding reductions that should have been taken in the CR that were not.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, I have no fault with my chairman. He tried. But the Senate balked at even citing the need to protect "important" Senators.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me offer a few examples. The fiscal year 2004 omnibus appropriation included a $50 million earmark in the DOE's science account for an indoor rain forest alongside the interstate highway in Iowa, which I opposed, and so did my ranking member at the time, now the chairman.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Department of Energy has been unable to execute this earmark because the sponsor has not produced the necessary non-Federal matching funds. Nearly $45 million remains unspent and unspendable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The House proposed to rescind this earmark, but the Senate refused to consider it. If ever there were a piece of low-hanging fruit ripe to be stripped out of the resolution, this is it. The 109th Congress had its infamous Bridge to Nowhere. The 110th Congress is now building its own legacy, starting with a $50 million "roadside attraction" in Iowa.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the NNSA weapons account, the House identified several sources of significant savings. The House proposed a total of $495 million of reductions from weapons activities, but the Senate again refused to accept this reduction because of perceived impact in New Mexico. The final CR contains only $94.5 million of reduction, leaving $400 million of savings untapped.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the fossil fuel account, 2006 funding in Energy included $49.7 million for oil and gas research, which is funded at discretionary spending in fiscal year 2006, but which is now mandatory by the Energy Policy Act of 2005.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The House proposed again, rightly, to eliminate this discretionary funding in the CR, which only duplicates the new mandatory funding. Instead, the Senate declared this account to be "untouchable" in the strong interest of a particular Senator in West Virginia.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Given the House majority passed <bill type="h" number="6">H.R. 6</bill> to take away perceived windfall profits in the oil and gas industry, it is surprising that it would now allow the same industry to "double dip" in the CR.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In summary, I would say again that the process being followed with this CR greatly disadvantages the House in our negotiations with the other body. Members should not delude themselves that we have stripped all of the pork from the CR. We have only succeeded in stripping out the House earmarks. Over in the other Chamber, it is, frankly, business as usual.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have had the opportunity to realize a half billion dollars of savings in energy and water portions of the CR and to apply those funds to other priority needs such as education, health care and law enforcement. I hope you all realize that in voting for this continuing resolution today means that you have decided that several hundred million of tax dollars will be better spent on welfare for the nuclear weapons labs than on these other pressing national needs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I encourage Members on both sides of the aisle to vote against this resolution and get rid of the pork.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400300" topic="NATIONAL LEASED HOUSING">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself 15 seconds.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, if ever there was a case of the pot calling the kettle black, we have just heard it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The gentleman is objecting because we were not able to go back 2 years to excise from a previous appropriation the rain forest project which was put into your bill when you were chairman. We have eliminated all earmarks for today and tomorrow. We cannot be expected to correct all of your mistakes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> There remain 9 minutes, 50 seconds for the gentleman from California and 9 minutes and 30 seconds for the gentleman from Wisconsin.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400239" topic="NATIONAL LEASED HOUSING">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 2 minutes to the gentleman from Georgia (Mr. Kingston).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400221" topic="NATIONAL LEASED HOUSING">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I thank the ranking member, Mr. Lewis, for the opportunity to speak on this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I oppose the bill; and the reason why, Mr. Speaker, is I think it is very important for our constituents to understand.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Yes, there was a mandate in November as there had been a growing mandate throughout the year to get rid of earmarks. Now when my constituents supported the President's call to get rid of $18 billion worth of earmarks, what they thought he meant was reducing spending $18 billion. They do not want earmarks eliminated for the sake of taking them out of the hands of elected people and putting them in the hands of non-elected bureaucrats, yet that is what this omnibus bill does.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now in the ag section, the total spending has gone from 100 to $150 billion down. That sounds like a good savings, some of it. You can argue, where did the savings come from?</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>One thing that was eliminated, $70 million in environmental quality incentive program, $44 million for conservation security programs. These are programs that help farmers, and they have a cost share. It helps farmers plan on environmental repairs, keeping nutrients out of flowing into streams, safe environmental practices on dairies like building lagoons, things like that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also eliminated $74 million in watershed and flood prevention, building small dams, and it eliminates $2 million from the USDA biomass program. Now at a time when we all want energy independence, eliminating the biomass program in the USDA doesn't make sense to me.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Also it eliminates $11 million in food stamp funding for the employment and training portion of food stamps. All important things.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But where does the money go? For one thing, it goes to the FDA bureaucrats. The FDA wanted about a $20 million increase. They get, under this bill, a $100 million increase, without a single committee hearing on it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, though, it is not just that the FDA is getting money. It is that the taxpayers aren't getting money. Earmarks have been eliminated, but the money does not go back to the taxpayers. It simply goes to the bureaucracy. And that is why I think we should recommit this bill because we can do a better job.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400300" topic="NATIONAL LEASED HOUSING">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 2 minutes to the gentleman from Indiana (Mr. Visclosky), the chairman of the Energy and Water Subcommittee.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Mr. VISCLOSKY asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400417" topic="NATIONAL LEASED HOUSING">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would, first of all, like to thank Chairman Obey. Under his leadership, the Appropriations Committee, and this Congress, has moved quickly to bring resolution to the fiscal work left undone in the last Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would also like to thank my partner, DAVE HOBSON, who just spoke a moment ago, and all of the members of the Energy and Water Subcommittee for their dedication and cooperation. And while I am at it, I would associate myself with the remarks of Mr. Hobson relative to the negotiations with the other body.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am disappointed that we are here today finishing a CR from last year. I would have liked my first role as the chairman of the Energy and Water Subcommittee to be focused on next year's responsibilities, instead of cleaning up the fiscal mess that was left to us.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, most importantly, this bill provides $300 million to improve the Department of Energy's ability to proceed with vital renewable energy and conservation research and development. This will allow the Department of Energy to pursue more technologies that would hold promise for reducing the emission of greenhouse gases and the importation of foreign oil while supporting the growth of our economy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Given the energy crisis facing our Nation, and the implications it poses for our economy, our environment, and national security, these investments in energy research simply could not wait any longer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This measure also provides $200 million to bolster physical science research. This increase is a first step in a long overdue improvement in government support for research into physical sciences.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Looking ahead, I hope to work with my partner, Mr. Hobson, as well as again, all of the members of the subcommittee. And I would indicate to my colleagues that I remain very concerned about the size of our weapons complex and the lack of progress being made to rationalize it in conformity to existing treaty agreements and current international circumstances.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Given this, and several other major initiatives being proposed by the Department of Energy, coupled with its fundamental failure to bring major projects in on time, let alone under budget, I will ask for the subcommittee to carefully and judiciously examine all major initiatives being undertaken so that we may fulfill our responsibility as good stewards of the people's money.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400239" topic="NATIONAL LEASED HOUSING">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 2 minutes to Mr. Wamp, the Appropriations Committee ranking member of the legislative branch.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400421" topic="NATIONAL LEASED HOUSING">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the first 100 hours is over. That was the easy part; softballs, for the most part, that you campaigned on and that many of us joined you on. But this is where the tough work of governing begins, really, and I don't want to join in the blame game because there is plenty to go around from last year and the Senate Republicans and this year in this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But as a 10-year member of the Appropriations Committee, I would ask the distinguished chairman of the Appropriations Committee to bring this legislation to the committee. Don't bring it straight to the floor. $463 billion worth of spending, and it is not a CR. It is not a clean CR. A lot of bells and whistles here.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a matter of fact, the distinguished chairman is known for carrying pencils in his coat pocket, and I wonder how many of those pencils he burned up putting this together. It was a lot of work. I commend you for this work. But it is a huge shift in priorities and it didn't come to the committee. So that is what I would ask is you go through the regular order and let's not do this again.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And then let me ask you specifically about the legislative branch portion of this bill. Page 137, because our chief administrative officer, I understand, will have money in this CR to stand up a committee which is controversial, even on your own side, this proposed Select Committee for Climate Change. And I would yield the balance of my time to you, Mr. Chairman, to ask, is there money in the legislative branch portion of this bill to fund what is not an authorized committee yet, but the proposed  committee, Select Committee for Climate Change?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield to the chairman.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400300" topic="NATIONAL LEASED HOUSING">
    <paragraph>The answer is that there is money, there is adequate money to provide for that committee, if, in fact, it is created. But the formal action on creation has not yet taken place.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400421" topic="NATIONAL LEASED HOUSING">
    <paragraph>And reclaiming my time, the Katrina Select Committee on our side was roughly a $400,000 committee. My understanding, the authority under this bill for the Select Committee on Climate Change would be about three times that amount, $1.2 million. I think we need to go through the regular order there as well.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400300" topic="NATIONAL LEASED HOUSING">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 1 minute to the gentleman from New York (Mr. Weiner) for a colloquy.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400426" topic="NATIONAL LEASED HOUSING">
    <paragraph>As you know, Mr. Chairman, the President and the Republican Congress drastically cut funding for the highly successful COPS program. In 1999 Congress appropriated $1.2 billion for the COPS program, and funding has plummeted since. The President has zeroed out this program every year since taking office and Congress gave no funding for COPS in either fiscal year 2006, or in the House-passed SSJC bill for fiscal year 2007. While the Office of Justice Programs, Community Oriented Policing  Services account referenced in section 20901 of the continuing resolution today includes other worthy programs, is it your preference that the additional funding be used for enhancement grants which can be used to hire additional police?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400300" topic="NATIONAL LEASED HOUSING">
    <paragraph>My preference is that additional funding would be available for enhancement grants which can be used for hiring. But that final decision will be up to the administration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400239" topic="NATIONAL LEASED HOUSING">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, could I inquire as to how much time is remaining on each side?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from California (Mr. Lewis) has 5 minutes, 50 seconds. The gentleman from Wisconsin (Mr. Obey) has 6 1/2  minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400239" topic="NATIONAL LEASED HOUSING">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 2 minutes to the gentlelady from Virginia (Mrs. Drake).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400658" topic="NATIONAL LEASED HOUSING">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I keep hearing from the other side of the aisle that they support our troops. Yet, this CR removes $3 billion from our troops and their families. I offered an amendment to fix this and they refused.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400300" topic="NATIONAL LEASED HOUSING">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself 10 seconds.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I, once again, repeat, this bill does not cut BRAC. It adds $1 billion to BRAC. The fiscal 2006 level was $1.5 billion. This bill will have $2.5 billion, and we will be adding more in the emergency supplemental.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400658" topic="NATIONAL LEASED HOUSING">
    <paragraph>Would the gentleman yield for a question?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400300" topic="NATIONAL LEASED HOUSING">
    <paragraph>With whatever time I have remaining of the 15 seconds.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400658" topic="NATIONAL LEASED HOUSING">
    <paragraph>Well, the article that I am reading, not just information that I have, is a continuing resolution released Monday night axes more than half of the money the Pentagon needs to meet its base realignment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400300" topic="NATIONAL LEASED HOUSING">
    <paragraph>With all due respect, I don't live in the world of newspaper articles. We produced this bill. I know what is in it. I would hope the gentlewoman would also learn what is in it.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400239" topic="NATIONAL LEASED HOUSING">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400300" topic="NATIONAL LEASED HOUSING">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 1 minute to the distinguished majority leader, Mr. Hoyer.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400189" topic="NATIONAL LEASED HOUSING">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I want to congratulate Mr. Obey, who was the ranking member in the last Congress, and who worked with Mr. Lewis to try to pass our appropriation bills and, in fact, we passed all but one of the appropriation bills. Unfortunately, we reported the Labor Health bill, which is the largest bill, other than the Defense bill, in June, and it failed to ever get to the floor of this House because it included minimum wage, and that was not favored by the majority.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now that we are in the majority, we are left with unfinished business. The gentlelady from Virginia mentions cutting something. We haven't cut anything. As a matter of fact, we have added $1 billion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If you had passed your appropriation bills, you may have been able to fund at appropriate levels. But you did not pass your appropriation bills. Yet, we hear on the floor today constant complaining from the other side of the aisle that they don't like the way we fixed their failures.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Well, very frankly, I think the American public will. First of all, the American public will be pleased that we are acting, that we are moving on this legislation, which is, essentially, the funding of 9 appropriation bills that failed to move through the House of Representatives and the Senate and to the President as they should have.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Obey has worked very hard with Senator Byrd. I know Mr. Lewis' staff has been very engaged in this as well. I know the Senate staff has been engaged in it. And I am hopeful that this bill will not only pass this House with a very handy vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are many people in this House, on the Republican side of the aisle who asked to achieve exactly what Mr. Obey has achieved in this bill. He has taken care of the veterans. He has taken care of veterans health. He has taken care of, for the first time in 4 years, trying to get college students Pell Grants that will give them some additional help to fund their college costs. When we had that vote on the floor of this House, we had 124 Republicans join us in that vote. This is one  additional step in trying to get college students a more affordable education.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Obey has moved in a number of areas to make our investments more productive and a better return for the American people. And this bill will provide for getting last year's business done that was left undone, so that we can move on to have what Mr. Wamp wants, and I want, and Mr. Obey wants and Mr. Lewis wants. That is, full and open discussion of the bills in subcommittee, in the full committee and on this floor. I think that is what we will have.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But ladies and gentlemen of this House, we need to complete last year's undone business. It wasn't our fault that it was not done. But whoever's  fault it was, it is not useful to say that it is your fault or my fault or somebody else's fault. It is useful to say we need to move forward. We need to fund government services. We need to fund the priorities of the American people. That is what this continuing resolution does.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I congratulate Mr. Obey, and I urge all of our colleagues to support this bill so we can finally, one-third of the way into the fiscal year, finally do what we should have done by September 30 of 2006.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400239" topic="NATIONAL LEASED HOUSING">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, somewhat responding to the majority leader's comment, I can't help but be moved to say that he suggested directly that Mr. Obey had spent a good deal of time with the gentleman from the Senate, Mr. Byrd, the two Members involved in this bill, and beyond that, a good deal of contact with our staff. Beyond those two Members, let me say that this has been a very fine product. It is a staff, nonelected staffperson's piece of work that involves</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I must say that it is important for me that the body know that I am committed to reducing the rate of growth of spending. $463.5 billion is a pretty significant rate of growth.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>But in the meantime, as we go about reducing spending growth, I will also work in a bipartisan spirit to move our bill through the committee and on time and under budget.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I will not, however, respond to either intimidation or any threats relative to the way we are handling the appropriations process. The Appropriations Committee will not become a small colony in the empire of this new leadership.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We renew our commitment to bills produced by regular order that will serve as a credit to our committee, to the national interest, as well as to the people from our districts we pretend to serve.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With that, the leader and I will work further together on this matter, but I am very concerned about the volume of staff direction here where in the final analysis the people know that they are not elected representatives of the House.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400300" topic="NATIONAL LEASED HOUSING">
    <paragraph>I yield the gentleman (Mr. Hoyer) another minute.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400189" topic="NATIONAL LEASED HOUSING">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for his comments, but I want to say, first of all, when he talks about $463 billion, I read in the newspaper today where OMB was very pleased that we stayed within the caps imposed by the Republican-passed budget. We took the Republican-passed budget, we took those numbers, we stayed within those caps. That is exactly what you did, Mr. Lewis, when you were chairman of the committee because that was the direction from the Budget Committee. I am understanding  that the White House even said that they were pleased with the fact that we stayed within the numbers when you talk about spending.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Secondly, let me say that you and I both served on the Appropriations Committee for a long period of time. In recent years, of course, we have not passed all the appropriation bills in the calendar year, much less the fiscal year, and we would pass omnibus appropriation bills with hundreds and hundreds of billions of dollars larger than this bill. One was passed January 31, the other was passed February 5. They were passed as conference reports with 1 hour of debate and no amendments, in which  substantial legislative language had been added in conference and not vetted on this floor or in committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I understand the gentleman's representations, but he and I have been here a long time and we have a long history of knowing what has transpired in the past. This is a process that was required by the failure of the last Congress to do its work. It has been done in a way that tries to get it done so that we can get on to do exactly what the gentleman wants for the 2008 bills, give them a full airing, full hearings. And I predict to my distinguished and very close friend, Mr. Lewis, we  are going to have a lot more hearings as we did when we were in charge, we had more hearings than we have had.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are going to have oversight, and we are going to have careful scrutiny of the taxpayers' dollars. And I look forward to joining my friend in that process in the regular order. We are doing this so that we can get on to that process to do exactly what the gentleman suggests because it is the right thing to do. And I look forward to working with him on that process.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400239" topic="NATIONAL LEASED HOUSING">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400300" topic="NATIONAL LEASED HOUSING">
    <paragraph>How much time do I have remaining?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from Wisconsin has 4 minutes and 5 seconds.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400300" topic="NATIONAL LEASED HOUSING">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I won't take the full 4 minutes. Let me simply say that it is necessary for the House to move forward with this legislation. It is easy to nitpick. It is interesting to me that the minority today has chosen to chastise us for decisions that we made not to go back 2 years and repeal some of the mistakes that the minority made when they were in the majority. They argue that we should have done that; they argue that we should have lived with a simple continuing resolution  at '06 levels. If we do that, that would mean we would not have the added funding for veterans health care, we would not have the added funding for BRAC, we would not have the added funding for the National Institutes of Health; we would not be able to raise the Pell grant by $260 for the maximum grant; we would not have the extra funding for energy research.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would ask Members to recognize that after a full year of the Republican minority not being able to produce and finish their work, it is time for us to finish their work so we can move on. The President is producing his new budget on February 5, which is next Monday. We need to clear the decks so we can deal with that afresh.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask for an "aye" vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400113" topic="NATIONAL LEASED HOUSING">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today to express great concern over the decreased funding for the Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA) in the Continuing Resolution for Fiscal Year 2007. Specifically, I am concerned about the drastic cuts to the Mobile Enforcement Teams (MET) and the Regional Enforcement Teams (RET). The MET and RET teams are on the front line each and every day assisting state and local law enforcement agencies to combat the onslaught of drug trafficking. The MET program  will be reduced by $30 million and the RET Program will be reduced by $9 million. The priorities in this bill do not represent the priorities of this Nation. How is it that $50 million can be set aside for a rainforest in Iowa in a so-called earmark-free continuing resolution, yet the DEA faces a massive reduction?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The district I represent, California's Fourth Congressional District, will feel the effects of these cuts. In particular, Nevada County faces a tremendous battle with methamphetamines every day. Methamphetamines are becoming an epidemic in this country. This reduction in funding will not only hurt the efforts of law enforcement, but also everyone who lives in a neighborhood being overrun with drugs and drug traffickers. This is the wrong time to be cutting the federal government's primary tool  to combat methamphetamine on a local level.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400227" topic="NATIONAL LEASED HOUSING">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, today Congress is considering a long-term continuing appropriations bill to fund large portions of the Federal Government through the end of fiscal year 2007. This legislation is necessary because Congress did not complete the appropriations process last year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are many reasons to support this bill. For example, the bill increases Pell Grant funding to make college more affordable, IDEA funding by $200 million to help our neediest students, and Head Start funding by $100 million to give our youngest kids the opportunity to learn. Funding for housing opportunities is increased by $1.4 billion. Without the increase HUD would be forced to deny approximately 220,000 voucher renewals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also boosts funding for local law enforcement by increasing funding for both the COPS program and the Byrne Justice Assistance Grants which directly impact funding for local law enforcement efforts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>NASA aeronautics funding, vital to the Cleveland economy, was increased by $166 million over the president's budget request. Furthermore, the bill contained an extension of the layoff ban, and prevents the NASA Administrator from gutting NASA Glenn.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also support the $3.6 billion increase in veterans healthcare funding that provides service for an anticipated increase of at least 325,000 patients and to meet rising healthcare costs. In the same vein, Defense Health Programs are increased by $1.2 billion to provide care for service members and their families--including treating service members wounded in action in Iraq and Afghanistan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our Nation is facing a crisis in healthcare. The bill provides necessary relief for the Community Health Center to finance over 300 new  or expanded health centers, serving an estimated 1.2 million new patients. The bill boosts funding for the Ryan White CARE Grants, the National Institutes of Health and the Indian Health Service.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill adds $1.3 billion to expand efforts to combat HIV/AIDS and TB. At the same time, $248 million was added to the Agency for International Development Malaria Programs to expand its bilateral global malaria initiative activities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill adds considerable funding for the protection of the environment by adding $197.1 million for the Clean Water State Revolving Fund. The revolving fund is distributed by formula and will fund additional water and wastewater infrastructure projects in every state, including Ohio.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill adds $100 million to cover operational shortfalls for parks, refuges, forests and other public lands; including facilities in northeastern Ohio.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill adds $1.5 billion for the Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy Resources program to accelerate research and development activities for renewable energy and energy efficiency programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, the bill forces greater transparency in the activities of the World Bank, requiring them to report public disclosure of loan agreements between World Bank and its borrowers. This sunshine rule will help ensure the World Bank loans are not destructive to third world nations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, this bill includes over $6 billion in nuclear weapons funding that I oppose. I have voted against the Energy and Water Appropriations bill, which contains funding for nuclear weapons, since 2002. I cannot bring myself to vote for any legislation that further endangers the world. I regret not being able to vote for all the positive aspects of this bill, but my conscience and my concerns about the threat which nuclear weapons pose to the world matter more.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Furthermore, I am concerned about the potential loss of jobs in Cleveland relating to the BRAC process. I appreciate that the bill contains additional funds for the BRAC process. I urge the Committee on Appropriations to fully fund the BRAC process as soon as possible to ensure the additional DFAS jobs can be transferred to Cleveland as previously scheduled.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400074" topic="NATIONAL LEASED HOUSING">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in strong support of <bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill>, providing further continuing appropriations for fiscal year 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I commend the Appropriations Committee for working in a bipartisan manner to construct a resolution that continues to fund the government for the remainder of the fiscal year. As Chairman of the Oversight Subcommittee on Information Policy, Census, and National Archives, I am especially pleased to note that <bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill> restores funding that is absolutely vital to conducting an accurate and cost-efficient 2010 census.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The funding in this bill will enable the Census Bureau to move forward with plans for the first-ever automated census in 2010. In addition to saving time and money, utilizing hand-held computers will improve accuracy and ensure the most precise enumeration possible of the American people. According to Preston Jay Waite, Associate Director for the Decennial Census, field trials have resulted in a 91 percent accuracy rate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As preparations for the 2010 Census proceed, active oversight will be important to ensure that all Americans are counted fairly. In 2000, the national census missed at least three million people--mostly the poor and minorities. I look forward to working with Ranking Member MICHAEL TURNER of Ohio and my other Subcommittee colleagues to conduct essential oversight needed to see that this never happens again.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the action we have taken today will guarantee that we don't retreat from the goal of using technology to improve the way we keep track of changes in our population. I thank my colleagues for passing this continuing resolution and will support efforts in the Senate to pass this legislation with the same commitment to adequately funding the 2010 Census.,</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400199" topic="NATIONAL LEASED HOUSING">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill>, which among other things avert the impeding budgetary train wreck left by the Republican-controlled 109th Congress. I want to pay particular tribute to Mr. OBEY, the Chairman of the Appropriations Committee for his incredible work in fashioning this legislation that will enable us to put behind us the mess left by last Congress and get on to the important business of addressing the real and pressing needs of the  American people.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, last November millions of Americans went to the polls to register the strong disgust with the Republican dominated control of the legislative and executive branches of our Federal Government. Americans were fed up with a Republican Congress and its legacy of a culture of corruption, its failure to address the pressing needs of the American people, its unwillingness to provide effective oversight of the executive branch, its fiscal irresponsibility that resulted in record budget deficits  and added trillions to the national debt, and its ability to complete one of the most basic tasks of the legislative branch: to pass the appropriations bills needed to fund the government. Is it any wonder that Americans were voting for a new way of doing the people's business when they elected the Democratic majorities in the House and Senate? I think not. We Democrats promised a new and better direction for America. And we have been delivering.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, behold what we accomplished in less than the first 100 legislative hours of our majority. We passed <bill type="h" number="1">H.R. 1</bill>, which implements the recommendations of the 911 Commission; we passed <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill>, raising the minimum wage by $2.10 an hour over three years and providing a much needed raise to nearly 5 million workers; we passed <bill type="h" number="3">H.R. 3</bill>, which will provide funding for embryonic stem cell research and provide hope for millions of Americans suffering from some of the most debilitating illnesses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But we did not stop there. We passed <bill type="h" number="4">H.R. 4</bill>, which requires Medicaid to negotiate lower prescription drug prices for our seniors and disabled citizens; we passed <bill type="h" number="5">H.R. 5</bill>, which will make college more affordable to middle and working class Americans by cutting the interest rate on federally insured student loans in half; and we passed <bill type="h" number="6">H.R. 6</bill>, which is a substantial start in making this country more energy independent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And we accomplished all this, Mr. Speaker, after draining the swamp and ending the culture of corruption by adopting the strongest, toughest ethics and lobbying rules in history.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, we clean up the fiscal mess left by the Republican-led 109th Congress. The last Congress abdicated its duty to be a faithful and responsible steward of the public fisc. They shirked their responsibility to establish the right priorities and make the right choices to serve the American people. They failed to pass nine of the eleven appropriations bills needed to sustain the operations of government for Fiscal Year 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, thanks to your superb leadership, and especially the extraordinary legislative craftsmanship of our remarkable Chairman of the Appropriations Committee, we rectify these Republican failures today. The Continuing Resolution we take up today, <bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill>, is not the ideal manner to fund the government and contains some provisions that each of us might not like, unlike the President's decision to escalate the war in Iraq, the choices reflected in <bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill> represent the best available  alternatives out of a universe of worst choices. That is why, Mr. Speaker, I rise to offer my support for the Fiscal Year 2007 Continuing Resolution, and my appreciation to the leadership, the Chairman and members of the Committee, and for all my colleagues who join me in voting for <bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, <bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill>, totals $463.5 billion, the amount remaining under the Republican budget resolution for the current fiscal year. Most programs are funded at FY 2006 levels with increases to cover the cost of pay increases. Of course, it was also necessary to make additions to maintain staffing levels, avoid furloughs, and generally meet increased costs or workloads for agencies, particularly the Department of Justice, the federal judiciary, the Social Security Administration, the FAA</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But Mr. Speaker, because the new Democratic majority knows how to, and does not shirk from, choosing wisely and setting the right priorities, in this continuing resolution we were also able to provide significant new investments for high priority needs in many areas, including veterans healthcare and assistance, law enforcement, public health, housing and education, scientific research, energy independence, transportation, and the environment. Let me discuss briefly some of the more important  and beneficial provisions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the area of veterans healthcare, the resolution provides $32.3 billion, an increase of $3.6 billion above the FY 2006 funding levels to provide service for the anticipated increase of at least 325,000 veteran patients and to meet rising healthcare costs', especially of our returning soldiers from Iraq and Afghanistan. As President Lincoln reminded us 142 years ago, we have a moral obligation to care for him whom has born the battle, and for his widow and orphan. We are going to keep that commitment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We also provide $21.2 billion, an increase of $1.2 billion to provide care for service members and their families, including treating service members wounded in action in Iraq and Afghanistan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, we will never neglect the needs of those who proudly don the uniform in the defense of the United States. That is why the resolution provides $13.4 billion to fund the Basic Allowance for Housing, an increase of $500 million. This increased funding is  needed to provide a down payment towards the funding shortfall caused by higher housing rates.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the vitally important area of public safety, law enforcement, and crime prevention, the resolution increases the funding for the Federal Bureau of Investigation by $216.6 million to fully fund 31,359 positions, including 12,213 agents and 2,577 Intelligence Analysts--doubling the number of Intelligence Analysts since September 11th. This amount also includes $100 million to proceed the FBI's plan to move from paper-based case management to electronic data sharing. The resolution also includes</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, as a member of the Judiciary Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security, I know that investing in crime prevention programs is an effective use of the taxpayers' precious dollars. That is why I am pleased that the resolution provides $520 million for Byrne Justice Assistance Formula Grants, an increase of $109 million, and $542 million for Community Oriented Policing Services (COPS), an increase of $70 million. Together these increases are the first step in reversing  the drastic cuts to State and local law enforcement programs made since the Bush administration came into office in 2001. I will immediately make the request for the U.S. Justice Department to fund the new crime-prevention needs of Houston.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, as we all know, education is destiny. The surest and most certain path to continued American prosperity lies in an educated citizenry. That is why I am especially pleased that for the first time in 4 years, the maximum Pell Grant has been increased, by $260 to $4,310. This long-overdue increase will help over 5.3 million students pay rising college expenses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The resolution also provides $10.7 billion for IDEA Part B State grants, an increase of $200 million to help school districts serve 6.9 million children with disabilities and special needs. If we are going to be serious about leaving no child behind, then we must make sure to adequately fund special education.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But there is more, Mr. Speaker. The resolution increases Title I K-12 Grants by $125 million and provides more than 38,000 additional low-income children performing below grade level with intensive reading and math instruction. Thus, we have begun to reverse the decline since 2005 in Title 1 support for elementary and secondary schools at a time of record enrollments (55 million students in 2006) and pressures for more accountability from No Child Left Behind requirements.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The resolution also contains $125 million targeted to the 6,700 schools that failed to meet No Child Left Behind requirements in the 2005-2006 school year, enabling them to implement improvement activities, such as teacher training, tutoring programs, and curriculum upgrades. According to the Department of Education, without this funding more than 80 percent of high-poverty districts would be unable to afford these improvements.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The value and efficacy of Head Start is well known and long established. That is why it is so scandalous that the Bush Administration has cut this program by 11 percent in real dollars since 2002. The resolution increases funding by $103.7 million to help prevent a drop in Head Start enrollments. The money the Department of Education will have will still allow for teacher incentive pay for Houston.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The resolution provides $1.9 billion, an increase of $206.9 million to finance more than 300 critically need new or expanded health centers, serving an estimated 1.2 million new patients. We also increase Ryan White CARE Grants by $75.8 million to bring it to its authorized funding level of $1.2 billion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One of the most important investments this nation can make to secure its long-term future is in the area of scientific research. As a long-term member of the Science Committee, I am keenly aware that to keep ahead of our international competitors we cannot scrimp when it comes to expanding the Nation's intellectual capital and knowledge base. That is why the resolution wisely funds the National Institutes of Health at $28.9 billion, an increase of $619.5 million. This level of funding reverses  a projected decline in new NIH research project awards and supports an additional 500 research project grants, 1,500 first time investigators, and expands funding for high risk and high impact research.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The resolution also provides an additional $50 million in new funding for the National Institute of Standards and Technology's (NIST) innovation programs for physical science research and lab support for nanotechnology and neutron research. Equally important, the resolution increases provides funding for the National Science Foundation in the amount of $4.7 billion, an increase of $335 million. This increase is a down-payment towards enhancing U.S. global competitiveness by investing in basic  science research.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, in an area close to my heart and important to my district, which is often referred to as the Energy Capital of the nation, the resolution increases funding to the Department of Energy's Office of Science by $200 million to support cutting edge research, including new energy technologies such as improved conversion of cellulosic biomass to biofuels. I also appreciate that the resolution increases funding for energy efficiency and renewable energy resources by $300 million which will  enable us to accelerate research and development activities for renewable energy and energy efficiency programs. NASA and in particular the Johnson Space Center can be funded by redisbursing funds in the Agency to avoid lost jobs and the stopping of important work. I will work for the continued work of NASA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, as Hurricane Katrina laid bare for all the world to see, affordable housing has for too long been a neglected priority in this country. The resolution makes a modest but useful stab at correcting this woeful situation. The Section 8 Tenant-Based Program is funded at $15.9 billion, an increase of $502 million, which will enable the Department of Housing and Urban Development to renew 70,000 housing vouchers currently in use by individuals and families. The Section 8 Project-Based  Program is budgeted at $5.9 billion, an increase of $939 million. This much needed increase will help HUD renew 157,000 housing vouchers currently in use by individuals and families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although no one likes to live in public housing, we must remember that for millions of our fellow citizens they are their home and sanctuary. For too long they have been neglected, which has led to an accelerated state of disrepair. That is why it is encouraging to see that the resolution provides an extra increase $300 million to enable Public Housing Authorities (PHAs) to address critical operating needs after last year's energy hikes saddled them with $287 million in unexpected utility costs.  Although this increase is still $672 million short of the total estimated need of $4.5 billion, it will help to restore staff levels, maintenance activities, elderly service coordinators, security officers and equipment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Also Mr. Speaker, the resolution contains language changing the funding formula for the Section 8 Tenant-Based Program. The current formula is based on information from 2004 that is out of date and results in some Public Housing Authorities (PHAs) getting more money then they can spend while others have less than they need. The resolution corrects this problem by directing HUD to use the most recent 12-month leasing and cost data. Last week HUD announced that a similar provision would be included  in their 2008 budget request to be implemented in 2009. By including the language now, 2007 funds will be put to their intended use--funding housing units for low-income families and individuals rather than sitting unspent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Next to human capital, few things are as important to the nation's economic future as is its physical infrastructure, especially its roads and bridges. That is why it is very good news that the federal aid highway program is fully funded at the level guaranteed in the</paragraph>
    <paragraph>SAFETEA-LU Act by providing an obligation limitation of $39.1 billion for FY 2007, $3.5 billion over the FY 2006 enacted level; and funding for Federal mass transit programs is increased by $470 million to $8.97 billion to meet the transit funding guarantees as required by SAFETEA-LU.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, America is a generous and compassionate Nation. That is why it is consistent with our values that the resolution increases Global HIV/AIDS funding by $1.3 billion to $4.5 billion. This increase will help to expand efforts to combat HIV/AIDS, and TB programs including in the 15 focus countries and the multilateral efforts through the Global Fund to Fight HIV/AIDS, TB and Malaria.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am proud that the United States is doing more than its share in helping to eradicate malaria, which is still too often an unnecessarily fatal disease in too many parts of the world. The resolution funds the Agency for International Development's Malaria programs in the amount of $248 million, an increase of $149 million. This will allow U.S. AID to expand its bilateral global malaria initiative activities from the current 3 countries to 7. Country programs expand access to long-lasting insecticide  treated bed nets, promote and support effective malaria treatment through the use of proven combination therapies; and increase prevention efforts targeted to pregnant women.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the continuing resolution explicitly eliminates directed spending projects ("earmarks") for Fiscal Year 2007 and retains the moratorium on earmarking in place until a reformed process was put in place. Unfortunately, many worthy earmarks are not funded  including the Boys and Girls Clubs, America's Promise, and the Thousand Points of Light Foundation. I know many of my colleagues are disappointed that the budgetary mismanagement by the  Republican-controlled 109th Congress necessitated this draconian measure. In spite of this prohibition I will fight to secure funding for the TSU Lab School and other projects.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But I take some consolation in Chairman OBEY's assurance that earmarks included in this year's appropriations bills will be eligible for consideration in the 2008 process, subject to new standards for transparency and accountability and that the Committee and leadership will work to restore an accountable, above-board, transparent process for funding decisions and put an end to the abuses that have harmed the credibility of Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although the resolution eliminates earmarks for the current fiscal year, I note Mr. Speaker, that the resolution will, however, continue to help State and local governments meet the needs of their communities by providing funding for grants through authorized discretionary and formula programs including Teacher Incentive Grants, Corps of Engineers programs, Military Construction, Department of Energy science programs, Agricultural Research Service operations, and the USDA Cooperative State Research,  Education, and Extension Service.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, perhaps the most compelling reason for supporting <bill type="hr" number="20">H. Res. 20</bill> is that stated by Chairmen OBEY and BYRD in their Joint Statement of December 13, with which I close:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is no good way out of the fiscal chaos left behind by the outgoing Congress. Indeed, this joint resolution provides the Administration far too much latitude in spending the people's money. But that is a temporary price that we will pay in order to give the President's new budget the attention and oversight it deserves and requires, and so that we can begin work right away at putting the people's priorities front and center. We, in the new Congress, have a responsibility to build the foundation  for a better future. We cannot begin that work until we fix the problems left behind by the Republican Congress. So, we must turn the page on the Republican failures and work together in the best interests of the American people.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I urge all members to support <bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill> so we can move forward and attend to real and pressing needs of the American people.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="LEE" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of the continuing resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today we are in this colossal mess because last year's Republican Congress failed to do its job.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Instead of passing the necessary spending bills to fund our Government, Republicans decided they would rather pass the buck.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Instead of owning up to their failure today, Republicans are crying foul! What hypocrisy Mr. Speaker!</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under Republican rule we have seen our country's finances literally flushed down the toilet. Our Nation's debt grew by over $3 trillion thanks to the Republicans. They passed massive tax cuts for the ultra rich. They got rid of common sense pay-as-you-go rules. And they started a completely unnecessary war in Iraq, whose true cost of nearly $450 billion, they have tried to hide from taxpayers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>They had their chance to try and make amends last year, but they failed to act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today Democrats are picking up the pieces and leading our country in a new, fiscally responsible, direction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This CR eliminates all earmarks, suspends the Congressional pay raise and provides critical increases to a number of important programs this year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In particular, I want to thank Chairman OBEY and my colleagues on the appropriations committee for providing over $4.7 billion for our global AIDS, tuberculosis, and malaria programs in FY07. This money will ensure the continued scale-up of these programs and will provide lifesaving anti-retroviral therapy to another 350,000 people this year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am also very pleased that the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) will receive an increase of $300 million for its public housing operating fund. This money will help the Oakland Housing Authority in my district to keep our public housing units open so that we can provide stable housing to thousands of low-income individuals and families who are in need.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Additionally the $1.4 billion increase for Section 8 housing programs and the change in formula will provide housing assistance for a quarter of a million people and help California get its fair share of funding to reflect rising rental costs in our state.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although not perfect, today's CR sends a very powerful message that the Democratic Congress is strongly committed to helping those who are most vulnerable in a fiscally responsible manner.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although we have still got a long ways to go to re-order our Nation's priorities, this CR is the first step. I urge my colleagues to support it.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400400" topic="MORATORIUM ON DIRECTED SPENDING PROJECTS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in strong opposition to the process used by the majority party to write and debate the bill under consideration today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ranking minority members were not consulted on this legislation or provided an opportunity for input. In fact, most of the majority party's own members had no input in this process. Appropriations Committee Chairman DAVID OBEY instead directed his staff members to write major budget legislation behind closed doors without involving elected Members of Congress. It appears staff members of Senate Appropriations Committee Chairman BOB BYRD conducted negotiations on behalf of the Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As reported in CongressDaily AM today, "most of the negotiations were conducted by staff." This information came from Chairman OBEY, who also said that Members of Congress only became involved in the negotiations "when matters became difficult." Let me repeat that: Unelected congressional staff for Chairmen OBEY and BYRD conducted negotiations on 9 of 11 major spending bills that make up the annual budget of the United States Government.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Why do we have an Appropriations Committee if the committee members have no input in the appropriations process? I propose the next legislation this Congress should debate is a bill to dissolve the House Appropriations Committee. It is clearly unnecessary since major budget negotiations can be conducted by staff instead of elected Members. Apparently, the Appropriations Committee consists entirely of Chairman OBEY, who can single-handedly dictate the legislative process and assign his  staff to take the place of elected Members of Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Handing responsibilities for major budget negotiations to congressional staff for Chairmen OBEY and BYRD is an abdication of responsibility. It also sets the stage for corruption on many levels. These staff-level negotiations were unknown to the public and the majority of elected Members. I am deeply concerned that damage and corruption to our laws will occur if Members of Congress are not thoroughly involved in the creation of legislation and knowledgable about the contents of  bills brought to a vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, allowing only 1 hour of debate and no opportunity for amendments on major $463.5 billion legislation that Members had only 1 day to review is further evidence of the majority party's lack of consideration for our system of government and the responsibilities of elected Members. I also wish Congress had completed the budget process last year, but this fact does not excuse the closed process used to write <bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill> this week.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I sincerely hope the majority party will begin including elected Members of Congress in the process of lawmaking, as the Constitution intended, and as the American people rightly expect. Our system of government of the people, for the people, and by the people depends upon our ability to work together to accomplish the business of the American people. I urge my colleagues from both sides of the aisle to join me in calling for a return to the regular committee process and more fair and open debate  of legislation with opportunities to offer amendments.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400184" topic="MORATORIUM ON DIRECTED SPENDING PROJECTS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in reluctant support of <bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill> the Continuing Resolution for FY 2007. Mr. Speaker, this is not the bill that I or any of my colleagues wish we were voting on today. This bill eliminates all earmarks, some for worthy projects like job training, community-based healthcare, and boys and girls clubs. I had hoped that each of the eleven FY 07 appropriations bills would have passed separately into law last year, with proper funding increases to ensure that we are  investing for the future. Unfortunately, the last Congress only passed two.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The last Congress failed at this, and we are left now left to pass a continuing resolution for the rest of FY07 without the detailed fine-tuning and funding increases the bills normally contain. The Republican failures on the budget created the worst budget mess since the Government shut down in 1996. It is no wonder that the debt has increased by more than $3 trillion since Republicans took control of the Government.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The funding of scientific research is crucial to our competitiveness, economic well-being, and quality of life. Flat funding in the context of inflation is difficult for everyone, but it is particularly damaging to scientific enterprise. Scientific budget items must change dramatically each year as large projects with short lives are constructed, go into operation, and are replaced. This year would be a particularly bad time for flat funding in the sciences. We have new international commitments  to energy research and new national projects that have completed construction and require operating budgets. We also have unprecedented and much-needed consensus to increase funding in the sciences to keep pace with our international peers. To this end, wrote with two others letters to the Appropriations Committee raising concerns about the impact of flat funding on the Department of Energy's Office of</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to point out a few positive points in the bill. This bill provides for a $3.6 billion increase over last year's level for VA healthcare funding. I'm pleased that this increase will make it possible for us to provide services for an additional 325,000 patients in the VA medical system, and to meet rising healthcare costs as have more returning veterans than any time since the Vietnam era. I'm also pleased that the bill includes some $4 billion for our housing program for military  families. These gains are important, but we have much more to do. As we begin looking at funding priorities for fiscal year 2008 and beyond, I believe it is imperative that the Congress finally meet America's obligation to provide for full funding of our veterans' health care system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>to mandatory funding can solve this chronic problem. I look forward to voting for such a proposal this year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill raises the maximum Pell grant award from $4,050 to $4,310. This increase, the first in 4 years, recognizes the essential role of the Pell grant program in improving access to higher education and as a critical component in comprehensive efforts to address college affordability. For years under Republican leadership, Congress all but ignored the growing college cost crisis that was preventing many qualified students from going to college. Now, in just the first month of this new Democratic  Congress, the House has already voted overwhelmingly to cut interest rates on need-based Federal student loans. And we have another major step towards putting a college education within reach of every qualified student by boosting the Pell grant scholarship by $260.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also increases Title I school funding by $125 million, bringing total funding from $12.7 to $12.8 billion. The proposed increase would reverse the decline in Title I funding since 2005 and would allow additional reading and math services for some 38,000 eligible children. I also support the proposed $125 million for the Title I school improvement fund. These funds, if passed would be targeted to the 6,700 schools designated as needing improvement under No Child Left Behind, thereby allowing  them to implement professional development initiatives, tutoring programs, and other improvements designed to raise student achievement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also spends $4.5 billion, an increase of $1.3 billion, to expand efforts to combat HIV/AIDS and TB programs, including in the 15 focus countries and the multilateral efforts through the Global Fund to Fight HIV/AIDS, TB, and Malaria. The bill also spends $248 million, an increase of $149 million, to allow the Agency to expand its bilateral global malaria initiative activities from the current three countries to seven.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The chairman deserves ones thanks for negotiating a bill better than a traditional continuing resolution, which would have jeopardized American national security, resulted in thousands of layoffs, and cut off healthcare for members of the U.S. Armed Forces and veterans. For example, the Food Safety and Inspection Service would have faced a month of furloughs, resulting in the closure of 6,000 meat processing plants; the federal judiciary would have had to fire 2,500 workers; and the Princeton  Plasma Physics Lab and other research facilities would have had to stop projects and layoff scientists. I ask my colleagues to pass this bill so that we can begin the FY 08 appropriations and make more important investments in our future.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400387" topic="MORATORIUM ON DIRECTED SPENDING PROJECTS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of cleaning up the Republicans' mess. The previous Congress failed to pass 9 of 11 appropriations bills, creating the worst budget mess since the Government shut down in 1996.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today's resolution is far from perfect. But while adhering to the spending limit in the Republican budget, it provides significant funding increases to several important programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, the continuing resolution for fiscal year 2007 provides housing assistance to 227,000 people through a $1.4 billion increase for section 8 housing programs. Second, it finances construction of hundreds of new community health centers and improvements to existing facilities. Third, today's bill increases funding for Head Start by $104 million to help prevent a drop in enrollments. Fourth, it raises the maximum Pell grant by $260, which will help more than 5.3 million students afford college.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It's time to get to work on the people's business. Cleaning up a mess is never fun, but because Republicans failed to take "personal responsibility" for this year's budget, it is necessary. I urge my colleagues to vote "yes."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400302" topic="MORATORIUM ON DIRECTED SPENDING PROJECTS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, today is a day when being in the majority is about paying for the very long list of mistakes from the last (Republican) Congress that simply refused to pay the bills.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Well, this Congress will not proceed down that road. Before we can begin the regular funding process, we have to pay the bills the last Congress ran up, then did not pay. That's where we are today. And it is a position none of us are happy about.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is a long list of items that should be in this CR that would have benefited the people in my south Texas Congressional district, but since the previous Congress could not be bothered to pay the bills, we will have to begin again to put these in our appropriations bills this year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Among the many items that will now go unfunded is an improvement to help speed up repair of helicopters coming home from and going back to Iraq and Afghanistan at the Corpus Christi Army Depot.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The items that this CR is not funding are not the wasteful spending that characterized the last several Congresses. The items we are cutting here are important national priorities for the health, education and well being of our children and the less fortunate among us, as well as defense priorities for the Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Just this morning, I chaired my first Readiness Subcommittee hearing--a joint hearing with Tactical Air and Land Subcommittee--where we heard time and time again about how much more help the depots needed to repair the equipment our soldiers in the field need so very much.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Not including the funding for helicopter repair at CCAD is part of the price we--as a nation--are paying for the disregard the previous Congress showed for the readiness of our troops, and for the disposition of the job Congress is elected to do.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400412" topic="MORATORIUM ON DIRECTED SPENDING PROJECTS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, there are many things that can be said against this continuing resolution, as the House has heard during today's debate. But after all those things have been said, I am convinced the only responsible choice is to vote for it--and I will do so.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In fact, it was the failure of responsibility on the part of last year's Republican leadership in Congress that brought us to where we find ourselves today. If they had done their job of developing and enacting the legislation to fund the essential functions of government, it would not be necessary for us to be acting now to make up for their failures.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In fairness, much of the blame rests with the Republican-led Senate. While the House last year did pass all but one of the regular appropriations bills, only two of those bills ever received a final vote in the other body--and only those two were enacted into law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But even here in the House, the Republican leadership never even brought to the floor the bill to fund the Departments of Labor and Health and Human Services--not before the election, evidently because they did not want to have to discuss it during their campaigns, but not even in the lame-duck session last year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Given the situation the resulted from their predecessors' failure, Chairman OBEY and his colleagues on the Appropriations Committee decided that the best way to proceed was to bring forward this long-term continuing resolution, intended to complete action on appropriations for the remainder of this fiscal year, and then to begin work on the appropriations bills for the fiscal year that lies ahead.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I support that decision, and I will support this continuing resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are parts of it that I think fall short of what should be done in a number of areas. But there are other parts that I strongly support, including the provision that withholds any increase in the pay of Members of Congress--something that I think is overdue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>More than a year ago--in October of 2005--I urged the House's conferees to agree to a Senate amendment to the fiscal year 2006 appropriations bill that would have withheld a cost of living raise for Members of Congress. I regret that my plea was in vain, because I think we should be prepared to do our part when our country is at war, our homeland security must be improved, and the federal budget remains deep in deficit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Withholding a congressional pay raise will make only a small change in the budget because the amount involved is minor compared with other expenditures. However, I think it is an appropriate first step for Members of Congress to forego this increase in our pay, and I am glad this legislation will have that effect.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also am very pleased that the resolution includes $300 million in additional funding for the Department of Energy's Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy, EERE, programs. My colleague Representative PERLMUTTER and I worked hard to get this funding included in the legislation, and I intend to work closely with  our colleagues in Congress and with the Department of Energy to ensure that the research programs carried out at National Renewable Energy  Laboratory, NREL, in Colorado benefit from a good deal of those funds.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Despite the importance of NREL's work, flat or decreased funding for NREL in recent years--coupled with earmarks and inflationary cost increases--has effectively reduced the funding for renewable energy research, which has led to a continuing struggle for needed resources and great instability at the lab. This in turn has severely affected the lab's ability to develop new technologies and continue the United States' leadership in renewable energy technologies. The boost for EERE funding in this  bill could go a long way toward helping NREL regain its critical momentum.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The parts of the legislation dealing with defense and national security include increased funding for defense health programs, for basic allowance for housing, and for two important Department of Energy nonproliferation programs--the International Nuclear Material Protection and Cooperation program, which secures weapons-grade nuclear materials in the former Soviet States, and the Global Threat Reduction Initiative, which secures high-risk nuclear material around the world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It also includes $2.5 billion for implementation of a round of military base closures authorized in 2005. While the $2.5 billion is an increase from the funding provided for fiscal year 2006, it will still leaves us $3.1 billion short of meeting our Base Realignment and Closure, BRAC, commitments and nearly $1 billion short of the funds needed for military construction projects. Since the Army links its military construction and troop movement plans to BRAC implementation, this shortfall could  have broad impacts on the rotation and return of troops and the building of new brigades.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It has been indicated that additional needs for BRAC and military housing will be addressed in the supplemental war spending bill we will soon consider in Congress. I hope that will be the case, and will work to achieve that result as well as to ensure that the Defense Department takes into account Colorado priorities as it makes the hard choices about which military construction projects to fund.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also am pleased that Chairman OBEY and his colleagues recognized the importance of science programs across different agencies, allowing for increases at the Department of Energy's Office of Science, the National Science Foundation, and the National Institute of Standards and Technology, NIST.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, I am greatly concerned about the impact this resolution could have on the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, NOAA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In my district, NOAA operates the Earth System Research Laboratory, which has the largest concentration of NOAA research staff in the Nation--300--as well as the largest concentration of university staff funded by NOAA research, for a total of 1,000 Federal and contract employees. NOAA's programs in Boulder include the Space Environment Center, which provides essential space weather forecasting services; the NOAA Profiler Network, which gathers key weather information for a range of other agencies,  including the Departments of Defense and Transportation; and the National Geophysical Data Center, the world's largest archive of geophysical data on observations of earth from space.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Funding for NOAA under previous continuing-resolution levels saw significant decreases, so I am pleased that overall the agency will see a return to the funding levels provided for fiscal year 2006. However, it is unclear how this will be distributed, and so there is a possibility that many important programs will not be adequately funded. I believe that we will have to work to address these issues when we consider the appropriation bills for fiscal year 2008.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>NIST also has a significant presence in Colorado. The NIST facilities at Boulder have contributed to great scientific advances, but these facilities are now over fifty years old and have not been well maintained. Many environmental factors such as the humidity and vibrations from traffic can affect the quality of research performed in the NIST labs. Scientists have difficulty conducting cutting edge research in labs that have leaking roofs. NIST has included building renovations as a priority  in past budgets, yet the final budgets have included so many earmarks that the agency's needs have not been met. The absence of similar earmarks from this resolution means that NIST may finally be able to address some of its most dire needs, including renovations of the Boulder facilities. I will work to ensure that much of the nearly $60 million in the NIST construction budget will be dedicated to renovating these facilities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The appropriators had many tough choices to make with regards to funding the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, NASA. Balancing the needs of the different NASA programs is critical and I appreciate that the appropriators realized that congressional intent needs to be clear and specific to ensure that no one program is completely devastated by funding cuts. While I am pleased that the decline in aeronautics research funding will be halted, I am also concerned about the cuts to the  science and exploration programs, as well as to the space operations. It is not yet clear how NASA will accommodate these cuts. NASA is important to the Nation, and I will continue to push for adequate funding from my position as chairman of the Space and Aeronautics Subcommittee of the House Science and Technology Committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Education is vital to our country's youth and our economic future and I am pleased that the appropriators have provided several important programs with funding increases that will help keep our country strong. These include increases above the fiscal 2006 funding levels for Pell Grants, the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act, IDEA, and Head Start. Furthermore, the appropriators made a step in the right direction by increasing funding in Title I of the No Child Left Behind Act, NCLB.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And I am pleased that by this resolution the Federal-aid highway program, in the Federal Highway Administration, is fully funded at the level guaranteed in the Safe, Accountable Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users, SAFETEA-LU, with an obligation limitation of $39.1 billion for fiscal 2007, $3.5 billion over the fiscal 2006 enacted level.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, in conclusion, Mr. Speaker, I think Chairman OBEY and his colleagues deserve the thanks of the House for the work they have done to clear away the rubble left by the Republican leadership last year and to replace it with a firm foundation on which to build in the future. Adoption of this resolution will write an end to last year's sorry story and take the first step on a better, more responsible approach to carrying out our duties as legislators. I urge approval of the joint resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400238" topic="MORATORIUM ON DIRECTED SPENDING PROJECTS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of the resolution before the House.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Few will take any great satisfaction with the manner in which the Congress is at last completing the budget process for 2007. This work was supposed to have been completed 4 months ago. It is important for everyone to understand how we got to this point and why we are forced to take the extraordinary step of approving a continuing resolution to fund nearly every domestic program for the balance of this fiscal year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are here today because the Republican majority that controlled the House last year failed to do its work. Last May, they voted for a budget resolution that was so unrealistic that not even they could find a way to live within it. As a direct result after 8 months, the former majority was able to complete action on just 2 of the 11 regular appropriations bills. Then, in early December, the outgoing leaders of the House and Senate decided to punt on the remaining funding bills, pass a stopgap  spending bill to keep the Government operating through February 15, adjourn the Congress, and leave town.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So now it is up to the new Congress to clean up this budgetary mess as best we can, and that's what the bill before the House does. It is an imperfect solution. There are any number of programs that deserve a lot more funding than we are able to give them here today. We are still constrained by the overall funding levels adopted in last year's budget resolution, a budget that not a single Democrat voted for. At the same time, I am glad that the measure we are considering today manages to increase  funding in a number of priority areas, especially veterans health care, medical care for U.S. troops wounded in Iraq and Afghanistan, the Federal highway program, medical research at the National Institutes of Health as well as some key education programs. I also applaud the decision to put a moratorium on Members' earmarks until a reformed process is put in place to provide an accountable and transparent process for funding these projects.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Even so, some of my colleagues on the other side of the aisle have gotten up to complain that we should have done better. They want less spending in some areas and more spending in others. After sitting on their hands for 8 months last year, they now object to the procedure we're using to clean up the mess they made. It is unfortunate that the people who are complaining the loudest today were unwilling to convince their own leadership to make these spending decisions last year by passing the  individual funding bills on time and getting them to the President for his signature.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The reality is that we are already 4 months into fiscal year 2007. There isn't time to spend another month or two debating spending bills that should have been completed last September. The agencies and the States have waited long enough for Congress to act, and the President is submitting his 2008 budget request to us next week. It's time for Congress to complete this work.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400125" topic="MORATORIUM ON DIRECTED SPENDING PROJECTS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in reluctant support of House Joint Resolution 20 to fund the essential services of the Federal Government through September 20 of this year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On November 7, the American people voted to fire the former Republican majority for gross  mismanagement of the Nation's finances and woeful neglect of the priorities of the American people. This imperfect legislation is necessary to clean up the mess the former majority left behind.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the former Republican majority passed only 2 of the 11 bills necessary to fund the discretionary accounts of the Federal Government. Failing to pass their obligatory legislation by October 1, 2006, the former majority passed a stopgap measure to keep the Government functioning when they adjourned the 109th Congress. Our new Democratic majority was left with the unfinished business of the fiscal year 2007 appropriations legislation. Today marks the 123rd day since the start of fiscal  year 2007, and the President's 2008 budget request is scheduled to be delivered to this Congress on Monday. Now is the time to finish last year's work, so we can move on to the essential work at hand to deliver a new direction for the American people.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although I am disappointed that funding priorities for our districts were left out of this bill, it is important to note several important improvements this bill makes over previous year's appropriations. For example, <bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill> will raise the maximum Pell grant award from $4,050 to $4,310, the first increase in 4 years of this critical effort to make college more affordable for working families. The bill increases special education funding under the Individuals with Disabilities Education  Act, IDEA, by $200 million. This Continuing Resolution will increase low-income public schools' Title I funding by $125 million and thereby reverse the decline in Title I education funding. Even with these increases, Federal investment in education continues to lag far behind the levels needed to create a first-class school system for the 21st century, and I look forward to working to address these shortfalls in the fiscal year 2008 appropriations legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am concerned about the military construction projects left out of this legislation, and I want Congress to work on a bipartisan basis to address this problem in the fiscal year 2007 supplemental appropriations legislation. This bill includes an important increase of $3.6 billion for veterans health care to meet the needs of an additional 325,000 patients, and it increases funding for health care services at the Department of Defense by $1.2 billion, including treating soldiers wounded in action  in Iraq and Afghanistan. The CR also increases funding for the basic allowance for military housing by $500 million. Finally, the bill increases funding for intelligence analysts at the FBI that are critical to protect the American people from the terrorist threat as well as increasing funding for COPS local law enforcement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, as a new member of the House Budget Committee, I have learned over the past several weeks that the budget mess created by the former majority is far worse than the American people know. It will take a lot of hard work to restore order to our Nation's books. <bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill> is the first necessary if unpleasant step in that vital effort. I urge my colleagues to join me in voting for this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400633" topic="MORATORIUM ON DIRECTED SPENDING PROJECTS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today to express my opposition to the Democrats' omnibus spending bill. The text of this legislation that would spend more than $463.5 billion in taxpayer dollars was first distributed to the minority less than 48 hours ago and will be debated for only one hour. In October the Democrats promised the American people increased transparency and accountability, but apparently, these promises are hard to keep in January.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While there are billions of dollars being spent without oversight or accountability, the omnibus also includes a provision that will alter the formula for distributing Section 8 housing funds. The current formula bases funding on an average of funding levels for May, June and July of 2004 with adjustments for inflation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The altered formula contained in the omnibus bill will base funding levels on the previous twelve months funding, accounting for inflation. The formula change will cut significant amounts of funding for more than half of our nation's public housing authorities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The formula change would result in a decrease in funding for three of the four major public housing authorities in my District. The Covington Housing Authority would lose $197,321, the Ashland Public Housing Authority would lose $75,578, and the Maysville Housing Authority would see a loss of $71,274, which is 23.4 percent of its operating budget. These housing authorities provide critical services to my constituents and an unexpected funding cut like this will only worsen the already poorly  funded public housing system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Changing the formula for Section 8 is a topic that deserves debate, but the formula included in the Democrats' omnibus spending bill has yet to see the light of day in either the House Financial Services Committee or, until now, on the House floor. Changing the formula midway through the year without debate or discussion is an unwise move and would wreak havoc on our public housing system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Contrary to claims made by Democratic leaders, it has been discovered that this bill contains numerous hidden earmarks that Democrats apparently hoped to ram through the House without debate. It is in the interest of the American people that we ask our colleagues across the aisle what else is buried in the 135 pages of this bill that will harm real people in our districts without ever having been debated in this House?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400388" topic="MORATORIUM ON DIRECTED SPENDING PROJECTS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this omnibus appropriations bill we consider on the floor today is not a typical Continuing Resolution, but changes funding levels and re-prioritizes projects from prior years. This CR is the longest in recent history. Most of them are 1-2 pages. This is 137 pages. Some of these changes are controversial as well as complicated, and I feel that the whole House would have benefited from a thorough appraisal of these proposals, a vigorous committee process, so that all  Members would have been fully apprised of the nuances and we could pass a wellthought out, carefully crafted omnibus spending bill. However, I was pleased that the crafters of this bill saw fit to include funding levels for Veterans' Affairs that come close to what the House Republicans passed in the last Congress,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For example, this bill does not eliminate 28 earmarks totaling $70 million, including the famed $50 million Rainforest in Iowa project. That $50 million could instead have been allocated to improving adaptive housing for disabled veterans. This bill also funds assistance to Independent States of the former Soviet Union at a level that is $11 million above the Administration's request. Had this bill been considered in Committees, we may have been able to determine that this $11 million excess  may be better spent on rehabilitation programs for blind veterans. Finally, instead of allocating $316 million for "Corporation for National and Community Service, Domestic Volunteer Service Programs," which includes funds to pay people to volunteer in the Americorps program. We could have used some of that money to increase the medical care for spinal cord injured veterans, or increasing</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="MORATORIUM ON DIRECTED SPENDING PROJECTS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, today I rise in support of <bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill>, the Revised Continuing Appropriations Resolution for Fiscal Year (FY) 2007. I commend Chairman OBEY and our House Leadership for bringing this Joint Resolution to the floor. While a Resolution such as this is not the ideal way to fund Government programs, the failure of the last Congress to complete its work left us with no viable alternative. In a very limited amount of time, the Appropriations Committee has done yeoman's  work to bring the FY 2007 appropriations cycle to a close in the Resolution that is before us today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many difficult choices had to be made in this Joint Resolution. I am pleased that one of those choices was to fund highway, transit, and highway safety programs at the levels guaranteed by the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (SAFETEA-LU). Under <bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill>, highway programs will be funded at $38.962 billion, an increase of $3.411 billion over FY 2006 enacted levels; transit programs will be funded at $8.975 billion, an increase of $470 million  over FY 2006; motor carrier safety programs will be funded at $520.5 million, an increase of $30 million over FY 2006; and highway safety programs will be funded at $821 million, an increase of $14 million over FY 2006.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These programs are funded by highway user revenues that have been deposited into the Highway Trust Fund, where they are held in trust for the purpose of meeting our surface transportation infrastructure needs. These needs are reaching crisis proportions. Congestion has worsened dramatically in recent years. In 2003, traffic congestion cost motorists $63.1 billion in terms of wasted time and fuel.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to meeting our infrastructure investment needs, the highway and transit funding levels set by this Joint Resolution will create an additional 192,000 family-wage construction jobs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would also like to mention one aviation-related matter. Under the previous Continuing Resolution, there was a technical anomaly that had the effect of reducing the amount of Airport Improvement Program contract authority  well below the intended program level. I am pleased that <bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill> corrects this anomaly, and further, ensures that the full amount of contract authority that is authorized for the Airport Improvement Program in FY 2007 remains  available. This will set the stage for a successful reauthorization of Federal aviation programs later this year, and I thank the Appropriations Committee for their assistance in this matter.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>All too often, long-term investments in our nation's infrastructure are short-changed in the face of the more immediate need to fund day-to-day operations. This Joint Resolution avoids such a short-sighted approach. Instead, it takes a longer-term view and recognizes the far-reaching effects transportation infrastructure investments have on our nation's economy, our competitiveness in the world marketplace, and the quality of life in our communities. Again, I applaud Chairman OBEY and  House Leadership for recognizing the value of fully funding highway and transit programs, and I urge my colleagues to support the Joint Resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400313" topic="MORATORIUM ON DIRECTED SPENDING PROJECTS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in opposition to this massive $463 billion dollar spending bill because it fails four critical tests: the accountability test, the common sense test, the compassion test, and most of all--the smell test.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Hatched behind close doors by the chairmen of the House and Senate appropriations committees with no input from Members or their constituents, <bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill> levels a devastating blow against New Mexicans and their communities. Our most vulnerable low-income residents will pay the heaviest price.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As Deputy Ranking Member of the Housing and Community Opportunity Subcommittee, I wish to point out that the Majority's arbitrary choices are ripping nearly one million dollars away from the public housing authorities in my district and the people they serve; including $272,428 from the Las Cruces Housing Authority; $158,355 from the Dona Ana Housing Authority; $30,461 from the Gallup Housing Authority; $40,717 from the Truth or Consequences Housing Authority; $15,076 from the Bernalillo Housing  Authority, $43,596 from the Los Lunas Housing Authority; and a combined total of $416,173 from the Region V and Region II Housing Authorities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A Section 8 voucher manager of one of my District's housing authorities described these drastic cuts as comparable to losing an entire month's worth of vouchers to the poor and needy families she serves. Another New Mexico housing authority representative stated that 100 families per month could lose access to vouchers in the region that housing authority serves.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Majority's carelessly slung meat cleaver doesn't stop there. <bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill> strips critical funding from the restoration of the Our Lady of Guadalupe Mission; essential economic development funding for a Business Park in Anthony-Berino; and desperately needed emergency ambulance services for the citizens of the Village of Columbus.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Two weeks ago, New Mexico Governor Bill Richardson and I announced our bipartisan determination to fight the dangerous scourge of methamphetamine use, production, and distribution in our state. Tragically, the Majority's ill-considered cuts will slash funding for the Drug Enforcement Administration Mobile Enforcement Teams (MET) by $30 million and 134 agents and Regional Enforcement Teams (RET) by $9 million and 23 agents. Our local and state law enforcement officers depend upon the MET and RET  initiatives as two of their most effective tools in this fight. Many officers in my district have told me that even at current levels, MET funding is insufficient.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Perhaps the Majority's leadership has decided this battle isn't worth fighting. A few moments with the individuals and families whose lives this evil drug has destroyed might change their minds. But they don't seem to have the time to stop and think about how their choices will affect the safety of real people.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill> also reduces the funding associated with the Base Realignment and Closure Commission (BRAC) process by nearly $4 billion, causing delays in the scheduled repositioning of the 1st Armored Division from Germany to Fort Bliss and the Air Force Special Operations Command from overseas to Cannon Air Force Base. The Majority's decision not only perpetuates inefficient overseas bases; it severely impacts the painstaking community development plans devised by cities like Las Cruces, Alamogordo,  and Clovis in New Mexico.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last, but certainly not least given the Majority's lip service in support of supplemental and alternative energy technologies, <bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill> shreds funding for promising initiatives in this area. Consider, for example, a letter I submit for the RECORD from Karl Gawell of the Geothermal Energy Association. Mr. Gawell states that this legislation "will be a serious setback for efforts in the House and Senate to restore the DOE geothermal research program."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have worked with Mr. Gawell to explore opportunities for expanded geothermal energy development in Southern New Mexico and I take his concerns very seriously. I hope that my colleagues will, too.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, as one who remains committed to vigorously fighting wasteful spending, I understand--and share--the Majority's desire to eliminate unnecessary earmarks. A rushed and ham-handed bill designed for appearances isn't the right way to do it. My constituents deserve the chance to have their voices heard--an opportunity which the normal process of public hearings is designed to provide.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Certainly, <bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill> contains positive elements, such as the significant increase it provides in funding for veterans. I wish I could vote yes for that reason alone--but I cannot support a bill that inflicts so much pain on so many New Mexicans in an indiscriminate and slipshod manner.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to join me in casting a "no" vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>GEOTHERMAL ENERGY ASSOCIATION,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington, DC, January 30, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR REPRESENTATIVE: I am writing to express our serious concern about the direction being set by the FY 07 Appropriations bill, <bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill>, that the House will be considered tomorrow. This bill will be a serious setback for efforts in the House and Senate to restore the DOE geothermal research program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While the bill includes a generic $300 million increase in funding for renewable energy, it allows the Secretary of Energy to distribute those funds. Meanwhile, we are told that the base for funding will be the Administration's FY 07 request, which for geothermal energy was ZERO!</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The House adopted an amendment last year to the Energy and Water Appropriations Bill sponsored by Representative Millender-McDonald appropriating $5 million for geothermal research in FY 07, and the Senate Appropriations Bill as reported by Subcommittee and Committee would have restored the entire $23.5 million geothermal program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is simply no justification for terminating geothermal energy research at the Department of Energy. Recent studies by the National Research Council, the Western Governors Association Clean Energy Task Force, and MIT all support expanding geothermal research funding to develop the technology necessary to utilize this vast, untapped domestic renewable energy resource.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We urge the House to take action to address this tragic situation as it considers the  FY 07 Appropriations bill and ensure continued funding for DOE's geothermal research efforts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Karl Gawell,</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400366" topic="MORATORIUM ON DIRECTED SPENDING PROJECTS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker. I rise today to express my support for the final passage of <bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill>, a joint funding resolution to provide continuing appropriations for fiscal year 2007. Let me be clear, although we have been able to take care of some of the most significant shortfalls, this is not a perfect funding resolution. This is also not the process that we would have preferred, because, as we all know, the funding for fiscal year 2007 should have been completed during the 109th session  of Congress under the Republican majority.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With respect to the agencies included within the jurisdiction of the Financial Services and General Government Subcommittee, a bi-partisan attempt was made to address the most pressing needs. For example:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>SBA disaster loans will receive $114 million for administrative costs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>SBA Salaries and expenses will receive an additional $17.7 million.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The District of Columbia will receive additional funds for public safety programs and $20 million for public transportation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Treasury will receive an additional $26.6 million for high-priority anti-terror and financial intelligence analyst activities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Judiciary will receive an additional $179.1 million to avoid furloughs and support critical functions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>OPM Retirement Systems Modernization will receive $13 million.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>National Archives will receive $7.7 million in additional funding for the Electronic Records Archive and $3 million for repairs relating to the flooding of Archives headquarters.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many important language provisions were also included in this resolution such as a continuation of resources to help rural communities, schools, and libraries afford telecommunications and information services. Without this language, funding would have to be cut or Universal Service fees would have to increase.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I was disappointed that we were unable to address the serious issue of privatized debt collection by the Internal Revenue Service, a practice that many Members have raised objections to continuing. I had also hoped to be able to address the HAVA funding that some states, including New York, may lose because of their inability to secure voting machines within the designated time frame. In addition, language provisions enacted in previous appropriations bills placing restrictions on how the District  of Columbia is able to spend its own budget are, unfortunately, continued in this resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, I do intend to vote in favor of this Continuing Resolution. As I stated earlier, it is not perfect, but it is the best that we could do with the funds that we had. Beyond the immediate Financial Services agency issues, there was an attempt to write a resolution that addressed our nation's highest priority needs. Veterans Healthcare will receive $32.3 billion, which is an increase of $3.6 billion above the 2006 funding level. Defense Health Programs will receive $21.2 billion, an increase  of $1.2 billion to provide care for our service members and their families. Providing health care for our veterans and military personnel is the right thing to do. Significant numbers of our veterans are now returning from Iraq and Afghanistan and we have an obligation to provide funding for their health care needs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I was pleased that additional funding was provided for Pell grants. This increased funding will help over 5.3 million of our students help to pay for ever increasing college costs. This Continuing Resolution also provided additional dollars for Head Start, a program that has proven its effectiveness. The National Institutes of Health received additional funds to support 500 more research project grants.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our community health centers were allocated an increase of $206.9 million to allow for the expansion or creation of over 300 health centers. These centers provide important health care services throughout the United States, and this funding will be utilized for priority health care needs. Ryan White CARE grants were increased to bring them to the authorized level. Finally, this resolution addresses important section 8 and public housing needs in our communities. All of these budget increases  are a part of a carefully crafted resolution that attempts to address some of our nation's greatest needs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would urge my colleagues to vote in favor of H.J. Res 20 so that it can go to the Senate and we can complete our work before our current resolution expires on February 15th. We will be receiving the President's 2008 budget next week, and as a Congress it is time to move forward and work on the 2008 funding needs for our government.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400228" topic="MORATORIUM ON DIRECTED SPENDING PROJECTS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I do not believe that it is in the best interest of the country to play the blame game on how we reached the current appropriations situation. The fact of the matter is that the 109th Congress did not get its work done on time, and we are here today to correct that problem. Before we vote on this bill, I feel compelled to make a couple of observations. First and foremost, I want to thank Mr. Obey and his staff for the hard work that they have put into  this bill. Mr. Obey faced an enormous task, and I believe that no matter how hard he tried, it would be impossible to address all of the funding needs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, I am concerned that despite all the rhetoric that the majority would work with the minority in crafting legislation, this bill was put together in the back room by the House and Senate majority, with little to no input from the minority. In addition, when discussing the nature of the CR, the majority stressed that this bill would not contain any earmarks. Yet, after negotiations were completed between the House and Senate Appropriations Committees, it appears that this bill will continue  to fund a limited number of earmarks championed by the Senate. While these earmarks are technical in nature, and the case can be made that they should not be considered earmarks, the fact of the matter is that they are earmarks, and I believe that it is wrong for us to stand up and claim that this bill does not contain earmarks when it does.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Given that we are operating under a closed rule, and that it us unlikely that the Senate will remove their earmarks, I am resigned to the fact that it is unlikely that we will have an opportunity to change this legislation. Had we operated under regular order, I believe that a bipartisan Appropriations committee could have crafted a more balanced bill, which I would have been willing to support.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400618" topic="MORATORIUM ON DIRECTED SPENDING PROJECTS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise on behalf of my constituents in the small rural town of Mendota, California.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank my friends Chairman OBEY and Ranking Member LEWIS, and Chairman MOLLOHAN and Ranking Member WOLF for their hard work and specifically for including sufficient funding to complete the construction of the Mendota Federal Correction Institution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Crowding at Federal medium-security facilities currently is 37 percent over capacity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Federal Bureau of Prisons expects 7,500 new Federal inmates annually.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Once constructed, Mendota would provide 1,552 beds to help address the growing demand.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The BOP has spent $100 million to complete 40 percent of a prison in Mendota.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With this bill, the Federal Government is stepping up to a commitment that was made to California and Mendota by providing enough funds to complete the prison.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mendota, is a city with an 18.6 percent unemployment rate and 42 percent living below the poverty line.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The prison will provide good jobs and a major boost to a very depressed local economy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, thank you to my colleagues, completing Mendota is a sign that our new majority is committed to responsible governance.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400030" topic="MORATORIUM ON DIRECTED SPENDING PROJECTS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of the Continuing Resolution and commend my colleagues in moving forward from the budgetary crisis left to us the 109th "Do-Nothing" Congress. I especially commend Chairman OBEY for the overall balance and fairness reflected in this CR given the difficult choices confronting him and the leadership in tackling such a complex fiscal policy challenge. I am pleased to see that key areas such as Veterans and Defense Health, Homeland  Security, Transportation, Education and Social Security will be provided modest increases in funding to keep pace with inflation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, I am concerned that not fully funding BRAC will likely delay some projects--for example in my district, Fort Benning may not have the ability to undertake the new construction projects planned in conjunction with the growth resulting from the BRAC process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Additionally, I recognize the explosion of congressional earmarks in recent years which funded special interest projects and promulgated negative perceptions about this legislative body. But the complete omission of earmarks on this year's CR is disconcerting. I am supportive of the process knowing that my district, which is among the poorest in the country, has benefited tremendously from earmarks. Specifically in my district, previously House-approved projects that stand to lose in the CR include  funding for: hospitals; water management systems; family counseling and youth mentoring; cancer education and early detection; upgrading sewer systems; and the list goes on.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In many cases, the earmark process has provided an important vehicle for Members of Congress to direct much needed federal support to very worthy projects and organizations which otherwise would be ignored.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We must not throw the "baby out with the bathwater." Moving forward, I pledge to work closely with the leadership on real and effective reforms especially in regards to transparency, efficiency, accountability, and ethics.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400165" topic="MORATORIUM ON DIRECTED SPENDING PROJECTS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today to speak on the FY 2007 Continuing Resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am pleased to see that the Appropriations Committee followed the President's recommendations with the American Competitiveness Initiative by increasing funds to physical sciences research. The funding that we put into basic research at the National Science Foundation and the Departments of Energy and Commerce will pave the way for innovative breakthroughs. I am hopeful that the Senate will also prioritize these important science initiatives so that we can ensure that America remains globally  competitive well into the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While many science accounts are adequately supported, the NASA account is not. <bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill> reduces NASA's planned FY 2007 funding by $545.3 million. Most of the savings come from the Exploration Systems account, the program that funds development of the next space vehicle. As this Congress understands, we need to retire the Space Shuttle in 2010 and introduce its successor shortly thereafter. The more we cut this budget item, the longer our nation must wait for continued manned access to space.  At a time when countries like China and India are challenging America in outer space, we need to remain leaders in this field. We cannot do that if Congress does not adequately fund our ventures into space.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am also disappointed that the Space Shuttle and International Space Station as well as the Space Science and Aeronautics programs are also underfunded.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is for these reasons that I introduced an amendment yesterday to restore funding to NASA. Unfortunately, the Rules Committee did not accept any amendments to this bill, and Congress will not have the opportunity to vote on this important program. In the last Congress, we voted to support the Vision for Space Exploration and return to the Moon. If we are to live up to that promise, then we need to follow through with adequate appropriations. We also need to give our current programs the best  chance to succeed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I will work with Chairman BART GORDON and the appropriators to ensure that the Fiscal Year 2008 budget will adequately address our Nation's space and aeronautics needs.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400011" topic="MORATORIUM ON DIRECTED SPENDING PROJECTS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today to discuss an issue of importance to my congressional district in Southwest Washington.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The White Pass Ski Area is located in the majestic Cascade Mountains in the Gifford Pinchot and Wenatchee National Forests. The area is commonly referred to by skiers as "the jewel of the Pacific Northwest" for its breathtaking views of Mt. Rainer and exciting skiing opportunities. The area, which provides critical tourism revenue to the surrounding rural communities, is now looking to expand to provide greater opportunities to skiers in the Pacific Northwest.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Washington State Wilderness Act of 1984 added over 23,000 acres of land to the Goat Rocks Wilderness Area and removed from wilderness designation 800 acres adjacent to the White Pass Ski Area as having "significant potential for ski development" and urging the Secretary of Agriculture to "utilize this potential, in accordance with applicable laws, rules and regulations."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Gifford Pinchot National Forest Land and Resource Management Plan allocated the 800-acre area that Congress had withdrawn from the Wilderness Area back in 1984 to Developed Recreation in recognition of the intent of Congress. However, the LRMP concurrently inventoried as roadless the same 800-acre area.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is well-understood that it was congressional intent to permit expansion of the White Pass Ski Area. I would like to submit for the record a letter signed by all living Members of the 1984 congressional delegation, stating that it was their intent to provide for the expansion of White Pass Ski Area. In a February 3, 2004 letter, the U.S. Department of Agriculture also confirmed this congressional intent, stating: "We agree that the intent of Congress was clearly to allow for ski area development  in the Hogback Basin."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Fiscal Year 2007 Interior Appropriations Bill that passed the House in May of last year included important information clarifying congressional intent to permit expansion of White Pass Ski Area. The language stated:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Committee notes that the Washington State Wilderness Act of 1984 removed from wilderness designation 800 acres of land adjacent to the White Pass Ski Area in Washington State for potential ski development. The Committee notes that the Gifford Pinchot National Forest Land and Resource Management Plan allocated the 800-acre area as Developed Recreation to allow for ski area expansion, while concurrently inventorying the same land as roadless to reflect its current physical character. The Committee  recognizes that it was the intent of Congress to permit ski area expansion into this 800-acre area and urges the Secretary of Agriculture, once the Environmental Impact Statement for the White Pass Ski Area's Master Development Plan is properly completed, to move forward expeditiously in approving the expansion plans in accordance with all applicable laws, rules, and regulations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, the Continuing Resolution that we are going to pass today does not include any report language, including the language clarifying congressional intent as it relates to White Pass Ski Area.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I wanted to bring this issue to the attention of my colleagues and highlight the fact that the House Appropriations Committee was prepared and willing to clarify congressional intent, and that the full House approved that clarification by voting for the Fiscal Year 2007 Interior Appropriations Bill in May. In keeping with this, I urge the Secretary of Agriculture to move forward expeditiously in approving the expansion plans in accordance with all applicable laws, rules, and regulations--once  the Environmental Impact Statement is properly completed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>July 7, 2005. </paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR SECRETARY JOHANNS: As members of the 1984 Washington Congressional delegation, we are writing to express our collective dismay over an injustice that has continued over the past 21 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over two decades ago, we succeeded in passing through the Congress the Washington Wilderness Act of 1984 (Washington Wilderness Act; P.L. 98-339). This legislation added 23,000 acres of wilderness along and near Highway 12, while removing from wilderness designation 800 acres that are adjacent to the White Pass Ski Area. As reported language stated, legislation removed the 800 acres from wilderness so the Secretary of Agriculture could evaluate its "significant potential for ski area development."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, twenty one years after passage of this Act, the White Pass Ski Area remains mired down in its third attempt at completing an Environmental Impact Study to add these acres. Something has gone terribly wrong.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The White Pass Ski Area, which began operations in 1952, is located at the crest of the Cascade Mountains in south-central Washington State within the boundaries of the Wenatchee-Okanagan and Gifford Pinchot National Forests. Plans for expansion of the White Pass Ski Area were first initiated in the late 1950's and included the Hogback Basin.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1961, the White Pass Company submitted to the Forest Service a survey and formal request for additional expansion area on the north slope of Hogback Mountain, and requested it not be incorporated within the anticipated wilderness boundary. The Forest Service concurred with the proposed boundary adjustments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, these discussions were not brought forward during Congressional evaluation of the proposed wilderness legislation. The Wilderness Act of 1964 (PL 88-577) subsequently incorporated the Goat Rocs Wild Area, including most of Hogback Basin, into the National Wilderness Preservation System as the Goat Rocks Wilderness. Despite the incorporation of the proposed expansion area into the Goat Rocks Wilderness, discussions concerning White Pass expansion plans and the need for a boundary adjustment  continued over the next 20 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the early 1980's supporters of the ski area approached Congress to lobby for a wilderness boundary adjustment during the days preceding passage of the 1984 Washington Wilderness Act. Environmental interests were concerned with the precedent created by adjusting the Wilderness boundary, but "agreed with the expansion of downhill skiing opportunities in exchange for significant expansion of Goat Rocks ....." (Sid Morrison letter to Supervisor O'Neal April 17, 1989).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the 1984 Washington Wilderness Act were to "(1) designate certain National Forest System lands in the state of Washington as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System, ..... and (2) insure that certain other National Forest System lands in the State of Washington be available for non-wilderness multiple uses." (PL 98-336, Sec 2(b)(1 and 2) Through the 1984 legislation, some 23,000 acres of land were added to the Goat Rocks Wilderness while 800 acres were released  from the wilderness area (refer to Goat Rocks Add. West Side map #WA-W-109, March 1984).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senate Energy and Natural Resources Committee Report (98-461) describing the legislation and its objectives provides further explanation of the wilderness release language in the Act. "As reported, <bill type="s" number="837">S. 837</bill> would add approximately 23,143 acres to the existing Goat Rocks Wilderness established by Congress in 1964. In addition, some 800 acres would be deleted from the existing wilderness. The 800 acres deleted from the existing Goat Rocks Wilderness Area have significant potential for ski development  and should be managed by the Secretary of Agriculture to utilize this potential, in accordance with applicable laws, rules and regulations (Senate Rpt. 98-461, page 10)."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The dilemma is that, because of multiple land use designations for the proposed expansion area, in combination with other procedural issues, efforts to approve expansion plans have been repeatedly thwarted. The conflicting, confusing and uncertain status of the subject lands needs addressing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The need for administrative action with respect to the White Pass Ski Area expansion  project is evident from the 40-year history of expansion attempts. Maintaining this area in a non-developed recreation status is not consistent with the intent of Congress. Over the past 21 years, various actions have continually frustrated the intent of Congress to allow for the potential expansion of White Pass Ski Area.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In order to prevent the failure of a third attempt to resolve the expansion need, White Pass is committed to complete another NEPA analysis. Based on findings from the analysis, we the undersigned strongly urge the current Washington Congressional delegation and the Secretary of Agriculture to provide a vehicle for the White Pass Company to expand into Hogback Basin without further delay and the threat of costly appeals and judicial reviews.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We hope that you will agree that the conflicting, confusing and uncertain status of the subject lands deserve your thoughtful clarification, correction and resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="MORATORIUM ON DIRECTED SPENDING PROJECTS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, at the conclusion of the 109th Congress, Republicans adjourned for the year without completing work on 9 of the 11 budget bills that fund the operations of the federal government. Completion of the federal government's annual budget is one of Congress' most critical tasks, but even though several months have gone by since the beginning of the fiscal year, only 2 of the 11 bills for fiscal year 2007--Defense and Homeland Security Appropriations--have been signed into  law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This failure to complete Congress' most basic task--to pay the country's bills--has left newly elected leaders of the House and the Senate with no choice but to make tough choices with regard to the fiscal year 2007 budget.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since October 2006, the federal government has been operating on the basis of a temporary measure known as a continuing resolution. This resolution is set to expire on February 15, 2007, and unless Congress approves funding for federal programs covering Agriculture; Commerce, Justice, and Science; Energy and Water; Foreign Operations; Interior and the Environment; Labor, Health &amp; Human Services, and Education; Legislative Branch; Military Construction and Veterans Affairs; and Transportation,  Treasury, and Housing, federal government operations in these areas will cease.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over the past weeks, House leaders have been writing legislation that would ensure the federal government remains operational through fiscal year 2007. Today, the House is considering <bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill>, a joint resolution that will keep the federal government open and require most federal programs to operate under tight budget constraints. While modest increases were allotted to some of America's high priority items, such as veterans' and military health care, law enforcement, and education, the bill  cuts over 60 federal programs and rescinds unobligated balances on many other programs to pay for them. Further, the bill explicitly eliminates special funding provisions, commonly referred to as "earmarks."</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill> is not a perfect bill, and I am concerned about how it might impact some federal programs that are important to Missouri residents. Despite my concerns, I have concluded that it is in our nation's best interest to quickly approve this appropriations package and focus our attention toward the President's fiscal year 2008 budget and the President's anticipated supplemental appropriations request for military efforts in Iraq and Afghanistan. I commend Congressman OBEY for drafting  such complex legislation that makes the best of a bad situation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400439" topic="MORATORIUM ON DIRECTED SPENDING PROJECTS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today to discuss the funding recommendations for accounts under the jurisdiction of the Defense Subcommittee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The House approved the conference report on the Defense Appropriations Act for fiscal year 2007 on September 26th, 2006 by a vote of 394 to 22, and the President signed the bill into law on September 29th. However, several important accounts that were previously within the jurisdiction of the Subcommittee on Military Quality of Life have been transferred back to the Defense Subcommittee, and therefore are addressed in this continuing resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Two of the most important of these are the Basic Allowance of Housing for our active duty members of the military, and the Defense Health Program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am pleased this continuing resolution provides the minimum funding level necessary for both these activities. This legislation provides an increase of $500 million for Basic Allowance for House above the fiscal year 2006 enacted level, and an increase of $1.2 billion for the Defense Health Program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, we need to recognize that both programs will need additional funds during the rest of this fiscal year. Rates for Basic Allowance for Housing were increased late last year following the normal survey of market housing rates. This has created a shortfall of $1.4 billion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, due to inflationary increases in health care costs and an Administration proposal for an increase in insurance co-payments that was not approved by the Congress, the Defense Health Program faces an additional shortfall of at least $700 million.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We must address these funding shortfalls later this year. Our highest priority in the Defense budget should be for the well-being of our military personnel, and I know my Subcommittee chairman shares my concerns. This continuing resolution is just a first step toward meeting that responsibility in fiscal year 2007.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400300" topic="MORATORIUM ON DIRECTED SPENDING PROJECTS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> All time for debate has expired.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400239" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Yes, I am opposed to the bill in its present form.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will report the motion to recommit.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from California?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400239" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the legislation before us is intended to eliminate earmarks to fund a variety of important Federal programs. In spite of those best intentions, however, a close reading of the bill revealed that earmarks were, in fact, left in.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Additionally, a number of critical programs affecting new law enforcement, military construction and military families have been shortchanged. In an effort to live up to the spirit of what this bill intended, my motion to recommit would eliminate nearly $600 million in earmarks, other unnecessary spending, and also use those funds to fully fund the Drug Enforcement Administration's effort to combat methamphetamines and other illicit drugs, restore critically needed funds to military construction  and military family housing accounts, and reduce the Federal deficit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Specifically, this motion would accomplish the following:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, rescind the remaining $44.6 million from the Senate's rain forest in Iowa earmark, eliminate $94 million unnecessary and unrequested funding for the Denali Commission, funding that is nothing more than a thinly-disguised Senate earmark for Alaska. Eliminate $400 million of ongoing earmarks from the NNSA weapons activity accounts. Eliminate $49.7 million of spending in DOE's fossil energy account, spending that duplicates mandatory funding by the Energy Policy Act of 2005.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My motion would distribute these savings in the following manner:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, $50 million for the DEA's efforts to combat meth and other illicit drugs; $275 million for basic allowance for housing; $86 million for critically needed military construction and family housing; $178 million for deficit reduction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I encourage my colleagues, both Republicans and Democrats, to live up to the spirit of this legislation by voting to eliminate earmarks and put those funds to better use by combating meth, supporting our military families and reducing the deficit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge a strong bipartisan vote on this motion to recommit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield whatever time may remain to Mr. Pearce of New Mexico.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400313" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise to support the Republican motion to recommit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last year, I held nearly 40 town hall meetings across New Mexico talking to our local communities about combating methamphetamine use in our towns. Twenty of these meetings were in schools with our school kids, and we found that five times the national average of kids in New Mexico are addicted to methamphetamines, up to 15 percent of our elementary and high school students are already addicted.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Two weeks ago, New Mexico Governor Bill Richardson and I announced our bipartisan determination to fight the dangerous scourge of methamphetamine use, production and distribution in our State. Tragically, the majority's ill-considered cuts will slash funding for the Drug Enforcement Administration Mobile Enforcement Teams, the MET teams, by $30 million and 134 agents, and Region Enforcement Teams, the RETs, by $9 million and 23 agents.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our local and State law enforcement officers depend on the MET and RET initiative as two of the most effective tools in this fight. Many officers in my district have told me that even at current level of funding, MET is insufficient.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Perhaps the majority leadership has decided battles against illegal drugs are not worth fighting. A few moments with the individuals and families who I met with in my 20 school meetings and 19 additional town hall meetings might change their minds. But we did not seem to have time to consider the people and the effects on the lives of kids in the real America that we face today. We were explained, well, maybe we made a few mistakes. Do tell. We made mistakes that affect the lives of the young  people of this Nation and the heart and the soul of this country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this motion to recommit. Work with us to protect and defend the families of New Mexico and all of America.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman has 30 seconds remaining.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400239" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400300" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in opposition to the motion to recommit.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400300" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the fact is that this is simply a nit-picking motion which, if adopted, would kill our chances of passing this resolution in the United States Senate and result in us living on an '06 continuing resolution, which would deny us the ability to provide additional funds for veterans health care, for education, for veterans housing and the like.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would point out, this resolution already adds $500 million to the basic allowance for housing. This CR already increases family housing construction by $210 million and funds military construction at the level of the President's request that have been authorized.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This motion would eliminate the weapons research account that has been of some controversy today. I would point out, we have already cut that account by $94 million. I doubt that the House wants to eliminate that nuclear weapons research.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would also say that in a new found and sudden burst of false piety, we are now being chastised because we did not reach back and eliminate an item that was approved 2 years ago for the State of Iowa by the majority. In fact, the gentleman who was chairman of the committee when that item was approved is none other than the gentleman offering the motion right now.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I don't mind clearing up the mistakes for last year, of the gentleman, I do mind being asked to go back 2 years to clear up your mistakes. That is asking too much, even for us.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Secondly, I would say that some of us may not like the Denali Commission, but it is a perfectly authorized program. And as much as I might like to see a project like that in my district, I don't have one, neither does the gentleman. I think it is illegitimate for us to single out one legitimate program for elimination that would require us, I think in the interest of fairness, to go back and look at hundreds of other programs that have been approved in the past. So I urge a "no" vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the previous question is ordered on the motion to recommit.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400239" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clauses 8 and 9 of rule XX, this 15-minute vote on the motion to recommit will be followed by 5-minute votes on passage of House Joint Resolution 20, if ordered, and the motion to suspend the rules and agree to House Concurrent Resolution 5.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400378" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on rollcall No. 71, I arrived at the door when the vote was called. I was detained at the office. Had I been present, I would have voted "nay."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the passage of the joint resolution.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400300" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I demand a recorded vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 5-minute vote.</chair>
</record>
