<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1216310404" ordinal="52" title="WHERE IS THE HOUSE?">
  <narrative>WHERE IS THE HOUSE? -- (House of Representatives - July 17, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H6714]</narrative>
  <chair> Under a previous order of the House, the gentleman from Georgia (Mr. Price) is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, here we are, Thursday afternoon, 3:58 p.m. All across the Nation, the day shift is ending, or about to end. Folks getting ready for the afternoon shift. Other folks that work the night shift are either just waking up or just going to sleep to get prepared for another day, another day of work.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Where is the House? The House has gone home, Thursday afternoon, and the House has gone home, not to return until next Tuesday. What didn't we do this week, like we didn't do last week, and the week before, and the week before, we didn't address the number one issue on the minds of Americans and hurting the American pocketbook, and that's the issue of gas prices, didn't address it, nothing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>Now, the majority will tell you that they brought to the floor a drill bill. What they brought to the floor today, Mr. Speaker, cynically, was what they called a drill bill. In fact, it was really just a "no energy" energy bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Why do I say that? Well, the bill had eight sections. Six sections are either current law or are clerical. Current law: No new energy. One of the sections mandated project labor agreements that would increase the construction costs of Alaskan pipelines by as much as 30 percent. Increasing costs: No new energy. The final section would increase the bureaucracy and the red tape for any new energy production. It didn't open any exploration onshore. It  didn't  open any exploration offshore. Increasing costs: No new energy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, what is the solution? Well, the solution is what the American people know, and that is that it's a broad array of items. It's conservation. Americans are doing an incredible job of trying to conserve. We're using less energy than we did last year. Conservation is the key, and we can all do more. It's finding alternative fuel, that fuel that will allow the 21st century to be an American energy 21st century. That will take a little while.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, in the near term, in the short term, what's the solution? Mr. Speaker, you know what it is. It's what your constituents tell you about. It's increasing supply. It is increasing the supply of energy, American energy for Americans. How do you do that? America has incredible resources.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Onshore resources: We ought to be doing more exploration. We're only using 6 percent of the eligible land to be leased to find American energy for Americans onshore.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Offshore: Deep-sea exploration. The vast majority of Americans support environmentally sensitive and sound deep-sea exploration. We ought to be doing that. Only 3 percent of the available territory is being utilized currently.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Utilizing clean coal technology: We now have technology available that allows us to use coal of which America is, remarkably, the world's greatest repository of coal in the world, and we ought to be using that for clean coal technology.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Oil shale, which exists in our western area: There are more than 2 trillion barrels of oil that could be extracted from oil shale in environmentally sensitive and sound ways.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, as you know, we're doing none of that. Now, it's not because there isn't legislation for it. In fact, we have bills right here at the desk: <bill type="h" number="3089">H.R. 3089</bill>, the No More Excuses Energy Act; <bill type="h" number="2279">H.R. 2279</bill>, the Expand American Refining Capacity Act; <bill type="h" number="5656">H.R. 5656</bill>, to Repeal the Ban on Acquiring Alternative Fuels; <bill type="h" number="2208">H.R. 2208</bill>, the Coal Liquid Fuel Act. All sorts of bills exist. They exist, but we aren't allowed a vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As you know, the majority party, the Democrat leadership, beholden to leftist individuals, will not allow a vote on the floor of the House. All we're asking is for a vote. We're not asking for a guaranteed outcome, just a vote. Give us a vote, Mr. Speaker. Why not? What are you afraid of? Why not have a vote? Why not respond to the demand of the American people and increase American energy for Americans? Bring down gas prices. We demand a vote. We hope that next week we'll see it.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
