<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1174924955" ordinal="26" title="SAFETEA-LU TECHNICAL CORRECTIONS ACT">
  <speaking speaker="400100" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="1195">H.R. 1195</bill>) to amend the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users to make technical corrections, and for other purposes, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Oregon (Mr. DeFazio) and the gentleman from Arkansas (Mr. Boozman) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400100" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days within which to revise and extend their remarks and to include extraneous material on <bill type="h" number="1195">H.R. 1195</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Oregon?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400100" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this legislation is truly a compendium of technical corrections. When you look at a bill the magnitude of SAFETEA-LU and its extraordinary importance in our economy, and I believe the signature accomplishment of the last Congress, there are bound to be some drafting errors and other minor concerns in the legislation. We recognized those quite early on and had hoped to pass this bill, this technical corrections bill, during the last Congress; but it was never considered by the Senate,  as are so many things that we do around here. Hopefully, this time we will get this needed work done.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are some essential things to be accomplished in this legislation. There is an oversight in the bill that results in the Surface Transportation Research Development and Deployment account being oversubscribed. People say, who cares.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Well, actually it means that critical programs for the Federal Highway Administration Legacy Research and research programs will not be funded, and that creates a major problem. For instance, this would mean that we would not get the biennial "Conditions and Performance Report." If we are going to maintain and improve our Nation's transportation infrastructure, we need to understand its status, its condition, and its need for future investment as we move toward yet another transportation bill  in the coming Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It provides appraisals of highways, bridges, and transit finance, their expenditures in those accounts, and compares it to the needs we have, operational performance and future investment requirements.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It also would free up additional funding for the National Surface Transportation Policy and Revenue Study Commission, something that was created as part of SAFETEA-LU and has yet to get its work accomplished. We have charged them with both looking at and assessing the future needs, building on the requirements I just mentioned, the annual reports of the Department of Transportation, but even going beyond that to determine our infrastructure needs both to maintain the current infrastructure, to  enhance it, and to mitigate congestion and to move toward a less congested and more fuel-efficient transportation future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>They have also been charged with looking at how we pay for these vital investments and assessing the current revenue source, the gas tax, and some assorted excise taxes with future needs. This is again critical work to be done by that commission.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This will better fund their work and give them some of the staff assistance they need, give them the capability of obtaining the data that they need, and extend the deadline for the report to Congress, which will be a crucial building block in the next transportation bill, by 6 months. We have now set a deadline of December 31, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also clarifies something regarding a sense of Congress regarding the buy America requirement. We feel that the Federal Highway Administration is not implementing the Buy America Act consistent with our, Congress's, statutory intent. They are beginning to break projects down into segments in a way that was not anticipated so that they can basically go around some of the buy America requirements. We want to reinforce here that the separate component test is not what we intended, and the  amendment included in this bill is intended to clarify congressional intent and provide guidance to the Federal Highway Administration in the implementation of that section of the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400040" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would like to thank the chairman for leading the charge on this important technical corrections bill. I want to voice my support for <bill type="h" number="1195">H.R. 1195</bill>, and I encourage my colleagues to do the same.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the time that has passed since SAFETEA-LU was signed into law, we have heard from the Department of Transportation and several States regarding fixes to different programs and high-priority projects. <bill type="h" number="1195">H.R. 1195</bill> addresses most of the areas that need correction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is important to note that this bill does not make substantial policy changes to SAFETEA-LU. Rather, this bill corrects provisions that were not workable in SAFETEA-LU. After we pass this bill, SAFETEA-LU will finally be able to accomplish what Congress voted to do 2 years ago.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bulk of this bill is section 105, which makes changes to over 200 of the high-priority projects in section 1702 of SAFETEA-LU. These changes address surface transportation projects in the bill that were unable to be executed, clarifying recipients, and increasing certain project funding levels, and decreasing others to achieve budget neutrality.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also makes a critical correction in the Transportation Research Program authorized in SAFETEA-LU. Errors were made in the research section of SAFETEA-LU that weakened the legacy research programs carried out by the Department of Transportation. This bill addresses that problem.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also extends the reporting deadline for the National Surface Transportation Policy and Review Study Commission established in SAFETEA-LU. This important commission is tasked with recommending a new direction in funding and policy for our surface transportation programs, and we look forward to seeing their final report.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, thank you, Mr. Chairman, for revitalizing this technical corrections bill. I hope all of my colleagues will join me in supporting the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400100" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400040" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield such time as he may desire to the gentleman from Alaska (Mr. Young).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Mr. YOUNG of Alaska asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400440" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would like to thank the gentleman from Oregon (Mr. DeFazio) for bringing this bill forth, and Mr. Oberstar, the chairman of the full committee. This was our bill. We worked on this jointly. Some people say, Why do you need a technical corrections bill?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If you remember, every highway bill we have ever passed has gone through a series of technical correction adjustments because when we write a bill, sometimes it is misinterpreted by highway departments and municipalities. This is purely a technical corrections bill. It adds nothing; it takes nothing away.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, we passed a good piece of legislation 2 years ago. It has been implemented, but it will be implemented in a better way with these corrections.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have talked with the gentleman from Oregon and all he has to say is "yes" or "no." Regarding Providence Hospital of Anchorage, we are looking for a solution to a problem. I agree that we shouldn't be paying for something that is already done, but I would like to have those moneys available to improve the transportation to the center hub of health care in the city of Anchorage. It is my understanding that the gentleman has agreed to work with me in conference to try to solve that problem.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400100" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, will the gentleman yield?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400440" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield to the gentleman from Oregon.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400100" topic="">
    <paragraph>Absolutely. The gentleman from Alaska has had extensive conversation with the chairman of the committee. It is my understanding that he is fully committed to helping resolve this issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is a problem with retroactive reimbursement, but we are looking at other ways to deal with critical access to a vital health facility in Anchorage.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400440" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman, and I look forward to working with the gentleman and the chairman of the full committee on the new highway bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe that the adjustments in this bill for the commission are set up for finding ways to fund, and it is crucially important to make sure that they have enough time to do that job. We are right in the process of not only finishing up SAFETEA-LU, but now we are in the process of beginning to write another bill which has to address the issue of transportation in this country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As you know how strong I supported the funding and the methods of funding previously was not successful, I think this Congress has a responsibility to provide the transportation for the Nation as a whole that can do the job.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400100" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank the gentleman from Alaska (Mr. Young) for his leadership as chairman of the full committee as we went through that process in the last Congress, and also the fact that he is willing to get out front at the beginning to begin to try to address what is actually an investment deficit so far as it goes to transportation in the United States, something that can be easily recognized if one travels to other countries and sees how committed they are, particularly to competitors  like China and the investments they are making which are absolutely on a massive scale to make their economy more efficient to move their people more efficiently.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We need to not only maintain what we have and live on the benefits of our past investment; we need to ensure more robust future investments. I assure the gentleman I have begun a series of hearings that are on two tracks in the subcommittee I chair to look both at the future investment needs and also potential ways to raise the funds we need to make those investments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I look forward to working with the gentleman and others as we go through that process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I do want to assure Members since there is a new sensitivity around here about PAYGO that <bill type="h" number="1195">H.R. 1195</bill> complies fully with House budget rules; and although it only addresses changes to previously authorized projects, not new projects, it also fully adheres to the new House Member earmark disclosure requirements.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is legislation that I recommend wholly to my colleagues, and they can vote for it in good conscience. It will help build our future and realize the full dream of SAFETEA-LU as we move through its full term.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400040" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, in closing, I want to thank Mr. DeFazio, Mr. Duncan, Mr. Oberstar, and Mr. Mica, and certainly their staffs, for working so hard together to rectify the technical corrections that we are addressing in SAFETEA-LU. And I also want to thank our former chairman, the gentleman from Alaska (Mr. Young), for his hard work in providing the leadership that we had in the last Congress to get the SAFETEA-LU bill done.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400273" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, <bill type="h" number="1195">H.R. 1195</bill> makes technical corrections to the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users, or SAFETEA-LU.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is the third time we have worked to finalize these technical corrections to SAFETEA-LU. During the 109th Congress, the House passed <bill type="h" number="5689">H.R. 5689</bill>, a bill to make technical corrections to SAFETEA-LU in June 2006.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>During the summer and fall of 2006, we worked with the Senate to create <bill type="h" number="6233">H.R. 6233</bill>, which is a very similar product to the bill we are considering today. Now, we are trying again.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As my colleagues have just said, <bill type="h" number="1195">H.R. 1195</bill> makes numerous technical corrections to Federal surface transportation programs authorized by SAFETEA-LU. The technical corrections included in this bill have been identified by the Department of Transportation and are mostly of a conforming nature, or to correct drafting errors. The most important correction we are making is to strengthen the Federal Highway research program by ensuring the continuation of the legacy research programs carried out by  the Department of Transportation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The majority of this bill is section 105, which makes changes to over 200 of the high priority projects in sec. 1702 of SAFETEA-LU. These changes address "broken" surface transportation projects, clarifying recipients and increasing certain project funding levels and decreasing others to achieve budget neutrality.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is one purely technical correction that is not included in this package. SAFETEA-LU inadvertently changed certain regulations for trucks with a gross vehicle weight of less than 10,000 pounds.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One of the implications of this error is that operators of these trucks no longer have to register or file insurance with DOT. Consequently, DOT can not regulate them for safety purposes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When Congress passed SAFETEA-LU, this change was not a policy change Congress knew about or intended to make. If Congress wanted to make this change, we would have debated and discussed it. Rather, this was something we were not aware of and has had very serious unintended consequences--especially for small businesses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I hope the Chairman, along with our colleagues in the Senate, will work with me to correct this technical problem.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Despite the omission of this important correction, I still support this legislation and I encourage my colleagues to do the same.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in strong support of <bill type="h" number="1195">H.R. 1195</bill>, a bill to make technical corrections to the surface transportation act, SAFETEA-LU.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1195">H.R. 1195</bill> makes technical corrections to the surface transportation act, Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (SAFETEA-LU), enacted in 2005. This is a non-controversial, bipartisan bill that is intended to correct drafting errors, make technical fixes, and clarify Congressional intent on several provisions of the SAFETEA-LU.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation is very similar to the two bills that passed the House last year, but were never considered by the Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although <bill type="h" number="1195">H.R. 1195</bill>, as amended, only addresses changes to previously authorized projects, the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, per my direction, has required Members of Congress to submit earmark disclosure certifications pursuant to Rule XXI of the Rules of the House of Representatives. In addition, the bill, as amended, complies with pay-as-you-go budget rules.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>SAFETEA-LU has been very successful and effective. Building on previous surface transportation acts, SAFETEA-LU provides the programmatic framework and investments necessary to begin addressing the nation's growing surface transportation needs. However, as with legislation of this magnitude, there were inadvertent drafting errors. The changes in this bill are required to ensure that all policies, programs, and projects embodied in the authorization act are implemented as intended by Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In particular, this bill makes critical fixes to the transportation research program authorized in SAFETEA-LU. Errors were made in the research program funding calculations that resulted in lower than intended funding levels  in several research programs. These technical fixes will recapture critical research funds for many essential programs, including:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Future Strategic Highway Research Program, a concentrated, results-oriented research program focused on solving the top problems of highway safety, reliability, capacity, and renewal; and</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The University Transportation Center Program which advances U.S. technology and expertise in the many disciplines comprising transportation through the mechanisms of education, research, and technology.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also clarifies section 1928 of SAFETEA-LU regarding the Sense of Congress concerning Buy America requirements for Federal-aid highway bridge projects. Congress does not believe that the Federal Highway Administration ("FHWA") is implementing the Buy America Act consistent with the statutory intent. Specifically, the "additional cost test" should be conducted on the basis of an entire bridge project, not on separate components of the bridge project. Regrettably, FHWA has applied the  test to separate components of a bridge project if the project is broken into several components for contracting purposes. The original Sense of Congress, as well as the amendment included in this bill, is intended to clarify Congressional intent and to provide guidance to the FHWA in its implementation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, <bill type="h" number="1195">H.R. 1195</bill> modifies the Repeat Intoxicated Driver Law to allow for the use of ignition interlock devices. This change gives States more flexibility to either continue with the current one-year license suspension requirement for repeat offenders, or permit a 45-day license suspension, after which limited driving privileges are reinstated provided an ignition interlock device is placed on the offender's vehicle.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Repeat offenders are a significant part of the United States drunk driving problem, representing about one-third of all Driving Under the Influence (DUI) arrests each year. It is estimated that between 50 and 75 percent of repeat offenders whose licenses have been suspended continue to drive illegally. An ignition interlock device prevents offenders who have alcohol in their system from operating their vehicle, but allows them to continue to drive to work, school, or an alcohol treatment program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph> Mr. Speaker, I urge my colleagues to join me in supporting <bill type="h" number="1195">H.R. 1195</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I submit the following exchange of letters between Mr. GORDON and myself regarding this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>&lt;em&gt;House of Representatives, Committee on Science and Technology,&lt;/b&gt;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington, DC, March 26, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR MR. CHAIRMAN: I am writing to you concerning the jurisdictional interest of the Committee on Science and Technology in matters being considered in <bill type="h" number="1195">H.R. 1195</bill>, to amend the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users to make technical corrections, and for other purposes. The bill amends research portions of <bill type="h" number="3">H.R. 3</bill>, Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (P.L. 109-59), which are within the Committee  on Science and Technology's jurisdiction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Committee on Science and Technology acknowledges the importance of <bill type="h" number="1195">H.R. 1195</bill> and the need for the legislation to move expeditiously. Therefore, while we have a valid claim to jurisdiction over the bill, I agree not to request a sequential referral. This, of course, is conditional on our mutual understanding that nothing in this legislation or my decision to forgo a sequential referral waives, reduces or otherwise affects the jurisdiction of the Committee on Science and Technology and that  a copy of this letter and of your response will be included in the Congressional Record when the bill is considered on the House Floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Committee on Science and Technology also asks that you support our request to be conferees on any provisions over which we have jurisdiction during any House-Senate conference on this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thank you for your attention to this matter.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>BART GORDON,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>House of Representatives, Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure,  </paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington, DC, March 26, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR CHAIRMAN GORDON: Thank you for your March 26, 2007 letter regarding <bill type="h" number="1195">H.R. 1195</bill>, to amend the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users to make technical corrections, and for other purposes. Your support for this legislation and your assistance in ensuring its timely consideration are greatly appreciated.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I agree that the research provisions in the bill are of jurisdictional interest to the Committee on Science and Technology. I acknowledge that by forgoing a sequential referral, your Committee is not relinquishing its jurisdiction and I will fully support your request to be represented in a House Senate conference on those provisions over which the Committee on Science and Technology has jurisdiction in <bill type="h" number="1195">H.R. 1195</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I value your cooperation and look forward to working with you as we move ahead with this important clean air legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>JAMES L. OBERSTAR, M.C.,</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400116" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would like to thank the Chairman for revitalizing this important technical corrections bill and voice my support for <bill type="h" number="1195">H.R. 1195</bill>. I encourage my colleagues to do the same.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There were many minor errors--in policy and in Members projects--in SAFETEA-LU that need technical correction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Most people may not remember, but the House and Senate actually passed a SAFETEA-LU technical corrections bill that was signed into law in October 2005. That bill was taken up with extreme urgency because it prevented the accidental shutdown of boat safety programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the time that has passed since the October 2005 SAFETEA-LU technical corrections bill was signed into law, we have heard from DOT and various states regarding fixes to different programs and high priority projects. I believe <bill type="h" number="1195">H.R. 1195</bill> addresses most of the areas which need correction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is important to note that this bill does not make substantial policy changes to SAFETEA-LU. Rather, this bill corrects provisions that were not "workable" in SAFETEA-LU. After we pass this bill, SAFETEA-LU will finally be able to accomplish what Congress voted to do 2 years ago.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1195">H.R. 1195</bill> addresses all of the true technical corrections except one. This bill does not include a correction to an error in the motor carrier title of SAFETEA-LU.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In SAFETEA-LU, we attempted to harmonize the definition of "commercial motor vehicle" with "motor vehicle". Unintentionally, this change removed trucks weighing 10,000 lbs or less from the truck exemption of the Fair Labor Standards Act and from DOT's safety oversight.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am very concerned with this change in policy that was never negotiated for or discussed during the bill's original conference.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, small trucking business, who will have to change their business plan in order to comply with the law, are going to suffer the most. These are the small businesses who have high overhead and small profits, but are providing necessary services and products to urban areas and rural towns across the country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This change is going to create great hardships on the small companies who are already in the business and most likely will inhibit others from entering the business.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is disappointing this Congress has not addressed this problem, but I hope we can do so before final passage of this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, thank you, Mr. Chairman, for revitalizing this technical correction bill and I hope all my colleagues will join me in supporting this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400009" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today to voice my strong support for <bill type="h" number="1195">H.R. 1195</bill>. This bill will make essential technical corrections to the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, and Efficient Transportation Equity Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank my friend, Rep. James Oberstar, and the Members of the Transportation and Infrastructure Committee for bringing this legislation to the floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation will provide support for vital projects to my home state of California, and in particular to the city of San Bernardino, located in my district. I commend the Chairman for his foresight in giving states the flexibility our districts need to carry out these important transportation projects.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am particularly pleased this bill includes a technical correction for High Priority Project # 2826. This change will allow transportation officials in the Inland Empire to double the number of grade separations constructed on the Alameda Corridor East.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is no doubt this project will go a long way to help reduce congestion and improve road safety for residents in my home district and all Californians traveling to and from the Inland Empire. I urge my colleagues to support our local communities and cast a vote in favor of <bill type="h" number="1195">H.R. 1195</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400040" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400100" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Oregon (Mr. DeFazio) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="1195">H.R. 1195</bill>, as amended.</chair>
</record>
