<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1185768000" ordinal="41" title="FRANK G. LUMPKIN, JR. POST OFFICE BUILDING">
  <narrative>FRANK G. LUMPKIN, JR. POST OFFICE BUILDING -- (House of Representatives - July 30, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H8841]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform be discharged from further consideration of the bill (<bill type="h" number="2309">H.R. 2309</bill>) to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 3916 Milgen Road in Columbus, Georgia, as the "Frank G. Lumpkin, Jr. Post Office Building," and ask for its immediate consideration in the House.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Illinois?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the bill, as follows</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="2309">H.R. 2309</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. FRANK G. LUMPKIN, JR. POST OFFICE BUILDING.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Designation.--The facility of the United States Postal Service located at 3916 Milgen Road in Columbus, Georgia, shall be known and designated as the "Frank G. Lumpkin, Jr. Post Office Building".</narrative>
  <narrative> (b) References.--Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the facility referred to in subsection (a) shall be deemed to be a reference to the "Frank G. Lumpkin, Jr. Post Office Building".&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, Frank Lumpkin, Jr. was born in Columbus on September 5, 1907. He was reared in Columbus, attended the 16th Street, now Woodall Elementary, School and Columbus High School, graduating from Riverside Military Academy in Gainesville, Georgia, in 1925. He was the first college football player from the University of Georgia to turn professional by joining the Philadelphia Eagles in 1933.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Lumpkin was stationed at the Pentagon during World War II. He developed an ordinance distribution plan that the British government said, "shortened the war by months." Mr. Lumpkin later served under General George Patton in Europe as a Lieutenant Colonel in the 709th Tank Battalion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Lumpkin was President of Willcox-Lumpkin Company an insurance agency founded by his grandfather, D. F. Willcox, in 1848, where he built his family's business into an internationally known firm that traded to 18 countries.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I commend my colleague Representative LYNN WESTMORELAND for introducing this legislation and I urge the swift passage of this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill was ordered to be engrossed and read a third time, was read the third time, and passed, and a motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
