<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1208880002" ordinal="26" title="NATIONAL HEALTH CARE DECISIONS DAY">
  <narrative>NATIONAL HEALTH CARE DECISIONS DAY -- (House of Representatives - April 22, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H2501]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400110" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and agree to the concurrent resolution (<bill type="hc" number="323">H. Con. Res. 323</bill>) expressing Congressional support for the goals and ideals of National Health Care Decisions Day.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the concurrent resolution.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the concurrent resolution is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="hc" number="323">H. Con. Res. 323</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas National Health Care Decisions Day is designed to raise public awareness of the need to plan ahead for health care decisions related to end-of-life care and medical decision-making whenever patients are unable to speak for themselves and to encourage the specific use of advance directives to communicate these important decisions;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Patient Self-Determination Act (42 U.S.C. 1395cc(f) et seq.), guarantees patients the right to information about their rights under State law regarding accepting or refusing medical treatment;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas it is estimated that only a minority of Americans have executed advance directives, including those who are terminally ill or living with life-threatening or life-limiting illnesses;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas advance directives offer individuals the opportunity to discuss with loved ones in advance of a health care crisis and decide what measures would be appropriate for them when it comes to end-of-life care;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the preparation of an advance directive would advise family members, health care providers, and other persons as to how an individual would want to be treated with respect to health care;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas to avoid any legal or medical confusion due to the emotions involved in end-of-life decisions, it is in the best interest of all Americans that each person over the age of 18 communicate his or her wishes by creating an advance directive;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Conditions of Participation in Medicare and Medicaid, section 489.102 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this resolution), require all participating facilities to provide information to patients and the public on the topic of advance directives;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services has recognized that the use of advance directives is tied to quality health care and has included discussions of advance directives in the criteria of the Physician Quality Reporting Initiative;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas establishing National Health Care Decisions Day will encourage health care facilities and professionals as well as chaplains, attorneys, and others to participate in a collective, nationwide effort to provide clear, concise, and consistent information to the public about health care decision-making, particularly advance directives; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas as a result of National Health Care Decisions Day, recognized on April 16, 2008, more Americans will have conversations about their health care decision, more Americans will execute advance directives to make their wishes known, and fewer families and health care providers will have to struggle with making difficult health care decisions in the absence of guidance from the patient: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved by the House of Representatives (the Senate concurring), That the Congress--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) supports the goals and ideals of National Health Care Decisions Day;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) supports the goals and ideals of advance care planning for all adult Americans;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) encourages each person in the United States who is over the age of 18 to prepare an advance directive to assist his or her loved ones, health care providers, and others as they honor his or her wishes;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) calls upon all members of this body to execute such documents and discussions for themselves; and</narrative>
  <narrative> (5) encourages health care, civic, educational, religious, and for- and non-profit organizations to encourage individuals to prepare advance directives to ensure that their wishes and rights with respect to health care are protected.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Michigan (Mr. Dingell) and the gentleman from Georgia (Mr. Gingrey) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Michigan.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400110" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and to include extraneous material on the resolution under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Michigan?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400110" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, at this time, I reserve the balance of my time. My good friend from Georgia, I know, has some important comments.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400151" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of <bill type="hc" number="323">H. Con. Res. 323</bill>, expressing congressional support for the goals and the ideals of National Health Care Decisions Day.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>National Health Care Decisions Day was recognized by hundreds of organizations across the United States last Wednesday, April 16, and it is appropriate for this body to stand with those organizations in recognition of this important day.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, first of all, though, I want to thank the distinguished chairman of the Energy and Commerce Committee, Mr. Dingell, and his staff for their cooperation in helping us get this to the floor. I want to thank the ranking member, Mr. Barton, and the minority staff and the 100 Members, many of them members of the Energy and Commerce Committee who are cosponsors of this resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the goals of the resolution are twofold. First, it aims to raise awareness of the importance for everyone at all stages of life to take the time to discuss important end-of-life medical decisions with their loved ones.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second, this resolution recognizes the emphasis of over 450 organizations spanning all 50 States that worked together on April 16 to educate Americans about their options in preparing advanced medical directives and appointing medical powers of attorney.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Of these groups, 75 are national organizations, including AARP, the American Bar Association, the American Medical Association, National Right to Life, and an additional 370 State and community organizations participated in the National Health Care Decisions Day efforts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, as a result of the National Health Care Decisions Day, thousands of people across the country have received information on advanced directives through newspaper articles, television, and radio broadcasts, all released last week on April 16. I want to thank and congratulate all those involved for their hard work on this important cause. I am also proud of the broad bipartisan support this resolution has garnered.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Companion legislation sponsored by Senators WYDEN and ENZI has already passed the Senate, and now over 100, as I mentioned earlier, of my fellow House Members of both sides of the aisle have signed on to this resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I want to urge the American people to invest time and effort into seeking out information on advanced directives. Advanced directives allow individuals to maintain control over their health care decisions even at the end of their lives, regardless of the circumstances they may face at that time. And I also encourage Americans to educate themselves on the options and details of the various types of advanced directives so that their wishes may be correctly documented and carried out.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me be very clear: This bill does not express what an individual's end-of-life decision should be. Those are the decisions that should be left to the individual undertaking this difficult but important step.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This resolution merely seeks to raise awareness about advanced directives themselves. And that's why this resolution is being supported by such a diverse range of organizations. Educating individuals and making them aware of their choices is a key to respecting and preserving life.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, as a physician, I cannot stress enough that these decisions should be made with the input of medical professionals and should be accessible to the patient's doctor in the time of greatest medical need. Too many times, families are left to guess what medical decisions their family member would have wanted. Think about the Terri Schiavo case a couple years ago. But physicians are sometimes left to guess as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A recent study by the U.S. Agency for Health Care Research and Quality  found that 75 percent of physicians whose patients had advanced directives were not even aware that those directives existed. This is a problem, Mr. Speaker, and I hope that as we get electronic medical records and HIT, Health Information Technology, becomes more sophisticated and intraoperable, these advanced directives can be stored electronically and be made accessible to the medical  staff in an instant, really, in a timely manner.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, in conclusion, Mr. Speaker, I want to encourage all Americans to set aside time to have what may very will be one of the most vital conversations that any family can have.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my fellow Members to vote in support of this resolution and to recognize the critical role of education in allowing Americans to effectively express their end-of-life wishes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With that, Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the gentleman from New York (Mr. Towns) will control the time.</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400409" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself as much time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in strong support of <bill type="hc" number="323">H. Con. Res. 323</bill>, expressing congressional support for the goals and ideals of National Health Care Decisions Day.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a cosponsor of this resolution, I understand the importance of making our health decisions clear to our family members and other loved ones through advanced directives. While it is very difficult for us to face the prospects of our own mortality, many of us write wills in order to ensure that our loved ones are adequately provided for in our absence. Unfortunately, we often do not take that care in making provisions regarding our end-of-life medical care.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nobody can predict when disease, tragedy, or other medical conditions will render one unable to make medical decisions for ourselves. Accordingly, we must plan ahead in case of such a tragedy to ensure that our wishes are properly carried out.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Advanced directives are an integral part of any care-delivery plan. They are simply a statement by a competent person that articulates the medical, legal, and personal wishes regarding medical treatment in the event of future incapacity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Where advanced directives are present, medical professionals, families, and loved ones are best able to make critical care decisions should a patient become unable to make sound judgments about their health care.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The resolution before us commemorates National Health Care Decisions Day on April 16, 2008. Although this specific day occurred last week, the goals and ideals of today should be recognized perpetually.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>This resolution encourages those 18 years of age and older to prepare advance directives. It also encourages medical, civic, educational, religious and other nonprofit organizations to promote advance directive preparation, particularly among their constituents.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to thank my colleague on the other side of the aisle, Representative PHIL GINGREY, for his work in raising this important issue. Our colleagues in the Senate have already recognized the need to highlight advance directives, and I urge us here in the House to do the same.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400151" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I just want to thank my friend from New York for his support of this resolution. And again, I want to thank the chairman of the committee, Mr. Dingell, for allowing this to be brought to the floor under suspension and for his support, and for the support of the majority staff, and also to my distinguished colleague, the ranking member of Energy and Commerce, Representative Barton, and the minority staff.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge all of my colleagues to support the resolution, as Representative Towns just said.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400409" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Michigan (Mr. Dingell) that the House suspend the rules and agree to the concurrent resolution, <bill type="hc" number="323">H. Con. Res. 323</bill>.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the concurrent resolution was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
