<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1182182403" ordinal="36" title="SBA WOMEN'S BUSINESS PROGRAMS ACT OF 2007">
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from New York (Ms. Vel&#xE1;zquez) and the gentleman from Tennessee (Mr. David Davis) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412235" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of the request to suspend the rules and pass <bill type="h" number="2397">H.R. 2397</bill>, the SBA Women's Business Programs Act of 2007. I would like to thank Chairwoman Vel&#xE1;zquez for working in a cooperative and bipartisan manner to bring this bill, authored by Ms. Fallin, a freshman member of the committee, to the House floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield such time as she may consume to the gentlewoman from Oklahoma (Ms. Fallin).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412230" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would like to begin by thanking Chairwoman Vel&#xE1;zquez and Ranking Member Chabot for their support for this legislation and also in helping to build a strong bipartisan coalition in the Small Business Committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill, the SBA Women's Business Act of 2007, will strengthen the Women Business Centers program that was established in 1997 by making it more efficient and more accountable. The Women's Business Centers are a very important part of the grant programs that are funded by the Small Business Administration. Today, Women's Business Centers all across the country are providing women entrepreneurs with much-needed technical assistance in starting and operating their own small businesses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the mid-1990s, the Federal Government began awarding grants to Women's Business Centers that were operating as nonprofit organizations in conjunction with institutions of higher learning. Originally, these grants were intended to be awarded to business centers in their first 5 years with the understanding that after the first 5-year period had ended, the center would be financially self-sustaining.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although many Women's Business Centers did meet this goal, some have not for a variety of reasons. As a result, a greater percentage of the funding for this program has been consumed by the operating costs of potentially unviable centers rather than the intended purposes of establishing new business centers. The result is a drag on the system and viable business centers that are not truly serving an unmet need in their communities. This jeopardizes the effectiveness in the viability of the entire  program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The SBA Women's Business Programs Act of 2007 will restore the original priorities held by the Federal Government when this program was created. By offering a three-tiered system of funding and lower caps on spending for older business centers, we can ensure a balanced percentage of funding is used to support both new and existing business centers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The first tier requires that at least 40 percent of the total funds be reserved for the purpose of establishing and supporting new Women's Business Centers during their first 5 years of existence. The second tier will use 20 percent of the total funds to help sustain the centers that have successfully existed during their first 5 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Lastly, the third tier will use a maximum of 40 percent of the funds to continue supporting centers that have existed for 8 years or more and have met the necessary benchmarks set forth by the SBA to receive this funding. This three-tiered system will offer a helping hand to newly established centers while slowly weaning the older centers off the dependency of the Federal grants.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is important to realize that this legislation does not affect the overall funding level of this program. Rather, it rearranges the distribution of funds to reflect the original intention of these grants, an offer of temporary assistance rather than one of permanent dependency on the Federal Government.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation will ultimately restore accountability and efficiency to a program that, while well intentioned, has become weighed down by inefficiency. These are goals that every Member of Congress can all support. The SBA Women's Business Programs Act of 2007 has passed in the Small Business Committee with overwhelming bipartisan support, and I want to encourage all my colleagues on both sides of the aisle to vote in favor of this today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412235" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no further speakers, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ms. VEL&#xC1;ZQUEZ. Mr. Speaker, the small business face in America is changing. We have more and more women who would like to get involved in opening and starting their businesses, and the bill that we have before us as sponsored by Representative Fallin does just that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It promotes opportunity for women by increasing access to business counseling and training through the development of the Women's Business Center. This will better enable women to have flourishing enterprises and help to spur job creation and economic development across this Nation. I urge adoption of this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412232" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, as a husband, a father of a young daughter, the proud brother to 6 sisters, and having served alongside dedicated women in the military, I have seen first-hand the role that women play in economically strengthening American society. And this is why I rise today to support <bill type="h" number="2397">H.R. 2397</bill>, the SBA Women's Business Programs Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Despite their significant contributions, women who work full time, year round, still only make 77 cents for every dollar made by their male counterparts, and women business owners, particularly those from socially and economically disadvantaged backgrounds, face significant challenges resulting from inadequate community resources. Such resources include lack of access to capital, training resources, and networks of assistance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, women-owned firms are one of the fastest growing, successful small business sectors. The number of women-owned firms has increased at nearly double the rate of all firms, and those with socially and economically disadvantaged backgrounds have grown at twice the rate of their counterparts and 6 times the rate of all U.S. firms. As the number of women entrepreneurs grows, particularly those from underserved communities, I believe it is critical that women have adequate and appropriate resources  to prepare them for success in the marketplace. To that end, <bill type="h" number="2397">H.R. 2397</bill> proposes to expand the agency's commitment to the Women's Business Centers (WBCs).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>WBCs provide in-depth, substantive, and outcome-oriented counseling, training and mentoring, resulting in substantial economic impact as measured by successful business start-ups, job creation and retention, and increased company revenues. They also provide financial, management, and marketing assistance to women small business owners.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2397">H.R. 2397</bill> supports the growth of women small business owners by expanding entrepreneurial development assistance, particularly in low-income areas. The legislation dedicates funding to the opening of new WBCs in underserved areas, while implementing new benchmarks to ensure centers that continually receive funds are meeting performance requirements. These metrics, which include information on clients served and fundraising plans, will help to preserve resources for centers that have demonstrated  success helping women entrepreneurs while promoting the expansion of assistance centers into underserved areas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2397">H.R. 2397</bill> is important legislation which promotes economic security for America's women, and I urge all my colleagues to support this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in strong support of <bill type="h" number="2397">H.R. 2397</bill>, the Small Business Administration Women's Business Programs Act of 2007. I commend my colleague from Oklahoma (Ms. Fallin) for introducing this important legislation to reauthorize the women's entrepreneurial development programs of the Small Business Administration (SBA).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Most notably <bill type="h" number="2397">H.R. 2397</bill> would authorize the SBA Administrator to provide financial assistance to private nonprofit organizations to conduct projects for the benefit of small businesses owned and operated by women. The bill notes that such projects shall provide, among other things, financial assistance, including training and counseling on how to apply for and secure business credit and investment capital, preparing and presenting financial statements, and managing cash flow and other financial  operations of a business concern; management assistance, including training and counseling in how to plan, organize, staff, direct, and control each major activity and function of a small business; and marketing assistance, including training and counseling in identifying</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2397">H.R. 2397</bill> would also direct that the National Women's Business Council (NWBC) conduct at least one study per year that evaluates the challenges hindering the success of women entrepreneurs, and mandates that NWBC select the topic for the study in consultation with the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Support for this legislation will help Congress fulfill its commitment to ensuring that women owned and operated small businesses are able to access the resources and training they may require in order to achieve success. I urge my colleagues to support <bill type="h" number="2397">H.R. 2397</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from New York (Ms. Vel&#xE1;zquez) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="2397">H.R. 2397</bill>.</chair>
</record>
