<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1213804802" ordinal="37" title="AMENDING CERTAIN LAWS RELATING TO NATIVE AMERICANS">
  <narrative>AMENDING CERTAIN LAWS RELATING TO NATIVE AMERICANS -- (House of Representatives - June 18, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H5490]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="5680">H.R. 5680</bill>) to amend certain laws relating to Native Americans, and for others purposes, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="5680">H.R. 5680</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. TABLE OF CONTENTS.</narrative>
  <narrative> The table of contents for this Act is as follows:&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <narrative>Sec..1..Table of contents.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..2..Colorado River Indian Tribes.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..3..Gila River Indian Community contracts.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..4..Land and interests of the Sault Ste. Marie Tribe of Chippewa Indians of Michigan.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..5..Morongo Band of Mission Indians Lease Extension.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..6..Cow Creek Band of Umpqua Tribe of Indians leasing authority.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..7..New Settlement Common Stock issued to descendants, left-outs, and elders.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. COLORADO RIVER INDIAN TRIBES.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; The Secretary of the Interior may make, subject to amounts provided in subsequent appropriations Acts, an annual disbursement to the Colorado River Indian Tribes. Funds disbursed under this section shall be used to fund the Office of the Colorado River Indian Tribes Reservation Energy Development and shall not be less than $200,000 and not to exceed $350,000 annually.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 3. GILA RIVER INDIAN COMMUNITY CONTRACTS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Subsection (f) of the first section of the Act of August 9, 1955 (25 U.S.C. 415(f)), is amended by striking "lease, affecting" and inserting "lease or construction contract, affecting".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 4. LAND AND INTERESTS OF THE SAULT STE. MARIE TRIBE OF CHIPPEWA INDIANS OF MICHIGAN.</narrative>
  <narrative> (a) In General.--Subject to subsections (b) and (c), notwithstanding any other provision of law (including regulations), the Sault Ste. Marie Tribe of Chippewa Indians of Michigan (including any agent or instrumentality of the Tribe) (referred to in this section as the "Tribe"), may transfer, lease, encumber, or otherwise convey, without further authorization or approval, all or any part of the Tribe's interest in any real property that is not held in trust by the United States for  the benefit of the Tribe.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Effect of Section.--Nothing in this section is intended to authorize the Tribe to transfer, lease, encumber, or otherwise convey, any lands, or any interest in any lands, that are held in trust by the United States for the benefit of the Tribe.</narrative>
  <narrative> (c) Liability.--The United States shall not be held liable to any party (including the Tribe or any agent or instrumentality of the Tribe) for any term of, or any loss resulting from the term of any transfer, lease, encumbrance, or conveyance of land made pursuant to this Act unless the United States or an agent or instrumentality of the United States is a party to the transaction or the United States would be liable pursuant to any other provision of law. This subsection shall not  apply to land transferred or conveyed by the Tribe to the United States to be held in trust for the benefit of the Tribe.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (d) Effective Date.--This section shall be deemed to have taken effect on January 1, 2005.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 5. MORONGO BAND OF MISSION INDIANS LEASE EXTENSION.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Subsection (a) of the first section of the Act of August 9, 1955 (25 U.S.C. 415(a)) is amended in the second sentence by inserting "and except leases of land held in trust for the Morongo Band of Mission Indians which may be for a term of not to exceed 50 years," before "and except leases of land for grazing purposes which may be for a term of not to exceed ten years".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 6. COW CREEK BAND OF UMPQUA TRIBE OF INDIANS LEASING AUTHORITY.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Authorization for 99-Year Leases.--Subsection (a) of the first section of the Act of August 9, 1955 (25 U.S.C. 415(a)), is amended in the second sentence by inserting "and lands held in trust for the Cow Creek Band of Umpqua Tribe of Indians," after "lands held in trust for the Confederated Tribes of the Warm Springs Reservation of Oregon,".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Effective Date.--The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply to any lease entered into or renewed after the date of the enactment of this Act.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 7. NEW SETTLEMENT COMMON STOCK ISSUED TO DESCENDANTS, LEFT-OUTS, AND ELDERS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Section 7 of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act, (Public Law 92-203; 85 Stat. 691), is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) by amending subsection (g)(1)(B)(iii) (43 U.S.C. 1606(g)(1)(B)(iii)), to read as follows:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(iii) The amendment authorized by clause (i) may provide that Settlement Common Stock issued to a Native pursuant to such amendment (or stock issued in exchange for such Settlement Common Stock pursuant to subsection (h)(3) of this section or section 1626c(d) of this title) shall be subject to one or more of the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(I) Such stock shall be deemed canceled upon the death of such Native, and no compensation for this cancellation shall be paid to the estate of the deceased Native or to any person holding stock.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(II) Such stock shall carry limited or no voting rights.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(III) Such stock shall not be transferred by gift as provided in subparagraph (h)(1)(C)(iii)."; and</narrative>
  <narrative> (2) in subsection (h)(1)(C) (43 U.S.C. 1606(h)(1)(C)), by striking "Notwithstanding the restrictions" and inserting "Expect as otherwise expressly provided in this chapter and".&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from the Virgin Islands (Mrs. Christensen) and the gentleman from Nebraska (Mr. Smith) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentlewoman from the Virgin Islands.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days in which to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from the Virgin Islands?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, <bill type="h" number="5680">H.R. 5680</bill>, introduced by our colleague, Mr. Grijalva, contains multiple proposals to address the needs of several Indian tribes and Alaska Native villages. I would like to commend Mr. Grijalva for his hard work on this legislation. Without his dedication and commitment, we would not be here this morning. Some of these provisions may seem small and insignificant, but they mean much to those they affect.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under this legislation, the Colorado River Indian Tribes would be authorized to receive funds from the Secretary of the Interior in order to establish and run an Office of Energy Development. Funds are available for such purposes under section 1(b) of the Act of June 1938. The establishment of an Office of Energy Development will allow the tribe to better oversee and manage the operation, management and funds derived from the BIA power system located on their reservation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation would authorize the Gila River Indian Community to agree to mediation over construction contracts. It supports the right of an Indian tribe to dispose of land held in fee simple status. It further authorizes two Indian tribes to enter into long term leasing of tribal land. Finally, this legislation clarifies certain powers of Alaskan Native Regional Corporations with respect to the issuance of common stock.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I urge passage of <bill type="h" number="5680">H.R. 5680</bill>, as amended.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412217" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="5680">H.R. 5680</bill> is a technical corrections bill amending several laws concerning Native Americans. This bill has six substantive sections that will increase tribal economic development in several western States, Michigan and also Alaska. The bill is supported by the administration, and I urge my colleagues to support the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I must add, of course, that opening up American reserves of oil, natural gas, geothermal energy and oil shale here at home would also help economic development, not only for Native Americans, but for all Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rather than devoting precious hours to legislation that covers a multitude of topics, and I understand many of them are necessary, others are more discretionary, I would ask, I would plead in fact as a member of the minority, that the leadership allow us the opportunity to vote on bills that would address the shortage of energy supply in our country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I will say that no single answer remains to solve our energy situation. That is why I believe so many sources of energy need to be on the table. We have heard various criticisms and various analogies, but the fact is that we need more energy supply. The economics point to that. The demands of our economy point to that. The checkbooks of every single American point to that. Households all across America, all across our economy need more access, more affordable access to energy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress ought not point a finger at those folks who they think use too much energy. Certainly I would not tell a farmer or rancher in my district of Nebraska they are caught up in consuming too much energy in producing food for America, or feed stocks for alternative energy. It takes energy to produce energy. Yes, I understand that, and we can do better with our policies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have no additional speakers, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from the Virgin Islands (Mrs. Christensen) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="5680">H.R. 5680</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the bill, as amended, was passed.</chair>
  <chair>The title was amended so as to read:</chair>
  <chair>"A bill to amend certain laws relating to Native Americans, and for other purposes.".</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
