<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1178553612" ordinal="29" title="HONORING THE CONTRIBUTIONS OF THE ROCKY MOUNTAIN SENIOR GAMES ON ITS 30TH ANNIVERSARY">
  <speaking speaker="412231" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution (<bill type="hr" number="290">H. Res. 290</bill>) honoring the contributions of the Rocky Mountain Senior Games on its 30th anniversary for significantly improving the health and well-being of older Americans.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the resolution.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Pennsylvania (Mr. Altmire) and the gentleman from Tennessee (Mr. David Davis) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412231" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, for 30 years the Rocky Mountain Senior Games has offered athletic competition and social opportunities to men and women, age 50 and older. Athletes of all abilities are encouraged to participate in over 30 athletic and social events. Competition is divided into male and female divisions, as well as mixed competition and by age groups. The purpose of the Rocky Mountain Senior Games is to motivate women and men over the age of 50 to pursue and maintain a healthy lifestyle.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 2006, the Rocky Mountain Senior Games hosted 1,035 participants from 17 States across the country. The Rocky Mountain Senior Games offers our Nation's seniors the opportunity to experience the thrill of competition and the joy of camaraderie, while improving their physical fitness.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is of vital importance that we encourage all adults to establish and maintain healthy lifestyles so that they can maintain a high quality of life as they grow older.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For 30 years, the Rocky Mountain Senior Games have helped improve the health and well-being of older Americans in our Nation. Every year, more and more seniors travel to Greeley, Colorado, to participate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I urge my colleagues to join me in honoring the Rocky Mountain Senior Games.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412235" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield as much time as she may consume to the gentlewoman from Colorado (Mrs. Musgrave).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400287" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, my resolution, <bill type="hr" number="290">H. Res. 290</bill>, recognizes the goals and the ideals of the 30th annual Rocky Mountain Senior Games, which will be held in the next few weeks in my district in Colorado.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Colorado Senior Development Council began hosting athletic competition for adults 50 and older in 1978; and today, the City of Greeley, and the Greeley Department of Recreation have partnered with the Colorado Senior Sports Development Council to host this popular event in the Rocky Mountain region.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The games originated in Colorado as a 1-day competition featuring four athletic events, including swimming, track and field, and basketball. Today, the Rocky Mountain games are among the oldest of its kind in the Nation and are among the most popular.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This year's games will be held from June 6-10, and there will be a wide range of events that include basketball, track and field, swimming, billiards, tennis, badminton, cycling, weight lifting, skeet and trap shooting, archery, a 5k and a 10k road race, a triathlon, and many others. The popularity of these events are made most evident by the high number of competitors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last year, for instance, there were more than 1,400 individuals who competed in the games, many of whom succeeded in qualifying for the bi-annual national games.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In fact, Colorado will be well represented at this year's national games, which will be held later this summer in Louisville, Kentucky. There are 640 Colorado athletes who have already qualified.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The individuals who participate experience friendly fellowship, camaraderie, and the exhilaration of competition. For a long time, fitness has been synonymous with Colorado. I think that's because of our wonderful sunny climate and our natural treasures that encourage people to get out and enjoy themselves. It's not surprising, then, that so many seniors continue exercising and seek out active competition, even as they begin to get older.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My bill recognizes these competitors and the benefits they are making towards their long-term health. I am pleased my colleagues in Congress, especially those in Colorado, are joining me today to approve this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412231" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask that Members be given 5 legislative days to insert material relevant to <bill type="hr" number="325">H. Res. 325</bill> and <bill type="hr" number="290">H. Res. 290</bill> into the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Pennsylvania?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412231" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412235" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise today in support of House Resolution 290 honoring the contributions of the Rocky Mountain Senior Games on its 30th anniversary for significantly improving the health and well-being of older Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We should recognize the hardworking volunteers and the event coordinators that make this week's events possible. Without their efforts, these games would not be possible. I ask my colleagues to support this resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400391" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I am proud to rise in honoring the Michigan State University Men's Hockey team in winning the Frozen Four, becoming the Men's National Collegiate Hockey Champions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On Saturday, April 7, 2007, a record crowd of 19,432 witnessed Michigan State defeat Boston College, 3-1, in the championship game of the 2007 NCAA Men's Frozen Four in Scottrade Center in St. Louis.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>During the first period, neither team was able to push the puck past the opposing goalie. As the championship game progressed into the final period, most fans thought the game was headed to overtime. MSU then "exploded" with three goals in the final 10 minutes of the game, icing the championship for MSU.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This victory constituted MSU's third national championship, and the first since 1986. Each member of the MSU Hockey organization made essential contributions to the team's success.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Justin Abdelkader, who was named the team's Most Outstanding Player, snapped a 1-1 tie with 18.9 seconds to go, seconds after ringing a shot off the goalie post.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Jeff Lerg made 29 saves, and Chris Mueller added an empty-net goal with 1.2 seconds left to clinch it for the 3-1 Spartan win.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>MSU Spartans' Head Coach Rick Comley has become only the third coach in college hockey history to win national titles at two Division I Universities, and has earned over 700 career wins. Coach Comley last won the NCAA Championship with Northern Michigan University in 1991.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Spartan Hockey Team not only demonstrated untouchable strength and skill, but also perseverance and determination to make Michigan State University and all of the State of Michigan proud.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The unyielding support from thousands of fans, family and friends, dressed in green, lined the streets of East Lansing where they turned out to welcome MSU's national championship hockey team back home.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am pleased to join with my colleague; Congressman Mike Rogers, who represents Michigan State University, and all the Michigan delegation in honoring MSU and its NCAA National Champion Men's hockey team.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am also very pleased that MSU selected my friend from Northern Michigan Hockey coach, Rick Comley, to lead MSU to its latest hockey title after its legendary hockey coach, Ron Mason, became MSU's athletic director.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, I congratulate the MSU Spartan Hockey Team on winning the 2007 NCAA Championship and recognize all the players, coaches, managers, staff, fans, and families who were instrumental in this great achievement.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412235" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Pennsylvania (Mr. Altmire) that the House suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, <bill type="hr" number="290">H. Res. 290</bill>.</chair>
</record>
