<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1185768000" ordinal="43" title="PRIVATE FIRST CLASS SHANE R. AUSTIN POST OFFICE">
  <narrative>PRIVATE FIRST CLASS SHANE R. AUSTIN POST OFFICE -- (House of Representatives - July 30, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H8842]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform be discharged from further consideration of the bill (<bill type="h" number="3034">H.R. 3034</bill>) to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 127 South Elm Street in Gardner, Kansas, as the "Private First Class Shane R. Austin Post Office," and ask for its immediate consideration in the House.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Illinois?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the bill, as follows</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="3034">H.R. 3034</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. PRIVATE FIRST CLASS SHANE R. AUSTIN POST OFFICE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Designation.--The facility of the United States Postal Service located at 127 South Elm Street in Gardner, Kansas, shall be known and designated as the "Private First Class Shane R. Austin Post Office".</narrative>
  <narrative> (b) References.--Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the facility referred to in subsection (a) shall be deemed to be a reference to the "Private First Class Shane R. Austin Post Office".&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>PFC Shane R. Austin was killed on October 8, 2006, when a grenade struck his tank in Ramadi, Iraq, west of Baghdad. He was assigned to the 1st Battalion, 35th Armor Regiment, 2nd Brigade Combat Team, 1st</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Armored Division in Baumholder, Germany.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Private Austin's grandmother said, "Although the emptiness and numbness is with the entire family, we hold the pride high that Shane was a hero before he left for the military, but now he is everybody's hero. Military was his dream; he intended to make it a career and that he accomplished . . . it was just a short career."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Private Austin served his country with distinction and courage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I commend my colleague Representative DENNIS MOORE for introducing this legislation and urge the swift passage of this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400282" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of <bill type="h" number="3034">H.R. 3034</bill>, legislation I have introduced with the rest of the Kansas delegation to rename the Gardner, KS, postal service facility the "Private First Class Shane R. Austin Post Office."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Private First Class Shane Austin grew up in Edgerton, KS, and attended Gardner-Edgerton High School before joining the U.S. Army. PFC Austin was 19 years old when he was killed on October 8, 2006, while serving in the United States Army's First Armored Division, during combat operations in Ramadi, Iraq. For his heroism, and for saving the lives of several fellow soldiers, Shane was awarded the Purple Heart and the Bronze Star.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>According to Captain Daniel Costin, Shane was a quiet, unassuming man who worked hard, whether it was cutting grass in rear detachment or conducting maintenance on his tank.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Shane's father Terrance also said that while Shane was a bit on the wild side before leaving for boot camp, when Shane came home after finishing basic training he stood tall, stared you straight in the eye, and had a firm handshake.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On October 8, 2006, Shane courageously sacrificed the most precious thing a person can offer to his country--his life; and our country, the state of Kansas, and the Gardner-Edgerton community owes Shane and his family absolute gratitude for the rights and freedoms that he so heroically fought to protect.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Shane also follows in the path of a long line of brave and courageous individuals from the Gardner-Edgerton area who have given the ultimate sacrifice to protect those same rights and liberties. In fact, soldiers from the area have given their lives in service to their country in the Civil War, World War I, World War II, the Korean War, and the Vietnam War, and their sacrifice must also be remembered and honored.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So today I am proud to join with my colleagues in remembering these brave individuals, and in offering this remembrance so that our community never forgets the sacrifice that a brave soldier from Kansas made for his country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill was ordered to be engrossed and read a third time, was read the third time, and passed, and a motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
