<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1169139604" ordinal="23" title="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRY">
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, parliamentary inquiry.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman will state his parliamentary inquiry.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, pursuant to the prior order of the House, would it be in order to call up <bill type="h" number="475">H.R. 475</bill> at this time?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The order of the House provides that the bill may be brought up at any time.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>Further inquiry, Madam Speaker.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman will state it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, pursuant to the prior order of the House, regarding <bill type="h" number="475">H.R. 475</bill>, is it correct that it allows for just 15 minutes of debate on each side, that is, 30 minutes total?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman is correct.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>Further parliamentary inquiry.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman will state his further inquiry.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>Is the Chair aware of any other legislative business that we are doing today?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman has not stated a parliamentary inquiry.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>Is the Chair aware of any further legislative business that we are doing today?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Chair would advise the gentleman to consult the leaderships on that question.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>Further inquiry, Madam Speaker.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman will state his inquiry.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>We do indeed understand the majority's desire to have a 5-day workweek, but is 30 minutes of work on a Friday considered a full day?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman is not stating a parliamentary inquiry.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I move to call up <bill type="h" number="475">H.R. 475</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Only a manager identified by the order of the House would be recognized to call up that bill.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the Chair.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
