<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1179158403" ordinal="13" title="SUPPORTING THE GOALS AND IDEALS OF A NATIONAL DAY OF REMEMBRANCE FOR MURDER VICTIMS">
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution (<bill type="hr" number="223">H. Res. 223</bill>) supporting the goals and ideals of a National Day of Remembrance for Murder Victims.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the resolution.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Davis) and the gentleman from Georgia (Mr. Westmoreland) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days in which to revise and extend their remarks.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Illinois?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a member of the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, I am pleased to join my colleague in the consideration of <bill type="hr" number="223">H. Res. 223</bill>, which supports the goals of a National Day of Remembrance for Murder Victims.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="hr" number="223">H. Res. 223</bill>, which has 59 cosponsors, was introduced by Representative JOHN SHADEGG from Arizona on March 7, 2007. <bill type="hr" number="223">H. Res. 223</bill> was reported from the Oversight Committee on May 1, 2007 by a voice vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, in 2005, there were 16,692 murders and nine negligent manslaughters reported in our Nation. This is obviously too many murders. And so I support the National Day of Remembrance for Murder Victims and recognize all organizations that provide services, such as support, guidance and counseling, to the loved ones and friends of murder victims.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is important that this day is not just a remembrance of those who tragically lost their lives, but a call to action. While some of us have not experienced acts of violence, we share responsibility to people who have lost their loved ones to murder. We should always reflect the moral virtues of respect and caring and sharing with one another, regardless of one's race, creed and national origin.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Of course, we remember the recent incidents that have just occurred at the university in Virginia. I also remember in my own neighborhood, where just last week a young man was killed on a bus. He turned out to be an absolute hero because he actually put himself in front of another student who was about to be shot. And of course that community and that family still grieves. So I urge that we all remember murder victims and their families by getting involved in our homes, communities, schools and  businesses to prevent violence.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I commend my colleague, Representative Shadegg from Arizona, for seeking to honor the memories of murder victims and recognize the impact on surviving family members.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge swift passage of this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400627" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself as much time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With the recent tragedy of Virginia Tech fresh in our minds, we take this time to remember the many victims of needless violence in our country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The devastation of families, victims and entire communities in which these tragedies occur is beyond calculation. Too often, victims' loved ones are left alone with their loss and feel overwhelmed with the devastating experience that has altered their lives forever.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>No one should have to cope with that loss alone. In such crushing times as these, families and friends look for sources of strength to sustain themselves. They also need ongoing support in dealing with the criminal justice system, which can be especially overwhelming during this period of grief.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The need for sources of strength are often found through a variety of support services, including counseling, crisis intervention, professional referrals and assistance in dealing with the criminal justice system. These organizations play an essential role in preserving the memories of victims of murder.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After the story of the murder fades, victim's family and friends are often left to cope without their loved ones alone. Thankfully, these counseling organizations provide the necessary support to the families and friends of murder victims so they can continue with their daily lives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These personal assaults on our citizens are also an assault on all of us. We must remain diligent in our efforts to curb violence. Our murder rate in this country is simply too high. People watch television, movies and play video games where murder is often glorified. Many of our youth engage in pastimes where they are exposed to violence at an early age. However, there is no age where it should be appropriate to introduce murder into anyone's life.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is incumbent upon all of us to recognize the selfless support groups in our communities who work tirelessly to help the thousands of friends and families of murder victims in this country every year. For these reasons, Mr. Speaker, I urge all my colleagues to join me in supporting <bill type="hr" number="223">H. Res. 223</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400627" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield as much time as he may consume to my distinguished colleague from Arizona (Mr. Shadegg).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400368" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for yielding and I thank my colleague from Illinois for his strong words of support.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise today in support of <bill type="hr" number="223">H. Res. 223</bill>, a resolution supporting the goals and ideals of a National Day of Remembrance for Murder Victims.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank the gentleman from Illinois and the gentleman from Georgia for their support, as well as the chairman of the full committee and the ranking member of the full committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation is in fact very important to very many Americans; indeed, to, sadly, too many Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I, along with my colleague, Mr. Chabot of Cincinnati, Ohio, introduced this resolution on behalf of murder victims and their families across our Nation. <bill type="hr" number="223">H. Res. 223</bill> does two simple things. First, it recognizes the many organizations that provide services to the loved ones of murder victims. As the two speakers before me have acknowledged, a victim of crime suffers greatly over and over again, and there are many organizations across our country that help them. The second thing this resolution  does is it supports the establishment and urges the establishment of a National Day of Remembrance for Murder Victims to be held on September 25th of each year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I noted that in our prayer today we were called upon to thank God for our loved ones and our families. This bill is very much about those loved ones and those families who are left behind when a murder is committed and someone is taken from us as a result of violence.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On September 25, 1978, 19-year-old Lisa Hullinger was murdered by her boyfriend. Three months after her death, her parents formed the National Organization of Parents of Murdered Children, headquartered in Cincinnati, Ohio. Parents of Murdered Children earnestly advocates for the thousands of parents who have lost a child as a result of violence. Parents of Murdered Children is one of many organizations that do this work, that help the friends and that help the families to try to cope with the  loss of a loved one.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Other organizations include the National Organization for Victim Assistance, Mothers Against Drunk Driving, as well as the National Crime Victim Law Institute. Each of these organizations plays a vital role, and there are so many others. This resolution not only honors Parents of Murdered Children, but all of the similar organizations providing support and assistance to the loved ones of murdered victims.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, since the introduction of this resolution I have received countless e-mails from all across the country, not just from my district, but from everywhere: from mothers, fathers, brothers, sisters, husbands, wives and children of murder victims.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>All of them have contacted me to say how much they appreciate what the United States House of Representatives is doing for them today. This legislation is indeed important.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We all know that there are established days of remembrance for many dark days in our Nation's history. There is, of course, one for 9/11. There is another one for the day of the Oklahoma City bombing. These were both solemn times in our Nation's history, and yet people are murdered every single day.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On 9/11, almost 3,000 Americans were brutally murdered. It is worth noting that every 10 weeks in this Nation, another almost 3,000 Americans are murdered. That is why I believe we need to establish a day that not only honors them and recognizes them, but also recognizes and honors the victims they leave behind, the family members, the fathers, the sons, the daughters, all of the others who suffer so much.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Each of us has a list of tragedies that we know of personally. My colleague from Illinois recited several. There are way too many.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I cannot rise today without thinking of Duane Lynn and his wife, Nila. Duane and Nila lived in a retirement community in north Phoenix after Duane retired from the Arizona Highway Patrol. One day they chose to attend a homeowners' association meeting in their neighborhood. Tragically, a killer walked into that meeting and senselessly murdered Nila. Nila died in Duane's arms. That was a crushing blow to him and a pain that he suffers every day.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But Duane took that negative pain and became an advocate for other victims. With his help, this Congress passed the Scott Campbell, Stephanie Roper, Wendy Preston, Louarna Gillis, Nila Lynn Crimes Victims Act of 2004.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also think of Sally Goelzer, whose brother, Hal, was murdered in a gang initiation killing. Sally took the pain of that incident and went to work to fight for tougher laws against gangs and against gang killers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am also reminded of the incredible story of Colleen Campbell and her tireless work on behalf of victims, as well as that of her husband, Gary. Colleen tragically has lost not one family member, but three family members on three separate occasions to murder.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, her son, Scott, was murdered. Then later her brother, well-known and famous in America for his work in auto racing, Mickey Thompson, was murdered. And then still later, her sister-in-law, Trudy Thompson, was murdered.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Colleen has spent 22 years in and out of various courtrooms in America dealing with the pain inflicted upon her by the murder of these three loved ones. Again, she has turned that negative pain into being a tireless advocate for victims and for victims rights. She was essential to the creation of victims rights legislation in California and she established Force 100, one of the earliest advocates for victims' rights across this Nation. Force 100 sought to create organizations in every single  State in America to advocate for victims of crime.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are so many stories. There are too many stories. But these victims and their courageous survivors need to know that we in the Congress, and we as a Nation, remember their tragedy and their courage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, this Congress, this House, can do its part. We can say that too many of us have been affected by the horrors of murder, by passing this simple, yet very important, resolution, acknowledging that murdered individuals are not the only victims; that those left behind to cope with the loss on a daily basis are victims also.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We can tell them, however, that those family members and loved ones are not alone. We can recognize the many organizations that do invaluable work to help them. That is why this resolution not only acknowledges the murder victims, but also honors the organizations and the people who devote  their lives to counseling, crisis intervention, assistance and other help in getting those victims through our criminal justice system. The work of these organizations  is so invaluable to so many.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The last organization I want to talk about is the National Crime Victim Law Institute at Lewis &amp; Clark College in Portland, Oregon. This organization, recently established, provides legal assistance to the victims of crime, and has established many programs in colleges across our country, and, I believe, in eight different law schools across our country, to help give legal assistance to the families and the loved ones of those murdered who are left behind.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="hr" number="223">H. Res. 223</bill> lets victims, families and friends know that they are not alone, and that we remember their loved ones. I urge my colleagues to join me in supporting this resolution and honoring all of those men and women who have devoted their lives to helping those among us who have to cope with the senseless violence of a murdered loved one.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400627" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no further speakers, and I yield back the balance of my time. I urge all my colleagues to vote for <bill type="hr" number="223">H. Res. 223</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>To close, Mr. Speaker, let me just commend the gentleman from Arizona once again for his introduction of this resolution and his passionate statement in favor of its passage. I would certainly concur with everything that he has said and urge passage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Davis) that the House suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, <bill type="hr" number="223">H. Res. 223</bill>.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400368" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this question will be postponed.</chair>
</record>
