<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1228928403" ordinal="34" title="THANKS AND WELL WISHES TO ROB NABORS">
  <narrative>THANKS AND WELL WISHES TO ROB NABORS -- (House of Representatives - December 10, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H10907]</narrative>
  <narrative>(Mr. OBEY asked and was given permission to address the House for 1 minute.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400300" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, for the last 4 years Rob Nabors has served as, first, the staff director of the then-Minority Democrats on the Appropriations Committee and, in the last 2 years, as the staff director of the entire committee. His work ethic has been legendary. He has worked all hours of the day like so many in this institution whose names are not publicly known. He has worked overtime. He's worked night and day. He's worked weekdays and weekends. He's demonstrated great judgment and skill.  And he has also been a bit of history because he is the first African American to have served as the staff director for the Appropriations Committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But now, alas, President-elect Obama has asked him to serve as the Deputy Director of OMB, and exercising the "faulty judgment" that we have come to expect from Chicago Bears fans, he has accepted that invitation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I simply wanted to take this moment to publicly in this institution thank him for the great service that he has provided this institution and the country and to wish him well on the road ahead.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400189" topic="">
    <paragraph>Will the gentleman yield?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400300" topic="">
    <paragraph>Surely.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400189" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I had the privilege of chairing a subcommittee on the Appropriations Committee many years ago, and Rob Nabors was my staff director, so I had an opportunity to work with him firsthand. And I want to echo the comments of Mr. Obey and, I know, the comments that Mr. Lewis will make.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Nabors is an individual of great intellect, great integrity, and great insight. And I want to frankly express on behalf of the House our appreciation to the President-elect for having the wisdom to choose somebody who knows the House so well and I think we will be able to work with very closely, although my impression is that his relationship with Mr. Obey may be modified just slightly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rob, congratulations to you.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400239" topic="">
    <paragraph>Will the gentleman yield?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400300" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield to the gentleman.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400239" topic="">
    <paragraph>I appreciate my chairman's yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, it has been my privilege to work with the chairmen both when they were in the minority and now running the place.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I must say that very few staff people combine both the intellect and personality kind of warmth that Rob reflects in the everyday work of this fabulous guy. He's a wonderful member of our staff. OMB is going to be very fortunate to have him, and we will miss him. So thank you very much.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400300" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield to the Speaker.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400314" topic="">
    <paragraph>Thank you very much, Mr. Chairman. I want to join my colleagues and sing the praises of Rob Nabors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are blessed in the Congress with magnificent staff on both sides of the aisle who serve the American people very well, none more excellent than Rob Nabors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is with great congratulations that we send him off to the new administration to work for President-elect and then President Obama but not without some sadness in losing him here in the Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rob, thank you for your service to our country, for your excellence in your work, and for the friendship that you have provided to many of us and for the courage and fortitude you have exhibited in working under the great leadership of Chairman Obey. Thank you, Rob Nabors, again.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
