<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1197997209" ordinal="69" title="ALLOCATIONS FOR HOUSE COMMITTEES">
  <narrative>ALLOCATIONS FOR HOUSE COMMITTEES -- (House of Representatives - December 18, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H16802]</narrative>
  <chair> Under a previous order of the House, the gentleman from South Carolina (Mr. Spratt) is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, under section 308(b)(1) of <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>, the Concurrent Resolution on the Budget for fiscal year 2008, I hereby submit for printing in the CONGRESSIONAL RECORD a revision to the budget allocations and aggregates for certain House committees for fiscal year 2008 and the period of 2008 through 2012. This revision represents an adjustment to certain House committee budget allocation and aggregates for the purposes of sections 302 and 311 of the Congressional  Budget Act of 1974, as amended, and in response to <bill type="h" number="6">H.R. 6</bill>, as passed the Senate on December 13, 2007 (Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007). Corresponding tables are attached.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under section 211 of <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>, this adjustment to the budget allocations and aggregates applies while the measure is under consideration. The adjustments will take effect upon enactment of the measure. For purposes of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974, as amended, a revised allocation made under section 211 of <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill> is to be considered as an allocation included in the resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under section 310 of <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>, the Concurrent Resolution on the Budget for fiscal year 2008, I hereby submit for printing in the CONGRESSIONAL RECORD a revision to the budget allocations and aggregates for certain House committees for fiscal year 2008 and the period of 2008 through 2012. This revision represents an adjustment to certain House committee budget allocation and aggregates for the purposes of sections 302 and 311 of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974, as amended, and  in response to <bill type="h" number="2761">H.R. 2761</bill>, as passed the Senate on November 16, 2007 (Terrorism Risk Insurance Program Reauthorization Act of 2007). Corresponding tables are attached.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under section 211 of <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>, this adjustment to the budget allocations and aggregates applies while the measure is under consideration. The adjustments will take effect upon enactment of the measure. For purposes of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974, as amended, a revised allocation made under section 211 of <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill> is to be considered as an allocation included in the resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
