<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1190044802" ordinal="14" title="CONGRATULATING SCIENTISTS F. SHERWOOD ROWLAND, MARIO MOLINA, AND PAUL CRUTZEN FOR THEIR WORK IN ATMOSPHERIC CHEMISTRY">
  <narrative>CONGRATULATING SCIENTISTS F. SHERWOOD ROWLAND, MARIO MOLINA, AND PAUL CRUTZEN FOR THEIR WORK IN ATMOSPHERIC CHEMISTRY -- (House of Representatives - September 17, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H10372]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400177" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution (<bill type="hr" number="593">H. Res. 593</bill>) congratulating scientists F. Sherwood Rowland, Mario Molina, and Paul Crutzen for their work in atmospheric chemistry, particularly concerning the formation and decomposition of ozone, that led to the development of the Montreal Protocol on Substances That Deplete the Ozone Layer.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the resolution.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the resolution is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="hr" number="593">H. Res. 593</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas in 1973, on the University of California, Irvine campus, chemists F. Sherwood Rowland and Mario Molina began researching the depletion of stratospheric ozone by the chlorofluorocarbon gases then used worldwide as refrigerants and aerosol propellants;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas on June 28, 1974, F. Sherwood Rowland and Mario Molina published in the scientific journal Nature, their path-breaking article, "Stratospheric Sink for Chlorofluoromethanes: Chlorine Atom-Catalysed Destruction of Ozone";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas in 1976, the work of F. Sherwood Rowland and Mario Molina connecting chlorofluorocarbons and atmospheric ozone depletion was confirmed by the National Academy of Sciences;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas in 1978, the United States banned chlorofluorocarbons as propellants in aerosol cans;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas in 1987, because of the research of F. Sherwood Rowland, Mario Molina, Paul Crutzen, and many other scientists, the international community acted through the adoption of the Montreal Protocol on Substances that Deplete the Ozone Layer ("Montreal Protocol");&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Montreal Protocol created the Multilateral Fund for the Implementation of the Montreal Protocol which provides funds to help developing countries to phase out the use of ozone-depleting substances;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Multilateral Fund for Implementation of the Montreal Protocol was the first financial mechanism to be created under an international treaty;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Montreal Protocol recognized that world-wide emissions of certain substances can significantly deplete and otherwise modify the ozone layer in a manner that is likely to result in adverse effects on human health and the environment;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas because of the adoption of the Montreal Protocol the levels of chlorofluorocarbon gases in the Earth's atmosphere have decreased;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas on September 17, 1987, the Montreal Protocol was open for signatures;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas to date, 191 nations have signed the Montreal Protocol;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas F. Sherwood Rowland, Mario Molina, and Paul Crutzen were awarded the Nobel Prize for Chemistry in 1995 for their work in atmospheric chemistry, particularly concerning the formation and decomposition of ozone; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas September 17, 2007, marks the twentieth anniversary of the signing of the Montreal Protocol: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, &lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; That the House of Representatives--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) congratulates scientists F. Sherwood Rowland, Mario Molina, and Paul Crutzen for their work in atmospheric chemistry, particularly concerning the formation and decomposition of ozone, that led to the development of the Montreal Protocol on Substances that Deplete the Ozone Layer; and</narrative>
  <narrative> (2) encourages the continued research of the interaction of humans and their actions with the Earth's ecosystem.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Indiana (Mr. Hill) and the gentleman from Texas (Mr. Hall) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Indiana.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400177" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and to include extraneous material on <bill type="hr" number="593">H. Res. 593</bill>, the resolution now under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Indiana?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400177" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise today in support of House Resolution 593, legislation that congratulates scientists Frank Sherwood Rowland, Mario Molina, and Paul Crutzen for their work in atmospheric chemistry concerning the formation and decomposition of ozone.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1973, Frank Sherwood Rowland and Mario Molina began studying the impacts of CFCs in the Earth's atmosphere at the University of California, Irvine. The chemists discovered that CFC molecules were stable enough to remain in the atmosphere until they reached the middle of the stratosphere. There the molecules would finally be broken down by ultraviolet radiation, releasing a chlorine atom.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rowland and Molina proposed that these chlorine atoms might be expected to cause the breakdown of large amounts of ozone (O3) in the stratosphere. Their argument was based upon an analogy to contemporary work by Paul J. Crutzen, which had shown that nitric oxide could catalyze the destruction of ozone.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Drs. Crutzen, Molina and Rowland were awarded the 1995 Nobel prize for  chemistry for their work on this problem. The Montreal Protocol was a landmark international agreement designed to protect the stratospheric ozone layer. The treaty was originally signed in 1987 and subsequently amended in 1990 and 1992. The protocol stipulated that the production of compounds that deplete ozone in the stratosphere, including chlorofluorocarbons, were to be phased  out by the year 2000.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The work of Dr. Rowland, Dr. Molina, and Dr. Crutzen was vital to the development of the Montreal Protocol, the reduction of ozone depleting compounds, and the restoration of our atmosphere. I applaud their work and ask that my colleagues support this resolution which thanks them for their important contributions to science.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400165" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of House Resolution 593, congratulating scientists F. Sherwood Rowland, Mario Molina and Paul Crutzen for their contribution to atmospheric chemistry, particularly the formation and decomposition of ozone. Their pioneering research on the effects of CFCs on the ozone layer in the early 1970s was the start of a nearly 15-year campaign that would include an overwhelming consumer reaction to products containing CFCs, a national ban on aerosols  and unparalleled international cooperation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Twenty years later, the Montreal Protocol has been described as one of the most successful international agreements to date. It is the ideal illustration of what can be accomplished when scientists, policymakers and industry work together toward a common goal. Uncertainty did not stop us from looking for alternative solutions. However, action was not taken until those uncertainties were addressed through further scientific research and until viable substitutes were available. Cooperation on environmental  problems requires that the outcome be beneficial for all parties. This was achieved through the Montreal Protocol.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I offer my thanks to these three scientists. The environmental consequences and economic impacts in terms of greater health costs and loss of crops and damage to vital species due to the use of CFCs could have been far worse if not for the work of F. Sherwood Rowland, Mario Molina, and Paul Crutzen.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I urge my colleagues to support House Resolution 593.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400356" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I am the proud sponsor of <bill type="hr" number="593">H. Res. 593</bill>, a resolution congratulating the scientists whose work led to the Montreal Protocol on Substances that Deplete the Ozone Layer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Montreal Protocol is an international treaty that has been a critical part of the global commitment to improving the environment for ourselves and future generations. The treaty was a science driven effort to address a specific human action that has real consequences on the ozone layer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Yesterday, September 16th was the 20th anniversary of when the Montreal Protocol was first made available for signature. Although the benefits of the Montreal Protocol are being realized worldwide, the science that led to its implementation is entirely homegrown.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1973, scientists Sherwood Rowland and Mario Molina began their work at the fantastic University of California, Irvine, in Orange County, California. Rowland and Molina researched the depletion of stratospheric ozone by chlorofluorocarbon gases. These CFC gases were used worldwide in many products as refrigerants and aerosol propellants. Like all scientific endeavors, Rowland and Molina started with a hypothesis. They realized that CFCs are very stable compounds in the lower atmosphere. Because  of that, the compounds could travel to the upper atmosphere and interact with other compounds that are critical to the upper atmosphere.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By June of 1974 the hypothesis of Rowland and Molina was confirmed by their own research; CFCs are broken down by ultra-violet radiation in the upper atmosphere and then interact with and deplete ozone molecules. Their work was published in the scientific journal Nature to a mixed reaction because CFCs were considered by many to be a wonder product that had many benefits and no negative consequences. However, a mixed reaction to a published article is not necessarily a bad thing since it is necessary  for published scientific work to hold up under intense peer review and scrutiny.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The National Academy of Sciences began testing the work of Rowland and Molina and by 1976, the Academy released a report that confirmed the scientific credibility of the ozone depletion hypothesis. To the credit of this institution, Congress acted quickly in response to the confirmed work of Rowland and Molina.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1978 the use of CFCs in aerosol propellants was banned in the United States. With the United States leading the way and significant studies being conducted by the Dutch scientist Paul Crutzen, the Montreal Protocol came into full force on September 17, 1987. To date, 191 nations have signed on to the Montreal Protocol.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1995, Rowland, Molina, and Crutzen were awarded the Nobel Prize for chemistry in recognition of their work--this was quite an achievement for UC Irvine as well. On the twentieth anniversary of the Montreal Protocol, let's once again recognize the homegrown science of Sherwood Rowland, Mario Molina, and Paul Crutzen that has had an ongoing and significant positive impact on the Earth's ecosystem.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to join me in supporting <bill type="hr" number="593">H. Res. 593</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400165" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400177" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no further requests for time, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Indiana (Mr. Hill) that the House suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, <bill type="hr" number="593">H. Res. 593</bill>.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the resolution was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
