<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1185768000" ordinal="37" title="DOLPH S. BRISCOE, JR. POST OFFICE BUILDING">
  <narrative>DOLPH S. BRISCOE, JR. POST OFFICE BUILDING -- (House of Representatives - July 30, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H8839]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform be discharged from further consideration of the bill (<bill type="h" number="2688">H.R. 2688</bill>) to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 103 South Getty Street in Uvalde, Texas, as the "Dolph S. Briscoe, Jr. Post Office Building," and ask for its immediate consideration in the House.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Illinois?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the bill, as follows</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="2688">H.R. 2688</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. DOLPH S. BRISCOE, JR. POST OFFICE BUILDING.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Designation.--The facility of the United States Postal Service located at 103 South Getty Street in Uvalde, Texas, shall be known and designated as the `Dolph S. Briscoe, Jr. Post Office Building'.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) References.--Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the facility referred to in subsection (a) shall be deemed to be a reference to the `Dolph S. Briscoe, Jr. Post Office Building'.</narrative>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>Amendment offered by Mr. Davis of Illinois</narrative>
  <narrative> Strike all after the enacting clause and insert the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. DOLPH BRISCOE, JR. POST OFFICE BUILDING.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Designation.--The facility of the United States Postal Service located at 103 South Getty Street in Uvalde, Texas, shall be known and designated as the "Dolph Briscoe, Jr. Post Office Building".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) References.--Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the facility referred to in subsection (a) shall be deemed to be a reference to the "Dolph Briscoe, Jr. Post Office Building".</narrative>
  <narrative>The amendment was agreed to</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, Mr. Dolph Briscoe was born on April 23, 1923 in Uvalde, Texas. He graduated from the University of Texas in 1942 and then served in the Army during World War II. After he returned from the war, he served in the Texas legislature from 1949 through 1957. He then left politics to manage his family's ranching and business interests.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1974, Mr. Briscoe was elected governor of Texas as a conservative, pro-business Democrat. He was one of the few governors to enact a balanced budget without raising or creating new taxes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Currently, Mr. Briscoe continues to be active in the agricultural community as a rancher in Uvalde and serves his community as the Senior Chairman of the First State Bank of Uvalde.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I commend my colleague Representative CIRO RODRIGUEZ for introducing this legislation and urge the swift passage of this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill was ordered to be engrossed and read a third time, was read the third time, and passed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The title was amended so as to read: "A bill to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 103 South Getty Street in Uvalde, Texas, as the `Dolph Briscoe, Jr. Post Office Building'.".</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
