<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1181145609" ordinal="42" title="GREEN ENERGY EDUCATION ACT OF 2007">
  <speaking speaker="400630" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="1716">H.R. 1716</bill>) to authorize higher education curriculum development and graduate training in advanced energy and green building technologies, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Lipinski) and the gentleman from Texas (Mr. McCaul) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400630" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and to include extraneous material on <bill type="h" number="1716">H.R. 1716</bill>, the bill now under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Illinois?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400630" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="1716">H.R. 1716</bill>, the Green Energy Education Act of 2007. I'd like to thank Mr. McCaul and Mr. Hill for their leadership on this important legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill authorizes the Department of Energy to contribute funds to the National Science Foundation's successful Integrative Graduate Education and Research Traineeship program, known as IGERT. IGERT awards prepare doctoral students by integrating research and education in innovative ways that are tailored to the unique requirement of newly emerging interdisciplinary fields and new career options.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many future green energy technologies, such as thin film solar technologies, will require interdisciplinary teams of scientists and engineers such as those trained under the IGERT program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill also authorizes the Department of Energy's high-performance-building technology programs to contribute to the National Science Foundation's ongoing curriculum development activities with the goal of improving the ability of engineers and architects to design and construct high-performance buildings.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Innovative technologies, coupled with a whole-buildings approach that optimizes interactions among building systems and components, enable buildings to use considerably less energy, while also helping to meet national goals for sustainable development, environmental protection and energy security.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The high-performance, or green, building movement is growing rapidly, but it is still a very small slice of the multibillion dollar building industry; and there's a real gap in university level education and training for the next generation of green building professionals. This bill helps address that gap.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In summary, this bill addresses a critical need to provide resources to universities to update their curricula and research efforts in alternative energy and high-performance buildings, and it improves coordination between the Department of Energy and the National Science Foundation in achieving this goal.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I'm pleased to support <bill type="h" number="1716">H.R. 1716</bill>, the Green Energy Education Act of 2007. Again, I want to commend Mr. McCaul and Mr. Hill for this important legislation; and I urge my colleagues to support <bill type="h" number="1716">H.R. 1716</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400654" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself as much time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to first thank Mr. Lipinski and my colleagues on both sides of the aisle for their strong support of this bill, which I introduced in the last Congress; and I'm pleased to see it get to the House floor in this Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The National Academies' Rising Above the Gathering Storm report echoed the call of many in the academic and business community for greater need to recruit and develop scientific and engineering talent to work on solving problems of national need.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Like many Members of Congress, I'm concerned about America's dependence on foreign sources of energy. Our reliance on imported energy only serves to increase our vulnerability to both external events and the actions of regimes that are, in many cases, openly hostile to the interests of the United States. One of the ways we can reduce the need for energy imports is to use our energy more efficiently.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Buildings consume more energy than any other sector of the economy, including industry and transportation. According to the U.S. Department of Energy, American buildings consume 39 percent of our Nation's primary energy and 70 percent of electricity. However, energy efficient building practices are not being fully utilized, in  part because of a lack of awareness about energy efficient technologies and design practices among building professionals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is why I introduced the Green Energy Education Act. This legislation authorizes the Department of Energy to partner with the National Science Foundation to support graduate education and curriculum development to advance DOE's broad energy technology development mission. Working through NSF, DOE will help develop the next generation of engineers and architects to produce buildings incorporating the latest in energy efficient technologies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In order to reduce the likelihood of duplicative and wasteful programs, this bill also allows the Department of Energy and the National Science Foundation to combine their efforts to find workable solutions to the issues surrounding building efficiency that then can be transferred to the marketplace.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Specifically, <bill type="h" number="1716">H.R. 1716</bill> will authorize DOE's Office of Science and applied energy technology programs to contribute funds to the NSF's successful Integrative Graduate Education and Research Traineeship program, which is already doing great work in this area.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill also authorizes the DOE to contribute to NSF's curriculum development activities in order to improve the ability of engineers and architects to design and construct more efficient and durable buildings.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this important step towards increasing America's energy independence.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400630" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this is another great effort that we are making, another important step in helping to reduce our energy consumption in this country. It's critical for national security, our economic security and to combat global climate change, and certainly energy efficient buildings, great work is being done in this, and much more work needs to be done.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have seen at the Department of Energy lab the work that is being done on some of this. I think much more needs to be done. This bill will help to provide these opportunities for more students, more people to learn about what it takes to make our buildings more energy efficient.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, I commend Mr. McCaul and Mr. Hill for this bill, and I urge my colleagues to pass this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400177" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, today the House will consider <bill type="h" number="1716">H.R. 1716</bill>, the Green Energy Education Act. As the lead Democratic sponsor of this bill, I am pleased that it has moved so quickly through committee. I believe its rapid movement onto the floor of the House for a vote is indicative of the bill's importance and timely subject matter.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1716">H.R. 1716</bill> promotes the design and construction of energy efficient buildings by authorizing the Department of Energy to partner with the National Science Foundation (NSF) in support of multidisciplinary graduate education and curriculum development activities that will enhance the DOE's broad energy technology development mission. By working with the NSF, DOE will help develop the next generation of engineers and architects to work effectively together to produce buildings and incorporating the  latest in energy efficient technologies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Buildings in the U.S. consume a disproportionate share of our energy and electricity. We must do something to make our buildings more energy efficient and friendly to the environment. In fact, buildings in the U.S. consume more energy than any other sector of the country, including industry and transportation. According to 2003 U.S. Department of Energy (DOE) statistics, U.S. buildings consume 39 percent of our nation's primary energy and 70 percent of electricity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We need to do everything we can to address the harmful things we are doing to the environment. This bill is a step in that direction--making buildings more energy efficient and less stressful on our energy and electrical supplies. And, it will save businesses considerable sums of money in the long run.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge all of my colleagues to vote for this important bill and take a step forward in easing our dependence on foreign and harmful energy sources.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400204" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="1716">H.R. 1716</bill>, the Green Energy Education Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, "green energy" is defined as energy that is produced and used in ways that lessen air pollution and other environmental impacts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An investment in green energy education will benefit our Nation in important ways. It is good for the environment, because it reduces environmental impacts of the production and delivery of energy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Green energy also reduces harmful greenhouse emissions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1716">H.R. 1716</bill> directs the Department of Energy to contribute funds to the National Science Foundation for the Integrative Graduate Education and Research Traineeship program. This program is important in supporting graduate education related to green energy projects.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also supports energy technology research and development for high tech buildings and for educational activities to teach students how to improve building design that is not harmful to the environment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I support <bill type="h" number="1716">H.R. 1716</bill> and urge my colleagues to support it also.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400630" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Lipinski) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="1716">H.R. 1716</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400654" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this question will be postponed.</chair>
</record>
