<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1182182403" ordinal="32" title="PROVIDING FOR EARMARK REFORM">
  <speaking speaker="400378" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Rules be discharged from further consideration of the resolution (<bill type="hr" number="491">H. Res. 491</bill>) providing for earmark reform, and ask for its immediate consideration in the House.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the resolution.</narrative>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from New York?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400115" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, reserving the right to object, I would simply ask my very distinguished Chair for an explanation of exactly what it is that we're doing here.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am happy to yield to the distinguished Chair of the Committee on Rules under my reservation, Madam Speaker.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400378" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What this measure does is absolutely guarantee that any earmark in a conference report that has not been passed in the House will be subject to a point of order even though the Rules Committee may have protected against all points of order.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400115" topic="">
    <paragraph>If I may, under my reservation, Madam Speaker, I would just like to make sure that we have in place a provision now, as was agreed on last week, that will ensure that the rights of Members, when it comes to raising a point of order, are maintained when it comes to appropriations bills.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would say, Madam Speaker, that I believe this is a very good start. My personal preference would have been that we could have gone back to the provision that we had last year to allow the same kind of protection for earmarks when it comes to both authorization and tax bills. And I hope very much, Madam Speaker, that we are going to have an opportunity to work together. I look forward to working with the distinguished Chair of the  Committee on Rules  and the leadership teams on both sides of the aisle to ensure that we can in fact pursue further transparency, openness, accountability and enforceability when it comes to the issue of earmarks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With that, I withdraw my reservation, Madam Speaker.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from New York?</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the resolution, as follows:</narrative>
</record>
