<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1174665652" ordinal="22" title="AUTHORIZING THE CLERK TO MAKE CORRECTIONS IN ENGROSSMENT OF H.R. 1227, GULF COAST HURRICANE HOUSING RECOVERY ACT OF 2007">
  <speaking speaker="400140" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent to correct a clerical error in the passage of the recommittal amendment to <bill type="h" number="1227">H.R. 1227</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Massachusetts?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, reserving the right to object, could the gentleman explain his request?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400140" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I will explain it. We had talked to members of the minority. In the engrossment of <bill type="h" number="1227">H.R. 1227</bill>, the Clerk made some clerical errors. We were notified; the staff of the Committee on Financial Services talked to the minority staff. This is a request to correct some errors that were made in the recommit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is not in any favor to us. If you want the thing uncorrected, go ahead and object.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>If I may, Mr. Speaker, I am just not recalling that.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400140" topic="">
    <paragraph>Well, I don't expect the gentleman to recall it. I did not recall it either. We didn't know they made clerical errors. They didn't tell us they made clerical errors.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, it is an innocent question. And the clerical error was?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400140" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, if the gentleman would yield to me, I don't know what the clerical error was. We were notified that there was an error in the transcription. We did not know what the error was. Members of our staff spoke to the minority staff on the Financial Services Committee and explained it. I don't know how they mistyped it. I wasn't there when they did it. I don't know what the clerical error is. I wasn't particularly concerned. We thought it was routine.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If the minority wants the bill to go uncorrected, that is the minority's choice. We did speak to the staff beforehand.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>Would the gentleman be willing to withdraw the unanimous consent request?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400140" topic="">
    <paragraph>I will withdraw it, but I am not sticking around to make it again.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I withdraw the request, and let it stand uncorrected.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The request is withdrawn.</chair>
</record>
