<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1196960402" ordinal="52" title="IN HONOR OF THE HONORABLE HENRY HYDE">
  <narrative>IN HONOR OF THE HONORABLE HENRY HYDE -- (House of Representatives - December 06, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H14453]</narrative>
  <chair> Under a previous order of the House, the gentleman from Florida (Mr. Mica) is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400273" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker and my colleagues, one of the greatest voices to ever be heard in these Chambers has been lost to the ages. I rise today to pay tribute to my good friend, a great American and my former colleague, Henry Hyde. Tomorrow in Illinois, one of the State's most capable and eloquent Members of Congress will be laid to rest.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It was my distinct honor to meet Henry Hyde, to serve with Henry Hyde and to call Henry Hyde my friend. In this House Chamber over the past 150 years, there have been many who have spoken. I submit that if you had the privilege to hear Henry Hyde speak here, you were indeed most fortunate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In this House of Representatives over the past several centuries, there have been many distinguished individuals. I submit that not only was Henry Hyde one of the most distinguished, but also one of the most appreciated individuals, one of the finest gentlemen, one of the greatest Americans to serve in this, the people's House.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Whether he was defending the unborn or relating his position to us on any matter before this House, Henry Hyde always spoke with dignity, conviction, principle and eloquence. When Henry Hyde addressed this House, its Members and all Americans listened. While everyone who knew Henry Hyde can tell us a very special story and personal experience about knowing Henry Hyde, there are several memories that I will always fondly cherish and remember.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I recall when Henry came to my district, came to my home in Florida. I will never forget when Henry Hyde stopped me, actually in this aisleway, here on the floor of the House, and in that aisleway he complimented me on my remarks that day. Imagine, Henry Hyde, the master orator, praising such common words. How honored I was by his compliment to so junior a Member on that day. There are many other stories I can tell about Henry Hyde and I know we can all share the other stories, but let me tell  you in closing to relate one of my last memories of this great man.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I had the privilege of traveling with Henry to the United States European interparliamentary meetings overseas, and on my last trip with Henry to one of these meetings, one of the last times that Henry Hyde as I recall him serving as chairman of the International Relations Committee, we were flying together with others across the Atlantic to make our next day's meeting. I woke up in the middle of the night and everyone in the cabin on the plane was sleeping, with one exception, and that was Henry  Hyde. Some of you may recall Henry had been quite ill towards the end of his service. He required assistance to walk, and I knew how uncomfortable and how difficult it was for him to travel. But here was Henry Hyde so committed to his responsibility, while in such great personal pain and discomfort that he could not rest, he had to sit up</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To Henry's wife and family, and on behalf of all the people of the Seventh Congressional District of Florida, and personally, I extend my deepest sympathies.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
