<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1193068802" ordinal="21" title="MESA VERDE NATIONAL PARK BOUNDARY EXPANSION ACT OF 2007">
  <narrative>MESA VERDE NATIONAL PARK BOUNDARY EXPANSION ACT OF 2007 -- (House of Representatives - October 22, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H11786]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="783">H.R. 783</bill>) to modify the boundary of Mesa Verde National Park, and for other purposes, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="783">H.R. 783</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "Mesa Verde National Park Boundary Expansion Act of 2007".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. FINDINGS; PURPOSES.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Findings.--Congress finds that--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) on June 29, 1906, Mesa Verde National Park was established as the first national park in the United States to preserve the works of humanity;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) on September 6, 1978, Mesa Verde National Park became the first World Heritage Site designated in the United States; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) Mesa Verde National Park protects some of the best preserved and notable archeological sites of the ancient Puebloan culture that flourished in the southwestern United States from approximately 600-1300, including the elaborate stone villages in the sheltered alcoves of the canyon walls referred to as "cliff dwellings".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Purposes.--The purposes of this Act are--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) to modify the boundary of Mesa Verde National Park--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) to protect the archeological sites located on property adjacent to the Park boundary;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) to extend and expand the knowledge and understanding of the ancient Puebloan culture, a major influence in the development of the southwestern United States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) to protect from potential development the scenic and biological value of the pinyon-juniper covered hills that--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) border the Park; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) are in full view of the Park entrance road; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (D) to protect the largest recorded colony of the globally imperiled Gray's Townsend Daisy, to ensure continuation of a major wildlife corridor, and to protect important habitat for wildlife; and &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) to provide greater opportunities to visitors, researchers, and surrounding communities to understand and appreciate the natural environment of Mesa Verde and the contributions of the ancient Puebloan culture to the region by providing the land required to construct a contemporary museum collections storage facility and visitor orientation center.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 3. DEFINITIONS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; In this Act:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) MAP.--The term "map" means the map entitled "Mesa Verde National Park Proposed Boundary Adjustment", numbered 307/80,180, and dated March 1, 2007.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) PARK.--The term "Park" means the Mesa Verde National Park in the State of Colorado.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) SECRETARY.--The term "Secretary" means the Secretary of the Interior.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 4. MESA VERDE NATIONAL PARK.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Acquisition of Land.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) IN GENERAL.--The Secretary may acquire the land or an interest in the land described in subsection (b) for addition to the Park.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) MEANS.--An acquisition of land under paragraph (1) may be made by donation, purchase from a willing seller with donated or appropriated funds, or exchange.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Description of Land.--The land referred to in subsection (a)(1) is the approximately 360 acres of land adjacent to the Park, as generally depicted on the map.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Availability of Map.--The map shall be on file and available for inspection in the appropriate offices of the National Park Service.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (d) Boundary Modification.--The boundary of the Park shall be revised to reflect the acquisition of the land under subsection (a).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (e) Administration.--The Secretary shall administer any land or interest in land acquired under subsection (a)(1) as part of the Park in accordance with the laws (including regulations) applicable to the Park.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 5. AUTHORIZATION OF APPROPRIATIONS.</narrative>
  <narrative> There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out this Act. &lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) and the gentleman from Texas (Mr. Gohmert) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Arizona.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Arizona?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, <bill type="h" number="783">H.R. 783</bill> authorizes a boundary expansion at Mesa Verde National Park in southwestern Colorado of approximately 362 acres. Mesa Verde National Park, established in 1906, contains the most extensive concentration of cliff-dwellings in the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="783">H.R. 783</bill> authorizes the acquisition of two parcels of the land that border the park. One parcel is in full view of the park's entrance road and contains important archaeological sites, an ancient forest, and the largest known population of a globally imperiled plant. This parcel is currently zoned for a subdivision, but the owners would prefer to protect the property through inclusion in the park.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The second parcel is currently owned by a park partner, the Mesa Verde Foundation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>The foundation intends to donate the parcel to the park for the development of a visitor information center and museum collection facility but cannot do so until the park boundary is expanded.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the administration has testified in support of this legislation, the Natural Resources Committee approved the legislation with a minor amendment by unanimous consent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to acknowledge, at this point, the hard work of the bill's sponsor, Representative JOHN SALAZAR, in bringing this important legislation forward. We support this bill and urge its adoption by the House today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400651" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, once again, I think my friend from Arizona has adequately explained the bill. We support it and I have no objections, and even though it's unusual here in Congress to yield back any time, we do so yield back our time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield such time as he may consume to the sponsor of this legislation, Representative JOHN SALAZAR.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400620" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I first want to thank Chairman Grijalva for assistance in moving this important piece of legislation forward.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I introduced <bill type="h" number="783">H.R. 783</bill>, along with my friend and colleague MARK UDALL from Colorado, to expand the boundary of Mesa Verde National Park. Mesa Verde National Park protects the most notable and best-preserved cliff dwellings in this country. The park is also vital to the economy of southwest Colorado.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Established by Congress in June 1906, Mesa Verde National Park was the first cultural park to be set aside in the National Park System.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over 1,400 years ago, the Puebloans settled at Mesa Verde where they built elaborate stone communities in the protected alcoves of the canyon, calling it home for over 700 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When President Teddy Roosevelt signed the law establishing Mesa Verde, he claimed that it was to "preserve the works of man."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The establishment of Mesa Verde set off intense public interest in preserving other such sites in the American southwest and nationwide. Today, the towns of Cortez and Mancos, in Montezuma County, Colorado, rely heavily on tourism from Mesa Verde National Park.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="783">H.R. 783</bill> authorizes the National Park Service to acquire two critically important plots at the gateway to Mesa Verde National Park. One is a 324-acre tract of private land to be acquired from the Henneman family. I want to credit the Henneman family, as they remained steadfast in their termination to see the property included in this park, and I'd like to thank them for their dedication.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The second plot of land is a 38-acre tract to be donated to the National Park Service by the Mesa Verde Foundation. With passage of <bill type="h" number="783">H.R. 783</bill>, the National Park Service will have the authority to accept the generous donation of this parcel from the foundation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In keeping with the longstanding tradition of preserving the resources and cultural heritage at Mesa Verde National Park, <bill type="h" number="783">H.R. 783</bill> will greatly enhance the visitor experience at Mesa Verde for future generations of Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge the House to adopt this important piece of legislation, and I urge my colleagues to someday come out and visit Mesa Verde National Park.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="783">H.R. 783</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the bill, as amended, was passed.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
