<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1184212800" ordinal="6" title="WELCOMING RABBI ELLEN S. WOLINTZ-FIELDS">
  <narrative>WELCOMING RABBI ELLEN S. WOLINTZ-FIELDS -- (House of Representatives - July 12, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H7659]</narrative>
  <chair> Without objection, the gentleman from New Jersey (Mr. Saxton) is recognized for 1 minute.</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400359" topic="">
    <paragraph>Thank you very much, Mr. Speaker.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I am pleased to take this opportunity to acknowledge the occasion of Rabbi Ellen Wolintz-Fields serving as today's guest chaplain. After that opening prayer, I might say that it is easy to see why our community is so graciously and well served by the rabbi. Her 3-year-old daughter, Cameron Elizabeth, is also with us here today, and we want to welcome her here as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The opportunity for having visiting chaplain guests is very special as it allows religious leaders from different faiths to begin our day of legislative duty.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On August 1, Rabbi Wolintz-Fields will celebrate her first anniversary as rabbi of Congregation B'Nai Israel in Toms River, New Jersey. Since 1950, this synagogue has served as a place of worship and guidance for teachings of Conservative Judaism while offering multiple support and volunteer services for our community. Today, the rabbi has over 400 families in her congregation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Throughout her time both studying and serving, the rabbi has received various awards and recognitions for her contributions to preserving the Jewish faith. She is a recipient of the Goldstein Prize for Jewish History and the Rosalyn Gooen Milians Education Award.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While she has numerous noteworthy achievements, the Rabbi is particularly proud of her family. She is married to Jonathan Fields and, in addition to Cameron Elizabeth, they have a 1 1/2 -year-old son, Coby Dov.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I appreciate the rabbi taking time from her busy schedule to visit Washington, DC in order to give the opening prayer in the people's House, and I am glad I had the occasion to assist her to do so.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
