<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1167946162" ordinal="4" title="SWEARING IN OF MEMBERS">
  <chair> According to precedent, the Chair will swear in the Members-elect en masse.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400184" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRY">
    <paragraph>I have a parliamentary inquiry, Madam Speaker.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman may state his inquiry.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400184" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRY">
    <paragraph>In light of the fact that there are nonpartisan and partisan lawsuits under way with regard to Florida's 13th Congressional District and that the votes of 18,000 voters were not recorded on the paperless electronic voting machines in an election decided by only 369 votes, may I ask for the record whether a notice of contest has been filed with the Clerk on behalf of Christine Jennings pursuant to law and what effect, if any, today's proceedings have on the pending contests?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Chair is advised by the Clerk that a notice of contest pursuant to statute, section 382 of title 2, United States Code, has been filed with the Clerk. Under section 5 of article I of the Constitution and the statute, the House remains the judge of the elections of its Members. The seating of this Member-elect is entirely without prejudice to the contest over the final right to that seat that is pending under the statute and will be reviewed in the ordinary course in the Committee  on House Administration.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400184" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRY">
    <paragraph>I thank the Speaker.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400328" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRY">
    <paragraph>Parliamentary inquiry, Madam Speaker.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman may state his inquiry.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400328" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRY">
    <paragraph>Am I correct, Madam Speaker, that the gentleman from Florida (Mr. Buchanan) has been certified by the Secretary of State as duly elected from the 13th District of Florida?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman is correct.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400328" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRY">
    <paragraph>I thank the Speaker.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> If the Members-elect will rise, the Chair will now administer the oath of office.</chair>
</record>
