<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1208966402" ordinal="36" title="ROCKY MARCIANO POST OFFICE BUILDING">
  <narrative>ROCKY MARCIANO POST OFFICE BUILDING -- (House of Representatives - April 23, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H2562]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="5528">H.R. 5528</bill>) to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 120 Commercial Street in Brockton, Massachusetts, as the "Rocky Marciano Post Office Building".</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="5528">H.R. 5528</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. ROCKY MARCIANO POST OFFICE BUILDING.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Designation.--The facility of the United States Postal Service located at 120 Commercial Street in Brockton, Massachusetts, shall be known and designated as the "Rocky Marciano Post Office Building".</narrative>
  <narrative> (b) References.--Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the facility referred to in subsection (a) shall be deemed to be a reference to the "Rocky Marciano Post Office Building".&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Davis) and the gentleman from Virginia (Mr. Davis) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Illinois.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days in which to revise and extend their remarks.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Illinois?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, it is my pleasure to yield such time as he might consume to the gentleman who introduced this legislation, Representative Lynch from Massachusetts.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Mr. LYNCH asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400249" topic="">
    <paragraph>Thank you, Chairman Davis, for yielding me this time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, <bill type="h" number="5528">H.R. 5528</bill> will designate the United States Postal Service facility located at 120 Commercial Street in the city of Brockton, Massachusetts, as the "Rocky Marciano Post Office Building."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At the outset, I would like to thank the members of the Marciano family and the public officials and the residents in the city of Brockton for their dedication in honoring Rocky Marciano, who was a remarkable champion and citizen, through the naming of this Commercial Street post office.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In particular, I would like to note the contributions made by Rocky Marciano's younger brother, Peter Marciano, Sr., also Brockton Mayor Jim Harrington, my good friend, his staff assistant, Donna Daily, Senator Bob Creedon, Representative Tom Kennedy, Chris Canavan and Gerry Creedon, as well as the city council, led by City Councilman Mike Brady.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>In addition, I would like to note the support of the Brockton High School's legendary football coach, Armond Columbo; Brockton resident Mark Casieri, who owns Rocky Marciano's boyhood home on Dover Street; Goody Petronelli, the iconic fight trainer and owner of downtown Brockton's renowned Petronelli Brothers Gym; and last but not least, Charlie Tartaglia, who is the owner of the historic George's Cafe on Belmont Street and whose walls and whose institution there serves as a pictorial shrine  to the sport of boxing and also to the life of Rocky Marciano and the city of Brockton.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, Rocco Francis Marchegiano, better known as Rocky Marciano, was born and raised in a working class family in the city of Brockton, Massachusetts. He attended Brockton High School, and from his induction in 1943 to his discharge in 1946, he served this country proudly as a United States Army private with the 150th Combat Engineers. It was during his Army service that Rocky Marciano first discovered his love for boxing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And as noted in Mr. Marciano's official biography, "There were those who didn't think much would become of the 190 pound heavyweight from Brockton in the early days." Nevertheless, during his subsequent professional heavyweight boxing career, Rocky Marciano, nicknamed the "Brockton Blockbuster," amassed a professional record of 49 wins, no draws, and no losses, with 43 knockouts. Rocky Marciano held boxing's heavyweight title from 1952 until 1956, and, notably, he remains the only heavyweight  champion in boxing history to retire undefeated.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, Rocky Marciano's legacy extends beyond the boxing ring. His achievements, his skill, and relentless work ethic and determination made Rocky Marciano the personification of what is best and proudest in the city of Brockton and in this country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As noted by sportswriter Ed Fitzgerald in a January, 1953, SPORT magazine article, "All Brockton came to love him and always will ..... He put the city on the map; he gave its citizens a new interest in life."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In his honor Brockton is commonly referred to as the "City of Champions," and in his footsteps, the city has borne other great champions, including former boxing middleweight champion Marvin Hagler and also the celebrated Brockton High School Boxers football team, who won back-to-back State championships in 2004 and 2005.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would like to thank Chairman Davis and his subcommittee staff, as well as Denise Wilson of the full committee, for their assistance with this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to join me in supporting <bill type="h" number="5528">H.R. 5528</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400098" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="5528">H.R. 5528</bill>, Representative Lynch's legislation to name a post office in Brockton, Massachusetts, on behalf its favorite son, Rocky Marciano.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the men who occupied the opposite corner for Rocky Marciano's 49 professional fights probably would agree on only one thing about him: that he was a magnificent fighter. In a career that lasted a little more than 8 years, he won all 49 of his pro fights. He still to this day is the only heavyweight to finish undefeated. He won 43 by knockouts, 9 of those in the first round. None of his first 16 fights lasted even five rounds. Only once did he win on a split decision, and only once  did he have to go the full 15 rounds to subdue an opponent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>His nose looked like a piece of cork, his eyes like black stilettos angrily firing out at his foes. His hands were like hammers, pounding relentlessly on the hapless men who opposed him. At 5&#xAC;10&#xAC;&#xAC;, 185 pounds, he was smaller and slower than most heavyweights. But what he lacked in size and speed, he made up for in his desire and toughness. And that's why the crowd loved him.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It was said that a Marciano knockout blow packed as much punch as an armor-piercing bullet; that it equaled  the force required to lift a 1,000 pound block 1 foot off the ground. It was enough, literally, to turn heads.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But what is not well known is that this hardscrabble Italian, who fought just twice outside the Eastern seaboard, was a genuinely good guy. He served in the Army, lent much of his winnings to friends, and worked for charitable endeavors. Ultimately, he died in the plane crash en route to give a speech for the son of a friend.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rocky Marciano was a self-made man. He grew strong on homemade weightlifting equipment and tough on a heavy bag made out of an old mail sack that hung from a tree in his backyard. As his plaque says at the International Boxing Hall of Fame: To define Rocky Marciano's career, one only needs to know 49-0, 49 fights, 49 wins.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With that, Mr. Speaker, I urge passage of this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, as a member of the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, I am pleased to present for consideration <bill type="h" number="5528">H.R. 5528</bill>, which seeks to commemorate the life of Rocky Marciano, the undefeated boxer from Brockton, Massachusetts, by naming a United States Post Office in his honor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rocky Marciano's story serves as a testament to the American Dream and the endless possibilities that line every street in our great country. His accomplishments remind us of the fact that the United States of America is a place where a poor and disadvantaged young man growing up in the rough neighborhoods of Brockton, Massachusetts, can aspire and achieve greatness.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="5528">H.R. 5528</bill> was introduced by Representative STEPHEN LYNCH of Massachusetts on March 4, 2008, and was considered by and reported from the Oversight Committee on March 13, 2008, by voice vote. The measure has the support of the nine members of the Massachusetts congressional delegation and upon passage will pay tribute to a man who demonstrated the limitless potential that lies within each human being. The obstacles Rocky Marciano had to overcome in life, whether they were physical, financial,  or spiritual, provide inspiration to us all.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rocco Francis Marchegiano was born in Brockton, Massachusetts, on September 1, 1923. Weighing 12 pounds and sporting a robust frame, it was obvious, even as a newborn, that Rocky Marciano was not a pushover. Yet his luck was not as healthy as his physique. At 18 months Rocky contracted pneumonia and would have perished were it not for his remarkably strong constitution. Thus starting from a tender age, Rocky learned how to fight back to overcome daunting odds.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>His first introduction to boxing came when he and some friends set up a stuffed mail sack in Marchegiano's backyard to serve as a boxing bag. Now, as chairman of the Federal Workforce, D.C., and Postal Service Subcommittee, I wouldn't normally approve of using mail sacks in such an abusive way. But in Rocky's case, I must say that his resourcefulness is quite admirable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At age 20 Rocky was drafted into the U.S. Army to fight overseas in the European theater. After only 8 months, he was flown back to the States where he awaited transfer to the Pacific in Fort Lewis, Washington. While stationed at Fort Lewis, he volunteered to represent his unit in a ring of amateur fights and eventually won the boxing tournament in 1946. From that point onward, sports history would be forever changed and Rocky Marciano would begin his long career as world champion until he announced  retirement in April of 1956.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On the eve of his 46th birthday in 1969, Marciano was aboard a small private plane that went down on its way to Des Moines, Iowa. In memory of Rocky Marciano and in honor of his accomplishment, I urge swift passage of <bill type="h" number="5528">H.R. 5528</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Davis) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="5528">H.R. 5528</bill>.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the bill was passed.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
