<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1185985401" ordinal="59" title="SAFETEA-LU TECHNICAL CORRECTIONS ACT OF 2007">
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="OBERSTAR" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="3248">H.R. 3248</bill>) to amend the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users to make technical corrections, and for other purposes.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Minnesota (Mr. Oberstar) and the gentleman from Florida (Mr. Mica) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="OBERSTAR" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members  may have 5 legislative days within which to revise and extend their remarks and to include extraneous and tabular material.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Minnesota?</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="OBERSTAR" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this bill is one that has not only bipartisan but bicameral agreement among all the committees of jurisdiction over the Nation's highways, highway safety and public transportation programs. Our Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, the Senate Committees on Environment and Public Works, Banking and Housing and Urban Affairs and Commerce, Science and Transportation, all of us met, discussed, agreed on these technical corrections.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In fact, in the last Congress, we were so much in agreement that we passed this bill five times in the House. They passed it a couple of times in the other body. But somehow it just never got to the point of being sent to the President.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We took it up again this year. We were going to include it in the Water Resources Development Act, but at the last moment, technical glitches arose in the other body.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So we are taking it up separately in this body in order to pass it and send it over to the other body. Hopefully, they will be able to act on it before the end of the week and send it to the President for the President's signature.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are over 400 technical corrections, really, truly technical in nature, waiting for 2 years to be adjusted and to be enacted. Tonight we can do that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="MICA" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, first of all, I would like to thank Chairman Oberstar, Ranking Member Duncan, Mr. DeFazio, who is the chairman of the Highways and Transit Subcommittee, everyone, including staff, for their work on this important technical corrections bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am pleased to rise tonight and voice my support for <bill type="h" number="3248">H.R. 3248</bill> and encourage my colleagues to do the same. This, in fact, is the fourth time we have brought this bill to the floor in the past 18 months. It is imperative that we pass this measure and for the Senate to follow our lead and pass it as well. I think we have a pretty good agreement with the Senate to do just that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Once the President signs this legislation, SAFETEA-LU, which is the major transportation and highway transit funding bill that we passed less than 2 years ago, all the provisions of that will finally be able to accomplish what Congress set out to do. There are many minor errors, and that was a pretty massive bill, and there are some minor changes in policy, tweaks in policy and in Member projects in the SAFETEA-LU bill that we passed that need this technical correction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have heard from the Department of Transportation and also several State DOTs regarding fixes to different programs and also high-priority projects. I believe this bill tonight addresses most of the issues that have been brought to the attention of our committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill also makes critical corrections to the Federal Highway Research Program to ensure that the department can continue essential research programs, including the Future Strategic Highway Research Program and the University Transportation Center Research Program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also extends the deadline for the National Surface Transportation and Policy and Review Study Commission and corrects several drafting errors regarding the Magnetic Levitation Transportation Deployment Program. Extending the deadline on the National Transportation Surface Policy and Review Study Commission is very important, particularly as we take on in 2009 the important responsibility of putting in place another bill that will replace SAFETEA-LU to set our policy and projects and  transportation priorities for the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, it is important to note that this bill does not make any substantial policy changes to the SAFETEA-LU bill, but, again, it deals with technical corrections. Again, this bill corrects provisions that were not workable by the States or by the Department of Transportation. They have relayed their concerns and we have addressed them in this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It also is important to note that the Congressional Budget Office has scored this bill and estimates that, over the 2007-2012 period, this bill will reduce contract authority by $1 million and will increase receipts by less than $500,000.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is one purely technical correction that is not included in this package. SAFETEA-LU inadvertently changes certain regulations for trucks with a gross vehicle weight of less than 10,000 pounds. When Congress passed SAFETEA-LU, this change was not a policy change that Congress knew about or intended to make. If Congress wanted to make this change, we would have debated and discussed it. Rather, this was something we were not aware of, and this change has had, in effect, very serious unintended  consequences, especially for our small businesses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I had hoped to fix this problem with a technical fix. However, some groups who have benefited from this error have, unfortunately, prevented us from doing so tonight and in this legislation. It is unfortunate a policy change that no Member anticipated and voted on will not be corrected in this legislation tonight.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Despite this particular shortcoming and oversight, again, I am pleased to have worked with Chairman Oberstar, Ranking Member Duncan in revitalizing this very necessary technical corrections bill, and I hope my colleagues will join me in supporting the bill tonight.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="OBERSTAR" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself 1 minute to observe a very tragic occurrence that happened just 2 hours ago in Minneapolis.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bridge on Interstate 35 over the Mississippi River near the University of Minnesota collapsed just 2 hours ago, dropping at least eight cars and a truck in the water. A school bus that had just barely missed crashing into the water was damaged, and students on board were bloodied and injured.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>The crumbled wreckage of the bridge is on the east bank and in the water. The concrete roadway is in the river gorge. It is a 40-year-old bridge, and it is a tragic occurrence, and I make that observation during the midst of technical corrections as an indication of how vitally important it is for us to continue our vigilance on the integrity and condition of the Nation's roadways.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="MICA" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, at this time, I am very pleased to yield 3 minutes to one of the most distinguished Members of the House, a former Speaker of the House of Representatives, the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Hastert).</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="HASTERT" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I thank the ranking member, and I would like to ask the chairman of the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure if he would enter into a colloquy with me.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="OBERSTAR" of="">
    <paragraph>Of course.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="HASTERT" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I have been informed by the Illinois Department of Transportation that there may be some confusion regarding the intent of one of the Illinois projects included in SAFETEA-LU. Funding provided for project number 12 in section 1302(e) of SAFETEA-LU was intended to be for the construction of Route 34 in Illinois, including interchanges and other improvements.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Federal Highway Administration has told the Illinois Department of Transportation that the language currently in SAFETEA-LU may restrict the scope of the project to only funding interchange improvements, when the intent of the language was also to fund other improvements along the Route 34 corridor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a result, I would like to clarify the intent of the language and work with the chairman and the ranking member to make sure that the language interpreted by the FHWA is done correctly in this manner.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="OBERSTAR" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, if the gentleman would yield.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="HASTERT" of="">
    <paragraph>I would be happy to yield.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="OBERSTAR" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I recall very well when crafting SAFETEA-LU, the project that the gentleman has raised, it was never the  intention of the committee nor the intention of the language to restrict the scope of the project only to the interchange when it is clear from the thrust of the project that it was intended to cover other improvements along the Route 34 corridor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Along with Mr. Mica, I will work with the Speaker to make adjustments. It is a little late for us to get it into this bill. If we had known about it sufficiently in advance, we certainly could have made an adjustment. But there will be other vehicles where we will be able to accomplish that, and we will work with the gentleman.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="HASTERT" of="">
    <paragraph>Once again, I thank you and look forward to working with you and Mr. Mica on this matter.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="MICA" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself 30 seconds.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to reiterate for the Record that the issue that former Speaker Hastert has brought before the floor, it is my understanding that we did not intend to restrict the scope of the project to only funding for interchange improvements, and the intent of the language was to also fund the other improvements on Route 34, and we will work with the gentleman from Illinois to make certain that point is clarified.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="OBERSTAR" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 2 minutes to the gentleman from Oregon (Mr. DeFazio), the chairman of the Surface Transportation Subcommittee.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DeFAZIO" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It was just about 2 years ago this month that we were struggling with the final details of the SAFETEA-LU legislation, in my opinion the signature legislation of the last Congress, bipartisan legislation, to improve the transportation efficiency of the United States of America, investing nearly $300 billion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But, as good as the bill was, there were technical problems, and we are correcting those here; and, as good as that bill was, we must do better in the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As chairman of the subcommittee, I have already begun hearings looking toward the reauthorization which we would hope to have accomplished by the expiration of this legislation, October 1, 2009. We hope not to go through multiple continuations and extensions as we did in the last Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We also need to find new resources to better address the infrastructure needs of our country. The Bush administration's own Department of Transportation estimated before the consideration of the last bill that we needed $375 billion, not $283 billion, just to keep up with the deterioration and the growth needs of the country, as pointed out by the gentleman from Minnesota.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We need to deal with congestion to improve American's lives, to become more fuel efficient, and to deal with just-in-time delivery for our businesses, to become a better competitor in the international community. Other nations are investing much more. We must do better. This is an interim step as we correct the bill from the last Congress, and I look forward to working with both sides of the aisle as we develop the next bill for 2009.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="MICA" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I am delighted to yield at this time to the gentleman from Tennessee (Mr. Duncan). And, actually, he is our ranking member of the Highway Subcommittee and has done an incredible job on this and also leading the Highway Subcommittee and former chairman of Water Resources and former chairman of Aviation, and he should have handled this bill, but I am delighted to yield 3 minutes to Mr. Duncan.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DUNCAN" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I thank my good friend from Florida, the ranking member, for yielding me this time; and I thank him for giving me the privilege of serving as the ranking member of the Highway and Transit Subcommittee. It is a pleasure to work with him and Chairman Oberstar and with my good friend, Chairman Peter DeFazio, on the Highway and Transit Subcommittee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, <bill type="h" number="3248">H.R. 3248</bill> make technical corrections to the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users, or what we typically call SAFETEA-LU.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is the fourth time we have worked to finalize these technical corrections to SAFETEA-LU. During the 109th Congress, the House passed <bill type="h" number="5689">H.R. 5689</bill>, a bill to make technical corrections to SAFETEA-LU in June, 2006. During the summer and fall of 2006, we worked with the Senate to create the bipartisan <bill type="h" number="6233">H.R. 6233</bill>, which was a very similar product to the bill that we passed at the beginning of this Congress. Now we are trying again; and hopefully this bill, <bill type="h" number="3248">H.R. 3248</bill>, will go to the President for  his signature of this very necessary bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As my colleagues have said, this bill makes numerous technical corrections to the Federal Surface Transportation Programs authorized by SAFETEA-LU. The technical corrections included in this bill have been identified by the Department of Transportation and State DOTs and are mostly of a conforming nature or to correct drafting errors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The most important correction we are making is to strengthen the Federal Highway Research Program by ensuring the continuation of the legacy research programs carried out by the Department of Transportation. This research hopefully will lead to not only safer highways but also less congestion, which is very, very important to this Nation, that we work on that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The largest section of this bill is section 105, which makes changes to almost 350 of the high-priority projects in section 1702 of SAFETEA-LU. These changes address "broken" surface transportation projects, clarifying recipients and increasing certain project funding levels and decreasing others to achieve budget neutrality.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I especially appreciate the fact that Chairman Oberstar and Ranking Member Mica have allowed me to put in language that will allow the city of Knoxville to go forward with a very important transit center project; and, also, I am very pleased that we are rearranging some funding so that the very small town of Calhoun, Tennessee, in my district, can pave some roads. This is very, very important to them. So often we leave out the small towns in rural areas or they don't get nearly  as much attention and funding as the big cities do.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a very good bill, and I urge the support of all of my colleagues. I think it is one that will pass with total bipartisan support.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="OBERSTAR" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="MICA" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I do have one additional speaker, Mr. McHenry, from Spruce Pine and Hickory and other wonderful locations in the great State of North Carolina; and I yield him 3 minutes.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="McHENRY" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I thank the ranking member for yielding me this time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The trial lawyers have an uncanny way of making their living. Although the title of this legislation is a technical corrections bill, one glaring technical correction that needs to be made is left out.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As the ranking member said earlier tonight, the original SAFETEA-LU bill amended the definition of a commercial motor vehicle to exclude vehicles 10,000 pounds and less. The Department of Transportation had never issued regulations of this type of vehicle, which is essentially a small van or something smaller. It seemed to clear up the books and just make sense when it was done at the time. All too often what seems to be a simple idea ends up having much more significant consequences.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What was considered a cleaning up of the books turned out to be a dramatic shift in labor law. The Fair Labor Standards Act exempts drivers of vehicles that can be regulated by the Secretary of Transportation. The definitional change of a commercial vehicle unwittingly brought a whole new class of employee under that act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In writing the provision, neither Congress nor the administration intended to fundamentally alter our national labor policies, but that is exactly what happened.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What are the consequences? As I said, the trial lawyers have an uncanny ability to find sources to make money off of. Companies across the country that believed that their business model was and is perfectly legal because it had been may get a knock on the door from their friendly neighborhood trial lawyer informing them that they are now liable for overtime wages dating back to August 15, 2005, when SAFETEA-LU was signed into law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress didn't know what they had done. The administration didn't know  they had done this. How can we expect a small delivery service or some satellite dish installer or plumber to know that their business model is no longer viable?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>No one will argue that people aren't entitled to a fair and equitable, appropriate wage, but if we are going to significantly alter national labor law, we should have a full and open debate and we should do it intentionally, not by accident and not by trial lawyers. I think that is the one glaring omission from this act. If we would fix that, we would have a number of employers from around this country who would be safe from more trial lawyer, frivolous lawsuits.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Shouldn't we ensure that companies are held liable? Sure, but we should do it as a Congress in a knowing way, a way that is befitting of this body, not by accident. We should not make them pay for our Congress' mistakes.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="MICA" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no further speakers. I was hoping the gentleman from Arkansas (Mr. Boozman) would make it to the floor. We took this bill out of the order we anticipated it coming up in, and the gentleman from Arkansas would have been recognized.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, I thank Mr. Oberstar working with our side of the aisle; Mr. Duncan, my ranking member; the lead Republican on the Highway Subcommittee, Mr. DeFazio; and all of the staff on both sides. They worked real hard on this and over some weekends.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We had originally planned to tack this onto the WRDA bill, but that was not meant to be. Actually, that might work out quite well because this might become law before WRDA, given the comments I have gotten from the White House on the WRDA legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But I thank all those involved in making certain that the laws that we pass have the intent and the content and the necessary corrections.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="OBERSTAR" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I listened thoughtfully to the comments of the gentleman from North Carolina. Those are issues that can be addressed in another time and another venue. We will most certainly address those matters in good order.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>As I said at the outset, this is the seventh time the House has passed this technical corrections bill. We've been waiting patiently for the other body to join us in meaningful action on the bill, and so I know there's going to be a recorded vote. That's going to be reaffirmation of the strong stand the House has taken on these, and they truly are technical matters. We ought to just get them passed so that we can get over, so the States and the Federal Government agencies can get on with the  work they need to undertake and that these adjustments to Members' projects can be made and be carried forward.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That's really what this is all about, and other matters that go beyond the scope of this current technical correction we will address in future legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="YOUNG" of="Alaska">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise to clarify an ambiguity in a provision in the SAFETEA-LU Technical Corrections Act of 2007. Specifically, section 105(a)(99) of the bill refers to a project known as "Dowling Road Extension/Reconstruction West," which goes in a west-east direction from Minnesota Drive to Old Seward Highway in Anchorage, AK. Unfortunately, the provision could be read to mean that the project goes in a westerly direction from Minnesota Drive to Old Seward Highway, which  would create a result that would be completely incompatible with the project since it would put the road in the middle of a lake and a bog. The word "west" as used in section 105(a)(99) is part of the name of the project, and is not intended to indicate the direction in which the project should be built.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="OBERSTAR" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time and ask for an "aye" vote on the bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Minnesota (Mr. Oberstar) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="3248">H.R. 3248</bill>.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="MICA" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this motion will be postponed.</chair>
</record>
