<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1181059208" ordinal="24" title="RIVERSIDE-CORONA FEEDER WATER SUPPLY ACT">
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="1139">H.R. 1139</bill>) to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to plan, design and construct facilities to provide water for irrigation, municipal, domestic, and other uses from the Bunker Hill Groundwater Basin, Santa Ana River, California, and for other purposes, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from the Virgin Islands (Mrs. Christensen) and the gentleman from Utah (Mr. Cannon) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from the Virgin Islands?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of <bill type="h" number="1139">H.R. 1139</bill>, as amended, is to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to plan, design and construct water facilities for municipal, domestic irrigation and other uses in the Bunker Hill Groundwater Basin, Santa Ana River in California.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1139">H.R. 1139</bill>, as amended, would authorize limited Federal financial assistance for the design and construction of 20 groundwater wells, groundwater treatment facilities, water storage and pumping facilities and 28 miles of pipeline in San Bernardino and Riverside Counties of California.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>The West, now more than ever, must explore and identify new ways of providing a reliable water supply to meet the current and future water demands of a rapidly growing population. <bill type="h" number="1139">H.R. 1139</bill>, as amended, seeks to accomplish this by building new pipelines and infrastructure that would allow for the storage of conserved water in groundwater basins.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This project would also serve to provide a critical emergency supply, aid in groundwater cleanup, and reduce dependence on the Colorado River and the very sensitive Bay-Delta.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank Mr. Calvert for his efforts on this legislation, and I urge my colleagues to join me in supporting <bill type="h" number="1139">H.R. 1139</bill>, as amended.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="1139">H.R. 1139</bill>. <bill type="h" number="1139">H.R. 1139</bill>, sponsored by the distinguished gentleman from California (Mr. Calvert), authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to assist the Western Municipal Water District in the planning, design, and construction of the Riverside-Corona Feeder. This project includes water storage, pumping facilities, and 28 miles of pipeline in San Bernardino and Riverside Counties, California.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation, as amended, is another step toward "drought proofing" Southern California and also reduces the region's dependence on imported water supplies, while providing limited Federal assistance. I urge my colleagues to support this important measure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield such time as he may consume to the gentleman from California (Mr. Calvert).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400057" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the Riverside-Corona Feeder Water Supply Act represents an important investment in the water infrastructure in western Riverside County, California, one of the fastest-growing regions in this country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At a time when water demand continues to grow due to the West's increasing population, traditional water sources have been confronted by a prolonged drought and other environmental challenges. In fact, just last week California water officials turned off the huge pumps that send water to Southern California from the Sacramento-San Joaquin Delta to protect a tiny imperiled fish. While the shutdown is only scheduled to last a week or two, it is a stark reminder that Southern California must continue  to reduce its dependence on imported water from the Delta and the Colorado River.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Western Municipal Water District provides water service to western Riverside County and serves a population of more than 600,000 people. The purpose of the Riverside-Corona Feeder water supply project is to capture and store water in wet years in order to increase Western's firm water supplies, provide a cost-effective water supply, and improve water quality.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>New wet year water will come from local runoff, including regulated releases from Seven Oaks Dam and the State Water Project and stored in San Bernardino groundwater basins. To deliver the stored water to consumers in Western's service area, the project will provide for new groundwater pumping and pipeline capability. As an additional benefit, the Riverside-Corona Feeder will provide the means to control water tables, thereby reducing liquefaction dangers in the Colton and San Bernardino communities.  Additionally, the project improves local water quality as perchlorate and other contaminants would be removed from the basin when water is extracted from the well heads via the Riverside-Corona Feeder.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I applaud Western and our local elected officials in Western Riverside County for taking bold, proactive steps in meeting our region's current and future water demand. In particular, I would like to acknowledge the leadership of Western's General Manager, John Rossi, as well as the Western board members, Charles Field, Tom Evans, Brenda Dennstedt, Don Galleano, and Al Lopez. I also want to thank my good friend Grace Napolitano, the chairwoman of the Water and Power Subcommittee, for  her leadership and support of my legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think it is crucial that we recognize and assist communities that are working to reduce their reliance on imported water, and I urge all of my colleagues to support the Riverside-Corona Feeder Water Supply Act.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from the Virgin Islands (Mrs. Christensen) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="1139">H.R. 1139</bill>, as amended.</chair>
</record>
