<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1214409602" ordinal="31" title="E-PRESCRIBING AND ITS POTENTIAL TO IMPROVE QUALITY AND HEALTH OUTCOMES IN OUR HEALTH CARE SYSTEM">
  <narrative>E-PRESCRIBING AND ITS POTENTIAL TO IMPROVE QUALITY AND HEALTH OUTCOMES IN OUR HEALTH CARE SYSTEM -- (House of Representatives - June 25, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H6015]</narrative>
  <narrative>(Ms. SCHWARTZ asked and was given permission to address the House for 1 minute and to revise and extend her remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400647" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, under the Democratic-controlled Congress, the country is moving in a new direction. Improvements in our health care delivery system are key parts of this new direction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I applaud my colleagues for an overwhelming bipartisan victory yesterday in support of our Nation's seniors, disabled and health care providers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Medicare bill we passed yesterday will not only prevent the impending physician fee cut, but it will also strengthen Medicare and will provide more accessible access to service and will promote improved patient safety and health outcomes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I'm proud to be a leader in Congress in promoting health technology. The legislation I introduced last year, which was included in the Medicare bill yesterday, promotes the use of E-prescribing by Medicare providers. Electronic prescribing will eliminate injuries, hospitalizations and mortalities that occur each year as a result of 1.5 million prescription errors annually.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The use of E-prescribing is smart; it is timely, and it is a major step forward in expanding the use of electronic medical records. It has the potential to improve quality, to improve health outcomes and to reduce costs in our health care system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge the Senate to pass and accept our legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
