<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1201064400" ordinal="11" title="A PANACEA TO THE ECONOMIC GROWTH CHALLENGE: THE FAIR AND SIMPLE TAX ACT">
  <narrative>A PANACEA TO THE ECONOMIC GROWTH CHALLENGE: THE FAIR AND SIMPLE TAX ACT -- (House of Representatives - January 23, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H392]</narrative>
  <narrative>(Mr. DREIER asked and was given permission to address the House for 1 minute and revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400115" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, as virtually everyone is talking about the need for us to have an economic stimulus package, I am very proud today to be introducing what I think is the closest thing to a panacea to the economic growth challenge that we are facing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This plan that I have introduced is the brainchild of my friends Bill Simon, Jennifer Pollom and Mike Boskin. It is a plan that is designed to allow people at the lower end of the spectrum on their first $40,000 in income to pay 10 percent, on income between $40,000 and $150,000, 15 percent, and on income above $150,000, 30 percent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It also, Madam Speaker, goes to the notion of encouraging economic growth by cutting the capital gains rate from 15 percent to 10 percent and cutting the top corporate rate from 35 percent to 25 percent. Remember, we have the second highest rate in the entire world when it comes to corporate tax. We need to focus on the issue of economic growth. It will actually apply the death penalty to the death tax, and it will take the alternative minimum tax and index it and ultimately eliminate it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, this is what we need to do to stimulate our economy. This is what we need to do to empower the people who will move and propel our economy forward. I urge my colleagues, Democrats and Republicans alike, to join as cosponsors of this very important legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
