<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1213718403" ordinal="26" title="MONTANA CEMETERY ACT OF 2008">
  <narrative>MONTANA CEMETERY ACT OF 2008 -- (House of Representatives - June 17, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H5421]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="3702">H.R. 3702</bill>) to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to convey certain land in the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest, Montana, to Jefferson County, Montana, for use as a cemetery, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="3702">H.R. 3702</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "Montana Cemetery Act of 2008".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. DEFINITIONS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; In this Act:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) COUNTY.--The term "County" means Jefferson County, Montana.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) MAP.--The term "map" means the map that is--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) entitled "Elkhorn Cemetery";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) dated May 9, 2005; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) on file in the office of the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest Supervisor.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) SECRETARY.--The term "Secretary" means the Secretary of Agriculture.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 3. CONVEYANCE TO JEFFERSON COUNTY, MONTANA.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Conveyance.--Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act and subject to valid existing rights, the Secretary (acting through the Regional Forester, Northern Region, Missoula, Montana) shall convey by quitclaim deed to the County for no consideration, all right, title, and interest of the United States, except as provided in subsection (e), in and to the parcel of land described in subsection (b).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Description of Land.--The parcel of land referred to in subsection (a) is the parcel of approximately 9.67 acres of National Forest System land (including any improvements to the land) in the County that is known as the "Elkhorn Cemetery", as generally depicted on the map.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Use of Land.--As a condition of the conveyance under subsection (a), the County shall--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) use the land described in subsection (b) as a County cemetery; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) agree to manage the cemetery with due consideration and protection for the historic and cultural values of the cemetery, under such terms and conditions as are agreed to by the Secretary and the County.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (d) Easement.--In conveying the land to the County under subsection (a), the Secretary, in accordance with applicable law, shall grant to the County an easement across certain National Forest System land, as generally depicted on the map, to provide access to the land conveyed under that subsection.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (e) Reversion.--In the quitclaim deed to the County, the Secretary shall provide that the land conveyed to the County under subsection (a) shall revert to the Secretary, at the election of the Secretary, if the land is--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) used for a purpose other than the purposes described in subsection (c)(1); or</narrative>
  <narrative> (2) managed by the County in a manner that is inconsistent with subsection (c)(2).&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from Guam (Ms. Bordallo) and the gentleman from Utah (Mr. Bishop) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentlewoman from Guam.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days in which to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from Guam?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="3702">H.R. 3702</bill> requires the Secretary of Agriculture to convey approximately 9.67 acres of land in the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest, Montana, to Jefferson County, MT for use as a cemetery. The parcel to be conveyed to Jefferson County is currently being used for these same purposes, and is known as "Elkhorn Cemetery." The conveyance will provide land to accommodate all known grave sites and any additional sites that may be outside of the concentration of known graves.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also provides for the continued protection of the historic and cultural values associated with the property.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, we have no objections, and it is time to put this bill to rest.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400029" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The gentlelady from Guam has adequately explained this bill. I'd like to commend congressman Denny Rehberg and his staff for their diligence in this particular bill; grateful for all for allowing the conveyance of this 10 acres of excess Forest Service land to the community of Jefferson County, MT to be used as their cemetery.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I join the gentlelady from Guam in saying that I am glad that we can finally put this issue to rest in peace.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I again urge Members to support the bill, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from Guam (Ms. Bordallo) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="3702">H.R. 3702</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this motion will be postponed.</chair>
</record>
