<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1223049602" ordinal="7" title="OUR JOB IS NOT DONE">
  <narrative>OUR JOB IS NOT DONE -- (House of Representatives - October 03, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H10701]</narrative>
  <narrative>(Mr. WILSON of South Carolina asked and was given permission to address the House for 1 minute and to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400433" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, today we vote on a piece of legislation that is an imperfect option and a terrible situation. But I hope Congress does not fail the American people by saying that this bill has solved the whole problem, because it has not.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bad lending practices, mishandling by financial firms and failed oversight by the Federal Government over decades are not addressed today. But we better step forward and address them as soon as possible.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a former real estate attorney for 25 years, I know firsthand that making home loans to individuals less than creditworthy can be destructive for those individuals and for this country. Government should not be telling banks that it is possible for them to make bad loans because the government will back them up.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our job is not done today. Going forward, Congress has an obligation to face and fix the roots of this crisis, reducing government control.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In conclusion, God bless our troops, and we will never forget September  11th. God bless Governor Sarah Palin for her service for America.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Mr. KUCINICH asked and was given permission to address the House for 1 minute and to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400227" topic="FROM THE NEW DEAL TO THE RAW DEAL">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, we have come a great distance in 75 years, from the New Deal to the raw deal, from having nothing to fear but fear itself, to being afraid of everything. We have traded democracy's warm heart, containing ideals of faith, fairness and frugality, for the greedy, cold, calculations of the Dow Jones ticker.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The New Deal saved free market capitalism with jobs and regulation. Now both sink in the swamp of speculation, manipulation and capitulation. The golden rule of "Do unto others as you would have them do unto you" is submerged by the rule of gold: `Do unto others before they do unto you.'</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Some people will ask of this Congress, what were we thinking? Why did we give a $700 billion bailout to Wall Street without fixing what caused the problem in the first place? Why did we rig free markets for security fraudsters? Why didn't we explore alternatives to let Wall Street solve its own problems? Why didn't we have money to save millions of homeowners, create millions of jobs and a green economy?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Why didn't we stop the speculators? Why wasn't there accountability? Why didn't we take time to make an intelligent decision? Why Why Why?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
