<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1185768000" ordinal="68" title="IDAHO AGRICULTURAL COLLEGE LAND GRANT">
  <narrative>IDAHO AGRICULTURAL COLLEGE LAND GRANT -- (House of Representatives - July 30, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H8912]</narrative>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="SANDLIN, HERSETH" of="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="3006">H.R. 3006</bill>) to improve the use of a grant of a parcel of land to the State of Idaho for use as an agricultural college, and for other purposes.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="3006">H.R. 3006</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. AGRICULTURAL COLLEGE LAND GRANT.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) In General.--Section 10 of the Act of July 3, 1890 (26 Stat. 215, chapter 656) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) by inserting "(a)" after "Sec. 10."; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) by adding at the end the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(b) Notwithstanding sections 3 through 5 of the Act of July 2, 1862 (commonly known as the `First Morrill Act') (7 U.S.C. 303 et seq.), the State of Idaho may--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(1) invest and manage earnings and proceeds derived from land granted to the State of Idaho pursuant to subsection (a), in accordance with the standards applicable to a trustee under Idaho law;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(2) deduct from earnings and proceeds generated from granted land any expenses that a trustee is authorized to deduct pursuant to Idaho law; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(3) use earnings and proceeds generated by the granted land for any uses and purposes described in that Act (7 U.S.C. 301 et seq.) without regard to the limitations set out in section 5 of that Act (7 U.S.C. 305) that prohibit the State from exceeding 10 per centum on the purchase of land and prohibit the State from purchasing, erecting, preserving, or repairing of any building or buildings.".</narrative>
  <narrative> (b) Effective Date.--The amendments made by subsection (a) shall take effect on October 27, 1998.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from South Dakota (Ms. Herseth Sandlin) and the gentleman from Virginia (Mr. Goodlatte) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentlewoman from South Dakota.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="SANDLIN, HERSETH" of="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="3006">H.R. 3006</bill>, a bill introduced by Congressman Simpson of Idaho and cosponsored by Congressman Sali, also of Idaho, that addresses an Idaho-specific problem.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The University of Idaho would like to construct a Center for Livestock and Environmental Studies to research environmental issues facing the dairy industry in central Idaho, but current law prevents the university from using proceeds from endowed lands toward funding for the center.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The dairy industry faces a number of significant EPA regulation, animal health and environmental issues, including nutrient management and odor control. Idaho is now the fourth largest milk-producing State, with 477,475 cows and 686 dairies in 2006.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To support the Idaho dairy industry and help address the challenges facing it, the University of Idaho, in collaboration with the College of Southern Idaho, Idaho Dairymen, Kimberley ARS/USDA and others, is seeking to develop the Center for Livestock and Environmental Studies in the Magic Valley area. The total cost of the center is projected to be $25-$35 million. The State of Idaho and the dairy industry have been willing to put forward a large percentage of funding, and the University of Idaho  is responsible for the remaining portion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The university would like to use the proceeds from endowed lands granted to the university by the Morrill Act. In order to do this, the Idaho Admissions Bill must be amended. Currently, lands granted to the University of Idaho through the Morrill Act can be exchanged and managed with the proceeds going only to the operation of buildings, not construction. This bill will lift that restriction within the Idaho Admissions Bill and will leave the Morrill Act untouched, making it Idaho specific.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Governor Otter and the Idaho Legislature have approved a $10 million appropriation for the center, contingent upon the passage of <bill type="h" number="3006">H.R. 3006</bill>, and additional funding is being raised by the Idaho dairy community.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400154" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I rise in support of this legislation and yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="3006">H.R. 3006</bill> is a simple amendment to the act granting statehood to Idaho. The legislation will allow Idaho additional flexibility to invest and manage earnings from the land grant provided under the first Morrill Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the Morrill Act of 1862 was to provide an amount of public land to be apportioned to each State, the proceeds of which were to be used to establish a college of agriculture. The Morrill Act is the foundation of our land grant college system and one we can continue to build upon with each farm bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of <bill type="h" number="3006">H.R. 3006</bill> is to provide additional flexibility to Idaho in how it manages funds derived from the original land grant. Specifically, this legislation would waive statutory limitations related to facility procurement and maintenance. This, in turn, will allow Idaho to construct a research facility addressing environmental concerns facing the dairy industry.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As stated previously, this is simple legislation for which I know of no opposition.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am told that any concerns the U.S. Department of Agriculture may have have been subsequently addressed. I, therefore, urge all Members to support this legislation</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400316" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I submit the following information for the RECORD on <bill type="h" number="3006">H.R. 3006</bill>:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>COMMITTEE ON AGRICULTURE,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington, DC, July 27, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR MR. CHAIRMAN: I ask your help in scheduling <bill type="h" number="3006">H.R. 3006</bill>, a bill to improve the use of a grant of a parcel of land to the State of Idaho, for consideration by the House of Representatives as soon as possible.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="3006">H.R. 3006</bill> was referred to the Committee on Agriculture and additionally to your Committee. The purpose of <bill type="h" number="3006">H.R. 3006</bill> is to allow the University of Idaho to construct a Center for Livestock and Environmental Studies to research environmental issues facing the dairy industry in central Idaho.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the interest of expediency, I ask that you allow the Committee on Natural Resources to be discharged from further consideration of the bill. This action would not be considered as precedent for any future referrals of similar measures or seen as affecting your Committee's jurisdiction over the subject matter of the bill. Moreover, if the bill is conferenced with the Senate, I would support naming Natural Resources Committee members to the conference committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I look forward to your response and would be pleased to include it and this letter in the report on <bill type="h" number="3006">H.R. 3006</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Collin C. Peterson,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>&lt;pre&gt;--&lt;/pre&gt;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>COMMITTEE ON NATURAL RESOURCES,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington, DC, July 27, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR MR. CHAIRMAN: Thank you for the opportunity to review the text of <bill type="h" number="3006">H.R. 3006</bill>, a bill to improve the use of a grant of a parcel of land to the State of Idaho. As you know, the Committee on Natural Resources was granted an additional referral on this legislation due to provisions therein which fall under the Committee's jurisdiction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of the continued cooperation and consideration that you have afforded me and my staff in developing these provisions, and knowing of your interest in expediting this legislation, I will discharge <bill type="h" number="3006">H.R. 3006</bill> from further consideration by the Committee on Natural Resources. Of course, this waiver is not intended to prejudice any future jurisdictional claims over these provisions or similar language. I also reserve the right to seek to have conferees named from the Committee on Natural Resources  on these provisions, and request your support if such a request is made.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Please place this letter into the committee report on <bill type="h" number="3006">H.R. 3006</bill> and into the Congressional Record during consideration of the measure on the House floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thank you for the cooperative spirit in which you have worked regarding this matter and others between our respective committees.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With warm regards, I am</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nick J. Rahall, II,</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400154" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="SANDLIN, HERSETH" of="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from South Dakota (Ms. Herseth Sandlin) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="3006">H.R. 3006</bill>.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the bill was passed.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
