<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1178553612" ordinal="25" title="SOUTH ORANGE COUNTY RECYCLED WATER ENHANCEMENT ACT">
  <speaking speaker="400290" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="1140">H.R. 1140</bill>) to authorize the Secretary, in cooperation with the City of San Juan Capistrano, California, to participate in the design, planning, and construction of an advanced water treatment plant facility and recycled water system, and for other purposes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from California (Mrs. Napolitano) and the gentleman from Colorado (Mr. Lamborn) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400290" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from California?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400290" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the purpose of <bill type="h" number="1140">H.R. 1140</bill>, as introduced by my colleague and former chair of the subcommittee, Mr. Ken Calvert, is to authorize the Secretary to participate in the design, planning and construction of an advanced water treatment facility and recycled water system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The continuing drought and the decrease in snow pack have led to a reduction in water supplies in many parts of the West. Water recycling projects can help communities protect against the adverse consequences of drought.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1140">H.R. 1140</bill> will authorize limited Federal financial assistance for two separate water recycling projects in Southern California. One, beautiful San Juan Capistrano, and the other in great San Clemente.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Recycled water can satisfy many water demands, and the enactment of this bill will continue our efforts to encourage the administration to include recycling as an effective water management strategy. I note it was left out of Water 2025, and I want to be sure that we continue to push forward for that which is very, very helpful to many communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I do urge my colleagues to join me in supporting 1140.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation, <bill type="h" number="1140">H.R. 1140</bill>, introduced by the distinguished former chairman of the Water and Power Subcommittee, Ken Calvert of California, authorizes limited Federal assistance for two water recycling projects in southern Orange County. This bill helps the cities of San Juan Capistrano and San Clemente meet their water supply needs, and reduces their dependence on imported water.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I commend Representative Calvert for his longstanding leadership in helping all of Southern California meet its future water needs through a combination of water recycling, desalting, conservation and water storage. I urge my colleagues to support this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 3 minutes to the gentleman from California (Mr. Calvert), the author of the bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400057" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I want to thank my chairman, Mrs. Napolitano, for the hard work that she has put into all these water bills and for her desire to make sure that areas such as southern California have water for the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The South Orange County Recycled Water Enhancement Act is a relatively modest yet important step toward meeting the long-term water needs for the West. Water recycling is an approach that more and more communities are tapping to meet local and regional water demand. To address the continued growth of water users, communities are truly maximizing the use of every drop of water.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The South Orange County Recycled Water Enhancement Act authorizes two water reclamation projects in the South Orange County portion of my district. South Orange County relies heavily on imported water from sources such as the Colorado River and the Bay Delta in northern California.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Water reclamation projects and other steps which reduce demand for imported water benefit all regional water uses. The first project outlined in this legislation is the San Juan Capistrano recycled water system, which would enable the City of San Juan Capistrano to provide recycled water to users throughout the city and its neighboring communities. To meet the local demand, the City has developed a project that includes the construction of a water treatment facility as well as transmission infrastructure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank the San Juan Capistrano Mayor Sam Allevato and the rest of the city council for their dedication to this important project.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The second part of this project is the San Clemente Reclaimed Water Project, which would expand San Clemente's reclaimed water infrastructure by doubling its production capability. When completed, San Clemente's recycled water project will reduce the city's demand of domestic water by 3,300 acre feet of water per year. I applaud San Clemente Mayor Jim Dahl and the entire city council for their entire commitment to water recycling.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, I want to thank my good friend Grace Napolitano, our chairwoman of the Water and Power Subcommittee, for her leadership and support of my legislation. I know she shares my belief that water recycling is an important tool in addressing growing water needs in the west. Mr. Speaker, I think it is crucial that we recognize and assist communities that are working to reduce their reliance on imported water, and I urge all colleagues to support the South Orange County Recycled Water  Enhancement Act.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400290" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, first of all, I want to thank staff on both sides who have been working collaboratively and in a bipartisan manner.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Water knows no political colors or boundaries. I think we need to work together to be able to ensure that our economy continues growing, that water will continue to flow through the faucets and in the rivers and dams and aquifers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And along with Mr. Lamborn, Mr. Speaker, I want to urge all Members to look at their district water needs, and begin to understand it and be able to work with it so that we can protect the rest of the States that are going through, whether it is droughts or other areas that they need help with.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I certainly want to thank my ranking member, Kathy McMorris, who isn't here, but certainly Mr. Lamborn, who has done a great job. And I want to thank him specifically, because to work collaboratively and get these bills out is critical not only in time but in the effect it has on our economy throughout the Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from California (Mrs. Napolitano) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="1140">H.R. 1140</bill>.</chair>
</record>
