<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1208880002" ordinal="25" title="MORLEY NELSON SNAKE RIVER BIRDS OF PREY NATIONAL CONSERVATION AREA ACT">
  <narrative>MORLEY NELSON SNAKE RIVER BIRDS OF PREY NATIONAL CONSERVATION AREA ACT -- (House of Representatives - April 22, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H2500]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400331" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="3734">H.R. 3734</bill>) to rename the Snake River Birds of Prey National Conservation Area in the State of Idaho as the Morley Nelson Snake River Birds of Prey National Conservation Area in honor of the late Morley Nelson, an international authority on birds of prey, who was instrumental in the establishment of this National Conservation Area, and for other purposes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="3734">H.R. 3734</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "Morley Nelson Snake River Birds of Prey National Conservation Area Act".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. RENAMING OF SNAKE RIVER BIRDS OF PREY NATIONAL CONSERVATION AREA.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Renaming.--Public Law 103-64 is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in section 2(2) (16 U.S.C. 460iii-1(2)), by inserting "Morley Nelson" before "Snake River Birds of Prey National Conservation Area"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) in section 3(a)(1) (16 U.S.C. 460iii-2(a)(1)), by inserting "Morley Nelson" before "Snake River Birds of Prey National Conservation Area".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) References.--Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the Snake River Birds of Prey National Conservation Area shall be deemed to be a reference to the Morley Nelson Snake River Birds of Prey National Conservation Area.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Technical Corrections.--Public Law 103-64 is further amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in section 3(a)(1) (16 U.S.C. 460iii-2(a)(1)), by striking "(hereafter referred to as the `conservation area')"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) in section 4 (16 U.S.C. 460iii-3)--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) in subsection (a)(2), by striking "Conservation Area" and inserting "conservation area"; and</narrative>
  <narrative> (B) in subsection (d), by striking "Visitors Center" and inserting "visitors center".&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from West Virginia (Mr. Rahall) and the gentleman from Tennessee (Mr. Duncan) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from West Virginia.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400331" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days in which to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the resolution under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from West Virginia?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400331" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the pending measure introduced by our colleague, MIKE SIMPSON, renames the Snake River Birds of Prey National Conservation Area in the State of Idaho as the Morley Nelson Snake River Birds of Prey National Conservation Area.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Morley Nelson was an ardent advocate for birds of prey and was instrumental in establishing the Snake River Birds of Prey National Conservation Area. The National Conservation Area includes approximately 500 acres and is one of the densest known nesting populations of eagles, falcons, owls, hawks, and other birds of prey in North America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I do commend our colleague, MIKE SIMPSON from Idaho, for his work on the bill. I support the passage of <bill type="h" number="3734">H.R. 3734</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400116" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, it's appropriate that the Snake River Birds of Prey National Conservation Area be named after Morley Nelson. Morley Nelson demonstrated how private voluntary wildlife conservation efforts can be far more effective than big Federal programs and showed that punitive laws, like the Endangered Species Act, can inhibit and interfere with more creative approaches.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He worked with Idaho Power to redesign their towers and power lines so eagles would not be electrocuted when they landed on them. This not only saved the eagles; it saved Idaho Power the substantial cost of power disruptions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He worked with private falconers to create a captive breeding and release program that was so successful, the peregrine falcon was one of the first species taken off the endangered species list. The Fish and Wildlife Service has yet to achieve a comparable recovery after more than 30 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am pleased to see Morley Nelson recognized for his great conservation achievements.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400331" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from West Virginia (Mr. Rahall) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="3734">H.R. 3734</bill>.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the bill was passed.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
