<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1170176402" ordinal="56" title="TWO U.S. BORDER PATROL AGENTS IN FEDERAL PRISON">
  <chair> Under a previous order of the House, the gentleman from North Carolina (Mr. Jones) is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400209" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, soon the page will bring forward a photo of two border agents who are now in prison. And it is a travesty of injustice as bad as I have ever seen.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The portrait is of the two border agents, Mr. Compean and Mr. Ramos. Mr. Compean has a wife and three children, one, his youngest, 4 months old. Agent Ramos has a wife and three sons.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, many of us in the House have made the House aware of this case. These agents were convicted last spring for wounding a Mexican drug smuggler who brought 743 pounds of marijuana across our southern border into Texas. The agents fired shots during a foot chase with the smuggler, who had fled in a van they were pursuing. The van contained approximately $1 million worth of marijuana. The U.S. Attorney's Office prosecuted the agents and granted immunity to a known drug smuggler for his  testimony against our border agents.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This prosecution has been questioned by many Members of Congress and by citizens throughout this country. These men never should have been prosecuted; yet they are now handcuffed in Federal prison. We have repeatedly petitioned President Bush to pardon these agents.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, after months of silence, the President said in a television interview last week that he would take a "sober look" at the case and a "tough look at the facts" to see whether these agents should be pardoned.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I hope that at this time the President and his staff will take an honest look at the facts of this case. The facts will tell the President what countless citizens and Members of Congress already know, that the United States Attorney's Office was on the wrong side of this case. The U.S. Attorney's Office prosecuted the agents almost exclusively on the testimony of an admitted drug smuggler who claimed he was unarmed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The drug smuggler received full medical care in El Paso, Texas, was permitted to return to Mexico, and is now suing the Border Patrol for $5 million for violating his civil rights.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The drug smuggler is not an American citizen. He is a criminal.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the extraordinary details surrounding the prosecution of this case ensure that justice has not been served. For the sake of the agents and their families and for the sake of the American people whom they were working to protect, I encourage the President of the United States to obtain the transcripts of this trial and review the facts of this case as soon as possible.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Real justice does not fear the truth. Real justice does not fear the truth. By pardoning these two innocent men, the President can immediately reverse an injustice that never should have happened to these Hispanic Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, in closing, I want to reiterate that Agent Compean and his wife have three children and one, his youngest, 4 months old; and that Agent Ramos, himself, and his wife have three sons.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congressman Poe, who will be speaking in a few minutes on another issue, I am sure, has been outspoken on this--and a number of other Members and even some on the Democratic side. This is an injustice that should never happen to an American citizen, never under any circumstances.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, please look at the facts of this case. Free these men. They have no business being in a Federal penitentiary for trying to protect the American citizens.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And God bless America</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
