<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1188956525" ordinal="17" title="GREEN CHEMISTRY RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT ACT OF 2007">
  <narrative>GREEN CHEMISTRY RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT ACT OF 2007 -- (House of Representatives - September 04, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H10023]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400011" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="2850">H.R. 2850</bill>) to provide for the implementation of a Green Chemistry Research and Development Program, and for other purposes, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="2850">H.R. 2850</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "Green Chemistry Research and Development Act of 2007".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. DEFINITIONS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; In this Act--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) the term "green chemistry" means chemistry and chemical engineering to design chemical products and processes that reduce or eliminate the use or generation of hazardous substances while producing high quality products through safe and efficient manufacturing processes;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) the term "Interagency Working Group" means the interagency working group established under section 3(c); and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) the term "Program" means the Green Chemistry Research and Development Program described in section 3.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 3. GREEN CHEMISTRY RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT PROGRAM.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) In General.--The President shall establish a Green Chemistry Research and Development Program to promote and coordinate Federal green chemistry research, development, education, and technology transfer activities.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Program Activities.--The activities of the Program shall be designed to--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) provide sustained support for green chemistry research, development, education, and technology transfer through--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) merit-reviewed competitive grants to individual investigators and teams of investigators, including, to the extent practicable, young investigators, for research and development;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) grants to fund collaborative research and development partnerships among universities, industry, and nonprofit organizations;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) green chemistry research, development, and technology transfer conducted at Federal laboratories; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (D) to the extent practicable, encouragement of consideration of green chemistry in--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) the conduct of Federal chemical science and engineering research and development; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) the solicitation and evaluation of all proposals for chemical science and engineering research and development;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) examine methods by which the Federal Government can create incentives for consideration and use of green chemistry processes and products;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) facilitate the adoption of green chemistry innovations;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) expand education and training of undergraduate and graduate students, and professional chemists and chemical engineers, including through partnerships with industry, in green chemistry science and engineering;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) collect and disseminate information on green chemistry research, development, and technology transfer, including information on--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) incentives and impediments to development and commercialization;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) accomplishments;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) best practices; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (D) costs and benefits;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (6) provide venues for outreach and dissemination of green chemistry advances such as symposia, forums, conferences, and written materials in collaboration with, as appropriate, industry, academia, scientific and professional societies, and other relevant groups;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (7) support economic, legal, and other appropriate social science research to identify barriers to commercialization and methods to advance commercialization of green chemistry; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (8) provide for public input and outreach to be integrated into the Program by the convening of public discussions, through mechanisms such as citizen panels, consensus conferences, and educational events, as appropriate.</narrative>
  <narrative> (c) Interagency Working Group.--The President shall establish an Interagency Working Group, which shall include representatives from the National Science Foundation, the National Institute of Standards and Technology, the Department of Energy, the Environmental Protection Agency, and any other agency that the President may designate. The Director of the National Science Foundation and the Assistant Administrator for Research and Development of the Environmental Protection Agency shall  serve as co-chairs of the Interagency Working Group. The Interagency Working Group shall oversee the planning, management, and coordination of the Program. The Interagency Working Group shall--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) establish goals and priorities for the Program, to the extent practicable in consultation with green chemistry researchers and potential end-users of green chemistry products and processes; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) provide for interagency coordination, including budget coordination, of activities under the Program.</narrative>
  <narrative> (d) Agency Budget Requests.--Each Federal agency and department participating in the Program shall, as part of its annual request for appropriations to the Office of Management and Budget, submit a report to the Office of Management and Budget which identifies its activities that contribute directly to the Program and states the portion of its request for appropriations that is allocated to those activities. The  President shall include in  his annual budget request to Congress a statement of the portion of each agency's or department's annual budget request allocated to its activities undertaken pursuant to the Program.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (e) Report to Congress.--Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Interagency Working Group shall transmit a report to the Committee on Science and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate. This report shall include--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) a summary of federally funded green chemistry research, development, demonstration, education, and technology transfer activities, including the green chemistry budget for each of these activities; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) an analysis of the progress made toward achieving the goals and priorities for the Program, and recommendations for future program activities.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 4. MANUFACTURING EXTENSION CENTER GREEN SUPPLIERS NETWORK GRANT PROGRAM.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Section 25(a) of the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act (15 U.S.C. 278k(a)) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) by striking "and" at the end of paragraph (4);&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) by striking the period at the end of paragraph (5) and inserting "; and"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) by adding at the end the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(6) the enabling of supply chain manufacturers to continuously improve products and processes, increase energy efficiency, increase recycling, identify cost-saving opportunities, and optimize resources and technologies with the aim of reducing or eliminating the use or generation of hazardous substances.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 5. UNDERGRADUATE EDUCATION IN CHEMISTRY AND CHEMICAL ENGINEERING.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Program Authorized.--(1) As part of the Program activities under section 3(b)(4), the Director of the National Science Foundation shall carry out a program to award grants to institutions of higher education to support efforts by such institutions to revise their undergraduate curriculum in chemistry and chemical engineering to incorporate green chemistry concepts and strategies.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) Grants shall be awarded under this section on a competitive, merit-reviewed basis and shall require cost sharing in cash from non-Federal sources, to match the Federal funding.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Selection Process.--(1) An institution of higher education seeking funding under this section shall submit an application to the Director at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Director may require. Minority Serving Institutions shall receive due consideration for such funding. The application shall include at a minimum--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) a description of the content and schedule for adoption of the proposed curricular revisions to the courses of study offered by the applicant in chemistry and chemical engineering; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) a description of the source and amount of cost sharing to be provided.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) In evaluating the applications submitted under paragraph (1), the Director shall consider, at a minimum--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) the level of commitment demonstrated by the applicant in carrying out and sustaining lasting curriculum changes in accordance with subsection (a)(1); and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) the amount of cost sharing to be provided.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Authorization of Appropriations.--In addition to amounts authorized under section 8, from sums otherwise authorized to be appropriated by the National Science Foundation Authorization Act of 2002, there are authorized to be appropriated to the National Science Foundation for carrying out this section $7,000,000 for fiscal year 2008, $7,500,000 for fiscal year 2009, and $8,000,000 for fiscal year 2010.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 6. STUDY ON COMMERCIALIZATION OF GREEN CHEMISTRY.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Study.--The Director of the National Science Foundation shall enter into an arrangement with the National Research Council to conduct a study of the factors that constitute barriers to the successful commercial application of promising results from green chemistry research and development.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Contents.--The study shall--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) examine successful and unsuccessful attempts at commercialization of green chemistry in the United States and abroad; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) recommend research areas and priorities and public policy options that would help to overcome identified barriers to commercialization.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Report.--The Director shall submit a report to the Committee on Science and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate on the findings and recommendations of the study within 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 7. PARTNERSHIPS IN GREEN CHEMISTRY.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Program Authorized.--(1) The agencies participating in the Program shall carry out a joint, coordinated program to award grants to institutions of higher education to establish partnerships with companies in the chemical industry to retrain chemists and chemical engineers in the use of green chemistry concepts and strategies.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) Grants shall be awarded under this section on a competitive, merit-reviewed basis and shall require cost sharing from non-Federal sources by members of the partnerships.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) In order to be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an institution of higher education shall enter into a partnership with two or more companies in the chemical industry. Such partnerships may also include other institutions of higher education and professional associations.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) Grants awarded under this section shall be used for activities to provide retraining for chemists or chemical engineers in green chemistry, including--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) the development of curricular materials and the designing of undergraduate and graduate level courses; and</narrative>
  <narrative> (B) publicizing the availability of professional development courses of study in green chemistry and recruiting graduate scientists and engineers to pursue such courses. &lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <narrative>Grants may provide stipends for individuals enrolled in courses developed by the partnership.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Selection Process.--(1) An institution of higher education seeking funding under this section shall submit an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as shall be specified by the Interagency Working Group and published in a proposal solicitation for the Program. The application shall include at a minimum--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) a description of the partnership and the role each member will play in implementing the proposal;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) a description of the courses of study that will be provided;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) a description of the number and size of stipends, if offered;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (D) a description of the source and amount of cost sharing to be provided; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (E) a description of the manner in which the partnership will be continued after assistance under this section ends.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) The evaluation of the applications submitted under paragraph (1) shall be carried out in accordance with procedures developed by the Interagency Working Group and shall consider, at a minimum--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) the ability of the partnership to carry out effectively the proposed activities;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) the degree to which such activities are likely to prepare chemists and chemical engineers sufficiently to be competent to apply green chemistry concepts and strategies in their work; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) the amount of cost sharing to be provided.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 8. AUTHORIZATION OF APPROPRIATIONS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) National Science Foundation.--There are authorized to be appropriated to the National Science Foundation for carrying out this Act--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) $20,000,000 for fiscal year 2008;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) $21,000,000 for fiscal year 2009; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) $22,000,000 for fiscal year 2010.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) National Institute of Standards and Technology.--There are authorized to be appropriated to the National Institute of Standards and Technology for carrying out this Act--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) $8,000,000 for fiscal year 2008;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) $9,000,000 for fiscal year 2009; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) $10,000,000 for fiscal year 2010.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Department of Energy.--There are authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Energy for carrying out this Act--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) $13,000,000 for fiscal year 2008;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) $14,000,000 for fiscal year 2009; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) $15,000,000 for fiscal year 2010.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (d) Environmental Protection Agency.--There are authorized to be appropriated to the Environmental Protection Agency for carrying out this Act--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) $10,000,000 for fiscal year 2008;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) $11,000,000 for fiscal year 2009; and</narrative>
  <narrative> (3) $12,000,000 for fiscal year 2010.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Washington (Mr. Baird) and the gentleman from Texas (Mr. Hall) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Washington.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400011" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days in which to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on <bill type="h" number="2850">H.R. 2850</bill>, the bill now under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Washington?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400011" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of <bill type="h" number="2850">H.R. 2850</bill>, the Green Chemistry Research and Development Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Chemical manufacturing produces great wonders for the world, but at the same time it can result in harm to health and the environment due to the use of hazardous materials and the generation of hazardous by-products. Green chemistry seeks to mitigate such harmful outcomes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In short, the goal of green chemistry is to minimize or to eliminate this harm by using safer materials and manufacturing processes. Besides protecting human health and the environment, green chemistry can offer economic advantages and improvements to worker safety, public safety, and our national security.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill before us today, <bill type="h" number="2850">H.R. 2850</bill>, the Green Chemistry Research and Development Act, establishes an interagency program to enhance green chemistry R&amp;D at NSF, EPA, DOE and NIST.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation will provide grants to individual researchers, spur university/industry partnerships, fund research at Federal laboratories, and train students in green chemistry science.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2850">H.R. 2850</bill> is the third iteration of a bill that Congressman Gingrey has introduced addressing this issue in three  separate Congresses. I want to applaud the gentleman from Georgia for his steadfast leadership on this, and I fully support the legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under Chairman Boehlert's leadership in the 108th and 109th Congresses, Democratic amendments were agreed to, and these amendments now make up sections of <bill type="h" number="2850">H.R. 2850</bill>. This bill is the product of good, bipartisan cooperation and has the support of our chairman, Mr. Gordon, from Tennessee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2850">H.R. 2850</bill> is a good first step, and I urge my colleagues to support this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400165" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume, leaving most of the time for Dr. Gingrey.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I want to just say that the Green Chemistry Research and Development Act of 2007 offered today by my good friend from Georgia, Dr. Gingrey, will provide for research and development of chemical products and processes so as to reduce the use of creation of hazardous substances. Advances in these areas have the potential of reducing the creation of substances that are harmful to our environment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In particular, <bill type="h" number="2850">H.R. 2850</bill> includes a competitive merit-based grant program to universities to incorporate green chemistry concepts into the curriculum for chemistry and chemical engineering. This will ensure that future generations will consider the importance of green chemistry ideas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation strives to build a base from which the creation of hazardous substances may be reduced. I look forward to Dr. Gingrey's comments on this bill and urge my colleagues to support it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400011" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no additional speakers, and would reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400165" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield 6 minutes to Dr. Gingrey.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400151" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, as a proud sponsor of this legislation, I rise to support <bill type="h" number="2850">H.R. 2850</bill>, the Green Chemistry Research and Development Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank my colleague on the Science Committee, Dr. Baird. I thank him for his kind comments. And certainly I want to thank our chairman, Bart Gordon, the ranking member, Mr. Hall of Texas, and all of the members of the Science Committee and staff. Both majority and minority have worked hard to bring this important bipartisan legislation through committee and to the House floor today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation has passed the House in the 108th and 109th Congresses, and I hope that the third Congress will truly be the charm and we will see <bill type="h" number="2850">H.R. 2850</bill> quickly passed by both Chambers and signed by the President.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, chemists can design chemicals to be safe, just as they can design them to have other properties like color and texture. As chemists design products and the processes by which those products are manufactured, they can and should factor in the possible creation of any hazardous by-products.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This technique of considering not only the process by which chemicals are produced, but also the environment in which they are created, is the basic definition of green chemistry. It is the method of designing chemical products and processes that at the very least reduce, and at the very best eliminate, the use or generation of hazardous substances.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the basic idea is this: Preventing pollution and hazardous waste from the start of a design process is far preferable to cleaning up pollution and waste at a later date. Additionally, the innovation created by this enhanced research will subsequently spur economic growth as developing new products and processes is an integral component of many industries, from fabrics to fuel cells, as an example.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Green chemistry doesn't just help protect our environment, it also protects our workers. The conditions under which chemicals are created and used can present many risks to those who work on their production. But if companies utilize green chemistry, the materials they use will be as benign as possible, vastly improving employee conditions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, despite all of the promise of green chemistry, the Federal Government invests very little in this area. <bill type="h" number="2850">H.R. 2850</bill> works to remedy this by promoting greater Federal investment in, and coordination of, this important research area. It does so by establishing a program that coordinates Federal green chemistry research and development activities within the National Science Foundation, the Environmental Protection Agency, the National Institute of Standards and Technology, NIST, and  the Department of Energy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Make no mistake, greater Federal attention will encourage universities and academic institutions around this country to train future workers in this exciting technology. <bill type="h" number="2850">H.R. 2850</bill> will achieve this by supporting research and development grants to partnerships between universities, industry and nonprofit organizations. It will also promote education through curriculum development and fellowships that will collect and disseminate information about green chemistry.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In past years, many industries, from chemical companies and pharmaceutical corporations, to carpet manufacturers and biotechnology businesses, have all endorsed <bill type="h" number="2850">H.R. 2850</bill>, showing a broad range of support for the merits of this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill is nearly identical to the version passed in the 109th Congress. The companies and corporations that have voiced their strong support for this bill realize that the advancement of green chemistry is positive for not only their businesses, but also our country's environment, our economy and our Nation's citizens.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The American Chemical Society, a nonprofit organization chartered by Congress, stated in support of <bill type="h" number="2850">H.R. 2850</bill>, "Green chemistry means continuously improving process safety and resource efficiency leading to reduced cost, waste and environmental impact. It is the ultimate proof that environmental and economic benefit in chemistry can be optimized simultaneously."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, an ounce of prevention is worth a pound of cure, and green chemistry promises a ton of pollution prevention. I urge my colleagues to support this bipartisan legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400165" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no other speakers, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400011" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would just reiterate my commendation to the gentleman from Georgia, Dr. Gingrey, and Mr. Hall for his leadership, and urge passage of this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400437" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, as chairman of the Technology and Innovation Subcommittee and a cosponsor of the bill, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="2850">H.R. 2850</bill>, the Green Chemistry Research and Development Act of 2007. I want to commend Dr. Gingrey for his work on this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Partnerships with universities, non-profits, industry and the Federal Government are important for the chemical industry's success. The transfer of technology from federally funded research to industry helps promote innovation, which helps the United States remain competitive in a global economy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Federal support of green chemistry can produce many benefits. First, companies will be able to produce more products less harmful to humans and the environment. Second, businesses will benefit from the facilitation of green chemistry research by the Federal Government and the subsequent transfer of technology to the private sector.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill presents opportunities to reduce impact on the environment while assisting our domestic industry to find new products through innovation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Recently, Columbia Forest Products, a company in my district, received an award for an innovation in green chemistry. The company produces interior plywood products. In collaboration with Oregon State University, Columbia Forest Products has created a soy-based product to use for its production of plywood, instead of traditional urea-formaldehyde resin.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2850">H.R. 2850</bill> will help create more opportunities for universities and companies to partner in green chemistry innovation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Washington (Mr. Baird) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="2850">H.R. 2850</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the bill, as amended, was passed.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
