<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1184817600" ordinal="21" title="RECOGNIZING THE MARINES OF COMPANY M ON THEIR 25TH ANNUAL REUNION">
  <narrative>RECOGNIZING THE MARINES OF COMPANY M ON THEIR 25TH ANNUAL REUNION -- (House of Representatives - July 19, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H8125]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400396" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Armed Services be discharged from further consideration of the resolution (<bill type="hr" number="541">H. Res. 541</bill>) recognizing the Marines of Company M (or "Mike Company") of the 3rd Battalion, 7th Regiment, 1st Marine Division on the occasion of their 25th Annual Reunion, and ask for its immediate consideration in the House.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the resolution.</narrative>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from California?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the resolution, as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="hr" number="541">H. Res. 541</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas the Marines of Company M (or "Mike Company") of the 3rd Battalion, 7th Regiment, 1st Marine Division served honorably and heroically in the Republic of Vietnam from July 1965 to October 1970 in defense of freedom, liberty, and political self-determination for the South Vietnamese people;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, during this period of more than five years, 137 Marines of Mike Company were killed in action and more than 1,000 were wounded in action;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, in recognition of its outstanding service, numerous unit awards were bestowed upon Mike Company, including--</narrative>
  <narrative>(1) Presidential Unit Citation Streamer with two Bronze Stars;</narrative>
  <narrative>(2) Navy Unit Commendation Streamer;</narrative>
  <narrative>(3) Meritorious Unit Commendation Streamer with two Bronze Stars;</narrative>
  <narrative>(4) National Defense Service Streamer;</narrative>
  <narrative>(5) Vietnam Service Streamer with two Silver Stars and three Bronze Stars;</narrative>
  <narrative>(6) Vietnam Cross of Gallantry with Palm Streamer; and</narrative>
  <narrative>(7) Vietnam Meritorious Unit Citation Civil Actions Streamer;</narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas the Marines of Mike Company have formed the Mike 3/7 Vietnam Association to honor the memories of their fallen comrades, celebrate the lives of their surviving comrades, express profound appreciation to their families and loved ones, recognize their monumental sacrifices and achievements, and immortalize their contribution to the Marine Corps legacy of courage, patriotism, and military excellence for the edification of, and emulation by, future generations;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, in pursuit of this goal, the Marines of Mike Company, along with their families, friends, and loved ones, decided to hold an annual reunion, with the first reunion having taken place on November 10, 1983, the 208th birthday of the Marine Corps; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Americans owe a debt of gratitude to the Marines of Mike Company for their selfless dedication to duty and their admirable display of courage under fire: Now, therefore, be it</narrative>
  <narrative> Resolved, &lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; That the House of Representatives, on behalf of a grateful nation, recognizes and commends the Marines of Company M (or "Mike Company") of the 3rd Battalion, 7th Regiment, 1st Marine Division on the occasion of their 25th Annual Reunion, which is being held this year in the District of Columbia.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <narrative>The resolution was agreed to.</narrative>
  <narrative>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</narrative>
</record>
