<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1214409602" ordinal="55" title="CIVIL RIGHTS FOR THE DISABLED">
  <narrative>CIVIL RIGHTS FOR THE DISABLED -- (House of Representatives - June 25, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H6083]</narrative>
  <narrative>(Ms. JACKSON-LEE of Texas asked and was given permission to address the House for 1 minute and to revise and extend her remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400199" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise to enthusiastically support the legislation that we just debated on the floor of the House. Having been detained in my Committee on Transportation Security and Critical Infrastructure during the debate, I wanted to come and support <bill type="h" number="3195">H.R. 3195</bill>, the ADA Restoration Act of 2007. This is truly a civil rights initiative, and it is important to restore the basic support and rights of those who are disabled in America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, through the Supreme Court's narrow decision and definition  of the word "disability," it made it very difficult for individuals with serious health conditions such as epilepsy, diabetes, cancer, muscular dystrophy, multiple sclerosis, and severe intellectual impairments to prove that they qualify for protection under the ADA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Supreme Court narrowed that definition in two ways: one by ruling that mitigation measures that help control an impairment, like medicine or hearing aids or other devices, must be considered a deserving disability; and, two, ruling that the elements of the definition must be interpreted strictly to create a demanding standard for qualifying as disabled.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, enough is enough. The civil rights of all Americans are an important constitutional element. We hold these truths to be self-evident that we are all created equal. This legislation, <bill type="h" number="3195">H.R. 3195</bill>, restores those rights. And I would like to affirm that my vote in the Judiciary Committee was a resounding "yes." The fact that I was detained, I want that to be reflected in the report.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is an important bill. This bill is heavily supported, and I throw my support to a new civil rights law in America.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
