<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1197565202" ordinal="11" title="HONORING FORMER LIEUTENANT GOVERNOR KARL OHS">
  <narrative>HONORING FORMER LIEUTENANT GOVERNOR KARL OHS -- (House of Representatives - December 13, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H15418]</narrative>
  <narrative>(Mr. REHBERG asked and was given permission to address the House for 1 minute and to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400335" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I rise today to honor one of Montana's most dedicated public servants, former Lieutenant Governor Karl Ohs. Last month Karl passed away in his Helena home due to complications caused by brain cancer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Born in Malta, Montana, in 1946, Karl was the portrait of a Montana farmer and rancher. Whether it was studying agricultural economics at Montana State University, meeting with fellow ag producers to discuss economic opportunities in the State, or working  the ranch, Karl was a vital supporter of our leading industry.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>His work on behalf of rural priorities didn't stop there. During his three terms in the House of Representatives and his 4 years as Lieutenant Governor, Karl was a proven leader. As a member of the Governor's advisory task force on drought and chairman of the National Lieutenant Governors Association, Karl represented Montana's needs not only on the State but on the national level. Additionally, his prominent role as mediator between the antigovernment Freeman and the FBI during a 1996 standoff,  for which he was awarded the FBI's highest civil service award, solidified Karl's status as a hardworking, straight-shooting cowboy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, in 2006, as chairman of the Montana Republican Party, Karl helped Republicans regain control of the State House, the only State in the Nation to see a legislative body change from Democrat to Republican control.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Most importantly, Karl was a dedicated father, a loving husband, and a good friend, who left a permanent impression on those who knew him.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>God rest his soul.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
