<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1181145609" ordinal="43" title="H-PRIZE ACT OF 2007">
  <speaking speaker="400630" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="632">H.R. 632</bill>) to authorize the Secretary of Energy to establish monetary prizes for achievements in overcoming scientific and technical barriers associated with hydrogen energy, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Lipinski) and the gentleman from South Carolina (Mr. Inglis) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400630" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and to include extraneous material on <bill type="h" number="632">H.R. 632</bill>, the bill now under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Illinois?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400630" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of <bill type="h" number="632">H.R. 632</bill>, the H-Prize Act of 2007, an innovative bill I introduced, along with Mr. Inglis of South Carolina, and that we passed in this House last year by a vote of 416-6.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>America faces a great challenge today, finding a new clean energy source that will free us from our dependence on foreign oil and will combat global climate change. Hydrogen has great potential to be this new source and the H-Prize Act will help focus America's technological and entrepreneurial talent on making it happen.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Hydrogen-fuel cars already exist. Last year I had the opportunity to drive a hydrogen-fuel car. It didn't drive much differently than a gas-powered car, except for the silence, silence that I am used to somewhat from driving a hybrid. But that was the only real performance difference. There is no performance difference. The only difference I know of is the silence.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But there are really currently significant technical and economic barriers that must still be overcome before we can put a hydrogen car in every American garage. Current hydrogen-powered vehicles cost about $1 million. But while several significant technological advances are necessary, they are within reach.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Just yesterday, it was reported in the Chicago Tribune that engineers at Purdue University are researching methods of producing hydrogen gas by combining aluminum with another metal, gallium, and adding water. This research could yield ways of overcoming hydrogen storage problems, allowing automobile engines to burn this gas with little modification.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While we must continue to invest in traditional grants to fund university research, we in Congress have the responsibility to find creative and new ways to inspire researchers, business leaders and our youth to solve the problems that society faces today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The H-Prize will help expand the possibility of hydrogen research, promoting people not normally involved in Federal research to explore one of the greatest challenges facing us today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Specifically, this legislation would establish competitively awarded cash prizes to spur innovations that advance the use of hydrogen as a fuel for transportation. Every 2 years, four $1 million prizes would be given for advances in the production, storage, distribution and utilization of hydrogen, and one $4 million prize would be awarded for advances in prototype hydrogen vehicles. At the end of 10 years, one grand prize of $10 million would be given for a transformational advance in hydrogen  energy technology.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to this $10 million grand prize, we are also seeking to raise up to $40 million to add to that grand prize, $40 million in private contributions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When these advances are made, hydrogen can fill critical energy needs even beyond transportation. Hydrogen will also be used to provide heat and generate electricity. The future possibilities of this energy source are enormous.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Most importantly, hydrogen will be a clean, domestic energy source. When used for energy, hydrogen produces no emissions besides water, zero emissions, an amazing advance over current energy resources. By utilizing hydrogen, we can improve our national security by lessening our dependence on foreign oil that often comes from unstable countries.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, America has always been at the forefront of technological breakthroughs. We have responded to great challenges, perhaps most famously, President John F. Kennedy's challenge to land a man on the moon before the end of the 1960s. We have seen that prizes have been an effective way to inspire technological advances.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Perhaps most famously the prize won by Lindbergh for his successful nonstop flight across the Atlantic. More recently, the Ansari X-Prize given to the first private team to build and fly a spaceship 100 kilometers above earth. The H-Prize is patterned after this X-Prize.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have seen that challenges and prizes help to spark the imagination of scientists, engineers and entrepreneurs, who invest blood, sweat, tears and often large sums of money, sums of money even larger than the prizes being given, to achieve a great goal.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask my colleagues to join me in supporting this bill today. Perhaps one day we will look back on the H-Prize as a catalyst to a better, cleaner, more secure America and world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400649" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 4 minutes to one of the co-chairs of the House Hydrogen Caucus, CHARLIE DENT from Pennsylvania.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400648" topic="">
    <paragraph>I too want to thank the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Lipinski) and the gentleman from South Carolina (Mr. Inglis) for working together so well to bring this important piece of legislation to the floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I was proud to join 415 of my colleagues in supporting this bill last Congress, and I am pleased that the H-Prize Act has been brought up again so that we can have an opportunity to enact this important legislation into law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise in strong support of <bill type="h" number="632">H.R. 632</bill>, the H-Prize Act. The Constitution of the United States provides that Congress has the power to promote the progress of science and the useful arts. We, in Congress, have an opportunity and obligation to promote scientific advancement today. For more than a century, America's industry, transportation, and households have been heavily reliant on foreign oil. We must now face newer realities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Petroleum is a finite resource. No matter how much we explore and discover, we will one day run out and booming worldwide demand is burning up resources and driving up prices. We must search for alternatives to wean us off our addiction to foreign sources of oil. The drive to produce energy economically can be advanced to American innovation and competition.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Fossil fuel technology was the impetus for 20th century industrial development. Today, hydrogen holds a promise of being the driver for the economy of the future and ushering in a new generation of an American energy independence.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Hydrogen makes up 98 percent of the known universe, and it is the third most abundant element of the earth's surface. It is the lightest of all gases, the coldest of all liquids, next to helium. As a component of water, minerals and acids, it makes up a fundamental part of all hydrocarbons and organic substances. Hydrogen is renewable, abundant, efficient and clean. Unlike carbon-based fuels, it does not create fumes or other harmful emissions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In fact, using hydrogen in fuel cells produces only electricity and pure water. By awarding prizes in three of the most critical areas of technological development, the H-Prize Act will incentivize the realization of scientific advancements that will break down the obstacles that stand in the way of the hydrogen economy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Specifically, H-Prize will promote technological advancements in hydrogen production, storage, distribution and utilization. Prizes will be awarded for the development of hydrogen vehicle prototypes that meet ambitious performance goals. Finally, the bill will award the implementation of critical transformational technologies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are not that far away from making hydrogen a functional source of energy. <bill type="h" number="632">H.R. 632</bill> will speed the development of breakthrough technologies that will make hydrogen a practical alternative to oil in our transportation sector and set our Nation on a path toward energy independence. I strongly urge all of my colleagues to support <bill type="h" number="632">H.R. 632</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, I do want to commend the two gentlemen, Mr. Lipinski of Illinois and Mr. Inglis of South Carolina, for their strong advocacy on this critical issue.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400630" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400649" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 3 minutes to the gentlelady from Florida (Ms. Ginny Brown-Waite).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400051" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in very strong support of the H-Prize bill that we have before us, <bill type="h" number="632">H.R. 632</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation encourages the best of what this House can offer, and that is ingenuity and the genius of the American inventor. We have always known that when the American people in our free markets put our minds to a problem, there is no stopping them. When we faced the challenges of World War II, for the run-away inflation of the 1970s, American genius and the free market prevailed and delivered our solutions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today's challenge is for us to reduce our dependence on foreign oil sources. Our goal is to create a free market diversified portfolio of energy sources, so that we are never again reliant on one single source for our energy needs. Whether with wind, solar, nuclear or biofuel, this Congress' goal should be to protect the environment with as little prejudice for or against alternative energy sources as possible.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One might ask why? As we are already seeing with ethanol, we should never forget the law of unintended consequences. By forcing ethanol into our gas tanks, Congress has unfortunately raised the price of our gas and the price of feed for our livestock.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>Listen up, America. Our experience with ethanol should be a cautionary reminder of the burdens government regulation places on our economy and the everyday lives of American families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What is so brilliant about the H-Prize is that, unlike most of the programs coming out of Congress, this bill doesn't mandate a specific form of technology or add additional regulatory burden. Indeed, instead, the H-Prize encourages the inventor and the market to generate the ideas and solutions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, Republicans pretty much have been shut out of debate and denied amendments, but this bill was one of our ideas from the last Congress which I voted for then, and I certainly will vote for now. I commend you for moving a free market approach through to the floor so that the 110th Congress can also do the right thing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400630" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400649" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First of all, Mr. Speaker, I want to thank my colleague from Illinois (Mr. Lipinski) for his work on a number of energy initiatives that we're collaborating on. This is one of those. I think it's a very exciting bill that won't solve all of our challenges, but it will get us down the road toward a brighter energy future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And it's always helpful to have a picture tell a thousand words. This is a picture of a gas line in a province in China on August 17, 2005. That's a line of cars waiting to buy gas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>ExxonMobil tells us the global energy demand is expected to grow by 60 percent between now and 2030. So we've got to find something to do in order to get to a brighter energy future, one that does not involve the restricted supply that we have when it comes to petroleum. So what we've come up with is an idea of using the incentives of a prize to make it happen, to make some breakthroughs happen when it comes to hydrogen.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Well, the good news is we've done prizes before. In 1927, Charles Lindbergh won a prize for being the first to make a successful transatlantic flight. It worked with flight, and it worked again here more recently when the Ansari X-Prize was created to incentivize space flight. On October 4, 2004, Burt Rutan's Spaceship 1 became the first private spacecraft with commercial potential, succeeding in going into space twice within 2 weeks; and the result was they won the Ansari X-Prize.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So the concept here is to build on that kind of legacy and create the H-Prize. The good news for our colleagues is this shouldn't be a terribly controversial vote. The last time we did it, we got 416 votes in favor of the H-Prize. So it's a do-over with a 416-6 margin last time. So we're hoping that it's going to be successful here today on the floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As my colleague from Illinois just said, Mr. Lipinski was telling us that the concept is to incentivize breakthroughs in hydrogen technology; and, as he said, technical breakthroughs would be rewarded with a $1 million prize and then prototypes every other year, $4 million. And then the transformational technology prize, the big one, would be a $10 million prize, hopefully augmented by up to $40 million of private money that's authorized under the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So the concept is to, basically, create the most nongovernmental way to achieve a governmental purpose, which is to break this dependence on oil. So we've created the H-Prize. It's a way of incentivizing entrepreneurs and inventors to come together and to create teams that can make this breakthrough.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The beauty of a prize, two beauties of the prizes to point out here to our colleagues, one is, if nobody does it, you don't pay the prize money out, so they've got to win it in order for us to incur the obligation to pay the money out. That's a good thing about prizes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The second thing that's very important about prizes is the breakthroughs may come from way outside the normal realm that you would expect; and it could be that it's not the normal people or the normal suspects that might come forward with a breakthrough. It may be somebody way afield.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For example, hydrogen breakthroughs may come from biological agents that create hydrogen as part of their metabolism. That's way outside the field of where a lot of people are expecting hydrogen production to come from. But if you have a prize that isn't restricted as to how you create the hydrogen, then you get a lot more entrants, and you get interest from a broad range of fields that may come in with the out-of-the-box thinking that can transform our energy supply.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I'm very pleased that we've got it on the floor today. I thank the gentleman from Illinois once again for his collaboration on these topics. I'm hopeful that today we'll pass it with a large margin and that we'll be successful with the other body and then a signature by the President, and this will be one of the ways that we can break this addiction to oil and move to a more stable energy future for America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400630" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this legislation is another great example of what we have been able to do on the Science and Technology Committee by working together in a bipartisan manner. Led by Chairman Gordon, working with Ranking Member Hall, I hope that we can continue this cooperation on other critical issues related to America's future technological competitiveness, energy dependence and global climate change. This is the type of bipartisan work we need to continue to be doing to make  progress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I'd also like to thank Mr. Inglis for all the work he has done on this. We worked on this bill last year. We worked together on that, and Mr. Inglis is the one who came forward at that time with the original idea on this. He's worked very well. We have continued to work to make progress, and I'm very hopeful that this year we have worked with the Senate and the administration. We can get this past not just the House but signed into law. Because I think this H-Prize act has really  great potential. It has the great potential to solve the great energy challenge we face today. But perhaps it may be most important in spurring the imagination of our youth, our most valuable resource in this country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I remember in the 1970s there was great excitement about alternative energy. There was an environmental movement, and there was the gasoline crisis, and there was great interest in helping clean up the environment, investing in alternative energy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It's something that really got me excited. I was caught up in it when I was in grade school back in the 1970s. I remember I did my eighth grade science  fair project on solar energy. That was back in 1980. We saw, unfortunately, though, that the interest in alternative energy really dropped off after that time. Not only interest, but then Federal funding dropped off.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>Just in talking to the Science Coalition this morning, they talked about how critical that was when that research funding dropped off. We can't afford to let that happen again. But what did happen with me is it really inspired me, got me interested. I went out and got a degree in mechanical engineering, and although I did not continue down that road, today I bring that background to this House and continue to work on these issues, understanding the importance of this issue and understanding the  importance of the Federal Government's really investing in our future and especially in alternative energy. And these challenges are great. We must really confront them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So today maybe this H-Prize Act will inspire another child out there today. He or she may become an engineer or a scientist or an entrepreneur who plays a hand in the next technological breakthrough. So there is great hope with this H-Prize Act. And today, Mr. Speaker, I ask my colleagues to join me by passing this bill, and hopefully in the future we can look back to today and see it as a major change and a major move forward for America and for the world.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400204" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="632">H.R. 632</bill>, the H-Prize Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The federal government should become more involved in supporting cutting-edge technologies to reduce greenhouse gas emissions and move our nation toward renewable energy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a member of the House Committee on Science and Technology, I committed toward supporting a variety of renewable energy technologies--including hydrogen.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="632">H.R. 632</bill> would create competitive cash prizes to reward innovative research, development commercial application of hydrogen energy technologies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Hydrogen cars and other vehicles would make such a difference in air quality, Mr. Speaker, especially in Texas. Cities in Texas have some of the poorest air quality in the Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Hydrogen-powered vehicles could be designed for mass-scale use. These vehicles would emit only water vapor as a byproduct and reduce our dependence on foreign oil in the long term.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Hydrogen, solar, wind, geothermal, and nuclear are all cleaner energy sources than fossil fuels. <bill type="h" number="632">H.R. 632</bill> is a positive step toward developing energy technologies that create a brighter future for our children and grandchildren.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400233" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of the H-Prize Act of 2007, <bill type="h" number="632">H.R. 632</bill>, an important step forward in making America more competitive and energy independent. As a founding member of the House Hydrogen and Fuel Cell Caucus and a cosponsor of this bill, I believe we must move forward in fostering innovation and competition in hydrogen technology, in order to end our addiction to oil.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>According to the Department of Energy, major advances must be made in hydrogen production, distribution, and storage before it can be widely used as a fuel source. The H-Prize Act would excite and attract innovators throughout the country to take up this important task. Specifically, the bill would authorize $50 million from fiscal year 2008 through fiscal year 2017 to be awarded in cash prizes to non-federal entities in three categories--technologies created to assist in the distribution or  production of hydrogen; development of hydrogen powered vehicles; and "transformational technology" related to production, storage, distribution, or use of hydrogen fuel. And importantly, the cash prizes would only go to individuals who produce breakthrough results in these categories, spurring competition and innovation into much needed technology.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Solution to our energy crisis can be found in our backyard. Hydrogen can be produced here on American soil. Companies such as UTC Power and Fuel Cell Energy in my district in Connecticut produce hydrogen fuel cells which are a clean, reliable form of energy. Technology such as this can relieve us from our dependence on foreign nations for our energy and create a much healthier alternative for our environment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I urge my colleagues to join me today in advancing science and supporting <bill type="h" number="632">H.R. 632</bill>. It's time for us to take leadership and commit to the safety and health of our nation by inspiring our nation's brightest to make hydrogen technology a reality.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400630" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Lipinski) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="632">H.R. 632</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400630" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this question will be postponed.</chair>
</record>
