<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1182182403" ordinal="21" title="RECOGNIZING THE SIGNIFICANCE OF NATIONAL CARIBBEAN-AMERICAN HERITAGE MONTH">
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and agree to the concurrent resolution (<bill type="hc" number="148">H. Con. Res. 148</bill>) recognizing the significance of National Caribbean-American Heritage Month.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the concurrent resolution.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Davis) and the gentleman from Idaho (Mr. Sali) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days in which to revise and extend their remarks.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Illinois?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, as a member of the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, I am pleased to  join my colleagues in the consideration of <bill type="hc" number="148">H. Con. Res. 148</bill>, a bill that recognizes the significance of National Caribbean-American Heritage Month.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="hr" number="148">H. Res. 148</bill>, which has 53 cosponsors, was introduced by Representative BARBARA LEE of California on May 14, 2007. <bill type="hc" number="148">H. Con. Res. 148</bill> was reported from the Oversight Committee on June 12, 2007, by a voice vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>National Caribbean-American Heritage Month was established to recognize the historical relationship between people of the Caribbean and the United States of America. Caribbean Americans present a rich diversity of countries, cultures and colloquialisms which are dispersed throughout communities in the United States. Caribbean immigration to the United States reached its peak in the last 5 years, with approximately 6 percent of the more than 7 million immigrants coming from the Caribbean.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since the founding of the United States, Caribbeans have had a significant role in shaping the conscience of America and are among our great leaders, entrepreneurs and entertainers, including such individuals as Sidney Poitier, Harry Belafonte, Colin Powell, James Weldon Johnson, Shirley Chisholm, Marion Jones, Juan Carlos Finlay, Oscar de la Renta, Malcolm X, Jean Baptiste Point du Sable, the founder of Chicago, Marcus Garvey, and many others.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I commend my colleague for introducing this legislation and I urge its passage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412201" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, each year in June, we celebrate our strong relationship with the Caribbean nations and appreciate the value and diversity they bring to the United States. We value National Caribbean-American Heritage Month and encourage people from across the country to join with those of Caribbean-American roots in these celebrations. From as far back as the 17th century, citizens from the Caribbean have immigrated to the U.S. Many were slaves, who faced the same obstacles struggling for equality  and independence.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are a Nation of immigrants, and this bill emphasizes the many contributions of Caribbean immigrants to our society. Over 5 million Americans proudly share the Caribbean heritage in promoting and attending Caribbean-style festivals around the country. These festivals appreciate the rich culture, history and diversity brought forth through the joining of these two nations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge all my colleagues to join me in supporting passage of House Concurrent Resolution 148.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no further requests for time, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Davis) that the House suspend the rules and agree to the concurrent resolution, <bill type="hc" number="148">H. Con. Res. 148</bill>.</chair>
</record>
