<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1190649602" ordinal="16" title="RECOGNIZING ALL HUNTERS ACROSS THE UNITED STATES FOR THEIR CONTINUED COMMITMENT TO SAFETY">
  <narrative>RECOGNIZING ALL HUNTERS ACROSS THE UNITED STATES FOR THEIR CONTINUED COMMITMENT TO SAFETY -- (House of Representatives - September 24, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H10702]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and agree to the concurrent resolution (<bill type="hc" number="193">H. Con. Res. 193</bill>) recognizing all hunters across the United States for their continued commitment to safety.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the concurrent resolution.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the concurrent resolution is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="hc" number="193">H. Con. Res. 193</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas in 2006 there were over 16,000,000 hunters in the United States of which only .0013 percent incurred an injury during the past hunting season;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas in 2006 this injury rate was lower than many other forms of recreation;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas there are 70,000 hunter education instructors teaching hunter safety, ethics, and conservation to approximately 750,000 students successfully each year;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas State fish and game agencies began offering hunter safety programs in 1949, and since then, more than 35,000,000 people have been certified;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas much of the success of hunter safety can be contributed to hunter education training and the role of responsible hunters in the field;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Congress commends Pennsylvania hunters for setting a new State safety record in 2006;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas hunters continue year after year to improve their safety record; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas hunters are the vital link in preserving and maintaining the great natural  resources in the United States, including wild places: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved by the House of Representatives (the Senate concurring), &lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; That the Congress--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) recognizes all hunters across the United States for their continued commitment to safety; and</narrative>
  <narrative> (2) directs the Secretary of the Senate to transmit a copy of this resolution to the Pennsylvania State Game Commissioner and the Director of the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Davis) and the gentlewoman from Illinois (Mrs. Biggert) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Illinois.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days in which to revise and extend their remarks.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Illinois?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, as a member of the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, I'm pleased to join my colleagues in the consideration of <bill type="hc" number="193">H. Con. Res. 193</bill>, a bill recognizing all hunters across the United States for their continued commitment to safety.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="hc" number="193">H. Con. Res. 193</bill>, which has 91 cosponsors, was introduced by Representative CHRISTOPHER CARNEY on July 26, 2007. <bill type="hc" number="193">H. Con. Res. 193</bill> was reported from the Oversight Committee on September 20, 2007 by a voice vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would like to yield to Representative Carney as much time as he would consume as the sponsor of this resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412234" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of a bipartisan resolution that honors our hunters for their commitment to safety. I want to particularly acknowledge the significant bipartisan support from the members of the Pennsylvania delegation, a great number of whom have signed on this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This resolution honors our hunters for their commitment to safety and stewardship of the environment. Hunting is a beloved tradition. It is something I enjoyed both with my father, when I was growing up, and now with my own children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But as any avid sportsman knows, hunters must have a commitment to safety. We recognize that this sport requires maturity and responsibility. In 2006, there were over 16 million hunters in the United States, of which only .0013 percent incurred an injury. This low injury rate demonstrates a clear commitment to safety. In fact, in 2006, hunters in Pennsylvania set a safety record, and for this I commend them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>State fish and game agencies have been offering hunter safety programs started in 1949, and since then more than 35 million people have been certified. That is why I introduced this resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank hunters for their commitment to safety, and honor those who teach hunting safety. Hunters have shown that they can proudly represent the sport and put safety first, and that is something that I am proud to support.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400027" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>House Concurrent Resolution 193 recognizes all hunters for their continued commitment to safety and to increase awareness of the organizations and programs dedicated to hunting education and safety activities. There are currently 16 million hunters in the U.S., of which less than 1 percent incurred an injury during the last hunting season. Continued education on hunting safety will ensure lower injury rates for future hunting seasons. The success of these programs has allowed more than 35 million  hunters to obtain certification. Fortunately, we can continue to see high safety records with responsible and safe hunters who are well educated on hunting safety.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support House Concurrent Resolution 193.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I might consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, in 2006 there were over 16 million hunters in the United States, of which only .0013 percent incurred an injury during the past hunting season. To ensure and raise awareness for hunter safety, there are 70,000 hunter education instructors teaching hunter safety, ethics and conservation to approximately 750,000 students successfully each year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Hunter safety can be contributed to hunter education training and the role of responsible hunters in the field. This helps to lower the incidence of hunting accidents, improve hunter behavior and restore many species of wildlife abundance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I commend my colleague, Representative CHRISTOPHER CARNEY, for introducing this legislation, and urge swift passage of this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400027" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would urge my colleagues to vote for this resolution, and yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Davis) that the House suspend the rules and agree to the concurrent resolution, <bill type="hc" number="193">H. Con. Res. 193</bill>.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this motion will be postponed.</chair>
</record>
