<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1179763212" ordinal="25" title="21ST CENTURY COMPETITIVENESS ACT OF 2007">
  <speaking speaker="400437" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="2272">H.R. 2272</bill>) to invest in innovation through research and development, and to improve the competitiveness of the United States.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Oregon (Mr. Wu) and the gentleman from Florida (Mr. Mario Diaz-Balart) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400437" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and to include extraneous material on <bill type="h" number="2272">H.R. 2272</bill>, the bill now under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Oregon?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400437" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, <bill type="h" number="2272">H.R. 2272</bill> is the culmination of a year-and-a-half-long bipartisan effort by members of the Science and Technology Committee to pass a package of competitiveness bills in response to recommendations in the 2005 National Academy of Sciences report, Rising Above the Gathering Storm. <bill type="h" number="2272">H.R. 2272</bill>, the 21st Century Competitiveness Act of 2007, is simply a package of five bills, each of which already has passed the House of Representatives by an overwhelming majority over the last 2 months.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We created a single bill as a basis for initiating discussions with the other Chamber on a comprehensive competitiveness bill that we could send to the President for his signature this year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The five bills rolled into <bill type="h" number="2272">H.R. 2272</bill> are <bill type="h" number="362">H.R. 362</bill>, the 10,000 Teachers, 10 Million Minds Science and Math Scholarship Act; <bill type="h" number="363">H.R. 363</bill>, the Sowing the Seeds through Science and Engineering Research Act; <bill type="h" number="1867">H.R. 1867</bill>, the National Science Foundation Authorization Act of 2007; <bill type="h" number="1868">H.R. 1868</bill>, the Technology Innovation and Manufacturing Stimulation Act of 2007; and <bill type="h" number="1068">H.R. 1068</bill>, to amend the High-Performance Computing Act of 1991.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank Chairman Gordon and Ranking Member Hall of the Science and Technology Committee for their bipartisan leadership on this bill and, in particular, on the 10,000 Teachers, 10 Million Minds Science and Math Scholarship Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also want to thank the ranking member of the Technology and Innovation Subcommittee, Mr. Gingrey, and the Chair and ranking member of the Research and Science Education Subcommittee, Mr. Baird and Mr. Ehlers, for all of their hard work on the NIST and NSF bills.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also want to thank all of the members of the Science and Technology Committee on both sides of the aisle for their contributions to these bills and for helping to move every one of them expeditiously and unanimously through the committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I especially want to thank the staff of the Science and Technology Committee on the majority side, Jim Wilson, Dahlia Sokolov, Colin McCormick, Mike Quear and our chief of staff, Chuck Atkins; on the minority side, Amy Carroll and Mele Williams. And  my friend from the other side may have additional names to add to that list.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me spend just a moment reminding my colleagues why we introduced this bill and why we urge support today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 2005, the National Academies assembled a blue-ribbon committee of national leaders in academia, business and government to address concerns about national prosperity in the global economy of the 21st century. The Academies' report was titled Rising Above the Gathering Storm: Energizing and Employing America for a Brighter Economic Future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That report cataloged a number of worrisome indicators about the U.S. position in an increasingly competitive world and provided recommendations to enable the Nation to maintain its competitiveness. The core recom-&#xD0;mendations are as follows: Recruit and train highly qualified science and math teachers; sustain and strengthen the Nation's traditional commitment to long-term, basic research; make the United States the most attractive setting in which to study and perform research so that we can  develop, recruit and retain the best and brightest minds; ensure that the U.S. is the premier place in the world in which to innovate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill before us today goes a long way in addressing all of those recommendations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2272">H.R. 2272</bill> puts and keeps the National Science Foundation and the NIST research labs on a 10-year path to doubling their projects.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill helps to train thousands of new teachers and provide current teachers with content and pedagogical expertise in their area of teaching.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill expands programs to enhance the undergraduate education of our future science and engineering workforce.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill expands early career grant programs for outstanding young investigators at both the NSF and the Department of Energy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill strengthens interagency planning and coordination for research infrastructure and information technology.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, in this increasingly competitive world, where jobs are rapidly being outsourced and we are importing more high-tech products than we are exporting, now is the time to act. Now is the time to strengthen our support for the creativity, innovation and talented workforce that makes the United States unique and gives us our edge.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The day our universities are no longer the most sought after in the world, the day we see a brain drain because our best and brightest young scientists and entrepreneurs can't get the funding to do their research and technology development here at home, the day that our innovation is outsourced, that is the day that truly concerns me.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2272">H.R. 2272</bill> is a key piece of the innovation agenda to make sure that that day never comes. It has the support of many businesses, professional associations and higher education groups and has already been passed in its five pieces by an overwhelming majority of Members of the House on both sides of the aisle.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I once again want to thank Chairman Gordon and Ranking Member Hall and all the members of the Science and Technology Committee for their hard work on this bill, and I urge my colleagues to support <bill type="h" number="2272">H.R. 2272</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400108" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise today in support of <bill type="h" number="2272">H.R. 2272</bill>, the 21st Century Competitiveness Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As my dear friend and colleague, the gentleman from Oregon (Mr. Wu) just stated, this legislation pretty much packages five bills that have already passed the House with, frankly, an overwhelming majority of the votes. In order to force a conference with the other body, we're now again trying to put these together.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As was stated here just a few weeks ago by Ranking Member Hall and, frankly, right now by my dear friend Mr. Wu, <bill type="h" number="362">H.R. 362</bill> and <bill type="h" number="363">H.R. 363</bill> include many of the provisions from last year's competitiveness legislation, as well as additional recommendations from the National Academy of Sciences Rising Above the Gathering Storm report, again as Mr. Wu just mentioned.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This report and the President's American Competitiveness Initiative, known as ACI, have emphasized the importance of strengthening science, technology, engineering and mathematics education in the United States to ensure that the Nation's workforce can compete globally in high-tech, high-value industries.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It's imperative, Mr. Speaker, that we do all we can to stay ahead of the curve and ensure that the next generation of high-tech industries and products are developed here in the United States, as Mr. Wu just said. These provisions are steps in the right direction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Also, as part of the ACI, President Bush targeted investment in physical science research to be doubled over the next 10 years at the National Science Foundation, the National Institute of Standards and Technology, and the Office of Science at the Department of Energy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank Mr. Ehlers and Mr. Gingrey for their extensive input in developing these bills and my Democratic colleagues for incorporating our priorities into this bipartisan legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would be remiss, Mr. Speaker, if I didn't especially thank the staff. As you know, Mr. Speaker, they do an incredible amount of work. They do so usually behind the scenes, don't get a lot of the credit. There's a couple here that have done an incredible job. Margaret Caravelli is here to my left and Leslee Gilbert, who is also here, have done an incredible job, and we never thank them enough. So, therefore, I want to do that today here on the floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I'm glad that <bill type="h" number="2272">H.R. 2272</bill> includes Mrs. Biggert's High Performance Computing Act. This part of the bill will improve our investment in high-performance computing research.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2272">H.R. 2272</bill> authorizes an investment in our future, an investment for continued technological advancement, and an investment to keep the United States as the leader, frankly, in the global marketplace.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge all my colleagues to support <bill type="h" number="2272">H.R. 2272</bill>. I thank all those who have worked on it. It's always a privilege to work with my dear friend, Mr. Wu.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400437" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400108" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 3 minutes to the gentleman from Georgia (Mr. Gingrey).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400151" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise this afternoon to support <bill type="h" number="2272">H.R. 2272</bill>, the 21st Century Competitiveness Act, and I want to thank the gentleman from Florida for yielding. I want to thank my chairman on the Technology and Innovation Subcommittee, Mr. David Wu of Oregon.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation we are voting on today is a combination of bills which the House has already overwhelmingly passed, reauthorization bills for both the National Science Foundation and the National Institute of Standards and Technology, as well as bills to promote science, technology, engineering and math, what we refer to as STEM education in our country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last year, with the American Competitiveness Initiative, President Bush laid out a vision to maintain America's edge in the global marketplace. These goals were spurred by a report issued by the National Academies, and it was entitled, as the gentleman from Florida said, "Rising Above the Gathering Storm."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This report looked at ways in which the Federal Government could enhance our country's science and technology enterprise so that we can continue to compete and prosper globally.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Commission made a variety of recommendations. Some of them include reforming K-12 education, as well as expanding and strengthening the basic research and science and engineering conducted in America. This comprehensive innovation bill addresses these concerns, and it helps to fulfill this vision. That's why I am proud, proud, to be an original cosponsor of <bill type="h" number="2272">H.R. 2272</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One provision in this legislation reauthorizes the National Institute of Standards and Technology, NIST, an agency in the Department of Commerce, as one of the three agencies  highlighted by the President's American Competitiveness Initiative, and it falls under the jurisdiction of the Technology and Innovation Subcommittee of which, as I said at the outset, I am a proud member.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The NIST employees play a critical role in NIST research, which enables cutting-edge technologies to make the leap from a basic research situation into successful commercial products. This is accomplished at NIST by conducting research that supports United States technology infrastructure by developing the tools to measure, to evaluate, and standardize processes and products in almost all industrial sectors, bullet-proof vests all the way to nanotechnology.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>From rewarding younger students for continuing their work in the fields of science and engineering, to increasing the amount of grants available to teachers and students who pursue continuing education in the STEM, science, technology, engineering, math fields, to providing financial aid to students who make a commitment that after college they will teach, working to ensure that we have a strong United States manufacturing base, <bill type="h" number="2272">H.R. 2272</bill> takes many important and critical first steps toward keeping  America competitive.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I again want to underline my wholehearted support for the 21st Century Competitiveness Act, and I urge all my colleagues, as I know they will, to do the same.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400108" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I just want to urge the adoption of this good legislation. I thank Mr. Wu for his leadership.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400437" topic="">
    <paragraph>I would also like to thank my colleague, Mr. Mario Diaz-Balart, for his leadership on the committee and for his good works on these bills.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I just want to reiterate to my colleagues that these are five pieces of legislation which have already passed the House of Representatives by massive margins. I urge all of my colleagues to support this unified version of the bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400412" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, today I am pleased to support <bill type="h" number="2272">H.R. 2272</bill>, the 21st Century Competitiveness Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>America has long been a center for science and engineering discovery. Just looking back over the 20th century, American ingenuity has been truly incredible. From Ford's Model T in 1908 and on to the personal computer in 1981, American innovations have transformed our Nation and the world, again and again, creating whole new industries and occupations. Going forward, new innovations will continue to be critical, both in maintaining a solid industrial and economic base and increasing our standard  of living.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Federal agencies, such as the National Science Foundation, NSF, and the National Institute of Standards and Technology, NIST, play a key role by funding cutting-edge research and training the next generation of scientists and engineers. Without Federal investment in Science, Technology, Engineering, and Math, STEM, research and education, very little of this achievement would have been possible--and we must continue this strong Federal support to reinforce our global competitiveness and our prosperity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2272">H.R. 2272</bill>, of which I am a cosponsor, will help strengthen and improve research and education efforts at NSF and NIST, helping to ensure that the United States continues to be a science and technology leader. Specifically, the legislation will reauthorize both NIST and NSF, as well as update the High Performance Computing Act of 1991.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For NSF, <bill type="h" number="2272">H.R. 2272</bill> will continue the effort to double its funding over a 10 year time period by authorizing almost $21 billion for fiscal years 2008-2010. The bill will also encourage the participation of more scientists who have not received NSF funding in the past through 1-year seed grants. By targeting these grants toward these new recipients, the legislation will help support early career researchers and encourage higher-risk research.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation also includes a needed funding increase for overall laboratory research at NIST. As part of the American Competitiveness initiative, NIST will use these funds to expand upon its world-class research, ensuring that the United States will continue to be globally competitive in many industries. I am also pleased to see that the legislation reauthorizes and gradually increases funding for key technology transfer programs like the Manufacturing Extension Partnership, MEP, program and  the Technology Innovation Program, TIP.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>NIST is particularly important to me because one of its key laboratories is located in Boulder, Colorado, in my district. The Boulder labs employ more than 350 people and serve as a science and engineering center for significant research across the Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A critical component of this legislation is that it includes funding for construction at these laboratories. NIST's Boulder facilities have contributed to great scientific advances, but they are now over 50 years old and have not been well maintained. Many environmental factors such as the humidity and vibrations from traffic can affect the quality of research performed at NIST. In fiscal year 2007, NIST-Boulder will begin an extension of Building 1 to make room for a Precision Metrology lab.  This new facility will allow for incredibly precise control of temperature, relative humidity, air filtration and vibration to advance research on critical technologies, such as atomic clocks telecommunications, and nanomaterials. To complete this extension, NIST will need further funding in fiscal years 2008 and 2009. <bill type="h" number="2272">H.R. 2272</bill> authorizes this critical funding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As co-chair of the STEM Education caucus, I am also pleased that <bill type="h" number="2272">H.R. 2272</bill> contains support and funding for NSF's STEM education programs. These programs include the Math and Science Partnerships program and the Noyce Scholarships program, as well as several STEM education grants that focus on teacher professional development. These will help increase the number of well-qualified science and math teachers across the country, both through creating more teachers from current college students and  by providing better training for the teachers already in our schools.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to thank Science and Technology Committee Chairman GORDON, as well as Ranking Member HALL and the other original cosponsors, for introducing this critical bipartisan legislation and working to bring it to the floor today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think we all recognize that investing in basic research and STEM education is critical for a strong economy and national security, and <bill type="h" number="2272">H.R. 2272</bill> will help us improve the critical support for STEM education and research. I encourage all of my colleagues to vote for this important legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400199" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of <bill type="h" number="2272">H.R. 2272</bill>, the 21st Century Competitiveness Act of 2007. Innovation has been a priority of the new Democratic majority in the 110th Congress; we have worked to ensure that the United States continues to be the global leader in technological innovation and progress. I strongly support this legislation, which encourages our Nation to invest in research and development, and I urge my colleagues to do so as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>According to a 2005 report by The National Academies, the United States is in danger of losing the competitive edge it currently enjoys in the global economy. Despite our proud tradition of innovation, this report warns that immediate action is necessary to ensure that the United States continues to be a leader in technological progress into the 21st century. This Congress is fully committed to answering that challenge.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, <bill type="h" number="2272">H.R. 2272</bill> contains many important provisions to strengthen America's prospects for global competitiveness. It improves and strengthens a number of scholarship programs at all levels of study, encouraging students and young people to pursue further education in science, technology, engineering, mathematics, and computing. Additionally, the bill establishes programs to provide support for researchers in science and engineering fields.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2272">H.R. 2272</bill> also reaffirms our commitment to scientific excellence by reauthorizing the National Science Foundation, NSF, for 3 years. The NSF ensures a continued national supply of scientific and engineering personnel, while promoting basic research and education across a wide array of scientific and technological disciplines. By authorizing continued funding for this institution, <bill type="h" number="2272">H.R. 2272</bill> is an important step towards ensuring continued American scientific progress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the interest of both economic prosperity and military capability, the United States must continue producing a workforce knowledgeable to maintain technological competitiveness. If we are to do this, this Congress must continue funding and strengthening needed investments in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics education and research. Supporting this bill is an important step, and I strongly urge my colleagues to join me in supporting this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400437" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Oregon (Mr. Wu) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="2272">H.R. 2272</bill>.</chair>
</record>
