<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1182182403" ordinal="24" title="INTERNATIONAL NUCLEAR FUEL FOR PEACE AND NONPROLIFERATION ACT OF 2007">
  <speaking speaker="400231" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="885">H.R. 885</bill>) to support the establishment of an international regime for the assured supply of nuclear fuel for peaceful means and to authorize voluntary contributions to the International Atomic Energy Agency to support the establishment of an international nuclear fuel bank, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from California (Mr. Lantos) and the gentlewoman from Florida (Ms. Ros-Lehtinen) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400231" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from California?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400231" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in strong support of our resolution, and I yield myself such time as I might consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this bill is a dramatic step forward in the epic struggle to contain the spread of nuclear arms around the globe. Our bill provides a safe, efficient and collaborative means of getting nuclear fuel to any country that pledges not to develop nuclear arms and delivers on that promise. It will help ensure stability and expose the subterfuge that we know Iran is perpetrating in order to further its nuclear weapons pursuit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We know full well, Mr. Speaker, that Tehran is actively pursuing a nuclear weapons program. But many are persuaded by Iran's argument that it needs access to a reliable nuclear fuel supply to meet its civilian power needs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, of course we know that Iran's argument is bogus, but Tehran has used the illusory threat of a global breakdown in the supply of nuclear reactor fuel to argue that it must have its own facilities to guarantee that its reactors are forever supplied with fuel. At the moment, Iran is going to have two of these reactors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We know that the Iranian pretext has been long recognized as a gap in the global nuclear non-proliferation regime. A state can exploit the non-proliferation treaty's recognition of its good standing to develop peaceful uses of the atom and acquire potentially dangerous technology such as uranium enrichment. It could then turn around and use the technology to support a nuclear weapons program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our legislation, the International Nuclear Fuel for Peace and Nonproliferation Act, addresses this gap in the nuclear non-proliferation regime and removes Iran's pretext for its so-called peaceful enrichment plan. It does so by promoting the development of an international regime of assured supply of peaceful nuclear power fuel to countries in good standing on their nuclear non-proliferation commitments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our legislation, Mr. Speaker, authorizes $50 million to support the establishment of an international nuclear fuel bank supervised by the International Atomic Energy Agency. This money will match the $50 million offered by Mr. Warren Buffett to the Sam Nunn Nuclear Threat Initiative.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Sam Nunn program support is crucial to the realization of this initiative, but so is the political will of countries around the globe capable of cooperating in such a regime. So after this bill's passage today, I intend to work with key nations to establish the international nuclear fuel bank.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am very pleased, Mr. Speaker, that our Secretary of State, Dr. Condoleezza Rice, and our former distinguished colleague Senator Sam Nunn, who has perhaps done more to advance the cause of nuclear non-proliferation than anyone else, have fully embraced this bill, and the administration is on record supporting it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ours is a broadly supported, bipartisan bill. It would not have come to fruition without the enthusiastic support of my good friend, the ranking member of the Foreign Affairs Committee, our colleague Ileana Ros-Lehtinen. It was approved by our committee unanimously, a rare phenomenon in this era of divisive partisanship.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is imperative that we keep nuclear weapons out of the hands of Iran and provide a source of peaceful nuclear fuel to all countries that are currently flirting with nuclear development programs. I, therefore, urge all of my colleagues to support this most important measure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400344" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, again, it's a joy to bring another truly bipartisan bill to the floor, thanks to the very able and skilled leadership of Chairman Lantos of our Foreign Affairs Committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill, as amended, Mr. Speaker, is a version of the original introduced by our esteemed Chairman Lantos and contains several new and important provisions that I would like to explain today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The first of these addresses the supposed right of all countries to manufacture their own nuclear fuel through enrichment or repossessing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The central problem of this assertion, Mr. Speaker, is that there's very little difference, as we know, in the technology that is used for civilian or for military purposes. So countries such as Iran, which are undoubtedly trying to acquire nuclear weapons, can innocently claim to be establishing a legitimate civilian nuclear program, a claim which can be virtually impossible for the outside world to disprove. For this reason, the acquisition of a similar capability by more and more countries,  for whatever reason, means that the technology and the infrastructure needed to manufacture nuclear weapons will expand as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The continued spread of this deadly capacity poses an existential threat to the United States and, indeed, the entire world. We cannot allow this to continue. Unfortunately, efforts to stop this growing danger are undermined by a common but erroneous interpretation of the Nuclear Non-Proliferation Treaty, or NPT, specifically article IV, which some assert gives every signatory country an absolute right to enrich and to reprocess.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is both surprising and disappointing that many of the most ardent opponents of continued proliferation throughout the globe are also strong advocates of this supposed unrestricted right. In fact, Mr. Speaker, the treaty clearly states that the right to nuclear technology is conditioned by articles I and II, which are aimed at preventing the spread of nuclear weapons, including the capacity to manufacture them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As such, it is the responsibility of countries seeking this capability to go beyond mere assertion and adopt measures that will conclusively demonstrate that it can be used only for peaceful purposes. It should not be the responsibility of the rest of the world to prove that the opposite is true. Iran has taught us the deadly foolishness of that approach.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe that it is profoundly wrong to hold the security of American people hostage to this flawed interpretation. Therefore, we have a responsibility to the people whom we represent to openly state the truth, that the NPT does not grant to all signatories an absolute right to enrich and reprocess. And the U.S. must work with our allies and others, as Mr. Lantos has pointed out, to ensure that this position becomes an integral element in the global non-proliferation effort.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A second set of changes to the original legislation places conditions on any country seeking to host a nuclear fuel bank, as well as on states that wish to receive fuel from the bank. The most important of these conditions, Mr. Speaker, is that state sponsors of terrorism would be prohibited from hosting a nuclear fuel bank and also from receiving fuel from it. This provision is essential to ensure that terrorist states, such as Iran, especially in their nuclear programs, do not benefit from  the establishment of such a bank.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A further provision mandates that both host and recipient states have an effective and enforceable export control program regarding nuclear and dual-use technology comparable to that of the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, there is a stipulation that countries seeking assistance from a fuel bank cannot possess enrichment and reprocessing facilities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A final set of changes, Mr. Speaker, would ensure that any fuel made available by the bank would be at the current market price, thereby sparing U.S. taxpayers from the open-ended burden of subsidizing the nuclear programs of other countries.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With the inclusion of these measures, Mr. Speaker, I am proud to cosponsor Mr. Lantos' legislation, and I believe that it will prove to be a significant addition to the global non-proliferation effort.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I strongly urge my colleagues to support it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no other speakers, and I yield back the balance of our time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400231" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, we have no additional requests for time, and we yield back the balance of our time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from California (Mr. Lantos) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="885">H.R. 885</bill>, as amended.</chair>
</record>
