<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1185163200" ordinal="18" title="LEWIS AND CLARK NATIONAL HISTORIC TRAIL LAND CONVEYANCE">
  <narrative>LEWIS AND CLARK NATIONAL HISTORIC TRAIL LAND CONVEYANCE -- (House of Representatives - July 23, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H8193]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="761">H.R. 761</bill>) to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to convey to the Missouri River Basin Lewis and Clark Interpretive Trail and Visitor Center Foundation, Inc. certain Federal land associated with the Lewis and Clark National Historic Trail in Nebraska, to be used as a historical interpretive site along the trail, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="761">H.R. 761</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. LAND CONVEYANCE, LEWIS AND CLARK NATIONAL HISTORIC TRAIL, NEBRASKA.</narrative>
  <narrative> (a) Conveyance Authorized.--The Secretary of the Interior may convey, without consideration, to the Missouri River Basin Lewis and Clark Interpretive Trail and Visitor Center Foundation, Inc. (a 501(c)(3) not-for-profit organization with operational headquarters at 100 Valmont Drive, Nebraska City, Nebraska 68410), all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the federally owned land under jurisdiction of the Secretary consisting of two parcels as generally depicted  on the map titled "Lewis and Clark National Historic Trail", numbered 648/80,002, and dated March 2006.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Survey; Conveyance Cost.--The exact acreage and legal description of the land to be conveyed under subsection (a) shall be determined by a survey satisfactory to the Secretary. The cost of the survey and all other costs incurred by the Secretary to convey the land shall be borne by the Missouri River Basin Lewis and Clark Interpretive Trail and Visitor Center Foundation, Inc.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Condition of Conveyance, Use of Conveyed Land.--The conveyance authorized under subsection (a) shall be subject to the condition that the Missouri River Basin Lewis and Clark Interpretive Trail and Visitor Center Foundation, Inc. use the conveyed land as an historic site and interpretive center for the Lewis and Clark National Historic Trail.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (d) Discontinuance of Use.--If Missouri River Basin Lewis and Clark Interpretive Trail and Visitor Center Foundation, Inc. determines to discontinue use of the land conveyed under subsection (a) as an historic site and interpretive center for the Lewis and Clark National Historic Trail, the Missouri River Basin Lewis and Clark Interpretive Trail and Visitor Center Foundation, Inc. shall convey lands back to the Secretary without consideration.</narrative>
  <narrative> (e) Additional Terms and Conditions.--The Secretary may require such additional terms and conditions in connection with the conveyance under subsection (a) or the conveyance, if any, under subsection (d) as the Secretary considers appropriate to protect the interests of the United States. Through a written agreement with the Foundation, the National Park Service shall ensure that the operation of the land conveyed under subsection (a) is in accordance with National Park Service standards  for preservation, maintenance, and interpretation.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (f) Authorization of Appropriations.--To assist with the operation of the historic site and interpretive center, there is authorized to be appropriated $150,000 per year for a period not to exceed 10 years.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) and the gentlewoman from Washington (Mrs. McMorris Rodgers) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Arizona.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members have 5 legislative days to revise and extend and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Arizona?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, <bill type="h" number="761">H.R. 761</bill>, sponsored by Representative Fortenberry of Nebraska, would transfer to a nonprofit foundation an existing visitor center for the Lewis and Clark Historic Trail in Nebraska. The legislation turns the site over to the nonprofit entity which currently manages the facility in partnership with the National Park Service.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This measure includes a reversionary clause and other safeguards to protect the Federal investment in the center.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have no objection to <bill type="h" number="761">H.R. 761</bill> and support its passage by the House today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mrs." name="RODGERS, McMORRIS" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="761">H.R. 761</bill> and yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="761">H.R. 761</bill> has been adequately explained by the majority. I am pleased that Mr. Fortenberry has brought us this legislation that will benefit both his constituents and taxpayers across the Nation.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="412217" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, along with my colleagues from Nebraska, I am pleased to offer my support for <bill type="h" number="761">H.R. 761</bill>, a bill that would authorize the conveyance of certain federal lands by the Secretary of Interior to the Missouri River Basin Lewis and Clark Interpretive Trail and Visitor Center Foundation, Inc. and authorize the appropriation of annual funds to operate the Center.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The journey of Meriwether Lewis and William Clark does not belong to Nebraska, but to all of America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Lewis and Clark Interpretive Center features descriptions of 178 plants and 122 animals recorded by Lewis and Clark during their explorations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This center should be a destination for any person who is interested in American history, in the species of flora and fauna then found in the unexplored regions of our country, or in the spirit of expansion that helped form our country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to join me in supporting this bill authorizing the transfer of Federal lands associated with the Lewis and Clark National Historic Trail in Nebraska to the private nonprofit foundation. It is a valuable resource for every American.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400640" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I am pleased to offer my strong support for <bill type="h" number="761">H.R. 761</bill>, a bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to convey a Lewis and Clark visitor center in my district from the National Park Service to a well-respected non-profit organization. As the sponsor of this bill, I encourage my colleagues to support this important legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to begin by expressing my sincere appreciation to the distinguished gentleman from West Virginia (Mr. Rahall), the Chairman of the House Committee on Natural Resources and the distinguished gentleman from Alaska (Mr. Young), the Ranking Member on the Committee, as well as the distinguished gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva), the Chairman of the National Parks, Forests and Public Lands Subcommittee, and the distinguished gentleman from Utah (Mr. Bishop),  the Ranking Member on the Subcommittee for their outstanding work in bringing this legislation to the Floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Lewis and Clark Interpretive Trail and Visitor Center is the culmination of a vision that was outlined 20 years ago. Starting with the efforts of former Congressman Doug Bereuter, the Center's completion required a great deal of hard work and dedication for which the entire Nebraska City community should be proud.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would also like to take this opportunity to express my gratitude to Nancy Hoch from Nebraska City, who has played such a key role in the construction of the visitor center and its ongoing operation. Her vision and leadership have been instrumental in making the center such an outstanding success.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill is very straightforward. It would simply convey certain federal land near Nebraska City associated with the Missouri River Basin Lewis and Clark Interpretive Trail and Visitor Center to the related non-profit group, the Missouri River Basin Lewis and Clark Interpretive Trail and Visitor Center Foundation, Inc. The bill also authorizes $150,000 annually for 10 years to operate the facility. This legislation would actually save the federal government about $50,000 a year since the National  Park Service currently provides about $200,000 for the center.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is important to note that I worked with the National Park Service in drafting the language for the bill and this proposed conveyance fits with the long-range plans for the center. I also believe that it would be the most cost-effective option for the Park Service.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="761">H.R. 761</bill> is cosponsored by both of my colleagues from Nebraska, Representatives Lee Terry and Adrian Smith. A companion bill in the Senate, <bill type="s" number="471">S. 471</bill>, has the support of both Nebraska senators, Chuck Hagel and Ben Nelson.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Interpretive Trail and Visitor Center is an outstanding resource and impressive facility. The non-profit organization associated with it includes a committed group of individuals who have spent many years making the center a reality and ensuring that it provides a meaningful and educational experience for those who visit. This legislative action is needed to fulfill the original plan for operating the visitor center.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Missouri River Basin Lewis and Clark Interpretive Center is truly unique. It is the only visitor center or museum in the United States to focus on the flora and fauna and scientific discoveries recorded by Lewis and Clark.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Lewis and Clark Expedition was a watershed mark in American history. Two centuries later, the courageous story of these two outstanding explorers and the Corps of Discovery continues to inspire Americans of all ages. This legislation will help ensure that future generations will have the opportunity to learn about this remarkable journey.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again Mr. Speaker, I encourage my colleagues to vote for <bill type="h" number="761">H.R. 761</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mrs." name="RODGERS, McMORRIS" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="761">H.R. 761</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the bill, as amended, was passed.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
