<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1210003202" ordinal="27" title="SENSE OF HOUSE OF ESTABLISHING A NATIONAL TEACHER DAY">
  <narrative>SENSE OF HOUSE OF ESTABLISHING A NATIONAL TEACHER DAY -- (House of Representatives - May 05, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H3042]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400074" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution (<bill type="hr" number="952">H. Res. 952</bill>) expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that there should be established a National Teacher Day to honor and celebrate teachers in the United States.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the resolution.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the resolution is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="hr" number="952">H. Res. 952</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas the education of children in the United States is the foundation of the future success of the United States;  &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas education is critical for the creation of an innovative workforce and for increasing the global competitiveness of the United States;  &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas teachers help students cultivate the knowledge and principles necessary to be successful in life;  &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas teachers are held to high expectations, while often receiving little compensation;  &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas teachers help instill civic responsibility among students in the United States;  &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas teachers deserve annual national recognition for their knowledge, selfless dedication to their profession, compassion, and sacrifice; and  &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Tuesday of the first full week of May of each year is an appropriate day for the establishment of National Teacher Day: Now, therefore, be it  &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That it is the sense of the House of Representatives that--  &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) there should be established a National Teacher Day to honor and celebrate teachers; and  &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) the President should issue a proclamation calling on the people of the United States to observe such a day with appropriate ceremonies, programs, and activities.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Missouri (Mr. Clay) and the gentleman from Connecticut (Mr. Shays) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Missouri.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400074" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Missouri?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400074" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, at this time I would like to yield as much time as my friend from Florida (Mr. Klein) may consume.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412198" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of H. Res 952, legislation calling for the establishment of a National Teacher Day. Few professionals touch as many lives as teachers do. They provide us with the knowledge and skills that we need to succeed in life, and their compassion, sacrifice, and dedication to their profession deserves national recognition.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As the son of an elementary school teacher, I was proud to introduce this resolution calling for the establishment of a national day of recognition for our Nation's teachers. My mother and so many other teachers across the country spend their lives working to inspire children and open their minds to new ideas so that they can grow up to be successful in whatever path they choose.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am sure that each and every one of our colleagues can identify a teacher from their past who left a significant mark on their lives. I know that I would not be here where I am today without the motivation and encouragement of teachers from my past who challenged me to aspire to greater things and pursue my dreams of public service.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For me, the teacher who provided the greatest impact of my life is Dr. Leatrice Rabinsky, a teacher at Cleveland Heights High School in Ohio. She was one of the pioneers of Holocaust education. Her teaching and experience left an indelible mark on me and led me to introduce legislation, as a State Senator in Florida, requiring the teaching of the Holocaust in all of Florida's public schools. Florida was one of the first States to pass and implement this policy which is now considered a model  for Holocaust education across this country, and I attribute that effort to Dr. Leatrice Rabinsky.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe it is important to recognize the hard work of our Nation's teachers who prepare our students to build a stronger America. The education of our children is critical to the success of our country, and despite limited compensation, in many cases, and increasingly high expectations, our teachers rise to the challenge each and every day.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In Florida, the average teacher earns about $43,000 per year, and nationally, teacher salary growth continues to lag behind inflation. This day of recognition is critical for bringing national attention to the pressing need to invest more in our teachers and our public schools. By providing teachers with the support, professional development, and compensation they deserve, we will retain more teachers in the profession and see significant gains in our public schools. No longer can we ask our  teachers to increase their workload and raise academic achievement without providing them with the resources they need to do so.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Teachers are a critical component to our increasing global competitiveness, and once again establishing our country as a world leader in the global economy, teachers will play a central role.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I'm proud to have voted for the passage of legislation that invests in our Nation's math and science teachers this year providing roughly 25,000 teachers with assistance in pursuing graduate degrees, summer training, and other types of professional development. I am confident that this is just the beginning of new Federal support investing in science, technology, engineering, and math education and providing incentives to teachers who wish to engage in these specialty areas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our teachers are charged with a very difficult task as the pressure continues to grow across the country to increase student achievement. However, they have taken on the challenge with incredible perseverance and determination, and their dedication to our students and their profession deserves thanks and recognition.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I'm hopeful with the passage of this resolution, every American will take time from their day to acknowledge the teachers in their lives, both past and present, for their commitment to this important profession.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would also like to thank my distinguished colleague, Congressman Roskam, for joining me in introducing this legislation, and I thank the overwhelming number of Members who have joined me in support of the establishment of a National Teacher Day.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge passage of this important legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400370" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, we've heard from the Democratic sponsor of the bill. I would like to yield to the Republican sponsor of the bill, Mr. Roskam, who is from Illinois and close to Chicago, such time as he may consume.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
