<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1171386003" ordinal="34" title="RECOGNIZING KAREN HAAS FOR HER SERVICE AS CLERK OF THE HOUSE">
  <speaking speaker="400228" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today to congratulate Speaker Pelosi for naming the first African American woman to be Clerk of the House of Representatives. And in doing so, I want to recognize the outstanding service of one Karen Haas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the reason I want to do this is because earlier on in her career, Karen and I both worked for then-Republican leader Bob Michel, and she was one of three or four people that ran the leader's office and did an extraordinary job. She then came to work for Speaker Hastert and had the assignment of trying to find people who could keep this House under control. And because of her extraordinary skill and abilities, Speaker Hastert appointed her Clerk of the House, which  is an impossible job because she has to put up with all of us, and she also has to keep the House running.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>She is an enormously talented woman and has done a great, great job for those of us who serve in the House. Tomorrow is her last day as Clerk of the House, and I thank all of you for giving her a standing ovation for a job well done.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400189" topic="">
    <paragraph>Will the gentleman yield?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400228" topic="">
    <paragraph>Of course I will yield.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400189" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for rising, and I thank the gentleman for his remarks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I said similar remarks, as the gentleman may know, last week. But I certainly want Karen to know, I want everybody in this House to know, that the opinions just expressed by Mr. LaHood reflect, I think, Karen, the opinions of everybody on this floor. You have done a wonderful job for the House of Representatives as an institution, a great job for your country, and we know you will be a great success in the future. And all of us stand ready to tell anybody who wants to know what an asset  you have been to the House of Representatives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400228" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the majority leader.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Good luck, Karen. Thank you for doing a great job.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
