<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1185508800" ordinal="15" title="THE FARM BILL">
  <narrative>THE FARM BILL -- (House of Representatives - July 27, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H8747]</narrative>
  <narrative>(Mr. ETHERIDGE asked and was given permission to address the House for 1 minute and to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400125" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, later this morning the House will take up the farm bill, <bill type="h" number="2419">H.R. 2419</bill>, and let me just share a couple of quotes, one from the American Farm Bureau:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>"The farm bill is one of our highest priorities. We understand there may be a motion to recommit the bill back to the House Committee on Agriculture. We urge you to oppose this amendment. Without the additional almost $4 billion in offsets, we cannot adequately fund the nutrition needs in the farm bill." This is signed by the president of the American Farm Bureau Federation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And from 24 different commodity groups that affect labor and commodities in America:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>"Dear Members of Congress, we support both the underlying farm bill and the additional nutrition spending which gives rise to the need for an offset. For that reason we appreciate the efforts of Members of Congress who have attempted to identify that offset and we would encourage those who are concerned about the offset identified by the Committee on Ways and Means to support <bill type="h" number="2419">H.R. 2419</bill> despite those concerns.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>"In any event, we urge the House to move expeditiously to pass <bill type="h" number="2419">H.R. 2419</bill>. We remain hopeful that the long congressional tradition of passing farm bills on a bipartisan fashion will not be broken." And it is signed by 24 groups from the American Soybean Association through the U.S. Rice Producers Association.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>American Soybean Association</paragraph>
    <paragraph>American Sugar Alliance</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Arkansas Rice Growers Association</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Missouri Rice Research and Merchandising Council</paragraph>
    <paragraph>National Association of Wheat Growers</paragraph>
    <paragraph>National Barley Growers Association</paragraph>
    <paragraph>National Cotton Council</paragraph>
    <paragraph>National Farmers Organization</paragraph>
    <paragraph>National Farmers Union</paragraph>
    <paragraph>National Sorghum Producers</paragraph>
    <paragraph>National Sunflower Association</paragraph>
    <paragraph>North Carolina Peanut Growers Association</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Oklahoma Peanut Commission</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Panhandle Peanut Growers Association</paragraph>
    <paragraph>South Carolina Peanut Growers Association</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Southern Peanut Farmers Federation</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Texas Peanut Producers Association</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Texas Peanut Producers Board</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Western Peanut Growers</paragraph>
    <paragraph>United Egg Producers</paragraph>
    <paragraph>USA Dry Pea &amp; Lentil Council</paragraph>
    <paragraph>USA Rice Federation</paragraph>
    <paragraph>US Canola Association</paragraph>
    <paragraph>US Rice Producers Association</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
