<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1185985401" ordinal="40" title="CHILDREN'S HEALTH AND MEDICARE PROTECTION ACT OF 2007">
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DINGELL" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, pursuant to House Resolution 594, I call up the bill (<bill type="h" number="3162">H.R. 3162</bill>) to amend titles XVIII, XIX, and XXI of the Social Security Act to extend and improve the children's health insurance program, to improve beneficiary protections under the Medicare, Medicaid, and the CHIP program, and for other purposes, and ask for its immediate consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to House Resolution 594, the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in the bill, modified by the amendment printed in House Report 110-285, is adopted and the bill, as amended, is considered read.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="RANGEL" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of this great piece of legislation that this august body has the privilege of supporting.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There may be some concerns in the House, some with merit, about procedure, but we on the Ways and Means Committee are so proud of the work that has been done by the subcommittee, led by Mr. Stark, working with Mr. Camp, that we had 15 hearings on what was involved in this bill and a half a dozen sessions where we just talked with the professionals to make certain that not only did we support the great work that had been done by the Dean of our House in terms of education, in  terms of Energy and Commerce and the SCHIP bill, but so at the same time we could preserve the benefits that are provided to our senior citizens through medical programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Stark did one great job at making certain that we worked with the administration, tried to find out where the abuses were and, where we could, we were able to raise $15 billion so that the poorest of our seniors would have the ability to receive health care enhanced.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>Of course, those who live in rural areas and who for years have not be able to receive the type of access to health care, we found $5 billion to do it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am not thoroughly convinced as to what PAYGO is going to mean in the future, but it is the rules of our party. It seems now that it makes some sense. But when you say that you have to enlarge this program so that an additional 6 million people, kids, that are already on the program, adding 5 million people to it, nobody, Republican or Democrat, liberal or conservative, does not believe that these children should be entitled to health care.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is not just the right and moral thing to do. But in terms of being fiscally responsible, everyone would tell you that having a kid in the family exposed to preventive care actually costs less money than just ignoring the care of our children. I could go even further in saying that, even kids that go to school, if they are not well, they can't learn. And God knows we have millions of people in the street that had health impediments, that they thought they were educational impediments, and they  are out there. I personally believe that a stronger country is a healthier country and a well-educated country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, it is true when you have these PAYGO rules and you don't want to raise taxes that you have to find the money. And so it is a great deal of empathy that I have for our poor cigarette smokers, because I used to be one; and, two, I just don't like the idea of regressive taxes where the poor are penalized. But I am learning to live with it in such a sense that these cigarette smokers, these addicts, they hate themselves for smoking. And I have stretched it to the point that when I talk with  them and tell them what we are about to do, after they finish coughing and spitting, they said, "I have got to stop this smoking." Then, when you look at the little kids, this is the one thing that an increase in prices sharply reduces, it is kids going to smoke.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, I am trying to get myself to think that maybe I am doing it for the tobacco companies, because they advertise they don't want kids to smoke, and we are going to help them by increasing the price of cigarettes, which one thing is abundantly clear, it will stop a lot of children from smoking.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I am going to yield the rest of my time to the gentleman from California, PETE STARK, who has done such a fantastic job in finding out where the problems were and bringing to this floor not only a great child insurance bill, but also improving Medicare, increasing the benefits of our seniors who are poor and help into rural areas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While we may have a lot of procedural differences, and I understand that, I just hope that whether you are Republican or Democrat that you feel comfortable being able to say that there may be some pain for cigarette smokers who really are costing us a lot of money with these lung transplants and whatnot. But that is painful enough.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So you may have some problem with your smokers. But just think about 11 million children and their families that love them so much and a country that wants them healthy, and I am certain that at the end of the day that the kids  are going to win, we will have a better health care delivery system, and you will feel very, very comfortable in talking about the procedural differences that you differed with. But, in your heart, you would know that every major  advocate for children and health and hospitals and doctors have signed up saying, "do the right thing." I personally believe that that is what you are going to do today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield the balance of my time to the gentleman from California, PETE STARK, the chairman of the Subcommittee on Health, and I thank him publicly, and the staff, for the fantastic job that they have done in having hearings and letting all Members have a better understanding of the problem, but, better than that, in being able to bring a solution to this floor today.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> Without objection, the gentleman from California will manage the remainder of the time for the Ways and Means Committee majority.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that there be one 1 hour of additional debate, equally divided between the majority and the minority, and within each of those subsegments, equally divided between the Ways and Means Committee and the Energy and Commerce Committee.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Texas?</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="STARK" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I object.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> Objection is heard. The time will remain the same.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DINGELL" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I hope that my good friend from California will not object.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would repeat that unanimous consent request.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DINGELL" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would hope my good friend would not object.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="STARK" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the right to object. I may discuss it at a later point, but at this time, I must object.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The gentleman from California reserves the right to object.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, does that mean we discuss the reservation now?</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DINGELL" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, reserving the right to object.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="STARK" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I object.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The gentleman from California has reserved the right to object.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="STARK" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I object.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> Now he objects. The gentleman from California objects.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="STARK" of="">
    <paragraph>Yes, Mr. Speaker, I object.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="RANGEL" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, may I be recognized to respond?</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> For what purpose does the gentleman from New York rise?</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="RANGEL" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, it appears as though the decision for extra time should be one that our leadership should have decided on. It just seems to me that since our leader has not been conferred with, that if you just reserve the opportunity, that in a very short while we will be able to discuss this.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, if the gentleman will yield, we have, just from the Energy and Commerce Committee on the minority side, a request for 25 speakers, plus several of our leadership. So if this unanimous consent request were to be agreed to, it would give each committee on both sides of the aisle an additional 15 minutes. I am sure there are many Members on the majority side, as on the minority, that wish to speak. I will offer it later on if you want to check on it.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="RANGEL" of="">
    <paragraph>Well, Mr. Speaker, the minority somehow manages to find time to speak on this and many other subjects. But I am saying that under normal conditions, you would think that your leadership would have discussed this issue with ours so that at some times the Members would know exactly what to expect.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, I don't see any reason why this should not be agreed upon, but I just don't think Members can come to the floor by unanimous consent and ask for an hour or 2 hours or 3 hours. We don't even know whether or not the minority intends to follow any other procedures that could kind of take away floor time in terms of debates and exchanges. Just based on some of the things that I've seen from your committee, it appears to me that we have to find out what you want to do with that hour.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, if the gentleman will yield, the gentleman has every right to be suspicious of the ranking member of the Energy and Commerce Committee. I am a devious fellow and I reserve all my options. But on this one, we were shooting straight and dealing off the top of the deck.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The gentleman from California has objected. Does the gentleman stand to object, or does he withdraw his objection?</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="STARK" of="">
    <paragraph>I object.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DINGELL" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I am going to make the same unanimous consent request, and then I will withdraw it. But first I want to make an observation here for the benefit of all of my colleagues and friends.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a very important piece of legislation. I am not going to defend the behavior of any Member here, and I am not going to criticize the behavior of any Member, but I am going to make an observation that I think is important.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a very important piece of legislation. Twelve million of our kids are going to have their health insurance increased or not depending on how we conduct ourselves today. I want to have a broad exposition. If you look at the time that we have to give to Members who wish to be heard on this, we are talking about a minute or 30 seconds, hardly enough time for any Member to adequately make a position on something which is important to him and to the kids.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think that we have a chance to do a great deal of good for our young people. I don't think that it is excessive to say we are going to give enough time so that this matter can be properly discussed, nor do I think there is any benefit in denying our Members the time to do this and denying the Members a chance to be heard.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, I am going to withdraw this.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The gentleman withdraws his request. Members may engage in debate by using their time.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DINGELL" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have asked unanimous consent and I reserved the right to object.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The gentleman cannot reserve the right to object on his own request. The gentleman reiterates a unanimous consent request.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="WAXMAN" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the right to object.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The gentleman from California.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="WAXMAN" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker and my colleagues, for goodwill, I would see it a wise course of action to give additional time, since the minority requests it, but I wouldn't be prepared to give them that time now.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The reason we are starting so late today on this bill is because we have been interrupted with procedural votes to delay us from debating this issue. In our own committee, the Energy and Commerce Committee, the gentleman from Texas said he had a lot of people from our committee who wanted to speak on the issue. They wouldn't let us debate any single issue of merit. They made us read the bill, to frustrate the committee from meeting at all.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let's renew this request for additional time later as a reward for good behavior, if we can see some good behavior. But right now, to this point, I haven't seen a lot of good behavior from the other side.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> Does the gentleman object or does he withdraw his reservation of the right to object?</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="WAXMAN" of="">
    <paragraph>I object.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I proudly stand for the First Amendment rights of even the Members of the minority, and I also stand for honoring the rules and the procedures developed over 200 years in the most Democratic body the free world has ever known, the House of Representatives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With that, I yield 1 minute to the distinguished minority leader from the great State of Ohio (Mr. Boehner).</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BOEHNER" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, let me thank my colleague for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker and my colleagues, the State Children's Health Insurance Program was created 10 years ago by a Republican Congress, along with our Democrat colleagues and a Democrat President. It clearly was a very bipartisan process from the beginning, and as we reauthorize this important program that Republicans, Democrats, the White House, everyone supports, I am saddened that we are here today with a very partisan bill done in a very partisan way.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thought in this reauthorization process, I know on our side, Mr. Barton, Mr. McCrery, their respective committees, wanted to work with our Democrat colleagues to develop a bill that we could all vote for. But that process never even got started. While there may have been some hearings in the Ways and Means Committee on this bill, there were no hearings in the Energy and Commerce Committee. We were presented with a 488-page bill the night before the markup. Now we have brought  this to the floor without a markup in committee, no amendments allowed to be offered by the minority and a limited time for debate. This saddens me and disappoints me. It did not have to be this way.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The result of this flawed process is a bill that expands government-run health care beyond anything that any one of us could have imagined over the last 10 years. I really do believe that Republicans and Democrats can work together to reauthorize this program in a way that will receive bipartisan support.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last November, the American people sent us a message here in Congress, but I don't think that message was, "I want you to cut my Medicare and I want you to raise taxes. I did not want you to raise my taxes."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When you look at the bill that we have before us, we have $193 billion worth of cuts to Medicare, a program to provide health insurance for our seniors. We are going to cut this $193 billion over 10 years, and we are going to raise tobacco taxes, which affects the poorest of America's citizens, and lay more of this tax burden on their backs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>In my district alone, some 14,267 seniors are going to have their Medicare costs increased, and about 73 percent of that number are likely to lose their Medicare Advantage Program altogether.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is not what the voters sent us here to do; and, believe me, the seniors in my district who take advantage of this very valuable program don't want to lose their benefits which will result from the passage of this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And so I say to my colleagues, we have a flawed bill on the floor today; and the flawed bill is the result of a flawed process. As I said last night to all of my colleagues, we represent nearly half of the American people. We have a right to be heard. We have a right to participate. And through the process over the last couple of weeks we have been denied the right to be involved in the process, denied the right today to be involved in trying to amend the bill to a point where we can have a bipartisan  product to send to the other body. I am disappointed by that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Later today, Republicans will offer a motion to recommit this bill, the only option that we have. And that motion to recommit will do this: It will reauthorize the SCHIP program for 1 year. There will be no Medicare cuts involved in this program, no benefits will go to illegal immigrants, and we will see to that in the motion to recommit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Fourthly, it will have a sense of the Congress that this bill should go back to the committee and, over the course of the next year, have the Republicans and Democrats on the respective committees work together to produce a bipartisan product that the President can sign into law. I think that is a responsible course of action, given what we have dealt with here over the last couple of weeks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would ask my colleagues to reject the underlying bill and vote for the motion to recommit.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DINGELL" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself 3 minutes.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <narrative>(Mr. DINGELL asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DINGELL" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the Children's Health and Medicare Protection Act, the CHAMP Act, is a good piece of legislation. It expands and improves a most successful program, bipartisan in character, created in 1997. That program has cut the rate of uninsured children by a full third. Some States have been able to ensure as many as 60 percent of the children who previously had no health insurance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill is about taking care of our kids. It is about taking care of the future of the country. Today, 6 million of our youngsters get their health care through the program. With this legislation, an additional 5 million previously uninsured children will be able to see doctors, receive immunizations, and get dental and mental health coverage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill requires that children receive priority in coverage. It allows States to cover pregnant women, recognizing that healthy moms make for healthy babies. I am certain my Republican colleagues on Energy and Commerce understood this point, because our clerk read this bill to them. As I am sure all of us there will recall, all some 486 pages were to be read.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The CHAMP Act does not allow one thin dime to be spent on illegal aliens. You will find this prohibition in section 135 of the bill. Nor does it create a government-run health insurance system. Coverage under CHIP and Medicaid are provided primarily through private health insurance. All but two States use some form of managed care for their programs. Nothing here will change that, and the newly covered children will be exactly the same kind of child in the same situation that every one of the  children now covered happens to be.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The CHAMP Act also covers and secures Medicare for the future. This past Monday marked the 42nd anniversary of President Johnson signing that wonderful piece of legislation into law. I was there.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The CHAMP Act shores up the Medicare trust fund, improves benefits for seniors, protects their ability to choose their own doctors, and these reforms effectively provide low-income seniors on Medicare with an additional $1,200 in benefits.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The CHAMP Act is an act of fiscal responsibility. Seniors in traditional Medicare will pay approximately three-quarters of a billion dollars in excess premiums to cover the overpayments now being made to HMOs, a great injustice. The things that my Republican colleagues are complaining about are that we stop that evil practice. The CHAMP Act also adds 3 years to the life of the trust fund by stopping these overpayments which are accelerating the insolvency of the Medicare trust fund.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I know that President Bush has pledged to veto counterpart legislation in the Senate that is much more modest in its ambitions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I include the rest of my speech for the Record and urge my Republican colleagues to read it. It is an excellent speech.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation before us accomplishes two critical goals. It will provide health care to as many as 12 million children. And it will allow our elderly to continue seeing their own doctors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The CHAMP Act--the Children's Health and Medicare Protection Act--improves a most successful program created with bipartisan support in 1997. That program has cut the rate of low-income uninsured children by one-third. Some States have been able to insure as many as 60 percent of their children who previously had no health insurance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, six million children get their health care through this program. With this legislation, five million previously uninsured children will be able to see doctors, receive immunizations, get dental care, and other coverage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation requires that children receive priority in coverage. It allows States to cover pregnant women, recognizing that healthy moms make for healthy babies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While I am certain that my Republican colleagues on the Committee on Energy and Commerce understand this point--because our wonderful clerk read the bill to them--I will restate it for others listening:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The CHAMP Act does not allow one Federal dime to be spent on illegal aliens. You will find this prohibition in section 135 of the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nor does the bill create a "government run" health care system. Coverage under CHIP and Medicaid are provided primarily through private insurance--all but two States use some form of managed care for their programs. Nothing here would change that. And the newly covered children are exactly the same as those now covered.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The CHAMP Act also secures Medicare for the future. This past Monday marked the 42nd anniversary of</paragraph>
    <paragraph>President Johnson signing Medicare into law. The CHAMP Act shores up the Medicare trust fund, improves benefits for seniors, and protects their ability to choose their own doctors. These reforms will effectively provide low-income seniors on Medicare with an additional $1,200 in their pockets.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The CHAMP Act is an act of fiscal responsibility. This year, seniors in traditional Medicare will pay nearly three-quarters of a billion dollars in excess premiums to finance overpayments to HMOs. Those overpayments will accelerate the insolvency of the Medicare trust fund. The CHAMP Act adds three years to the life of the Trust Fund.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am well aware that President Bush has pledged to veto counterpart legislation in the Senate that is much more modest in its ambitions, and I have received my own veto letter from the Secretary of the Department of Health and Human Services. They stand on one side of the debate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let's look at who stands on the other side: 12 million children. The American Medical Association. The American Academy of Pediatrics. The National Rural Health Association. The National Council on Aging. The AARP. The Federation of American Hospitals. The March of Dimes. The Children's Defense Fund. The NAACP. The National Governors Association, including the Governors of New York, Michigan, California, Illinois, and Maryland, and the Catholic Health Association--which notes that "the most  important pro-life thing the Congress can do right now is ensure that the State Children's Health Insurance Program is reauthorized."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A vote against this bill is a vote to deprive six million children of healthcare. A vote against this bill is a vote to continue the plunder of the Medicare Trust Fund by bloated private interests. A vote against this bill is a vote to deny seniors in Medicare additional benefits.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge all of my colleagues to stand up for what's right for children, seniors, people with disabilities, and taxpayers: support the speedy passage of the CHAMP Act.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself 2 minutes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To follow up on our distinguished minority leader, I want to say what the Republicans are for in this debate before we talk about some of the flaws in the pending bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are for authorization of the SCHIP legislation. We are for covering low-income and near-low-income children so they have health care benefits.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are for making sure that the States that are out of funding receive additional funds beginning October, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So we want to reauthorize the SCHIP program. We do believe that it should be maintained as a block grant program and not become an entitlement program. We believe it should be reauthorized for a specific period of time, not become an open-ended entitlement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We believe that SCHIP payments should be restricted to citizens of the United States and legal residents who have been here at least 5 years. We do not believe SCHIP payments should be allowed for illegal aliens who have come into this country without the proper documentation. So we are for reauthorization of SCHIP. We are for covering our low-income and near-low-income children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We disagree with our friends on the majority side on the number of individuals that we are talking about. We believe that children below 200 percent of poverty that do not have health insurance or health coverage today are in the neighborhood of 700,000, not 7 million.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But we do understand that if you raise the level to 400 percent, if you allow States to self-certify above that level so there really is no income test, we do understand if you do that, almost every child in America, 78 million children, could be eligible for some sort of SCHIP assistance under the majority Democratic plan. But if you restrict it to low-income and near-low-income children below 200 percent of poverty, we believe that the Republican substitute, which was not made in order by the  Rules Committee at 2 a.m. this morning, solves that.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="STARK" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Much has been said by the distinguished chairman of the Energy and Commerce Committee, by the distinguished chairman of the Ways and Means Committee on how this bill helps Americans. Five million kids will receive medical coverage insurance that they don't now have. Seniors will receive preventative care with no copayments. They will receive mental health care at parity. Rural benefits will be extended to the rural communities that need assistance for access to their population. Low-income seniors  will receive assistance in paying for their co-pays and their premiums.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill is fully funded over 10 years, something my Republican colleagues never did in the past. I want to remind my colleagues that there are many myths being floated around here today. It is important to note that 83 of my Republican friends in 1997 voted for an identical bill. The bill that they voted on has the exact same income eligibility that was passed in 1997. The minority leader, the ranking member of the Ways and Means Committee, the ranking member of the Health Subcommittee on the  Ways and Means Committee, all voted for this and included a cigarette tax to pay for it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And I might added that the reductions that they put in their Medicare bill were five times greater than the adjustments we made in the bill today. It included an increase in the Federal tobacco tax.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now I don't know what has changed. Maybe they have learned to hate children in the interim, but nothing has changed in the eligibility. It is the same bill. If it was good for you, then it is better now. And it does a fair thing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The public is sick of radical ranting. They want health care for kids and seniors, and the way to get that is to support the bill before us today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 2 minutes to the ranking member of the Health Subcommittee on the Energy and Commerce Committee, the gentleman from Georgia (Mr. Deal).</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DEAL" of="Georgia">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this is a program that started 10 years ago with a $40 billion Federal authorization of expenditures. The current bill before us would spend $128.7 billion over the next 10 years. When added with the State money, that is over $255 billion in taxpayer money over the next 10 years. That is over a quarter of a trillion dollars. And what do you get for it?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>CBO says you will cover 600,000 more eligible children, 600,000 children. You would be better off to give each one of them $80,000 in cash, and they would probably get better results.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1996, we had an immigration bill that provided that if you wanted to bring somebody and sponsor somebody to come into this country legally, you would have to say they would not go on the public rolls of Medicaid and other programs for 5 years. This bill removes that. CBO says that alone will cost $2.2 billion, and we let sponsors off the hook and we put them on the public payroll.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If we have a bill like the Senate was considering that would make 20 million illegals legal, that cost alone would be $140 billion a year. What it does, too, is it says, in the area of immigration, we are going to spend $400 billion paying for translators, not just to serve people but to enroll them in the program. That is $400 million.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now they can say this does not open it up to illegal immigrants just by saying that. CBO says it will cost $2 billion because they think that is the cost that it is. What they are saying is just sign an affidavit that says you are legally in this country. I have speeders who would just like to sign an affidavit saying they have a driver's license. I have taxpayers who would like on April 15 to sign an affidavit saying they didn't have any taxable income; just take my word for it. And if you believe  just signing an affidavit is a deterrent to people illegally in the country, then you also believe we can just put a sign at the Mexican border saying, if you don't have permission, just don't come in.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a ridiculous piece of legislation. It will undermine the purposes of the original bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DINGELL" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 2 minutes to the gentleman from Michigan (Mr. Stupak).</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="STUPAK" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I want to congratulate Mr. Dingell and Mr. Pallone on crafting a well-balanced bill and for all of the hard work you and your staff have spent on the CHAMP Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The State Children's Health Initiative Program was enacted with bipartisan support a decade ago to reduce the number of low-income, uninsured  children by expanding eligibility levels and simplifying application procedures.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 2006, SCHIP provided insurance to 6.7 million children. In Michigan, roughly 118,000 children are enrolled in SCHIP. Eighty-six percent of these SCHIP children are of working parents who are unable to afford private health insurance for their children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>SCHIP is vitally important to children living in our country's rural areas. Of the 50 counties with the highest rates of uninsured children, 44 are rural counties.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation commits $50 billion to reauthorize and improve the SCHIP program to protect and continue coverage for 6 million children. In addition, this legislation ensures coverage for an additional 5 million children that are eligible but currently uninsured.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am also very pleased to see the rural investments in the CHAMP Act which maintains Congress's commitment to rural America by extending a number of provisions that, if left to expire, would negatively affect rural beneficiaries' access to Medicare health services.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The CHAMP Act provides health care for children, expands preventive Medicare medicine for our seniors and helps make health care more affordable, available and accessible in rural America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I urge my colleagues to vote in favor of this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 2 minutes to the distinguished former Speaker of the House and currently the ranking member of the Energy and Air Quality Subcommittee of the Energy and Commerce Committee, the gentleman from the great State of Illinois (Mr. Hastert).</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="HASTERT" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I stand somewhat chagrined that we bring this bill to the floor of this great House, the floor that deliberates on the issues that take care of the needs of people, but this bill comes under a charade, a charade that we are going to help the poorest and most disadvantaged children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>The SCHIP program that we put in place 10 years ago started to do that, and we can't expand that, but this bill covers people up to four times of poverty. That is a family of four earning $82,000 a year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What it does is say if you go out into the private sector and you continue to buy health care for you and your family, you're going to pay a tax, and that tax will fund other people, not just children, but expand the amount of adults covered by SCHIP, which is supposed to be for children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the State of Illinois, my State, 60 percent of the people on SCHIP are adults, not children; 40 percent are covered by children. If we want to cover children, let's change it so we cover children. This bill doesn't do that. This bill expands what we do for adults, adults that should be able to be paying their own way in American society.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What this bill does is open the doors for all other types of people to be able to be involved in government-paid health care, and that's the bottom line. It's government-paid health care. It's Hillary care all over again.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And what we do is take, at the cost of seniors who get Medicare Advantage, who get choices of their own health care plans, we take it away. We wipe it out, and we give it to people who are illegal aliens and aliens. And don't kid yourself, it's going to happen.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, if we want to take health care on the backs and take it away from seniors and give it to people who haven't made their way in this country, who haven't got their citizenship, then this bill does it. It's a bad bill for a bad time, and it's coming under the false pretences of trying to do something for children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Vote "no."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, it's unfortunate that today we are considering legislation which was rushed through the House without proper consideration in the Energy and Commerce Committee. There were no legislative hearings held by the Subcommittee or full committee on a bill that could cost taxpayers over $300 billion. That is simply unacceptable and the American people have the right to know what this bill is really about.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This Congress has the opportunity to correct flaws in SCHIP and bring spending in the program under control. Rather than return the focus back to our most vulnerable children, the CHAMP Act would greatly expand coverage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, it changes law to now define a child as someone as old as 21. It also expands coverage to more adults, and families with incomes upwards of 400 percent of the poverty line. This equates to an annual salary of over $82,000.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are sending the message to families across the country--drop your children from your private insurance--the American taxpayer will foot the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Furthermore, at a time when Americans look to Congress to secure our borders and enforce our existing immigration laws, the Democrat leadership, through the CHAMP Act, is taking leaps in the opposite direction by opening the door to free health insurance for illegal aliens.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It does so by removing language from the Deficit Reduction Act requiring proof of citizenship to receive SCHIP and Medicaid. This will make it nearly impossible for the Federal Government to prevent illegal immigrants from accessing these programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The American people are getting a clear message today from the new majority. They want your tax dollars to provide incentives to those who choose to break our laws and enter this country illegally.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And our Democrat colleagues would pay for this reckless expansion of SCHIP by cutting Medicare Advantage plans and significantly raising premiums on seniors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Millions of seniors depend on Medicare Advantage plans to provide the benefits they need and services they can't otherwise get with traditional Medicare. Especially our seniors in rural and underserved communities. The CHAMP Act will immediately eliminate these enhanced benefits and choices so many have come to rely on.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our Democrat friends are once again attempting to empower the Government to ration healthcare in this country. This will take choices out of every American's hands when it comes to their well-being and leaves the decisions to a government-run managed care system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Instead, we should be encouraging the participation of private plans regardless if it is for children, families, or seniors. This creates competition in the marketplace, which we know lowers out-of-pocket costs while expanding benefits for the insured.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe, given the opportunity to properly debate and offer amendments, we could ensure coverage to our most vulnerable children in a fiscally responsible way without raising taxes and sacrificing Medicare services for our seniors. Unfortunately Republicans were denied that right today. I urge my colleagues to vote "no" on the CHAMP Act.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="STARK" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I just remind the former Speaker that he voted for the same benefits in 1997, and nothing has changed since then.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield 1 minute to the gentleman from Michigan (Mr. Levin), who remembers what happened in 1997.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <narrative>(Mr. LEVIN asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="LEVIN" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, some issues are complicated. This one is quite simple. It's kids and more benefits for seniors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Five million more kids. I just wonder how many on the minority side are going to stand up and say no to 5 million kids, including kids where you live. Benefits for seniors are improved. And then we hear there will be benefits for illegal aliens, illegal immigrants? It's false. It's a lie.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This does not go to illegal immigrants. I did read the bill, and I also read the minds of the American people.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also read the minds of the American people. They want the children of America covered by health insurance, and the Republicans have failed to do it in their years here.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We're going to do it today for the 5 million kids in the United States of America. That's what this is all about.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise in strong support of the Children's Health and Medicare Improvement Act of 2007. This legislation re-authorizes the State Children's Health Insurance Program and improves Medicare for all beneficiaries.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Some of the issues we debate in Congress are complicated. This issue is quite simple. It is about kids getting health care and seniors getting better Medicare benefits. The American people want the children of America covered by health msurance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The current health insurance program covers 6 million children nationwide, including 55,000 kids in my home State of Michigan. But when two-thirds of the 9 million uninsured kids in America are eligible, but not participating, we need to extend the reach of the program. Extending this program means giving States the resources they need to reach out and cover these 6 million kids.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This important legislation not only allows more kids to have health insurance, but it also  makes long-needed improvements to the Medicare program. Improvements include ensuring physician access for Medicare beneficiaries, lowering the cost of mental health care for seniors, eliminating co-pays and deductibles for preventative services like mammograms and colonoscopy screenings, and expanding programs that help low-income seniors pay for their health  care and prescriptions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Republicans reject this bill because it does not fit their rigid ideology. This bill is about a program that works and kids that need health care.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 1 minute to the distinguished gentlewoman from Nashville, Tennessee (Mrs. Blackburn), a member of the committee.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mrs." name="BLACKBURN" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I support the original intent of SCHIP to cover our low-income children at 200 percent of the Federal poverty level; yet the bill before us really strays from that, and we all know it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And we're debating this under a lockdown rule because the Rules Committee refused to allow Republican amendments to this bill, and I will tell you, I found that 1 a.m. meeting for the Rules Committee informative and entertaining in an unfortunate sense.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The debate on this, as my colleague said, is pretty simple: Who will manage and control the health care sector that comprises one-seventh of our Nation's economy. That's what this is about today. Are individual Americans going to have the freedom to make those choices or are those Americans going to be relegated to being a faceless file on a bureaucrat's desk with that bureaucrat making those life-and-death decisions? Our future health care system is going to be shaped by the way we answer those  questions on this floor today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under this Democrat bill, there will be billions spent to enroll children into SCHIP.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I encourage my colleagues to oppose this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DINGELL" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, my good Republican friends will be discussing process, and we want to discuss kids and the future of the country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For that purpose, I yield 2 minutes to the distinguished chairman of the subcommittee, my friend, Mr. Pallone of New Jersey.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="PALLONE" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, there shouldn't be any doubt here today about what the Republicans are trying to do. They are trying to destroy the SCHIP program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We spent 18 hours in our committee where they wouldn't let the bill come up. The substitute that they had in the committee would put so many barriers in the program that, in effect, the program would die.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Don't believe them. They don't want to provide the additional funds. They know that this expires on September 30, and it will if we don't do something today; that there will be a million kids that will automatically not have their health insurance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We're not changing any of the eligibility today. It's they that want to change the eligibility.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The fact of the matter is CBO tells us, and I have it right here, that this bill would cover another 5 million children who are currently uninsured.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, my colleagues on the other side know that the States have run out of money. Georgia ran out of money in March. They came to us and begged us for more money. States ran out each month of money. We had to put money in the supplemental appropriations bill because the States ran out of money.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We need a lot more money to make sure that these 5 million kids are covered. They want to stop that. They're not proposing to cover any additional kids. They want to cut that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There's no illegal aliens covered in this bill. There never were. There's no language in here that says that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is not an entitlement. It's a block grant set up by Newt Gingrich. Newt Gingrich was the guy who set it up as a block grant, giving the States flexibility. The States want flexibility. Some of them want to go a little higher. Well, it's George Bush, the President of the United States, that granted the waiver so they could have some adults or kids at higher incomes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Who are you kidding? This is a Republican program, but you are now walking away from it. You don't want to fund it. You want to deny eligibility. You want to kill the program. That's what you're all about here today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And don't let anybody kid you. Eighteen hours we had to listen while the bill was being read. Today, they want to delay. They're kidding no one saying that they want an SCHIP program. Don't believe what they say. It's simply not true.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>You vote for this bill today to expand this program to provide more kids, not more eligibility. And if you don't, this will die and those kids are not going to have health insurance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have health insurance for our kids as Members of Congress. That's okay for our own kids but not for the rest of these poor kids.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> All Members are reminded to direct their comments to the Chair.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, page 76 and 77, section 143 of the original committee print repeals the requirement for documentation presentation for children covered under SCHIP.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With that, I yield 1 minute to the gentleman from Michigan, a member of the committee, Mr. Rogers.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="ROGERS" of="Michigan">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, a letter recently from the NAACP says: We strongly support maintaining adequate funding for the Medicare Advantage program that serves as a critical funding for accessing health care services, particularly for low-income and minority Medicare beneficiaries.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Talk about what's in the bill. Don't use children as your shield. This is the single largest cut to Medicare in the program's history. Absolutely, it is, and let me tell you what you are cutting. Read the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>You're cutting stroke victims from inpatient rehab. You're cutting doctors. You're cutting oxygen equipment and wheelchair services to seniors. You're cutting seniors' home health care, cutting hospital payments, cutting skilled nursing care for the sickest seniors in nursing homes. You're cutting dialysis services for kidney cancer patients. You're cutting imaging services for cancer and cardiac patients.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The list goes on. You're telling seniors once we slash the Medicare Advantage payments, we're going to push you on to part B, and guess what, your premiums are going up. We can work this out.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This was a Republican-generated idea when it started, SCHIP, to include those 200 percent or below of children in poverty, and I will tell you that there's not one thing that helps those kids under 200 percent of poverty, and you will get more of illegal immigrants at the expense of seniors. This is a bad bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The time has expired. Would the gentleman please refrain from talking on.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="STARK" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 1 minute to the distinguished gentleman from Washington (Mr. McDermott), a member of the Ways and Means Committee. Pending that, I would like to point out that he understands that in 1997 the Republican bill had five times greater reduction in Medicare spending than this bill does today, which 83 Members of the Republican party who are still in Congress voted for at that time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <narrative>(Mr. McDERMOTT asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="McDERMOTT" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the debate comes down to this: Do you favor big tobacco or children? Do you favor big tobacco and insurance company profits or seniors? We come down on the side of children and seniors, and that's what this bill is all about.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>You've heard over and over and over again there is no change of eligibility, but you insist on saying the same untruth because you want to make a point in the press. That is wrong. There are not any illegal aliens going to get in here. What we took out was what you put in. The fact is that we took out your requirement that people bring in papers when their kid is sick and dying, and you're saying to a parent, now you've got to prove you're a citizen before we'll take care of your kid.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That's what you're doing. You've taken your clothes off in public. You don't want to take care of children.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> All Members are reminded to please address their remarks to the Chair.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I'd like to point out CBO scores this as $1.9 billion. So somebody is not telling the truth on the floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield 1 minute to a distinguished member of the committee, Mr. Burgess of Texas.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BURGESS" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I thank the chairman. One minute is scarcely enough time to discuss what we need to discuss today. So I would, just like the chairman of the full committee, put my entire statement into the Record.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I want to confine my comments today to issues that surround issues for physician reimbursement. I had two amendments last night in Rules Committee that were not made in order that would have vastly improved physician reimbursement. Instead, we have language in the Democratic underlying bill that provides a small uptick for the next 2 years, then you fall off the cliff, and then you're frozen for the next 10 years. Hardly measures that will encourage people to go into the practice  of medicine in the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also want to reference section 651, the whole hospital exemption. Mr. Speaker, I would just point out that in the Rules Committee it was made in order that several hospitals would actually be grandfathered out or carved out of that exemption, and most of these hospitals lie in Democratic districts. I have a letter from 75 constituents, physicians back in my home State of Texas, who strongly object to the whole hospital exemption in this bill, and I will submit that for the Record as  well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Democratic party is prepared to take its first step toward cradle to grave government involvement in the lives of all Americans. The 40-plus page SCHIP bill that was unveiled to this committee in the wee hours of last Wednesday represents legislative malpractice. We shouldn't be surprised because we've been here before. A handful of Democratic staff, working behind closed doors, without any input from the real world have produced just what we should expect: a bloated and complicated proposal  that grows the size of government, diminishes state fiscal accountability and an individual's personal responsibility, and likely erodes the independent practice of medicine.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I doubt anybody in this body, Republican or Democrat, really understands what is in this proposal. We've not had one legislative hearing on this bill and haven't even taken this bill through regular order in the Energy and Commerce Committee. As a member of the Health Subcommittee of that panel, I'm disappointed in that fact because the subcommittee has shown an ability to come together and work out partisan differences. I haven't spoken with Chairman Pallone, but I imagine he shares  that sentiment to some degree.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Just recently, Republicans and Democrats came together to report out a bill that improves drug safety and FDA review of new drugs and devices. We worked through our differences and produced superior legislation. But all that bipartisan comity has been thrown out the window. Any rationalization of how we can vote on this bill and report to our constituents that we conducted an in-depth review of this legislation would be farcical at best, especially when we have learned that the Rules Committee  plans to report out a completely different measure in the dark and early hours this coming Wednesday.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Kids need a safety net, but the safety net shouldn't apply to those that can and should help themselves. Taking money from taxpayers to give it to families that have the resources to purchase health insurance for their children is irresponsible. And if affordable options don't exist for these families, well forget it, because this bill doesn't lift a finger to reform an insurance market burdened by regulation and lack of choice.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On immigration, this bill all but ensures that states like mine and other border states will be saddled with more cost as it rewards those that illegally enter our country. The debate on illegal immigration is often ruled by emotion but the provisions in this bill relating to immigrant health care are equally suited--this bill makes little to no effort to understand this dynamic and only serves to pour gasoline on an inferno.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On Medicare, this bill misses the mark widely. This bill would make a bad investment in an attempt to fix Medicare physician payment and in doing so, members will find themselves in the position of spending billions more in the future to fix the problem again.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We shouldn't fool ourselves that this is realistic policy making. For those members about to head home and face their constituents at coffees, lunches, and town halls they should be wary of what Speaker Pelosi is force feeding this body.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>BAYLOR MEDICAL CENTER AT FRISCO,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Frisco, TX, August 1, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR CONGRESSMAN BURGESS: We are physicians that practice at Baylor Medical Center at Frisco. Today, we are writing to express our deep concern about the language in the S-CHIP bill (CHAMP Act) once again attempting to prohibit physicians from owning or investing in any hospital. While this legislation contains many important and generous provisions, such as the reauthorization of SCHIP and the SGR fix, Section 651 virtually eliminates physician owned hospitals for no reason other than  the enmity of certain competitors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Much has been written about the negative effect this ownership has had on our community hospitals where we also practice. Many of the large hospital systems claim they are being harmed by physician-owned specialty hospitals in their communities. Yet none of them has provided any factual data to support their claim that they are unable to provide "essential services" as a result of specialty hospitals. In fact each of the last 6 years the American Hospital Association has reported a 6% increase  in profits in their member hospitals. And many of their arguments (e.g. "specialty hospitals typically do not provide emergency care") simply is not accurate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The benefits of the physician ownership model are so convincing that a growing number of not-for-profit healthcare systems, including some of the largest members of the American Hospital Association, have embraced the concept of physician ownership.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>MedPAC, CMS, and GAO have all studied this issue. Not one of them has concluded that physician owned hospitals represent a threat to the community hospitals where they exist. To the contrary, some have concluded that the overall increase in quality of care greatly benefits the communities in which they exist.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We believe that a major part of our success is due to the fact that individual physicians are partners in the ownership in the facility. As any business owner, we take pride in our facility and have worked hard to make sure the quality of medical care remains high. And frankly, we are much more aware of the costs and how to better deliver care more cost effectively. Through disclosure policies our patients are aware of the physician ownership and our surveys reveal very high patient satisfaction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The best way to manage health care costs is to encourage physicians to become involved in the development of new models for the delivery of surgical and other health services. Maintaining the status quo by giving acute care hospitals protection from market forces will only lead to higher health care costs for us all.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When voting, please consider carefully the decision you will be asked to make regarding physician ownership, it will not only affect your constituents' rights as a patient to have the most convenient cost effective care, it will affect the delivery of health care for generations to come.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincere regards,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>AMENDMENT TO <bill type="h" number="3162">H.R. 3162</bill></paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment would modify Title III of <bill type="h" number="3162">H.R. 3162</bill> that addresses Medicare physician reimbursement. While <bill type="h" number="3162">H.R. 3162</bill> provides temporary relief to address scheduled Medicare physician payment cuts, it does nothing to address the problem in the long-term, and would in fact exacerbate the problem in the long-term. The amendment does the following:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>1. Reset to 2007 the base year for application of the Sustainable Growth Rate (SGR), and eliminates the Sustainable Growth Rate in 2010. The practical effect of this on Medicare physician payment would provide physicians with over a 1 percentage increase in 2008 and  2009, and stable and sustainable growth rate in payment from 2010 and into the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>2. Makes available incentive payments for increased quality reporting and implementation of health information technology.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>3. Provides annual reports to physicians on billing patterns under Medicare.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>4. Provides an annual report to Medicare beneficiaries on annual Medicare expenditures.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>5. Mandates a study on whether quality reporting requirements on health care disparities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Amendment to <bill type="h" number="3162">H.R. 3162</bill>, as Reported [By The Committee on Ways and Means] Offered By Mr. Burgess of Texas</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <narrative>(CHAMP amendment)</narrative>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DINGELL" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield to the distinguished gentleman from Virginia (Mr. Moran) for purposes of a unanimous consent request.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="MORAN" of="Virginia">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent to insert a statement for the Record refuting the fact that this has anything to do with undocumented children. The fact is that the current provision prohibits undocumented children from getting health care, but if we don't pass it, it will deny tens of thousands of children who are legally eligible.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BURGESS" of="">
    <paragraph>I object.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, parliamentary inquiry, where are we?</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> Objection has been heard. The gentleman objected. It's for the gentleman from Michigan to yield time.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>So Mr. Dingell controls the time?</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> That's correct.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DINGELL" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield to the distinguished gentlewoman from California (Ms. Eshoo) 1 minute.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="ESHOO" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I thank the distinguished chairman of the Energy and Commerce Committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, today is one of the most exciting days since I've come to the Congress, having been elected first in 1992. I think today is a day of history, a day of history for the children of our country, because the fact is that there are nearly 9 million American children without guaranteed access to health care in our Nation today. I think that is a national shame.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, we correct that. We build on a successful bipartisan program of Republican and Democratic Governors, of leaders in the Congress past, of a program that has worked.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It has not been riddled by fraud, and what we do today very simply is add 5 million American children in the rolls of health care. It is private insurance for almost all of the States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We also strengthen Medicare. I would suggest that my friends on this side of the aisle are on the wrong side of history.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 1 minute to the distinguished gentleman of the committee from the great State of Florida (Mr. Stearns).</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <narrative>(Mr. STEARNS asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="STEARNS" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would say to the gentlelady from California who said this is a great day in history, it was a great day in history when, in 1997, the Republicans, who had the majority, initiated and started this program. The Democrats are saying this is a great day, what a great day, when the Republicans started the SCHIP program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, this bill, you have heard it all before. Obviously, it creates a new entitlement, crowds out private insurance with government coverage, offers perverse incentives to States; and, my friends, it contains a huge tax increase, with more on the way. Lastly, it punishes Medicare beneficiaries. This is very troubling, particularly in Florida. We have so many seniors that actually use Medicare Advantage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The fact that they are going to eliminate this program to pay for this is really outrageous. It will disproportionately harm racial minorities and rural senior citizens by taking funds away from Medicare Advantage, a successful, lower-cost option for health care for seniors and use it to enroll and federally insure adult men and women who have the ability to work and receive health care from their employers in the open market.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="STARK" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield to the distinguished member of the Ways and Means Committee, a member of the Health Subcommittee, the gentleman from Georgia (Mr. Lewis).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Pending that, I would explain that he knows that the NAACP, in a letter of endorsement, has said that this legislation fills a much-needed gap that currently exists in health care services for some of the most vulnerable citizens, low-income children, seniors and the disabled.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="LEWIS" of="Georgia">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, health care is a basic human right. It is unacceptable to see a young child die because his family could not afford for him to see a dentist. This should never, ever, happen in the United States of America. It is wrong. It must not be tolerated any longer, and today we said "no more".</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill would give 6 million children access to health care. For our seniors who rely on Medicare, this bill helps our low-income seniors and makes prevention more affordable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I applaud the work of Chairman Rangel and Chairman Stark for making these important improvements. I am proud to have worked on this bill to help those who suffer from chronic kidney disease and end-stage renal disease receive the highest quality care and to take the first of many steps towards preventing these terrible diseases.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Until we can make health care right for every American, we have a moral mission, a mission and a mandate to start with the most vulnerable among us, our children and our seniors. We can do no less. Vote "yes" on the CHAMP Act. Do it now. Do it today.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, could I inquire of the time remaining on each side on this part of the bill?</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The gentleman from Texas has 18 minutes remaining, and the gentleman from Michigan has 22 1/2  minutes remaining.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 1 minute to a distinguished member of the committee from the great State of Illinois (Mr. Shimkus), the winning pitcher on the congressional baseball team.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <narrative>(Mr. SHIMKUS asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="SHIMKUS" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, under the current Illinois SCHIP program, it covers up to 200 percent of poverty, $41,300 in annual income for a family of four; 26,830, or 31 percent of all families with children under the age of 18, in my district are already eligible for either Medicaid or SCHIP.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In this bill, Democrats have opposed cutting at least $194 billion in Medicare spending. Specifically, the Democrats have proposed cutting Medicare spending for 6,070 seniors in my district who  are currently enrolled in Medicare Advantage. Payments for hospital inpatient care will be cut $2.7 billion; inpatient rehabilitation services, $6.6 billion; skilled nursing facilities, a $6.5 billion cut; certain drugs, $1.9 billion in cuts; home health care,</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="STARK" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DINGELL" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 1 minute to the distinguished gentleman from Texas (Mr. Gene Green).</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <narrative>(Mr. GENE GREEN of Texas asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400160" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRY">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in strong support of the Children's Health and Medicare Protection Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is the best piece of legislation since 1997 when the children's health care was created, but this time we will cover 5 million more children if we vote "yes" today for this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to particularly thank the committee, although we didn't get to have a markup in ours because the Republican minority refused to let us even have votes on our amendments, so we have to have it on the floor today. We have to have that discussion. I am just glad they included that it would cover 12 months of insurability for our children, because some States have made 6 months the way to cut children off of health care.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me say one other thing. I have heard, particularly last night, I think it was insulting to say that this bill takes money away from seniors to give to illegal alien children. You ought to be ashamed of yourself. That's just outrageous. When you look at the bill and actually current law that we don't change, it prohibits undocumented children from getting any assistance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now the States are going to be the ones that have to prove that. If the States can't do it, they have to pay for it. It is just outrageous that you throw out the "illegals" every time you don't have any other argument.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am particularly proud of the SCHIP provisions in this legislation, which would provide much-needed health insurance coverage to low-income children in need.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Currently, the SCHIP program provides coverage to 6 million low-income American children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, an additional 6 million children are eligible for SCHIP benefits, yet remain uninsured.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation would reach about 5 million of those children by putting in place a more efficient funding formula based on projected enrollment and providing states with incentives to find eligible children and get them enrolled.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am particularly thankful for the committee's support of our language to ensure that children in SCHIP get 12 months of continuous eligibility.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This provision is critical to ensuring that eligible SCHIP children remain in the program and are not dropped due to cumbersome bureaucratic requirements imposed on families whose primary focus is on making ends meet.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A recent Health Affairs article underscores the importance of continuous eligibility in addressing retention problems in SCHIP.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Of the policy options suggested, the authors state that "[f]irst and foremost, the renewal process should be simplified as much as possible, by reducing the frequency of renewal to once a year."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill does just that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For many states, this bill reaffirms the compassionate and effective policies currently in place.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But for a state like mine, this bill will ensure that the State of Texas does right by Texas children and doesn't use the flexibility inherent in the program to kick them off the rolls on a budgetary whim.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I encourage my colleagues to stand up for low-income children and pass this important legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> All Members are reminded to please address their remarks through the Chair.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the CBO baseline score shows that Medicare cuts total $157 billion over the 10-year period.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 1 minute to the gentleman from Staten Island, a member of the committee, Mr. Fossella.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="FOSSELLA" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, Mr. Addison Good is an 80 year-old retired cook from Staten Island. He survives on a very limited income of Social Security and a small pension. Through every step of his hip operations, his Medicare Advantage plan paid for the services and drugs that he needed. He switched to a new plan that provides even better benefits at lower cost. He says he does not know how he would get the care he needs without his Medicare Advantage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me say up front, we will consider Mr. Addison Good as we consider the legislation; and I support the SCHIP program, I support its reauthorization, I support expanding access to health care for low-income children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I do not support this ill-conceived plan that pits parents against their grandchildren. Make no mistake, the bill cuts Medicare by more than $190 billion. In my district alone, it will reduce funds for Medicare Advantage by $58 million for the 38,000 enrollees in just the first year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The real-world impact of slashing $58 million in Medicare in Staten Island, Brooklyn, for seniors enrolled in this program could result in the following: either denied access to the program altogether, to lose health care benefits like hearing, vision and dental services or have to pay more out of pocket. We should not gut Medicare or punish seniors to achieve a Democratic goal.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="STARK" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DINGELL" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, we reserve the balance of our time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 1 minute to another member of the committee, Mr. Sullivan of Oklahoma.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="SULLIVAN" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, it's really astounding that there is nothing in this bill that stops States from covering illegal immigrations in this bill. People have come up to me and said, you know, the Democrats, the people in the Senate wanted to allow illegal aliens to get free Social Security benefits. Now they want to give free health care, and that's wrong.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is nothing in this bill that prevents adults, States from covering adults, giving them health care. There's nothing in this bill that prevents States from even covering the children of the Members of Congress in this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think this is a bill that should not happen. I rise today in strong opposition to it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One of my problems is that it eliminates the 5-year waiting period for immigrants who deserve to be eligible for Medicare and SCHIP. Congress wisely created this waiting period, and eliminating this waiting period will exacerbate our current immigration problems and further endanger government health care programs. By repealing this current law, millions of citizens will be eligible for Medicaid and SCHIP immediately.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Had this bill been brought to the committee, the proper thing, I had an amendment that would have saved taxpayers $2.2 billion having this waiting period.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to vote "no."</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 1 minute to another distinguished member of the Energy and Commerce Committee, the gentleman from California (Mr. Radanovich).</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="RADANOVICH" of="">
    <paragraph>I thought I would use my time to talk about the Ag approps bill. Just kidding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, we must ensure that all children who qualify for the SCHIP program are taken care of, but I have grave concerns about the SCHIP reauthorization bill, which doesn't target low-income kids but does increase mandatory spending by almost $130 billion over 10 years. This is not the way to provide coverage for anybody.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am particularly concerned that the CHAMP bill defines children as up to the age of 25. I am not aware of any other Federal program that defines the term "children" this broadly, and I certainly don't think that my constituents could agree that governments should be using health care funds intended for low-income children to cover a 25-year-old.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is not what SCHIP is supposed to be about. I don't believe that the creation of a new entitlement program costing hundreds of billions of dollars is in the best interests of our children. Are we going to encourage people and make it easier for them to take advantage of the private health care market, or are we going to have the government grabbing for control of all health care services?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation certainly indicates where our majority is trying to go. These are not procedural differences but major philosophical differences.  Under this bill, Donald Trump's daughter, Ivanka, will be enrolled in the SCHIP program.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, might I inquire as to the time?</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The gentleman from Texas has 14 minutes remaining, the gentleman from Michigan has 21 1/2  minutes remaining, the gentleman from California has 19 minutes remaining, and the gentleman from Louisiana has 30 minutes remaining.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DINGELL" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, our problem is a simple one, and I say this with respect and affection to my colleague. Our Republican colleagues have chosen to allocate time with two committees on this side and one committee on that side. The end result is that there is one committee on the Republican side which is not using its time. In order to balance out the time use, Mr. Stark and I are reserving our time at this time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the gentleman from Texas is in a quandary. I am not aware we were able to determine anything for the other side. I don't know why they are allocating their time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="STARK" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, it was just my intent to accommodate my friends in the minority who have been asking for all this extra time, but I guess if they have lost their speakers, they really don't need any.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 1 minute to the gentleman from California (Mr. Thompson), a member of the Health Subcommittee of the Ways and Means Committee, who recognizes that the American Medical Association has, in their endorsement, has said that this legislation addresses two of the AMA's highest priorities, providing health insurance coverage for low-income coverage and protecting seniors' access to care by preventing drastic cuts in the Medicare funding for physician services.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="THOMPSON" of="California">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, keeping kids healthy today means that the government will inherit a healthier Medicare population tomorrow. Investing in our children is both common sense and it's cost-effective.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It was very difficult to watch the former majority allow the national debt to grow to record heights. Today, I am proud that the new Democratic leadership has said no to deficit spending.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The CHAMP Act is emblematic of that shift. It is completely paid for. The CHAMP Act guarantees that both eligible children and Medicare seniors can access qualify health care.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Make no mistake. Without this legislation, 5 million new kids won't be able to get health care, and millions more already in the program will see their benefits cut.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Without this legislation, physicians will take the biggest rate cut in the history of the Medicare program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Without this legislation, Medicare benefits that are critical to rural communities will expire.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, with the passage of the CHAMP Act, Congress has taken an historic step. So be a champion for kids, be a champion for seniors and be a champion for common sense.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Vote "aye" on the CHAMP Act.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 1 minute to the distinguished leader of the Republican Study Committee, Mr. Hensarling of Texas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="HENSARLING" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, today the Democrat majority in Congress will no doubt ram through a bill representing the single largest step in Washington-controlled, bureaucratized, rationed, socialized health care, and they will do this under the guise of insuring needy children who are already insured under Medicaid or are already insured under the SCHIP program, which we could reauthorize. And they do this by turning SCHIP into a new entitlement, threatening to bankrupt the very children they  claim to be helping. They do this by cutting Medicare, hastening the bankruptcy of the Medicare trust fund. They do this by cutting Medicare Advantage plan, threatening the health care choices of millions of our seniors. They do this by increasing taxes on working Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a threat to our children's fiscal health, it is a threat to our Nation's and children's physical health. It should be rejected.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I renew my unanimous consent for 1 additional hour of time equally divided between the majority and the minority.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="DeGETTE" of="">
    <paragraph>I object.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Who objected, Mr. Speaker?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The gentleman has to be on his feet to object.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The gentlewoman from Colorado has objected. She is on her feet.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="STARK" of="">
    <paragraph>I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DINGELL" of="">
    <paragraph>I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, it would appear at this time that many of the difficulties that confront us could be addressed by the appearance of our good friends on the minority side of the Ways and Means.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move that the House do now adjourn.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> Pursuant to House Resolution 594, the previous question is ordered to final passage without such an intervening motion.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Parliamentary inquiry. I thought a motion to adjourn was in order at any time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> Pursuant to House Resolution 594, the previous question is ordered to final passage without intervening motion other than recommittal. As such, a motion to adjourn may not be entertained.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Parliamentary inquiry. What is House Resolution 594? Is that the closed rule?</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The rule for consideration of this bill.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Then I suggest the absence of a quorum, Mr. Speaker.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> That may not be entertained unless the Chair is putting the question, in accord with clause 7 of rule XX.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Then I yield 1 minute to a member of the committee, Mr. Terry of Nebraska.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="TERRY" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, first of all, I want to state that I believe that we should cover our low-income uninsured children, and I do believe we should make efforts to get them all in. If it was just that, we would be all in agreement. But that is not before us today. And I do believe that part of this attacks health insurance as we know it today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Number one, they defund Medicare Advantage, which is where people can opt out of Medicare and actually go into a managed program by a health insurance company. So they defund that, attacking that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Next is, for the first time, they are going to place a tax on health insurance policies, driving up the costs, so making it more unaffordable so more people drop out.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Then probably just as egregious as the other, an amendment that was denied, a Republican amendment, that says if there is a child that is eligible by the requirements but already insured can't drop that insurance or their insurer can't drop them, forcing them to go into the State-run free health insurance. That was denied.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So what we see here is a step-by-step process of making health insurance companies less effective and nationalizing health care.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="STARK" of="">
    <paragraph>I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DINGELL" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield to the distinguished gentlewoman from California (Ms. Harman) for purposes of a unanimous consent request.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <narrative>(Ms. HARMAN asked and was given permission to revise and extend her remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="HARMAN" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in strong support of this bill and commend Chairman Dingell for his enormous work.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Regardless of the business before the House, for the past two weeks, a drumbeat of dire predictions has been maintained on this floor about the so-called terrorism gap--the failure of Democrats to fix the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act, or FISA, to permit  our intelligence agencies to intercept foreign-to-foreign communications related to international terrorism. The argument is specious on its face. Democrats are just as committed as our colleagues  on the other side of the aisle to preventing another terrorist attack on the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a member of the Gang of Eight from 2002-2006, I am very familiar with FISA and our Terrorist Surveillance Program. While I agree that some technical adjustments are appropriate, the core principle of FISA and the 4th Amendment--that individualized court warrants are required if the communications of a U.S. person are involved--must be preserved.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But my question is, in the context of the CHAMP Act now before us: where is the outrage for the 5 million American kids who have no health insurance and no prospect of getting it unless we pass this bill?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What is the real objective of Members who continue to clutter an essential debate on improving health outcomes for our neediest children with alarmist exchanges on the surveillance of potential terrorists? Perhaps it is to jam Democrats and score partisan points before the August recess instead of reaching out to the most vulnerable among us.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The CHAMP Act reaches out by providing insurance to 11 million children, covering mental health and dental benefits, and by allowing States to cover pregnant women and family planning.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It reauthorizes Title V abstinence education, but requires that it be medically and scientifically accurate, as well as proven effective. I expect every Member agrees that no Federal program should use taxpayer dollars to give inaccurate information to young people.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The CHAMP Act makes improvements to the Medicare program, too, providing our most vulnerable seniors with better coverage for cost-saving preventive care and by making it easier to apply for benefits.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me bring the issue close to home. The Venice Family Clinic, located in my congressional district, is the largest free clinic in the Nation. They know something about reaching out to the most vulnerable in our communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Clinic staff told me today about an 8-year-old boy and his younger brother. Both of them are on the waiting list for SCHIP because the program is maxed-out--and their working mother doesn't earn enough to buy health insurance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This child suffers epileptic seizures every couple of weeks. He worries constantly about when the next one will occur, when and if he will be able to see a doctor or have access to medication that could help him. These are not things an 8-year-old in a country as rich as ours should be worrying about.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Expanding SCHIP will cover these children. It will change their lives, and the lives of 11 million other low income American kids.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>FISA can, should and will be fixed--and we can fix health insurance for kids, too. Every child deserves the health insurance that my four children and one grandchild have. And I have two more grandchildren on the way. Hopefully, the CHAMP Act will be law before they are born early next year.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DINGELL" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 1 minute to another distinguished member of the Energy and Commerce Committee, Mr. Pitts of Pennsylvania.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="PITTS" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would like to focus on one important failure of this legislation that I think the pro-lifers on the other side of the aisle would be interested in.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since 2002, the present administration has granted the States the option of providing SCHIP coverage to the child before birth, the unborn child, prenatal care and other health services for the unborn child and the pregnant mother. Unfortunately, the bill offered today would override current regulation and extend coverage in the name of the pregnant woman only. My amendment to codify the words "unborn child" was disallowed, not made in order last night.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Protecting only the pregnant woman could lead to a greater number of abortions. It would make the woman eligible for all publicly-funded services, including State-funded elective abortions. In States with Medicaid expansion programs, this could increase the number of women eligible for free abortions, thus promoting more abortions of unborn children in the name of children's health. This bill's language essentially classifies the pregnant woman herself. It does not make sense.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="STARK" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that the time allotted to the minority members of the Ways and Means Committee be forfeited.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>I object to that.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="STARK" of="">
    <paragraph>I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The gentleman from Michigan? Does anybody wish to yield time?</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DOGGETT" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, could you give us a time report? How much time remains for each?</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The gentleman from Louisiana has 30 minutes; the gentleman from California has 17 1/2  minutes; the gentleman from Texas has 11 minutes; the gentleman from Michigan has 21 1/2  minutes.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DOGGETT" of="">
    <paragraph>How much does the gentleman from Louisiana have?</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> 30 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DOGGETT" of="">
    <paragraph>None of it has been used.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="LINDER" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have a parliamentary inquiry.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The gentleman will state his inquiry.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="LINDER" of="">
    <paragraph>Would you tell us how much time they have combined, the two committees and our two committees combined, left?</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The gentleman from Michigan has 21 1/2  minutes remaining; the gentleman from California has 17 1/2  minutes remaining; the gentleman from Louisiana has 30 minutes remaining; and the gentleman from Texas has 11 minutes remaining.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent to proceed out of order and engage in a colloquy with Mr. Stark and Mr. Dingell for purposes of trying to understand what is going on.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Texas?</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="STARK" of="">
    <paragraph>I object.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="STARK" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent to insert in the Record a letter from the Catholic Health Association of the United States, which in part states that: We believe the most important pro-life thing that Congress can do right now is to ensure that the State Children's Health Insurance Program is reauthorized.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from California?</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Reserving the right to object, Mr. Speaker, I will not object if the gentleman from California will explain to me why we are fighting over what was in a pre-agreed-upon time arrangement. We have got six or seven speakers from the Energy and Commerce Committee. We are simply trying to do it in a balanced way. The gentleman from California has 17 minutes; the gentleman from Michigan has, I believe, 21 minutes. We just wish that the time go down in a balanced way. I don't understand  why that should be a problem.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The gentleman from Texas will suspend.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>I yield to my friend from California to explain to me why they don't want to use some of their time right now.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="STARK" of="">
    <paragraph>I am happy to respond. You are a couple minutes ahead of us, and of course I am dying to hear what my colleagues on the Republican side of the Ways and Means have to say.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Reclaiming my reservation, my understanding was that the Energy and Commerce Committee was going to go first, and then the Ways and Means Committee was going to go in the second hour. That is why Mr. McCrery is reserving his 30 minutes.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="STARK" of="">
    <paragraph>If the gentleman would yield.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>I would be happy to yield.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="STARK" of="">
    <paragraph>I think you have just touched on a misunderstanding. We had been led to believe that we would be rotating around among the various committees, and so that now we are kind of out of balance. Our understanding is that we would rotate back and forth between Energy and Commerce and Ways and Means for the full time. I apologize to the gentleman if we misled. Our concern was that we  would be out of balance in the time between the two committees.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The Chair will clarify that the gentlemen from California and from Michigan have a combined total of 39 minutes remaining; the gentlemen from Louisiana and from Texas have a total of 41 minutes remaining.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>I withdraw my reservation on the gentleman's unanimous consent request.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from California?</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="PRICE" of="Georgia">
    <paragraph>Reserving the right to object, Mr. Speaker, it is apparent that that was the letter that was requested to be inserted earlier, and the gentleman himself objected to it.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="STARK" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I withdraw my unanimous consent request.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The request is withdrawn.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 2 minutes to the gentleman from Arizona, a distinguished member of the committee, Mr. Shadegg.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="SHADEGG" of="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for yielding, and I really wish this debate was about what my colleagues on the other side want to make it about. I wish this bill was a debate about the uninsured children of the near poor or the working poor. I wish it was a debate like we had 10 years ago about insuring children too well off to get Medicaid but not well enough to buy insurance. But that is not what it is about. It is about cutting Medicare to provide health care services to middle- and upper  middle-income children and to provide health care services to adults.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And when you hear SCHIP, children, you don't expect that. When you think it is to go to the uninsured, you don't expect that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The median income in America, listen carefully, is $45,000. This bill will extend SCHIP benefits to families earning $60,000 and up to $80,000. That means it does not provide money for health insurance to the poor or the near poor or the working poor. We are all for that. That is why we initiated the program. We just don't think it ought to go to upper middle-income Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And let's see what the program has done. Sixty-one percent of the children who are in the SCHIP program today had private health insurance before the program was created. They dropped their private health insurance to take SCHIP. Is that what generous, compassionate Americans want to do for the poor? I don't think so. They dropped their private insurance to take SCHIP.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>CBO says that the Democrats' billions of dollars larger program will produce one person dropping private insurance for every one person who gets SCHIP insurance. Speaker after speaker on the other side has said this will insure 5 million more children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>What they don't tell you is that 5 million children, according to SCHIP, will drop their private insurance. Obviously, what they want is to take people off of private insurance and put them on SCHIP. That's not what the American people understand when they understand that that is supposed to be a bill about the children of the working poor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to oppose this bill. It's a fraud.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="STARK" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield to the gentleman from Rhode Island (Mr. Kennedy) for a unanimous consent request.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <narrative>(Mr. KENNEDY asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="KENNEDY" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of this legislation that raises parity for mental health for Medicare enrollees from 50 percent to 80 percent and for SCHIP from 75 percent to 100 percent, an additional $3 billion in this bill for mental health care. That's why we ought to support it.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="STARK" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 1 minute to another distinguished member of the committee, the ranking member of the Veterans Affairs Committee, the gentleman from Indiana (Mr. Buyer).</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BUYER" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I don't consider this a high-water mark for Congress in the 15 years I've been here. I don't consider it a high-water mark because I'm very disappointed in us, in how we have conducted ourselves with regard to our process, in how we have treated ourselves to each other, the lack of intolerance with regard to how we view each others' opinions. I don't think this is a high-water mark. A lot of this is taking place at the committee levels, and I have to reiterate my disappointment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We can battle it out. The democratic process is never meant to be pretty and easy. It's a difficult process, but it's exactly what it was meant to do so we wouldn't have capricious actions, that we wouldn't have power centralized and imperialistic from the top down. And that's what kind of happened here, and I'm very bothered by it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is no "time of the essence." Yes, this is a program that we came together in a bipartisan fashion and passed almost 10 years ago to care for children, poor and impoverished and to take care of them; and we've done that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We can extend that existing program and work together in a bipartisan fashion, if that's what this was really about. But it's not.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, in addition to myself, I only have one additional speaker that's currently on the floor. I would encourage my friend from Michigan, if he has any speakers, to use some of his time at this point in time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The gentleman from Michigan has 21 1/2  minutes remaining. Does he wish to yield any time?</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DINGELL" of="">
    <paragraph>The gentleman from Michigan will continue to reserve.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="STARK" of="">
    <paragraph>I continue to reserve, Mr. Speaker.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>I reserve.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The gentleman from Louisiana has 30 minutes remaining. The gentleman from Texas has 8 minutes remaining. So 38 minutes total on the minority side, 39 minutes total on the majority side.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DINGELL" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, out of a surcease of good will for my Republican colleagues, at this time I yield 1 minute to the distinguished gentlewoman from Colorado (Ms. DeGette).</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="DeGETTE" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, children who receive well-child care begin their lives healthy and ready to learn in school; and this care is cheaper and more humane than reliance on the emergency room.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of SCHIP, 6 million children of the working poor get the care they need for a healthy start to their lives. Despite the success, our work is not complete. Six million uninsured children are still eligible for SCHIP but not currently enrolled. The CHAMP Act will build on the strong bipartisan foundation of SCHIP and insure these remaining children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Those on the other side of the aisle will put forth a proposal in the motion to recommit that not only fails to cover these 6 million remaining children, but it will result in current beneficiaries losing coverage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are halfway to covering the uninsured children in this country, and the Republicans want to pack up and go home. Thank goodness they weren't in charge of the mission to the moon. Neil Armstrong would have gone halfway to the moon and been ordered back to earth. Mission accomplished.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, halfway is not mission accomplished. Vote "yes" for kids, vote "yes" on this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 1 minute to a distinguished member of the committee, Mr. Walden of the great State of Oregon.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="WALDEN" of="Oregon">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I agree that the SCHIP program is a good program, as it was created in a bipartisan manner many years ago. Its extension would be a good thing. But what we have before us today on the floor is not, because it robs from senior citizens in my district and elsewhere to provide extraordinary and expanded coverage of health care to people who may already have it, as well as much higher income levels. Eighty to one hundred thousand dollars you could be making, your  kids could be eligible for your current health insurance from your employer, and this program, as proposed by the Democrats, would actually take those off, or potentially could take those kids off, as well as take away the Medicare choice that seniors in my district, some 31,798 seniors in my district run the potential of losing the choice they have for Medicare.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I was at a town meeting in the eastern part of my district about 2 weeks ago; and a woman said, please, Congressman, don't let them take away my Medicare. And that's what's happening today. And it's unfortunate the process has been so usurped that we didn't have time other than 1 minute to talk about it.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The gentleman from Michigan has 20 1/2  minutes remaining. The gentleman from California has 17 1/2  minutes remaining, for a total of 38 minutes. The gentleman from Louisiana has a total of 30 minutes remaining. The gentleman from Texas has 7 minutes remaining.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DINGELL" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would yield 1 minute at this time to the distinguished gentlewoman from California, my dear friend, Mrs. CAPPS.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mrs." name="CAPPS" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this bill is the reason I came to Congress, to continue my work for children's health. It's a blight on our Nation that millions of children in hardworking families still have no access to health care, and today we can undo that wrong. Through this fiscally responsible bill we ensure that millions more eligible children will be able to get primary care, manage life-threatening illnesses, improve their school attendance and grow into healthy, productive adults. And how  fitting that at the same time we will improve Medicare for seniors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I wish to submit for the Record the piece by Ron Brownstein in today's L.A. Times where he calls the Bush and Republican arguments against this bill as not much more than stealing health care from babies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We do have a choice today. We can continue to ignore the health of millions of babies and children, or we can take the high moral ground and pass this bill which will provide health care to those who need it most.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to commend Chairmen DINGELL, PALLONE, RANGEL, AND STARK for all the hard work they and the committee staff have done. I urge my colleagues to vote "yes" on the CHAMP Act. Do something positive today for America's children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Stealing Healthcare From Babies</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Does President Bush really believe what he's saying about the effort from congressional Democrats and some leading Senate Republicans to provide health coverage for millions of uninsured children? He's portraying it as the first step on a slippery slope toward "government-run healthcare," as if senior senators in both parties were conspiring with Michael Moore to import Cuban doctors to inoculate and indoctrinate American children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In fact, Congress is moving responsibly to remove a blot on the nation: the 8 million children without health insurance. It is doing so by expanding the State Children's Health Insurance Program, or SCHIP, a state-federal partnership that the Republican Congress and President Clinton created in 1997 to cover kids in working-poor families. Final votes on the House and Senate floors could come this week.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Bush, seemingly determined to provoke every possible confrontation with congressional Democrats, has pledged to veto the bills. And with the GOP congressional leadership, he is fighting the proposals with a swarm of misleading and hypocritical arguments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Bush complains that expanding the program costs too much. But cost was no object when Bush and congressional Republicans sought to court seniors by creating the Medicare prescription drug benefit in 2003.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under the bipartisan Senate bill, Washington would spend about $56 billion over the next five years to cover almost half of the nation's uninsured children. Over the same period, the Medicare entitlement that Bush signed (after more than four-fifths of House and Senate Republicans voted for it) will cost nearly $330 billion. Is social spending affordable only when it benefits constituencies Republicans prize in elections?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Next, Bush complains that the SCHIP expansion would require "a huge tax increase." Actually, both the House and Senate plans would raise taxes just on tobacco. And the sponsors are increasing taxes only because they have committed to the novel notion of paying for their program. When Bush and the Republican Congress created the expensive Medicare drug benefit, they did not provide any new revenue to fund it. They just billed the cost to the next generation through higher federal deficits. Now  Bush is condemning Democrats for displaying more responsibility.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Bush also disparages the SCHIP expansion as an attempt "to encourage people to transfer from the private sector to government healthcare plans." But studies have found that three-fourths of children covered under the current program receive their care through private insurance plans that contract with the states, notes Edwin Park of the liberal Center on Budget and Policy Priorities. In that way, the program is no different than Bush's prescription drug plan: The government pays for services  delivered by private insurance companies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Bush's argument that the SCHIP changes will unacceptably "crowd out" private insurance is misleading in another respect. It's true, as Bush charges, that if the program is expanded, some eligible families would shift their children into it from private coverage, hoping to save money or improve care. The Congressional Budget Office estimates that children making such a switch would account for about one-third of the 6 million kids expected to enroll in the expanded SCHIP program under the Senate  plan, and hence one-third of the added cost.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But as CBO Director Peter Orszag notes, all efforts to expand coverage for the uninsured inevitably spill some benefits on those who already have insurance. And the Senate SCHIP plan, by limiting that spillover to one-third of its cost, is actually more efficient than most alternatives for expanding coverage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Bush, for instance, wants to reduce the number of uninsured by providing new tax incentives for buying coverage. But the Lewin Group, an independent consulting firm, recently calculated that 80 percent of the benefits from Bush's plan would flow to people who already have insurance. Such numbers help explain why Orszag recently said that, dollar for dollar, expanding SCHIP "is pretty much as efficient as you can possibly get" to insure more kids.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Bush's most outrageous argument is that expanding SCHIP "empower[s] bureaucrats." In reality, covering more children would empower parents like Sheila Miguel of Sun Valley, Calif.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Miguel used to spend hours in emergency rooms trying to obtain asthma medicine for her daughter, Chelsea, but since enrolling her in a SCHIP-funded program, Miguel can take her to reliably scheduled clinic visits.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Bush says he wants "to put more power" over healthcare "in the hands of individuals." By freeing Miguel's family from the worry and drudgery of repeated emergency room visits, that's exactly what SCHIP does.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Few of the lower-income working families that rely on this program have the time to follow this week's legislative struggle, much less analyze how it serves the White House's apparent strategy of embroiling congressional Democrats in unrelenting conflicts with Bush that alienate swing voters. In that political skirmishing, these families have been reduced to collateral damage. They deserve something better from a president who once called himself a "compassionate conservative."</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>I would like to yield 2 minutes to the distinguished Republican whip and a member of the committee who is on leave, Mr. Blunt of Missouri.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BLUNT" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I'm thankful to the former chairman and the ranking member for yielding to me on this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It seems to me that what we have here is a bill that has not benefited from the process of hearings. Most of our friends in the majority today, I assume, will vote for this bill. Most of our friends on our side are going to vote against this bill, and I believe that during the month of August the voters will have the hearings that we should have had in advance. I believe what we'll find out is this bill has needless problems in it in the name of expanding SCHIP.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My good friend, Ms. DeGette, mentioned the moon mission. It does seem to me that, in this bill now, the moon is the limit. The original bill said 200 percent of poverty, with some flexibility to the States. We're in favor of extending these guidelines.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The original proposal, as we understood it from the majority, was 400 percent of poverty. Families who made 80, $85,000 would get free health insurance for their children. I don't think that limit is there any more. I believe it's up to the States under this bill. If you made 1,000 times the poverty rate and your State wanted to insure you, they could do that and your initial payment from the Federal Government would be 95 cents on every dollar.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We're going to offer a recommital today that extends the current SCHIP program; that gives us the time to talk about it and ways that make it better; that reinstates the current law on immigrants, where, if you come to this country, you have to have a sponsor, and you can't participate in programs like this for the first 5 years. That's been one of the workable parts of our immigration policy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We would propose we don't have self-verification, where people who are here illegally just can walk up and sign up and say I'm legally here.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We'll have a doctor fix. We'll do something about the therapy caps. And, in my district, 21,033 people who would lose their choice of Medicare don't lose their choice of Medicare. Restricting Medicare benefits to pay for children's health care is not the right thing.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="STARK" of="">
    <paragraph>I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>I'm going to try one more time here.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that there be 1 hour of additional time allotted on the pending legislation, equally divided between the majority and the minority, and, within that, equally divided between the Ways and Means Committee and the Energy and Commerce Committee.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="STARK" of="">
    <paragraph>Reserving the right to object.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The gentleman reserves the right to object.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DINGELL" of="">
    <paragraph>And I make a similar reservation.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="STARK" of="">
    <paragraph>If I could inquire of the distinguished gentleman from Texas, it's my understanding that this unanimous consent request has been negotiated between the majority and minority leadership.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>We share the same understanding.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="STARK" of="">
    <paragraph>And as part of it that we would proceed expeditiously to use the debate, move to passage, and without intervening stalling motions.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>We have the same understanding.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="STARK" of="">
    <paragraph>Then I withdraw my reservation.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DINGELL" of="">
    <paragraph>I have no objection.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Texas?</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Hallelujah.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, at this point in time, I reserve my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="STARK" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, with this new-found wealth of time, I'm happy to yield 1 minute to the senior member of the Health Ways and Means Subcommittee, the gentleman from Texas (Mr. Doggett), who understands that the Lance Armstrong Foundation has urged a vote in favor of 3162, a legislation scored as a key vote for people affected by cancer; and Mr. Armstrong is a constituent of Mr. Doggett.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DOGGETT" of="">
    <paragraph>Surely if Lance Armstrong can overcome mountains in France, we can overcome the mountains of obstructionism and of excuses to provide our children and our seniors the health coverage that they need.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By including significant portions of two Medicare bills that I filed, today's legislation supports grandparents as well as grandchildren. All seniors would get preventive care, and many of the 3.3 million poor seniors not receiving any help today would get the extra help for which they qualify.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, those seniors most in need are often least aware that help exists. We must identify and notify those entitled to extra help with prescription drugs and simplify the application process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We also ensure that drug coverage is not lost by our seniors who saved a small nest egg or receive help and groceries from their children--behavior that we ought to encourage, not punish.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>Importantly, we mandate that patients suffering from cancer, AIDS, and mental illness receive access to life-saving medications. Without this protection, vulnerable patients are held hostage by "cost cutting decisions" by private insurance companies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While Lance inspires us to live strong, we can "vote strong" and improve the lives of children, seniors, and Americans fighting to get well again. Approve this important legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, could I inquire as to how much time there is remaining?</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The gentleman from Michigan has 34 1/2  minutes remaining; the gentleman from California has 31 1/2  minutes remaining; the gentleman from Texas has 20 minutes remaining; and the gentleman from Louisiana has 45 minutes remaining.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 2 1/2  minutes to a distinguished member from the great State of Georgia, Dr. Gingrey.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="GINGREY" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I want to talk about policy and process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a situation where in the process the voices on both sides of the aisle have literally been shut down by bringing forward one of the most important pieces of legislation, I think, that I have had to discuss in the 4 1/2  years that I have been a Member of this Congress. To say to the 11 position Members, almost equally divided between the Democrats and the Republicans, that we don't want to hear your voice, we don't want to hear some amendments that you might want to proffer because you  have spent maybe 30 years, in my case maybe 25 years, 250 years in the aggregate of these 11 physicians' practicing medicine, no one being able to bring meaningful amendments to this issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The other side has talked many times about the Republican former majority running up this massive debt and borrowing money from the Chinese. I am going to tell you something. This might be a time, Mr. Speaker, where the new majority should borrow this $75 billion massive expansion of the SCHIP program from the Chinese rather than getting the money off the backs of our Medicare recipients under Medicare Advantage, 8 million of whom choose that option, and many of those are the lowest income; and  also encouraging 22 million people to become addicted to smoking so they could raise this revenue. The chairman says it is a modest increase in tax on a pack of cigarettes. Indeed, Mr. Speaker, it doubles the tax on a pack of cigarettes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So we have a better idea. I am opposed to this bill in its present form, and I support the Republican motion to recommit, which is the Barton-Deal bill, which says, look, we will cover children that are slipping through the cracks. The CBO estimates, Mr. Speaker, that 600,000 children have fallen through the cracks. They are in that group 100 to 200 percent of the Federal poverty level. Under the Barton-Deal plan, we can cover them and we will do that. We don't need to increase the funding by</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DINGELL" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, at this time, I yield 2 minutes to the distinguished gentleman from Maine (Mr. Allen).</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="ALLEN" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, there are 11 million reasons to vote for this bill, and each is a child in a working-class family who will grow up healthier and stronger as a result of its passage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Every dollar we invest in the SCHIP program saves money over time. The children we cover are far less likely to require more expensive health care later on, far more likely to be better achievers in school and much better prepared to become productive adults.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>SCHIP today provides health care to 6 million children. This bill will cover an additional 5 million children who qualify for SCHIP but today lack coverage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Maine has developed one of the best SCHIP programs in the Nation. This bill offers States the flexibility to tailor outreach efforts to their specific needs and capacities. Failure to pass this legislation would mean the loss of health coverage for millions of children. But every child should have access to quality, affordable health care.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am proud of the comparative effectiveness research provision in this bill. It will reduce health care costs and improve quality for all Americans. It does that by providing doctors and their patients with valid evidence-based information on how different treatments for particular medical conditions compare to one another. This data can help doctors and their patients determine whether or not new or high-priced drugs, devices, and other medical treatments provide better clinical outcomes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a critically important piece of legislation. It helps our kids. It preserves Medicare for our seniors. It makes sure our physicians and other providers are adequately reimbursed. I urge my colleagues to support this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 1 1/2  minutes to the gentleman from Georgia, Dr. Price.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <narrative>(Mr. PRICE of Georgia asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="PRICE" of="Georgia">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I appreciate the opportunity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have in my hand here a letter from the American Association for Homecare, Coalition for Pulmonary Fibrosis, the COPD Alert, the Council for Quality Respiratory Care, and the National Emphysema/COPD Association asking us not to vote for this bill that would enact cuts in their programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a physician, I understand the negative consequences of greater governmental involvement in health care.  This bill will cut Medicare benefits. It will tax every single American with private health insurance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, why would they do this? Why would they pass a bill like this? The answer, Mr. Speaker, is because they can. But their motives are laid bare. Their motives are laid today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The true desire of those on the left is to gradually and enticingly move all Americans to Washington-controlled bureaucratic health care. Read the bill. Read the bill. It's right there.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It's not what we ought to be doing. It's not what Americans want. I urge my colleagues to oppose this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="STARK" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would like to yield 1 minute to the distinguished gentleman from California, a member of the Ways and Means Committee (Mr. Becerra). Pending that, I would point out that he is well aware that the National Hispanic Medical Association has endorsed the bill, and I would like to submit their endorsing letter into the Record.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>MEDICAL ASSOCIATION,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington, DC, July 25, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR CHAIRMAN DINGELL: On behalf of the National Hispanic Medical Association (NHMA), a non-profit association representing 36,000 licensed Hispanic physicians in the United States, we write to express our strong support for the Children's Health and Medicare Protection Act, <bill type="h" number="3162">H.R. 3162</bill>, which will allow the State Children's Health Insurance Program (SCHIP), Medicare, and Medicaid to expand enrollment of Hispanic children and elderly. Since one in five Hispanic children are currently uninsured  and only 10 percent of Hispanics eligible for Medicare are enrolled, these programs are vital to increasing access to health care.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The mission of NHMA is to improve the health of Hispanics and other underserved populations. We support the SCHIP section that allows states to cover legal immigrant children and legal immigrant pregnant women, covers dental care and mental health care, provides state performance bonuses if they can demonstrate that they have enrolled new children who are currently eligible, but not enrolled, and creates the Children's Access, Payment and Equity Commission, that will examine issues of health  disparities. We support the Medicare section that calls for reducing health disparities through demonstrations for language services reimbursement and targeted outreach, new quality data relating to disparities, expands the Low Income Subsidy and Medicare Savings Programs, and mandates a report on Culturally and Linguistically Appropriate Standards</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In summary, the National Hispanic Medical Association supports the Children's Health and Medicare Protection Act, <bill type="h" number="3161">H.R. 3161</bill>, because it will increase access to health insurance for Hispanics and will, thus, improve the health of all Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Elena Rios, M.D., M.S.P.H.,</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BECERRA" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The CHAMP Act is a victory for children's health, it is a victory for seniors' health, and it is a victory for American taxpayers who expect us to be fiscally responsible.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Why shouldn't 11 million American children from working families in this country have the same access to health care that the children of every single Member of Congress has? The taxpayers pay our salary and they make it possible for us to get health care benefits. Why shouldn't 11 million American children who live with parents who are working day to day have the same access?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Like our victory this year in increasing the minimum wage for America's workers, expanding health care coverage to 5 million children is long overdue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My colleagues on the Republican side of the aisle voted a few years ago to add a prescription drug benefit under Medicare that costs about eight times as much as the benefit we would offer to the 11 million children would cost. Why not do it for our kids?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are doing this in a way that is fiscally responsible. The CHAMP Act will not add a single cent to the Federal deficit that the Bush administration has created.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is sound policy. Let's vote for the CHAMP Act for our kids and our seniors.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would like to yield 1 minute to the distinguished gentleman from the great State of Nebraska (Mr. Fortenberry).</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="FORTENBERRY" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, everyone agrees that children deserve proper health care. The SCHIP program is an important program that provides health insurance for over 6.6 million of America's neediest children. I supported its renewal, but I believe it must be done responsibly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation overreaches. It cuts Medicare and also allows some adults to claim health care coverage meant for children. Good public policy should not pit the children against their grandparents.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This 465-page bill makes sweeping changes to American health care and tax policies. It needs thorough, thoughtful, and deliberate analysis, and time has not been provided for adequate examination. The SCHIP bill could have clear bipartisan support, I believe, but instead it contains a labyrinth of provisions, some of which hurts seniors. Mr. Speaker, I believe this Congress can do better.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DINGELL" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield at this time 1 minute to my very dear friend, the gentleman from New Jersey (Mr. Andrews).</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <narrative>(Mr. ANDREWS asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="ANDREWS" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, somewhere in America right now an 8-year-old girl comes home to her mother and father and says she has a numbness and ache in her right arm, and they worry about it, wondering whether it is just a strain from playing on the playground or whether she has a serious disease of her nervous system. But they can't send her to the pediatrician because they do not have enough money left in the family budget this week and they have no health insurance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The question before the House is whether or not to provide health insurance for that family and that little girl. Yes or no?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill says "yes." It pays for it responsibly by a modest increase in the cigarette tax and by eliminating subsidies to health insurance companies. You can say whatever you want, but the question comes down to that: yes or no? It is time we voted "yes" for that little girl and her family, voted "yes" on this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I want to yield 1 minute to the Member of Congress with the largest number of Social Security recipients, the gentlewoman from the great State of Florida (Ms. Ginny Brown-Waite).</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400051" topic="NHMA, NATIONAL HISPANIC">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today on behalf of the 43,000 senior citizens living in my congressional district who will lose their Medicare benefits if the bill before us today becomes law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Everyone in this Chamber wants to extend SCHIP because it has helped many children, but not at the expense of their grandparents. Let me repeat: 43,000 of my constituents, 693,000 Floridians, and 8.3 million seniors nationwide will be pushed off of Medicare plans in favor of other priorities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today we are seeing the biggest raid on the Medicare trust fund seniors have ever seen, with no regard to those who rely on Medicare Advantage for their only access in many rural areas to health care benefits.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Some of the specific cuts that are in this bill are a 43 percent cut to patients who rent lifesaving oxygen equipment, a $7.2 billion cut for home health services, a $6.5 billion cut for skilled nursing facilities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, cutting the only health care program many of my constituents use would be unconscionable.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from Michigan has a total of 31 1/2  minutes remaining, and the gentleman from California has 30 minutes remaining, for an aggregate total of 61 1/2  minutes. The gentleman from Texas has 14 minutes, and the gentleman from Louisiana has 45 minutes, for an aggregate total of 59 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DINGELL" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I continue to reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="STARK" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I continue to reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I respectfully reserve the balance of my time at this time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DINGELL" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I note that Mr. McCrery has time remaining.  He is a very valuable Member of this body, and I'm sure he would make very good use of the time that's available to him, and I would suggest that the business of the House could be expedited by having Mr. McCrery proceed to yield time to members of the Ways and Means Committee on the minority side.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I just wish to make an observation that the tradition of normal procedure is to alternate between majority and minority. We just had a minority speaker. It should be the opportunity of the majority to tell their side of the story.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The Chair notes that it was an alternation between two committees on one side and two committees on the other side of the House.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DINGELL" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would then yield, with the understanding that the Democrats want to give the choice of the doctor, while our good Republican friends want to give a choice of HMOs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With that, I yield 2 minutes to the distinguished gentleman from New York (Mr. Engel).</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="ENGEL" of="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the reauthorization of State Children's Health Insurance is unquestionably one of the most important bills we will pass this year. This bill will protect six million kids currently covered by SCHIP and provide coverage for an additional five million children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill provides aggressive outreach to enroll children by simplifying enrollment procedures and awarding States bonuses for finding more children. This is important since two-thirds of the uninsured children in our Nation are actually eligible but not enrolled in Medicaid or SCHIP.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What is the response of our Republican friends? Block the bill from coming up in our committee; create phony issues because they're against insuring children. Illegal amnesty? Give me a break. No hearings? We've had seven hearings on this bill. Eligible for private insurance? 93.5 percent of the children we cover in this bill would have no private insurance without this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What is the President's response? Under the President's plan, this program would see its funding cut from last year; and, worse, the amount allocated for its reauthorization would be less than half of the amount required to maintain coverage for current beneficiaries.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He says he will veto this bill because it covers too many children. This is unconscionable. Sixty-one national advocacy groups devoted to improving children's health request that we fund the SCHIP program at 60 billion additional dollars. The President countered with $4.8 billion. Clearly, there is a disconnect.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are proud that, despite budgetary constraints, we will be able to reauthorize our SCHIP program at $50 billion. I am proud that we will be covering 11 million low-income children under this reauthorization, and I know our Nation will be better off for it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is an amazing feat. Passing bills like this is why we should all feel honored to be Members of Congress. I'm sorry that my Republican friends just continue to say no. We say yes, yes to 11 million children, yes to saying that our children ought to be insured, yes to saying that America's children need our help. Pass this bill. It is good for all our children.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I wish to yield 2 minutes to the distinguished gentleman from Georgia (Mr. Deal), ranking member of the Health Subcommittee.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DEAL" of="Georgia">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, we've heard a lot of opinions today about the effects of this bill; and opinions are, of course, of different perspectives on the bill. But there is an agency that we all rely on, supposedly, to give us the facts, and that is the Congressional Budget Office.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, there has been an argument about whether or not this bill, in its reforms, will go back to a system that would allow illegal immigrants to be covered. Now, we can say that it doesn't, but CBO says that, by changing that provision back to the way it used to be, that over the next 5 years it will cost $800 million and over the next 10 years it will cost $1.9 billion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, CBO is simply saying that if you make it easier for illegals to enter the program, that's the price tag. They wouldn't say that if they didn't have some basis for coming up with those numbers. They didn't just pull them out of the air.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The other part deals with legal immigrants. We have had a policy in this country that if someone wants to bring a family member, a friend, or sponsor somebody to come in and we give that person coming in legal status, that they are not eligible to participate in our social programs, such as Medicaid, for the first 5 years. Their sponsor signs an affidavit that they will be personally responsible for that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill removes that waiting time. So when you bring someone in, they can immediately sign up for the Medicaid rolls. Now, CBO says that that will cost $900 million over the next 5 years and $2.2 billion over the next 10 years. Now, the truth of the matter is that this bill gives incentives to States to allow this to happen.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge a "no" vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
</record>
