<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1213200004" ordinal="24" title="INCREASING AMERICAN JOBS AND ENERGY PRODUCTION RESPONSIBLY">
  <narrative>INCREASING AMERICAN JOBS AND ENERGY PRODUCTION RESPONSIBLY -- (House of Representatives - June 11, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H5220]</narrative>
  <narrative>(Mr. BOUSTANY asked and was given permission to address the House for 1 minute and to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400636" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, people in southwest Louisiana understand that increasing American energy production means more American jobs, good high-paying American jobs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>They also know that a magic bullet will not lower the price at the pump for families, but increasing American energy production in a responsible way will help, and it will create American jobs. The American people want to increase energy production in a responsible, environmentally friendly way.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>They want to see unleashing of American entrepreneurship and ingenuity. They don't want any further delays in seeking energy independence, and they know that this is in the interest of national security.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Families in southwest Louisiana and across the country want to see solutions to the high prices at the pump, and Republicans have viable answers to this. We have introduced a number of bills. The American people are now asking the Democratic leadership in Washington if they have solutions, because so far they haven't seen any.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, the Democratic Presidential nominee suggests to CNBC's John Harwood yesterday that while the U.S. would be better off without such a shock in gas prices, he sees higher prices as a good thing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I don't get it. I just don't get it. We can work together to solve this problem. We can decrease America's dependence on foreign sources. It's a sensible thing to do, and I urge my colleagues to join me in this quest.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
