<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1205164802" ordinal="24" title="CONGRATULATING THE WOMEN'S WATER POLO TEAM OF UCLA FOR WINNING THE 2007 NATIONAL CHAMPIONSHIP">
  <narrative>CONGRATULATING THE WOMEN'S WATER POLO TEAM OF UCLA FOR WINNING THE 2007 NATIONAL CHAMPIONSHIP -- (House of Representatives - March 10, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H1428]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412209" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution (<bill type="hr" number="493">H. Res. 493</bill>) congratulating the women's water polo team of the University of California, Los Angeles, for winning the 2007 NCAA Division I Women's Water Polo National Championship, and congratulating UCLA on its 100th NCAA sports national title, making it the most accomplished athletic program in NCAA history, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the resolution.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the resolution is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="hr" number="493">H. Res. 493</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas on May 13, 2007, the women's water polo team of the University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA), defeated Stanford 5-4 in the championship game of the NCAA Division I Women's Water Polo National Championship tournament;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the victory gave Head Coach Adam Krikorian and the Bruins women's water polo team their third consecutive NCAA Championship and was the team's fifth overall national title;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Kelly Rulon, a driver for the Bruins, was selected as the tournament's Most Valuable Player;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas UCLA women's water polo players Kelly Rulon, Emily Feher, Courtney Mathewson, Jillian Kraus, and Kacy Kunkel were named to the NCAA All-Tournament First Team;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the UCLA women's water polo team finished the 2007 season with a record of 28 wins and 2 losses, and now has a record of 90 wins and 6 losses over the past 3 seasons;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the 2007 Women's Water Polo National Championship makes UCLA the first school ever to win 100 NCAA sports national titles;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas UCLA won its 100th NCAA title less than 58 years after the UCLA men's tennis team won the school's first NCAA title in 1950;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas 16 different men's and women's sports programs contributed to the Bruins' 100 NCAA national championships, including--</narrative>
  <narrative>(1) men's basketball in 1964, 1965, 1967, 1968, 1969, 1970, 1971, 1972, 1973, 1975, and 1995;</narrative>
  <narrative>(2) men's golf in 1988;</narrative>
  <narrative>(3) women's golf in 1991 and 2004;</narrative>
  <narrative>(4) men's gymnastics in 1984 and 1987;</narrative>
  <narrative>(5) women's gymnastics in 1997, 2000, 2001, 2003, and 2004;</narrative>
  <narrative>(6) men's soccer in 1985, 1990, 1997, and 2002;</narrative>
  <narrative>(7) women's softball in 1982, 1984, 1985, 1988, 1989, 1990, 1992, 1999, 2003, and 2004;</narrative>
  <narrative>(8) men's swimming in 1982;</narrative>
  <narrative>(9) men's tennis in 1950, 1952, 1953, 1954, 1956, 1960, 1961, 1965, 1970, 1971, 1975, 1976, 1979, 1982, 1984, and 2005;</narrative>
  <narrative>(10) men's track and field in 1956, 1966, 1971, 1972, 1973, 1978, 1987, and 1988;</narrative>
  <narrative>(11) women's outdoor track and field in 1982, 1983, and 2004;</narrative>
  <narrative>(12) women's indoor track and field in 2000 and 2001;</narrative>
  <narrative>(13) men's volleyball in 1970, 1971, 1972, 1974, 1975, 1976, 1979, 1981, 1982, 1983, 1984, 1987, 1989, 1993, 1995, 1996, 1998, 2000, and 2006;</narrative>
  <narrative>(14) women's volleyball in 1984, 1990, and 1991;</narrative>
  <narrative>(15) men's water polo in 1969, 1971, 1972, 1995, 1996, 1999, 2000, and 2004; and</narrative>
  <narrative>(16) women's water polo in 2001, 2003, 2005, 2006, and 2007;</narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas UCLA teams have won 14 NCAA national championships during the tenure of Daniel G. Guerrero, the current Director of Athletics at UCLA; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas UCLA, under the leadership of Chancellor Gene Block, continues to establish itself as one of the top research universities as well as top athletic programs in the Nation: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, &lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; That the House of Representatives--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) congratulates the women's water polo team of the University of California, Los Angeles, and Head Coach Adam Krikorian for winning the 2007 NCAA Division I Women's Water Polo National Championship;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) congratulates UCLA on becoming the first school to win 100 NCAA sports national championship titles, making it the most accomplished athletic program in NCAA history; and</narrative>
  <narrative> (3) recognizes the achievements of all the players, coaches, students, alumni, and staff of UCLA who were instrumental over the years in this prestigious achievement. &lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Iowa (Mr. Loebsack) and the gentleman from New York (Mr. Kuhl) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Iowa.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412209" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I request 5 legislative days during which Members may insert material relevant to House Resolution 493 into the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Iowa?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412209" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Mr. LOEBSACK asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412209" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I rise today to congratulate the University of California, Los Angeles, on its 100th NCAA team championship. On May 13, 2007, the women's water polo team, led by head coach Adam Krikorian, defeated Stanford 9-4 in the last round of the Women's Water Polo National Championship tournament, thereby making the University of California, Los Angeles, the first team in history to win 100 NCAA team championships.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This was the team's third consecutive NCAA championship and its fifth overall national title. Team member Kelly Rulon was selected as the tournament's Most Valuable Player, and Ms. Rulon and four of her teammates, Emily Feher, Courtney Mathewson, Jillian Kraus, and Kacy Kunkel, were named to the NCAA all-tournament team.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>UCLA won its first national title in men's tennis in 1950. Since then, 16 different athletics programs, nine men's programs and seven women's, have won national championships in the sports of basketball, golf, gymnastics, soccer, softball, swimming, tennis, track and field, volleyball, and, of course, water polo. In the last 5 years alone, under the leadership of director of athletics Dan Guerrero, UCLA teams have won 14 NCAA national championships in nine different sports.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This extraordinary achievement is a tribute to the skill and dedication of the many players, coaches, students, alumni, families, professors, staff, and fans who have helped to make UCLA an athletic powerhouse as well as an academic force.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I express my support for <bill type="hr" number="493">H. Res. 493</bill> and urge my colleagues to pass this measure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400642" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="hr" number="493">H. Res. 493</bill> as well. But there is a person in the Chamber who is a little closer than the gentleman from Iowa or myself from New York, and so I yield such time as he may consume to the gentleman from California (Mr. Lewis).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Mr. LEWIS of California asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400239" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I very much appreciate my colleague's courtesy. Almost all that I was going to say about UCLA's prowess in athletics has already been stated for the Record.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Having said that, Madam Speaker, many a person looking at the wondrous world of athletics oftentimes thinks only of the 11 banners that involves John Wooden's era as coach of UCLA's basketball team. As has been suggested, one would really miss the point of the fabulous work done at the UCLA campus, way beyond athletics, in academics, et cetera. But indeed, the women's water polo team set the standard by winning the 100th championship when they won one more time. It is a fabulous item to be associated  with UCLA and to get this recognition from so many great friends.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the meantime, I want you all to know that my dog Bruin very much appreciates the attention.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I rise today to congratulate the UCLA Bruins for being the most accomplished athletic program in NCAA history, having won 100 NCAA championships.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many observers might presume that for UCLA the only game in town is men's basketball. Many walk into Pauley Pavilion and see 11 championship banners, experience the legacy of John Wooden, and presume that's all there is. But for UCLA, that is only the beginning.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The UCLA men's tennis team won the first NCAA championship for the Bruins in 1950 and the last 58 years have been witness to an unprecedented record of success. Including the 11 men's basketball titles, UCLA's championship record extends across 16 different programs including multiple titles in men's volleyball, 19; men's tennis, 16; women's softball, 10; men's track and field, 8; men's water polo, 8; women's gymnastics, 5; women's track and field, 5; and women's water polo, 5.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>UCLA's 100th championship came from the women's water polo team, which won its third consecutive NCAA Division I championship on May 13, 2007. The Bruins, coached by Adam Krikorian, finished 28-2 and have been 90-6 over the past three seasons. Courtney Mathewson scored three goals and Jillian Kraus added two more as the Bruins beat rival Stanford. Kelly Rulon was selected as the tournament's Most Valuable Player. Rulon, Mathewson, and Kraus were joined by Emily Feher and Kacy Kunkel as members  to the NCAA All-Tournament First Team.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These championships reflect the philosophies of great Bruin coaches like basketball icon John Wooden and volleyball legend Al Scates. Their commitment to hard work, discipline, and sportsmanship has created a legacy of victory unparalleled in college sports. Additionally, the contributions of all the fans, students, alumni, and staff have been instrumental over the years in helping UCLA achieve 100 championships.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The list of Bruin athletes who contributed to the school's heritage of victory is a rollcall of the greatest athletes of our time: Lewis Alcindor, Arthur Ashe, Evelyn Ashford, Jimmy Connors, Gale Devers, Mitch Gaylord, Florence Griffith-Joyner, Jackie Joyner-Kersee, Karch Kiraly, Jackie Robinson, Bill Walton, and others.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I'm especially proud that UCLA is a public university committed to diversity and fulfilling the promise of Title IX. Since 1982, Bruin women teams have contributed 30 championships to UCLA's total. This is enough to put them 11th on the NCAA's all-time champions list.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One hundred championships is a reflection of the teamwork that is the hallmark of UCLA athletics and its strong tradition of combining excellence in athletics with excellence in academics. UCLA's commitment to hard work, discipline, and sportsmanship has created a tradition of victory unparalleled in college sports.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400642" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I join with my colleagues from Iowa and California in support of this resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I rise today in support of House Resolution 493--Congratulating the women's water polo team of the University of California, Los Angeles, for winning the 2007 NCAA Division I Women's Water Polo National Championship, and congratulating UCLA on its 100th NCAA sports national title, making it the most accomplished athletic program in NCAA history.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On May 13, 2007, the UCLA women's water polo team defeated Stanford 5-4 in the championship game of the NCAA Division I Women's Water Polo National Championship tournament.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The victory gave head coach Adam Krikorian and the Bruins women's water polo team their third consecutive NCAA championship and was the team's fifth overall national title.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Kelly Rulon, a driver for the Bruins, was selected as the tournament's most valuable player; and Emily Feher, Courtney Mathewson, Jillian Kraus, and Kacy Kunkel were named to the NCAA All-Tournament First Team.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The UCLA women's water polo team finished the 2007 season with a record of 28 wins and 2 losses and now has a record of 90 wins and 6 losses over the past 3 seasons.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This national title makes UCLA the first school ever to win 100 NCAA sports national titles--only 58 years after the UCLA men's tennis team won the school's first NCAA title in 1950. Along the way, 16 different men's and women's sports programs contributed to the Bruins' 100 NCAA national championships.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>UCLA teams have won 14 NCAA national championships during the tenure of Daniel G. Guerrero, the current director of athletics. Under the leadership of Chancellor Gene Block, UCLA continues to establish itself as one of the top research universities as well as top athletic programs in the Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I extend my congratulations to Chancellor Block, Athletics Director Guerrero, Head Coach Adam Krikorian and his staff, all of the hard-working players, the fans, and to UCLA. I am happy to join my good friend and colleague Representative Lewis in honoring this exceptional team and all of its accomplishments and wish all involved continued success.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="T, LINDA" of="">
    <paragraph>S&#xC1;NCHEZ of California. Madam Speaker, I proudly rise today to congratulate the University of California, Los Angeles--My alma mater--on its 100th NCAA team championship.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In a Nation with so many colleges and universities known for their strong sports programs, heck, in a city the size of Los Angeles with sports powerhouse USC right across town, this is a truly amazing accomplishment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At UCLA, which has so many firsts in other areas, the 2007 UCLA women's water polo Team helped UCLA reach another first: the first to 100 NCAA team championships.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On May 13, 2007, the women's water polo team, led by Head Coach Adam Krikorian, defeated Stanford 9-4 in the last round of the Women's Water Polo National Championship tournament, thereby making history.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This was the team's third consecutive NCAA championship and its fifth overall national title. Team member Kelly Rulon was selected as the tournament's Most Valuable Player, and Ms. Rulon and four of her teammates--Emily Feher, Courtney Mathewson, Jillian Kraus, and Kacy Kunke--were named to the NCAA all-tournament team.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>UCLA won its first national title in men's tennis in 1950. Since then, 16 different athletics programs--nine men's programs and seven women's--have won national championships in the sports of basketball, golf, gymnastics, soccer, softball, swimming, tennis, track and field, volleyball, and, of course, water polo.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the last 5 years alone, under the leadership of Athletic Director Dan Guerrero, UCLA athletics teams have won 14 NCAA national championships in nine different sports.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This extraordinary achievement is a tribute to the skill and dedication of the many players, coaches, students, alumni, families, professors, staff, and fans who have helped to make UCLA an athletic powerhouse as well as one of the top academic universities in the Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>UCLA's accomplishment also demonstrates the success of Title IX. Of the 100 NCAA championships that UCLA teams have earned, women's teams have been responsible for 30. And the NCAA didn't even begin awarding championships in women's sports until the 1981-82 season.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To all the athletes of UCLA, past and present, male and female, you rock.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400642" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I have no further requests for time, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412209" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Iowa (Mr. Loebsack) that the House suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, <bill type="hr" number="493">H. Res. 493</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412209" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this motion will be postponed.</chair>
</record>
