<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1192032002" ordinal="46" title="PROVIDING FOR EXPENSES OF SELECT COMMITTEE ESTABLISHED UNDER H. RES. 611">
  <narrative>PROVIDING FOR EXPENSES OF SELECT COMMITTEE ESTABLISHED UNDER <bill type="hr" number="611">H. RES. 611</bill> -- (House of Representatives - October 10, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H11466]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400092" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I ask unanimous consent for the immediate consideration of the resolution (<bill type="hr" number="723">H. Res. 723</bill>) providing for the expenses of the select committee established under House Resolution 611.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the resolution.</narrative>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Alabama?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the resolution, as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="hr" number="723">H. Res. 723</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Resolved,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. EXPENSES OF SELECT COMMITTEE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Payment of Expenses.--There shall be paid out of the applicable accounts of the House of Representatives not more than $300,000 for the expenses of the select committee established under House Resolution 611, as agreed to August, 3, 2007 (hereafter referred to as the "select committee").&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Consultants.--The select committee shall be treated as a standing committee of the House for purposes of section 202(i) of the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 (2 U.S.C. 72a(i)).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Vouchers.--Payments under this resolution shall be made on vouchers authorized by the select committee, signed by the chairman of such committee, and approved in the manner directed by the Committee on House Administration.</narrative>
  <narrative> (d) Regulations.--Amounts made available under this resolution shall be expended in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Committee on House Administration.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <narrative>The resolution was agreed to.</narrative>
  <narrative>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</narrative>
</record>
