<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1178553612" ordinal="19" title="GRAND TETON NATIONAL PARK EXTENSION ACT OF 2007">
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="1080">H.R. 1080</bill>) to modify the boundaries of Grand Teton National Park to include certain land within the GT Park Subdivision, and for other purposes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) and the gentleman from Colorado (Mr. Lamborn) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Arizona?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1080">H.R. 1080</bill> was introduced by our colleague from Wyoming, Representative Barbara Cubin. The legislation would authorize the Secretary of the Interior to expand the boundaries of the Grand Teton National Park to include approximately 50 acres that landowners in the adjacent Grand Teton Park Subdivision wish to donate to the park.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The subdivision is located adjacent to the park's eastern boundary and is visible from the park's main road. According to the National Park Service, the land is similar in character and quality to the adjacent parklands and offers unobstructed views of the Teton range and across the broad valley of Jackson Hole.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One lot in the subdivision was owned by the Gerald Halpin family. The remaining seven lots were donated by the Halpin family to private organizations, including the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation, the National Park Foundation, and the Grand Teton National Park Foundation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>All of these owners would like to donate their land to the park, but the parcels lie outside the existing park boundary. The 1950 law creating the park includes a provision forbidding expansion of any national park or monument in Wyoming without the express authorization of Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1080">H.R. 1080</bill> would authorize the Secretary to accept the donation of lands within the subdivision and, upon acquisition, adjust the boundary of Grand Teton National Park. The bill would also prohibit the future sale, donation, exchange or other transfer of the acquired land without congressional approval.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Related legislation passed the other body in the 109th Congress and has been reintroduced by Senator Craig Thomas of Wyoming and approved by the Senate Energy and Natural Resources Committee earlier this year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the National Park Service has testified in support of the bill, and it cleared the National Parks, Forests and Public Lands Subcommittee, and the full Natural Resources Committee on voice votes without any amendments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, Representative Cubin is to be commended for her work on this legislation. We support passage of <bill type="h" number="1080">H.R. 1080</bill> and urge its adoption by the House today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1080">H.R. 1080</bill>, introduced by our colleague Congresswoman Barbara Cubin, would modify the boundaries of the Grand Teton National Park to include 49 acres of privately donated land. I commend Mrs. Cubin for her work on this legislation. This highly valuable land, which has been valued at nearly $20 million, is being conveyed to the Park Service at very minimal cost.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Representative Cubin and her staff did an excellent job working with the private individuals and groups who are donating the land and with the Park Service. The 49 acres are beautiful and highly desirable land that will enhance Grand Teton National Park.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This noncontroversial bill was favorably reported by the Natural Resources Committee by unanimous consent, and I urge my colleagues to support <bill type="h" number="1080">H.R. 1080</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would also like to add that our thoughts and prayers are with Representative Cubin and her husband, Dr. Cubin. We wish him a quick and speedy recovery.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no additional speakers, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no additional speakers, and I yield back the balance of our time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="1080">H.R. 1080</bill>.</chair>
</record>
