<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1181059208" ordinal="26" title="CEILING INCREASE ON FEDERAL SHARE OF WATER RECLAMATION PROJECT">
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="1175">H.R. 1175</bill>) to amend the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to increase the ceiling on the Federal share of the costs of phase I of the Orange County, California, Regional Water Reclamation Project.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from the Virgin Islands (Mrs. Christensen) and the gentleman from Utah (Mr. Cannon) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members have 5 days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from the Virgin Islands?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would first like to commend my friend and our colleague from California, Representative Loretta Sanchez, for her dedicated and hard work on this legislation over several Congresses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of <bill type="h" number="1175">H.R. 1175</bill>, as introduced by Ms. Sanchez, is to amend the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to increase the Federal cost share of phase one of the Orange County, California Regional Water Reclamation Project.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The project authorized by <bill type="h" number="1175">H.R. 1175</bill> will supplement existing water supplies by providing a new, reliable, high quality source of water to recharge the Orange County Groundwater Basin and protect it from further degradation due to seawater intrusion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank Ms. Sanchez for her efforts on this legislation and urge my colleagues to join me in supporting <bill type="h" number="1175">H.R. 1175</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="1175">H.R. 1175</bill> and yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Democratic bill manager has adequately explained the bill. This legislation has been cosponsored by five of my Republican colleagues, Mr. Calvert, Mr. Gary Miller of California, Mr. Rohrabacher, Mr. Royce and Mr. Campbell of California.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400356" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="1175">H.R. 1175</bill>, a bill that I have introduced for two consecutive Congresses. I am pleased to see that the bill is on the Suspension Calendar today. I would like to thank the House leadership for making that happen.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1175">H.R. 1175</bill> would increase the ceiling on the federal share of the Orange County, California, Regional Water Reclamation Project--from $20 million to $51,874,849. This project will ultimately allow Orange County to complete its innovative groundwater replenishment system, which is designed to reuse advanced treated wastewater to recharge the aquifer in northern Orange County.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This aquifer is the primary source of drinking water for over 144,000 families in Orange County each year, serving about 2.3 million residents from north and central Orange County. This reclamation effort has the potential of creating a new water supply of 72,000 acre-feet per year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The OC Groundwater Replenishment Project is an innovative program which has drawn national and international attention. Many U.S. states and foreign nations--including Japan, Korea, Taiwan--have come to Orange County to look at our tertiary cleaning system. They have observed that reusing recycled water--especially important in the arid west--will help preserve and recharge overdrawn river and groundwater supplies, and will help protect our environment from unexpected scarcity of water.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What this bill does is to increase the federal share of the project, bringing it closer to the 25 percent level, the level at which almost every other reclamation project is funded in the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act of 1992 and the Reclamation Cycling and Water Conservation Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The project is not just important to Orange County, California, but also to the entire western United States. By recycling our own water, we will not rely so heavily on the Colorado River Aqueduct or water from the San Francisco Bay Delta.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Members from both sides of the aisle recognize the need for this project and have been consistently supportive of this effort. I would like to thank, in particular, my colleagues from Orange County who are all original cosponsors of this bill. I appreciate their continued support for this legislation, and this important project.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me thank, again, the gentleman from West Virginia, Mr. Rahall, for his support, as well as Ranking Member Young, Subcommittee Chairwoman Napolitano and Ranking Member McMorris for their overwhelming support of <bill type="h" number="1175">H.R. 1175</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, let me thank Denis Bilodeau, Irv Pickler, Virginia Grebbien, Philip Anthony, Craig Miller, and everyone affiliated with the Orange County Water District and Orange County Sanitation District for their hard work and leadership in groundwater treatment and recycling. Their innovation has put Orange County at the forefront of water recycling and groundwater replenishment technology. I thank them for all they continue to do for Orange County.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this measure.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from the Virgin Islands (Mrs. Christensen) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="1175">H.R. 1175</bill>.</chair>
</record>
