<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1176998405" ordinal="29" title="WATER RESOURCES DEVELOPMENT ACT OF 2007">
  <chair> Pursuant to House Resolution 319 and rule XVIII, the Chair declares the House in the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for the consideration of the bill, <bill type="h" number="1495">H.R. 1495</bill>.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the bill is considered read the first time.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise in strong support of <bill type="h" number="1495">H.R. 1495</bill>, the Water Resources Development Act of 2007, a bill long in the making, 6 years in the making, a bill that has ultimately passed the House, not passed the Senate, passed the House, passed the Senate, not gone to conference.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We tried in the closing hours of the 109th Congress to wrap this measure up, then-Chairman DON YOUNG and I, working with our counterparts in the other body, attempting to reach an agreement, but it just proved insurmountable, too insurmountable an obstacle to get there.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In this 110th Congress, we resumed on the base of the legislation that has built up over 6 years, over three Congresses, and working with the distinguished gentleman from Florida (Mr. Mica), the ranking member on the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, we spent a great deal of time together thinking through how to proceed with this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We agreed on basic principles that we would start with the bill that passed the House. There was no conference ever consummated in the 109th Congress. So we decided that the benchmark bill for this Congress would be only those measures that were in the bill of the 109th Congress, and we started from there. And then we have worked our way through myriad issues, Members who wanted new projects or amendments or additions to existing projects; and in all cases, we made very, very difficult, but I  think honest and consistent, decisions about the legislation we bring before you today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to assure Members that are concerned, that have issues that have arisen since the 109th Congress, that those issues that need to be addressed by projects of the Corps of Engineers will be addressed in subsequent legislation. As soon as we are able to move this bill through the House, through conference with the Senate, which I am confident can be done before the middle of June, maybe earlier if the other body will be able to free itself to work with us in conference, we can get this done  very quickly, and then begin on the next round of water resources projects which I guarantee is not going to take 7 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>We are going to deal with somebody, maybe in the next 7 or 8 months after the conclusion of this legislation. Again, I express my appreciation to the gentleman from Florida for consistently working to move this critically important legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure is the proud inheritor of a long tradition of work, of investment in America's transportation needs, water resources, where the very first concerns of the new Nation in 1789 and the first act of the first Congress, 1789, was to authorize the establishment of a lighthouse, at the entry to Hampton Roads in Virginia.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Starting from that point, this committee continued the direction of the Constitution to build and maintain post roads. Well, not all roads were built just for the postal service; but, again, it was the spirit of the Constitution, the spirit of the new Nation that we needed mobility. The Nation was founded along the waterways, the salt water coasts, the inland waterways. It has been our task to assure mobility, movement of people and goods through waterways, and then the highways, later the railways,  and then the airways.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Here we come with this massive bill, because the President, because Congress hasn't done its work; and the last time a President signed a Water Resources Development Act was in 2000. Well, we hope that the next one will be this year, which we fully expect.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are many issues that have arisen in the intervening years, some that were weighing heavily upon us when we began this process in 2000 of crafting the current WRDA bill on the Great Lakes. Invasive species are threatening our native aquatic species, biota and flora, as well as a new issue called a deadly fish virus, a hemorrhagic virus that destroys the fisheries and is carried in ballast waters from one region of the Great Lakes to another.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have language in this bill that will initiate an emergency program by the Corps of Engineers to protect the vital food supply and the quality of the waters.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Lake Superior, because of a drought in the Great Lakes watershed, has seen the water level drop 8 inches in the past 3 years and will drop another 2 inches this year with the beginning of the major shipping season. It will be at nearly its lowest level in history. That has meant that vessels carrying iron ore from the upper lakes to the lower lakes steel mills have gone out 7,500 tons light.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It means two or three extra voyages per vessel per season, raising the cost of iron ore, raising the cost of steel, affecting our competitiveness. We have legislation, we have language in this legislation that will direct the Corps to undertake an accelerated dredging program making up for the 15 years they haven't done the dredging because we have had high waters on the Great Lakes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We authorize locks, improved extended locks on the Mississippi River system, seven extended locks to take the 600-foot locks to make them 1,200-foot locks. A barge tow leaving Clinton, Iowa, round-trip to New Orleans, back to Clinton, Iowa, takes 820 hours. New Orleans is the world's most important grain export facility.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We can cut 60 hours off that round-trip by extending the locks at 1,200 feet so the tows that are 1,200 feet don't have to be broken in half, sent through 600 feet at a time, lashed together, go through the next lock and do it all over again. We are in a world competitive market on which grain moves on as little as an eighth of a cent a bushel. Every time you have to spend those extra hours going through the locks, you are raising the cost of our commodities, which makes us less competitive with,  say, Brazil, which is mounting a massive soybean export facility at Recife, which is 2,500 miles further out in the Atlantic Ocean than New Orleans is.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have legislation here, language in this legislation to deal with the restoration of the Everglades, a matter of great interest to the gentleman from Florida, for which he has been an eloquent advocate. They are in a state of disrepair. The buffer to protect them from storms is weak because of our inaction, and we are going to deal with that issue, as well as the wetlands along the Gulf of Mexico from Texas, Louisiana, Mississippi, Alabama, all the way on to Florida.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are insistent on addressing the needs of the Everglades, the needs of the Louisiana coastal region and in Louisiana, New Orleans area, the Mississippi River gulf outlet, which allowed salt water intrusion to come up from the gulf, kill the wetlands. It allowed the overtopping of St. Bernard Parish. We have got to restore that wetland, and this legislation will do that at the request and insistence of the Louisiana delegation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are many other important features in this legislation. In all, 56 chiefs' reports, we had a request of over 1,500 projects. There are over 700 projects in this legislation. More than 300 Members of the House have a direct interest in the legislation. We welcome their interest in this participation. We bring to this body a very critical and supportable piece of legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400273" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, first of all, I would like to urge all Members of the House on both sides of the aisle to support <bill type="h" number="1495">H.R. 1495</bill>, which is known as the Water Resources Development Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As we have heard from the chairman, this bill authorizes and directs the Corps of Engineers to carry out various studies, projects and programs relating to navigation, flood damage reduction, shoreline protection, dam safety, shoreline protection and recreation and environmental restoration and protection.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our subcommittee, led by Mr. Baker of Louisiana, held two days of hearings on projects, programs and policies during the development of this legislation. After a careful review, the committee was able to approve the authorization of more than 50 projects with the chiefs' reports relating to flood damage reduction, navigation, hurricane and storm damage reduction, and environmental restoration.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We also have in this legislation, navigation and ecosystem restoration projects for the upper Mississippi River. Illinois waterway system, and Everglades restoration project, which I would like to talk about in just a moment, and conserving and restoring the Louisiana coastal area.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have in the bill a provision for streamlining and expediting the Corps of Engineers' project delivery and permits system. We have provisions for improvement of the Corps of Engineers' planning and project development process, including independent peer review of larger and more controversial studies. We also have authorization of a number of smaller project modifications, investigations, related to our civil works programs of the Corps of Engineers. I think all in all we have a good piece  of legislation that we have worked on in a bipartisan fashion, and you see the product before us today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, I know the administration has issued a position opposing this legislation. However, I want to talk to a couple of points that they have raised. They do have a responsibility to be good trustees of the public monies and  the difficult situation we find ourselves in financially.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But in this legislation between 3 and $4 billion would be typically spent during a WRDA cycle or authorization process on this type of legislation. We have not had a bill since the year 2000. So actually if you do simple math on that, you can see that the total cost of this bill in Federal dollars, $13.1 billion, is reasonable. The total cost with the State participation is $17.8 billion. But we do, indeed, have a backlog of projects over what would amount to at least three cycles. So this WRDA  bill, this authorization legislation, in fact, combines the equivalent of all of those years of backlog of projects. The price tag, in fact, is consistent with that assumption.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While this bill is considered costly by some, the 2005 WRDA legislation contained almost 900 projects. That is another complaint of the administration, too many projects. This bill contains 682 project provisions. Not that Mr. Oberstar, myself, Ms. Johnson, Mr. Baker haven't had Members throughout the Congress come to us and beg and plead to have additional projects that are critical to their district included in this legislation. I think we, too, have been good custodians  and responsible in crafting this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me say that the administration also raised some questions about cost benefits. We have gone through this. Mr. Oberstar, myself, Mr. Baker, Ms. Johnson, we have looked at cost benefits. We have done our very best to ensure that the taxpayers' dollars again are well spent and there is a good return for the investment that is being made here by the Federal taxpayer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So those are the reasons that I disagree with my administration on this. I actively support this. I think we have done this in a very good fashion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, I want to talk to some of the measures that are in the bill. You have heard the chairman talk about some of the measures that are in this bill. This bill is important to me, not only as a Member of Congress, and I don't represent the Everglades, but I do represent the State of Florida. It is interesting how it takes time to undo some of the damage that mankind has done to our natural resources and national treasures.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have a copy of the Palm Beach Post, which I kept in a file, from Sunday, April 11, 1993, irony, same month a number of years ago, talking about the Everglades, reversing man's mistakes. I started working on that along with the Clinton administration, Secretary Babbitt. Hear is an article from July 4, 1994, about a $465 million government industry agreement to start cleaning up the Everglades, which had been damaged by man's abuse.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Here is another article I pulled from the news journal Daytona Beach News-Journal that says: "Representative John Mica and the other Members of central Florida's House delegation are in a fortunate position to finish the work the Senate started." This is the year 2000. Here we are in 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, in 2000 we authorized a study. What is important about this bill is we authorize for the first time projects that actually do construction and work in restoring our precious national treasure, and Florida's national environmental treasure, the Everglades.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>So that is one reason why I am excited about this piece of legislation. It does take a long time and a lot of money.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, I do want to also cite that I just inherited the responsibility of the Transportation leader on the Republican side, and I never realized how important these projects are to individual Members. For example, not on our side of the aisle, but Ms. Matsui, a Democrat Member, she has a project in here that would provide a 100-year level of flood protection for the city of Sacramento. Almost a million Americans live in the capital of California, more than twice the population of the  pre-Katrina New Orleans that today has only an 80-year level of flood protection. No other community in America of this size has this little flood protection. This is a project important to Ms. Matsui.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are not Republican projects, there are not Democrat projects; there are projects for the people that are important to their survival. And we have seen the mistakes and the errors of our ways in Katrina. Mr. Baker can speak to what he has gone through in Louisiana. We need not repeat those errors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So here we have in this legislation an opportunity to help her and 299 other districts. I wish it was 435. So it has been put together in a bipartisan way.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And finally, on my effort, I tried to do it in a transparent way. All of the Republican projects have been on file, open to the public, and any of the earmarks, open to public and press scrutiny. So I have tried to do it in a manner that restores public faith, because I would rather have elected Members of Congress make those decisions, fight for them, and have it done and conducted in a transparent fashion rather than have some bureaucrat down there decide where the taxpayer money, which they  just paid in in huge amounts over the past week to Washington, get expended. That is our responsibility, it is elected officials' responsibility, not appointed bureaucrats who don't have the responsibility we have under the Constitution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, again, I recognize my colleagues on the other side of the aisle, Mr. Oberstar, Ms. Johnson and Mr. Baker. I also want to thank Mr. Costello, who is no longer the Chair or the ranking member, and Mr. Duncan, who was the Chair because this is an inherited work. Again, several bills are combined that are long overdue. So I urge their passage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield myself 1 minute to express my great appreciation again to the gentleman from Florida for his thoughtful discussion. I join him in his statement on the administration's statement of policy. I think they have it wrong, and the gentleman stated it just right.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over the past 6 years, if we had passed the water resources bill in a timely fashion, it would have been in the range of $2 billion a year. That is normal. So what we are dealing with is a huge, pent-up backlog.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, as the gentleman said, this is an investment in America, and Members of Congress representing their constituents, their businesses, their water resources, know what they need. They have come forward with thoughtful recommendations, and this bill reflects those recommendations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have served as a filter to weed out those in our best judgment that did not measure up on cost-benefit analysis. So we have set a standard for the future and we have, in accordance with the rules of the House, made all of the Member projects available, and will continue to do that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to acknowledge the splendid work of the Chair of the Subcommittee on Water Resources, Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson. She has devoted years of her service in the Congress to consideration of water resources vital to her State of Texas. She has taken ownership of these issues and led the subcommittee hearings. Even this afternoon, she has hearings going on in our committee room while she is here to help manage the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 5 minutes to the gentlewoman from Texas (Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400204" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Thank you, Mr. Chairman.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am pleased to rise to support <bill type="h" number="1495">H.R. 1495</bill>, the Water Resources Development Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill authorizes water resources projects and the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers policy and programmatic changes that our Congress has failed to consider for far too long.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Water resources legislation is most effective when it is considered biennially. I support this 2-year cycle, as it provides stability to the program and assurance to the non-Federal sponsors who support Corps projects.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When we let them go, they get to be more costly. And, unfortunately, no water resources bill has been enacted since 2000, the entire term of our current administration. This is a result, in part, of a failure of the current administration to engage in this important legislation, as well as a failure of the Congress to reach agreement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last year, we came very close to resolving our differences with the other body in conference. However, we ultimately ran out of time. I hope this legislation that we consider today can take us to that point and further, releasing this backlog of authorizations to fix our existing infrastructure and  to authorize new flood control, navigation and environmental restoration projects.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are trying very hard to move a little ahead of the next flooding. We must do that. And they are not going to kick out Democrats or Republicans for flooding, it is going to be whoever is in the way. It is purposeful that we have brought this bill to the floor as early as we have in this session.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The authorizations in the language are time sensitive, and there should be no surprise that this bill contains a substantial number of provisions. Many of these authorizations have been waiting for action more than 6 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Within the 110th Congress, the committee intends to move two water resources bill. This first one contains a logjam of more than 6 years of issues. The second bill will consider new projects and policy changes that we were not able to add to this legislation, that we will consider today. This approach may not be traditional, but it is necessary.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since Congress last passed a Water Resources Development Act, we have seen Hurricanes Katrina and Rita tear up the gulf coast and my home State of Texas, flooding cities, damaging economies and businesses, and threatening public health.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Florida Everglades continue to need attention and restoration to save the unique treasures it brings to the State and our country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill also contains smaller projects that may be less publicized but just as vital to communities that rely on various water resources for their livelihood.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As in the past, these projects were not considered on a partisan basis, but on individual merit. Their approval should not be considered solely on whether they are Democratic projects or Republican projects; these are human projects. They should be considered on their contributions to public safety and economics.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1495">H.R. 1495</bill> authorizes programmatic changes to the Corps of Engineers that previously have passed the House, but have stalled in the failed conference negotiations. During the 109th Congress we came close to resolving these differences with the Senate. I urge my colleagues to once again support these provisions. Everybody who has been here more than 6 years ought to know what everything is in this bill because they have seen it over and over and over again. We must engage the other body and together  produce the best package for Corps reform.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to acknowledge Chairman Oberstar for his leadership and eloquence in the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, as well as the interest and expertise that he shares on water resources issues.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also would like to thank our ranking member, Mr. Mica, and the ranking member of the subcommittee, Mr. Baker, for their knowledge and effort and partnership with me, and for their support.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I strongly support this legislation. I hope and urge my colleagues to vote in favor of its final passage. The time is now.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400012" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, at this time I recognize a valued member of the committee, Mr. Brown, for 2 minutes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Mr. BROWN of South Carolina asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400049" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for yielding me this time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in strong support of this critical legislation. I want to thank so many on this committee for their hard work and long dedication to this legislation, especially our chairman, Mr. Oberstar, and our ranking member, Mr. Mica; and the subcommittee chairwoman, Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson, and Mr. Baker, the ranking member. I also thank Mr. Duncan, the former chairman, and Mr. Costello, who is the ranking member.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have been working on this bill now for my term in Congress, and this is my fourth term, and I am happy today we are here to present it again.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One of the most important elements in this bill are reforms made to the processes and procedures of the Army Corps. The infrastructure needs of our Nation have never been at a higher level. We need to do all we can to ensure that the limited dollars available are spent wisely, and the reforms in this bill will give the Corps the tools to make that happen.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, the bill makes significant changes to the project delivery process used by the Army Corps. The process the Corps has to go through now to deliver a project are long and hard, to say the least. This bill makes commonsense change to streamline that process to help our communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Improving infrastructure is not a partisan issue, it is a commitment we as a Nation must ensure is met. If we do not, then we as a Nation will be facing significantly greater environmental and economic challenges than we do currently.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In closing, I want to say again that I strongly support this legislation and I am confident we will enact a bill this year. I also want to thank my friends and colleagues on the committee as we all have joined to invest so much effort into this particular legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am proud to stand with you in support of its passage.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 2 minutes to the gentleman from Oregon (Mr. Blumenauer), an alumnus of the committee.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400033" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I appreciate the gentleman's courtesy, and I am proud of the time that I was able to work with you for 10 years on this subcommittee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise in support of the bill. As was referenced by the Chair of the committee and the subcommittee, this is an important and complex bill with 682 projects. They are important economically. They are important environmentally. We found out less than 2 years ago how critical they are to the Nation. Hurricane Katrina revealed it can literally be a matter of life or death.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation has been hung up since the year 2000, in part because of disagreements about the reform agenda with the Corps of Engineers. I am pleased that we have signaled an effort to try and move forward, to be able to break that impasse with this legislation, the provisions in it and others that will follow.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am also pleased to have an opportunity to offer an amendment to update the principles and guidelines that would help the Corps move even closer to developing environmentally, fiscally, and structurally sound projects.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me be clear. The amendment will not impact any project currently under way or anything covered in this legislation. It would simply tell the Corps of Engineers to update their own principles and guidelines, the playbook for developing water resources projects that are over 25 years old. The National Academy of Sciences has said they are woefully out of date. And the Corps and the Congress' inability to update these principles and guidelines is one of the reasons why the Corps has drawn criticism  from the Government Accountability Office, the National Academy of Sciences, and the OMB, along with internal Pentagon reviews.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is one of the reasons why we have had trouble passing WRDA in the last 6 years and reconciling it with the Senate which has similar provisions. It does not affect anything in the bill currently; and I think it will be an opportunity for us not just passing the bill, but it would be a reason for the President to sign it, given the problems they have had.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I appreciate the hard work that has been done. I appreciate the opportunity to speak in support of the bill, and look forward to having support for the amendment for updating the principles and guidelines later in the afternoon.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400012" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 1 1/2  minutes to the gentlewoman from West Virginia (Mrs. Capito), a valued member of the committee.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400061" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in strong support for the reauthorization of the Water Resources Development Act. I would like to thank Chairman Oberstar, Ranking Member Mica, Subcommittee Chairman Johnson and Ranking Member Baker for their hard work in getting this legislation to the floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It has been too long since the water resources bill has become law, and it is important that we continue to move this and make this reauthorization a reality. Projects authorized in this bill are critical to our national waterways transportation system that businesses and industry in every State and congressional district rely on to move their products.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In my State of West Virginia, a well-maintained system of navigable waterways is crucial to moving coal from our mines to plants across the country to power this Nation's economy. The bill addresses local needs. I am pleased that this legislation recognizes the important water and wastewater challenges in West Virginia by continuing the authorization for the Central West Virginia Environmental Infrastructure Program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>This program has provided access to clean water and wastewater treatment to many rural West Virginians who otherwise would be without these critical utilities. I am pleased that this Corps of Engineers program will be able to continue assisting local public service districts to address these important community needs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank the committee for their hard work. I look forward to the final passage and the President's signature on this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Could the Chair advise the time remaining on both sides.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from Minnesota has 13 minutes remaining. The gentleman from Louisiana has 17 minutes remaining.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 1 1/2  minutes to the distinguished gentleman from Colorado (Mr. Salazar).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400620" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I want to thank the gentleman from Minnesota (Mr. Oberstar) for yielding, and I would like to recognize him, as well as the ranking member, for the exceptional leadership on this critical issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise today in support of <bill type="h" number="1495">H.R. 1495</bill>, the Water Resources Development Act of 2007. I urge the swift passage of the measure. Passage of this bill is long overdue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My communities are desperately waiting for infrastructure projects which are of major importance to their districts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My district includes hundreds of small communities that have narrow economic and tax bases. Small communities like these often are unable to address the significant infrastructure needs. Water infrastructure is vital to the economy and stability of these small communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My rural communities rely on antiquated water systems, and they need to be updated. Without the means to update old systems, many of our constituents and communities nationwide have been living in substandard conditions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is not only an environmental health issue. A lack of sufficient water resources can effectively prevent the community from moving forward with critical infrastructure, like additional housing for its inhabitants.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill is an important and necessary step in protecting our Nation's water infrastructure. Quite simply, Mr. Chairman, we cannot afford not to pass this critical legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this investment in water resource development and conservation projects and the passage of this much-needed bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400012" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, at this time I would like to yield 2 minutes to my distinguished colleague from Louisiana who has worked tirelessly on assisting the people of the storm-stricken area, Dr. BOUSTANY. </paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400636" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I want to thank my colleague from Louisiana for yielding time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in support of this bill. WRDA reauthorization is long overdue, and it is vital that we pass <bill type="h" number="1495">H.R. 1495</bill> and get a bill signed into law this year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>WRDA authorizes nearly $2.1 billion for the Louisiana coastal area, and it will allow the Army Corps of Engineers to move forward on many critical coastal restoration and hurricane protection projects statewide.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also want to thank Chairman Oberstar for accepting my amendment in committee to add projects identified in the Southwest Louisiana Coastal Hurricane Storm and Reduction Study to the list of priority projects and projects to be expedited under this bill. Thank you, Mr. Chairman.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This study is the first comprehensive assessment of hurricane and flood protection needs of southwest Louisiana. The Corps has nearly completed the reconnaissance phase, and I anticipate that we will enter into an agreement with the State to proceed with the feasibility phase in the near future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is important that we expedite these projects, not only for southwest Louisiana, but for the entire Nation because in southwest Louisiana our waterways protect much of the vital and necessary energy infrastructure that keeps this country running.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have one of the largest strategic petroleum reserves in my district that is affected here. Also, the Henry Hub, which is where pricing is set for natural gas for the country, is in my district. And it was actually flooded in Hurricane Rita.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And nearly 25 percent of the liquefied natural gas will run through my district by 2015.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These waterways and coastal wetlands are far more than just commercial routes or playgrounds. They are a critical buffer to protect homes, business and our energy infrastructure and our way of life in Louisiana. What we are talking about is America's energy coast, a working coast.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I urge my colleagues to support this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400012" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, at this time I would like to recognize a Member who has expressed interest in this subject matter, Mr. Hulshof, for 2 1/2  minutes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Mr. HULSHOF asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400190" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="1495">H.R. 1495</bill>. I grew up in the shadow of levees along the Mississippi River in southeast Missouri. And while the river, at times destructive, the river has been a provider for me and my family, delivering the grain from our farm to international markets.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And I will tell you, as the gentleman from Minnesota has stated, the nickels and dimes that we saved by shipping via barge were often the difference between our farm ending up in the red or ending up in the black. Those few cents have helped keep food on our table; clothes on our back; and, over the years, kept our farm even within our own family.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Title VIII of the legislation, lock modernization, will insure that farmers in northeast Missouri and farmers in Iowa and Illinois, Minnesota, Wisconsin and elsewhere will continue to have the same benefit that my family had, the ability to ship crops to international markets via the most cost-effective method.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I will tell you that a recent study by the Food and Ag Policy Research Institute, FAPRI, found that if the Mississippi River and Illinois waterways were forced to close, possibly because of a massive lock failure, that farmers, our own U.S. farmers, would lose between $645 million and $806 million a year, a year in increased transportation costs. We experienced a glimpse of that in the aftermath of Hurricane Katrina when the river was shut down, navigation was shut down for a short time during  the fall of 2005. Farmers endured a 60-cent-per-bushel penalty on a bushel of corn during that critical time in September of 2005. And a massive failure, unfortunately, is a distinct possibility.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These locks are standing just out of habit, or as my constituent, Senator KIT BOND, is fond of saying, "These locks belong in the National Register of Historic Locations." They were built in the 1930s to accommodate steamboats for the next 50 years. As the gentleman pointed out, these locks are no longer navigation aids, but hindrances. They are 600 feet long. The modern barge is close to 1,200 feet, often three across and five long.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What I want to emphasize again to my friend from Oregon who spoke, and others, these locks benefit the American public in other ways. The typical tow removes 870 18-wheel tractor trailer trucks from our already congested roads, bridges, and interstate highways. A gallon of diesel fuel will push one ton of freight 2 1/2  times further by barge than by locomotive; nine times farther than by truck. Moreover, according to the Environmental Protection Agency, towboats emit 35 to 60 percent fewer pollutants  than locomotives or trucks. All in all, all worthy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge its support.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield myself 1 3/4  minutes, and I yield to the gentleman from Wisconsin.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412240" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, in the last Congress the House approved a  water resources bill that included language to modify the navigation channel for the Fox River in Wisconsin. This provision, which was inserted by my predecessor, would have modified part of the navigational channel from 150 feet wide to 75 feet and from an authorized depth of 18 feet to 6 feet. However, the Congress adjourned and the work never was completed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This year I requested that this language not be included in the water resources bill because of my concern that it might impair the navigability of the Fox River and the potential for future commerce. It is my understanding that a 9-foot authorization depth is considered the minimal depth for a navigational channel to safely handle barge traffic.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to work with the Congress, with the chairman in conference to ensure that whatever language is included in the conference agreement, it will not adversely impact the navigability of the Fox River and will accomplish the goals of a safe cleanup of the Fox River.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for his leadership on this issue. The question of the Fox River has been on the agenda of the committee for over 20 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And the gentleman has stated the issue very well: that 6-foot channel depth is simply not viable for today's barge traffic.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And there is also the issue of PCB contamination in the lower Fox River. The gentleman has shown real foresight in dealing with the issue both of navigation and of cleanup. So the Superfund really ought to deal with this problem. It is not going to. We are going to be vigilant on the matter. If there is an opportunity in conference to address the issue in an appropriate manner, we will do that. If not, we will do it in a subsequent water resources bill. And I look forward to coming to Green Bay  to see the gentleman's district and the lower Fox River.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400012" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, at this time I would like to yield 2 minutes to a gentleman who is a former chairman of the Water Resources Subcommittee and who put an enormous amount of work into the product on the House floor today, Mr. Duncan.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400116" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I first want to commend Chairman Oberstar, Ranking Member Mica, Chairwoman Johnson, with whom I spent so many hours. She was my ranking member during the entire 6 years that I had the privilege of chairing the Water Resources and Environment, or during part of the time that I chaired the Water Resources and Environment Subcommittee, and such a good friend, and Ranking Member Baker, for bringing this bill to the floor today and for  their good and hard work on this legislation. And I urge its support.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a very conservative bill, Mr. Chairman. It is a bill that passed this House with only eight dissenting votes a few years ago and then later only 14 dissenting votes. The bill passed with over 400 votes in favor of it each time in the House. We did our work, but then it got held up in the other body.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Some people say that these projects should be paid for entirely on a local basis. But I can tell you there is a very important Federal role in regard to our water resources because people in California or New York or Michigan use the water in Tennessee. And people expect us to have a good wastewater and clean water system in this country. And yet it is something that people take for granted probably more than anything else that I can think of. And we have got to improve and strengthen our water  resource system in this country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over the last few years, we have spent many billions on the water system, our wastewater and clean water systems in Iraq. But we have fallen down at the Federal level on what we are doing on our wastewater and clean water systems in this country. And most of the spending has been done by the State and local governments and particularly by the ratepayers. And so this is a very necessary, very overdue bill, as many have pointed out. And I urge support for this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield to the distinguished gentleman from Florida (Mr. Mahoney) 1 1/2  minutes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412197" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise today in strong support of <bill type="h" number="1495">H.R. 1495</bill>, the Water Resources Development Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Seven years ago Congress, in the spirit of bipartisanship, had the wisdom to protect for future generations one of America's most precious natural areas, the Everglades, by authorizing the largest environmental restoration project in our Nation's history, the Comprehensive Everglades Restoration Plan (CERP).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This ambitious plan consists of over 40 projects that, when completed, would restore much of the Everglades. The plan, from its inception, was a joint venture, an equal partnership with the people of my State of Florida to share in the costs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am sorry to say that Washington has failed to honor its word and live up to its commitment. In fact, to the shame of the Republican-controlled Congress and the current administration, not a single WRDA bill has been passed since 2000. Not a single penny spent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am proud to say that during this same period of time, Florida has spent over $2 billion to get CERP going. In fact, this is so important in my district that the good people from Martin County voted to increase their taxes to help pay.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In my 16th Congressional District we are going to get the opportunity to restore the Indian River Lagoon.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Stuart, Florida, which straddles the lagoon, is the sailfish capital of the world and was built on tourism based on its world-renowned fishing. I have seen the black and white photos of wagons overflowing with fish. I have seen the photos of kids swimming in the lagoon.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is time to quit talking about fixing it. It is time for our kids to go fishing. It is time for this Congress to have the courage and leadership to pass <bill type="h" number="1495">H.R. 1495</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400012" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, at this time I would yield 1 minute to Mrs. Biggert.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400027" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in strong support of <bill type="h" number="1495">H.R. 1495</bill>. My district in Illinois represents the front line in the fight to keep the Asian carp from decimating the ecosystem of the Great Lakes and endangering a multi-million dollar commercial fishing industry.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>Competing with native species for food, living space, and spawning areas, these voracious fish grow to between 50 and 150 pounds, eat up to 40 percent of their body weight every day, and each female can carry up to a million eggs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill before us today will enable the Army Corps of Engineers to fortify its aquatic and invasive species dispersal barrier, an invisible, underwater, electric fence on the Chicago Ship and Sanitary Canal in Illinois that repulses fish like the Asian carp.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is why I rise today, to thank Chairman Oberstar and Ranking Member Mica, as well as Subcommittee Chairman Johnson and Ranking Member Baker, for recognizing the continuing threat of the Asian carp and including provisions in this bill to protect the Great Lakes. Our Great Lakes are too important just to leave them vulnerable to invasive species like the Asian carp.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 1 1/2  minutes to the distinguished gentleman from Missouri (Mr. Carnahan).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400638" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise as a strong supporter and cosponsor of this Water Resources Development Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This new Democratic Congress has made reauthorizing WRDA a top priority. I thank Chairman Oberstar and Subcommittee Chairwoman Johnson for their work in quickly moving this bill of national significance to help protect America's waterways.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These projects are vital to my home State of Missouri. Our local economy is driven by use of such important routes as the Mississippi, Missouri, and Illinois Rivers. Commerce on these rivers will be greatly benefited by this bill's strong commitment to repair current locks and reconstruct new locks on the Mississippi River.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a member of the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment, I have fought on behalf of my constituents to secure new levels of funding to help throughout our region. In particular, the bill authorizes $35 million for combined sewer overflow elimination in St. Louis. Some of our wastewater infrastructure dates back to the Lincoln administration.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The great flood of 1993 exposed serious flaws in the St. Louis flood wall. This bill addresses that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Lastly, this bill continues the exciting progress of the Great Rivers Greenway in St. Louis City and County. By creating an aquatic ecosystem restoration, constructing bike paths, and increasing access to the Mississippi River, my constituents will gain more use of one of our national treasures.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These projects are important to the strength of our community and the health of our waterways. I stand in strong support of <bill type="h" number="1495">H.R. 1495</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400012" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, at this time I would like to yield 3 minutes to the gentlewoman from California (Mrs. Bono).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400039" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I thank the gentleman for yielding me this time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise today to offer my concerns regarding a provision that was not included in this legislation, yet it is of significant importance to all of southern California. My concerns pertain to the importance of addressing the issues associated with the Salton Sea in southern California, which is California's largest lake.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This body of water is significant not only because of its role in becoming an economic engine for the future, but also because of the impacts that will be felt in our local economy and environment if action is not taken.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In order to address the problems associated with the Salton Sea, I have worked to include moneys within WRDA in prior congressional sessions. My goal is that moneys can be included to fund pilot projects in my district that would begin the proper steps to restore the sea.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To meet this need, yesterday I offered an amendment in the Rules Committee that would provide $26 million for the restoration projects. Unfortunately, today we do not have the chance to vote on this important funding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is important to note that my amendment would have directly mirrored language that was included in the final version of the WRDA legislation in the 109th Congress, <bill type="h" number="2864">H.R. 2864</bill>. At that time, displaying the bipartisan nature of this proposal, both the chairman and the ranking member, and now chairman, Mr. Oberstar, agreed that this language was important and worthy of inclusion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The support of the Senate remains consistent with their approval in conference of this project last year and its recent inclusion in their WRDA legislation reported from the Environment and Public Works Committee just a few weeks ago. I am grateful that we have the support from the other body on a Salton Sea provision.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The time is right to act, as the State of California is on the verge of determining a plan that will permanently save the Salton Sea. The status quo, Mr. Chairman, is simply not an option. Massive yearly fish die and the potential for the deterioration in local air quality due to blowing sediments are a very serious reality. These problems will likely only worsen in the future, depending on the actions the State of California and our Federal Government take.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I now yield to the gentleman from Florida in the hopes of entering into a colloquy.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400273" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I thank the gentlewoman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First of all, I know, Mrs. Bono, that you have worked tirelessly on behalf of restoration of the Salton Sea project. Only through a technicality in our agreement for moving forward with this legislation has your Bono Salton Sea restoration provision been left from this bill. But you have my assurance that you will have top priority for consideration for the conference on something you have worked year after year and so hard for. So before this gets to the President's desk, you have my  assurance that it will be part of the President's bill, if we have a bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400039" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, reclaiming my time, I thank the gentleman.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And I just want to reiterate that since my coming to Congress, I took over this issue actually from my late husband, Sonny Bono, and we did pass the Sonny Bono Memorial Act in 1998. I thank the gentleman very much for his understanding of how important this is and southern California's willingness to help me as we move forward in conference.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, will the gentlewoman yield?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400039" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>I yield to the gentleman from Minnesota.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I concur in the remarks of the distinguished ranking member, and we are committed to working together either in conference or subsequently in resolving this matter.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 1 1/2  minutes to the distinguished gentleman from Maine (Mr. Allen).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="ALLEN" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in strong support of <bill type="h" number="1495">H.R. 1495</bill>, the Water Resources Development Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In particular, I want to call attention to section 3065 and to thank Chairman Oberstar and the Chair of the subcommittee, Ms. Johnson, for their support of the city of Saco, Maine.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Section 3065 authorizes construction of modifications to an Army Corps of Engineers jetty at the mouth of the Saco River in the Camp Ellis neighborhood of Saco. The Corps built the jetty more than 130 years ago and subsequently has lengthened, smoothed, and raised it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, the jetty is destroying the Camp Ellis neighborhood by contributing to what the Maine State geologist has called the worst coastal erosion in the State. Thirty-eight homes have been lost to the sea. Currently, homes that were once six rows back from the shoreline are in danger of being destroyed. During winter nor'easter storms, one part of Camp Ellis often becomes an island.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These dangerous conditions are caused by a structure erected, improved, and maintained by the United States Government. For that reason I believe that the Federal Government must act to alleviate the problem. Section 3065 funds a spur jetty and a series of breakwaters that will diminish the force of wave action on the beach. For the past 7 years, I have been actively involved with Federal, State, and local officials, as well as with Camp Ellis residents, all dedicated to fixing the Camp Ellis  erosion problem.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Passage of WRDA could not be more timely. On Monday I was there in the middle of the storm surge, and during this week's nor'easter, Camp Ellis lost at least two homes to the sea. If the proposed modifications to the jetty had been made, these homes would not have been destroyed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge passage of this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400012" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, at this time I yield 2 minutes to my distinguished colleague from Louisiana (Mr. Jindal).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400634" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I want to thank Chairman Oberstar, Chairwoman Johnson, and Ranking Members Mica and Baker for their excellent work on <bill type="h" number="1495">H.R. 1495</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation is critical to the entire country, but for Louisiana in particular it provides much-needed authority and direction for the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers to design and construct a comprehensive hurricane, flood, and coastal protection program safeguarding hundreds of thousands of lives and tens of billions of dollars in industry and infrastructure vital to our Nation's economy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>WRDA specifically allocates approximately $1.2 billion for actions to restore Louisiana's coastal wetlands over the next decade, including a plan for the closure and environmental restoration of the MRGO, the Inner Harbor Navigational Canal Lock, other projects like the Ouachita River levees and the Red River basin and several other projects throughout the State.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Among the critical projects included in the WRDA bill is the Morganza to the Gulf Hurricane Protection project. This project is the best solution to protecting exposed areas in the bayou region of Louisiana.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am very pleased that the administration softened its stance on Morganza to the Gulf, which will provide essential hurricane protections to those in Terrebonne and Lafourche Parishes. When complete, this project will provide category 3 protection for 200,000 citizens and approximately $8 billion of public and private infrastructure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Though I certainly would have preferred an unqualified endorsement for Morganza to the Gulf from the administration, I look forward to working with my colleagues in the House to ensure that Morganza and other important projects remain intact in the final bill. I urge my colleagues to support <bill type="h" number="1495">H.R. 1495</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank again the chairman, and ranking member, Mr. Baker, in particular, for their work on this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield such time as he may consume to the distinguished gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Costello), former ranking member of the subcommittee, who devoted an enormous amount of his time, along with Mr. Duncan, in shaping this bill in the previous Congress and now leads us on aviation as the chairman of the Aviation Subcommittee.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400082" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I thank Chairman Oberstar for yielding time to me.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, today we are considering the Water Resources Development Act of 2007. This bill addresses what the Congress has failed to do in previous years, enact a WRDA bill that addresses the critical infrastructure needs of our country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to thank Chairman Oberstar, Chairwoman Johnson, Mr. Mica, Mr. Baker, and the former chairman of the subcommittee, Mr. Duncan, for a job well done in bringing this bill to the floor today. Without their leadership and their persistence, we would not have a bill here to consider on the floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1495">H.R. 1495</bill> authorizes projects for major flood control, navigation, environmental restoration, and other water projects and authorizes several important projects to restore and enhance the Nation's environmental infrastructure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The United States transportation system has an extensive system of highways, ports, locks and dams, and airports. Yet we continue to neglect upgrading and modernizing our infrastructure. We should not build our infrastructure and then walk away from it without maintaining and modernizing it as it becomes antiquated, like we have done with the Upper Mississippi and the Illinois Waterways lock and dam system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In <bill type="h" number="1495">H.R. 1495</bill> we are again authorizing the Upper Mississippi and Illinois Waterways system. This bill authorizes the replacement of 600-foot navigation locks with seven new 1,200-foot locks. In addition, the bill authorizes the largest environmental restoration program next to the Florida Everglades project to ensure that the project goes forward while respecting the environment and minimizing any adverse impact.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our current system loses about 10 percent of its capacity due to the system failure and breakdowns because it has exceeded its life expectancy by over 20 years. The system cannot handle today's traffic in an efficient, cost-effective manner, and it is costing taxpayers tens of millions of dollars to patch it together, let alone the cost in time and money to the users. Modernizing that infrastructure is the right thing to do. It is a necessity, and I am glad to see that this bill is moving forward  on such a significant project to our economy and our commerce.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, again I salute Chairman Oberstar, Chairwoman Johnson, Mr. Mica, Mr. Baker, and Mr. Duncan for their leadership and hard work. And I strongly support this legislation and urge my colleagues to support it.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400012" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, at this time I yield 1 minute to the gentlewoman from Ohio (Mrs. Schmidt).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Mrs. SCHMIDT asked and was given permission to revise and extend her remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412010" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise today in support of this legislation because it is long overdue. Seven years is a long time and much has changed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill includes language important to my own district, but more importantly, it has national importance. We need this legislation to authorize new Army Corps of Engineer water infrastructure studies and projects. And it is not just about new projects, but how the Corps manages them, and for Congress to have an opportunity to exercise its oversight authority over current and future projects. This legislation is long overdue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to commend our committee leadership on both sides for working in a bipartisan fashion to move this so quickly. I thank everyone for their hard work, and I look forward to voting for this this evening.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>I yield 2 minutes to the distinguished gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Hare).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412204" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise today in strong support of the Water Resources Development Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill authorizes important long-overdue flood control, dam safety and environmental restoration projects. In my district, the Great Flood of 1993 took the lives of 47 people and resulted in over $15 billion in catastrophic damages throughout much of the Mississippi River basin. I support this bill for the safety of my constituents.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Additionally, over 50 percent of our locks and dams have aged beyond their life cycle, and they are crumbling. WRDA authorizes repair of these structures and includes critical provisions to modernize seven new locks and dams on the upper Mississippi and Illinois Rivers. These improvement will expand navigation capacity, reduce shipping delays, and accommodate larger barge tows, which is critical for the $12 billion worth of products that the river transports ever year, as well as the agriculture,  commercial and labor interests of my State of Illinois.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill includes a much-needed program to restore the upper Mississippi River ecosystem and authorizes completion of the Emiquon Wildlife Preserve in my district. This preserve is one of the largest flood plain restoration projects in the country outside the Florida Everglades, and I am proud to have sponsored its inclusion in this bill today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support the Water Resources Development Act. By improving our water resources infrastructure, we will make our river communities safer and strengthen our Nation's economy and environmental welfare.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400012" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I claim the remainder of our time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to express my appreciation to Chairman Oberstar, Chairman Johnson and of course my ranking member, Mr. Mica, for their very diligent and hard work; more specifically, for the time spent in the great State of Louisiana after the landfall of Hurricane Katrina. The committee has come down, Members often more than once, to observe for themselves the damage that has been caused by this unbelievable natural catastrophe.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill under consideration today will begin an enormous and monumental project for the restoration of coastal Louisiana. It is not just about keeping people with the ability to live on the water's edge; it is giving the ability to stop the storm surge coming inland and bringing about the type of devastation that we have painfully experienced again.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation is a landmark, certainly for the traditional reasons. Many Members have interests in projects for economic development reasons, for control of public water systems, for enhancing water runoff and minimizing agricultural and other sources of contamination to our water systems. But this bill is really important for maintenance of life and quality of life in our State, and it will begin the meaningful restoration of what is a tremendous natural asset, coastal Louisiana.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would emphasize what has already been stated repeatedly: this is a process resulting in over 600 projects which has come about over a 6-year period. And so it is my deepest hope that this House will this evening favorably adopt 1495, that the Senate will work expeditiously with us in moving forward, and that the administration will find a way to sign this important jobs bill into law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>$13.1 billion is a lot of money, and when coupled with the local matched dollars which are required, it will be a significant shot in the economic arm for the construction industry across this country. So I am most appreciative of the opportunity to have participated in this process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am grateful to my Democratic colleagues for their kind and hard work on this subject and listening to the people of Louisiana in their hour of need. For that we are and will always be most appreciative.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, how much time do we have remaining on our side?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from Minnesota has 1 1/2  minutes remaining.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>There is an old saying among seafarers: "No helmsman is tested in fair water." The gentleman from Louisiana was tested in the aftermath of Katrina, and I saw him at the helm in Baton Rouge when our committee made a tour of the devastation wreaked by Hurricane Katrina. I was impressed then and continue to be by his composure, his grasp of facts, grasp of the magnitude of the problem, and his willingness to address the issues in a coordinated and bipartisan manner. I salute him  for his continued leadership and service not only to the State, but to the Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, I express my appreciation to the gentleman from Florida (Mr. Mica) for similarly taking the helm in a time of turbulence when we had this work of 6 years thrust upon us, trying to sort it out, do the right thing and serve our Members, their districts, and our Nation at the same time and measure each project against the yardstick of balance that has historically guided the Corps of Engineers and guided the work of this committee, and I think we have come here with a good product.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And I especially appreciate, once again, the splendid work of the gentlewoman from Texas, Ms. Johnson, who is the Chair of the subcommittee and who has put her heart and soul into seeing this bill move forward.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400347" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise to support <bill type="h" number="1495">H.R. 1495</bill>, the Water Resources Development Act of 2007. This bill, which authorizes water projects through the Army Corps of Engineers, is essential to maintaining and improving our Nation's vital water resources and infrastructure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill is long overdue. Congress has been unable to enact a comprehensive WRDA bill since the year 2000. Without Federal resources authorized in this bill, critical projects needed to sustain and protect America's water needs into the future have been stalled. I commend Chairman Oberstar for his leadership and steadfast commitment to this vital issue. I thank his hardworking staff, who worked long hours to complete this bill, which is a top priority of our new Democratic Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a representative from southern California where water is a scare and precious resource, I appreciate the distinguished Chairman's efforts to put forth a bill that advances essential water resource infrastructure projects in the region.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am particularly pleased that this legislation includes an historic authorization for revitalization efforts along the Los Angeles River. The $20 million authorization contained within the bill will mark a significant Federal commitment to transforming the LA River from an unsightly concrete flood control channel into green space that will promote badly needed recreation, housing and job creation opportunities. In addition, the legislation will enable the Army Corps of Engineers to develop a  plan to improve water quality, restore historic habitats, and enhance the river's flood protection function.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For years, I have worked with my colleagues from Los Angeles to obtain Federal funding for studies on promising revitalization projects along the River. Our efforts have secured over $3 million for studies at various sites, including the Cornfields site in downtown Los Angeles. With the inclusion of the LA River projects in the WRDA authorization, the Army Corps of Engineers can begin to break ground on these revitalization activities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to take this opportunity to recognize my local community and public officials who have worked tirelessly to make the Los Angeles River revitalization project a success. The LA River revitalization plan reflects the vision of City Councilman Ed Reyes, who for many years has led the effort at the local level. I commend him for his commitment to enhancing the quality of life for the communities along the River and for all Angelenos.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also applaud the strong support of Mayor Antonio Villaraigosa and the local stakeholders who continue to explore ways to convert the land adjacent to the Los Angeles River into parks, housing, and economic opportunities for our local communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The passage of WRDA with the LA River revitalization project will continue an exciting alliance between the federal government, the City of Los Angeles and Los Angeles County. We have worked in particular to enrich the lives of the many families who live in the communities along the River and to enhance opportunities for economic development associated with revitalization.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I look forward to continuing to work with my colleagues to build upon this exciting opportunity to transform the LA River from an unsightly and environmentally void industrial space to a communal recreational space in which all Angelenos can take pride.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank the Committee for its hard work and urge my colleagues to support this important legislationy.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400238" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in strong support of the Water Resources Development Act and urge its passage by the House. I want to compliment Chairman Oberstar and the Transportation and Infrastructure Committee for making early passage of this legislation a priority. The last Water Resources bill was signed into law over 6 years ago by President Clinton. It is Congress' job to renew this law every 2 years, but for whatever reason, we have been unable to reach agreement with the other  body and get a final bill to the President for his signature.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Nation's water and environmental infrastructure problems won't wait forever. We need to overcome our past differences and move this bill to upgrade and modernize our Federal programs relating to navigation, flood damage reduction, shoreline protection, dam safety, water supply, recreation, and environmental restoration.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to express my thanks to Chairman Oberstar for including a project I requested to authorize Federal funding to implement restoration projects in Lake St. Clair. In the past, Lake St. Clair has been described as "the forgotten lake." No longer. Today, many of my constituents refer to Lake St. Clair as the "Heart of the Great Lakes." We need to protect and restore it. Lake St. Clair is not the largest body of water in the Great Lakes System, but it is absolutely one of the most  heavily used portions of the Lakes in terms of fishing, boating and drinking water.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Two years ago, the Corps of Engineers completed a comprehensive management plan for Lake St. Clair and the St. Clair River. Congress paid for this plan. The recommendations contained in the management plan will help shape Lake St. Clair's future, but only if they are implemented. Having come this far, we can't let the report and its recommendations become another study that sits on a shelf and gathers dust. Everyone, including the federal government, has to step forward and take responsibility  for turning these recommendations into action.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, I support the bill before the House and urge its adoption.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400218" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in strong support of this bill that will finally move forward important construction, navigation, and ecosystem restoration projects along the Mississippi River, Great Lakes, and elsewhere. In particular, <bill type="h" number="1495">H.R. 1495</bill> will authorize the corps of engineers' sustainability plan for the upper Mississippi River.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On the eve of Earth Day, founded by the great Senator from Wisconsin Gaylord Nelson, what better gift to the people of the upper Mississippi River basin than the largest ever investment in ecosystem restoration in the river's history? This bill will have a tremendous impact on water quality, wildlife habitat, and recreation in the upper Mississippi River region.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Reauthorization of the Water Resources Development Act has been a long time coming, and it has seen some improvement over the years. The current bill, for instance, includes an important provision, that I included, requiring that construction and restoration projects on the upper Mississippi achieve equal progress so that construction and navigation improvements do not degrade the river ecosystem. The WRDA bill of 1986 established the upper Mississippi River system as the only waterbody in the  Nation recognized by Congress as both a "nationally significant ecosystem and a nationally significant commercial navigation system," so it is important that the needs of these two aspects of the river are met in tandem.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Bush administration also has recognized the ecological importance of the basin by making the upper Mississippi River Basin environmental management program a priority project in the corps budget. A relatively modest program with authorized funding of $33.5 million, the EMP has demonstrated remarkable results in restoring river habitats all along my congressional district in western Wisconsin and beyond. And its long-term resource monitoring program has produced invaluable data and knowledge.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, it is especially fitting that we pass this bill today in light of the 20th anniversary that EMP celebrated last year. This bill, <bill type="h" number="1495">H.R. 1495</bill>, and the accompanying manager's amendment contain language assuring that the navigation and ecosystem sustainability plan will continue the EMP's mission, including long-term resource monitoring.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But this bill will address long-standing needs well beyond the upper Mississippi. This country's water resources infrastructure was largely constructed 70 or more years ago, and much of it has fallen into various states of disrepair and neglect. Hurricane Katrina so clearly demonstrated to the world the consequences of this lack of attention. Reauthorization of WRDA is a necessary first step in meeting the needs of our citizens, industry, and environment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge all of my colleagues to join me in support of this vital legislation so that residents of low-lying areas can be reassured that  the levees that protect them will be made adequate, so that farmers will know they will be able to ship their grain downriver to be exported to foreign markets, and hunters, anglers, and birdwatchers will know that the habitat they know and love will be maintained.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400031" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I would like to thank Chairman Oberstar and Ranking Member Mica, as well as Subcommittee Chairwoman Johnson and Ranking Member Baker for their hard work and leadership on this important legislation--the first water improvement and conservation package in seven years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Following several earlier impasses, I want to take this opportunity to commend the spirit of bipartisanship and compromise on this important measure. I hope it extends to a bicameral bipartisanship in the weeks to come.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill benefits all Americans and their families who use and enjoy our Nation's waterways, public beaches--including over 300 miles of coastline along my district--and for U.S. businesses that depend on healthy and viable waterways throughout the country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My district benefits from the good work that the Army Corps of Engineers does for coastal communities by helping small towns deal with multiple concerns ranging from erosion to longstanding environmental challenges. The Corps is currently working on several projects on eastern Long Island that will dredge inlets, restore damaged ecosystems, and study coastal health.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, <bill type="h" number="1495">H.R. 1495</bill> will go a long way toward supplying the Corps with all the resources it needs to protect coastal communities and vacationers by modernizing project planning and approval.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I thank the Chairman and Ranking Member again for their hard work on this issue, and I look forward to working with my colleagues to make sure that we get a WRDA bill to the President as soon as we can. We simply cannot afford to let another year go by without passing this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400120" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise today in strong support of <bill type="h" number="1945">H.R. 1945</bill>, the Water Resources Development Act (WRDA). As the Democratic Majority begins our second 100 days, we are continuing to move America forward, and WRDA does just that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill will help commerce by improving navigation on waterways and making it easier to bring products to market. This bill will invest in our future by modernizing the locks and dams on the Mississippi River and elsewhere. This bill will protect the Great Lakes by finally making the Asian Carp barrier permanent. This bill invests in rural and urban America alike by renewing our commitment to protecting the environment and the economy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Water Resources Development Act is a good bill that has been written in a bipartisan process to address the needs of the whole country, but there are two parts of the bill in particular that I am especially proud are included.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The locks on the Mississippi River and Illinois Waterways are in need of repair, and WRDA finally addresses the long overdue need for lock modernization. Navigation in the upper Mississippi supports more than 400,000 jobs and 90,000 high-paying manufacturing jobs, and passage of WRDA will create more jobs in the region. Every year, shipping in the upper Mississippi River adds up to about $1.2 billion to our economy. Modernizing the locks will go a long way to ensuring the livelihoods of the men  and women that rely on these waterways.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Another project in WRDA that is critical to the Great Lakes and important to all of Chicago is the Asian Carp barrier. As the residents of the Fifth Congressional District know, invasive species pose a severe threat to Lake Michigan, capable of billions of dollars in economic losses and inestimable environmental damage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Asian Carp in particular has affected Great Lakes fisheries, and I have been working with my Great Lakes colleagues in making sure that this barrier is funded and operational to protect the Great Lakes from Asian Carp.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, the Water Resources Development Act is a hat trick--it's good for the environment, it's good for the economy, and it's good for America's future. I want to thank Mr. Oberstar and Mr. Mica for all of their good work, and I am glad that we are getting this bill done. I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> All time for general debate has expired.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I offer an amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will designate the amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is the so-called traditional manager's amendment that we have worked on for weeks in a bipartisan manner across the aisle within the committee to work out technical changes and modifications to the bill that came to the attention of the committee after consideration of the bill in March. A project of this magnitude always has some issues that we need to resolve, and we have done that quite well in this manager's amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Among some of the highlights are a provision that is of great importance to the 35 million people who live along the Great Lakes. There is a provision to direct the Secretary of the Army, along with directors of other agencies and entities, to carry out an emergency project to control and prevent spreading a viral hemorrhagic septicemia (VHS) virus in the Great Lakes and the connecting channels. I alluded to this issue at the outset of my remarks at the beginning of the legislation. It is an  infectious viral disease of  fish and has caused fish kills throughout the lakes. It has been a problem in Europe, it is a problem in Japan, and now we have confirmed presence in Lake Ontario, Lake St. Clair, Erie, St. Lawrence River. It was discovered in Lake Huron. It is migrating up the lakes, killing fish in its wake caused by ballast water that is infected on vessels plying the Great Lakes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It spreads rapidly. We don't really know how it spreads, but we need to attack this issue now. There is a multibillion dollar fishery industry throughout the Great Lakes, sport fish and commercial fishery, and this provision will help us deal with and hopefully find a way to contain this devastating virus.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We also have authorizations for new projects in water and wastewater-related infrastructure. For years, these were traditionally practices of the Environmental Protection Agency, but they have run out of money, frankly. Even though we have passed the State Revolving Loan fund bill in this committee to deal with the matter, there still are huge needs. No one better than the Corps of Engineers is equipped to deal with the needs of environmental infrastructure. So in cooperation with the Department  of Agriculture's Rural Utilities Service program, the State Revolving Loan fund of the EPA, Corps of Engineers will help communities rebuild their infrastructure and provide for public health and economic vitality of our towns all across America. The needs of communities have not gone away; the ability to deal with them has simply diminished.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Corps can do this work; they have proven they can. And we have a very vigorous and I think constructive environmental infrastructure program in the manager's amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I would yield such time as she may wish to the gentlewoman from Texas.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400204" topic="">
    <paragraph>Thank you very much, Mr. Chairman.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I support the manager's amendment on this water resources bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The manager's amendment reflects project and policy revisions that have come to the attention of the subcommittee that I chair, and the subcommittee of Water Resources Environment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since the bill was passed out of committee, the Transportation and Infrastructure, in March, the amendment contains authorizations that are by no means inequitable to those that were contained in the bill that passed out of committee. Likewise, the projects in the manager's amendment were not considered on a partisan basis but on a need basis and merit. And this has been a long tradition in our committee, and I hope we will always have that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I support the amendment. And I want to express my appreciation to the persons who did do all of the certifications and all the new paperwork we have to do. And I want to thank the ranking member on the subcommittee as well as the full committee and our general chairman. Thank you so very much.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400012" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise to claim the time in opposition, although I am not in opposition and therefore ask unanimous consent to claim such time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the gentleman from Louisiana is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400012" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I just want to speak for a moment as to process and my appreciation for the manner in which the chairman handled this particular legislation. At the time of some of the subcommittee consideration, there were some Members who had not completed the necessary documents for submission of their projects in the required form, and the chairman made clear that should a Member provide the necessary information in a timely manner, that their projects would be included for consideration.  And the manager's amendment reflects the closure of that verbal agreement in allowing many Members to complete the necessary documentation, therefore enabling the committee to include their projects of interest in the final mark before the House this evening. That is a model of how appropriate legislative consideration should be engaged, and I want to express appreciation to him.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I can verify for him if there is ever any question that there are a large number of Members who have a very deep and abiding interest in this subject matter, I have a list. And they also are appreciative of the willingness to give opportunity for appropriate consideration.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The manager's amendment is extraordinarily important in that it touches about a hundred projects which otherwise would not be included. I certainly hope that those present will support the adoption of the amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, at this time, I would yield such time as the gentleman may consume to my ranking member, Mr. Mica.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400273" topic="">
    <paragraph>Might I inquire of the Chair as to how much time is remaining.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from Louisiana has 3 1/2  minutes remaining.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400273" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First of all, I rise in strong support of the manager's amendment. Mr. Oberstar, after the election, became the Chair, I became the ranking member of the Transportation Committee. And we inherited, indeed, a huge backlog of projects. We also inherited a bill that required earmarking because they are Members' projects, and everyone knows the problems that we have had with earmarks in the past. So I can assure the Members that on both sides of the aisle we have done everything possible  to vet these projects. I am also sorry that we can't put even more projects in.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We just had Mrs. BONO here, and her heart and soul in her work in Congress, which is something she inherited, actually the work, too, of her late husband, Sonny Bono, a good friend and colleague.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>She wanted that so badly in this, and it is so important, the restoration of the Salton Sea, for her district. You can see how important these projects are to Members and their districts. So we have a good work product.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me make one point I did not make in opposition to the administration's position on this piece of legislation in that it cost too much. If you look at 2000 when we started these projects, maybe they did cost $5 million. I can tell you that just with inflation and the cost of doing construction projects, having been in the development business, that every day we delay will cost us more; and that is why these projects cost us more, and that is why I am in opposition to the administration's point  there.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have evenly divided the projects. I don't think we could have had a fairer distribution. They are Republican, they are not Democrat, but they are of national and district importance, and I think we have done as good a job as you can. I am sure you can find something wrong or questionable, if anyone seeks to do that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I urge adoption of the manager's amendment, and I urge all Members on both sides of the aisle to move and urge the passage of this bill, not only through the House but through the other body and conference, so that we can do a better job for the people that we represent in these important environmental and water resources projects.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400012" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for his remarks, and I certainly would be remiss if I did not comment on his effort to provide for transparency and disclosure of Members' requests. It was a new process. We had a lot of new paperwork to engage in. But at the end of the day, I think the public interest is well served and every Member is well served by having such disclosure made in a timely manner; and for his leadership in providing that counsel, I am most appreciative.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, we have labored mightily to comply with the new rules of the House, to cut every one of the projects back with each of the Members, each of 300 Members who had a project in the last Congress that carried over to this Congress. We have worked very diligently to serve as a filter for Members, to filter out problems that they had, projects that really might not comply,  that should not be considered at this stage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We bring forward to you a bill that has been on the Internet, that is fully vetted, and should pass with overwhelming support.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> All time for debate on the amendment has expired.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400042" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I offer an amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will designate the amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400042" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Before I explain the amendment, I would like to thank Ms. Johnson and Mr. Oberstar for their hard work. We have finally got something out here to work with. I thank the gentleman from Louisiana and the gentleman from Florida for working together with us. It is something that our country needed very, very badly, and was overdue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in support of this amendment that is highly important to the State of Iowa constituents and also a number of folks in northern Missouri. As a member of the Transportation and Infrastructure Committee, I would like to especially give my appreciation for this opportunity that is before us today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My amendment is critical to the future availability of quality drinking water for farmers, residents and businesses in southern Iowa and northern Missouri. Rathbun Regional Water Association is the largest rural water system in Iowa and one of the largest in the United States. Rathbun Regional Water Association supplies potable water to 60,000 people in the rural areas of 15 counties and 41 communities in southern Iowa and northern Missouri from the association's water treatment plant at Rathbun  Lake. Rathbun Lake is the source of raw water for the treatment plant.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rathbun Rural Water Association has experienced steady growth in the demand for potable water. In response to this demand, Rathbun Rural Water Association doubled the capacity of its treatment plant in 2000 and made improvements to its distribution system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rathbun Rural Water Association has completed an analysis of future water demand in its service territory. This analysis indicates that Rathbun Regional Water Association must take steps to meet continued growth in demand for potable water. The ability to secure the rights of the remaining drinking water pool in Lake Rathbun, a facility managed by the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers, is critical to meet demand.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are 15,000 acre-feet of water supply storage in Rathbun Lake. Rathbun Regional Water Association has purchased the rights to 6,680 acre-feet of this water and storage from the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers. It is essential that they be able to acquire the rights of the remaining over 8,000 acre-feet of water supply storage in Rathbun Lake in order to satisfy the growing demand for potable water in its service territory. This remaining acre-feet in water would provide access to approximately  2.7 billion gallons of water.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The amendment submitted today takes two critical steps to ensure the availability of water for the region. First, it directs the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers to grant Rathbun Rural Water the right of first refusal to contract for any increment of the remaining water supply storage allocation in Rathbun Lake. This language is in accordance with the recommendations in the Rathbun Lake Reallocation Report approved by the chief of engineers on July 22, 1985.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second, it allows Rathbun Regional Water Association to contract for the remaining water supply storage allocation in total, or incrementally as dictated by the demand of the potable water demand in the association's service territory, at such time as the full amount of storage may be purchased.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment ensures access to quality water supply for rural residents, small communities and businesses in southern Iowa and northern Missouri. It enables Rathbun Rural Water to better manage the expense of purchasing water storage allocation in a manner that reduces the financial burden on its customers and ensures the vitality of Rathbun Regional Water Association to fulfill its commitment to an extensive rural area.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I join with my colleague from Iowa, Congressman Loebsack, in this request, and I urge my colleagues to support this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I ask unanimous consent, though I am not in opposition to the amendment, to claim the time in opposition to the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Minnesota?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I support the amendment offered by the gentleman from Iowa. We have had a bipartisan agreement on this.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield to the distinguished gentleman from Louisiana.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400012" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I just wish to compliment the gentleman on his amendment. We have reviewed it. We have no objection to its consideration and adoption.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="">
    <paragraph>The gentleman from Iowa (Mr. Boswell) and our former colleague from Iowa, Mr. Leach, have long worked with the committee on this issue of Rathbun Lake. It is as much a tribute to the gentleman from Iowa (Mr. Boswell) as to our former colleague, Mr. Leach. The gentleman has described the issue very well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In initial consideration of this legislation, there was a PAYGO issue, and the gentleman from Iowa has worked with us on both sides of the aisle to resolve the matter. We no longer have an impact on direct Federal spending in the amendment. Therefore, it passes our committee standards.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I strongly support the amendment and appreciate the support of the gentleman from Louisiana.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400042" topic="">
    <paragraph>Thank you, Mr. Oberstar, and the gentleman from Louisiana, I appreciate your help and your work with us on this. I would join again with Congressman Loebsack and urge passage of this amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400204" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I support the amendment offered by my colleague, Mr. Boswell.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congressman Boswell has been working with the Committee to resolve scoring issues related to modifications for the Rathbun Lake, Iowa project that had surfaced since the project was last included in the Water Resources Development Act of 2005.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is my understanding that these issues have now been settled.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge the adoption of this amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400042" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> All time for debate on the amendment has expired.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400391" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I offer an amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will designate the amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400391" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, in fiscal year 2006, the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers and the Office of Management and Budget set new guidelines for maintenance dredging of commercial harbors in their budget for fiscal year 2006. The Corps excluded harbors that move less than 1 million tons of cargo each year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The House is on record that the Corps' neglect of these harbors is unwise and unreasonable. With Members' help during consideration of WRDA, the Stupak-Hoekstra-Delahunt amendment to prohibit the Corps from using a tonnage-based standard was included in the House bill by voice vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now the Corps is back with a similar tonnage-based formula. This formula essentially credits $2 for maintenance dredging for every ton of product moved. The harbor is then provided only the amount from the formula, regardless of the actual cost to dredge a harbor. This policy not only discriminates against rural America by significantly limiting dredging of harbors in smaller communities, but it is pound wise and penny foolish.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For example, under the Corps proposal, my harbor in Ontonogan, Michigan, will move just over 300,000 tons of material, so the Corps will provide $643,000 worth of maintenance dredging, even though its dredging cost is more than $1 million.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, there are almost 300 harbors across this country that face the same problem. Our small harbors will never be able to adequately dredge, but will silt in with each passing year. Thus, pound wise, penny foolish.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These Corps guidelines will have a detrimental effect on small-town, rural America, causing job losses, increased hardship for business, and endanger our Nation's entire shipping infrastructure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Each harbor that has been maintained by the Corps for years has unique characteristics other than just the amount of tonnage it moves. For example, annual dredging helps prevent flooding in Ontonogan, and dredging plays an essential role in preserving the economy and lifeline of this harbor town. By only considering the amount of tonnage a harbor handles, the administration ignores the benefits provided to businesses and residents that depend on electricity, flood mitigation and other purposes  beyond the tonnage handled.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With this new policy, the Corps also disregards the fact that approximately two-thirds of all shipping in the United States either starts or finishes at a small port. By ignoring the smaller communities, the Corps is also significantly harming the Nation's economy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With the Corps' proposed maintenance dredging guidelines, in each year our small harbors' maintenance remains uncertain. Without this Stupak-Hoekstra-Delahunt amendment, the economic vitality and the dream of economic expansion for these 300 communities remain uncertain.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As the House considers this WRDA legislation, I am again offering this amendment with Congressmen Hoekstra and Delahunt, which keeps the maintenance dredging the same as it has been before the Corps and OMB came up with these tonnage proposals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For the sake of our Nation's small harbors, from which two-thirds of all shipping in the United States either starts or finishes at small ports, I encourage my colleagues to adopt our amendment, which would ensure that all harbor maintenance is funded fairly, regardless of the amount of tonnage a harbor handles.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I ask unanimous consent to claim the time in opposition to the amendment, although I do not oppose the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Minnesota?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400012" topic="">
    <paragraph>Reserving the right to object, if I may make an inquiry of the gentleman, we have a cosponsor on our side of the amendment. Will the gentleman be happy to yield?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I will yield time to the gentleman, of course.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400012" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I withdraw my reservation of objection.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the gentleman from Minnesota is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="">
    <paragraph>In the preceding Congress, this amendment was offered on the floor during consideration of the WRDA bill, and it passed by voice vote; WRDA passed by 406 votes. It requires adequate budgeting by the administration for maintenance of small, low-use harbors. These are relatively smaller harbors; they may not handle thousands of containers or millions of tons of bulk commodities shipped on the Great Lakes, as we do in the Harbor of Duluth, but they are important projects and facilities  that place lives and livelihoods at risk on the fierce storms of the Great Lakes, because these are also harbors of refuge. So I strongly support it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I am happy to yield to the gentleman from Michigan (Mr. Hoekstra).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400182" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank my colleague for yielding and I am thankful for his support and help on this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would also like to thank my colleague from Michigan for bringing this amendment together. I think we both recognize the importance of this amendment. My congressional district, I think we kind of represent God's country. I represent about 200 miles of Lake Michigan shoreline. I don't think I want to get into an argument with my colleague from Michigan as to how much shoreline he represents from the Great Lakes, but it is well in excess of that number.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But we both have recognized that the current Corps guidelines present a distinct hardship to our communities, many of the communities along the Great Lakes. We don't meet the newest guidelines that establish the roughly 1 million tons or whatever of cargo that need to flow through a harbor. And this is a change in the Corps' position. For the last 14 years that my colleague and I have been in Congress, the Corps has done a very, very good job and recognized its responsibility for taking care  of these small and medium-sized harbors which they classify as recreational harbors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But they are much more than recreational harbors. For many of our communities they do, we do transfer cargo through these ports, but the harbors form the economic development zone for these communities. And if the harbors and the channels are not dredged, this economic lifeline goes away. And when the economic lifeline goes away, eventually these communities go away.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a policy that Congress needs to address because, from a disappointing standpoint, the administration has made an administrative decision that these harbors will not be taken care of. Congress needs to speak on this issue. I am glad that we can move this forward in a bipartisan basis and send a piece of legislation to the administration that no longer provides them with the latitude as to whether these harbors will be dredged or not. These harbors need to be dredged. They will be dredged.  This is exactly the appropriate message to send.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank my colleagues on the other side of the aisle for taking the initiative in bringing this legislation forward.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman from Michigan for his statement. I just wanted to point out that the Great Lakes have gone through 15 years, in the 1960s, into the 1970s, into the 1980s, nearly a 20-year period of abnormally high level. Now we are going  through a seventh year of low water drought in the watershed of the Great Lakes. The Corps of Engineers has avoided dredging costs all during those two decades of high water on the Great Lakes. It  is time now to recoup, to do the dredging that is needed, especially for these small harbors, harbors of refuge, small commercial harbors. And the gentleman's amendment will ensure that this issue stays on the agenda of this and future administrations. So I urge support of the amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400391" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, in closing, I would like to thank Chairman Oberstar. He has been a great help throughout my whole career here, but especially on issues confronting the Great Lakes and WRDA and other areas of his expertise in transportation infrastructure. And Mr. Baker has also been a friend and very helpful, as has Ms. Johnson.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is a bipartisan piece of legislation. I would hope that the Members support it. If we are going to truly care about waterborne commerce and transportation in this Nation, we must remember that two-thirds of all commerce on our Nation's waterways start and begin at the small ports the Army Corps no longer wishes to dredge and maintain. We need support on this amendment, and I ask for your support.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400102" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, for my district--coastal Massachusetts--our waterways are as important as our roadways. They are also a vital part of the Nation's transportation infrastructure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is the responsibility of the Army Corps of Engineers to help keep our harbors, rivers and other channels in navigable condition. In New England, the Corps is responsible for maintaining 171 ports and harbor channels, yet the Bush Administration budget includes funding to take care of just one. That is because the rules for Army Corps projects were changed by the Bush Administration to now favor large, commercial waterways. This constitutes an abandonment of Federal responsibility and quite  simply, is an assault on smaller communities all over the country, putting lives and the economic health of coastal communities at risk.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The rationale for these changes is that financial constraints require us to abruptly change Army Corps' priorities to favor projects with "true value to the Nation." This sounds good--but is dangerously misleading. The changed formula focuses only on commercial tonnage and mileage, so smaller projects do not have a chance--even though they are critical to the economy and public safety.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When waterways close due to sediment build-up, the commercial fishing industry suffers. Tourism is compromised. And our transport stops--sometimes dead in the water. The Coast Guard can't undertake "search and rescue" because they can't move--literally.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Just as a deteriorating highway or bridge needs repair, our waterways need maintenance. If the traffic through a harbor requires an eight-foot draft and sediment builds up, leaving only five feet available, vessels cannot pass. It is larger, commercial vessels like tankers, fishing boats and barges that face the greatest difficulty and are most likely to run aground.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Entire portions of our local economy are organized around the sea and the easy transport of people and products in and out of our harbors. When you consider our island communities--such as Martha's Vineyard, Nantucket, and Cuttyhunk--the waterways carry all the necessities for local citizens, everything from food and water to lumber and heating oil.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In Chatham Harbor, which hosts the largest fleet of commercial fishing vessels in my district, we face a constant problem with shoaling. It is a 900-foot channel and when it is not clear, millions of dollars are at risk. Each year it is now a fight to keep the fishing industry on Cape Cod in business.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It's the same thing with Green Harbor in Marshfield, where we have the second highest lobster catch harbor in New England. In Woods Hole, we have a major Coast Guard station which launches many cutter search-and-rescue missions a year. Without regular dredging, that emergency equipment is land-bound. In that same harbor, the Federal government has invested millions in a state-of-the-art NOAA research vessel, the Bigelow. But, these WHOI vessels and Navy vessels cannot do essential research because  the harbor is clogged with sentiment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For coastal communities, our waterways are critical to their economic well-being. I urge my colleagues to support this Amendment and support our mariners, our fishermen, the Coast Guard, and small coastal communities throughout the country.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the amendment offered by the gentleman from Michigan (Mr. Stupak).</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400033" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I offer an amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will designate the amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400033" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield myself 2 minutes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, this amendment simply requires the Secretary of the Army to update the principles and guidelines used by the Army Corps of Engineers in formulating, evaluating, and implementing water resource projects. As I said on the floor earlier today, they have not been updated since 1983. It is embarrassing that the Corps is operating under guidance a quarter century old.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have learned a lot in the last 25 months, as I look to my colleague from Louisiana, about Katrina and others in  terms of the Corps. Imagine how things have changed in the last 25 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under this amendment, the Army Secretary would incorporate the latest scientific and economic knowledge, eliminate biases and disincentives, would be required to consult with the public and other Federal agencies while updating the principles and guidelines.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to be clear about what it would not do. It would not impact any project already underway or impact any project that is in the bill that has been created here today. It would not prevent the Corps from doing structural projects and would not delay any projects at all. It is why it is supported by the American Society of Civil Engineers, the professionals who actually do the work, taxpayer organizations, and environmental groups.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The National Academy of Sciences in a report from the year 2000 pointed out that the current principles and guidelines were state-of-the-art thinking when it was written, and some of the concepts and paradigms that underpin it are relevant today. However, in over 20 years since it has been updated and revised, it needs to be revised to reflect contemporary management paradigms; analytical methods; legislative directives; social, economic, and political realities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I deeply appreciate the work with the committee's staff, the Chair and subcommittee Chair in getting this to this point.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400012" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in opposition to the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from Louisiana is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400012" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I am certainly appreciative of the gentleman's interest and have worked with him closely on a number of matters through the course of the years. And just in this instance we have a matter of policy difference.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The P&amp;G planning process utilized by the Corps does not begin with an idea that something must be done. It is not a process through which a commercial activity will automatically or inordinately be concluded must be implemented. The plan that is proposed must seek certain levels of justification; that is an iterative process where various parties are heard from over time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As to the element of whether the P&amp;G has been modified or not, I have done some work on the matter over the last days, knowing of the gentleman's interest in this amendment. And I can go back further over time, but on September 30 of 1999, the Corps issued Engineering Regulation 1165-2-501, which speaks directly to the gentleman's interest to encourage to the maximum extent practicable the restoration of aquatic ecosystems.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>From the gentleman's amendment, the 1999 issuance speaks directly to a nonmonetary output compatible with P&amp;G selection criteria; meaning, we should look at things broader than just dollars and cents.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On April 22, 2000, regulation 1105-2-200 recognized the national ecosystem restoration plan on a par with national economic development.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>March 26, 2002, chief of engineers issues the environmental operating principles affirming sustainable development.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>May 1, 2003: to provide for procedural guidance for formulating and evaluating projects consistent with environmental sustainability.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There was another on May 5, 2005. But to ensure the gentleman has time for his question, I will wrap up by saying, I have been assured by the Corps that they are working as diligently as one can work to accommodate environmental sensitivities while at the same time assuring that projects move forward in a timely manner.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The reason for my concern, as the gentleman knows, I am highly sensitized to our recovery from the Katrina-Rita days, and I know the gentleman's amendment is worded in such a fashion that, if it is authorized prior to the adoption of this language, it has no effect. But going forward, we are going to be doing this stuff for a very long time in our State.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The unintended consequences of these additional standards are going to be costly to local sponsors, and they are going to require significant additional programmatic time to achieve, not to ignore the gentleman's concerns that ecosystem restoration is a valuable and salutary goal that we should pursue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am happy to yield to the gentleman.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400033" topic="">
    <paragraph>I want to be clear that what you just stated that our goals, the things that you just cited, have never been incorporated into the principles and guidelines, have they?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400012" topic="">
    <paragraph>Yes. We may have a dispute as to the meaning of the words that we have on the page, but I will be happy to provide the gentleman.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>May 5, 2005: planning in a collaborative environment to build on modernized guidance, improve Corps projects through greater collaboration with all stakeholders. I am skipping a little bit here. Broaden project selection criteria to encompass net beneficial effects in all four P&amp;G accounts; national economic development, regional development, economic development, environmental quality, and other social effects.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So it goes beyond even environmental aspects in their planning process.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400033" topic="">
    <paragraph>And my question was, Is it not true that the Corps has not adopted those things into the principles and guidelines?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400012" topic="">
    <paragraph>All I can speak to from my knowledge is Corps-issued Engineering Circular 1105-2-409 on May 5, 2005.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400033" topic="">
    <paragraph>Engineering Circular that has not been incorporated into their principles and guidelines.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400012" topic="">
    <paragraph>The distinction between a statutory adoption and a circular being issued is managerial direction to people who are implementing the programmatic requirements. It may be a difference of no distinction to the gentleman; but my opinion is, after spending some time with the Corps individuals, they feel they are on top of and are trying as best they can within financial constraints to achieve the goals the gentleman is prescribing. My worry is this will now transfer a financial liability  to the local sponsor which does not now exist and may well, because of the times outlined in the gentleman's amendment, protract the timely construction of worthwhile projects.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I, for example, am not sure whether this applies to aids to navigation. I don't know. I am not suggesting it does, but the way the amendment is constructed, I am worried about scope and reach. And please understand, I want to be helpful to the gentleman's interest. I am not at all averse to constructing projects in an environmentally safe and sound manner. I am just not sure that the goals the gentleman seeks are the results we would get out of the adoption of the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400033" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 1 minute to the gentleman from Wisconsin (Mr. Petri).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400318" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank my colleague for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in support of the Blumenauer amendment, the bill before us, which would require the Army Corps of Engineers to revise the principles and guidelines under which the Secretary formulates and evaluates water resource projects.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It has been almost 25 years since any type of revision has been made to the Corps' decision-making process for formulating, evaluating, and implementing a project. The National Academy of Sciences has twice recommended that these guidelines be updated.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We want to be sure that we have a fair and impartial analysis of projects and that we don't set in place a procedure that inevitably leads to the largest projects getting built, not the most cost-effective ones.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The amendment is supported by many organizations, including the American Rivers, Taxpayers for Common Sense, and Republicans for Environmental Protection.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Up-to-date scientific engineering and environmental tools should be taken into account when looking at projects. As Representative Blumenauer has said, it is time to bring the Corps into the 20th and 21st centuries.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400033" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 1 minute to the gentleman from Vermont (Mr. Welch).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412239" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, as you know, this legislation will authorize projects that are vitally important to our communities, to our citizens, to our environment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment is intended to begin the process of reforming the Army Corps of Engineers process so it can be done better. I support and applaud the leadership of the Committee on Transportation and the cosponsors of this amendment. We must establish transparency, collaboration and accountability within the Corps of Engineers so as to better serve our communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What this amendment does is begin that process by citing improvements that can be made in the principles and the guidelines. This is essential because some of the things that have happened that have been adverse to our communities and to our citizens have been foreseeable and predictable. The reforms that we are beginning to take with this amendment are to foresee, predict and avoid.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Secondly, independent peer review. I want to recognize the work of the committee of including that in this legislation. It is my hope that going forward in the conference committee that will actually be strengthened.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400012" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I ask unanimous consent that each side be given an additional 2 minutes for a total of 4 minutes for debate on this amendment only.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Louisiana?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400012" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield such time as he may consume to the gentleman from Tennessee (Mr. Duncan).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400116" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman from Louisiana for yielding me this time, and I thank the majority side for agreeing to this unanimous consent request.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I simply wanted to rise to say this. During my 6 years as chairman of the Water Resources and Environment Subcommittee, I do not believe we had a better member or more active member than the gentleman from Oregon, and I certainly have the greatest admiration and respect for him and his concern about this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I simply wanted to rise to say this. I don't believe this Congress could pass a stronger environmental bill than this legislation that is before us at this time; Chairman Oberstar has continually made sure of that. And when we started with this bill several years ago, some people wanted no Corps reform at all; some people wanted so much Corps reform that really they were trying to stop every project that was included in this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Costello, who was my ranking member at that time, we compromised, we worked out things.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to commend the staff for their work in this regard, and we put in many environmental concerns the first time around. Then we put in even more the second time around when we passed this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are now here again. We have given reform on peer review now so that all the major projects, all the projects over $50 million are subject to peer review. We have put in environmental reform and Corps reform in regard to mitigation issues. We have put in Corps reform in regard to project planning so that all the concerns of all the environmental groups who want to be involved in this process will be included.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I just want to point that out, how environmentally strong this legislation is thanks to not only our efforts on this side and the staff and Mr. Baker, but also Chairman Oberstar, Mr. Costello, Chairwoman Johnson with a lot of contribution from the gentleman from Oregon (Mr. Blumenauer) himself.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400033" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 30 seconds to the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Costello).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, there is a lot of confusion over the Blumenauer amendment, and let me just say that the Blumenauer amendment does not affect the language on independent review. The Blumenauer amendment will make the study process more efficient, and for that reason I ask my colleagues to support the Blumenauer amendment and support the bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400033" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 1 minute to the gentleman from Minnesota (Mr. Oberstar), our distinguished chairman.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I appreciate the concerns of the distinguished ranking member of the subcommittee about time and cost. We certainly don't want to add any more time than Corps projects already take to evolve, nor do we want to foist additional costs on local governments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The language of the amendment of the gentleman, though, is simply to take current practice that the Corps has in its principles and guidelines, but to make those principles and guidelines into current law. I have talked with the Corps representatives in the chief's office, and they say, well, we're looking for direction from Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This language will not add time, will not create costs that are not already being incurred under our existing practice, and in that spirit, I think the amendment should be accepted.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400033" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, may I inquire as to the time remaining?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from Oregon has 1 1/2  minutes remaining.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400033" topic="">
    <paragraph>Then I will close.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I deeply appreciate the words of support that have been offered here by my colleague from Wisconsin (Mr. Petri); from my distinguished chairman, Mr. Oberstar; and from the former ranking member of the Water Resources Committee, Mr. Costello.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to be clear that what was offered up by my friend, the distinguished ranking member of the subcommittee, in no way undermines what I said. These principles and guidelines have not been updated. There are procedures and circulars discussed by the gentlemen from LA. They have not been incorporated into an updated, revised principle and guideline for the Corps of Engineers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is why the National Academy of Public Administration, one of the many scientific organizations to recommend updating the principles and guidelines, they released their recommendation after the circular that the gentleman from Louisiana mentioned. His information simply is not current in terms of how the Corps is operating and all the independent bodies, the Science Board, the public administrators, why the American Engineering Association, as well as taxpayers and environmental groups say  it is past time to fix this situation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For those of you who care about getting something actually through Congress, you ought to support this amendment. One of the hang-ups between the House and the Senate has been this issue of reform. The Senate has stronger language than this. I think it will help bridge the gap. I urge its adoption.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> All time for debate on the amendment has expired.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400222" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I offer an amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will designate the amendment.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> Without objection, the modification is approved.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400222" topic="MODIFICATION TO AMENDMENT NO. 6 OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, the scope of this amendment now is focused exclusively on Lake County, Illinois, and mainly the watershed of the Des Plaines River. This is a river in which several outdated and unused dams are preventing the return of higher-end predator fish, specifically pike and walleye, through the upper Des Plaines and Fox River Valleys.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, I have worked on this amendment and consulted with my colleague, Congresswoman Melissa Bean, and we both agree on a bipartisan basis that the return of these high-end predator fish will not only help restore the environment of upper Lake County and its Fox River and Des Plaines watersheds, but also will be a help to sports fishing and boating in these areas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For these reasons, the removal of these very small but damaging structures will go a long way to restoring the ecosystems along the lines of the Chicago Paddlers Association and the Nature Conservancy and their recommendations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to particularly thank John Mica and his staff, especially Amy Steinmann for her work on this, as well as Chairman Oberstar for his help on this because this is going to make a big difference in the ecosystem of Lake County, Illinois, and we hope to invite all of you, maybe Mr. Baker as well, to come for a day, hopefully 5 years from now, of exciting sports fishing in northern Illinois.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="MODIFICATION TO AMENDMENT NO. 6 OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I ask unanimous consent to claim time in opposition, though I am not in opposition to the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the gentleman from Minnesota is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="MODIFICATION TO AMENDMENT NO. 6 OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>And I do so to speak deliberately, carefully and thoughtfully so that the Speaker pro tempore can reach the House floor in order that the committee may rise and report the bill to the House with sundry amendments and that we can conclude action on the bill. I mean, let's be honest about what we're doing here in the spirit of transparency.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But the gentleman from Illinois speaks for himself and also the gentlewoman from Illinois (Ms. Bean) who shares this river with him and also our former Speaker, Mr. Hastert, whom I saw on the House floor just prior to consideration of the legislation. So he thought this would be a good idea because he would be able to do some walleye fishing on the river, and we are all for fishing walleyes, and the gentleman has had a very, very clear and narrowly drawn objective.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am glad we have been able to work this out in a manner that suits his concerns and allays the fears and concerns of those in the Western States that thought this was going to be a major hindrance to hydroelectric projects.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I thank the gentleman for tailoring the language of the amendment to the needs at hand and to allay the broader concerns.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield such time as he may require to the gentleman from Louisiana (Mr. Baker).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400012" topic="MODIFICATION TO AMENDMENT NO. 6 OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I just wanted to express a word of appreciation to the gentleman for revision of his amendment as it now appears before Members. He worked diligently with the staff in order to assure that some concerns that had been raised had been alleviated, and we find ourselves at a point where we have an amendment to which I do not believe there is objection.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At some point later in the evening I assume we will agree to adopt it and then later we will take up the underlying bill and pass that as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I assume that the gentleman has sufficiently consumed enough time to where the managerial matters of his earlier interests may have now been resolved, I hope.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="MODIFICATION TO AMENDMENT NO. 6 OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400222" topic="MODIFICATION TO AMENDMENT NO. 6 OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>I would just like to state to the gentleman that I thank you very much for your senior leadership on this bipartisan legislation. I would hope that we could all agree that pike and walleye fishing should not be reserved for those citizens of only Wisconsin and Minnesota and can now return to the citizens of northern Illinois, who will see this ecosystem restored.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="MODIFICATION TO AMENDMENT NO. 6 OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>How much time do I have, Mr. Chairman?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from Minnesota has 2 1/2  minutes remaining.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="MODIFICATION TO AMENDMENT NO. 6 OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>I want to use this opportunity to thank the Chair of the Subcommittee on Water Resources, the gentlewoman from Texas (Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson), for the superb work she has done shaping the bill and bringing us to this point; and to the ranking member of the subcommittee, Mr. Baker of Louisiana, whom I previously eulogized for his work in the gulf; and our full committee ranking member, Mr. Mica.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This has truly been an effort bringing this bill forward, and essential to this team have been the staff. I am always grateful for the staff because that is where I started in this body 44 years ago, as clerk of the Subcommittee on Rivers and Harbors, the predecessor of the Committee on Public Works. It was the first committee of the Congress in the first Congress in 1789.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank Ryan Seiger of the majority staff; Ted Ilston, Beth Goldstein, Mike Brain, Rod Hall of Congresswoman Johnson's staff; Dave Heymsfeld of the full committee; John Anderson, a distinguished long-time professional on the minority side; Geoff Bowman, Tim Lundquist, Jim Coon of the full committee staff; and Charlie Ziegler, whom I have known for so many years, a friend of long-standing. I don't have old friends anymore, friends of long standing, when you get to my age.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the Legislative Counsel's Office, Curt Haensel and the ever-talented Dave Mendelsohn. All have worked together, pitched in to help us bring this bill to this point. We are ready now to conclude action on the amendment of the gentleman from Illinois.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the amendment offered by the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Kirk).</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400419" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>At this time in its present form I am.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will report the motion to recommit.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Oregon?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I object.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will read.</narrative>
  <chair> The gentleman from Oregon is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400419" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Thank you very much, Mr. Speaker.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to first commend the gentleman from Minnesota. He has a tough job; he has done it well on this committee. I have enjoyed my work over the years on issues where we have agreed. I bring this motion to recommit to the floor for a couple of reasons.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The first deals with the issue of global warming and America's energy independence. I was appointed recently to the Select Committee on Energy Independence and Global Warming. We have had a lot of hearings there and in the Energy and Commerce Committee and in the Energy and Air Quality Subcommittee about how do we make America both energy independent and reduce our carbon emissions and greenhouse gas emissions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Obviously, coming from the Pacific Northwest, we are blessed in that a large percentage of our electrical generation comes from these large hydropower projects. Hydropower for America means no greenhouse gas emissions, virtually, virtually none. I suppose you could say there is some in the creation of the cement that goes into the concrete that makes up the dams, but once they are built, they are 90 percent efficient and no carbon emissions. So, obviously, there is discussion out there in the  courts and elsewhere about reducing hydropower by eliminating dams.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think it would help us in our work, in both the Select Committee on Energy and Independence, and on global warming, to know what the impacts are and if you remove the hydropower system in any course or place, what the impacts on domestic energy cost to consumers would be; what would the need be to import more energy as replacement, because obviously that is one of the issues that we look at. If you take out a particular power generation capacity, and especially one that is 90 percent efficient  and doesn't emit green house gases, then what's the carbon footprint for the replacement power?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We would look at that and call for a report on the types of fossil-based fuels or other energy sources, perhaps including clean nuclear, to replace this power that would likely be utilized.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, we ask for a report on maintenance of the lock system as well, which is extraordinarily important. I want to point out that in 2004 alone, more than 160 million tons of carbon emissions were avoided in the United States when 268 million megawatt hours of hydroelectricity were generated. Hydropower offsets more carbon emissions than all other renewable energy sources combined.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If they were to be removed, the dams in the Northwest, it would take six and a half 500-megawatt coal-fired plants to replace the energy generated, not that anybody is talking about replacing them all. That, though, would increase CO</paragraph>
    <paragraph>2 emissions by 47.4 billion pounds, 47.4 billion pounds. </paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let's look at this in replacement of shipping terms, if we don't take care of locks. In the Columbia and Snake River system, certainly in the Columbia River, certainly at John Day, there are issues about these antiquated locks that are having real maintenance needs, and yet we lack funding in some cases to deal with it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A tow of four 3,500-ton grain barges equates to 400 trucks each at 400 horsepower. For example Tidewater Barge Company, a single example, Tidewater ships about 6 million tons up and down the Columbia River each year. These 6 million tons would require 171,200 trucks if the barging capability was removed. Over 171,000 trucks. So you can see why I am concerned about lock maintenance and the need to continue down that path. This motion to recommit would do that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield to the gentleman from Louisiana.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400012" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As I understand the amendment, it is to require a study, an inventory, and an assessment of our hydroelectric capacity that is under the Secretary's jurisdiction, further to examine the advisability of perhaps private ownership of those facilities for the public interest, or whether we should enhance the government-owned and -operated facilities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So it is an examination of our energy resources to determine how we should best go forward, and the Congress does not require today the expenditure of any new money for such purpose other than that to accomplish the study.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400419" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>I think as spelled out in this motion to recommit, the gentleman is correct.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400012" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman. With that understanding, I would just express support for the gentleman.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400419" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Certainly anything that would be required here, because it does require the Corps to inventory, develop and maintain all lands, properties, et cetera, for the potential of producing hydropower. Obviously, though, we waive no environmental laws. Anything that would be authorized or result or interpreted that way from this language would require appropriation. There would be all the reviews that are required for any other law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge support of the motion to recommit.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in opposition to the motion to recommit.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from Minnesota is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>First of all, we had a very clear agreement within the committee on the Democratic and Republican side not to take new items that were not in the 109th Congress Water Resources Development Act. We have vigorously adhered to that, kept a great many projects out.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This proposal is not only new, but it is massive, it is huge, it is not a study of potential effects. It has very clear declarative language: the Secretary shall inventory, develop and maintain all lands, properties, projects, meaning hydroelectric projects. The language at the very outset prohibits any action that may be proposed, as is being considered along the Snake River, to remove dams for environmental purposes, and by directing the Secretary to undertake this action, creates a PAYGO issue.  There is a clear budgetary consequence in that language.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This motion goes well beyond the intent of the Water Resources Development Act. It goes beyond the bipartisan agreement we have in bringing this bill to the floor. It authorizes unlimited projects without consideration of environmental impacts or consideration of taxpayer expense.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>It impacts legislation that we already have in this bill. It goes far beyond the scope that we intended in WRDA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We can consider the gentleman's proposal in future authorizations of WRDA and in hearings that we will undertake, but this amendment has no place during floor consideration of this bill at this late hour when it clearly brings into play items well beyond the scope of the agreement between the Democrats and Republicans on the bill and well beyond the scope of the purpose of the legislation. It imposes vast, potential new expenditures and requirements upon the Secretary, some of which are not even  well understood at this point.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I oppose the motion, and I urge a "no" vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the previous question is ordered on the motion to recommit.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400419" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 9 of rule XX, the Chair will reduce to 5 minutes the minimum time for any electronic vote on the question of passage of the bill.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 5-minute vote.</chair>
</record>
