<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1185768000" ordinal="40" title="CONGRATULATING THE DETROIT TIGERS FOR WINNING THE 2006 AMERICAN LEAGUE PENNANT">
  <narrative>CONGRATULATING THE DETROIT TIGERS FOR WINNING THE 2006 AMERICAN LEAGUE PENNANT -- (House of Representatives - July 30, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H8840]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform be discharged from further consideration of the resolution (<bill type="hr" number="488">H. Res. 488</bill>) congratulating the Detroit Tigers for winning the 2006 American League Pennant and for bringing the City of Detroit and the State of Michigan their first trip to the World Series in 22 years, and ask for its immediate consideration in the House.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the resolution.</narrative>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Illinois?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the resolution, as follows</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="hr" number="488">H. Res. 488</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas this is the 10th American League Pennant won by the Detroit Tigers;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Manager Jim Leyland is a 3 time Manager of the Year and 1 of 7 managers in the history of baseball to win the pennant in both the National and American Leagues;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the manager and coaching staff have done a remarkable job guiding this team to victory;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas General Manager Dave Dombrowski and Owner Mike Ilitch have assembled and led a team that has revitalized the Tigers franchise;</narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas all 25 players on the playoff squad contributed to their remarkable postseason victories over the New York Yankees and the Oakland Athletics, including American League Rookie of the Year Justin Verlander, as well as Magglio Ord&#xF3;&#xF1;ez, Iv&#xE1;n Rodr&#xED;guez, Jeremy Bonderman, Kenny Rogers, Sean Casey, Carlos Guill&#xE9;n, Alexis G&#xF3;mez, Omar Infante, Pl&#xE1;cido Polanco, Brandon Inge, Craig Monroe, Marcus Thames, Curtis Granderson, Ram&#xF3;n Santiago, Neifi P&#xE9;rez,  Nate Robertson, Todd Jones, Jason Grilli, Zach Miner, Wilfredo Ledezma, Fernando Rodney, Joel Zumaya, Jamie Walker, and Vance Wilson;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Detroit Tigers have a history of great players and managers, including Ty Cobb, Al Kaline, Hank Greenberg, and Sparky Anderson; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Detroit has a vibrant sports tradition because Michigan fans have faithfully supported their teams; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the New York Yankees and Oakland Athletics proved worthy and honorable opponents during the post-season: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, &lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; That the House of Representatives--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) congratulates the Detroit Tigers on winning the 2006 American League Pennant; and</narrative>
  <narrative> (2) commends the players, coaches, management, and all the other personnel of the Detroit Tigers, as well as the fans, on this great victory.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the Detroit Tigers has won 10 American League Baseball Pennants. In 2006, they made their first trip to the World Series in 22 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I join all my colleagues in congratulating the Detroit Tigers on winning the 2006 American League Pennant. Additionally, we commend the players, coaches, management, and fans for this great victory and accomplishment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I commend my colleague Representative Mike Rogers for seeking to congratulate the Detroit Tigers for winning the 2006 American League Pennant and for bring the City of Detroit and the State of Michigan their first trip to the World Series in 22 years and urge the swift passage of this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The resolution was agreed to.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
