<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1190908802" ordinal="27" title="PROVIDING FOR CONSIDERATION OF H.R. 3567, SMALL BUSINESS INVESTMENT EXPANSION ACT OF 2007">
  <narrative>PROVIDING FOR CONSIDERATION OF <bill type="h" number="3567">H.R. 3567</bill>, SMALL BUSINESS INVESTMENT EXPANSION ACT OF 2007 -- (House of Representatives - September 27, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H10944]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400065" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, by direction of the Committee on Rules, I call up House Resolution 682 and ask for its immediate consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the resolution, as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="hr" number="682">H. Res. 682</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Resolved, &lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; That at any time after the adoption of this resolution the Speaker may, pursuant to clause 2(b) of rule XVIII, declare the House resolved into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for consideration of the bill (<bill type="h" number="3567">H.R. 3567</bill>) to amend the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to expand opportunities for investments in small businesses, and for other purposes. The first reading of the bill shall be dispensed with. All points of order against consideration  of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. General debate shall be confined to the bill and shall not exceed one hour equally divided and controlled by the chairman and ranking minority member of the Committee on Small Business. After general debate the bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule. The bill shall be considered as read. All points of order against provisions of the bill are waived. Notwithstanding clause 11 of rule XVIII, no amendment to the bill shall be in order except those printed in the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution. Each such amendment may be offered only in the order printed in the report, may be offered only by a Member designated in the report, shall be considered</narrative>
  <chair> The gentleman from California is recognized for 1 hour.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400065" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, for the purposes of debate only, I yield the customary 30 minutes to the gentleman from Washington (Mr. Hastings). All time yielded during consideration of the rule is for debate only.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield myself such time as I may consume and I ask unanimous consent that all Members have 5 legislative days within which to revise and extend their remarks on House Resolution 682.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from California?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <chair/>
  <speaking speaker="400065" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, House Resolution 682 provides for consideration of <bill type="h" number="3567">H.R. 3567</bill>, the Small Business Investment Expansion Act of 2007, under a structured rule. As the Clerk reported, the rule provides for 1 hour of general debate equally divided and controlled by the chairman and ranking minority member of the Committee on Small Business. The rule waives all points of order against consideration of the bill except for clause 9 and 10 of rule XXI. The rule makes in order all three amendments  that were submitted for consideration that are printed in the Rules Committee report accompanying this resolution. Finally, the rule provides for one motion to recommit with or without instructions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the Small Business Administration states that it "helps Americans start, build, and grow businesses." Lately, however, the Small Business Administration's actions have spoken louder than their words. And, unfortunately, SBA's actions have not spurred innovation and development but stifled them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Given the high cost of purchasing additional capital assets, small businesses are dependent upon financing, which typically comes in the form of venture capital or angel investments. Despite the SBA's intent, its investment programs have fallen short and the needs of small business have gone unmet. In fact, due to SBA's ineffective investment programs, small businesses are now faced with more than $60 billion in unmet capital needs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a tragedy. Small businesses form the backbone of our economic growth. In fact, they are responsible for creating three out of every four jobs in the United States. Imagine how many businesses could grow and how many jobs could be created if we could deliver even a fraction of that unmet need.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Small businesses are vital to our economy, and we cannot afford for our budding entrepreneurs to be denied the opportunity to succeed. By making the SBA an efficient partner in business development, small businesses will have better and more widespread access to venture capital and angel investments that they need.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the bill before us today, <bill type="h" number="3567">H.R. 3567</bill>, has strong bipartisan support. It passed the Small Business Committee by a voice vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Among other things, <bill type="h" number="3567">H.R. 3567</bill> streamlines the Small Business Investment Company program. Last year this public/private partnership leveraged more than $21 billion to over 2,000 small businesses. However, the current leverage limits are overly complex and the heavy reliance on debt-based lending programs has hampered the investment in veteran-, minority-, and women-owned businesses. <bill type="h" number="3567">H.R. 3567</bill> will simplify how leverage caps are calculated and revise the limitations on aggregate investments to  increase small business investment opportunities. In addition, it provides incentives to target veteran-, minority-, and women-owned businesses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second, the bill updates the New Markets Venture Capital program. This program was established specifically to address the unmet equity needs of low-income communities. However, this program has been woefully underfunded, and as a result, investment in low-income communities has suffered. <bill type="h" number="3567">H.R. 3567</bill> expands the New Markets Venture Capital program and provides additional incentives for small manufacturing companies in low-income areas. This will be especially important to areas like those in my  district in Merced County.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Third, the bill establishes a new Office of Angel Investment to focus on increasing equity investments in small businesses. Angel investors are high net-worth individuals who invest in and support start-up businesses in their early stages of growth and currently account for the creation of more than 51,000 new businesses every year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="3567">H.R. 3567</bill> promotes this crucial source of financing for entrepreneurs through the creation of an Angel Investment program within SBA's investment division. This new program provides matching financing leverage to eligible angel groups with 10 or more investors. The bill also directs the SBA to create a Federal angel network, a searchable directory of angel groups on the SBA Web site to better match up angel investors with small businesses seeking financing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also addresses many deficiencies in the Surety Bond program to assist small businesses in obtaining the backing they need to compete for construction contracts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this bill reflects Democrats' commitment to providing real solutions to remove the obstacles facing America's small business owners, innovators, and entrepreneurs. I would like to thank the Small Business Committee for their hard work and thoughtful work in bringing this legislation to the floor today. In particular, I extend my thanks to my good friend from Pennsylvania (Mr. Altmire) and Chairwoman Vel&#xE1;zquez.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, we all recognize the importance of small business to our economy, and we must act on this bipartisan bill without further delay.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400171" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I want to thank the gentleman from California, my good friend (Mr. Cardoza), for yielding me the customary 30 minutes, and I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, as a former small business owner, I recognize the need for legislation to help update and streamline Small Business Administration programs and leverage new investment strategies in order to expand small business investment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, we must also make a commitment to small business that tax relief measures that passed the House the last several years should not be allowed to expire at the end of this year. With a month left before Congress's target adjournment date and just 3 months left of 2007, small businesses are depending on Congress to act quickly to renew tax relief which has allowed them to create more jobs and grow, helping America's economy grow at the same time. Tax relief and reduced regulatory burdens  can make all the difference whether a small business is profitable at the end of the year or is forced to close its doors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, yesterday the Rules Committee adopted a structured rule for consideration of <bill type="h" number="3567">H.R. 3567</bill>, the Small Business Investment Expansion Act of 2007. While this rule makes all submitted amendments in order, I believe the underlying bipartisan bill that is supported both by the chairman and ranking member of the Committee on Small Business should have been considered under an open rule on the House floor today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Yesterday the ranking member, Mr. Dreier, on Rules gave the Democrat majority on Rules the opportunity to double the number of open rules that this body has heard other than appropriation bills reported from the committee this Congress. Unfortunately, Democrat members of the Rules Committee denied bringing the underlying bipartisan bill to the floor under an open rule process. Thus only two, Mr. Speaker, only two of 433 Members of the House will be able to offer amendments on this bill  today. While this is disappointing, this, unfortunately, is not an unusual practice of this Rules Committee, despite promises of openness made to the American people just last year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, earlier this year, House rules were adopted that require the disclosure and allow Members to challenge earmarks in appropriation bills;  however, under current House rules, earmarks and authorization bills and tax bills do not have to be disclosed and are not allowed to be challenged. This loophole needs to be closed, and I am going to give my colleagues in this House another opportunity to send a strong message to the American taxpayers  that we are serious about earmark transparency. Therefore, I will be asking Members to oppose the previous question so that I may amend the rule to allow for immediate consideration of House Resolution 479, the earmark accountability rule. By defeating the previous question, we will be</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As my colleague LINCOLN DIAZ-BALART observed yesterday, it has been a good week for earmarks and a bad week for transparency. We have an opportunity to change that, and I hope the Democrat majority will not make this another missed opportunity to make good on their promises to seek earmark transparency to American taxpayers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to oppose the previous question.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent to have the text of the amendment and extraneous material inserted into the Record prior to the vote on the previous question.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Washington?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400171" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400065" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the gentleman discusses the question of an open rule. In fact, we adopted every amendment that was presented to the Rules Committee and brought it to the floor today. There were three amendments offered. All three amendments will be before the House today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And the question on a Small Business Committee bill that deals with the wide diversity that small businesses can impact really allows, under the House rules, under the germaneness rules, that almost any measure, not related to this bill, but almost any measure could be brought to the floor under an open rule. It's much more appropriate for the Rules Committee to manage the debate and the time spent on this House floor by asking all Members to submit their amendments that they might want to put  forward on this particular bill and debate them in an orderly fashion on the floor. And that is why the committee adopted the rule that it did, a structured rule, to manage the rule in an appropriate rule way.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The second question is on the question of earmarks that the gentleman raised. And I would just like to refer to page 24 of the report submitted to the House that accompanies this bill, and title XIV is a statement of no earmarks. I should read that to the House at this time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It says: "Pursuant to clause 9 of rule XXI, <bill type="h" number="3567">H.R. 3567</bill> does not contain any congressional earmarks, limited tax benefits, or limited tariff benefits as defined in clause 9(d), 9(e), or 9(f) of rule XXI." The statement is very clear that there are no earmarks in this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the Democrats believe that small businesses are a fundamental part of our Nation's economic growth and that government has a responsibility to provide increased investment opportunities to ensure their long-term successes. <bill type="h" number="3567">H.R. 3567</bill> creates a renewed focus on minority-owned small businesses and small businesses in low-income areas, both of which have been traditionally faced with difficulty in gaining access to equity investment. It also paves the way to better serve thousands of  small businesses and give a much-needed jolt to our economy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, we must continue to shepherd our small businesses to give them every opportunity to succeed for today and for tomorrows yet to come. This bill will move us in that direction, and small businesses will be that much closer to making their dreams of prosperity a reality with the passage of this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge a "yes" vote on the rule and on the previous question.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The material previously referred to by Mr. Hastings of Washington is as follows:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Amendment to <bill type="hr" number="682">H. Res. 682</bill> Offered by Mr. Hastings of Washington</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At the end of the resolution, add the following:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>SEC. 3. That immediately upon the adoption of this resolution the House shall, without intervention of any point of order, consider the resolution (<bill type="hr" number="479">H. Res. 479</bill>) to amend the Rules of the House of Representatives to provide for enforcement of clause 9 of rule XXI of the Rules of the House of Representatives. The resolution shall be considered as read. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the resolution to final adoption without intervening motion or demand for division  of the question except: (1) one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by the chairman and ranking minority member of the Committee on Rules; and (2) one motion to recommit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>&lt;pre&gt;--&lt;/pre&gt;</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(The information contained herein was provided by Democratic Minority on multiple occasions throughout the 109th Congress)</narrative>
  <narrative>The Vote on the Previous Question: What It Really Means</narrative>
  <narrative>This vote, the vote on whether to order the previous question on a special rule, is not merely a procedural vote. A vote against ordering the previous question is a vote against the Democratic majority agenda and a vote to allow the opposition, at least for the moment, to offer an alternative plan. It is a vote about what the House should be debating.</narrative>
  <narrative>Mr. Clarence Cannon's Precedents of the House of Representatives, (VI, 308-311) describes the vote on the previous question on the rule as "a motion to direct or control the consideration of the subject before the House being made by the Member in charge." To defeat the previous question is to give the opposition a chance to decide the subject before the House. Cannon cites the Speaker's ruling of January 13, 1920, to the effect that "the refusal of the House to sustain the demand for the  previous question passes the control of the resolution to the opposition" in order to offer an amendment. On March 15, 1909, a member of the majority party offered a rule resolution. The House defeated the previous question and a member of the opposition rose to a parliamentary inquiry,</narrative>
  <narrative>Because the vote today may look bad for the Democratic majority they will say "the vote on the previous question is simply a vote on whether to proceed to an immediate vote on adopting the resolution *.*.* [and] has no substantive legislative or policy implications whatsoever." But that is not what they have always said. Listen to the definition of the previous question used in the Floor Procedures Manual published by the Rules Committee in the 109th Congress, (page 56). Here's how the Rules  Committee described the rule using information from Congressional Quarterly's "American Congressional Dictionary": "If the previous question is defeated, control of debate shifts to the leading opposition member (usually the minority Floor Manager) who then manages an hour of debate and may offer a germane amendment to the pending business."</narrative>
  <narrative>(f) Deschler's Procedure in the U.S. House of Representatives, the subchapter titled "Amending Special Rules" states: "a refusal to order the previous question on such a rule [a special rule reported from the Committee on Rules] opens the resolution to amendment and further debate." (Chapter 21, section 21.2) Section 21.3 continues: Upon rejection of the motion for the previous question on a resolution reported from the Committee on Rules, control shifts to the Member leading the opposition  to the previous question, who may offer a proper amendment or motion and who controls the time for debate thereon."</narrative>
  <narrative>Clearly, the vote on the previous question on a rule does have substantive policy implications. It is one of the only available tools for those who oppose the Democratic majority's agenda and allows those with alternative views the opportunity to offer an alternative plan.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400065" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time, and I move the previous question on the resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on ordering the previous question.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and the Speaker pro tempore announced that the ayes appeared to have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400171" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX, further proceedings on this question will be postponed.</chair>
</record>
