<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1216051202" ordinal="13" title="NATIONAL SEA GRANT COLLEGE PROGRAM AMENDMENTS ACT OF 2008">
  <narrative>NATIONAL SEA GRANT COLLEGE PROGRAM AMENDMENTS ACT OF 2008 -- (House of Representatives - July 14, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H6412]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="5618">H.R. 5618</bill>) to reauthorize and amend the National Sea Grant College Program Act, and for other purposes, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="5618">H.R. 5618</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "National Sea Grant College Program Amendments Act of 2008".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. REFERENCES.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Except as otherwise expressly provided therein, whenever in this Act an amendment or repeal is expressed in terms of an amendment to, or repeal of, a section or other provision, the reference shall be considered to be made to a section or other provision of the National Sea Grant College Program Act (33 U.S.C. 1121 et seq.).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 3. FINDINGS AND PURPOSE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Findings.--Section 202(a) (33 U.S.C. 1121(a)) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) by amending paragraph (1)(D) to read as follows:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(D) encourage the development of preparation, forecast, analysis, mitigation, response, and recovery systems for coastal hazards;";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) in paragraph (2) by striking "program of research, education," and inserting "program of integrated research, education, extension,"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) by striking paragraph (6) and inserting the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(6) The National Ocean Research Priorities Plan and Implementation Strategy issued by the National Science and Technology Council's Joint Subcommittee on Ocean Science and Technology on January 26, 2007, identifies research priorities for compelling areas of interaction between society and the ocean, and calls for the engagement of a broad array of ocean science sectors (government, academia, industry, and non-government entities) to address the areas of greatest research need and opportunity.</narrative>
  <narrative> "(7) The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, through the national sea grant college program, offers the most suitable locus and means for such commitment and engagement through the promotion of activities that will result in greater such understanding, assessment, development, utilization, and conservation. The most cost-effective way to promote such activities is through continued and increased Federal support of the establishment, development, and operation of programs and projects  by sea grant colleges, sea grant institutes, and other institutions, including strong collaborations between Administration scientists and research and outreach personnel at academic institutions.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Purpose.--Section 202(c) (33 U.S.C. 1121(c)) is amended by striking "to promote research, education, training, and advisory service activities" and inserting "to promote integrated research, education, training, and extension activities".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 4. DEFINITIONS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Amendments.--Section 203 (33 U.S.C. 1122) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in paragraph (11) by striking "advisory services" and inserting "extension services";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) in each of paragraphs (12) and (13) by striking "(33 U.S.C. 1126)"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) by adding at the end the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(17) The term `regional research and information plan' means a plan developed by one or more sea grant colleges or sea grant institutes that identifies regional priorities to implement the National Ocean Research Priorities Plan and Implementation Strategy.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(18) The term `National Ocean Research Priorities Plan and Implementation Strategy' means such plan and strategy issued by the National Science and Technology Council's Joint Subcommittee on Ocean Science and Technology on January 26, 2007.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Repeal.--Section 307 of the Act entitled "An Act to provide for the designation of the Flower Garden Banks National Marine Sanctuary" (Public Law 102-251; 106 Stat. 66) is repealed.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 5. NATIONAL SEA GRANT COLLEGE PROGRAM, GENERALLY.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Program Elements.--Section 204(b) (33 U.S.C. 1123(b)) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) by amending in paragraph (1) to read as follows:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(1) sea grant programs that comprise a national sea grant college program network, including international projects conducted within such programs and regional and national projects conducted among such programs;";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) by amending paragraph (2) to read as follows:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(2) administration of the national sea grant college program and this title by the national sea grant office and the Administration;"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) by amending paragraph (4) to read as follows:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(4) any regional or national strategic investments in fields relating to ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes resources developed in consultation with the board and with the approval of the sea grant colleges and the sea grant institutes.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Technical Correction.--Section 204(c)(2) (33 U.S.C. 1123(c)(2)) is amended by striking "Within 6 months of the date of enactment of the National Sea Grant College Program Reauthorization Act of 1998, the" and inserting "The".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Functions of Director of National Sea Grant College Program.--Section 204(d) (33 U.S.C. 1123(d)) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in paragraph (2)(A), by striking "long-range";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) in paragraph (3)(A)--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) by striking "(A)(i) evaluate" and inserting "(A) evaluate and assess";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) by striking "activities; and" and inserting "activities;"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) by striking clause (ii); and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) in paragraph (3)(B)--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) by redesignating clauses (ii) through (iv) as clauses (iv) through (vi), respectively, and by inserting after clause (i) the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(ii) encourage collaborations among sea grant colleges and sea grant institutes to address regional and national priorities established under subsection (c)(1);&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(iii) encourage cooperation with Minority Serving Institutions--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(I) to enhance collaborative research opportunities for faculty and students in the areas of atmospheric, oceanic, and environmental sciences, and remote sensing;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(II) to improve opportunities for, and retention of, students and faculty from Minority Serving Institutions in the NOAA related sciences; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(III) to increase the number of such students graduating in NOAA science areas;"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) in clause (iv) (as so redesignated) by striking "encourage" and inserting "ensuring".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 6. PROGRAM OR PROJECT GRANTS AND CONTRACTS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Exemption From Limitation on Cost Share.--Section 205(a) (33 U.S.C. 1124(a)) is  amended in the matter following paragraph (2), by inserting "or that are appropriated under section 208(b)" before the period at the end.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Special Grants; Maximum Amount.--Section 205(b) (33 U.S.C. 1124(b)) is amended by striking the matter following paragraph (3) and inserting the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;"The total amount that may be provided for grants under this subsection during any fiscal year shall not exceed an amount equal to 5 percent of the total funds appropriated for such year under section 212.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 7. EXTENSION SERVICES BY SEA GRANT COLLEGES AND SEA GRANT INSTITUTES.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Section 207(a) (33 U.S.C. 1126(a)) is amended in each of paragraphs (2)(B) and (3)(B) by striking "advisory services" and inserting "extension services".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 8. FELLOWSHIPS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Restriction on Use of Funds Available for Fellowships.--Section 208 (33 U.S.C. 1127) is amended by adding at the end the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(c) Restriction on Use of Funds.--Amounts available for fellowships under this section, including amounts accepted under section 204(c)(4)(F) or appropriated under section 212 to implement this section, shall be used only for award of such fellowships and administrative costs of implementing this section.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Technical Correction.--Section 208(a) (33 U.S.C. 1127(a)) is amended by striking "Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of the National Sea Grant College Program Act Amendments of 2002, and every 2 years thereafter," and inserting "Every 2 years,".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 9. NATIONAL SEA GRANT ADVISORY BOARD.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Redesignation of Sea Grant Review Panel as Board.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) REDESIGNATION.--The sea grant review panel established by section 209 of the National Sea Grant College Program Act (33 U.S.C. 1128), as in effect before the date of the enactment of this Act, is redesignated as the National Sea Grant Advisory Board.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) MEMBERSHIP NOT AFFECTED.--An individual serving as a member of the sea grant review panel immediately before the enactment of this Act may continue to serve as a member of the National Sea Grant Advisory Board until the expiration of such member's term under section 209(c) of such Act (33 U.S.C. 1128(c).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) REFERENCES.--Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to such sea grant review panel is deemed to be a reference to the National Sea Grant Advisory Board.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) CONFORMING AMENDMENTS.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) IN GENERAL.--Section 209 (33 U.S.C. 1128) is amended by striking so much as precedes subsection (b) and inserting the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;"SEC. 209. NATIONAL SEA GRANT ADVISORY BOARD.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(a) Establishment.--There shall be an independent committee to be known as the National Sea Grant Advisory Board.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) DEFINITION.--Section 203(9) (33 U.S.C. 1122(9)) is amended to read as follows:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(9) The term `Board' means the National Sea Grant Advisory Board established under section 209.";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) OTHER PROVISIONS.--The following provisions are each amended by striking "panel" each place it appears and inserting "Board":&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) Section 204 (33 U.S.C. 1123).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) Section 207 (33 U.S.C. 1126).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (iii) Section 209 (33 U.S.C. 1128).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Duties.--Section 209(b) (33 U.S.C. 1128(b)) is amended to read as follows:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(b) Duties.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(1) IN GENERAL.--The Board shall advise the Secretary and the Director concerning--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(A) strategies for utilizing the sea grant college program to address the Nation's highest priorities regarding the understanding, assessment, development, utilization, and conservation of ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes resources;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(B) the designation of sea grant colleges and sea grant institutes; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(C) such other matters as the Secretary refers to the Board for review and advice.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(2) BIENNIAL REPORT.--The Board shall report to the Congress every two years on the state of the national sea grant college program. The Board shall indicate in each such report the progress made toward meeting the priorities identified in the strategic plan in effect under section 204(c). The Secretary shall make available to the Board such information, personnel, and administrative services and assistance as it may reasonably require to carry out its duties under this title.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Extension of Term.--Section 209(c)(2) (33 U.S.C. 1128(c)(2)) is amended by striking the second sentence and inserting the following: "The Director may extend the term of office of a voting member of the Board once by up to 1 year.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (d) Establishment of Subcommittees.--Section 204(c) (33 U.S.C. 1123(c)) is amended by adding at the end the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(8) The Board may establish such subcommittees as are reasonably necessary to carry out its duties under subsection (b). Such subcommittees may include individuals who are not Board members.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 10. AUTHORIZATION OF APPROPRIATIONS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Authorization.--Section 212(a) (33 U.S.C. 1131(a)) is amended to read as follows:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(a) Authorization.--There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this title--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(1) $66,000,000 for fiscal year 2009;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(2) $72,800,000 for fiscal year 2010;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(3) $79,600,000 for fiscal year 2011;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(4) $86,400,000 for fiscal year 2012;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(5) $93,200,000 for fiscal year 2013; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(6) $100,000,000 for fiscal year 2014.".</narrative>
  <narrative> (b) Repeal of Distribution Requirement.--Section 212 (33 U.S.C. 1131) is amended by striking subsection (c), and by redesignating subsections (d) and (e) as subsections (c) and (d), respectively. &lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from Guam (Ms. Bordallo) and the gentleman from South Carolina (Mr. Wilson) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentlewoman from Guam.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from Guam?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, <bill type="h" number="5618">H.R. 5618</bill>, the National Sea Grant College Program Amendments Act of 2008, is legislation that I introduced this past March. The bill reauthorizes the National Sea Grant College Program Act to improve marine resource conservation, management and utilization.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sea Grant Colleges sponsor a wide range of applied and basic marine science research, education, training and technical assistance programs promoting the understanding, the assessment, the development, the utilization and the conservation of ocean, coastal and Great Lakes resources. The reauthorization bill affords the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration the ability and the flexibility to strengthen the current network of Sea Grant Colleges and their collaborating institutions through  fiscal year 2014. It does so based on the sensible recommendation of the Sea Grant Association, the Sea Grant Review Panel, the National Sea Grant Program Office, and other stakeholders.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By reauthorizing this program, the opportunity for enlisting more partnering institutions and increasing the overall number of designated Sea Grant Colleges remains. Capacity building for eventual Sea Grant College designation is ongoing at several institutions. And I note that in reauthorizing the program, <bill type="h" number="5618">H.R. 5618</bill> keeps intact in current law the authority for NOAA to provide administrative, technical and financial assistance to institutions preparing and aiming for eventual Sea Grant College  designation. The current eligibility criteria have ensured ultimate success with the entire program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The University of Guam, in my district, Mr. Speaker, continues to plan for eventual designation. I support NOAA's efforts to assist with capacity building at the University of Guam and at other institutions in the Western Pacific region and across the United States that are working to develop the expertise and resources necessary to be designated a Sea Grant Institution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, Mr. Speaker, I note that in reauthorizing the overall program, we also renewed the authority for the continuation of the highly successful Dean John A. Knauss Marine Policy Fellowship program. Several of us here serving in Congress have had the extraordinary opportunity to host a legislative Sea Grant Fellow in our office. The skill and the competency of the Sea Grant fellows are a testament to the strength and the depth of the Sea Grant College program. The contributions of Sea Grant  fellows in both the executive and the legislative branches have helped ensure policy is both crafted and implemented with an invaluable science perspective.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In reauthorizing the National Sea Grant College Program, Congress reaffirms its national value to protecting our human and our environmental health to the design and the utilization of sustainable development practices, and to the overall advancement of important research and extensive activities in the Marine Sciences.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With our support, the network of Sea Grant Colleges is positioned to continue collaborative ground-breaking research and engagement in the Marine Sciences with stakeholders in communities all across the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I therefore ask Members on both sides to support passage of this noncontroversial bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400433" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the majority, capably led by Congresswoman MADELEINE BORDALLO of the Republic of Guam, has superbly explained the bill. The National Sea Grant College Program has been an important component in addressing local and regional research for needs for ocean and Great Lakes issues. The program, such as the one at Buford, South Carolina, has been extremely effective in disseminating science-based information to citizens through education and outreach  programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="5618">H.R. 5618</bill> reauthorizes this important marine science program, and I support its passage with particular appreciation for the Buford Laboratory.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no further speakers on this particular piece of legislation. I want to thank my colleague, Mr. Wilson of South Carolina, for his supportive remarks.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400128" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in strong support of <bill type="h" number="5618">H.R. 5618</bill>, amending the National Sea Grant College Program Act and reauthorizing the program that is scheduled to expire fiscal year 2008.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First and foremost, I want to commend Congresswoman BORDALLO of Guam, Chairwoman of the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, and Oceans of the Committee on Natural Resources, for taking the initiative to introduce this important legislation. This bill is an example of the efforts by the Congress to support our many Sea Grant College programs in improving marine resource conservation and management.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="5618">H.R. 5618</bill> implements changes in the Sea Grant Program, which is administered by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, NOAA, that were recommended by the National Research Council in their 2006 report that has strong support from the various agencies and the Sea Grant Association. Such recommendations include increasing the interaction between the National Sea Grant and the individual state programs. It will improve programmatic performance reviews that will strengthen oversight  and accountability but at the same time will ensure that Sea Grant programs are consistent and supportive of the national objectives. Importantly, the increase in funding levels will greatly assist in the needs of our coastal and Great Lake communities and will improve program activities and research that have been at a standstill because of flat-funding for the past few years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Like our national land grant programs, the National Sea Grant College Program is a powerful resource in maintaining America's status in the world for research and development of our marine sciences. It is a program that we must continue to strengthen and support.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this legislation will authorize funding for the National Sea Grant Program until FY 2014. The inclusion of the many recommendations by the NRC in the language of the bill and the strong support of the Federal agencies and the Sea Grant Association reinforce the necessity to pass this legislation immediately. Given that almost 54 percent of our population lives on the coast, the U.S. has continued to provide so little for marine policy research. Through <bill type="h" number="5618">H.R. 5618</bill>, I am hopeful that  we are able to increase this necessary funding to monitor the drastic changes that are greatly affecting our coastlines.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am grateful for the work that Sea Grant has been able to provide through research and projects to my Congressional district. Through the University of Hawaii, Sea Grant has a strong presence at the American Samoa Community College and has continued to educate students of the necessity in protecting our reefs and marine environments. They have also continued to provide the tools for marine research that is urgently needed by the U.S. territories.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For these reasons, I urge my colleagues to pass <bill type="h" number="5618">H.R. 5618</bill>. Again, I thank my colleagues for their support of this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400129" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="5618">H.R. 5618</bill> the National Sea Grant College Program Amendments Act of 2008 authored by my friend and chairwoman of the Natural Resources Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife and Oceans, Representative Madeleine Bordallo.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The National Sea Grant College Program has, since 1966, provided research grants, traineeships and fellowships which help graduate students and researchers study areas of the ocean which have strong effects on people. This is mostly done through the State Sea Grant programs which operate in most coastal States in conjunction with major universities. The Sea Grant programs provide valuable research and education into the economics, public health, and environmental impacts where people connect  with the oceans. I have trouble thinking of a better return to the public on our research investments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The National Sea Grant program operates the Dean John A. Knauss National Marine Policy Fellowship which provides graduate students in ocean science and environmental studies the opportunity to bring their expertise as a fellow in a Congressional office or in a Federal agency office to gain experience and impact ocean policy. In my tenure in Congress, I have had 11 Sea Grant Fellows in my office. They have provided invaluable knowledge and passion for the oceans that have improved my understanding  and helped to bolster my fight for the oceans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In California, we are lucky to have two Sea Grant Programs: the California Sea Grant program operated through the world class University of California system and the Southern California Sea Grant program operated through the University of Southern California. These programs are on the ground in California connecting the research and policy community, providing research grants, and educating the public, scientists, and policy makers on the importance of human interactions with the ocean.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the National Sea Grant programs have done a lot with a little money and I am confident that they will continue this tradition. I cannot emphasize enough the need for this Congress to provide for ocean stewardship now. The oceans and the Great Lakes belong to all the people of the United States and it is our duty to understand the implications of our actions on them. I support the National Sea Grant College Program Amendment Act and I urge my colleagues to join me.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from Guam (Ms. Bordallo) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="5618">H.R. 5618</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the bill, as amended, was passed.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
