<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1193068802" ordinal="37" title="ENERGY STORAGE TECHNOLOGY ADVANCEMENT ACT OF 2007">
  <narrative>ENERGY STORAGE TECHNOLOGY ADVANCEMENT ACT OF 2007 -- (House of Representatives - October 22, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H11814]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400155" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="3776">H.R. 3776</bill>) to provide for a research, development, and demonstration program by the Secretary of Energy to support the ability of the United States to remain globally competitive in energy storage systems for vehicles, stationary applications, and electricity transmission and distribution, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="3776">H.R. 3776</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "Energy Storage Technology Advancement Act of 2007".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. DEFINITIONS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; For purposes of this Act--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) the term "Department" means the Department of Energy;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) the term "electric drive vehicle" means--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) a vehicle that uses an electric motor for all or part of its motive power, including battery electric, hybrid electric, plug-in hybrid electric, fuel cell, and plug-in fuel cell vehicles, and rail transportation vehicles; or&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) mobile equipment that uses an electric motor to replace an internal combustion engine for all or part of the work of the equipment;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) the term "islanding" means a distributed generator or energy storage device continuing to power a location in the absence of electric power from the primary source;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) the term "microgrid" means an integrated energy system consisting of interconnected loads and distributed energy resources, including generators and energy storage devices, which as an integrated system can operate in parallel with the utility grid or in an intentional islanding mode;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) the term "Secretary" means the Secretary of Energy;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (6) the term "self-healing grid" means a grid that is capable of automatically anticipating and responding to power system disturbances, including the isolation of failed sections and components, while optimizing its own performance and service to customers; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (7) the term "spinning reserve services" means an amount of electric generating capacity in excess of the amount needed to meet peak electric demand.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 3. BASIC RESEARCH PROGRAM.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) In General.--The Secretary shall conduct a basic research program to support the development of energy storage systems for electric drive vehicles, stationary applications, and electricity transmission and distribution, including research on--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) materials design;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) materials synthesis and characterization;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) electrolytes;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) surface and interface dynamics;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) modeling and simulation; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (6) thermal behavior and life degradation mechanisms.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Funding.--For activities carried out under this section, in addition to funding activities at National Laboratories, the Secretary shall award funds to, and coordinate activities with, a range of stakeholders including the public, private, and academic sectors.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Authorization of Appropriations.--There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for carrying out this section $50,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2009 through 2014.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 4. APPLIED RESEARCH PROGRAM.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) In General.--The Secretary shall conduct an applied research program on energy storage systems to support electric drive vehicle, stationary application, and electricity transmission and distribution technologies, including research on--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) ultracapacitors;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) flywheels;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) batteries and battery systems (including flow batteries);&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) compressed air energy systems;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) power conditioning electronics;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (6) manufacturing technologies for energy storage systems;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (7) thermal management systems; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (8) hydrogen as an energy storage medium.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Funding.--For activities carried out under this section, in addition to funding activities at National Laboratories, the Secretary shall award funds to, and coordinate activities with, a range of stakeholders including the public, private, and academic sectors.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Authorization of Appropriations.--There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for carrying out this section $80,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2009 through 2014.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 5. ENERGY STORAGE SYSTEMS DEMONSTRATIONS.</narrative>
  <narrative> (a) In General.--The Secretary shall carry out a program of new demonstrations of advanced energy storage systems. These demonstrations shall be regionally diversified and shall expand on the Department's existing technology demonstration program. These demonstrations should include the participation of a range of stakeholders, such as rural electric cooperatives, investor owned utilities, municipally owned electric utilities, energy storage systems manufacturers, electric drive vehicle  manufacturers, the renewable energy production industry, State or local energy offices, the fuel cell industry, and universities. Each of the demonstrations shall include one or more of the following objectives:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) Energy storage to improve the feasibility of "micro-grids" or "islanding", or the transmission and distribution capability to improve reliability in rural areas.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) Integration of an energy storage system with a self-healing grid.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) Use of energy storage to improve security to emergency response infrastructure.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) Integration with a renewable energy production source, either at the source or away from the source.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) Use of energy storage to provide ancillary services, such as spinning reserve services, for grid management.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (6) Advancement of power conversion systems to make them smarter, more efficient, able to communicate with other inverters, and able to control voltage.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (7) Use of energy storage to optimize transmission and distribution operation and power quality, which could address overloaded lines and maintenance of transformers and substations.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (8) Use of advanced energy storage for peak load management of homes, businesses, and the grid.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (9) Use of energy storage devices to fill up nonpeak generation periods for electricity demand to make better use of existing grid assets.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Authorization of Appropriations.--There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for carrying out this section $30,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2009 through 2014.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 6. VEHICLE ENERGY STORAGE DEMONSTRATION.</narrative>
  <narrative> (a) In General.--The Secretary shall carry out a program of electric drive vehicle energy  storage technology demonstrations. These technology demonstrations shall be conducted through consortia, which may include energy storage systems manufacturers and their suppliers, electric drive vehicle manufacturers, rural electric cooperatives, investor owned utilities, municipal and rural electric utilities, State and local governments, metropolitan  transportation authorities, and universities. The program shall demonstrate one or more of the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) Novel, high capacity, high efficiency energy storage, charging, and control systems, along with the collection of data on performance characteristics such as battery life, energy storage capacity, and power delivery capacity.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) Advanced onboard energy management systems, and highly efficient battery cooling systems.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) Integration of such systems on a prototype vehicular platform, including with drivetrain systems for passenger, commercial, and nonroad electric drive vehicles.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) New technologies and processes that reduce manufacturing costs.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) Integration of advanced vehicle technologies with electricity distribution system and smart metering technology.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Authorization of Appropriations.--There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for carrying out this section $30,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2009 through 2014.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 7. SECONDARY APPLICATIONS AND DISPOSAL OF ELECTRIC DRIVE VEHICLE BATTERIES.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) In General.--The Secretary shall carry out a program of research, development, and demonstration of secondary applications of energy storage devices following service in electric drive vehicles, and of technologies and processes for final recycling and disposal of these devices.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Authorization of Appropriations.--There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for carrying out this section $5,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2009 through 2014.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 8. COORDINATION AND NONDUPLICATION.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;  To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall coordinate activities under this Act with other programs and laboratories of the Department and other Federal research programs.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 9. COST SHARING.</narrative>
  <narrative> The Secretary shall carry out the programs under sections 6 and 7 in compliance with section 988 (a) through (d) and section 989 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (42 U.S.C. 16352(a) through (d) and 16353).&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Tennessee (Mr. Gordon) and the gentleman from Washington (Mr. Reichert) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Tennessee.</chair>
  <chair/>
  <speaking speaker="400155" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and to include extraneous material on <bill type="h" number="3776">H.R. 3776</bill>, the bill now under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Tennessee?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400155" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I am pleased that the House will consider today <bill type="h" number="3776">H.R. 3776</bill>, the Energy Storage Technology Advancement Act. I would like to thank my colleagues on the Science and Technology Committee for their unanimous support in making this a good, bipartisan piece of legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In particular, I would like to thank my good friend and ranking member, Mr. Hall, for his interest in this field of research. In crafting <bill type="h" number="3776">H.R. 3776</bill>, I adopted several provisions from a bill Mr. Hall introduced earlier this year, and he and his staff have worked hard to make this a good bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="3776">H.R. 3776</bill> authorizes research, development and demonstration activities for energy storage technologies that offer a wide range of economic, environmental and security benefits.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Stationary energy storage systems will bring efficiencies to the electric delivery system, will improve grid reliability and security, and can even help to postpone the need for additional, costly electric generation facilities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Energy storage technologies can also help to integrate renewable energy sources into the grid by making electricity from these intermittent resources more stable and reliable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Furthermore, advanced battery systems can revolutionize our transportation sector by allowing for more electric-drive vehicles, thus reducing our reliance on conventional transportation fuels.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But unfortunately, we may be fast losing our ability to develop and manufacture these technologies at home. Through the collaborative public-private research, development and demonstration programs authorized in <bill type="h" number="3776">H.R. 3776</bill>, we can ensure that the United States establishes a robust domestic manufacturing base for these technologies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To truly transform the way we manage our energy use, we must do more than make incremental improvements to current technologies. Our economic and environmental security lies in our ability to deploy the next generation energy technologies. Advances in energy storage are vital to diversifying our energy supplies and transforming our transportation sector.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Once again, I thank my colleagues on the Science and Technology Committee for working with me on this legislation, and I urge all Members to support the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400660" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="3776">H.R. 3776</bill>, the Energy Storage Technology Advancement Act, and I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Electricity is the lifeblood of our country. Without reliable electricity, our country would not be the world leader that it is today. Therefore, anything that can be done to improve and secure the reliability of the electric grid should be supported and encouraged. <bill type="h" number="3776">H.R. 3776</bill> aims to do just that by focusing research and development on ways to store energy which would not only assist in reliability, but also efficiency of fuel use and security of not only our grid but also, in a broader sense,  of our country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Energy storage would allow for the enhanced use of renewable energy such as wind and solar.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Currently, the ability of wind energy and solar energy to contribute electricity to the electric grid is tied to when the wind is blowing or when the sun is shining, therefore, making these sources not as reliable as conventional sources of energy such as coal, natural gas and nuclear. With energy storage, excess generation that is unable to be used at the time of generation can be stored for use at a later time. This allows for wind and solar energy to be potential sources of base load generation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to energy storage for stationary sources, there is also a promising field of energy storage for vehicles, the most recognizable example being batteries that would be used in plug-in hybrids. Plug-in hybrids would allow for a further decrease in transportation fuel consumption from conventional hybrids, thereby increasing our national security by decreasing our reliance on foreign sources of oil.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="3776">H.R. 3776</bill> addresses the battery obstacle by including a research and development program into batteries and battery systems and a demonstration program to prove the viability of the R&amp;D.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I'd like to thank the chairman of the Science and Technology Committee and sponsor of this bill for recognizing the importance of energy storage to our country's energy future and also for including portions of Ranking Member Hall's energy storage language that was included in <bill type="h" number="2483">H.R. 2483</bill> and cosponsored by several members of the Science and Technology Committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400155" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, let me say there's no question that Mr. Hall played a major role in this, and I'm glad that we could have this type of, again, bipartisan unanimous bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If my friend from Washington State has no other speakers, I have none.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400660" topic="">
    <paragraph>I have no further speakers, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400155" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Tennessee (Mr. Gordon) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="3776">H.R. 3776</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the bill, as amended, was passed.</chair>
  <chair>The title was amended so as to read: "A bill to provide for research, development, and demonstration programs  in advanced energy storage systems for electric drive vehicles, stationary applications, and electricity transmission and distribution applications, to support the ability of the United States to remain globally competitive in this field, and to promote the efficient delivery and use of energy.".</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
