<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1194282001" ordinal="75" title="NATIONAL BIBLE WEEK">
  <narrative>NATIONAL BIBLE WEEK -- (House of Representatives - November 05, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H12725]</narrative>
  <chair> Under a previous order of the House, the gentlewoman from North Carolina (Ms. Foxx) is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400643" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today to celebrate a book that has changed the course of history and left its mark on every level of our society. The Bible has been a God-given source of guidance for humanity for thousands of years and was a wellspring of wisdom and truth for the Founders of our Nation. As we approach National Bible Week, which is traditionally celebrated during the week of Thanksgiving, it is important to pause and reflect on how this Good Book has shaped the world, changed countless  millions of lives, and brought humankind to a better understanding of our God and of our place in the world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Bible is a deep repository of fundamental and universal truth that has stood as a guide post for the generations. It teaches us how we ought to relate to our Creator and how to love our fellow human beings. During times of turmoil, confusion and strife, I can think of no more important source of guidance than the wisdom of this unchanging and inspired book.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Bible offers us hope when circumstances are dire. The Bible is a source of strength when our human frailty brings us low, and when we are surrounded by darkness, as the psalmist wrote, the Bible "is a lamp to our feet and a light to our path." In all of its transcendent wisdom, the Bible does not fail to connect to our human condition. It kindles our joy and beckons us to know God regardless of our place in life.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Throughout my life, I have drawn on the words of the Bible to lead me and inform my moral compass. The Bible is an unshakeable pillar of truth that provides the surest of moral foundations for society's founded on and reliant on its inspired content. The Bible has nourished a dialogue of our Nation's public square and has bolstered the development of a strong moral identity for hundreds of years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I encourage my fellow Americans to dig deep into the Good Book and discover for themselves what riches God's word has in store for them.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
