<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1213027204" ordinal="32" title="DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA WATER AND SEWER AUTHORITY INDEPENDENCE PRESERVATION ACT">
  <narrative>DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA WATER AND SEWER AUTHORITY INDEPENDENCE PRESERVATION ACT -- (House of Representatives - June 09, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H5084]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="5778">H.R. 5778</bill>) to preserve the independence of the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="5778">H.R. 5778</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority Independence Preservation Act".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. ENSURING INDEPENDENCE OF CHIEF FINANCIAL OFFICER OF DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA WATER AND SEWER AUTHORITY.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Clarification of Inapplicability of 2005 Omnibus Authorization Provision.--The District of Columbia Home Rule Act is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) by redesignating the section 424 added by section 202(a)(1) of the 2005 District of Columbia Omnibus Authorization Act (Public Law 109-356; 120 Stat. 2036) as section 424a; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) in section 424a, as so redesignated, by adding at the end the following new subsection:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(e) Inapplicability to Water and Sewer Authority.--The authority of the Chief Financial Officer under this section does not apply to personnel of the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority established pursuant to the Water and Sewer Authority Establishment and Department of Public Works Reorganization Act of 1996.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Effective Date.--The amendments made by subsection (a) shall take effect as if included in the enactment of the 2005 District of Columbia Omnibus Authorization Act.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 3. PRESERVING EXISTING INDEPENDENCE OF DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA WATER AND SEWER AUTHORITY.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) In General.--Part F of title IV of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act (sec. 1-204.91 et seq., D.C. Official Code) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) by amending the heading of such part to read as follows: "PART F--INDEPENDENT AGENCIES AND AUTHORITIES"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) by adding at the end the following new section:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;"INDEPENDENT FINANCIAL MANAGEMENT, PERSONNEL, AND PROCUREMENT AUTHORITY OF DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA WATER AND SEWER AUTHORITY</narrative>
  <narrative> "Sec. 496.  (a) Financial Management, Personnel, and Procurement Authority.--Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act or any District of Columbia law, the financial management, personnel, and procurement functions and responsibilities of the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority shall be established exclusively pursuant to rules and regulations adopted by its Board of Directors. Nothing in the previous sentence may be construed to affect the application to  the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority of sections 445A, 451(d), 453(c), or 490(g).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(b) Consistency With Existing Authorizing Law.--The rules and regulations adopted by the Board of Directors of the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority to establish the financial management, personnel, and procurement functions and responsibilities of the Authority shall be consistent with the Water and Sewer Authority Establishment and Department of Public Works Reorganization Act of 1996, as such Act is in effect as of January 1, 2008.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Clerical Amendments.--(1) The table of contents of such Act is amended by amending the item relating to part F of title IV to read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>"Part F--Independent Agencies and Authorities".</narrative>
  <narrative> (2) The table of contents of such Act is further amended by adding at the end of the items relating to part F of title IV the following:&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <narrative>"Sec..496..Independent financial management, personnel, and procurement authority of District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 4. PRESERVING EQUAL ELIGIBILITY OF RESIDENTS OF JURISDICTIONS SERVED BY DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA WATER AND SEWER AUTHORITY TO SERVE AS EMPLOYEES OF AUTHORITY.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) In General.--Section 213 of D.C. Act 17-172 is repealed, and each provision of law amended by such section is restored as if such section had not been enacted into law.</narrative>
  <narrative> (b) Effective Date.--Subsection (a) shall take effect as if included in the enactment of D.C. Act 17-172.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Davis) and the gentleman from Indiana (Mr. Burton) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Illinois.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days in which to revise and extend their remarks.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Illinois?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I now yield myself such time as I might consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a member of the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, I'd like to present for consideration <bill type="h" number="5778">H.R. 5778</bill>, the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority Independence Preservation Act, which clarifies the original intent of previously enacted legislation establishing an independent water and wastewater utility agency for the national capital region.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="5778">H.R. 5778</bill> was originally introduced by Representatives CHRIS VAN HOLLEN and TOM DAVIS April 10, 2008, and was discharged from the Oversight Committee on June 6, 2008. As chair of the House Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, Postal Service, and the District of Columbia, I convened a hearing to discuss the merits of this legislation before us on April 15, 2008, where we learned that the bill had the support of the various regional localities that are served by the authority.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority, also known as D.C. WASA, was created in 1996 through congressional and local government action which was intended to establish an independent regional utility agency that would be responsible for providing drinking water and wastewater treatment services to the District of Columbia and wholesale wastewater treatment services to certain Maryland and Virginia suburban jurisdictions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Before the enactment of a series of WASA-related statutes, the agency experienced a grave financial and serious operational difficulties. However, I am happy to report that ever since the agency was restructured back in the late 1990s, WASA has made significant progress in carrying out its statutory mandate of providing retail drinking water distribution, wastewater collection, and wastewater treatment services to over 2 million Washington metropolitan regional customers, of which the Federal  Government is included.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="5778">H.R. 5778</bill> clarifies the original intent of the applicable statutes concerning WASA's Board's responsibilities, including the financial management, personnel, procurement, and all other operations of the authority. A recent amendment to the bill will help to ensure that the residents and employees of the applicable jurisdictions are eligible for employment with WASA under the same terms and conditions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And so, Mr. Speaker, as a regional partner, it is important that we continue to show our commitment to strengthening and assisting WASA in its efforts to upgrade and improve the agency's operations, equipment, and long-term functionality. <bill type="h" number="5778">H.R. 5778</bill> is an important step in that direction. Therefore, I urge its adoption.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400055" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Mr. BURTON of Indiana asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400055" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, as my colleague just said, the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority Independence Preservation Act is very important.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="5778">H.R. 5778</bill> would amend the D.C. Home Rule Act to clarify that the chief financial officer of the District of Columbia does not have authority over the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority, or WASA. WASA is a regional entity, funded by rate payers living in D.C., Maryland, and Virginia. Under current Federal law, however, WASA's finances are under the jurisdiction of the D.C. chief financial officer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A memorandum of understanding has been in place between WASA and the District of Columbia CFO for many years stating that the CFO would not exercise its authority over WASA. However, it was recently determined that such a memorandum was not legally enforceable and that Federal law needed to be changed in order to make the previous agreement enforceable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>The purpose of <bill type="h" number="5778">H.R. 5778</bill> is to codify in Federal statute the Water and Sewage Authority's financial independence from the District.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And with that, Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, we have no further requests for time and no further speakers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank the gentleman from Indiana for his support and thank the entire committee for its support. I urge passage of this resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400098" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of <bill type="h" number="5778">H.R. 5778</bill>, the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority Independence Preservation Act. Representative VAN HOLLEN and I introduced this legislation to reaffirm the independence of the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="5778">H.R. 5778</bill> would amend the D.C. Home Rule Act to clarify that the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority, or WASA, is an independent agency with financial authority independent from the District of Columbia. After all, WASA is a regional entity, funded by ratepayers living in D.C., Maryland and Virginia.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In October 2000, Congress approved the conference report for the FY2001 District of Columbia appropriations, which contained language regarding the functions and responsibilities of the District of Columbia Chief Financial Officer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At that time, I engaged in a colloquy on the floor with then Chairman of the District of Columbia Appropriations Subcommittee Ernest Istook to clarify that the amendments to the CFO's responsibility's did not infringe upon the financial independence of the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority. Subsequently, a memorandum of understanding was signed between WASA and the District's CFO at the time Anthony Williams stating that the CFO would not exercise its authority over WASA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, it was recently determined that such a memorandum was not legally enforceable and that Federal law needed to be changed in order to make the previous agreement enforceable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Therefore, the purpose of <bill type="h" number="5778">H.R. 5778</bill> is to codify in Federal statute the Water and Sewer Authority's financial independence from the District.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I urge my colleagues to support passage of this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Davis) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="5778">H.R. 5778</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the bill, as amended, was passed.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
