<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1194282001" ordinal="25" title="EXPRESSING SUPPORT FOR THE GOALS OF VETERANS EDUCATE TODAY'S STUDENTS (VETS) DAY">
  <narrative>EXPRESSING SUPPORT FOR THE GOALS OF VETERANS EDUCATE TODAY'S STUDENTS (VETS) DAY -- (House of Representatives - November 05, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H12475]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400133" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and agree to the concurrent resolution (<bill type="hc" number="60">H. Con. Res. 60</bill>) expressing support for the goals of Veterans Educate Today's Students (VETS) Day, and for other purposes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the concurrent resolution.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the concurrent resolution is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="hc" number="60">H. Con. Res. 60</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas the United States has, in the course of its history, fought in many wars and conflicts to defend freedom and protect the interests of the Nation;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas millions of men and women have served the Nation in time of need as members of the Armed Forces;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the service of veterans has been vital to the Nation, and the sacrifices made by veterans and their families should not be forgotten with the passage of time;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas children throughout the Nation would benefit from programs that provide education about veterans and that instill a patriotic appreciation of the sacrifices made by veterans to defend freedom and to protect the interests of the Nation;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas efforts are being made throughout the Nation to devote November 10, or another date as may be designated, to an event known as Veterans Educate Today's Students Day; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas schools that participate in Veterans Educate Today's Students Day set aside a portion of the school day for the study, recognition, and appreciation of veterans: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved by the House of Representatives (the Senate concurring), &lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; That the Congress--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) recognizes the importance of veterans to the United States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) expresses support for the goals of Veterans Educate Today's Students Day;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) urges teachers, civic leaders, and veterans to carry out programs that educate children about the service of veterans and the sacrifices made by veterans and their families; and</narrative>
  <narrative> (4) encourages the people of the United States to participate in local and national activities recognizing Veterans Educate Today's Students Day and other events that foster education about the importance of veterans to the Nation.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from California (Mr. Filner) and the gentleman from Florida (Mr. Stearns) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from California.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400133" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, I am proud to bring to the floor another motion, another resolution, another action that will help us understand and better appreciate the contributions of our veterans from many wars. I want to thank Congressman Frank Pallone from New Jersey, who offers this resolution, and it will recognize our Nation's veterans for their sacrifice to our country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Currently, brave men and women who are fighting in missions throughout the world, including in Iraq and Afghanistan, do not have an exact avenue to let us know what has occurred or let us know how to appreciate or spread that appreciation to others in our society. This resolution will provide an avenue to educate our children about the sacrifice our servicemembers and their families are making.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Veterans Educate Today's Students Day will designate November 10 as VETS Day that would call for teachers, civic leaders, and veterans to carry out programs to educate children about the service of our Nation's veterans and their sacrifice. VETS Day is a day students can be taught to appreciate that because of our Nation's veterans we are able to enjoy the many freedoms that we take for granted. VETS Day should be the day we highlight veterans' service, American freedoms and pass on to our children  our American ideals. This is why I urge all my colleagues to join me in support of <bill type="hc" number="60">H. Con. Res. 60</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400388" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a simple resolution, just basically expressing support for the goals of Veterans Educate Today's Students Day, and for other purposes. I believe that in this case it will be November 10, the day before Veterans Day, when this will be celebrated. So obviously we need to support this resolution. It expresses the sense of the support of Congress for the goals of this VETS Day.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is noticeable that we recognize the importance of educating the children of today about this sacrificial history of veterans and their families so close to the national day of honor for those same veterans, which is on November 11, Veterans Day.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My colleagues, the number of veterans today is not as large as it used to be. The children in schools are less likely to have a parent, uncle or aunt who served in the military who could tell them about their experiences. My father served in Iwo Jima. He could tell me about his experience during that Pacific war. He has since been deceased. But I remember him talking about it and how much education it was for me. So those from the Greatest Generation who have passed from this world leave behind  a legacy of courage, loyalty, and honor. This legacy was picked up and continued by the next generation of veterans from the Korean War, the Vietnam War, military engagements in Haiti and Kosovo, Gulf War I, and today in the current conflicts in Afghanistan and in Iraq.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, Mr. Speaker, to set aside a specific day to educate our children about the sacrifice, the gallantry of our Nation's heroes demonstrates the importance of that service. It is because of them that we still have the freedom in this Chamber and the freedom we cherish today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, some school districts are already taking steps in this direction by inviting veterans to speak in their classrooms on Veterans Day and share their stories with the students and all the teachers. We should encourage this worthwhile educational activity in more schools across the Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I encourage my colleagues to join me in support of <bill type="hc" number="60">H. Con. Res. 60</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400133" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I am honored to yield such time as he may consume to the author of this resolution, a man who fights for veterans in his district and around the Nation, Mr. Pallone from New Jersey.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400308" topic="">
    <paragraph>Thank you, Mr. Chairman.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, as we approach Veterans Day on November 11 of this month, I want to say a few words about why I introduced House Concurrent Resolution 60 which, as you know, expresses support for the goals of Veterans Educate Today's Students Day, or VETS Day.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Throughout our Nation's history, millions of men and women have served the U.S. in times of need as members of the armed services, and these veterans and their families have made sacrifices that should not be forgotten with the passage of time. In the U.S., hundreds of memorials and monuments stand to honor those who have served in the armed services. While these tributes help remind Americans of the great sacrifices that were made to protect our freedoms, they can't educate today's youth the  way actual veterans can.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The VETS Day essentially would urge teachers and civic leaders to organize events and forums where students can interact with America's veterans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="hc" number="60">H. Con. Res. 60</bill> would encourage schools to set aside a portion of the day in November to allow veterans to answer students' questions while conveying important stories and lessons about their service. I actually have participated in these kinds of programs in my own district, Mr. Speaker; and I know how valuable they can be.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At a time when the men and women of our armed services are in harm's way, we should be educating today's students on the sacrifices these brave men and women make every day. The children of our Nation will benefit from programs that provide education about veterans and instill a patriotic appreciation of the sacrifices made by veterans to defend freedom and protect the interests of our Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, I think the most important thing is hearing firsthand accounts from veterans themselves, and that is the best way that students can better understand veterans' service and sacrifice. Again, I want to thank the chairman for his assistance and urge swift passage of this resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400388" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I will conclude by saying that obviously encouraging the people of the United States to participate in local and national activities, recognizing Veterans Educate Today's Students Day, or VETS Day, is something that we should remind all Americans about  how important it is and realize that it not only fosters education of our youth, but it also provides the veterans an opportunity to explain things perhaps that no one has ever  asked them or taken the time to say, what was it like? So in a way, it is an opportunity for them, as well as the students.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge adoption of this resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400133" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, again I want to thank Mr. Pallone for authoring this resolution. I know many of us who give speeches on Memorial Day and on Veterans Day note always that there are not many youth in the audience. And to bring these stories to our students, to our youth, is extremely important.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous support of this resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would also ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days in way to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on House Concurrent Resolution 60.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from California?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from California (Mr. Filner) that the House suspend the rules and agree to the concurrent resolution, <bill type="hc" number="60">H. Con. Res. 60</bill>.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the concurrent resolution was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
