<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1197997209" ordinal="42" title="OPEN GOVERNMENT ACT OF 2007">
  <narrative>OPEN GOVERNMENT ACT OF 2007 -- (House of Representatives - December 18, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H16788]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400074" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the Senate bill (<bill type="s" number="2488">S. 2488</bill>) to promote accessibility, accountability, and openness in Government by strengthening section 552 of title 5, United States Code (commonly referred to as the Freedom of Information Act), and for other purposes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the Senate bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the Senate bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="s" number="2488">S. 2488</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "Openness Promotes Effectiveness in our National Government Act of 2007" or the "OPEN Government Act of 2007".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. FINDINGS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Congress finds that--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) the Freedom of Information Act was signed into law on July 4, 1966, because the American people believe that--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) our constitutional democracy, our system of self-government, and our commitment to popular sovereignty depends upon the consent of the governed;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) such consent is not meaningful unless it is informed consent; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) as Justice Black noted in his concurring opinion in Barr v. Matteo (360 U.S. 564 (1959)), "The effective functioning of a free government like ours depends largely on the force of an informed public opinion. This calls for the widest possible understanding of the quality of government service rendered by all elective or appointed public officials or employees.";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) the American people firmly believe that our system of government must itself be governed by a presumption of openness;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) the Freedom of Information Act establishes a "strong presumption in favor of disclosure" as noted by the United States Supreme Court in United States Department of State v. Ray (502 U.S. 164 (1991)), a presumption that applies to all agencies governed by that Act;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) "disclosure, not secrecy, is the dominant objective of the Act," as noted by the United States Supreme Court in Department of Air Force v. Rose (425 U.S. 352 (1976));&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) in practice, the Freedom of Information Act has not always lived up to the ideals of that Act; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (6) Congress should regularly review section 552 of title 5, United States Code (commonly referred to as the Freedom of Information Act), in order to determine whether further changes and improvements are necessary to ensure that the Government remains open and accessible to the American people and is always based not upon the "need to know" but upon the fundamental "right to know".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 3. PROTECTION OF FEE STATUS FOR NEWS MEDIA.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Section 552(a)(4)(A)(ii) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</narrative>
  <narrative> "In this clause, the term `a representative of the news media' means any person or entity that gathers information of potential interest to a segment of the public, uses its editorial skills to turn the raw materials into a distinct work, and distributes that work to an audience. In this clause, the term `news' means information that is about current events or that would be of current interest to the public. Examples of news-media entities are television or radio stations broadcasting to the  public at large and publishers of periodicals (but only if such entities qualify as disseminators of `news') who  make their products available for purchase by or subscription by or free distribution to the general public. These examples are not all-inclusive. Moreover, as methods of news delivery evolve (for example, the adoption of the electronic dissemination of newspapers through telecommunications services), such alternative</narrative>
  <narrative> "(l) FOIA Public Liaisons shall report to the agency Chief FOIA Officer and shall serve as supervisory officials to whom a requester under this section can raise concerns about the service the requester has received from the FOIA Requester Center, following an initial response from the FOIA Requester Center Staff. FOIA Public Liaisons shall be responsible for assisting in reducing delays, increasing transparency and understanding of the status of requests, and assisting in the resolution of  disputes.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Effective Date.--The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 11. REPORT ON PERSONNEL POLICIES RELATED TO FOIA.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Office of Personnel Management shall submit to Congress a report that examines--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) whether changes to executive branch personnel policies could be made that would--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) provide greater encouragement to all Federal employees to fulfill their duties under section 552 of title 5, United States Code; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) enhance the stature of officials administering that section within the executive branch;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) whether performance of compliance with section 552 of title 5, United States Code, should be included as a factor in personnel performance evaluations for any or all categories of Federal employees and officers;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) whether an employment classification series specific to compliance with sections 552 and 552a of title 5, United States Code, should be established;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) whether the highest level officials in particular agencies administering such sections should be paid at a rate of pay equal to or greater than a particular minimum rate; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) whether other changes to personnel policies can be made to ensure that there is a clear career advancement track for individuals interested in devoting themselves to a career in compliance with such sections; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (6) whether the executive branch should require any or all categories of Federal employees to undertake awareness training of such sections.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 12. REQUIREMENT TO DESCRIBE EXEMPTIONS AUTHORIZING DELETIONS OF MATERIAL PROVIDED UNDER FOIA.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Section 552(b) of title 5, United States Code, is amended in the matter after paragraph (9)--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in the second sentence, by inserting after "amount of information deleted" the following: ", and the exemption under which the deletion is made,"; and</narrative>
  <narrative> (2) in the third sentence, by inserting after "amount of the information deleted" the following: ", and the exemption under which the deletion is made,".&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Missouri (Mr. Clay) and the gentleman from Virginia (Mr. Davis) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Missouri.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400074" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members have 5 legislative days in which to revise and extend their remarks.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Missouri?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400074" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise today in support of final passage of <bill type="s" number="2488">S. 2488</bill>, the Openness Promotes Effectiveness in Our National Government Act of 2007, or the OPEN Government Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill is a companion measure to legislation that I introduced earlier this session, <bill type="h" number="1309">H.R. 1309</bill>, the Freedom of Information Act Amendments of 2007, which was passed by the House in March. After months of negotiations between both Chambers, <bill type="s" number="2488">S. 2488</bill> provides a strong, reasonable and bipartisan approach to streamlining the FOIA process and increasing transparency in government.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Two key provisions within the OPEN Government Act include expanding access to attorneys' fees for citizens who successfully challenge an agency's denial of information, along with the creation of a new FOIA tracking system for pending requests.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, the bill will require agencies to disclose the type of FOIA exemptions used to redact specific information sought after in many requests.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Lastly, the bill will establish a government-wide ombudsman to help reduce the number of requests that are eventually resolved through costly and time-consuming litigation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="2488">S. 2488</bill> provides actual access to government information to which the American people are entitled. I want to thank all of the Members and staff who have contributed to the development of this legislation. I urge my colleagues to support its passage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400098" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of <bill type="s" number="2488">S. 2488</bill>, legislation to reform the process for the public to request and receive information under the Freedom of Information Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For 40 years, FOIA has ensured the public's access to government records. The 1966 act replaced the old need-to-know standard with today's right-to-know practice, placing the burden on the government to justify any need for secrecy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, the FOIA process has recently struggled to keep up with the public's demand for documents. Since 2002, FOIA requests have increased dramatically. This additional volume has delayed processing and created backlogs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Legislation designed to streamline and improve the FOIA process was championed last Congress by Mr. Smith from Texas. His bill moved through subcommittee to the full committee with the assistance of the chairman of the Government Management Subcommittee, Mr. Platts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, President Bush issued an executive order in December 2005 which adopted many of the process improvements contained in Mr. Smith's legislation, making FOIA operations more citizen-centric and results oriented.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This Congress, the majority took this bill and made additional changes but moved beyond process reforms and into substantive changes to FOIA policy. Although I had a number of concerns  with the House legislation, I supported it in an effort to improve FOIA overall. In the intervening months since the House passed its version, we have been able to work with the Senate and the administration to improve the House bill and make it more balanced. I urge  my colleagues to support this compromise legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400074" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would like to thank the gentleman from Virginia, the ranking member, for working with the majority on this important piece of legislation and getting this product to the floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At this time, Mr. Speaker, I would also like to thank our esteemed chairman of the Oversight and Government Reform Committee, Mr. Waxman, for his leadership on shepherding this bill through the Congress and would like to recognize the gentleman from California for such time as he may consume.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400425" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I thank the gentleman for yielding to me and I want to congratulate him on this accomplishment. This is a very good bill. Many people have played an important role in getting this bill to us today, and none any less than the chairman of the subcommittee who has shepherded it through to this point.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise in support of the OPEN Government Act. The bill contains important provisions to improve public access to government records. This year the House of Representatives passed a series of good government bills to improve openness and accountability in the executive branch. These bills include legislation to increase access to Presidential records, improve contractor accountability, strengthen whistleblower protections, disclose information about donors to Presidential libraries, and enhance  the independence of agency inspectors general.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill, <bill type="s" number="2488">S. 2488</bill>, is the first part of this reform agenda that Congress will enact into law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senate bill is not as strong as the House-passed bill. It does not include a provision which I thought was a key one establishing a presumption that government records should be released to the public unless there is a good reason to keep them secret. But the legislation does include important reforms to the Freedom of Information Act, our Nation's best-known and most widely used open government law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The provisions in this bill will help FOIA requesters obtain responses to their requests, reduce backlog at all agencies, and increase transparency in agency compliance, improve access to attorneys' fees for requesters who are improperly denied information, and provide an alternative to litigation for requesters who are facing delay or denials.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Bush administration has an obsession with secrecy. Over the last 7 years, it has systematically undermined our open government laws, while radically expanding its powers to operate in secret. Government today has more power than ever to peer into the private lives of American citizens; yet American citizens know less and less about what their government is actually doing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It will take a concerted effort over many years to peel back this curtain of secrecy. We need to restore the presumption that government records belong to the taxpayer. We need more certain deadlines and stronger penalties if this legislation makes little headway in reducing FOIA delays. And we still need to enact the other good government reforms that this body has already passed but that remain stalled in the Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But this bill is a good first step. I am proud that this Congress is fighting for the public's right to know and urge adoption of this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400098" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, before I yield to my friend from Texas, I also want to thank Mr. Clay, the subcommittee chairman, for helping to mold this and bring it to the floor; Mr. Turner from Ohio, who is the ranking member; Mr. Platts; and of course Chairman Waxman for his leadership on this issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me also add, on the majority staff, Anna Laitan has taken a lead role, and we appreciate the work of she and other staff members. And on the minority staff, Mason Allinger, Chas Phillips and Ellen Brown for their work on this.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield such time as he may consume to the gentleman from Texas (Mr. Smith).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400381" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman from Virginia (Mr. Davis) not only for yielding me time, but also for his favorable mention a few minutes ago when he was speaking.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I strongly support the Openness Promotes Effectiveness in our National Government Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation gives the public more information and better insight into the workings of the government by strengthening the Freedom of Information Act, called FOIA. FOIA performs a vital check and balance on the Federal branch. It protects our open system of government and ensures that the government responds as it should to the American people. Unfortunately, the process for obtaining information is overly burdensome and Federal agencies have become less and less responsive to the requests  for information. This deters citizens from obtaining information to which they are entitled.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Taxpayers should have the opportunity to obtain information from the Federal Government quickly and easily. This legislation contains several provisions similar to those in a bill I introduced last March. These include provisions regarding recovery of attorneys' fees, penalties for agencies that do not comply within the specified FOIA time limits, and additional agency reporting requirements.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am pleased that the bill under consideration today creates a more open government without threatening national security or invading personal privacy. The ability to obtain records from the Federal Government is one of the fundamental rights of the American people. When the government closes the doors on information, the people cannot monitor their government. Democracy is based on the people's right to know. That is why I support the Freedom of Information Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this bill rightly makes it easier for citizens to get answers to their requests for information, and that's why I hope all of my colleagues will support it.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400074" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400098" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I want to just take a moment to highlight some of the improvements that have been made to this legislation since the House-passed version last March.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, we clarified the definition of news media for purposes of fee waiver requests. New methods for gathering and delivering news are constantly developing. The definition of news, indeed, the definition of a journalist is evolving rapidly. We provided a balanced framework for making that determination, one that we think makes sense in the era of new media.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second, this legislation raises the threshold for the recovery of attorneys' fees, compared to what was included in the House-passed bill. The new threshold is a step in the right direction, but I remained concerned the threshold in <bill type="s" number="2488">S. 2488</bill> is still too low. I hope we'll continue to take a close look at the substance of this provision because ultimately attorneys' fees come out of the taxpayers' pockets.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, I am pleased to note the provision repealing the so-called Ashcroft memorandum was eliminated, and I know this was also of concern to the gentleman from Texas. The Ashcroft memorandum established that the administration would defend agency decisions to withhold records under a FOIA exemption if the decision was supported by a sound legal basis, replacing the pre-9/11 Janet Reno standard of always releasing information absent foreseeable harm. I think preservation of the Ashcroft policy  is the right policy to adopt in the current environment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As I've stated since we began work on this legislation, improving the procedural aspects of FOIA should be our goal. It's something we all agree on, and this bill moves us closer to that. Although the debate on the appropriate balance between open access and protected records will go on, I trust we'll continue to try to balance national security with the vital principles of open government.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Once again, I urge my colleagues to support this legislation. I again want to commend the gentleman from Missouri for his work on this.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400074" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, in closing, let me thank all of my colleagues too for the work that they did to craft this piece of legislation that I think goes a long way in improving FOIA. And <bill type="s" number="2488">S. 2488</bill> provides a strong, reasonable, and bipartisan approach to streamlining the FOIA process and increasing transparency in our government. It also provides actual access to government information to which the American people are entitled.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, let me thank all of my colleagues for their support and help and effort on this legislation. And I urge my colleagues to support its passage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Missouri (Mr. Clay) that the House suspend the rules and pass the Senate bill, <bill type="s" number="2488">S. 2488</bill>.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the Senate bill was passed.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
