<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1213718403" ordinal="68" title="STATUS REPORT ON CURRENT LEVELS OF ON-BUDGET SPENDING AND REVENUES FOR FISCAL YEARS 2008 AND 2009 AND THE 5-YEAR PERIOD FY 2009 THROUGH FY 2013">
  <narrative>STATUS REPORT ON CURRENT LEVELS OF ON-BUDGET SPENDING AND REVENUES FOR FISCAL YEARS 2008 AND 2009 AND THE 5-YEAR PERIOD FY 2009 THROUGH FY 2013 -- (House of Representatives - June 17, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H5461]</narrative>
  <chair> Under a previous order of the House, the gentleman from South Carolina (Mr. Spratt) is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I am transmitting a status report on the current levels of on-budget spending and revenues for fiscal years 2008 and 2009 and for the 5-year period of fiscal years 2009 through 2013. This report is necessary to facilitate the application of sections 302 and 311 of the Congressional Budget Act and sections 301 and 302 of <bill type="sc" number="70">S. Con. Res. 70</bill>, the Concurrent Resolution on the Budget for Fiscal Year 2009.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The term "current level" refers to the amounts of spending and revenues estimated for each fiscal year based on laws enacted or awaiting the President's signature.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The first table in the report compares the current levels of total budget authority, outlays, and revenues with the aggregate levels set by <bill type="sc" number="70">S. Con. Res. 70</bill>. This comparison is needed to enforce section 311(a) of the Budget Act, which creates a point of order against measures that would breach the budget resolution's aggregate levels.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The second table compares the current levels of budget authority and outlays for each authorizing committee with the "section 302(a)" allocations made under <bill type="sc" number="70">S. Con. Res. 70</bill> for fiscal years 2008 and 2009 and fiscal years 2009 through 2013. This comparison is needed to enforce section 302(f) of the Budget Act, which creates a point of order against measures that would breach the section 302(a) discretionary action allocation of new budget authority for the committee that reported the measure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The third table compares the current levels of discretionary appropriations for fiscal years 2008 and 2009 with the "section 302(a)" allocation of discretionary budget authority and outlays to the Appropriations Committee. The Appropriations Committee shortly will be distributing this section 302(a) allocation among its subcommittees, creating 302(b) suballocations. At that time, a point of order under section 302(f) of the Budget Act will become applicable to measures that would breach the  applicable section 302(b) suballocation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The fourth table gives the current level for fiscal years 2010 and 2011 for accounts identified for advance appropriations under section 302 of <bill type="sc" number="70">S. Con. Res. 70</bill>. This list is needed to enforce section 302 of the budget resolution, which creates a point of order against appropriation bills that contain advance appropriations that: (i) are not identified in the statement of managers; or (ii) would cause the aggregate amount of such appropriations to exceed the level specified in the resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enactment of measures providing new budget authority for FY 2008 in excess of $5,395 million (if not already included in the current level estimate) would cause FY 2008 budget authority to exceed the appropriate level set by <bill type="sc" number="70">S. Con. Res. 70</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enactment of measures providing new budget authority for FY 2009 in excess of $982,972 million (if not already included in the current level estimate) would cause FY 2009 budget authority to exceed the appropriate level set by <bill type="sc" number="70">S. Con. Res. 70</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enactment of measures providing new outlays for FY 2008 in excess of $2,653 million (if not already included in the current level estimate) would cause FY 2008 outlays to exceed the appropriate level set by <bill type="sc" number="70">S. Con. Res. 70</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enactment of measures providing new outlays for FY 2009 in excess of $615,816 million (if not already included in the current level estimate) would cause FY 2009 outlays to exceed the appropriate level set by <bill type="sc" number="70">S. Con. Res. 70</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enactment of measures resulting in revenue reduction for FY 2008 in excess of $4,000 million (if not already included in the current level estimate) would cause FY2008 revenues to fall below the appropriate levels set by <bill type="sc" number="70">S. Con. Res. 70</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enactment of measures resulting in revenue reduction for FY 2009 in excess of $67,755 million (if not already included in the current level estimate) would cause FY2009 revenues to fall below the appropriate levels set by <bill type="sc" number="70">S. Con. Res. 70</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enactment of measures resulting in revenue reduction for the period of fiscal years 2009 through 2013 in excess of $336,570 million (if not already included in the current level estimate) would cause revenues to fall below the appropriate levels set by <bill type="sc" number="70">S. Con. Res. 70</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>[Budget Authority in Millions of Dollars]</paragraph>
    <paragraph>28,852</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enacted advances:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Employment and Training Administration</paragraph>
    <paragraph>---</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Job Corps</paragraph>
    <paragraph>---</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Education for the Disadvantaged</paragraph>
    <paragraph>---</paragraph>
    <paragraph>School Improvement</paragraph>
    <paragraph>---</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Children and Family Services (Head Start)</paragraph>
    <paragraph>---</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Special Education</paragraph>
    <paragraph>---</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Career, Technical and Adult Education</paragraph>
    <paragraph>---</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Payment to Postal Service</paragraph>
    <paragraph>---</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Tenant-based Rental Assistance</paragraph>
    <paragraph>---</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Project-based Rental Assistance</paragraph>
    <paragraph>---&lt;p&gt;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>n.a.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enacted advances:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Corporation for Public Broadcasting</paragraph>
    <paragraph>---&lt;p&gt;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>U.S. CONGRESS,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington, DC, June 17, 2008.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dear Mr. Chairman: The enclosed report shows the effects of Congressional action on the fiscal year 2008 budget and is current through June 13, 2008. This report is submitted under section 308(b) and in aid of section 311 of the Congressional Budget Act, as amended.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The estimates of budget authority, outlays, and revenues are consistent with the technical and economic assumptions of <bill type="sc" number="70">S. Con. Res. 70</bill>, the Concurrent Resolution on the Budget for Fiscal Year 2009, as approved  by the Senate and the House of Representatives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since my last letter, dated January 29, 2008, the Congress has cleared several acts that affect budget authority, outlays, and revenues. Please see footnote 1 of the accompanying report for a list of those acts. This is CBO's first current level report since the adoption of <bill type="sc" number="70">S. Con. Res. 70</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Robert A. Sunshine</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enclosure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>U.S. CONGRESS,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>CONGRESSIONAL BUDGET OFFICE,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington, DC, June 17, 2008.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR MR. CHAIRMAN: The enclosed report shows the effects of Congressional action on the fiscal year 2009 budget and is current through June 13, 2008. This report is submitted under section 308(b) and in aid of section 311 of the Congressional Budget Act, as amended.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The estimates of budget authority, outlays, and revenues are consistent with the technical and economic assumptions of <bill type="sc" number="70">S. Con. Res. 70</bill>, the Concurrent Resolution on the Budget for Fiscal Year 2009, as approved by the Senate and the House of Representatives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is CBO's first current level report for fiscal year 2009.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enclosure.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
