<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1210003202" ordinal="14" title="FOREIGN SERVICE MEMBER REST">
  <narrative>FOREIGN SERVICE MEMBER REST -- (House of Representatives - May 05, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H3024]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400423" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="3658">H.R. 3658</bill>) to amend the Foreign Service Act of 1980 to permit rest and recuperation travel to United States territories for members of the Foreign Service.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="3658">H.R. 3658</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. INCLUSION OF UNITED STATES TERRITORIES AS ELIGIBLE FOR REST AND RECUPERATION TRAVEL FOR MEMBERS OF THE FOREIGN SERVICE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; The Foreign Service Act of 1980 is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in section 901(6)(B) (22 U.S.C. 4081(6)(B)), by inserting after "United States" the following: "or its territories, including American Samoa, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and the United States Virgin Islands"; and</narrative>
  <narrative> (2) in section 903(b) (22 U.S.C. 4083(b)), by striking ", its territories and possessions, or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico" and inserting "or its territories, including American Samoa, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and the United States Virgin Islands".&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from California (Ms. Watson) and the gentleman from Texas (Mr. Poe) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentlewoman from California.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400423" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members  may have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the resolution under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from California?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400423" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in strong support of this resolution and yield myself as much time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to recognize our colleague from Puerto Rico (Mr. Fortu&#xF1;o) and the distinguished chairman of the Subcommittee on Asia, the Pacific and the Global Environment, Mr. Faleomavaega, for putting forward a very important measure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="3658">H.R. 3658</bill> amends the Foreign Service Act to give the Secretary of State needed authority to ensure that foreign service officers from U.S. territories, including Puerto Rico, American Samoa, Guam and the U.S. Virgin Islands, are provided the same benefits as their colleagues from the 50 States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Currently, the State Department provides air transportation home from overseas assignments for the purpose of rest and recuperation to all foreign service officers who reside in any of the 50 States. However, current law does not permit the department to provide the same benefit to foreign service officers who reside in any of the territories.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The State Department has informed us that they do not have any objection to this measure. The cost of implementing it would be very small as it would impact very few foreign service officers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this important resolution that would rectify an inequity in the treatment of our dedicated foreign service officers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400652" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in strong support of <bill type="h" number="3658">H.R. 3658</bill>, introduced by my good friend from Puerto Rico (Mr. Fortu&#xF1;o).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill will make a long overdue clarification to the Foreign Service Act that will allow American foreign service officers to take rest and recuperation travel, commonly referred to as R&amp;R, in American Samoa, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands and, of course, the United States Virgin Islands.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>American diplomatic personnel who serve at hardship posts overseas are allowed to take State Department-funded R&amp;R travel either at locations abroad or locations in the United States. But the phrase "locations in the United States" has been interpreted by the State Department regulation to exclude U.S. territories for some reason. That interpretation has placed a distinctly unfair burden on foreign service officers from those territories who might wish to spend their R&amp;R with families at home.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It also puts U.S. territories at a disadvantage compared to other destinations abroad or in the United States where our diplomatic personnel may want to travel to rest and recuperate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to commend our colleagues who have sponsored this legislation to remove this inadvertent and unfair provision. <bill type="h" number="3658">H.R. 3658</bill> is a worthy bill that deserves our unanimous support.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400423" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no further requests for time, and I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400652" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield such time as he may consume to the gentleman from Puerto Rico (Mr. Fortu&#xF1;o), the author of this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. FORTU&#xD1;O. I thank my colleague.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to begin by thanking Chairman Berman for ushering <bill type="h" number="3658">H.R. 3658</bill> through the committee process. In his short time as chairman, Mr. Berman has shown intelligence, generosity and strong bipartisan spirit, the same leadership qualities displayed by his predecessor, the irreplaceable Tom Lantos.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank my good friend, Ranking Member Ileana Ros-Lehtinen, as well. I continue to marvel at her devotion to her constituents in south Florida and at her tireless efforts to help light the lantern of freedom in dark places around the world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also want to thank the representatives from the other U.S. territories, all of whom are original cosponsors of <bill type="h" number="3658">H.R. 3658</bill>. And I want to thank you, Ms. Watson, and you, Judge Poe, for your support for this bill. I note that Ms. Watson served as a U.S. Ambassador to Micronesia and therefore brings a special expertise to this subject.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the specific purpose of <bill type="h" number="3658">H.R. 3658</bill> is to permit Foreign Servicemembers to take rest and recuperation travel, known as R&amp;R, in the five U.S. territories. The broader objective of the bill is to ensure that Federal employees from the U.S. territories enjoy the same rights and privileges as their fellow citizens from the 50 States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am pleased that the American Foreign Service Association supports <bill type="h" number="3658">H.R. 3658</bill>, and that the State Department does not oppose its passage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the Foreign Service Act lists the instances in which the State Department may pay the travel-related costs of Foreign Servicemembers. One section of the FSA states that the Department may pay the travel costs incurred by Foreign Service personnel for what is known as home leave. The purpose of the home leave is to ensure that Foreign Servicemembers who have been sent abroad undergo a period of reorientation to the United States. The FSA provides that home leave may be taken  in the 50 States and the U.S. territories.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Another section of the FSA states that the Department may pay the costs incurred by Foreign Servicemembers for R&amp;R travel. Unlike home leave, which is granted to all Foreign Servicemembers who serve abroad, R&amp;R is granted only to those stationed at hardship posts. Under the current FSA, R&amp;R may only be taken in locations in the United States. State Department regulations have interpreted this phrase to exclude U.S. territories.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, there is no principled basis for allowing Foreign Servicemembers to take home leave but not R&amp;R in the U.S. territories, and <bill type="h" number="3658">H.R. 3658</bill> amends the FSA to eliminate the distinction. Just as they proudly serve in our Nation's Armed Forces, residents of the U.S. territories also represent this great country abroad as diplomats. These men and women from the territories take the same risks and endure the same long absences from their families as their colleagues from the States. Making  certain that our laws treat these public servants on equal terms is the only right thing to do.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask you to consider the case of Mr. Ramon Negron. Mr. Negron is a U.S. citizen born and raised in Puerto Rico, a graduate of West Point, and a lieutenant colonel in the Army Reserve. Mr. Negron currently serves as a political economic officer at the U.S. Interests section in Havana, Cuba, which is a hardship post. Mr. Negron's next posting, to begin this summer, is as the Embassy Office Director in Basra, Iraq. It is neither sensible, nor fair, that under current law the State  Department will not cover the cost of airfare so this U.S. citizen, U.S. soldier and U.S. diplomat can travel home to Puerto Rico to be with his family before leaving for the Middle East. <bill type="h" number="3658">H.R. 3658</bill> will correct this disparity.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400423" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400652" topic="">
    <paragraph>I would inquire of the gentlewoman if she has any other speakers.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400423" topic="">
    <paragraph>I have no other speakers.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="3658">H.R. 3658</bill>, to amend the Foreign Service Act of 1980 to permit rest and recuperation travel to United States territories for members of the Foreign Service, sponsored by my good friend and neighbor, Mr. Fortu&#xF1;o of Puerto Rico.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the Foreign Service Act unfortunately is not consistent in the way it treats citizens from the mainland and those from the territories. While it allows for the State Department to pay for Foreign Service members to return home, to any of the 50 states or U.S. territories, after being posted abroad, it only permits residents of the 50 states who are at hardship posts, such as Iraq and Afghanistan, to be granted R &amp; R for a period of time while posted.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill, at its core, is about equal and fair treatment for residents of the U.S. territories. When most of us hear the word home, we have a clear picture in our head of where that is. But for these Foreign Service members, it is not that simple. Under current law, these diplomats must pay their own way if they want to visit their family and friends back home in the territories, while diplomats from the states have their travel costs covered.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although these members are from a U.S. territory, they are our fellow citizens and commit their lives to the diplomatic causes. They join for the love of their country and risk their safety in dangerous posts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill before us today would eliminate this unequal and unfair treatment between Foreign Service members who reside in the territories and those that reside in the states. I urge my colleagues to support passage of <bill type="h" number="3658">H.R. 3658</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400652" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400423" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from California (Ms. Watson) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="3658">H.R. 3658</bill>.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400239" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I object to the vote on the ground that a quorum is not present and make the point of order that a quorum is not present.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this motion will be postponed.</chair>
  <chair>The point of no quorum is considered withdrawn.</chair>
</record>
