<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1207152003" ordinal="14" title="CONGRATULATING TYLER HANSBROUGH OF POPLAR BLUFF, MISSOURI">
  <narrative>CONGRATULATING TYLER HANSBROUGH OF POPLAR BLUFF, MISSOURI -- (House of Representatives - April 02, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H1893]</narrative>
  <narrative>(Mrs. EMERSON asked and was given permission to address the House for 1 minute and to revise and extend her remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400121" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today to congratulate our Southeast Missouri favorite son, Tyler Hansbrough of Poplar Bluff, Missouri, for his unanimous selection to the AP All-American First Team for collegiate basketball. Mr. Hansbrough has earned this honor through his excellence both on the basketball court and off.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If anything, his receipt of this award ought to focus us on Mr. Hansbrough's character, not on his scoring statistics. This young man recently earned rare praise from long-time coach Rick Pitino, who remarked, "I haven't seen a guy play every possession like that in a long time. I have actually never seen it."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Not only is Tyler a leader, he is a leader by example. His work ethic has improved players, coaches and fans of the game at every level he has played.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Hansbrough takes his obligation of leadership seriously. His coach at North Carolina, Roy Williams, has called him the most focused player he has ever coached. All of these attributes result in Mr. Hansbrough serving as a role model for his teammates and for every aspiring student-athlete in the Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Undoubtedly Mr. Hansbrough will continue to succeed in basketball. I believe he will continue to succeed in life, too. As he provides a national example of dedication, teamwork, effort and leadership, I congratulate Tyler Hansbrough on his selection as a First Team All-American. I also commend him for the contributions he makes as a role model to millions of Americans who aspire to the example he has set.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
