<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1201539602" ordinal="19" title="HONORING THE TEXAS WATER DEVELOPMENT BOARD">
  <narrative>HONORING THE TEXAS WATER DEVELOPMENT BOARD -- (House of Representatives - January 28, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H465]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400204" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution (<bill type="hr" number="832">H. Res. 832</bill>) honoring the Texas Water Development Board on its selection as a recipient of the Environmental Protection Agency's 2007 Clean Water State Revolving Fund Performance and Innovation Award, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the resolution.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the resolution is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="hr" number="832">H. Res. 832</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas the Texas Water Development Board (TWDB) was honored as a 2007 recipient of the Environmental Protection Agency's Performance and Innovation in the SRF Creating Environmental Success (PISCES) Award on November 5, 2007;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Clean Water State Revolving Fund (CWSRF) program in Texas has been a front-runner and a precedent-setting program in wastewater management for many years, and its CWSRF leveraging practices as well as other established management practices are used by many other States as examples to enhance the management of their funds;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the CWSRF program in Texas has successfully awarded communities approximately $4,300,000,000 in low-interest loans to finance 472 water infrastructure projects across Texas;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas these projects, which serve approximately one-half of the population of Texas and treat about 2,100,000,000 gallons per day of wastewater, provide direct environmental and public health benefits;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the TWDB is proposing to increase the marketability and demand for the CWSRF program by pursuing the use of extended loan terms beyond the authorized 20-year term to a 30-year term;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the TWDB developed a State Revolving Fund Information Management System to satisfy the need for more timely and accurate information on the status of water and wastewater loan projects as those projects move through the phases of the preapplication process and beyond;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the TWDB has actively encouraged asset management as evidenced by its creation of a Best Management Practices Guide for water conservation;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the TWDB established direct authority and responsibility for the coordination of the CWSRF program by creating State Revolving Fund Coordinator positions;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the TWDB's Intended Use Plan Post-Mortem Review was lauded for identifying various activities that will be used in improving future CWSRF Intended Use Plan development processes;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the TWDB holds interoffice planning meetings that serve as monthly forums to provide for interoffice discussion on State Revolving Fund policies, procedures and processes, and deadlines;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the TWDB assigned cross-functional, multidisciplinary teams to manage project performance review from application phase through construction, and these teams are responsible for identifying and developing solutions to project circumstances that may cause a project to fall behind its schedule; and</narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas the TWDB was also noted for its outstanding regional water planning activities, best management practices in the areas of nonpoint source pollution funding, instream flow program, work with the United States Army Corps of Engineers to amend the Federal water resources development legislation to further enhance its watershed approach, funding of water reuse projects, agricultural and municipal water conservation projects, and water conservation education activities: Now, therefore, be  it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the House of Representatives--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) honors the Texas Water Development Board on its selection by the Environmental Protection Agency as a 2007 Performance and Innovation in the SRF Creating Environmental Success (PISCES) Award recipient; and</narrative>
  <narrative> (2) recognizes the importance of adequate investment and management of water resources in sustainable development, including environmental integrity and human health and overall quality of life in the United States.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from Texas (Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson) and the gentleman from Wisconsin (Mr. Petri) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentlewoman from Texas.</chair>
  <chair/>
  <speaking speaker="400204" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days in which to revise and extend their remarks and to include extraneous materials on <bill type="hr" number="832">H. Res. 832</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from Texas?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400204" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Texas Water Development Board was created in 1957 with the mission "to provide leadership, planning, financial assistance, information and education for the conservation and responsible development of water for Texas." Additionally, the Texas Water Development Board provides water planning, data collection and dissemination, financial assistance, and technical assistance services to the citizens of the State.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Texas Water Development Board was selected this past November as a recipient of the Environmental Protection Agency's 2007 Performance and Innovation in the Clean Water State Revolving Fund Creating Environmental Success Award at the Council of Infrastructure Financing Authorities annual conference in Denver, Colorado.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this is extraordinary for Texas because normally we get on the other end of things of this sort. But the Texas Water Development Board provides loans and grants to local governments and entities for various projects.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The financial assistance programs are funded through State-backed bonds, a combination of State bond proceeds and Federal grant funds, or limited appropriated funds.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To date, the Texas Water Development Board has successfully awarded communities approximately $4.3 billion in low-interest loans to finance 472 water infrastructure projects across the State of Texas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The State of Texas currently administers the second largest Clean Water State Revolving Fund in the Nation, second only to New York. In 2007 alone, the Texas Water Development Board made 32 loan commitments through the Clean Water State Revolving Fund, for a total of $692 million.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Of the 32 total commitments made out of the Clean Water State Revolving Fund in 2007, approximately 8 percent of the funds were committed to disadvantaged communities, and 10 percent were committed to small communities with populations consisting of less than 10,000 residents.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Texas Water Development Board is working with the EPA to strengthen the program, including the ability to offer extended term financing up to 30 years to help communities that may need more time to repay the loan. Additionally, the Clean Water State Revolving Fund program is being proactively marketed to ensure that all Texas communities are aware of the benefits offered by this program. And, Mr. Speaker, I am delighted to be able to honor such a vital organization in the State of Texas.  It's sometimes a rare occasion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Texas Water Development Board is recognized as a leader in the State water planning and water-related infrastructure financing. I would like to thank my colleagues from the Texas delegation for joining me in this resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400318" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the resolution before us, House Resolution 832, recognizes the Texas Water Development Board on its selection as the 2007 recipient of the Environmental Protection Agency's Performance and Innovation in the State Revolving Fund Creating Environmental Success Award. This award is given to one State in each of the 10 different EPA regions and highlights successfully designed projects that further the goal of clean water.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Texas Water Development Board was created in 1957 to provide leadership, planning, financial assistance, information and education for the conservation and responsible development of water for Texas. Its mission is a vital part of Texas' overall vision, mission, and goals related to maintaining the State's natural resources, health, and its economic development.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To accomplish its goals for the State's water resources and for providing the portable water and wastewater services, the Texas Water Development Board provides water planning, data collection and dissemination, financial assistance, and technical assistance services to the citizens of the State of Texas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The tremendous population growth that the State has had and will continue to experience and the continual threat of severe drought only intensify the need for the Texas Water Development Board to accomplish its goals in an effective and efficient manner.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Clean Water Act State Revolving Loan Fund in Texas has awarded communities more than $4 billion in low-interest loans to finance 472 water infrastructure projects across the State of Texas. These projects serve approximately one-half of the population of that State, treat about 2 billion gallons per day of wastewater, and provide direct environmental and public health benefits to Texans at large.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In Texas, the Northwest Water Reuse Initiative consists of a $10.7 million project in El Paso County to deliver treated wastewater for reuse to agricultural, commercial, industrial and residential users from El Paso's Northwest Water Treatment Plant.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Texas also financed a wastewater reclamation initiative to deliver reclaimed water from the city of Austin's Walnut Creek Wastewater Treatment Plant, the first step in the city's development of a transmission and distribution service, serving customers with reclaimed water.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This resolution recognizes the importance of Federal-State partnerships in addressing water resources needs in the United States, and specifically the effective and efficient manner in which the State of Texas is managing its State Revolving Loan Fund program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I encourage all Members to support this project.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, <bill type="hr" number="832">H. Res. 832</bill> recognizes the Texas Water Development Board on its selection as a 2007 recipient of the Environmental Protection Agency's Performance and Innovation in the State Revolving Fund Creating Environmental Success Award. (PISCES)</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This award is given to one State in each of the ten different EPA regions and highlights successfully designed projects that further the goal of clean water.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Texas Water Development Board (TWDB) was created in 1957 to provide leadership, planning, financial assistance, information, and education for the conservation and responsible development of water for Texas. Its mission is a vital part of Texas' overall vision, mission, and goals related to maintaining the State's natural resources, health and economic development.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To accomplish its goals for the State's water resources and for providing affordable water and wastewater services, the Texas Water Development Board provides water planning, data collection and dissemination, financial assistance and technical assistance services to the citizens of Texas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The tremendous population growth that the State of Texas has and will continue to experience, and the continual threat of severe drought, only intensify the need for the Texas Water Development Board to accomplish its goals in an effective and efficient manner.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Clean Water Act State Revolving Loan Fund in Texas has awarded communities more than $4 billion in low-interest loans to finance 472 water infrastructure projects across the State of Texas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These projects serve approximately one-half of the population of Texas, treat about 2 billion gallons per day of wastewater, and provide direct environmental and public health benefits to Texans at large.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In Texas, the Northwest Water Reuse Initiative consisted of a $10.7 million project in El Paso County to deliver treated wastewater for reuse to agricultural, commercial, industrial, and residential users from El Paso's Northwest Wastewater Treatment Plant.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Texas also financed a wastewater reclamation initiative to deliver reclaimed water from the City of Austin's Walnut Creek Wastewater Treatment Plant, the first step in the city's development of a transmission and distribution system serving customers with reclaimed water.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This resolution recognizes the importance of Federal-State partnerships in addressing water resources needs in the United States and specifically the effective and efficient manner in which the State of Texas is managing its State Revolving Loan Fund Program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I encourage all Members to support the legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="hr" number="832">H. Res. 832</bill>, honoring the Texas Water Development Board on its selection as a 2007 recipient of the Environmental Protection Agency's Performance and Innovation in the State Revolving Fund ("SRF") Creating Environmental Success Award. This resolution was introduced by my colleague from Texas (Ms. Johnson), who is Chairwoman of the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment of the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 2005, to recognize outstanding successes of the States' Clean Water State Revolving Fund programs, the Performance and Innovation in the SRF Creating Environmental Success Awards, or the "PISCES" awards, were created. The Awards recognize successfully designed projects or organizations that utilize exceptional planning, management, and financing to further the goals of clean and safe water for our citizens.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The PISCES award, which is biennially bestowed on one State entity per region, is an attempt to reward innovation and stewardship in meeting the Clean Water and wastewater needs of the Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 2007, the Region 6 recipient of this award was the Texas Water Development Board.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, I would be remiss if I failed to also recognize the Region 5 award winner--Minnesota's Agricultural Best Management Practices Loan Program, operated by the Minnesota Department of Agriculture through funds and assistance obtained through the Minnesota Public Finance Authority.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Texas Water Development Board has managed its funds exceptionally, awarding communities more than $4 billion in loans to finance more than 450 water infrastructure projects across the state. These projects help Texas treat more than two billion gallons of wastewater per day, resulting in significant environmental and health benefits.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Board has also been an active partner with the Committee and Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment--twice testifying before the Committee on issues ranging from the enormous nationwide need for wastewater infrastructure investment to the long-term stewardship of water resource measures through thoughtful, statewide watershed planning.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I support this resolution honoring Texas' water and environmental management, and urge my colleagues to agree to the resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400318" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400204" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no further requests for time, and I simply want to ask everyone to support the resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from Texas (Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson of Texas) that the House suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, <bill type="hr" number="832">H. Res. 832</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the resolution, as amended, was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The title of the resolution was amended so as to read:</chair>
  <chair>"Honoring the Texas Water Development Board on its selection as a 2007 recipient of the Environmental Protection Agency's Performance and Innovation in the SRF Creating Environmental Success Award".</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
