<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1179871463" ordinal="41" title="ALIEN SMUGGLING AND TERRORISM PREVENTION ACT OF 2007">
  <speaking speaker="400025" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="2399">H.R. 2399</bill>) to amend the Immigration and Nationality Act and title 18, United States Code, to combat the crime of alien smuggling and related activities, and for other purposes, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from California (Mr. Berman) and the gentleman from Florida (Mr. Keller) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400025" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and to include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from California?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400025" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this legislation gives Federal prosecutors and agents stronger enforcement weapons against the most pernicious forms of human smuggling, terrorism-related smuggling and smuggling that results in kidnapping, rape or an attempt to kill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill is based on a provision that has been added into <bill type="h" number="1684">H.R. 1684</bill>, the Homeland Security Department Reauthorization Act, in its committee markup. The supporters of that provision agreed to withdraw it from that bill so the Judiciary Committee, the committee of primary jurisdiction, could take a closer look.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The resulting bill amends both 8 U.S.C. 1324, the alien smuggling prohibition, and 18 U.S.C. 2237, the prohibition against failure to heave to, to provide for extraterritorial jurisdiction, increase maximum penalties for serious offenses and clarify the necessity defense that applies to legitimate maritime rescues.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill applies not just to human smuggling in the maritime context, but to all cross-border human smuggling. It provides appropriately tough penalties for the kind of serious smuggling offenses I've just described, while distinguishing those from other types of transport such as noncommercial efforts to reunify families. While these practices also violate our immigration laws, they do not fall into the same category of offense, and should not be treated as harshly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although the bill streamlines and strengthens the current offense language, it does not abandon existing case law that applies to alien smuggling offenses. For instance, it will remain a violation of Federal law both to bring illegal aliens to the United States and to bring other aliens across the border through places other than those designated as official entry ports. This is especially critical as Congress mandates that the Department of Homeland Security institute biometric entry and exit  systems. For an orderly and fair immigration system to work, people must come in through these sites.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also prevents the current list of illegal activities, smuggling, recruiting, transporting and harboring, without adding new activities, such as assisting aliens in their efforts to enter our country. Again, this preserves the distinction between true smuggling and the work of groups such as faith-based organizations, who seek to serve the alien community on humanitarian grounds.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because this important distinction is preserved, the Judiciary Committee believes the religious activities exception in current law is sufficient, and the bill doesn't expand it. The bill also preserves current law in treating the offense of helping to bring in one's close family members as a misdemeanor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also establishes for the first time in Federal law that it is illegal to transport persons under inhumane conditions, such as in an engine compartment, a storage compartment or other confined space; or overloaded or intentionally run ashore and grounded at high speed and left to scatter. Those kinds of inhumane practices have resulted in death or serious injury to numerous alien passengers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, the bill directs the Sentencing Commission to consider providing further sentencing enhancements for particularly egregious offenses. Such enhancements should reach the smuggling of aliens in a life-threatening manner, the abandonment of aliens in the desert or discharging them onto spits of land that will be submerged in a high tide, or those cases that involve the facilitation of terrorism.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I strongly urge my colleagues to support this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400212" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself as much time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise to discuss <bill type="h" number="2399">H.R. 2399</bill>, Alien Smuggling and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me address a few basic issues about this legislation. First of all, what is alien smuggling? What is the existing law? What are the changes that we're proposing? And what, if any, are the problems that we need to fix with regard to this issue of alien smuggling?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Well, let's begin with what is alien smuggling. Alien smuggling is the process whereby people often known as "coyotes" take someone from a country like Mexico and sneak them in, often under the cover of darkness, into the United States for an average fee currently of approximately $1,500 per person. It requires specialized skills; and folks often feel that they can't come over, say, from Mexico to California and bypass all the border security agents without having a coyote or alien smuggler  to help them. So they often have their family members pay the $1,500 fee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I wanted to know more about this, so I personally went to the San Diego-Mexico border and spent a week traveling around at 2, 3 in the morning with Border Patrol agents as they arrested illegals and alien smugglers as they came across the border. And I learned from the Border Patrol agents that their biggest frustration is that they have arrested the same alien smugglers more than 20 times. In fact, the agents I met with were so demoralized they had what's called a wall of shame.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And it's hard to see from where you sit, Mr. Speaker, but this is a wall showing over 200 photographs of alien smugglers who they have repeatedly arrested, some of them more than 20 times, such as Antonio Amparo Lopez. And it is currently the law that if you smuggle someone into the United States for financial gain you will be sent to Federal prison for a minimum of 3 years. And yet, agent after agent told me they arrest the same people and they weren't prosecuted by the local San Diego prosecutor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Well, the existing law, 3 years mandatory minimum if you smuggle someone into the United States. What does this bill do? It keeps the existing law at 3 years for smuggling someone in for financial gain, but adds some newer, stiffer penalties for certain people that you bring in. For example, if a smuggler brings someone in who is a known terrorist, then instead of being a mandatory 3 years in prison, you could be subjected to up to 30 years in prison.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And here is the challenge that I want to talk a little bit about this issue and why it's so important: When Attorney General Gonzales came before the Judiciary Committee on April 6, 2006, I relayed to him the story that I just relayed to you, Mr. Speaker, about the problems with these alien smugglers not being prosecuted. I happen to have a transcript, and I said on April 6 to the Attorney General, "The pathetic  failure of your U.S. attorney in San  Diego to prosecute alien smugglers who have been arrested 20 times is a demoralizing slap in the face to Border Patrol agents who risk their lives every day. It also undermines the credibility that you and President Bush have when you talk tough about enforcing laws. And it renders meaningless the laws this Congress passes to crack down on alien smugglers."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Then I asked him, "What, if anything, will you do to see that the U.S. attorney in San Diego prosecutes these alien smugglers, at least those that have been repeatedly arrested by Border Patrol agents?"</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is what the Attorney General said: "I'm aware of what you're talking about with respect to the San Diego situation and we are looking into it. We're asking all U.S. attorneys, particularly those on the southern border to do more, quite frankly. We need to be doing more.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>"But the U.S. attorneys along the southern border tell me that the existing law regarding alien smugglers could be tighter. There is a discussion and debate now about what the language should be. No one wants to prosecute those who are engaged in Good Samaritan activities. We are looking into the situation in San Diego, and we are directing that our U.S. attorneys do more because you're right; if people are coming across the border repeatedly, particularly those who are coyotes and they're smugglers  or they're criminals or felons, they ought to be prosecuted."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, I bring this up because there happen to be a few of us in Congress, and I happen to be one, who are pretty familiar with this issue of alien smuggling, familiar enough, having been there and talked with the Attorney General, talked with the Border Patrol agents. But we didn't have any input to this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have the bill before us that we are debating. This is the last version, the one we're debating on. And the date on it is May 22, at 1:35 p.m. It is now 3:40 p.m. It's as thick as a small town phone book, and yet we've only had it for a couple of hours. There have been no hearings. No subcommittee markup. No full committee markup.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, I'm not someone who usually gets up and complains about process, but this is an example where someone like me and others of the committee could have been quite helpful if we had had hearings, could have had a markup. There are a couple of major flaws in this bill that I'll talk about. And I say this in good spirit. I'm going to actually vote for this bill because I think your intentions are correct. But let me just give you two examples.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, if you help smuggle in a terrorist, you can go to jail for up to 30 years. Under the language of this bill, you have to show that the smuggler knew that the person was a terrorist and knew that he intended to engage in terrorist activities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, you don't have to be Johnny Cochran to successfully defend a defendant in that particular case. The standard is just almost impossible for a prosecutor to prove. For example, let's say that you have Mohammad Atta on the stand, and he's just been detained by a Border Patrol agent and we want to apply this new provision.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If I was the defense attorney, my first question to the Border Patrol agent would be, Mr. Border Patrol Agent, you've arrested my client. You want to send him to prison for 30 years. Did Mr. Atta show you his al Qaeda ID card? No? Did Mr. Atta show you the picture that he has with Bin Laden and his family? No? Did he show you some videotape showing him on the monkey bars in the Afghanistan training camps? No? Well, if not, how do you know with mathematical certainty that this guy is a terrorist?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It's almost impossible to prove.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That's an example of something we could have fixed during the markup, saying, if you brought this person into the country for financial gain and he's a member of the terrorist watch list, we're going to give you an enhanced sentence up to 30 years. But we didn't have that chance because there was no markup.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Another thing that's flawed is, it doesn't fix the Good Samaritan exception. There's language in this bill that talks about Good Samaritans. Specifically, it says it is a defense, if you are arrested for a religious organization or one of its members to provide room, board, travel, medical assistance or other basic living expenses. That's the situation of a nun, for example, helping someone who's going to die out there in the 110-degree heat. We all believe that that should be provided.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But I read you the transcript of the Attorney General; he said, because this Good Samaritan exception needs to be tightened, and it does. For example, under this law, because you didn't talk with us about fixing it, if you are a member of the Red Cross or you're a member of the United Way, which is not religious affiliated, you could still be prosecuted.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, none of us wants that to happen.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My point is, as this bill moves forward, I'm willing to support it because I support the intent behind it. I support getting tough with alien smugglers. But the bottom line is, we need to fix this in conference. We need to work with Republicans and Democrats to include our input to make sure that at the end the day we have a much better bill that we can be proud of.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400025" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 4 minutes to the gentleman from Indiana, the sponsor of the legislation, Mr. Hill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Mr. HILL asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400177" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I want to thank Chairman Conyers and Chairman Thompson and Chairman Oberstar for working with me to draft this legislation. The staff has been extremely helpful, and I'm very pleased with the outcome of this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Alien Smuggling and Terrorism Prevention Act would provide all levels of law enforcement with the tools they need to detain those who knowingly bring illegal aliens into our country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Additionally, it would provide prosecutors and judges with clear proof and sentencing guidelines. The bill also significantly enhances penalties for illegal alien smuggling. The crime is raised from a misdemeanor to a felony under this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is estimated that there are currently more than 20 million illegal immigrants in this country. The cost of illegal immigration to our health care system, public education system, prison system and social services continues to rise without any sign of stopping or slowing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We must reform our immigration system to make it more efficient and effective. This bill is the first step towards doing so.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>It concentrates on easing the job of law enforcement, and it is my hope that this bill will act as a deterrent for illegal-alien smugglers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to this bill, Congress must enact tough, comprehensive immigration reform that does not award illegal aliens with amnesty. We need to make sure that employers who hire illegal aliens are punished, and we need to strengthen our border security.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At the same time, however, we must remember that legal immigration has served America well. America was built by hardworking people from all over the world. Many of them played by the rules and prospered while helping to build a stronger America, and our national immigration policies must reflect this reality. As long as immigrants enter our country legally, abide by our laws, and work hard to strengthen our communities, I believe they have a right to live in this Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But the personal safety and well-being of all citizens, as well as the security of U.S. jobs, are my chief concern. Therefore, I strongly urge passage of <bill type="h" number="2399">H.R. 2399</bill>, the Alien Smuggling and Terrorism Prevention Act.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400212" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no further requests for time, and I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400025" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 2 minutes to the chairman of the Homeland Security Committee, the gentleman from Mississippi (Mr. Thompson).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400402" topic="">
    <paragraph>I appreciate the yielding of the time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in strong support of the Alien Smuggling and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>During consideration of the Homeland Security authorization bill earlier this month, I made a commitment to my colleagues that the House would  have the opportunity to vote on maritime smuggling legislation. I am pleased to have been able to work with the Judiciary and Transportation Committees to craft this critical homeland security legislation. It addresses not only alien smuggling at sea, but also alien smuggling by land and air.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Specifically, the Alien Smuggling and Terrorism Prevention Act includes tough new penalties for those who recruit, encourage, transport, or shield from detection aliens who cross our land, maritime, or air borders illegally. These enhanced penalties are essential to discouraging criminals from building tunnels in remote parts of the desert to smuggle aliens across our borders.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We know that the same people that smuggle drugs into our country are ready and willing to smuggle individuals who would do us harm. In fact, in January we learned of a plot to smuggle about 20 would-be terrorists into the United States from Mexico for $8,000 a head. The drug dealers called them "Osama's guys."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill requires that interdicted smugglers and aliens be run against all available terrorist watch lists. This is an important step in protecting America from terrorists.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would especially like to commend the gentleman from Indiana (Mr. Hill) for authoring this commonsense enforcement legislation. He is to be commended for his commitment to border security.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, Mr. Speaker, I thank my colleagues for working together on this important legislation and urge all Members to give it their support.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400212" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400025" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 2 minutes to the gentleman from Indiana (Mr. Donnelly).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412205" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in strong support of my friend Mr. Hill's bill to get tough on criminals who undermine our Nation's safety.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the Alien Smuggling and Terrorism Prevention Act is a commonsense bill whose time is overdue. This legislation clarifies current law and would more severely punish those criminals who smuggle illegal aliens into our country, lengthening the amount of time they would have to be imprisoned and providing strong new sentences for those who assist terrorists.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, Mr. Hill's bill recognizes that there must be real penalties for people who break our laws. When it comes to our immigration policies, we first need to prove to Americans that we can secure our borders against intruders and provide strong enforcement of existing laws. We need to get law enforcement and Federal agents all the tools they need to do their jobs effectively.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We should provide the resources and technology our businesses need to better verify the citizenship of potential employees and crack down on employers who knowingly flout workplace laws. We must not provide amnesty for those who have broken our laws. And, Mr. Speaker, I regret that the recent proposal on comprehensive immigration reform in the Senate does not appear to have passed these tests.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I strongly urge my colleagues today to vote for <bill type="h" number="2399">H.R. 2399</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400212" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask my colleagues to vote "yes" on this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400025" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I only want to make two points. The gentleman from Florida gave a discussion about the legislation and put it into the context of the Southern District of San Diego, and I just did want to note for the record that the Department of Justice that decided to recommend the U.S. attorney's termination had commended her specifically for her handling of immigration cases.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And the second point I guess I wanted to make on this issue was would it be that the people in charge had ensured that the offices most impacted by illegal immigration and by illegal alien smuggling and those districts on the border of this country had been given the resources to the Justice Department disbursed to the U.S. Attorney's Office so they weren't held under hiring freezes and constrained to try to deal with an enormous issue with a very limited number of prosecutors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from California (Mr. Berman) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="2399">H.R. 2399</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400025" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this question will be postponed.</chair>
</record>
