<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1212595202" ordinal="11" title="SUPPORT H.R. 3021, 21ST CENTURY GREEN HIGH-PERFORMING PUBLIC SCHOOL FACILITIES ACT">
  <narrative>SUPPORT <bill type="h" number="3021">H.R. 3021</bill>, 21ST CENTURY GREEN HIGH-PERFORMING PUBLIC SCHOOL FACILITIES ACT -- (House of Representatives - June 04, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H4880]</narrative>
  <narrative>(Ms. LORETTA SANCHEZ of California asked and was given permission to address the House for 1 minute and to revise and extend her remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400356" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I rise today in support of <bill type="h" number="3021">H.R. 3021</bill>, a bill that will help our local schools build the high-quality classrooms that our students deserve.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This responsible legislation, which we will consider today, provides for needed investments in public school facilities, investments that will result in improved student performance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our Nation's public school facilities are in disrepair. This is a disgrace, and it impedes our students' ability to learn. Local education agencies want to make a difference, but they need our help.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With our younger students, we know that maintenance issues draw them away from focusing on what they need to focus on in the classroom, when they see chipping paint, water dripping from ceilings, poor heating and cooling. We need to change that. And older students cannot be prepared for the 21st Century if they don't have a 21st Century classroom.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These examples are not just anecdotal. There is firm evidence that suggests that we must invest in our school facilities in order to improve students' performance. By failing to do so, we are sending our youth a message that we don't care about them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I hope that my colleagues will vote with the best interests of our students and vote on this legislation in the affirmative today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
