<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1182268804" ordinal="38" title="ENERGY AND WATER DEVELOPMENT AND RELATED AGENCIES APPROPRIATIONS ACT, 2008">
  <chair> Pursuant to House Resolution 481 and rule XVIII, the Chair declares the House in the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for the further consideration of the bill, <bill type="h" number="2641">H.R. 2641</bill>.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> When the Committee of the Whole rose earlier today, a request for a recorded vote on amendment No. 19 by the gentleman from Minnesota (Mr. Kline) had been postponed.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will read.</narrative>
  <chair> The Clerk will designate the amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400324" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I appreciate this opportunity. I'd like to thank my colleagues, Congresswoman SHELLEY BERKLEY from Nevada and Congressman DEAN HELLER for being cosponsors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I'd like to talk for a moment about the infamous Yucca Mountain project, probably the most studied piece of real estate on the planet as we know it today. That is because the Department of Energy and Members of this Congress are trying to prove to the American people that the Yucca Mountain project is safe.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, in the last budget of last year, 60 percent of that budget was spent redoing problems with a broken project at Yucca Mountain.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, it's broken. Study after study after study have proven that it's a broken project; not only broken, but it's a colossal waste of taxpayers' dollars. Thousands, if not millions of millions of dollars have been spent on investigating the Yucca Mountain project to look at their flaws.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My committee last year alone, we looked at thousands of e-mails where the science had been falsified. They've spent over $20 million fixing the project from the research that we had done in my committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, if it was Wall Street that was looking at this project, they would shut it down. Most every senior management personnel at Yucca Mountain and the Department of Energy regarding the disposal of nuclear waste have either quit or left the project.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Terrorism is another issue. We're trying to put millions and millions of tons of nuclear waste in one spot. It creates an additional terrorist target.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It's an unproven science, but yet we're going to roll this nuclear waste through communities across our country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, the bottom line, even if I supported the project, which I don't, even if I was a nuclear industry, which I'm not, I would say it's the biggest waste of taxpayers' dollars. It's literally a hole in the ground.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would encourage that Members of this Congress visit Yucca Mountain. It is a $12 billion waste of money. If I were the nuclear industry, if I were this Congress, I would find another site. I would store it on site or find some other location.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The science is broken. Time and time again, we have found that it's a flawed project, it's flawed science. If it were another project, if it was a school bus, if was a space shuttle, with this many errors and this many problems we would stop the project.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I encourage this Congress to support my amendment striking $202 million from this very flawed project.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400417" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in opposition to the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from Indiana is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400417" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, the gentleman's amendment would eliminate all nondefense funding for Yucca Mountain. High-level radioactive waste exists in over 38 States. I believe it is irresponsible to leave it where it is forever, and it is essential to have a repository where it can be safely left for up to a million years while the radioactivity decays away.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This waste comes from maintaining our nuclear weapons stockpile and from spent fuel from civilian nuclear reactors that generate 20 percent of all electricity in the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Yucca was chosen by Congress in 1982 as a permanent geological repository for high-level waste and billions have been spent to characterize the site and prepare for licensing and construction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Failure to open Yucca Mountain and take custody of commercial spent nuclear fuel will cost the taxpayers over $7 billion by 2017 when the repository could open. Cutting funding and delaying the filing of a license application by only a year will simply exacerbate the problem and increase this cost by more than a half billion dollars.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Failure to proceed with a reasonable approach to disposing of spent nuclear fuel will cause the Nuclear Regulatory Commission to stop licensing new nuclear reactors and extending the licenses of existing plants. Every new and extended license must satisfy the waste confidence clause. So this amendment will constrain our ability to grow our economy without emitting any more greenhouse gasses. In the coming years, it will choke off nearly 20 percent of U.S. electricity generated by nuclear power  plants.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And, again, we have tried to strike a very reasoned balance in this bill as far as funding for the repository and other programs to initiate a sound nuclear industry in the short term, and I am opposed to the gentleman's amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400324" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 2 minutes to my friend and an adamant opponent of Yucca Mountain, Shelley Berkley from Nevada.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400024" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I want to thank my colleague for this very thoughtful amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Yucca Mountain project is a failure. Twenty years after Nevada was unfairly singled out as the proposed dumpsite for this Nation's radioactive garbage, the only waste at Yucca Mountain is the $12 million that has now been wasted on this ridiculous proposal.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Plans for Yucca Mountain threaten the safety of the families I represent and the lives of 50 million Americans who will be at risk from shipments of toxic radioactive garbage headed to Yucca Mountain. One spill involving this deadly nuclear waste could make people sick, die, and shut down our roads and railways, and cost millions to clean up.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nuclear waste shipments are also prime targets for terrorists looking to unleash radiation on unsuspecting communities or to steal material needed to make a dirty bomb. Current plans call for thousands of nuke waste shipments on America's roads and railways, each one vulnerable to a handheld missile or 9/11-style suicide attack, the results of which could be devastating.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Decades of "mobile Chernobyls" passing by homes, schools, hospitals, houses of worship, each an accident waiting to happen. And believe me, Mr. Chairman, our first responders have no training and no resources needed to deal with incidents involving these nuclear waste shipments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We talk about money and saving money by putting more money into Yucca Mountain? We have absolutely no idea how much Yucca Mountain is going to cost because there is no cost estimate. We have no time estimates. We have no radiation standards. We don't have canisters that currently exist that can store this nuclear waste and not have the nuclear material leach into the groundwater that is going to pollute all of the Southwestern United States water supplies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, if we want to do something for the American people, let's end this ridiculous folly before it costs us any more money. We have the power to do it in Congress. It is time that we stop this ridiculous proposal.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400417" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield such time as he may consume to the ranking member, Mr. Hobson, in opposition to the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400180" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in opposition to the gentleman from Nevada's amendment, as he might expect and as his colleague might expect.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At some point we all have to go beyond parochial politics and do the right thing for the entire Nation. This is a NIMBY approach: "not in my backyard." Under any scenario you might imagine, from the construction of new nuclear power plants to shutting down all existing plants tomorrow, from continuing with the once-through fuel to cycle to beginning to recycle our spent nuclear fuel, we will need the first repository at Yucca Mountain. If we pursue recycling, we can avoid the need to build  eight more Yucca Mountains, but we still need that first repository.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Federal Government has a statutory and contractual obligation, already adjudicated in the courts. It is costing us money by not getting it operational on Yucca Mountain.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But this is not solely a question about what to do with commercial spent fuel. One-tenth of Yucca's capacity by weight, and up to one-third of its capacity by volume, is dedicated to defense spent fuel and high-level waste.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Without Yucca Mountain this material will stay put in places like Hanford, Idaho, Savannah River, and West Valley. Many of these sites already have enforceable cleanup agreements requiring these materials to be shipped off to the geologic repository.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to think we don't need a repository, but we do need a repository. We need it now, not 100 years. We need to move forward with this. And my real desire is that we won't have to build eight of them someplace and certainly not in Nevada. But we have got to finish this one off. It is a waste of taxpayers' money not to do it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge opposition to this amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400324" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I appreciate the comments of my colleague from Ohio. But I believe there are Members of Congress that are in a rush to find a place. They have spent 20 years in a rush. And in the midst of that time, we have created a project that is a colossal waste of taxpayers' dollars. We need to find a site that is safe.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I support nuclear energy. I do not support the waste being in Nevada because it is absolutely broken.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I appreciate this time and encourage this Congress to stop the funding of this very flawed project and find a site that is safe for the American people.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412218" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise today in strong support of the Porter-Heller-Berkley amendment to the Energy and Water Appropriations Act for fiscal year 2008. This amendment would strike the funding for the proposed Yucca Mountain site, and help end this enormous financial disaster for the taxpayers and for Nevada.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Colleagues, Yucca Mountain is in my district, Nevada's Second District.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our State has been dealing with this issue for literally decades, the Federal Government has spent billions of dollars, and we are frankly almost no closer today to opening this site than we were years ago.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As has been stated by my Nevada colleagues, over the past 20 years the proposed site has suffered from gross mismanagement, faulty science and research, and contract mismanagement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But we aren't just opposed to this site in an arbitrary manner. In fact, a number of solutions exist that are acceptable and safer, like dry-cask storage for example.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If you're opposed to nuclear waste traveling through your communities, creating safety and security hazards in your neighborhoods, then you should support this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If you're concerned about the taxpayers, wasting their funds, and the wise stewardship of Federal tax dollars, then support this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Both Senators, the Governor and the House delegation are united in opposition to Yucca Mountain. That should send a very clear message to us here in the House about the opposition in Nevada.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Support the Porter-Heller-Berkley amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400324" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400417" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the amendment offered by the gentleman from Nevada (Mr. Porter).</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400324" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I demand a recorded vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 6 of rule XVIII, further proceedings on the amendment offered by the gentleman from Nevada will be postponed.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will read.</narrative>
  <chair> The Clerk will designate the amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400414" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman this amendment that I am introducing, which I will subsequently withdraw, expresses my concern about the committee's action to cap loan guarantees at $7 billion for new energy projects designed to reduce carbon emissions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And before I ask unanimous consent to withdraw the amendment, I am going to ask the chairman to enter into a colloquy with myself, and I will also submit remarks from Mr. Towns, coauthor with me; as well as my ranking member of the Energy and Commerce Committee, Mr. Barton.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, under the Energy Policy Act of 2005, the Congress authorized funding to provide loan guarantees for any technology which reduces carbon emissions. That was designed to help a vast array of technologies such as wind, solar, clean coal, ethanol, and nuclear. Your committee excluded new nuclear plants as one of the technologies eligible for loan guarantees under the 2005 Energy Policy Act. And as a supporter of nuclear power, I oppose that exclusion. I am concerned that this may delay  new projects that are being planned, and I am hopeful that these concerns can be addressed when you reach a conference with the Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would also note that the authorization in the energy appropriation bill is just that, an authorization. No appropriation is required. It is a standard practice that Federal loan guarantee programs have an annual loan volume authorization in an appropriations bill  and that the program which is authorized in title 17 of the Energy Policy Act is unique. We must remember that it is self-financing and requires no taxpayer funds. Utilities that are building  these plants will pay all of the costs associated with the program, including administrative costs of processing the loan guarantee applications and the credit subsidy cost of issuing the loan guarantee itself.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, Mr. Chairman, I would like you to help us if you can address these concerns.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400417" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, will the gentleman yield?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400414" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>I yield to the chairman of the subcommittee, my good friend, Mr. Visclosky.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400417" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I appreciate the gentleman's yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And I want to acknowledge that we in Congress authorized the loan guarantee program for advanced technology that addresses clean air and climate concerns. The Federal Credit Reform Act explicitly states that loan obligations can only be made to the extent there is an affirmative action on the part of the Appropriations Committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Federal Credit Reform Act provides that new direct loan obligations may be incurred and new loan guarantee commitments may be made for fiscal year 1992 and thereafter only to the extent that, one, new budget authority is provided in an appropriations act; and, two, a limitation on the use of funds for the cost of a loan guarantee has been "provided in an appropriations act"; or, three, "authority is otherwise provided in appropriations acts."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, it is the implementation of this program that has raised the concerns of the committee. Our fiscal year 2008 bill does not provide loan guarantees for the nuclear industry. The request for guaranteed loans from the Nuclear Energy Association, subsidized by the Federal Government, is very large. It overwhelms what the bill provides for the entire energy community. The administration had asked for a total of $4 billion for the nuclear energy industry and the coal industry. This does not  come close to what the Nuclear Energy Association has indicated they need. The Nuclear Energy Association indicates a need for $25 billion in Federal guaranteed loans for fiscal year 2008 and more than that in fiscal year 2009. The "system," meaning the DOE loan guarantee infrastructure, cannot accommodate a request of this size at this time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would also point out that the fiscal year 2006 joint continuing resolution included $4 billion in Incentives For Innovative Technology loan guarantees for the Department of Energy to execute, without defining which technologies to target. The Congress did not limit the use of this initial $4 billion for nuclear projects. The administration chose not to make these loans available to the nuclear community.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>I believe in the "go slow approach." We should take all deliberate speed for the new DOE programs. I recommend this approach to the Congress on this one based on my continuing concerns about how DOE has managed it to date. I am, however, open to new information about the industry's plan for innovative technology deployment and discussion about how DOE can implement the program. I pledge to work with the gentleman to see if we can come to an agreeable solution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400414" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for the helpful understanding. I look forward to working with you and Mr. Hobson.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400018" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I thank the Gentleman. I rise to associate myself with the remarks of my good friends from Michigan and New York in support of this amendment. Nuclear power must be a part of our future energy supply. Companies that are planning to build new nuclear plants estimate that they will request a loan of $20 to $25 billion in FY '08. The companies expect to complete loan guarantee agreements in FY '08 because they must have financing in place in order to maintain their  current schedules. Without loan guarantees for new nuclear plants, we risk a delay in bringing more safe and emission free nuclear plants online at a time when we are trying to diversify our supplies of power as quickly as possible. I thank the Gentleman for yielding me this time and I yield back.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400409" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I thank the Gentleman. Mr. Chairman, I rise in support of this amendment which also goes to the heart of my concerns that certain technologies were excluded from receiving loan guarantees. Nuclear power emits no greenhouse gases and needs to be part of the solution towards addressing the concerns of climate change. In some cases, companies have stated that without loan guarantees, plans for new nuclear plants will be abandoned in favor of other forms of generating capacity  to meet the growing demand for baseload electricity. This will not serve our nation's energy security and environmental interests. The Export-Import Bank has billions of dollars of loan guarantees available for financing these types of projects overseas. Some people</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400414" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, at this point I would ask unanimous consent to withdraw my amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the amendment is withdrawn.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400417" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I ask unanimous consent that the gentlewoman from California (Mrs. Tauscher) be allowed to offer her amendment at this time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Indiana?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400396" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, this amendment has been discussed with the Energy and Water Development Subcommittee, and I understand it is acceptable to the chairman and the ranking member.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Before explaining my amendment, I want to congratulate Chairman Visclosky and Ranking Member Hobson for the bill before the House today. It is a strong testament to their talents. Among its achievements, the bill provides substantial increases for two broad national priorities that I have long championed, nuclear nonproliferation activities to prevent the spread of weapons of mass destruction and the materials and technologies that be can used to create such weapons, and scientific  research on technologies to reduce our dependence on foreign sources of energy and on fossil fuels in general.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The committee report takes a series of bold actions involving the Nation's nuclear weapons program, including directing the Department of Energy to reevaluate its plans for modernizing the nuclear weapons complex and demanding rapid consolidation of weapons-usable nuclear material. I want to commend the Energy and Water Subcommittee for their fine work.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also provides critical funding increases to a lesser known national priority, the National Ignition Campaign, which is being carried out at the Lawrence Livermore National Lab in my district. When the NIF is completed in fiscal year 2009, it will be a scientific tool unlike anything the world has ever seen.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The National Ignition Facility will give U.S. scientists unprecedented insight into nuclear weapons phenomena, without nuclear explosions, and thus play a crucial role in the science-based stockpile stewardship program, which ensures the safety and reliability of our nuclear deterrent without nuclear testing. I commend the committee for its support of this critically important program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I do need to mention, however, that the report accompanying the bill includes a few instances where I believe the Appropriations Committee ventured beyond what was authorized in  the weapons activities account by the House Armed Services Committee, where I serve as chairman of the Subcommittee on Strategic Forces.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Directing the relocation of the long-planned Pit Disassembly and Conversion Facility, commencing weapons disassembly activities at the Nevada Test site without a feasibility assessment, and initiating a major new construction project at the Idaho National Lab are all examples of actions that would be more appropriately dealt with by the authorizing committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Separately, by cutting the funds for the mixed oxide fuel facility while demanding improved execution on the project, I believe it sets up an unfair task for the Energy Department. Having said that, Chairman Visclosky and Ranking Member Hobson, as well as our staff, have been very open to dialogue on these issues, and I truly, truly appreciate that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My amendment modifies the bill to address two actions recommended by the committee report. First, the amendment confirms that the pit facility will be located at the Savannah River site. The site was selected by a former record of decision that was issued in 2000, which was in turn based on the environmental impact statement completed in 1999.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And second, the amendment directs that weapons dismantlement activities funded by the bill to be conducted at sites authorized to conduct such activity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to sincerely thank the chairman and ranking member for agreeing to accept this amendment. We are very grateful for the spirit of cooperation in which this amendment was achieved. I believe this cooperation is possible because at the end of the day we are in fundamental agreement on most of these issues.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I trust that going forward we can continue discussing these projects, as well as others, and work together moving the country forward concerning the future of a nuclear weapons complex.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge adoption of this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400417" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I move to strike the last word.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400417" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I appreciate the recognition, and simply rise to accept the gentlelady's amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This has been a collaborative effort. And I would want to also congratulate the gentlewoman from California and all of her subcommittee members for their very good and strong leadership in rationalizing the nuclear weapons complex and bolstering the nuclear nonproliferation programs at the National Nuclear Security Administration.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The fact is, the gentlelady in particular has exercised great leadership in the issues of nonproliferation, making sure we have an appropriate and rationalized weapons complex, and that again, we are very deliberative as far as what the long-term nuclear policy of this country is. And again, I also appreciate her very early interjection into the work of this subcommittee, and her cooperation as well as her staff's cooperation. And again, it is my pleasure, on behalf of the subcommittee, to accept  her amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400396" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I am very excited to continue to work with the chairman and the ranking member of the Energy and Water Development Appropriations Committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As I said earlier, our two staffs have worked very closely together to achieve what I think is some very good work on the National Nuclear Weapons Complex and other issues. I appreciate his accepting of this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the amendment offered by the gentlewoman from California (Mrs. Tauscher).</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400049" topic="MOMENT OF SILENCE IN MEMORY OF NINE SOUTH CAROLINA FIREFIGHTERS WHO PERISHED IN LINE OF DUTY">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, last night, nine brave firefighters from my district lost their lives in the line of duty. Responding to a fire in the West Ashley area of Charleston, these men made the ultimate sacrifice in service to our community in what was the single worst loss of firefighters since 9/11. This tragedy is a somber reminder of the dangers our first responders face on a daily basis as they serve to protect us and our property. We are forever grateful for their service  and deeply sadden by their loss.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our hearts and prayers go out to the families of these courageous men: Captain William "Billy" Hutchinson, Captain Mike Benke, Captain Louis Mulkey, Engineer Mark Kelsey, Engineer Bradford "Brad" Baity, Assistant Engineer Michael French, Firefighter James "Earl" Drayton, Firefighter Brandon Thompson and Firefighter Melven Champaign.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These men, who had over 100 years of service among them, gave their lives doing a job they loved.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I now yield to my good friend, Mr. Clyburn.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400075" topic="MOMENT OF SILENCE IN MEMORY OF NINE SOUTH CAROLINA FIREFIGHTERS WHO PERISHED IN LINE OF DUTY">
    <paragraph>I thank my friend, Mr. Brown, for yielding me this time. Not since 9/11 have we been reminded so poignantly of the sacrifice our first responders make to protect our safety. These nine firefighters gave the ultimate sacrifice last night doing the jobs they loved. As Charlestonians, South Carolinians and Americans, we are grateful for their service and deeply saddened by their loss.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our hearts go out to their families and their colleagues. This devastating loss is one that touched the hearts of our entire Nation, and we grieve with them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr., once said, "Everybody can be great because anybody can serve. You only need a heart full of grace, a soul generate by love and you can be that servant."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These firefighters were public servants in the truest sense. They answered the call to serve their community, and today Charleston and South Carolina are better places for their service.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Among the nine that perished was a combined 123 years of service to the Charleston Fire Department. This is a remarkable testament to their dedication and selflessness. Their experience and service cannot be replaced, and their contributions will not be forgotten.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I ask my colleagues to rise and join me in a moment of silence.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, 2-minute voting will continue.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400301" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I move that the Committee do now rise.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The motion was agreed to.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Accordingly, the Committee rose; and the Speaker pro tempore (Mr. Walz of Minnesota) having assumed the chair, Mr. Pomeroy, Acting Chairman of the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union, reported that that Committee, having had under consideration the bill (<bill type="h" number="2641">H.R. 2641</bill>) making appropriations for energy and water development and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2008, and for other purposes, had come to no resolution thereon.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
