<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1192636802" ordinal="14" title="BREAST CANCER AWARENESS MONTH">
  <narrative>BREAST CANCER AWARENESS MONTH -- (House of Representatives - October 17, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H11643]</narrative>
  <narrative>(Mr. MORAN of Virginia asked and was given permission to address the House for 1 minute and to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400283" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today to recognize Breast Cancer Awareness Month. Virtually every American has been impacted in one way or another by this deadly disease. More than 3 million women currently live with breast cancer. Each year tens of thousands of our wives, our mothers, our daughters will die from it. One of our colleagues, Congresswoman Jo Ann Davis, was just taken before her time from breast cancer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, despite medical advances, breast cancer remains the second leading cause of cancer death among American women. In the United States, one in seven will develop the disease during her lifetime. But still a cure remains elusive. Congress hasn't given up the fight. <bill type="h" number="1157">H.R. 1157</bill>, the Breast Cancer and Environmental Research Act, and <bill type="h" number="715">H.R. 715</bill>, the Annie Fox Act, are two bills that would bring crucial Federal support to two key areas of breast cancer research: research into environmental  causes of the disease, and research into the causes of the disease in young women who tend to develop more aggressive forms of it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Additionally, in this year's Defense appropriations bill, $127.5 million was approved by the House for breast cancer research.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Women all over the country are organizing to raise national awareness. The Alexandria, Virginia Walk for Breast Cancer Awareness this Saturday is a prime example of the activism which is bound to make a difference in our daughters' lives.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
