<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1189094404" ordinal="46" title="STATUS REPORT ON CURRENT SPENDING LEVELS OF ON-BUDGET SPENDING AND REVENUES FOR FY 2007 AND FY 2008 AND THE 5-YEAR PERIOD FY 2008 THROUGH FY 2012">
  <narrative>STATUS REPORT ON CURRENT SPENDING LEVELS OF ON-BUDGET SPENDING AND REVENUES FOR FY 2007 AND FY 2008 AND THE 5-YEAR PERIOD FY 2008 THROUGH FY 2012 -- (House of Representatives - September 06, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H10201]</narrative>
  <chair> Under a previous order of the House, the gentleman from South Carolina (Mr. Spratt) is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am transmitting a status report on the current levels of on-budget spending and revenues for fiscal years 2007 and 2008 and the five-year period of fiscal years 2008 through 2012. This report is necessary to facilitate the application of sections 302 and 311 of the Congressional Budget Act. This status report is current through September 5, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The term "current level" refers to the amounts of spending and revenues estimated for each fiscal year based on laws enacted or awaiting the President's signature.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The first table in the report compares the current level of total budget authority, outlays, and revenues for the fiscal years 2007 and 2008, and the five-year period of fiscal years 2008 through 2012 with the aggregate levels set by <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>, the Concurrent Resolution on the Budget for Fiscal Year 2008. This, comparison is needed to enforce section 311(a) of the Budget Act, which creates a point of order against measures that would breach the budget resolution's aggregate levels. The  table does not show budget authority and outlays for years after fiscal years 2007 and 2008 because appropriations for those years have not yet been considered.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The second table compares the current levels of budget authority and outlays for spending by each authorizing committee with the section 302(a) allocations made under <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill> for fiscal years 2007 and 2008 and fiscal years 2008 through 2012. This comparison is needed to enforce section 302(f) of the Budget Act, which creates a point of order against measures that would breach the section 302(a) allocation of new budget authority for the committee that reported the measure. It is also  needed to implement section 311(c), which exempts committees that comply with their allocations from the point of order under section 311(a).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The third table compares the current levels of discretionary appropriations for fiscal years 2007 and 2008 with the section 302(b) suballocations of discretionary budget authority and outlays among Appropriations subcommittees. The comparison is also needed to enforce section 302(f) of the Budget Act because the point of order under that section equally applies to measures that would breach the applicable section 302(b) suballocation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The fourth table gives the current level for fiscal years 2009 and 2010 of accounts identified for advance appropriations under Section 206 of <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>. This list is needed to enforce the budget resolution, which prohibits advance appropriations that are: (i) not identified in the statement of managers or (ii) would cause the aggregate amount of such appropriations to exceed the level specified in the resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enactment of measures providing any new budget authority for FY 2007 (if not already included in the current level estimate) would cause FY 2007 budget authority to exceed the appropriate level set by <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enactment of measures providing new budget authority for FY 2008 in excess of $928,108,000,000 (if not already included in the current level estimate) would cause FY 2008 budget authority to exceed the appropriate level set by <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enactment of measures providing any new outlays for FY 2007 (if not already included in the current level estimate) would cause FY 2007 outlays to exceed the appropriate level set by <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enactment of measures providing new outlays for FY 2008 in excess of $587,128,000,000 (if not already included in the current level estimate) would cause FY 2008 outlays to exceed the appropriate level set by <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enactment of measures resulting in revenue reduction for FY 2007 in excess of $4,176,000,000 (if not already included in the current estimate) would cause FY 2007 revenue to fall below the appropriate level set by <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enactment of measures resulting in revenue reduction for FY 2008 in excess of $34,577,000,000 (if not already included in the current estimate) would cause FY 2008 revenue to fall below the appropriate level set by <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enactment of measures resulting in revenue reduction for the period of fiscal years 2008 through 2012 in excess of $175,852,000,000 (if not already included in the current level estimate) would cause revenues to fall below the appropriate levels set by <bill type="sc" number="2">S. Con. Res. 2</bill>].</paragraph>
    <paragraph>U.S. CONGRESS,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>CONGRESSIONAL BUDGET OFFICE,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington, DC, September 6, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR MR. CHAIRMAN: The enclosed report shows the effects of Congressional action on the fiscal year 2007 budget and is current through September 5, 2007. This report is submitted under section 308(b) and in aid of section 311 of the Congressional Budget Act, as amended.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The estimates of budget authority, outlays, and revenues are consistent with the technical and economic assumptions of <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>, the Concurrent Resolution on the Budget for Fiscal Year 2008, as approved by the Senate and the House of Representatives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Pursuant to section 204(b) of <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>, provisions designated as emergency requirements are exempt from enforcement of the budget resolution. As a result, the enclosed current level report excludes these amounts (see footnote 1 of the report).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since my last letter to you, dated June 11, 2007, the Congress has cleared and the President has signed the following acts that affect budget authority, outlays, or revenues for fiscal year 2007: An act to extend the authorities of the Andean Trade Preference Act until February 29, 2008 (P.L. 110-42); and a bill to provide for the extension of Transitional Medical Assistance (TMA) and the Abstinence Education Program through the end of fiscal year 2007, and for other purposes (P.L. 110-48).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Robert A. Sunshine</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enclosure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>U.S. CONGRESS,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>CONGRESSIONAL BUDGET OFFICE,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington, DC, September 6, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR MR. CHAIRMAN: The enclosed report shows the effects of Congressional action on the fiscal year 2008 budget and is current through September 5, 2007. This report is submitted under section 308(b) and in aid of section 311 of the Congressional Budget Act, as amended.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The estimates of budget authority, outlays, and revenues are consistent with the technical and economic assumptions of <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>, the Concurrent Resolution on the Budget for Fiscal Year 2008, as approved by the Senate and the House of Representatives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Pursuant to section 204(b) of <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>, provisions designated as emergency requirements are exempt from enforcement of the budget resolution. As a result, the enclosed current level report excludes these amounts (see footnote 1 of the report).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since my last letter to you, dated June 11, 2007, the Congress has cleared and the President has signed the following acts that affect budget authority, outlays, or revenues for fiscal year 2008: An act to extend the authorities of the Andean Trade Preference Act until February 29, 2008 (P.L. 110-42); a bill to provide for the extension of Transitional Medical Assistance (TMA) and the Abstinence Education Program through the end of fiscal year 2007, and for other purposes (P.L. 110-48); a joint  resolution approving the renewal of import restrictions contained in the Burmese Freedom and Democracy Act of 2003, and for other purposes (P.L. 110-52); and Implementing Recommendations of the 9/11 Commission Act of 2007 (P.L. 110-53).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Robert A. Sunshine</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enclosure.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
