<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1185163200" ordinal="41" title="COMMEMORATING THE 300TH ANNIVERSARY OF NEW MILFORD, CONNECTICUT">
  <narrative>COMMEMORATING THE 300TH ANNIVERSARY OF NEW MILFORD, CONNECTICUT -- (House of Representatives - July 23, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H8236]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution (<bill type="hr" number="528">H. Res. 528</bill>) commemorating the 300th anniversary of the Town of New Milford, Connecticut.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the resolution.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the resolution is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="hr" number="528">H. Res. 528</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas New Milford is located in Litchfield County, on the western border of Connecticut, in the Housatonic Valley;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the settlement of New Milford began in 1706, when John Noble, Sr., purchased a portion of land known as Weantinogue;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas in 1707, Noble and his daughter settled in New Milford, followed by 12 other families;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas beginning in 1774, New Milford demonstrated its support for the Revolutionary War by providing financial support to the servicemen and sending 285 of its 2,700 inhabitants to battle;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas New Milford was a center of Underground Railroad work in Connecticut, with many of its residents offering their homes as places for slaves to take refuge on their journey to freedom;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the late 1800s marked the arrival of many new industries and businesses in New Milford, including the manufacturing of furniture, paints, and pottery;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas in 1902, New Milford's worst disaster occurred when a raging fire completely destroyed the town's main business district on Bank Street;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the population of New Milford stood at 3,000 in 1880 and has grown to nearly 30,000 today;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas at 64 square miles, New Milford is the largest town in Connecticut; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas New Milford has been modernized through commercial and industrial growth, while retaining its deep sense of history, scenic beauty, and traditional New England character throughout the past 300 years: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, &lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; That the House of Representatives--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) congratulates the Town of New Milford, Connecticut, on the occasion of its 300th anniversary; and</narrative>
  <narrative> (2) honors the Town of New Milford for its significant history, impressive growth, and considerable contributions to the State of Connecticut and the United States.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Davis) and the gentleman from Tennessee (Mr. Duncan) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Illinois.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days in which to revise and extend their remarks.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Illinois?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a member of the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, I am pleased to join my colleague in consideration of <bill type="hr" number="528">H. Res. 528</bill>, a bill that commemorates the 300th anniversary of the Town of New Milford, Connecticut. <bill type="hr" number="528">H. Res. 528</bill>, which has 53 cosponsors, was introduced by Representative Christopher Murphy on June 28, 2007. <bill type="hr" number="528">H. Res. 528</bill> was reported from the Oversight Committee on July 19, 2007, by a voice vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I commend my colleague, Representative Christopher Murphy, for seeking to commemorate the 300th anniversary of New Milford, Connecticut. I urge swift passage of this resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400116" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="hr" number="528">H. Res. 528</bill> commemorates the Town of New Milford, Connecticut, on its 300th anniversary. New Milford is not the largest city, but under the definitions of the State, it is the largest town within the State, with a population of nearly 30,000 residents. This quaint and friendly community is home to thriving businesses and manufacturing industries and has abundant historical roots.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>New Milford was established and founded in 1707 when John Noble, Sr. of Westfield, Massachusetts, purchased a large portion of land for his family. More families arrived in the new community soon afterwards, and the settlement began to flourish. Over time, new churches and schools were founded, and in 1774, the town saw 285 of its men leave to serve in the Revolutionary War.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In its 300 years, New Milford has seen weather-related tragedies, devastating illnesses, and damaging fires hit the town. But it has overcome these tragedies and events and today has many successful industries and businesses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>New Milford educates its residents and visitors each year through cultural tours, concert events, art fairs, and camps. It has witnessed much history and seen tremendous growth in its 300 years and is certainly one of the most pleasant places to live in this Nation today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am pleased to support <bill type="hr" number="528">H. Res. 528</bill> to honor this historic 300th anniversary.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, it's my pleasure to yield such time as he might consume to the author of this legislation, Representative Christopher Murphy from the Fifth District of Connecticut.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412194" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would like to thank my friend from Tennessee and from Illinois for supporting the resolution here today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think it's fitting, in part, that we are here in the House of Representatives on this august floor in order to celebrate a town, New Milford, Connecticut, which is, in part, responsible for our very existence here today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The first citizen of New Milford is often referred to as Roger Sherman, whose statute sits not far outside this body. Why is that? Because after being an entrepreneur in New Milford, Connecticut, Roger Sherman came to the Constitutional Convention and was one of the authors, the primary author, of the Connecticut Compromise, which was responsible for the United States Government having a bicameral legislature with both the House and the Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We're very proud of him. We're very proud of the incredibly rich historical tradition in New Milford. As was referenced, the number of people who rose from New Milford to fight in the Revolutionary War is remarkable, given its small size. It also became a central stop, a central hub on the Underground Railroad in the 50 or 60 years after the Revolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It has grown over time from a community that was founded first by only 12 families to now a town that not only enjoys one of the largest land masses in Connecticut, but also has 30,000 people there and still has retained its small-town charm.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I really urge anyone who has plans to travel throughout the northeastern section of this great United States, to try to divert a little bit of your trip to see the quaint village of New Milford. Not only does it have a small, but bustling, downtown of quaint shops on the side streets off of the green, but a growing commercial industrial sector as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I was privileged to be able to march in a very festive 300th anniversary parade a few weeks ago, and I'm very pleased to join my colleagues here to celebrate its 300th anniversary on the floor of the House of Representatives today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge passage of the resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400116" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I will simply close by congratulating the town of New Milford on this historic anniversary, its 300th anniversary. And I commend the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Davis) and also the gentleman from Connecticut (Mr. Murphy) for bringing this matter to the attention of the House.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time and urge passage of this resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Davis) that the House suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, <bill type="hr" number="528">H. Res. 528</bill>.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the resolution was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
