<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1197910803" ordinal="30" title="DAN MILLER POST OFFICE BUILDING">
  <narrative>DAN MILLER POST OFFICE BUILDING -- (House of Representatives - December 17, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H15482]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400295" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="4342">H.R. 4342</bill>) to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 824 Manatee Avenue West in Bradenton, Florida, as the "Dan Miller Post Office Building".</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="4342">H.R. 4342</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. DAN MILLER POST OFFICE BUILDING.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Designation.--The facility of the United States Postal Service located at 824 Manatee Avenue West in Bradenton, Florida, shall be known and designated as the "Dan Miller Post Office Building".</narrative>
  <narrative> (b) References.--Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the facility referred to in subsection (a) shall be deemed to be a reference to the "Dan Miller Post Office Building".&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from the District of Columbia (Ms. Norton) and the gentleman from California (Mr. Issa) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentlewoman from the District of Columbia.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400295" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days in which to revise and extend their remarks.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from the District of Columbia?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400295" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I am pleased to join my colleagues in consideration of <bill type="h" number="4342">H.R. 4342</bill>, designating the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 824 Manatee Avenue West in Bradenton, Florida, as the Dan Miller Post Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="4342">H.R. 4342</bill> was introduced by Representative Buchanan of Florida on December 10, 2007, was reported from the Oversight Committee on December 12, 2007, by voice vote. This measure has been cosponsored by the entire Florida delegation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Representative Dan Miller represented Florida's 13th District in this House from 1992 to 2002. Currently he is teaching at the University of South Florida and is developing the Manasota Institute of Public Policy and Leadership at the Sarasota Campus of the University of South Florida.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Former Representative Miller's efforts in Congress as well as in academia have been greatly appreciated, and I urge swift passage of this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I reserve the balance of my time, Mr. Speaker.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400196" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I served with Congressman Dan Miller. He, unlike most Members of Congress, came here, said he would stay for a period of time, as the Founding Fathers thought, and return to his life at home.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He was elected from the 13th District of Florida in 1992, and after 10 years, five terms, retired in 2003. He did so not to seek higher office, not for any reason except that he felt that he came here for a period of time, served for the time he'd promised, and went back. He has, in fact, returned to his life and appropriately has resettled in southwest Florida at the University of South Florida.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I look forward to seeing him up here again some day. I look forward to his continued process of participating here in helping those of us in Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is unusual for a Member of Congress to come, stay for a period of time, and not return to lobbying, not seek higher office, but in fact to go back to being the citizen that he can be and to give to his community and to be available should we need him.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I join with my colleagues and the Government Reform Committee that unanimously voted this out in urging the passage of the Dan Miller Post Office.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400273" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, it is with great pleasure that I join in recognizing the distinguished career of one of my former colleagues, the Honorable Dan Miller of Bradenton, FL. My friendship with Dan actually dates back more than four decades to 1962, when we were best friends and members of the Delta Chi fraternity at the University of Florida. Throughout my time in college, our post-college years and finally our years serving in the House of Representatives together from the great State of Florida,  I have always cherished his friendship, admired his public service and enjoyed knowing his wife Glenda and their wonderful family.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dan Miller will always be remembered in these Halls for his congenial nature, his leadership on a host of issues, and his commitment to fiscal restraint. When he ran for Congress, he was a staunch advocate of shrinking the size and scope of the Federal Government and reducing the impact of onerous Federal regulation in the lives of average Americans. He remained true to his convictions throughout his 10 years in this institution and would be proud to know that he will be remembered that way.  He served as a Member of Congress with an appreciation for the history around him and a passion for the job and the goals he came to Washington to achieve that we would all be well-served to emulate. I know that I join family friends and colleagues in supporting this well-deserved recognition by Congress.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412196" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of renaming the Bradenton Main Post Office at 824 Manatee Avenue West as the "Dan Miller Post Office Building" in honor of former Congressman Dan Miller.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I can think of no better way to honor the public service of this former Florida Congressman than to designate the Bradenton Main Post Office in his name.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dan Miller is a successful Bradenton businessman, educator, and community leader who represented Florida's 13th District in Congress from 1992 to 2003, when he retired from the House.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He is a principled and effective leader who was consistently recognized as one of the top fiscal conservatives in Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congressman Miller helped balance the Federal budget for the first time in 30 years by using Federal resources wisely--cutting waste, fraud, and abuse while supporting important programs like the National Institutes of Health, where Dan led the effort to double NIH funding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dan managed the congressional oversight of the 2000 U.S. Census, the most successful census to date despite many efforts to politicize the process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congressman Dan Miller is a statesman who commanded bipartisan respect and befriended lawmakers on both sides of the aisle.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He is a man of integrity who kept his word to term-limit himself and serve only five terms in Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congressman, successful businessman, respected educator--I am honored to call Dan Miller a friend and advisor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am also proud to hold the seat he once held and pleased to pay tribute to him by sponsoring this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge all of my colleagues to support <bill type="h" number="4342">H.R. 4342</bill> in honor of former Congressman Dan Miller.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400196" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400295" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from the District of Columbia (Ms. Norton) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="4342">H.R. 4342</bill>.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the bill was passed.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
