<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1208188802" ordinal="34" title="RECOGNIZING DAVIDSON COLLEGE WILDCATS MEN'S BASKETBALL TEAM ON THEIR TREMENDOUS SEASON">
  <narrative>RECOGNIZING DAVIDSON COLLEGE WILDCATS MEN'S BASKETBALL TEAM ON THEIR TREMENDOUS SEASON -- (House of Representatives - April 14, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H2246]</narrative>
  <narrative>(Mr. WATT asked and was given permission to address the House for 1 minute and to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400424" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I rise today to recognize and pay tribute to Davidson College, President Tom Ross, Coach Bob McKillop, and the Davidson College Wildcats men's basketball team, which had one remarkable basketball season. Davidson College is one of a number of outstanding colleges and universities in my congressional district. The Wildcats basketball team finished its regular season undefeated in the Southern Conference, won the Southern Conference tournament, and went on to their third  consecutive NCAA tournament appearance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the NCAA tournament, Davidson College delivered three stunning upsets, eliminating the Gonzaga Bulldogs, the Georgetown Hoyas, and the Wisconsin Badgers on their way to the Elite Eight. In the Midwest regional finals, the Wildcats gave a tremendous effort before ultimately falling to Kansas by 2 points. Kansas, of course, went on to win the National Championship. By any measure Davidson College was the Cinderella team of this year's NCAA tournament.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In a fitting tribute to his coaching and leadership, Coach Bob McKillop received the Coach Clair Bee Award on April 7, honoring the NCAA Division I men's basketball coach who has made the most significant positive contribution to the sport during the year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I wish Coach McKillop and his Cinderella Davidson Wildcats continued success. I am fortunate to represent Davidson College and their outstanding scholars and athletes in Congress. We'll be back next year.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
