<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1174320004" ordinal="18" title="TAUNTON, MASSACHUSETTS, SPECIAL RESOURCES STUDY ACT">
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="1021">H.R. 1021</bill>) to direct the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a special resources study regarding the suitability and feasibility of designating certain historic buildings and areas in Taunton, Massachusetts, as a unit of the National Park System, and for other purposes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) and the gentleman from Utah (Mr. Bishop) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Arizona?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, <bill type="h" number="1021">H.R. 1021</bill> directs the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a special resources study to determine if certain historic buildings and areas in Taunton, Massachusetts, are suitable and feasible for designation as a unit of the National Park System. The bill was introduced by the gentleman from Massachusetts, Mr. BARNEY FRANK.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Taunton is a city rich in cultural and historic resources. The city is home to nine historic districts, with more than 600 properties on the National Registry of Historic Places. A comprehensive study of these resources will help to determine if inclusion within the National Park System is appropriate. This study will be completed in consultation with the State historic preservation officer, State Historical Society, and the city of Taunton and other appropriate organizations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I want to congratulate Representative Frank for his efforts on behalf of this legislation and this community. I would note that identical legislation was approved by the House in the last Congress, and we urge our colleagues to support the measure today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400029" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1021">H.R. 1021</bill> has been adequately explained by the majority, and we have no objection to this legislation. We also have no other speakers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="1021">H.R. 1021</bill>.</chair>
</record>
