<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1185336000" ordinal="30" title="SECOND HIGHER EDUCATION EXTENSION ACT of 2007">
  <narrative>SECOND HIGHER EDUCATION EXTENSION ACT of 2007 -- (House of Representatives - July 25, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H8411]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400179" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the Senate bill (<bill type="s" number="1868">S. 1868</bill>) to temporarily extend the programs under the Higher Education Act of 1965, and for other purposes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the Senate bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the Senate bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="s" number="1868">S. 1868</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "Second Higher Education Extension Act of 2007".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. EXTENSION OF PROGRAMS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Section 2(a) of the Higher Education Extension Act of 2005 (Public Law 109-81; 20 U.S.C. 1001 note) is amended by striking "July 31, 2007" and inserting "October 31, 2007".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 3. RULE OF CONSTRUCTION.</narrative>
  <narrative> Nothing in this Act, or in the Higher Education Extension Act of 2005 as amended by this Act, shall be construed to limit or otherwise alter the authorizations of appropriations for, or the durations of, programs contained in the amendments made by the Higher Education Reconciliation Act of 2005 (Public Law 109-171) to the provisions of the Higher Education Act of 1965 and the Taxpayer-Teacher Protection Act of 2004.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Texas (Mr. Hinojosa) and the gentleman from New York (Mr. Kuhl) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Texas.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400179" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I request 5 legislative days during which Members may insert materials relevant to <bill type="s" number="1868">S. 1868</bill> into the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Texas?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400179" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Mr. HINOJOSA asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400179" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I rise in strong support of <bill type="s" number="1868">S. 1868</bill>, a bill to extend the Higher Education Act through October 31, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill is very straightforward. It simply extends the current programs authorized under the Higher Education Act until October 31, 2007, giving us the time to fully consider and complete the reauthorization before us in the 110th Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are making progress. We have passed a historic investment in student financial aid in the College Cost Reduction Act. We have also laid the groundwork to reauthorize the other core higher education programs, including teacher preparation, developing and strengthening institutions, college readiness and outreach programs, including international education, graduate education and others. We put out a call for recommendations and received over 85 responses from individuals, organizations, and  coalitions from across the Nation. We hear them loud and clear.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am looking forward to working with all of my colleagues in the House to produce a strong reauthorization of the Higher Education Act that will earn broad support.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to thank Congressman McKeon, ranking member of the full committee, and Congressman RIC KELLER, ranking member of the Subcommittee on Higher Education, Lifelong Learning and Competitiveness, as well as our chairman, GEORGE MILLER, for working together with me to expedite this extension.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I respectfully urge all my colleagues to pass this legislation overwhelmingly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400642" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, for the last several years my colleagues on the Education and Labor Committee have worked to renew, and indeed improve, the Higher Education Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last Congress, we passed <bill type="h" number="609">H.R. 609</bill>, the College Access and Opportunity Act, which made important reforms to the Pell Grant program, the Perkins loan program, and provided more accountability in the area of college costs. Unfortunately, the Senate was not able to act, and the legislation died.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>This Congress, the House has passed the reforms to address some of the problems that have arisen in the student loan industry and has passed legislation that made changes to the mandatory spending programs under the Higher Education Act through the reconciliation process. As of yesterday, the Senate has passed both the reconciliation bill and the Higher Education Act reauthorization bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The latest extension of the Higher Education Act expires on July 31, 2007. Today, we are passing another extension through October 31, 2007. It is my hope that the House will soon renew the remaining Higher Education Act, but in the meantime Congress must once again act to extend this bill, which we have done so previously on several occasions with bipartisan support. So today I rise in support of legislation to do so once again.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="1868">S. 1868</bill>, the second Higher Education Act of 2007, will ensure that vital Federal college access and student aid programs continue, I repeat continue, to serve those students who depend upon them. This legislation extends the Higher Education Act for a brief time, just 3 months. At the same time, <bill type="s" number="1868">S. 1868</bill> also gives Congress additional time to complete a review of the remaining higher education programs as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I encourage my colleagues to support this bill before us today and work with us in the coming months to complete a fundamental reform package so that we can better serve the American students pursuing a college education.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400179" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I want to thank Congressman Kuhl from New York for his positive remarks on <bill type="s" number="1868">S. 1868</bill>, and together we are going to ask that our colleagues join us and pass this legislation overwhelmingly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Texas (Mr. Hinojosa) that the House suspend the rules and pass the Senate bill, <bill type="s" number="1868">S. 1868</bill>.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the Senate bill was passed.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
