<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1179331205" ordinal="30" title="PERSONAL EXPLANATION">
  <speaking speaker="400160" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, on rollcall No. 356, had I been present, I would have voted "present."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Pending is the demand of the gentleman from Georgia for a recorded vote.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 5-minute vote.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I yield to the gentleman from Hawaii (Mr. Abercrombie) for the purpose of making a unanimous consent request.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Mr. ABERCROMBIE asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400001" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, as disappointing as it may be for all the Members that I will not now deliver an oration, I will submit a formal statement on the work of the Air and Land Forces Subcommittee. I thank my good friend, colleague and mentor, Mr. Saxton, and all the Members, Republican and Democratic alike, on the Air and Land Forces Subcommittee.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I yield 4 minutes to my colleague and friend, the gentleman from Mississippi (Mr. Taylor), who is the chairman of the Subcommittee on Seapower and Expeditionary Forces.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400399" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I want to thank all of the Members of the Seapower and Expeditionary Forces Subcommittee for their cooperation on this. I want to thank in particular Ranking Member Saxton and Chairman Abercrombie for the funds that were transferred from their portions of the bill to address the immediate warfighter needs in Iraq.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, a disproportionately high number of Americans are dying in Iraq in explosions that involve Humvees. We as a Nation have spent a lot of money to protect the troops that ride in them. Unfortunately, the enemy has discovered that Humvees are vulnerable from the bottom. This bill includes $4.1 billion, ten times more than the President's request, to field a new generation of vehicles, a mine resistant ambush-protected vehicle, to protect the troops in Iraq. This could only be done  with the cooperation of the Air and Land Forces Subcommittee and the Seapower and Expeditionary Forces Subcommittee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Keep in mind that the President's budget request was actually written about a year ago. It is responding to the needs as we see them in the field, and I think a very good move. We also want to thank the great staff of the Seapower and Expeditionary Forces Subcommittee for the work that they have done.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The President asked for seven ships in this year's budget: a Gerald Ford class aircraft carrier; a Virginia-class submarine; an LPD 17; two LCSs; a T-AKE cargo ship; and a Joint High Speed Vessel. Because of the good work of the subcommittee and the cooperation of the other subcommittees of the Committee on Armed Services, this committee has added an additional LPD 17, an additional T-AKE cargo ship, and the forward funding for an additional submarine.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Bush administration's Defense budgets have grown by well over $100 billion during their tenure. Unfortunately, the Navy fleet has shrunk by 50 ships during the same time. This marks the first attempt on the part of the committee in a long time to reverse that trend and get our Nation back on course for a 313-ship Navy, and I want to thank all those who helped make that possible.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>Additionally, the bill funds a competitive engine program for the Joint Strike Fighter. It fully funds the administration's request for ship and aviation construction and procurement. It fully funds the administration's request for the operation of the Maritime Administration.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill would allow the Secretary of the Navy to come up with a program for capital expenditure in shipbuilding to help modernize our shipyard infrastructure and reduce the cost of our Navy ships to the taxpayers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It will allow for the multi-year procurement for Virginia-class submarines, and it will direct the Secretary of the Navy to design and construct the next generation of surface warships with integrated nuclear power systems.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, it makes no sense at all to have aircraft carriers that carry 30 years' worth of fuel on board when the vessels that are necessary to protect them have to refuel every 5 days. We are addressing this vulnerability to our fleet and, more importantly, we are taking a huge step on behalf of the Department of Defense to make our Nation less dependent on foreign sources of fuel.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to acknowledge that none of these initiatives could have taken place without the great cooperation and leadership on the part of the former chairman, Mr. Bartlett. Addressing the nuclear power issue is a direct result of his making the committee aware of our vulnerabilities to fuel, and the need for shipyard modernization again is a direct result of his efforts while he was chairman. It is also with the great cooperation of the minority and the members of our staff that  we present this portion of the bill to the Congress and ask for its approval.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="NOTICE TO ALTER ORDER OF CONSIDERATION OF AMENDMENTS">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, pursuant to sections 3 and 4 of House Resolution 403, and as the chairman of the Armed Services Committee, I request that during further consideration of <bill type="h" number="1585">H.R. 1585</bill> in the Committee of the Whole and following general debate, the following amendments be considered in this order: amendment No. 33, amendment No. 29, amendment No. 49, the en bloc package, and amendment No. 8, amendment No. 14, amendment No. 21, and amendment No. 38.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400359" topic="NOTICE TO ALTER ORDER OF CONSIDERATION OF AMENDMENTS">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I yield 3 minutes to the ranking member of the Military Personnel Subcommittee, the gentleman from New York (Mr. McHugh).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400264" topic="NOTICE TO ALTER ORDER OF CONSIDERATION OF AMENDMENTS">
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, I rise simply to say, as we have heard from previous speakers, and perhaps to state the obvious, this piece of legislation, <bill type="h" number="1585">H.R. 1585</bill>, is a strong bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>More importantly, in my judgment it is a bill that was put together in a collaborative and bipartisan manner. I want to pay my respects, my words of appreciation to the full committee Chair, the gentleman from Missouri (Mr. Skelton), who came through this, his first trial by fire, I think, with great efficiency; as well as, of course, the gentleman from California (Mr. Hunter), the former chairman, now ranking member. But most importantly, I want to thank the new chairman of  the Personnel Subcommittee, a gentleman who I had the honor and opportunity to serve with as the ranking member when I had the opportunity to serve as Chair, Dr. Vic Snyder, who worked together again in a bipartisan manner, and in that way has produced  a product which I think overall we can all support with not just a great deal of enthusiasm but a great deal of pride.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>All of us feel very strongly on the Personnel Subcommittee that when the Members come to the floor, it is good that they talk about the broad range of effects and benefits in this bill. But it makes us feel proud, Madam Chair, when we note that those things that the Members take most pride in and cite most often are a product of the work of the Personnel Subcommittee. The reason for that is very, very simple.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The success of the United States military is today, as it has always been, not in high weapons systems, as important as they are, not in sophisticated platforms, not in all of those things that give our fighting men and women an edge, but the true edge is in the fighting men and women themselves. And this bill contains many benefits, many added advantages that they so richly deserve.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It provides an increase in end strength, something we have taken up and we need to continue, is embodied in this bill. A basic pay raise that will continue the 8-year effort we have had to increase the pay of our men and women in uniform, drawing down that pay gap between the civilian and military forces, drawing it down currently under the ramp to 2012 when it will be as little as 1.5 percent, resisting so-called efficiency wedges and savings in the TRICARE and other military health care programs,  saving money for those hardworking men and women protecting our interests wherever they may be, here at home, and their families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Wounded Warrior Assistance Program that I had the honor of working with, along with Dr. Snyder, and along with the chairman and the ranking member to address those challenges that we saw so very dishearteningly at places like Walter Reed and others.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>All of this combined is a good bill that works on a bipartisan basis. I urge all of my colleagues to support the bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="NOTICE TO ALTER ORDER OF CONSIDERATION OF AMENDMENTS">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I yield 2 minutes to my friend and colleague, the gentleman from Washington (Mr. Smith), who is the chairman of the Subcommittee on Terrorism and Unconventional Threats and Capabilities.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400379" topic="NOTICE TO ALTER ORDER OF CONSIDERATION OF AMENDMENTS">
    <paragraph>Thank you, Madam Chair.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First of all, I want to thank the chairman of the Armed Services Committee, Ike Skelton, for the fantastic job he has done on this mark. He has done it in a bipartisan fashion. And also, of greatest importance, this mark funds the war that we are fighting.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have troops in the field in harm's way. We fund the priorities that they need right now. And given all of the demands on the Armed Services Committee, that is no easy feat. The chairman and all members of the committee have made that a priority, and I want to thank him for that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also believe that we have well-funded the broader war on terrorism that my subcommittee has a significant part of, Subcommittee on Terrorism.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The fight against al Qaeda and the ideology they espouse and those who would support al Qaeda or that ideology is not just in one place. It is in many places in the world. It is in Africa, Southeast Asia, certainly in the Middle East and elsewhere. To combat that ideology, we need a force that is trained in unconventional warfare, that is trained in asymmetric warfare, and we need the Special Operations Forces who are trained to go into parts of the world, to understand the culture and work with  the local communities and stop al Qaeda-like insurgencies before they start. That training is critical.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is much easier to fight that type of battle than to get dragged into a larger war. We have had incredible success in places like the Philippines and Chad and Kenya and elsewhere because our Special Operations Forces understand irregular warfare, get in there and work with the local communities to stop insurgencies before they start. I believe this mark reflects that priority. It is certainly one of the highest priorities for our subcommittee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank the ranking member, the gentleman from Texas (Mr. Thornberry), for his leadership on this issue as well. We have put language, money and report language in the bill that will prioritize irregular warfare, unconventional fights, so that we can defeat al Qaeda globally and understand all of the different challenges that go into that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, I thank the gentleman from Missouri (Mr. Skelton) for his outstanding leadership of this committee. It is a privilege and honor to serve with him, and to thank him for this mark and this bill that I think adequately prepares our military to fight the battles we face.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400359" topic="NOTICE TO ALTER ORDER OF CONSIDERATION OF AMENDMENTS">
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, I would like to yield such time as he may consume to the ranking member of the Seapower Subcommittee, Mr. Bartlett.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400017" topic="NOTICE TO ALTER ORDER OF CONSIDERATION OF AMENDMENTS">
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, I rise in strong support of <bill type="h" number="1585">H.R. 1585</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, I would like to take this opportunity to recognize the outstanding service rendered to the Nation by our men and women in uniform, who, like their forebears, are meeting today's security challenges with true dedication and professionalism.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would also like to thank the gentleman from Mississippi (Mr. Taylor), chairman of the Seapower and Expeditionary Forces Subcommittee on which I serve as ranking member, for his leadership, for his friendship which I really appreciate, and unwavering commitment to our servicemembers. I also want to thank our very capable staff.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, I think our colleagues will find that this bill reflects a fair and balanced treatment of the issues facing the United States Navy and Marine Corps. In collaboration with the Air and Land Forces Subcommittee and Chairman Skelton and Ranking Member Hunter, we provided full funding for the Mine Resistant Ambush Protected Vehicle, or MRAP, which is protecting our troops against IEDs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By strengthening the shipbuilding program and authorizing eight new ships, we addressed the Navy's number one and number two unfunded priorities. We must reverse the steady decline in the number of battle force ships we have seen for nearly two decades.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nevertheless, in order to provide the number of ships our warfighters say they need, we must inject fiscal discipline into our shipbuilding program. To that end, <bill type="h" number="1585">H.R. 1585</bill> includes a provision that would limit the practice of design and build concurrency, a practice which has delayed and increased costs for a number of shipbuilding programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Continuing efforts from prior years' Defense authorization bills, we have included a provision to push for modernization in shipyards through process, infrastructure improvements, and workforce training.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An April 2007 study commissioned by the Department of Defense found that the risks associated with the cost and supply of oil will make the U.S. military's ability to rapidly deploy on demand "unsustainable in the long term."</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1585">H.R. 1585</bill> also forges new ground by requiring that future major combatant vessels have integrated nuclear propulsion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I conclude by applauding the remaining provisions in the bill supporting the Navy and Marine Corps and authorizing appropriations and authorities for the Maritime Administration. I urge full support of <bill type="h" number="1585">H.R. 1585</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="NOTICE TO ALTER ORDER OF CONSIDERATION OF AMENDMENTS">
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, I yield 3 minutes to the gentlewoman from California (Mrs. Tauscher) who is the chairwoman of the Subcommittee on Strategic Forces.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400396" topic="NOTICE TO ALTER ORDER OF CONSIDERATION OF AMENDMENTS">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, first I would like to congratulate the gentleman from Missouri, the distinguished chairman of the committee, on his first mark of the national security defense bill. He is a fabulous member and a great leader. I appreciate all of the hard work that has been put into this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also want to thank my ranking member, the gentleman from Alabama (Mr. Everett), for his hard work and his willingness to work in a bipartisan way to achieve what I consider to be a very significant mark for the Strategic Forces Subcommittee; also, the members of the subcommittee and our fabulous staff.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, this bill is a bill that I have worked on with my colleagues to incorporate four priorities into the bill before the House.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, this bill aims to create a public discussion about nuclear weapons by  establishing a congressionally appointed bipartisan commission designed to reevaluate U.S. strategic posture. This commission would provide valuable recommendations to Congress regarding the proper mix of conventional and nuclear weapons needed to meet new and emerging threats.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second, the bill slows the Department of Energy nuclear weapons initiatives. We limit reliable replacement warhead funds to design and cost study activities and eliminate funding for the proposed Consolidated Plutonium Center. Instead, we increase funding to strengthen the Stockpile Stewardship Program, as well as the weapons complex.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Third, the bill funds ballistic missile defense systems that will protect the American people, our deployed troops, and allies against real threats while shifting resources away from longer term, high-risk efforts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It fully funds the Army missile defense budget request for the Patriot PAC-3 missile, including funding for the Patriot "Pure Fleet" initiative.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It fully funds the Ground Based Missile Defense System to protect the United States against a potential threat from North Korea or Iran.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It includes funding for Aegis BMD and fully funds THAAD development and deployment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, we are boosting funding for space capabilities that deliver near-term benefits to the warfighter and improve space situational awareness and survivability.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, this bill strikes a balance between near-term needs and long-term investment, and it creates the means to help bring our nuclear weapons policies into the 21st century. I urge my colleagues to support this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400359" topic="NOTICE TO ALTER ORDER OF CONSIDERATION OF AMENDMENTS">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I yield 4 minutes to the ranking member of the Terrorism Subcommittee, the gentleman from Texas (Mr. Thornberry).</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400404" topic="NOTICE TO ALTER ORDER OF CONSIDERATION OF AMENDMENTS">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, I want to express my strong support for that section of the bill which was produced by the Terrorism and Unconventional Threats and Capabilities Subcommittee. I especially appreciate the efforts and cooperative spirit of the chairman, Adam Smith, and the work of the subcommittee members and the staff.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As he mentioned a few moments ago, that section of the bill supports the 5-year growth plan for the Special Operations Forces, which was recommended by the 2005 QDR. It also improves the Department's ability to harness technological innovation and funds the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency, DARPA, as well as other basic research in the Department.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, as we discuss the various sections of this very large bill, I also think it is important that we step back and remember the broader context in which we operate. One is that we face a ruthless, determined, adaptable adversary who at this moment is concentrating their efforts in Afghanistan and Iraq, but poses a threat to us and our allies all over the world. We live in a world where technology that can destroy massive numbers of human lives is spreading around the world, and some  of the places where that technology exists are not as politically stable as we would like.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We face threats to our country using some of the very technology we rely upon, whether it's satellites or whether it's the Internet; and in the face of all that, we have national security structures that were developed during the Cold War. And as with all large organizations, the Department of Defense and other government agencies have a difficult time adapting.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It may be that the most important part of this bill is the funding of a study to recommend changes in the National Security Act of 1947, which will help us be better organized and better adaptable for the security challenges in the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, I'd like to make one other point that concerns me about the broader national security context in which we operate. There is much that is in this bill that is very good. We will debate some important amendments and a lot of amendments that are not that deal with smaller issues, and then I expect that this bill will pass by a very large vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And then next week or the week thereafter, we are going to have another vote that will undercut much of the good that is in this bill by giving hope to our enemies and discouragement to our friends. This Congress will pat itself on the back for passing a pay raise for the troops, but then it will tie the hands of the commanders who are sent to implement the Nation's strategy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This Congress will make the job of the military in fighting terrorists in key places harder by the political debate and by the actions we take; and so I would encourage Members to read and study "Unconventional Warfare," and I think they will find, as one writer put it, that it uses all available networks, political, economic, social and military, to convince the enemy's political decision-makers that their goals are unachievable or too costly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And so, Madam Chair, it would seem to me to be a sad day if this Congress takes action that undoes the good that our military does every day on the ground, the achievements that they win in the field; and yet I fear, by some of the votes that we've taken, that may be dangerously the direction we may be headed.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400359" topic="NOTICE TO ALTER ORDER OF CONSIDERATION OF AMENDMENTS">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairwoman, I yield the remainder of this minute to the gentleman from Georgia (Mr. Westmoreland) for purposes of a motion.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400627" topic="MOTION TO RISE BY MR. WESTMORELAND">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I move that the Committee do now rise.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair/>
  <speaking speaker="400627" topic="MOTION TO RISE BY MR. WESTMORELAND">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I demand a recorded vote, and pending that, I make the point of order that a quorum is not present.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Chair will count for a quorum. Does the gentleman withdraw his point of order?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400627" topic="MOTION TO RISE BY MR. WESTMORELAND">
    <paragraph>No, Madam Chairman, I do not.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Evidently a quorum is not present.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This is a 5-minute vote.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, may I inquire as to the time remaining on each side on general debate, please.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from Missouri has 24 1/2  minutes remaining. The gentleman from New Jersey has 21 minutes remaining.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is deadly serious business, Madam Chairwoman. I have witnessed here the number of procedural motions, which I have refrained from commenting upon, but this is deadly serious business.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a bill to authorize funds for the United States military. That is our constitutional job to do. And procedural motions are fine, but let's get on with taking care of the troops and giving them their pay raise and the medical care and the equipment that they need.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As we say back in Missouri, "'nough said."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield 4 minutes to the gentleman from Texas (Mr. Reyes).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400337" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, I thank the gentleman for yielding, and couldn't agree more with his comments on how serious this authorization is and our duty to do what we have been sent here to do, especially today for our military.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So with that, Madam Chair, I rise to express strong support for <bill type="h" number="1585">H.R. 1585</bill>. And I want to thank the gentleman from Missouri (Mr. Skelton), our chairman, and the ranking member, Mr. Hunter, for the great job that they have done on crafting together a piece of legislation that is so vital and important.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Having said that, Madam Chair, in July of 2008, the Army will conduct a limited user test with soldiers from the Army Evaluation Task Force based at Fort Bliss using the first spinout of the FCS technologies. I know that the gentleman from Missouri understands how critical the first spinout of FCS technologies is for our Nation's warfighters, our warfighters that are currently at war in Iraq and Afghanistan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I would now like to yield to the chairman of the Armed Services Committee in the hope of entering into a colloquy so that he can discuss how the bill addresses this very important and vital issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield to the chairman.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairwoman, I thank the gentleman for yielding. And first I want the gentleman from Texas to know how much the committee appreciates his strong support for our Nation's Armed Forces, particularly for the United States Army. He is just superb. The Army is bearing the brunt of the burden of military operations in Iraq, as well as Afghanistan, and our committee has worked to ensure that soldiers on the ground have the equipment they need to accomplish their mission and come home  safely.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Beyond taking care of the needs of the warfighters in the field today, we must address the Army's long-term modernization and readiness requirements. That is why the bill before us here today fully funds the most critical elements of the Future Combat Systems program, which will keep the program on track to conduct the limited user test next summer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While the bill cuts some funding for some redundant programs and overhead costs, along with parts of the program which are not scheduled to be fielded until 2015, the $2.8 billion in the bill includes full funding for all Spinout 1 activities, allowing them to continue as planned.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to assure the gentleman from Texas that we will continue our efforts to balance the Army's immediate near-term as well as long-term needs as we work through the conference process. As Congressman Abercrombie said last week during consideration of the bill in the committee, finding that balance is a work in progress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To the gentleman from Texas, you have my assurance that we will provide funding for the FCS program so that the Army can move forward with modernizing its equipment and its networks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As we focus our efforts, as we focus our dollars on today's soldiers, we can't shortchange our future forces.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400337" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Reclaiming my time. I thank the gentleman for his efforts in support of our military forces. Our soldiers, sailors, airmen, and marines have no better friend in Congress than IKE SKELTON; and on behalf of the Fifth Brigade of the First Armored Division at Fort Bliss, I want to thank the chairman for his assurance that their work in support of FCS and Army modernization, as they prepare for the test event next summer, will not be affected by the bill that we are debating today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>FCS represents the cornerstone of the Army's modernization plans, and I appreciate the chairman's understanding of the need to continue investing in the Army's future even as we face the challenges of today's wars in Iraq and Afghanistan.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400359" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, I yield 3 minutes to the gentleman from Missouri (Mr. Akin), the ranking member of the Oversight Subcommittee.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400005" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, one of the things that you can be only an amateur student of are various battles, or military history, and it becomes immediately obvious, the importance of information. Just randomly, you can think of Pearl Harbor, knowing whether the Japanese are coming. Or, particularly, the Battle of Midway, where you have the Japanese force, far superior to the American force, but the Americans knew where the Japanese aircraft carriers were and the Japanese only knew where one of the  American aircraft carriers was. As a result, America won that significant Battle of Midway, even though we had an inferior force, based on information.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, I have heard discussion about how proud we are of Future Combat Systems, which is a fancy word for a computerized system to help our warfighters have the information that they need in order to do their job. That program is the first major Army modernization program in 40 years, and under this bill, it is being cut by 25 percent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>This was not a feel good kind of vote. This was a strict party-line vote, the Democrats voting to cut it by 25 percent, the Republicans trying to restore funds and being turned down in that request.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, when you cut a program by 25 percent, particularly as complicated as this is with all the computers that are talking to each other, the software, the communications disciplines and the platforms involved, that is a significant change and a significant slowdown to a very important part of our future, and that is the ability to have real-time, online information for our warfighters.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is not just important to the Army, as important as it is to the Army, because the Marines and the Navy are going to be waiting also for perhaps a lot of this software to be the prototype for their systems that they develop later. So what we are doing is basically pushing back, slowing and delaying and cutting down 25 percent, or $867 million, from this program. We have tried to replace those funds some, with some things that are completely not necessary, such as a high speed boat for the  Army, which hasn't even been designed, and have been turned down and not even allowed to offer that amendment here on the floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, who is it who is going to pay for this degradation of the modernization of our Army? It is going to be our sons and daughters, my own sons that are involved, and this is not a good thing. This is not a good trade-off. We must advance the modernization. Information has always throughout history been critical to warfare. It is all the more so now.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And so I am strongly opposed to this significant cut and the hurting of our ability to get information to our warfighter.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400337" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, I now would like to yield 2 minutes to our friend and colleague from California, the gentlelady, Ms. SANCHEZ. </paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400356" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I rise today in support of <bill type="h" number="1585">H.R. 1585</bill>, the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to thank my chairman, Mr. Skelton, for his really great work in producing a Defense bill with support from both sides of the aisle. It is commendable that Chairman Skelton was able to pass this bill on a vote of 58-0, given the heated and the very polarized debates that we were having in the House Armed Services Committee, especially with respect to the war in Iraq.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And as Chairman Skelton has repeatedly said, the purpose of this bill is to provide our troops with the equipment and the support that they need to carry out their mission.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I, for example, voted against granting the President the authority to use force in Iraq, and I have continued to question his repeated surges and his failing policies in Iraq. I have repeatedly asked the President to provide a plan to safely redeploy our troops to come home from Iraq.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But, having said this, until we can get our brave men and women home from Iraq, we must provide them with what they need to perform their mission. And that is what this bill does. At the same time, it asks the tough questions of the Defense Department and of this President.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One question, for example, that I have for the Department of Defense that I have been asking over and over for the last 4 years, what happened to the approximately 329,000 Iraqi security forces that had been trained? Specifically, where are they assigned? Are they reporting for duty? Or are they now working for the insurgency? And this bill asks that question.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Defense authorization bill as a whole asks for accountability and for oversight from the President and from the Department of Defense. And I ask my colleagues to stand together and to pass this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400359" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairlady, I'd like to yield 3 minutes to the gentleman from Minnesota, who joined this House several years ago after having spent 25 years in the Marine Corps, Congressman JOHN KLINE. </paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400224" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, I'd like to take this opportunity to thank the committee members and Chairmen SKELTON and SNYDER for their support of the Yellow Ribbon Reintegration Program in this year's Defense authorization bill in the en bloc amendment. Inclusion of this program in the bill will move us forward as we seek to fill a gap that has only widened as our Nation has come to rely increasingly on the National Guard and Reserves to assist in combat operations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Based upon his experiences as a returning Vietnam War veteran, Minnesota National Guard Adjutant General Larry Shellito took the lead to build a reintegration program for returning Guardsmen who lack the established support infrastructure of their active duty counterparts. General Shellito and the Minnesota National Guard leadership have developed an innovative program to change how returning soldiers and airmen are reintegrated back into their communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Through experiences drawn from the deployments of smaller units to Iraq and Afghanistan and Kosovo, they developed a unique combat veteran reintegration program with a focus on supporting soldiers and their families throughout the entire deployment cycle. This multifaceted program includes workshops for families and communities to help them for their servicemember's return and training events at 30, 60 and 90-day intervals for servicemembers following their demobilization.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The training events have given Guardsmen and Reservists the opportunity to engage VA and health care representatives, while also allowing platoon sergeants and commanders to check in with their troops. Experience has shown that catching signs of post-traumatic stress disorder, substance abuse, or even marital problems early can prevent even more severe problems in the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe the Yellow Ribbon Reintegration Program represents the best ideas of not only Minnesota but also States and territories throughout the Nation that have stepped in to provide reintegration services to their troops.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As envisioned, the Yellow Ribbon program included members of the other Reserve components in only a voluntary, unpaid status due to financial constraints. So I would like to thank Chairmen SKELTON and SNYDER for their support in finding the additional funding necessary to expand this program beyond the National Guard to all Reservists.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me just close by saying that this program has the support of Lieutenant General Blum, the chief of the National Guard Bureau and many other organizations, the National Guard Association of the United States, the Enlisted Association of the National Guard of the United States, the Naval Reserve Association, the Noncommissioned Officers Association, and the Retired Enlisted Association. I will submit those letters for the Record.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, I would like to thank Chairmen SKELTON and SNYDER for their hard work in making this possible.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>AND THE AIR FORCE,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Arlington, VA, May 4, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR CONGRESSMAN KLINE: As you describe in your letter, the Minnesota National Guard's "Beyond the Yellow Ribbon Reintegration" program does a great job filling the gap in transition assistance services experienced by all Reserve Component members returning from a combat deployment. I consistently hear from Adjutants General, our troops and their families that the current transition program conducted at the active component demobilization station doesn't well serve the needs of the National  Guard and the other Reserve components.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We see, for example, that many DD Form 214, Certificate of Release or Discharge from Active Duty, prepared at the active duty demobilization station contain significant errors and require correction at the home station. As you know from your own military experience, the DD 214 is an essential ticket to access veteran's benefits. The time required to correct these forms is a burden on our veterans. Like the rest of the transition assistance program of health care, education, VA and employment  counseling, Minnesota, among other states, has demonstrated that it can be provided better at the home station.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Several states participated in a National Guard-wide working group convened last fall to capture the best practices nationwide. The recommendations of that working group echo the results of previous twenty-four months of DoD working groups in which my staff has participated. We have just begun another DoD working group, this one chartered by Congress on the subject of Guard and Reserve transition to civilian employment. That report is due to Congress in October 2007. There are several very effective  programs in our States to model--the solution set to this issue is well defined. The National Guard Bureau has well documented lessons learned from studying this issue. The need for more time to accomplish transition assistance at the home station is clear.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Providing a better transition and reintegration experience for our Guardsmen is a top priority for me and Lieutenant General Clyde Vaughn, the director of the Army National Guard. There are currently 37,000 Guardsmen deployed to fight the war on terror. It's expected that another 60,000 will deploy within the next 18 months. Almost a full third of the National Guard and their families will require transition assistance in the near term. A national program, implemented swiftly, would arrive just  in time for them. I salute and appreciate your continuing interest in the welfare of our National Guardsmen.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Lieutenant General, U.S. Army, </paragraph>
    <paragraph>OF THE UNITED STATES, INC.,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington, DC, May 8, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR REPRESENTATIVE KLINE: Since the first militia units were formed in Massachusetts on December 13, 1636, the National Guard has been an indispensable part of our nation's Armed Forces. Members of the National Guard have performed their "federal" mission with distinction in every major conflict.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Until recently, the National Guard was considered a "Strategic Reserve." However, as the Cold War ended, troop levels in all of our Armed Services were reduced, resulting in the Guard representing a higher percentage of the Total Force. Terrorist attacks by Muslim extremists and other conflicts such as the Balkans, Afghanistan and Iraq have required the United States to take military actions, resulting in significant Guard "call ups." The National Guard is now an "Operational Force," a  fact clearly articulated by all senior Pentagon leaders.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After risking their lives during deployments, our returning National Guard members often return to civilian life confronting health care issues, legal uncertainties, strained relationships, unemployment, depression, and Post Traumatic Stress Disorders requiring follow-on assistance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>NGAUS strongly supports <bill type="h" number="2090">H.R. 2090</bill> now before the 110th Congress which seeks to strengthen and coordinate the programs and benefits available to National Guard members in the critical reintegration process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We owe the young men and women, who are selflessly serving our states and nation, the tools and resources they need to reintegrate with their families and communities upon their return. Anything less is an abrogation of our responsibilities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Brigadier General, USAF, (ret.), </paragraph>
    <paragraph>ENLISTED ASSOCIATION OF THE NATIONAL GUARD OF THE UNITED STATES,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Alexandria, VA, May 8, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Enlisted Association of the National Guard of the United States (EANGUS) is the only military service association that represents the interests of every enlisted soldier and airmen in the Army and Air National Guard. With a constituency base of over 414,000 men and women, their families, and a large retiree membership, EANGUS engages Capitol Hill on behalf of courageous Guard persons across this nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On behalf of EANGUS, I'd like to offer our letter of support for <bill type="h" number="2090">H.R. 2090</bill>, the Yellow Ribbon Reintegration Program Act of 2007. Your legislation will establish a national combat veteran reintegration program to  provide National Guard members and their families with sufficient information, services, referrals, and proactive outreach opportunities throughout the entire deployment cycle.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The model of excellence which began in Minnesota will be a beacon of what right looks like for the rest of the nation. This legislation outlines the program and designates the resources that the National Guard will use to provide assistance where it is most needed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thank you for your continued support of our military and veterans. If our association can be of further help, feel free to contact our Legislative Director, SGM (Ret) Frank Yoakum.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Working for America's Best!</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Michael P. Cline,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>ASSOCIATION OF AMERICA,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Alexandria, VA, May 8, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR REPRESENTATIVE KLINE: On behalf of the nearly 362,000 members of the Military Officers Association of America (MOAA), I am writing to express our support for your bill, <bill type="h" number="2090">H.R. 2090</bill>, to improve transition services for returning National Guard and reserve veterans of the war on terror.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nearly six hundred thousand of our nation's citizen-warriors have served on active duty since 9/11 and many thousands more are in the deployment pipeline for second or third tours. The special challenges of reintegrating them back into their communities are addressed in your legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2090">H.R. 2090</bill> would establish a national combat veteran reintegration program that models the best practices of state programs to provide reserve component combat veterans and their families the information, outreach support and services they need throughout the entire deployment cycle.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Traditional transition assistance programs (TAP) are not meeting the unique needs of our Guard and Reserve troops and their families. Your bill provides a funding network of support that will have a direct impact on the reenlistment and continuation decisions of overstressed citizen-warriors. Your bill supports military personnel readiness in the long war on terror.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>MOAA strongly supports integrating your bill as an amendment to the House version of the National Defense Authorization Act for FY 2008 and expanding the program as quickly as possible to meet the needs of other mobilized reserve component troops.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Norbert Ryan, Jr.,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>NAVAL RESERVE ASSOCIATION,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Alexandria, VA, May 8, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR REPRESENTATIVE KLINE: On behalf of the 23,000 members of the Naval Reserve Association and 73,000 members of the Navy Reserve, I am writing to express our support for your bill, <bill type="h" number="2090">H.R. 2090</bill>, to improve transition services for returning Navy Reservist, and Reserve Component veterans of the war on terror.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nearly six hundred thousand of our Nation's citizen-warriors have served on active duty since 9/11 and many thousands more are in the deployment pipeline for second or third tours. The special challenges of reintegrating them back into their communities are addressed in your legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2090">H.R. 2090</bill> would establish a national combat veteran reintegration program that models the best practices of state programs to provide reserve component combat veterans and their families the information, outreach support and services they need throughout the entire deployment cycle.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Traditional transition assistance programs (TAP) are not meeting the unique needs of our Guard and Reserve troops and their families. Your bill provides a funding network of support that will have a direct impact on the reenlistment and continuation decisions of overstressed citizen-warriors. Your bill supports military personnel readiness in the long war on terror.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Naval Reserve Association strongly supports integrating your bill as an amendment to the House version of the National Defense Authoriztion Act for FY 2008 and expanding the program as quickly as possible to meet the needs of other mobilized reserve component troops.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>RADM, USNR (Ret.),</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Non-Commissioned Officers Association of the United States of America,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Alexandria, VA, May 8, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR REPRESENTATIVE KLINE: I write on behalf of the Members of the Non Commissioned Officers Association to express our support of your bill, <bill type="h" number="2090">H.R. 2090</bill>, to improve transition services for returning members of the National Guard and Reserve veterans from America's war on terror.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2090">H.R. 2090</bill> would establish a national combat veteran reintegration program that models the best practices of state programs to serve reserve component combat veterans, their families, and survivors with information, outreach support, and vital services they need throughout the entire deployment cycle.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Approximately six hundred thousand of our nation's citizen-soldiers have served on active duty since 9/11. Many of these members of the Guard and Reserve and thousands more are in the rotational deployment schedule for a second or third tour. Your legislation is a remarkable step forward to address the transitional needs as they return to their communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Traditional transition assistance programs (TAP) do not meet the unique needs of members of the Guard and Reserve and their families. The funding network of support proposed in your legislation will directly impact reenlistment and continuation decisions of personnel overcome by the rigors of involvement in the nation's extended war on terror.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The NCOA would strongly advocate that your bill be integrated as an amendment in the House version of the National Defense Authorization Act for FY 2008. We need to ramp up programs to meet the needs of all mobilized reserve component personnel.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Richard C. Schneider,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>THE RETIRED ENLISTED ASSOCIATION,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Alexandria, VA, May 8, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dear Congressman Kline: On behalf of the more than 100,000 members of The Retired Enlisted Association (TREA), their spouses and families, I am writing in support of your legislation, <bill type="h" number="2090">H.R. 2090</bill>, the Yellow Ribbon Reintegration Program Act of 2007. It has been obvious for quite some time that members of the Reserve Component of America's Armed Forces lack the same kinds of support programs when they return from overseas combat theaters that active duty personnel have. Your bill will go  far in rectifying that lack of support and we whole-heartedly and enthusiastically support its passage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many of our members are retired from the Guard and Reserve components and they still care deeply about those who continue to serve. While the situation has changed dramatically in recent years, you may recall that in the past Guard and Reserve personnel were often treated as "poor stepchildren" when it came to benefits afforded them in return for their service to our nation. Now that they have become full operational partners of our nation Armed Forces, they must receive the benefits and services  they need and deserve and your bill to establish a national combat veteran reintegration program will help accomplish that goal.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>TREA strongly supports integration of your bill as an amendment to the House version of the FY 2008 National Defense Authorization Act and we look forward to its enactment into law in the coming months.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Larry Madison,</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400337" topic="MILITARY OFFICERS">
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, I now yield 2 minutes to my good friend and colleague, the gentleman from New Jersey (Mr. Andrews).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Mr. ANDREWS asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400008" topic="MILITARY OFFICERS">
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, I rise in support of this bill which I believe merits the support of Members of both parties because it makes three strategic judgements that are very sound and very right.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, it makes the judgment that the highest priority of the Congress should be the pay, the benefits and the well-being of the families of the men and women who wear the uniform of the country. Together, as Republicans and Democrats, we're doing more in this bill than we've ever done before to serve those needs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second, this bill makes the right strategic judgment to deal with the urgent present needs of men and women in theater in the field. Yes, this is at the expense of future systems that will some day aid our competitive edge. And I believe in funding those systems. But the choice we need to make today is the up-armored vehicles, the weaponry, the training, the support for men and women in Iraq, in Afghanistan, in the heat of battle today. This is the right strategic judgment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, this bill decides to take $764 million out of strategic missile defense, still giving the President 91.5 percent of what he asked for, and spending the money on securing loose nuclear material in the former Soviet Union, spending the money on converting reactors that could be turned into bomb material in the former Soviet Union. These threats were identified as the principal threat to the national security by the 9/11 Commission. This is the right strategic judgment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For these and many other reasons, I would urge both Democrats and Republicans to vote "yes" on this very fine bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400359" topic="MILITARY OFFICERS">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairlady, I'd like to yield 4 minutes to the ranking member of the Veterans' Affairs Committee, the gentleman from Indiana (Mr. Buyer).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400056" topic="MILITARY OFFICERS">
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, I come to the floor once again to defend veterans and the country. And I'm also equally disappointed that there are not many veterans willing to stand in the well against provisions in the Defense bill that would increase the price of prescription drugs in the VA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, why don't I have enough friends in the well? Well, they're going to have to answer for themselves for that question.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But what is occurring here in the House is an assault upon drug manufacturers in the country. There is this quest and design that, let's get what available drug there is out there to everyone at the lowest price. How wonderful that would be.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We, in this country, have a unique system. It's called the free market. It's called capitalism. We say unto the world, bring your greatest minds to America. You can go to the capital market, you can make an investment at risk to press the bounds of science that will increase the quality of life of our people and those around the world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Yet, there's an assault upon that system. The assault continues. It began in January whereby the Democrat majority wanted to extend Medicare drug pricing by saying, let's take the VA Federal Supply Schedule and extend that into the Medicare. Bad idea. Democrats tried that back in 1990 and found out that, whoa, that increased drug prices to veterans, and repealed it. But they passed it again in January.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, what did they do in the Defense bill? In this Defense bill they've now taken the extension of the Federal Supply Schedule and extended it into the retail drug pharmacy benefit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When I did the redesign of the TRICARE pharmacy benefit in the Department of Defense, I created not only the retail network pharmacy benefit, I created the out of retail network pharmacy benefit, and at no time did I ever, ever, believe that we would extend Federal Supply Schedule into the TRICARE pharmacy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So what is about to happen? When you take the system in the VA and you extend that, and you create the pool and make it larger, you are cost shifting. And when you cost shift, you're going to increase these prices in the VA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, in the VA that's about 7 million veterans. It's about 1 percent of the market. You say, oh, Steve, that's not a big number. Well, it is ironic to me how Members will pound their chests and say, well, you know, I said no to an increase in a pharmacy copay, but they're about to vote "yes" to increase drug prices for veterans when they vote for this Defense bill. This is wrong, and it should not be done, and I'm appealing to Members not to do this.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And I am disturbed, disturbed that my good friend, Ike Skelton, denied two of my amendments. I've worked for 15 years with Chairman Skelton on many, many different issues, and I am stunned that he would deny my opportunity to offer two amendments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One was very simple. It would be to have the Secretary certify that before he could implement this program you have to certify it will not increase prices on the VA. Why would you deny that amendment?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>They are going to deny the amendment because they know, going into this, that the creation of this program is going to increase prices on veterans. I just cannot believe we're about to do that here.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Secondly, we should listen to the experts. If you're about to deny a particular drug under the formulary on TRICARE, you'd better have a pretty good reason, and we ought to be able to go to the committee to do that. But they're not going to do that. At this point I am pretty disturbed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400359" topic="MILITARY OFFICERS">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400383" topic="MILITARY OFFICERS">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I yield 1 1/2  minutes to my colleague the gentlewoman from California (Mrs. Davis).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400097" topic="MILITARY OFFICERS">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I rise today in support of <bill type="h" number="1585">H.R. 1585</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation recognizes the extraordinary efforts by our servicemembers and makes great strides towards resetting our force and ensuring our overall readiness. However, it is only the beginning.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We know that part of readiness is having a military health care system that understands the strains on our force and is capable of handling the mental health needs of our servicemembers both at home and abroad. If we are going to deploy our men and women at the current pace, we must, we must, make sure we understand the consequences of our policy decisions. We must prepare our troops for the stress of service in theater.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I agree with General Petraeus, who recently spoke in favor of redoubling our education efforts to identify potentials for abuse among our servicemembers. The recent Army study indicating tolerance of torture among some of our troops shows why we need to do more.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Through mental health provisions in this bill, Congress has begun to ask important questions, important questions about the results of war and developing best practices for identifying and treating combat-related stress disorders.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I strongly urge my colleagues to vote in favor of this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400224" topic="MILITARY OFFICERS">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, at this time I am pleased to yield 3 1/2  minutes to my friend and colleague, the gentleman from Georgia, Dr. Gingrey, a member of the Armed Services Committee.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400151" topic="MILITARY OFFICERS">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I thank the gentleman from Minnesota for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise today in support of <bill type="h" number="1585">H.R. 1585</bill>, the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to say a special thanks to Chairman Skelton, my good friend, and also to Ranking Member Hunter, as well as Subcommittee Chairman Abercrombie and Ranking Member Saxton, for their tireless efforts in support of our soldiers, our sailors, our airmen, and marines who are bravely defending us both at home and abroad.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, while not a perfect bill, this legislation covers a wide scope of issues that are vitally important to our armed services, both active and reserve components, and clearly meets the immediate needs of the warfighter.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>From a 3.5 percent across-the-board pay raise to an additional $4.1 billion for the MRAP, Mine Resistant Ambush Protected vehicles, this legislation addresses the most pressing needs of our troops during a very, very trying time for this country. I am further pleased that the bill provides for an increase of 13,000 Army and 9,000 Marine Corps active-duty personnel, as well as $1 billion for National Guard equipment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While I applaud the work of the committee in addressing pressing readiness issues, I am very concerned, Madam Chairman, about the deep cuts to missile defense and, of course, the Army Future Combat Systems. A viable missile defense system is critical to deterring and countering emerging threats to our national security, especially as Iran and North Korea develop their nuclear capabilities. I look forward to working with Chairman Skelton and Ranking Member Hunter and the rest  of the committee as this bill moves forward to address these program needs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am pleased, however, that the Armed Services Committee voted unanimously on a bipartisan basis to support another program critical to our national security. Madam Chairman, that is section 1243 of this bill. It affirms that WHINSEC, the Western Hemisphere Institute for Security Cooperation, is effectively accomplishing its mission and expresses that because of this success, the Department of Defense should continue utilizing this program to promote security cooperation with Latin American countries.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Those who have been taking the time to visit WHINSEC at Fort Benning in Columbus understand the critical importance of this program. By virtue of WHINSEC, the United States is able to engage the military and the security forces of Central and South American countries in a forum where they will be able to learn our values regarding democracy and human rights, especially now human rights, while also being trained in counter-narcotics and counter-terrorism tactics.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is so important to remember that this may be the only medium we ever have to engage the future military and political leaders of these Latin American countries, who are America's closest neighbors; and they can serve as  our closest allies. If we were not to engage with these nations, we would be abandoning our most effective means of developing relationships with the security forces of Central and South America. The void created would be filled by  countries with different values than our own regarding democracy and human rights, countries, Madam Chairman, such as Venezuela and China, whose influence in the region is growing. And, therefore, I am glad that the Armed Services Committee stands behind WHINSEC.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, there is much to be proud of in this bill, and I again commend Chairman Skelton and Ranking Member Hunter for their efforts to keep this bill focused on the needs of the warfighter, a fact I hope is not lost as we progress through the amendment process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge all my colleagues to remember the importance of a strong national defense and to prioritize that over partisan issues which divide us.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400224" topic="MILITARY OFFICERS">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I yield to the gentleman from Indiana (Mr. Buyer) for the purposes of making a motion.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400056" topic="MOTION TO RISE OFFERED BY MR. BUYER">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I move that the Committee do now rise.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion to rise.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400056" topic="MOTION TO RISE OFFERED BY MR. BUYER">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I demand a recorded vote, and pending that, I make the point of order that a quorum is not present.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Chair will count for a quorum. Does the gentleman from Indiana withdraw his point of order?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400056" topic="MOTION TO RISE OFFERED BY MR. BUYER">
    <paragraph>I do not.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Evidently a quorum is not present.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This is a 5-minute vote.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I yield 1 minute to the gentleman from Connecticut (Mr. Courtney), a member of the Armed Services Committee.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412193" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, in 2001, when President George Bush took office, the size of the United States Navy consisted of 315 ships and submarines. Today, the size of that Navy has fallen to 276 ships and submarines. Despite this shocking decline and the damage, the damage, that it has done to our shipbuilding base in this country, the President continued to propose a shipbuilding budget this year which will continue that deterioration.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If his shipbuilding plan continues, for example, the size of our Virginia-class attack submarine fleet will fall below 40 submarines, starting 7 years from now, and will stay there for 15 years. That is far below what the Navy has warned us is an acceptable level for a submarine fleet to meet its mission request.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise in support of this Defense bill because it will stop the decline that has occurred over the last 6 years of America's Navy and will invest $588 million in an advanced procurement for a Virginia-class attack submarine and stop the bathtub effect of the decline of the submarine production schedule which the President proposed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I applaud Chairman Skelton and Chairman Taylor for their efforts to restore the size of our Navy.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400224" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I am pleased to yield 3 minutes to the gentleman from South Carolina (Mr. Wilson).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400433" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Thank you, Congressman Kline. Thank you for your leadership and your service in the Marine Corps of the United States. Thank you for your family's participation, serving today as part of our effort overseas. I am very proud of your son's service. We are very grateful to the Kline family of Minnesota.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise today in support of <bill type="h" number="1585">H.R. 1585</bill>, the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008, and its provision for authorizing additional troop strength for both the United States Army and Marine Corps. I appreciate Chairman IKE SKELTON and Ranking Member Duncan Hunter's work in crafting this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As directed by the House Committee on Armed Services, in fiscal year 2008 the Army's end strength will be 525,400, a 13,000-person increase, and the Marine Corps' end strength will be 189,000, 9,000 more than last year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a member of the Armed Services Committee, as a 31-year veteran of the Army Reserves and Guard, and, most importantly, as the proud parents of four sons who are serving in the military today, I know firsthand of the extraordinary opportunities of military service.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Increasing the size of our military is imperative in our fight to win the global war on terrorism. By ensuring we have an adequate number of soldiers, we can decrease troop deployment time and increase training and readiness, thus improving our military's capability and effectiveness.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bases I directly represent, Fort Jackson for the Army and Parris Island for the Marines, are producing the best professionals to protect American families in the world. I am particularly pleased that the effort to increase troop strength is bipartisan. I have been impressed that last year Congresswoman ELLEN TAUSCHER of California introduced legislation for troop strength increase.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In conclusion, God bless our troops, and we will never forget September 11.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I yield 1 minute to my friend, the gentlewoman from New Hampshire, Ms. Shea-Porter.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412219" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I was honored to be a military spouse, and I am now honored to be in the House of Representatives and on the Armed Services Committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I stand here today in support of this bill. This bill takes care of our military men and women and it also takes care of their families. It provides a raise for the military that is long overdue. It provides for their housing. It takes care of our military and our families. And it cares for those who are injured, especially brain injuries, which we are concentrating on now.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It helps rebuild the military. Our military has been weakened by the war in Iraq, and it is now time to support these people. So I am very proud to stand here.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It also takes care of the National Guard. It will provide a fourth star for the National Guard so they will have a seat at the table to talk about the policy in the United States. The National Guard deserves this. They also have an increase in the budget of $1 billion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I am proud here as a member of the Armed Services Committee to lend my support to this and to urge my colleagues to vote for this.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400224" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, I yield 3 1/2  minutes to the gentleman from Indiana (Mr. Buyer).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400056" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Thank you very much for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am back on the floor, and I am here to make an appeal to my good friend, IKE SKELTON. I am here to make an appeal, Mr. Chairman, because I need you to help me. Help me understand why I shouldn't be so upset here today. You have a provision in the bill that is going to open up the Federal Supply Schedule and extend that pricing into DOD whereby when you do that we expand the pool. When you expand the  pool, you cost shift. Not only do you cost  shift, you are going to increase pharmaceutical costs onto 7 million veterans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So our history here is that it was a Democrat-controlled Congress back in 1992 that said we are going to create the Federal Supply Schedule and we are going to do this cost control. Why? Because if anyone is entitled in our society to have this benefit, it is our disabled veterans. Then what happened? Then in the 1990s we sort of reformed eligibility with regard to the VA and expanded that criteria so the Federal Supply Schedule expanded beyond the disabled veterans now to all veterans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And now what has happened, you want to expand it, Chairman Skelton, into the DOD TRICARE pharmacy benefit program. When you do that, we are going to increase the price of prescription drugs for veterans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Do not go home and pound your chest and say I am denying increase in copays when you are about to vote for increases in drug prices for 7 million veterans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Chairman Skelton, I offered two amendments before the committee, and they were both denied.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Members are reminded to direct their comments to the Chair, not to another Member in the second person.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400056" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I offered two amendments directly to the Rules Committee asking one of my colleagues, who is the chairman of the Armed Services Committee, to do these amendments, and they were denied. It was dumbfounding to me.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400215" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>If the gentleman would yield and answer how it would raise the cost to veterans and explain how it would, that would be helpful.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400056" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Sure. If Federal discounts expand, price levels would be pushed up, the VA would pay a higher price for the drugs it provides to veterans. So this would place an increased pressure on the funding of veterans health care.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400215" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>According to whom?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400056" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>GAO even did an analysis of the expansion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We asked them to look at it with regard to Medicare, when you tried to do it on Medicare, and pass the House. We know that any time you expand Federal pricing and you increase the pool, drug prices in fact will go up.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a matter of fact in 1990, talk to Chairman JOHN DINGELL because he passed that back in 1990, and they realized they made a mistake and it increased the price on veterans, and we had to repeal it. I ask you to talk to Chairman Dingell.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400215" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Well, I am sure the pharmaceutical industry would tell you that because they have a lot to lose by expanding it.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400056" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>I reclaim my time. Who has a lot to lose? We all have a lot to lose. If you want to open up and do price controls in pharmaceutical manufacturing, we all lose as a society. We will all lose.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Does the gentleman from Minnesota yield for purposes of that motion?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400224" topic="MOTION TO RISE OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Yes, I yield for purposes of the motion.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion to rise.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400056" topic="MOTION TO RISE OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I demand a recorded vote, and pending that, I make the point of order that a quorum is not present.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Chair will count for a quorum. Does the gentleman from Indiana withdraw his point of order?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400056" topic="MOTION TO RISE OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>I do not.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Evidently a quorum is not present.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This is a 5-minute vote.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I yield 2 minutes at this time to the gentleman from Georgia, my friend, Mr. Marshall, who is also a member of the Armed Services Committee.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400254" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I very much appreciate the job that you and the ranking member and the staff and members of the committee have done in putting this bill together. It is an appropriate balance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, the bill appropriately balances the needs of all of our branches and all of the different defense needs that we have, both present and future, whether it's in space or land or air or on the water. What I want to particularly mention is that part of the bill that contemplates the kinds of conflicts that we are likely to have in the future and how we need to organize ourselves to better address those conflicts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have found, with our experience in Afghanistan and Iraq most recently, but historically with our experience in Vietnam, that our conventional force has a very difficult time dealing with the kind of conflicts that we are seeing in Iraq, Afghanistan, and the kind of conflict that we saw in Vietnam.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In Vietnam and today, we learned lessons, and those lessons are reflected in some of the things that we have in the committee's report and in the bill itself. We contemplate, for example, that in the Special Operations Command, more emphasis will be placed upon special forces and building partner capacity and developing partnerships globally that can enable us to work effectively with indigenous populations since, frankly, those indigenous populations are the ones that are going to have to be  principally responsible for security issues within those countries.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are in a new era here across the globe. Angry individuals have access to information that can enable them to develop very lethal weapons. Robert Wright describes this as the "growing lethality of hatred." It's a new era. It requires a new approach.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think this bill heads in that direction, and I expect over the future years will head even more in that direction. That approach has to involve effective partnerships with security forces worldwide to keep an eye out for the kinds of threats that can be brought home to the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for his leadership.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I think we only have about 2 1/2  minutes left on this side. I would continue to reserve and ask my good friend from Missouri to recognize some more of his speakers.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I yield 1 1/2  minutes to the gentleman, my friend and colleague, the gentleman from Maryland (Mr. Cummings), who is also a member of the Armed Services Committee.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400090" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I rise today in support of the National Defense Authorization Act. This legislation is of vital importance, because it ensures that the Department of Defense has the funding necessary to replenish the depleted resources of the U.S. military and provides accountability standards as our military operations continue in Iraq. One of the critical issues we addressed in the House Armed Services Committee was the need to support our troops in combat operations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We accomplish this task by providing $141.8 billion in emergency supplemental spending, which will provide for new combat vehicles and armor that will protect our men and women in uniform from traumatic brain injuries and  increase their overall survival rate. Additionally, this bill safeguards and enhances access to care and treatment programs for our injured servicemembers under the auspices of the Wounded Warriors Assistance Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, we address the need for oversight and accountability standards for our military operations in Iraq. Congressman DAVID LOEBSACK and I have an amendment included in the bill that requires Secretary Gates, General Petraeus and Ambassador Crocker to submit reports to the Congress on the status of the implementation of the Joint Campaign Plan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to vote in favor of this critical defense bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I yield 2 minutes to the gentleman from Iowa (Mr. Boswell).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400042" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>First, I, too, would like to join with others in our appreciation of Chairman Skelton and Mr. Duncan for their good work, 58 unanimous votes coming out of committee. That says a lot.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I think it's important for us to realize some things in the future that are going on with our forces that many of us who participated over the years, you and I, have got some concern about, that's readiness.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If you haven't talked to your adjutant generals back in your home State, you ought to do that. You ought to have a talk with them, because it's something we ought to address. I know the ranking member and chairman understand this, but we have to do it. You have got a good bill. You have done what we ought to do.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have to think about what happens next. I think we have to realize that there is some disparity about what is going on, even in the Iraq operation, because we have to figure out what we want to do in the future. What do we want as the policy, as the structure, as we think about the added forces that we are going to have to do.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We think about deployment. You know, they tell me that about 80 percent of the casualties over there, and probably some of you have more accurate information, are from the infantry. But they are only about 20 percent of the force.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>You think about that, there's something going on here that's evolved in all of this that we haven't really addressed. We are thinking about the dearth of those who are reenlisting in the very important rank, the backbone of the Army, and I would guess the Marines as well, and that's the E-6. There are more of those that are doing the leadership positions throughout a various variety of things, as well as the O-2s and O-3s.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>And those are young people, younger people, who have got some amount of service, but they have got to talk to their families about reenlisting and continuing on. They are not staying, and this ought to be a concern. We have got to address that, and we have got to do that in the very, very near future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So we have to sit down and say, what is our structure, what is our policy, before we go ahead and do the things that we have to do.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>I yield 2 minutes to my friend, the gentleman from Rhode Island (Mr. Kennedy).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400215" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, I want to acknowledge Chairman Skelton and Ranking Member Hunter for their good work on this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This authorization has very strong provisions on mental health, a number of them addressing the stigma issues regarding mental health, identifying the reintegration needs of our Reservists. Our Reservists make up nearly half of those fighting on behalf of the war on terror.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mental health nurse practitioners: It establishes a nurse practitioner graduate education program in the Uniformed Services University of Health Sciences program that includes psychiatric mental health practices.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It has mental health counselors who can now be reimbursed by TRICARE for services provided to our troops and their families. These counselors are cost-effective and ready to serve the families of our servicemembers as well as our servicemembers themselves.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Also, we have the Mental Health Initiative that will coordinate the Department of Defense's research and development programs and provide opportunities for researchers to better improve identification and diagnosis of mental health problems.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, we have the Psychological Kevlar, which will help us begin to prevent the post-traumatic stress disorder problems that we are seeing many of our soldiers come back from Iraq suffering from. It is important that we include in our basic training, before our soldiers go abroad, not only physical resiliency and training but mental resiliency and training, so that they are as prepared to defend themselves mentally as they are physically before it is too late, before they suffer the terrible  psychological wounds that yield them so disabled in many respects after the war, when it is too late.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, Madam Chairman, this bill includes provisions that will take account of measuring the quality and satisfaction of our military men and women in our military hospitals. We cannot wait for more of the kinds of Walter Reed anecdotal stories to rise to the surface before we begin to measure the quality and satisfaction in our military hospitals, and I am pleased to see this amendment adopted in the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The authorization has very strong mental health provisions that will help address the stigma our troops confront in seeking mental health care, increase the number of mental health professionals to serve the mental health needs of our troops and their families, and advance research developed from the nation's academic and medical base to better improve DoD's mental health research and treatment programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Addressing stigma issues among reservists: The Secretary of Defense will establish a working group to identify the reintegration needs of our reservists. The working group will examine different programs operated by different services, States, and commands to help reservists. From there, it can identify best practices and develop plans to incorporate these practices across the military.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mental health nurse practitioners: The establishment of a nurse practitioner graduate education program at the Uniformed Services University of Health Sciences. The program's specialties would include psychiatric mental health practice.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mental health counselors: Mental health counselors can now be reimbursed by TRICARE for services provided to our troops and their families. The counselors are a cost-effective force ready to serve and help our service-members and their families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Military mental health initiative: This initiative would coordinate the Department of Defense's mental health research and development programs and provide an opportunity for researchers to better improve the identification diagnosis, and treatment of mental health issues.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This plan will help incorporate evidence-based preventive and early intervention strategies into pre-deployment training, combat theater operations, and post-deployment service to strengthen our warfighters' psychological resiliency.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Introducing our soldiers to mental health care only after they have been exposed to combat is far too late. We need to familiarize our soldiers and their families with how to recognize and deal with the symptoms of combat stress and trauma--and the benefits of mental health care--from early on in their military career.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our soldiers are trained from the moment they enter basic training or boot camp on how to physically protect themselves from harm.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We need to ensure that they are just as well trained in protecting themselves psychologically as well.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>At this time I yield 2 minutes to my colleague, the gentleman from Pennsylvania (Mr. Carney).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412234" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, Mr. Chairman, I am here today in support of our Nation's veterans. The GI bill has provided education to many of our Nation's finest honorable men and women. But, unfortunately, there is a provision that excludes our National Guard and Reserve from receiving their GI benefits after they have left the military.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment, which comes from bipartisan legislation that I have introduced on the same topic, will express the sense of Congress that we need to lengthen the period of time that a Guard or Reserve member has to take advantage of the GI bill after he or she completes their service to 10 years. Right now, when they leave the service they lose their educational benefits. If they are deployed, they lose those benefits shortly after they return.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We owe it to our National Guard and Reserve members to have up to 10  years to take advantage of the GI bill of education. This is similar to the benefits extended to active duty members of the military, and our National Guard and Reserve deserve the same benefit because the National Guard and Reserve are playing an ever-increasing role in combat. They are finding it harder and harder to achieve their degrees while enlisted.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, as a lieutenant commander in the U.S. Naval Reserve, I have witnessed firsthand the critical role the National Guard and Reserve play in our Nation's security. It saddens me to learn that the National Guard and Reserves have missed their recruiting goals for 2005 and 2006. The military provides immense benefits to those that sign up, but it cuts off the Guard and Reserve when it comes to education benefits. What better way to ensure our military remains an all-volunteer force by  encouraging more people to join the Guard and Reserve?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a former professor at Penn State, I understand the value of education and believe that an educated workforce is a better workforce for all of America. We want our brave men and women who risk their lives for our country to have access to education. Denying our National Guard and Reserve their education benefits is unfair to our troops, unfair to their families, and hurts our entire country. We should allow our troops to serve their country honorably, and then reward them with higher education  when they are finished.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The National Guard and Reserve are becoming indistinguishable from active duty now, and they need this benefit. We owe it to our troops and their military families back home. I urge all Members to support it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I am here today in support of our Nation's Veterans. The GI bill has provided education to many of our Nation's fine and honorable men and women. Unfortunately, there is a provision which excludes our National Guard and Reserves from receiving their GI bill benefits after they have left the military.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment, which comes from the bipartisan legislation that I have introduced on the same topic, will express the sense of Congress that we need to lengthen the period of time that a Guard or Reserve member has to take advantage of the GI bill after he or she completes their service to 10 years. Right now, when they leave the service, they lose their education benefits. If they are deployed, they lose the benefits shortly after.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We owe it to our National Guard and Reserve members to have up to 10 years to take advantage of their GI bill education benefits. This is similar to the benefits extended to active duty members of the military. Our National Guard and Reserves deserve this same benefit. Because the</paragraph>
    <paragraph>National Guard and Reserves are playing an ever-increasing role in combat operations, they are finding it harder to achieve their degree while enlisted.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a lieutenant commander in the U.S. Navy Reserve, I have witnessed firsthand the critical role that National Guard and Reserves play in our Nation's security. It saddens me to learn that the National Guard and Reserves missed their recruiting goals in both 2005 and 2006. The military provides immense benefits to those that sign up, but it cuts off the Guard and Reserves when it comes to education benefits. What better way to ensure our military remains an all volunteer force by encouraging  more people to join the Guard or Reserves?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a former professor at Penn State Worthington, I understand the value of education and believe that an educated workforce is a better workforce for all of America. We want our brave men and women who risk their lives for our country to have access to education. Denying our National Guard and Reserves their education benefit is unfair to our troops, unfair to their families, and hurts the entire country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We should allow our troops to serve their country honorably and reward them with a higher education when finished. The National Guard and Reserves are becoming indistinguishable from active duty now. They need this benefit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We owe this to our troops and our military families back home. I urge all Members of Congress who care about our troops and military families back home to vote in favor of this amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, may I inquire on the time, and may I also inquire if the gentleman from California has additional speakers.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from Missouri has 2 1/2  minutes. The gentleman from California has 2 3/4  minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>I want to thank all Members who participated in the general debate, and all the great subcommittee chairmen and ranking members, and the chairman of the committee for putting together this great bill, and will now enter the amendment process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is just one point that I wanted to make in listening to my colleague finish up in talking about the mental health of America's soldiers, sailors, airmen, and marines.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One observation that I have made over the years in being around people that wear the uniform is that while a number of the stresses and the difficulties that have been spoken of are real, it is also real that the coolest, calmest, most balanced, most stable American citizens, I believe, are the folks that wear the uniform in Iraq and Afghanistan. And while it is true that enemy fire can hurt you and damage you mentally as well as physically, it is also true that that fire can make you stronger.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Having spent time with guys like Chuck Yeager, guys like the great Vic Taylor, many others who have been under fire and in various situations in real combat in the world's wars, it has always occurred to me that the people who have the greatest mental stability are people that come out of the combat zones.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I want to make sure that this debate doesn't send the message that somehow Americans who wear the uniform are victims, and that the inevitable result of their wearing the uniform and serving in combat is that they are going to somehow be damaged mentally, because that is not the case.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And I would just conclude by reflecting on the fact that I take a number of folks who are wounded in Iraq and Afghanistan hunting, which the Hunter family likes to do, and I take them hunting with my grandchildren. And there are few people that I will trust my grandchildren with, but the people I will trust my grandchildren with out in the great outdoors, with loaded weapons, are members of the United States Army and the United States Marine Corps who have been to combat. Those people have the  greatest sense of balance and sense of judgment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And, again, in my mind, America's citizens who are the coolest and the calmest under fire and have the greatest sense of balance and judgment are people that wear the uniform and have been in combat.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, I yield 1 minute to the gentleman from Rhode Island (Mr. Kennedy).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400215" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, when speaking about mental health, we should be speaking about it in terms of a positive. That is what makes us stronger. I think when the gentleman says that when we speak about mental health, we want to be careful so as not to make people feel like they are victims, looks at it in a negative way.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Frankly, I am proud that at John F. Kennedy Special Warfare Center at Fort Bragg the Green Berets have insisted that they have psychiatrists on call 24 hours, 7 days a week, not because they are the weakest branch of the military, but because they are the strongest and they want to remain the strongest. And they know that if they are to remain the strongest, they don't want to be thinking about anything else in their mind when they use their sharpshooter and they are called to duty for this country,  where they are going to parachute in and use their technical expertise they have been trained to do. They know that they want to be able to do that job sufficiently, and that is why they have had this important mental health allowed for them, and that is why I think it is so important to have these facilities available for them.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, we are nearing the end of the general debate portion of the consideration of this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank my ranking member, my friend, DUNCAN HUNTER, for his hard work and for his cooperation in getting us to this point. And it was difficult at times, but we have gotten here. So I just want him to know that I am appreciative.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And I also want to say that the purpose of our affection and attention is the young men and young women in uniform. Despite all of the procedural motions that we have had, out of all of this at the end of the day, and maybe  at the end of tomorrow, we will have done an excellent job, because this bill is basically a very good bill for the defense and for the young people of our Nation in uniform.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So let's not forget the purpose of what we are doing here. Let's not forget that we are doing this in a bipartisan effort. Let's not forget that, at the end of the day, we will make America one major step safer by passing a good piece of legislation for our country.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400378" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I am proud today to offer an amendment to <bill type="h" number="1585">H.R. 1585</bill>, the Fiscal Year 2008 National Defense Authorization Act, that will make certain the Niagara Falls Air Reserve base continues to play an integral role in our homeland defense.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Niagara airbase is home to the 914th Air Reserve and the 107th Air Guard. Both units have been deployed to Iraq and Afghanistan, and are responsible for patrols over large metropolitan areas and key infrastructure throughout the Northeast and Midwest.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The value of the men and women serving at Niagara was clearly demonstrated during the tragic events of September 11th. The 107th was the first Refueling Wing to fly Combat Air patrols over New York City. In addition, a specialized unit of the 914th, trained in identifying and preparing the remains of disaster victims, was instrumental in the 9/11 recovery mission.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The 2005 Base Realignment and Closure Commission determined that the airbase would better serve our Nation if the 107th Guard unit became an Associate Air Wing of the 914th Reserve.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is the first time in Air Force history that a Guard unit will associate with a Reserve unit. Predictably, the Air Force is facing a number of unprecedented challenges in attempting to shift assets around in order to meet the BRAC mandate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I and the Western New York Congressional delegation have been working with the Air Reserve and the Air Guard for over a year and a half to determine the optimal allocation of aircraft at the base to ensure that both units can adequately complete their missions. The uncertainty surrounding what comes next at Niagara has created a lot of anxiety for the service members at the airbase and the Western New York community. The Air Force must determine a way forward with Niagara this year to ensure  that the base continues to play a key role in protecting our Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Accordingly, my amendment simply directs the Secretary of the Air Force to submit a report to the House and Senate Committees on Armed Services detailing the Air Force's plan for future aviation assets at the Niagara airbase. I want to thank Chairman SKELTON and his staff for working with me to draft this amendment, and I urge the House to adopt it.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400001" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I have the honor of serving as the Chairman of the Air and Land Forces Subcommittee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill is about balancing the capabilities and readiness of our current military forces with future required military capabilities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our military personnel are at risk each and every day. Our first priority is to make sure our men and women in uniform are properly supported by ensuring our acquisition programs adequately support current military requirements.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We cannot shortchange the current force for promised future capabilities when we are losing people everyday in Iraq and Afghanistan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Air and Land Forces subcommittee's jurisdiction in this bill includes approximately $100 billion in Army and Air Force programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our priorities do not always agree with those of the Pentagon, but our objective is clear--to do our very best to ensure our military personnel get the best available equipment as soon as it can be properly tested--armored vehicles; body and vehicle armor; improvised explosive device jammers, unmanned aerial vehicles, small arms, night vision equipment, and related equipment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill addresses a number of key requirements:</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1585">H.R. 1585</bill> provides $4.1 billion in additional funds to fully fund a tactical vehicle referred to as M-RAP, or Mine Resistant Ambush Protected vehicle, to better protect our personnel against mines and improvised explosive devices. The budget request included less than $500 million to meet this $4.6 billion requirement which, as of last week, is now Secretary Gates' number one priority.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over a billion dollars is provided for Stryker combat vehicles.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill fully funds body armor, Up-Armored Humvees, Armored Security vehicles, and vehicle add armor kits at $5.4 billion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also provides $4.5 billion for programs established to counter improvised explosive devices.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An additional billion dollars is provided for funding of National Guard and Reserve Equipment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Overall, the bill represents an increase of 40 percent for Army procurement accounts over last year's budget request.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ten C-17 strategic airlift aircraft have been added to the bill at a cost of over $2.4 billion, to maintain the C-17 production line and sustain the strategic airlift fleet.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Joint Strike Fighter competitive engine program has been funded at $480 million to provide two producers of engines for that program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have had to make some difficult choices to fund the highest priority programs and stay within the budget top-line. Some programs will have to make adjustments. We understand that, and will work together as the process evolves to ensure that these adjustments can be accommodated as best as possible. In closing, I again want to thank my distinguished chairman and ranking members of the full committee and our subcommittee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill is deserving of a "yes" vote from every Member of this body.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="1585">H.R. 1585</bill>, the National Defense Authorization Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, let me extend my thanks to Armed Services Committee Chairman Skelton and Ranking Republican Duncan Hunter for bringing this partisan legislation to the Floor today. The bill before us authorizes funding for our national defense programs in the coming year, including our military operations in Iraq and Afghanistan. It enjoys the support of both Republicans and Democrats on the Armed Services Committee, and in fact was reported out of committee by a unanimous vote. I am  very pleased to note that while some circumstances have changed in this Congress, the Armed Services Committee remains one in which Members on both sides of the aisle remain committed to comity, bipartisanship, and the best interests of our Nation's defense and our brave men and women in uniform. I congratulate both Chairman Skelton and Mr. Hunter on their successful efforts, and intend to vote in support of this bill later today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would take this opportunity to raise concern with one of the amendments made in order under the rule, specifically, the Altmire/Udall Amendment, which would expand employer mandates under the Family and Medical Leave Act. Let me state at the outset that I will not oppose this amendment, nor will I urge my Republican colleagues to do so. I do, however, for the record and for the good of this legislation going forward, want to note my strong concerns with this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, let me say that as a matter of procedure and responsible legislative process, I am deeply troubled that this amendment comes to the Floor today without so much as a cursory examination by the only committee of jurisdiction in the House, the Committee on Education and Labor, on which I serve as Senior Republican Member. The Altmire/Udall Amendment represents a significant expansion of the Family and Medical Leave Act, and would be the first such expansion in the 14-year history of the Act.  Yet it has not been the subject of a single hearing in the Committee on Education and Labor, nor has any Member of the House or my Committee had the opportunity to examine the impact of this amendment in even the broadest sense. Where, as under this amendment, we are talking about expanding a federal mandate that potentially impacts large and small employers in every industry and every state in the union, I think we owe more to our constituents.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I do not want my concern and my remarks to be construed as simply procedural, or solely a function of marking jurisdictional turf. While I do believe that respect for the committee legislative process is important, I want to make clear that I have substantive concerns as a matter of policy with the Altmire/Udall Amendment. The Amendment would appear to broadly expand the Family and Medical Leave Act, allowing any covered employee to make use of leave for "any exigency" that arises out of the  fact that a family member is called to active duty. Now I am certain that Members on both sides of the aisle would agree that the question of whether and how we ensure that workers whose families have been impacted by a call-up to active duty are able to address legitimate needs is a valid question. I am concerned, however,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Earlier this year, the Department of Labor set forth a Request for Information seeking detailed evidence and recommendations for both regulatory and legislative changes to the Family and Medical Leave Act. That process is ongoing as we speak. Members on both sides of the aisle and various stakeholders have made clear that the Act deserves serious examination--particularly with respect to questions as to when and how leave can be taken, and what sorts of leave and notice are appropriate. In light  of these facts, to embark on piecemeal expansion of one of the most significant federal labor laws adopted in the last 20 years, strikes me as irresponsible, and setting a very bad precedent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As I indicated, I think I understand the concerns of the sponsor that this amendment is intended to address, and I think those are concerns that many might share. For that reason, I will not oppose the amendment. I've made my concerns with both the substance and procedure of this amendment clear. I would hope that as this bill moves forward, and if we find ourselves in conference with the other body, we will take the necessary time to examine this amendment in detail, and work towards ensuring  that it accomplishes its goals in a reasonable, responsible, and targeted way.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400315" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, on Monday I was proud to visit with sailors at Naval Station Norfolk, the largest military station in the world. When the 78 ships and 133 aircraft home ported at Norfolk are not at sea, they are alongside one of the 14 piers or inside one of the 15 aircraft hangars for repair, refit, training and to provide the ship's or squadron's crew an opportunity to be with their families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As I looked into the eyes of our brave men and women in uniform, I felt sick knowing that instead of getting the support they need in this fight, this Democratic Congress is pulling the rug out from under them. Democrats on the House Armed Services Committee rejected Republican efforts to adopt an amendment to <bill type="h" number="1585">H.R. 1585</bill> that would have authorized emergency supplemental appropriations for Fiscal Year 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I rise today to condemn the Democratic plan to fund the war on the installment plan. Failure to pass an acceptable long-term supplemental appropriations bill for FY07 is a clear and present danger to our troops in Iraq and Afghanistan, to the Department of Defense institutionally, and to its national security mission to defend the homeland.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Tomorrow marks the 100th day since the administration asked Congress to provide funding for our troops. Because Congress has not sent the President an acceptable supplemental funding bill, DoD will notify Congress today of its intent again to transfer an additional $1.4 billion from Navy and Air Force personnel accounts to fund on-going Army operations in the War on Terror. This funding will last about a week.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This latest transfer request is the fifth one necessitated by the lack of supplemental funding. In sum, two have been necessary to fund Army operations, one to fund procurement of Mine Resistant Ambush Protected vehicles, one to bolster the Iraqi Security Forces, and one to counter improvised explosive devices.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to these transfers, the Army has moved funding originally allocated for fourth quarter expenses into the third quarter. The Army Operations and Maintenance account--the principal account that covers day-to-day Army operations--no longer has any funding available for the fourth quarter operations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Moving money around like this creates uncertainty and inefficiency, ultimately costing the taxpayers more money in the long run and wreaking havoc on existing contracts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The funding delay has already caused disruptions. Delays have limited DoD's ability to properly contract for the reconstitution of equipment for active and reserve forces. This increases the readiness risk of our military with each passing day. Needless delays in accelerated fielding of new force protection capabilities such as the Mine Resistant Ambush Protected vehicle and counter-lED technologies. Depletion of funds necessary to accelerate the training of Iraqi security forces.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Without relief soon, the Department of Defense will be forced to take further drastic steps like halting training, delaying deployments and re-deployments, and/or resorting to the use of the Feed and Forage Act, which permits obligation of funds prior to appropriation in emergency situations, an extremely poor and disruptive way of waging a war on terror.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, our troops need funding and they need it now.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>2007 REPROGRAMMED FUNDS FOR THE DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DoD has $4.5 billion in General Transfer Authority. All transfers in excess must come from other sources. War-related reprogramming includes: Mine Resistant Ambush Protected (MRAP) Vehicles: $32 million from emergency funding for Humvees and radios; Iraq Security Forces Fund: $800 million Under General Transfer Authority as well as various Army military personnel, procurement, and research and development programs (includes helicopter modifications, ammunition, and communications equipment);  IED Defeat: $825 million Under General Transfer Authority from 4th quarter Navy and Air Force personnel accounts funding; and Army Operations: $3 billion under General Transfer Authority from 4th quarter Navy and Air Force personnel accounts funding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Total Requested Transfers: $4.918 billion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Total General Transfer Authority Remaining: $342 million.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>LETTER FROM DEFENSE SECRETARY ROBERT GATES TO CONGRESSIONAL LEADERSHIP ON INCREMENTAL FUNDING PROPOSALS:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Delays have limited DoD's ability to properly contract for the reconstitution of equipment for active and reserve forces. The readiness risk of our military increases with each passing day. The funding delay has caused needless delays in accelerating fielding of new force protection capabilities such as the Mine Resistant Ambush Protected (MRAP) vehicles and counter-IED technologies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The delay has caused a depletion of funds necessary to accelerate the training of Iraqi security forces. "The prospect of segmenting and further delaying funding that is urgently needed can only result in additional disruption and uncertainty in department operations ..... An organization the size and complexity of the Department of Defense needs a certain measure of funding stability and predictability. Without it, compensatory measures are required that cause, at best inefficiency and at worst  a reduction in the Department's ability to carry out its national security mission."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>SECRETARY OF DEFENSE TALKERS (WE RECEIVED THESE FROM A FRIEND THAT ASKED WE NOT IDENTIFY THE SOURCE):</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because Congress hasn't sent Congress an acceptable supplemental funding bill, DoD will notify Congress of its intent again to transfer an additional $1.4 billion. This funding will only last about a week. The latest transfer request is the 5th one necessitated by the lack of supplemental funding. The Army has moved funding originally allocated for fourth quarter expenses into the third quarter.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Army Operations and Maintenance account--the principal account that covers day-to-day Army operations--no longer has any funding available for fourth quarter operations. Without relief soon, DoD will be forced to take further drastic steps like halting training, delaying deployments and re-deployments, and/or resorting to the use of the Feed and Forage Act, which permits obligation of funds prior to appropriation in emergency situations, an extremely poor and disruptive way of waging a war  on terror.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Beginning in mid-April, the Army will slow the purchase of repair parts and other supplies, relying instead on existing inventory to keep equipment operational. Joint Letter to Chairman Obey from Gen. Peter J. Schoomaker, Adm. Michael G. Mullen, Gen. T. Michael Moseley, and Gen. James T. Conway: "Without approval of the supplemental funds in April, the Armed Services will be forced to take increasingly disruptive measures in order to sustain combat operations. The impacts on readiness and quality  of life could be profound."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Gen. Peter Pace: After mid-April, "the army has told us that they will have to begin curtailing some training here at home for Guard, Reserve, and for units, which means that the baseline for those units will be reduced as far as their capability, and when they're called, it will take them longer to be ready and could, over time, delay their availability to go back into combat."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Defense Secretary Robert Gates: "This kind of disruption to key programs will have a genuinely adverse effect on the readiness of the Army and the quality of life for soldiers and their families. I urge the Congress to pass the supplemental as quickly as possible."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mrs." name="DAVIS, JOANN" of="Virginia">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, <bill type="h" number="1585">H.R. 1585</bill> clearly focuses on the readiness of our troops.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a first step to improving the readiness of our forces, the bill requires the Secretary of Defense to include status of the National Guard in the quarterly readiness reports to Congress. Not only will this provide visibility on the status of our guard units to support the Federal mission, but will also provide updates to the Governors and to the Congress on the ability of these units to accomplish their civil support missions. The bill goes on to require the Secretary of Defense to report annually  to Congress on the status of prepositioned stocks and to establish a timeline for reconstituting those prepositioned stocks in the event they are downloaded for use by our deployed troops. While these reporting requirements seem small, they will do a great deal to ensure that priority and necessary funding is applied to areas that need it the most.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would also like to highlight that this bill authorizes $250 million to address training shortfalls throughout the services and recommends $165 million above the President's budget request for depot maintenance. Properly funding depot maintenance ensures that the equipment our troops need to not only engage in combat operations, but to also train and prepare for deployment, is available and ready for them when they need it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Once again, I would like to state that I am proud of this legislation and I encourage all members to support it for the steps it takes to ensure our troops are ready to meet the needs of our nation.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400402" topic="FROM APRIL 16 HERITAGE MEMO TITLED, &quot;FUNDING NEEDS PROMPT ARMY SPENDING CONSTRAINTS.&quot;">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I rise today to commend Chairman IKE SKELTON and the staff of the Armed Services Committee for working to strengthen the National Guard. Support of the men and women who so bravely serve our Nation as citizen-soldiers is critical to our nation's security.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Inclusion of several National Guard provisions in <bill type="h" number="1585">H.R. 1585</bill>, the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008, sends a powerful message to our first military responders around the nation that we recognize their numerous contributions, many of which extend far beyond war fighting. As chairman of the Committee on Homeland Security, I am heartened that this legislation provides resources to the Guard's needs here at home for missions relevant to homeland security and sustainability in  our States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over the last 5 years, the Guard has nobly accepted and completed missions in Iraq, Afghanistan and elsewhere abroad. True to form, Guardsmen and women from almost every State have sacrificed a great deal, including in some instances their lives, to stay true to the motto of "always ready, always there."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Provisions in this legislation will provide $1 billion to address the strain on Guard and Reserve units in the States who are facing critical equipment shortages. For the first time, we will ensure that State Guard units are prepared for homeland security missions such as disaster response. Equally important is language in this bill that will encourage integration between the National Guard Bureau and other Defense components, such as Northern Command, who share responsibility for protecting  the homeland.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In short, this legislation incorporates key recommendations from the Commission on the National Guard and Reserve. It takes us a step closer toward closing the gap between Guard units categorized as ready and Guard units resourced to be ready.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400244" topic="FROM APRIL 16 HERITAGE MEMO TITLED, &quot;FUNDING NEEDS PROMPT ARMY SPENDING CONSTRAINTS.&quot;">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I rise today in strong support of the Saxton-LoBiondo-Smith-Andrews amendment which will provide members of the Armed Services and their families living on military bases with more security. It would require a federal background check for unescorted civilians, including contractors and vendors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The security gap that exists at our Nation's military bases was highlighted by the recent plot against Fort Dix by terrorists. Fortunately due to the intervention of an ordinary citizen and the professionalism of the FBI, this plot to attack was thwarted. Next time, we might not be so fortunate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is simply common sense that we should know who is entering our military bases and why they are there. Background checks on all contractors and vendors will help secure these sensitive facilities and ensure an additional layer of security for our servicemen and women who live and work on our military bases.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I strongly urge that all Members vote for this amendment to protect our military bases and our military personnel and their families.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> All time for general debate has expired.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400360" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I offer an amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will designate the amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, I rise to speak about the amendment. I don't rise in opposition to the amendment, but I would like to take the time and address the issue.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the gentleman from California is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, we've looked over the amendment. It's really an adjustment of a part of the base bill that we have that allows for this memorandum of understanding between these three primary entities, State, DOD and AID, to make sure that they have an understanding of authorization of the carrying of the weapons by contractors, the rules of engagement, coordinating movement of contractors, collecting information relating to offenses under UCMJ and also, additionally, what the gentlelady  has offered in her amendment, the issuance of guidance on all equipment, including uniforms, body armor, weapons and the collection of information related to casualties suffered by contractors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And our only concern, of course, is that we have enough time for this memorandum of understanding to be put together after the bill becomes law, which in some cases is late December, hopefully long before then. And so what we do need is to have the ability of the administration, if they don't have that together. And one thing we all agree on is you've got to do this right when they do it, when they issue this memorandum of understanding. So they need to have time to do it; that we do have a waiver  or an extension of time that would be allowed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And so I've talked this over with the gentlelady, who is the author of the amendment. She's amenable to extending the time period for this memorandum of understanding to be worked out, and the chairman has graciously agreed that he also supports that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And so just in a simple informal colloquy, I'd just ask the chairman if it's his agreement that, in conference, we would work to extend the time wherein the memorandum of understanding could be worked out if, in fact, it can't be done within 90 days of the first of January 2008. Would the gentleman agree to effect that in conference?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="">
    <paragraph>Yes. If the gentleman would yield.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Absolutely.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="">
    <paragraph>I certainly do agree. I think that's a reasonable request, and I think the gentlelady from Illinois also would agree to it.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>I would further ask the gentlelady if that's fine with her, if she would be in accord with that.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400360" topic="">
    <paragraph>Yes, it is.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Thank you very much. In that case we support this amendment and would not object to its adoption.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400360" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I yield 1 1/2  minutes to Mr. Price of North Carolina.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400326" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I thank Ms. Schakowsky for yielding and for her good work on this amendment, the Schakowsky-Price amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also want to thank Chairman Skelton for his significant steps he takes in this bill to address the vast challenges surrounding battlefield contracting. He generously worked with me to include key elements of <bill type="h" number="369">H.R. 369</bill>, my bill regarding security contractors, and I appreciate his leadership.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Very quickly, I want to highlight three additional improvements this amendment will make to language in the bill. First, it will require the departments doing the vast majority of contracting, DOD, State, USAID, to track contractor casualties. We believe over 800 contractors have been killed in Iraq and many more injured. But what's the exact toll? We do not know. Our amendment will change that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Secondly, the amendment will require these departments when appropriate to issue guidance on appropriate equipment and uniforms for contractors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And thirdly, it will require the departments to clarify how a provision inserted in last year's defense bill, which places certain contractors under the Uniform Code of Military Justice, will be implemented.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These are three simple but important additions that make the bill's current language even stronger, ensuring that the agencies engaged in contracting on the battlefield will develop an effective framework for managing and overseeing contractors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Four years into the war in Iraq, and after all the stories of waste and abuse and criminal misconduct, I think we can agree that this is not too much to ask. I urge my colleagues to support the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Will the gentlelady yield?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400360" topic="">
    <paragraph>Yes, I would yield.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>I just wanted to thank the gentlelady for, respectfully, for her addition to this amendment and her concern about the contractors. And you know, just reflect for a second, that our contractors who go over to the warfighting theaters in Iraq and Afghanistan undertake enormous danger, and a large number of them have been killed and wounded. And many of them, the ones that I have met, are largely American veterans who have, they go for two reasons; one is they do make good money. It's  a job, it's a worthwhile job. They feel like they're supporting our country. They also have a great, the ones I've talked to, have a great deal of concern for the troops. They have a feeling of partnership with the people that wear the uniform of the United States, and they are a great asset to this country. And I think it's appropriate that we follow, we carefully watch how they're treated and how they're protected. I think that's absolutely appropriate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank the chairman for embedding this base provision in the base bill, and  members on the Republican and Democrat side who've worked to put this together, and I thank the gentlelady for her thoughtful addition.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400360" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I yield my remaining time to Chairman Ike Skelton.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, let me take this opportunity to compliment the gentlelady, Ms. Schakowsky, and also Mr. Price, the gentleman from North Carolina, and thank the ranking member, Mr. Hunter, for working this out. It's a step in the right direction. It's also an example of bipartisanship, and we appreciate it.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the amendment offered by the gentlewoman from Illinois (Ms. Schakowsky).</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400139" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I offer an amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will designate the amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400139" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I yield myself 3 1/2  minutes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, most people don't realize while our troops are in harm's way in Afghanistan and Iraq, that their family members back home, if they want to send them a care package, whatever that care package may consist of, from a young child's homework assignment or a drawing or an artist's rendering, to just something from home to help them in their time of trouble, right now those families must pay for it. And on average, it's not unusual for a family to incur about $1,500 a year in postage  to mail those packages.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My amendment would authorize free mailing privileges for family members of our servicemen and women serving in Iraq and Afghanistan. I believe the amendment offers tremendous opportunity to increase the morale of our troops overseas which, as we are well aware, is a necessary component to have a confident and fully prepared military.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to thank, of course, Chairman Skelton, Ranking Member Hunter, Personnel Subcommittee chairman, Mr. Snyder, and my good friend, JOHN MCHUGH from New York, for helping to bring this amendment to fruition.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I drafted the amendment in response to concerns expressed to me by many family members that it was becoming too costly to send those regular care packages to their loved ones overseas. I heard story after story of families that are already finding it hard to make ends meet now having to spend as much as $1,500 a year to mail care packages.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These packages, as I mentioned, bring a touch of home to our servicemembers. Pictures, cards, school projects from kids, and I'm told there's not good pepperoni in Afghanistan yet, so that comes as well. But they also provide the military men and women with basic necessities like additional shampoo or powder or perhaps phone cards.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In my district of Staten Island and Brooklyn, residents join together and raise money to help military families send these packages overseas. I was inspired by the outpouring of support for our servicemen and women, particularly in Dyker Heights, Brooklyn, where postal service employees raise money to cover the postage for every package sent to our troops. In Staten Island residents formed the Staten Island Project Home Front, Incorporated, a nonprofit organization dedicated to serving our deployed  troops and their families by sending thousands of care packages. This month alone they sent over 230 packages to our soldiers overseas. It was with acts of generosity and patriotism such as these that prompted this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The amendment has also received the support of organizations such as the VFW, American Legion, National Association of Uniformed Services. And to quote the VFW, "Letters and packages from home do wonders in boosting morale of our men and women serving in harm's way, and high morale transfers to combat ready and effectiveness." Comments such as this I wholeheartedly agree with.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It goes without saying that our servicemen and women are making enormous sacrifices fighting this war on  terrorism and defending freedom and liberty. They face great challenges under trying circumstances, and often without some necessities such as blankets or toothpaste. It falls upon their families back home to get them these supplies and to cover the cost of shipping them overseas. The amendment will make life a little easier for our soldiers and to  ease the financial burden on those back home. It's a simple way of bringing a touch of home to America's heroes overseas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In short, what it would do would give each family member a voucher, the equivalent of sending a 10-pound package every 2 months, and would reduce that cost to those families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I'd also submit for the Record letters in support from the VFW and the American Legion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>THE UNITED STATES,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington, DC, May 15, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR REPRESENTATIVE FOSSELLA: On behalf of the 2.4 million members of the Veterans of Foreign Wars of the United States (VFW) and our Auxiliaries, I am pleased to offer our strong support for the "Supply Our Soldiers Act of 2007" (<bill type="h" number="1439">H.R. 1439</bill>), which provides for free mailing privileges for personal correspondence and parcels sent to members of the Armed Forces serving on active duty in Iraq or Afghanistan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As you are aware, letters and packages from home do wonders in boosting the moral of our men and women serving in harms way; and high moral translates to combat readiness and effectiveness. Unfortunately, too many military families are financially strained and cannot absorb the cost of postage to send parcels on a recurring basis. Your initiative goes a long way in eliminating that burden.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thank you for taking the lead and introducing this measure. We look forward to working with you to ensure it is enacted.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Director,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>THE AMERICAN LEGION,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington, DC, May 17, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR REPRESENTATIVE FOSSELLA: As you and your colleagues consider the Defense Authorization bill for FY 2008. The American Legion wants you to know that we wholeheartedly support your amendment that benefits members of the Armed Services serving in Iraq and Afghanistan by allowing free mailing of packages to these troops.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As the nation's largest wartime veterans' organization, The American Legion has long supported initiatives that impact the quality of life for our heroes serving overseas. This amendment would allow service members families to mail a package up to 10 pounds every two months to these war zones, free of charge. This is but one small way in which we can show the troops that we support them and what they do, and perhaps make life in a combat zone more bearable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, thank you for taking the initiative in sponsoring this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Director,</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="VETERANS OF FOREIGN WARS OF">
    <paragraph>Would the gentleman yield?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400139" topic="VETERANS OF FOREIGN WARS OF">
    <paragraph>I yield 30 seconds to the gentleman from California (Mr. Hunter).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="VETERANS OF FOREIGN WARS OF">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for yielding, and on our side we think this is an excellent amendment. And I want to thank the gentleman whom I've traveled with to the warfighting theaters, and thank him for his concern for our troops, and we support the amendment strongly.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400139" topic="VETERANS OF FOREIGN WARS OF">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="VETERANS OF FOREIGN WARS OF">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I claim time in opposition, though I will not oppose this amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the gentleman from Missouri is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="VETERANS OF FOREIGN WARS OF">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, actually I thank the gentleman from New York for bringing this amendment forward. It would provide cost free vouchers to allow mailing of packages to members serving in Iraq and also in Afghanistan, and the committee has no objection and appreciates the thoughtfulness on this issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I yield back.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400139" topic="VETERANS OF FOREIGN WARS OF">
    <paragraph>I yield the remaining time to the gentleman from Virginia (Mr. Tom Davis).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Mr. TOM DAVIS of Virginia asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400098" topic="VETERANS OF FOREIGN WARS OF">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, General Walter Boomer, the commander of the Marines in the first gulf war, once said, a soldier's best friend, next to his rifle, is the postman.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment, which is a scaled down version of <bill type="h" number="1439">H.R. 1439</bill>, the Supply Our Soldiers Act of 2007, sponsored by the gentleman from New York (Mr. Fossella) and myself, will help our soldiers, our sailors, our airmen and marines fighting in Iraq and Afghanistan receive letters and packages more regularly from their loved ones.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We're not able to be with our heroes fighting in Iraq and Afghanistan, but we're able to send a little piece of home overseas to them. Whether it's mailing the basic essentials or a videotape and a letter, tangible items from loved ones are always appreciated.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>Holding a son or daughter's art project or biting into a homemade cookie reminds them that they support what they are doing and the sacrifices they are making for our country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The cost of sending letters and packages overseas to Iraq and Afghanistan can be a burden for a family already making great sacrifices. I think that regular communication between soldiers and their families should not be inhibited by the cost of postage, and some things just can't be e-mailed. This amendment will help soldiers receive the necessary supplies and words of encouragement from loved ones more frequently, keeping morale raised while in the combat zone.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the amendment offered by the gentleman from New York (Mr. Fossella).</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="NOTICE TO ALTER ORDER OF CONSIDERATION OF AMENDMENT">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, may I make an inquiry?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman may inquire.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="NOTICE TO ALTER ORDER OF CONSIDERATION OF AMENDMENT">
    <paragraph>Would it be possible, Madam Chairman, to bring forward the amendment of the gentleman from Pennsylvania at a later moment as opposed to what was announced earlier?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Chair can reannounce in different order for that amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="NOTICE TO ALTER ORDER OF CONSIDERATION OF AMENDMENT">
    <paragraph>Yes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will designate the amendments en bloc.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I urge the committee to adopt the amendments en bloc, all of which have been examined by both the majority and the minority.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, at this time I yield 1 minute to my friend, the gentleman from Rhode Island (Mr. Kennedy).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400215" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I thank the gentleman from Missouri and the gentleman from California.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My amendment simply requires the Department of Defense to examine a process by which they would further add for the collection of data by which our servicemembers could rely on an apples-to-apples comparison of our military health care system, so that they could get a proper evaluation of the status of our health care system, so that we could avoid the kinds of anecdotal stories that we found out through the Walter Reed scandal.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We shouldn't be finding this out through stories. We ought to be able to find this out through the garnering of data. And this is one of the ways that we seek to do so. By garnering this information just like we would through our regular health care system, we should do so through our military health care system, and that is what this amendment would do.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I yield 1 minute to my friend from California (Mr. Thompson).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400403" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I thank the chairman for yielding and both him and the ranking member from California for accepting this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is an important amendment that is a first step in solving a very serious problem on our military bases both here in the States and abroad; and it is a problem that, unfortunately, spills over into our communities. And this is the issue of members of criminal street gangs joining the military and getting the training that they get in the military and now, unfortunately,  on the battlefield, and then bringing that back into the community and deploying  those tactics on the streets in our neighborhoods.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a serious problem. It is documented. The FBI has a report. This is a problem that we need to get ahead of and stop before we have more serious problems than we do already.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank the chairman and ranking member for accepting this amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I yield 1 minute to the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Mitchell).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412187" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I rise today in support of an amendment that will help improve the transfer of medical records from the Department of Defense to the Veterans Administration upon discharge.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment will help ensure that when a soldier, sailor, airman, or marine voluntarily authorizes the transfer of his or her medical information to the VA, the information will, in fact, be transferred.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank Chairman Skelton for supporting this amendment. His dedication to our fighting men and women is legendary, and our Nation's veterans are lucky to have him on their side.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also want to thank Representatives ZACH SPACE, TIM WALZ, and CIRO RODRIGUEZ. I am proud to serve with them on the Veterans' Affairs Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations. They have been full partners in this endeavor, and as the chairman of our subcommittee, I am honored by their support.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And, finally, I want to thank Chairman Filner. His leadership has been invaluable, and I am grateful for his help.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I yield 2 minutes to the gentlewoman from West Virginia (Mrs. Capito).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400061" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I would like to thank the chairman and ranking member of the House Armed Services Committee for their hard work on this important legislation that will help provide our military with the resources they need to successfully execute their mission.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have a very simple amendment today expressing the sense of Congress that the Arlington National Cemetery shall provide a site for a memorial marker to honor the lives of United States Armed Forces members who died in an air crash at Bakers Creek, Australia, on June 14, 1943. The amendment provides that the Secretary of the Army shall have the exclusive authority over the design of the memorial and the selection of the site.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This little-known tragedy occurred during World War II, a conflict that was fought and won by what has been called America's Greatest Generation. Unfortunately, the men who died in the Bakers Creek crash were never recognized as belonging to that group of great American heroes. During their service in the South Pacific, they were on a routine flight from Australia, returning from a week's leave for R&amp;R. The plane crashed in Bakers Creek, Australia. Unfortunately, due to orders to keep the Allied  presence in Australia a secret, the crash was kept a secret by the military.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thankfully, many of the families, some of whom live in my district, now know the true story of how their relatives died. My amendment would merely recognize their sacrifice by honoring their service with a memorial marker at Arlington National Cemetery.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, will the gentlewoman yield?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400061" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield to the gentleman from California.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I just want to say that we on this side are in total agreement with her amendment. We thank her for bringing it in such a thoughtful way and we support it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I yield 1 minute to my colleague, the gentleman from Minnesota (Mr. Walz).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412214" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I thank the chairman and the ranking member for their outstanding work on this incredibly important piece of legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I offer a simple amendment, and I rise in support, encouraging my colleagues to support the amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After spending 24 years in the Army National Guard, I know that members of our Armed Forces don't join the military simply for the benefits that are there. But I also know that benefits can help improve retention and aid servicemembers when they return to civilian life.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One benefit that has given our servicemembers a problem over the years is the Federal Tuition Assistance program. This program is based on a first-come, first-serve benefit. Servicemembers join up thinking this is a guaranteed benefit only to find out that the funding has run out. While serving in the National Guard and now as a Member of Congress, I have heard numerous complaints weekly about this program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My amendment would direct DOD to report relevant information on this program by telling us how many servicemembers are eligible for this and how many receive the benefit. The study would examine the program's effect on retention as well as how it interacts with State tuition assistance programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We owe our servicemembers the benefits they are promised. This amendment would give us the necessary information to improve the program, to maximize the use of our dollars, and get it directed at our soldiers who need it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support it.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I just want to say, we appreciate the gentleman and his amendment on this side and thank him for bringing it to the floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, at this point, I would like to yield 3 minutes to the gentleman from Ohio (Mr. Turner).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400411" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I would like to thank Chairman Skelton and Ranking Member Hunter for including my amendment in this package.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My amendment provides certainty to servicemembers deployed in a contingency operation that their child custody arrangements will be protected.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In some cases, courts are overturning established custody arrangements while the custodial parent is serving our country in a contingency operation, such as Iraq or Afghanistan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>States have become aware of this issue and are looking at what action they can take to support our men and women in uniform. The State of Michigan passed a law in 2005 to provide these protections to military personnel. The amendment offered today is modeled after the established Michigan law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Much is asked of our servicemembers, and mobilizations can disrupt and strain relationships at home. This additional protection is needed to provide them peace of mind that the courts will not take away their children because they answered the country's call to serve. This amendment protects them and it protects their children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, I thank Chairman Skelton and Ranking Member Hunter for supporting this important amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, will the gentleman yield?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400411" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield to the gentleman from California.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I just want to thank the gentleman. What an essential and important amendment this is.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We recognized and have embedded in law the remedies for a service person who may be overseas and may lose his house or may have a judgment taken against him, a civil law liability judgment, and we have tried to protect him from that. And the idea of having a child taken from you while you are serving overseas can only have a demoralizing effect on members of the armed services.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So this protection is very much needed, and I thank the gentleman from Ohio. We have total support on this side for his amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400411" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, reclaiming my time, I thank Mr. Hunter and I want to thank Chairman Skelton again for this important amendment that will provide peace of mind for those who are serving.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, at this time, I would like to yield 3 minutes to the gentleman from Indiana (Mr. Buyer) for the purposes of a colloquy with myself and Mr. Skelton.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400056" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I thank Mr. Hunter and Chairman Skelton.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am deeply concerned about the unintended consequences that section 703 may have on the price of drugs for America's veterans. I rise today and  ask for your help to request the Government Accountability Office to conduct a study of the impact of the proposed provision to provide Federal pricing authority to the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs. I ask the chairman if he would be willing to request the GAO to conduct such a  study.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield to Chairman Skelton.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I thank the gentleman for bringing the issue forward. And I assure the gentleman we do not want to raise the price of drugs for America's veterans and neither do we want to raise the price of drugs for men and women in uniform and their families. I will be pleased to work with the gentleman and my ranking member, Mr. Hunter, to request that the GAO conduct a study of the impact of Federal pricing on both the Department of Defense as well as the Department of  Veterans Affairs and report back to Congress on its findings.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, will the gentleman yield?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400056" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield to the gentleman from California.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I support the chairman and I will support the gentleman's request for a study by the GAO after 1 year to assess the impact to the Department of Veterans Affairs and the DOD of providing Federal pricing to DOD to purchase drugs in a retail pharmacy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400056" topic="">
    <paragraph>Reclaiming my time, I want to thank Chairman Skelton for his support of this quest, and I believe that such a review will help alleviate any uncertainty with regard to this proposal, and I want to also thank Ranking Member Hunter.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To my good friend, Chairman Skelton, you and I have had a great history together in this body for the last 15 years, and I consider you a personal friend. I apologize to you for when I let my passion get to the side of me. I am deeply sorry if in any manner you took my words directly personal to you because I would be offended if you felt that way.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>You are a genuine human being, and we all recognize that your passion and your support for the men and women who serve in the military is real and, more importantly, it is genuine; and equally, my passion with regard to the men and women in the military and our veterans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>You and I will agree more than we ever disagree, and this is a moment where we may find ourselves in conflict. If I crossed the threshold to my good friend, I deeply apologize to you. I hope you accept my apology.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="">
    <paragraph>Well, it is certainly kind of you to make mention of that, and I appreciate it very much. I thank you for your friendship, of course, through the years. I do agree that we have been good friends and we have worked together so well. So that, of course, is all behind us. Thank you very much.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I do look forward to working with you and Mr. Hunter on the issue as we move forward to protect not only our Nation's veterans, but our military personnel as well. And I think we will get there in this matter.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400107" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise on behalf of my colleagues ALCEE L. HASTINGS, Ileana Ros-Lehtinen and Mario Diaz-Balart to introduce an amendment to <bill type="h" number="1585">H.R. 1585</bill>, the Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008. The amendment recommends that the Secretary of the Navy establish and maintain a Navy Senior Reserve Officers' Training Corps, ROTC, program at the University of Miami in Coral Gables, Florida.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, the University of Miami is committed to assisting in the education of the armed services officer corps. The university currently houses Army and Air Force ROTC programs with great success. In fact, the university has recently committed to build a new ROTC-only facility should a Navy program be added. This would provide the best environment for college education and officer training for our Armed Forces.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The south Florida community is an ideal place for a Navy ROTC program. The proximity to important military installations such as the Key West Naval Air Station and the United States Southern Command only serves to advance the real world training to which senior reserve officers are exposed during their military education.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, a Navy ROTC program at the University of Miami will further the Navy's continued mission to diversify their officer corps through increased recruitment, retention, and career development in minority populations. With a 50 percent minority student body, the university is well-situated to help the Navy achieve its laudable goal. Miami is the "gateway" to the Americas. The diversity of our community and the knowledge of our hemisphere would greatly augment the quality of officer  training for our military.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, for these and other reasons, I am pleased to introduce this amendment with my colleagues and urge all members to support this important Navy ROTC program at the University of Miami.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412187" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise today in support of an amendment that will help improve the transfer of medical records from the Department of Defense to the Veterans Administration upon a soldier, sailor, airman or marine's discharge.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment will help ensure that when one of our troops voluntarily authorizes the transfer of his or her medical information to the VA, that information will, in fact, be transferred.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sadly, the safe and efficient transfer of medical records to the VA has been, and continues to be, a persistent problem. Despite numerous attempts to design and implement a system for sharing vital medical information, the DOD and VA have been unable to do so.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This information is essential to the well-being of our veterans. Without it, we cannot ensure that they receive the proper medical care from the VA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Veterans' Affairs Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations has held hearings on this issue, and we have heard a myriad of explanations for why this is the case.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>According to the Government Accountability Office, one of them is a technical, legal hurdle involving the law that protects the privacy of patients' medical records: the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act. According to the GAO, the DOD and VA have differing interpretations of HIPAA, and as a result, HIPAA has become a barrier against the sharing of medical information.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And even worse, the HIPAA hurdle has persisted for years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In May 2005, the GAO reported,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DOD and VA have been working on a data sharing agreement for over 2 years, but have not reached an agreement. DOD and VA differ in their understanding of HIPAA Privacy Rule provisions that govern the sharing of individually identifiable health data for servicemembers currently receiving that exchange. DOD's and VA's inability to resolve these differences has impeded coming to an agreement on exchanging seriously injured servicemembers' individually identifiable health data.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At the time, the DOD and VA were attempting to draft a memorandum of understanding to enable them to begin sharing medical information. However, according to the GAO, even if they had completed the memorandum of understanding, HIPAA would have remained a barrier. Specifically, the GAO found,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>..... the draft memorandum restates many of [the legal authorities contained in the I ["HIPAA"] Privacy Rule for the use and [disclosure of individually identifiable health data. As a result, even if the memorandum of understanding is finalized, DOD and VA will still have to agree on what types of individually identifiable health data can be exchanged and when the data can be shared. &lt;p&gt;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This just does not make any sense.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>HIPAA is supposed to ensure the privacy of a patient's medical records, not prevent their transfer, at the patient's request, to his or her doctor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If the DOD and the VA can't recognize this, then I believe it is time for Congress to clarify it for them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Mitchell, Space, Walz, Rodriguez Amendment would require the DOD to provide every member of our Armed Forces a HIPAA authorization form, the voluntary signing of which would legally obligate the DOD to transfer that servicemember's medical records to the VA upon his or her discharge.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to emphasize that participation in this process would be completely voluntary. No member would be forced to share his or her medical information because of this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rather, the amendment would merely ensure that when a servicemember unambiguously authorizes the transfer of his or her medical information to the VA, that information will, in fact, be transferred.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank House Armed Services Committee Chairman Ike Skelton for supporting our amendment. His dedication to our fighting men and women is legendary, and our Nation's veterans are lucky to have him on their side.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also want to thank Representatives Zach Space, Tim Walz and Ciro Rodriguez. I am proud to serve with them on the Veterans' Affairs Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations. They have been full partners in this endeavor, and as the subcommittee's chairman, I am grateful.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, I want to thank Chairman Filner. His leadership has been invaluable, and I am honored to have his support.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the amendments en bloc offered by the gentleman from Missouri.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400008" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I offer an amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will designate the amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400008" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield myself 3 1/2  minutes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Mr. ANDREWS asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400008" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I believe that it is in the interest of freedom-loving people around the world to deny the present regime in Tehran access to a nuclear weapon.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The amendment that I submit does not raise the issue of the propriety of Iran having a nuclear weapon. The amendment I submit raises the issue of the propriety of this coequal branch of our government asserting its proper constitutional authority.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My amendment contemplates, Mr. Chairman, the following circumstances, and I want to be very clear about this. If our troops in Iraq become involved in a fight that requires them to in some way engage, in order to defend themselves, Iranian personnel in a given situation, they have the right and power and authority to do so.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, if our planners on the military side, as part of their normal planning exercises, as they do throughout the world and around the globe, find it necessary to game out and analyze the circumstances under which we would prepare for conflict with Iran, they have the authority to do so. Any American soldier or servicemember under any circumstances has the authority to defend himself or herself, and the President has the authority to act under emergency or self-defense circumstances.  However, in those circumstances under which the President would wish to initiate a major contingency operation in Iran, this amendment says he may not use funds which we have authorized and appropriated to fight the wars in Iraq and Afghanistan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The amendment asserts the proper constitutional authority of this coequal branch of government. The Constitution vests us, as the duly elected representatives of the people, with the authority and responsibility to decide when this country will initiate hostilities in order to serve our national interest absent an emergency or a self-defense situation. This amendment preserves that emergency authority of the President. It preserves the self-defense authority of the President. But it properly  asserts the duly assigned constitutional role of this branch to decide the circumstances under which we should go forward with a major contingency operation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, whether Members believe that we should be more aggressive or less aggressive with Iran, they should support this amendment. Whether Members believe that we should pursue more active diplomacy or a different kind of diplomacy, they should pursue and support this amendment. The question here is not the proper policy with respect to Iran. The question here is the proper allocation of constitutional authorities between and among the branches.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would urge both Republican and Democratic Members to vote "yes" on this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in support of this amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the gentleman from Missouri is recognized for 10 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, if you are a young man or young woman in either Iraq or Afghanistan in American uniform, you would like to know that monies authorized and appropriated from this body for Iraq or Afghanistan will not be diverted to planning any operations elsewhere. That's what this is. This simply ensures that funds that Congress approved for other purposes are not diverted to planning operations against Iran. It's that simple.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It increases the ability of Congress to provide oversight for planning of military operations, and it would not restrict the Department of Defense from planning any necessary contingencies regarding Iran using the base defense budget.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a good amendment, and I compliment the gentleman from New Jersey (Mr. Andrews) for offering it.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in opposition to the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Chair allocated the time, because there was no objection, to the gentleman from Missouri. If there is unanimous consent, perhaps the gentleman from Missouri could allocate 5 minutes to the gentleman from California.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="">
    <paragraph>I certainly do.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the gentleman from California is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I have enormous respect for my great friend from New Jersey, who has shared and fought on common ground with this Member for many years on items of interest and national defense that we shared support of.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In this case, I must oppose this amendment strongly for this reason. The nation that he's talking about, Iran, borders obviously one of our important warfighting theaters, that is, Iraq. We have seen evidence, it has been reported by our warfighting commanders that Iran has participated in moving instruments of death; that is, extremely effective IEDs that have been used against American troops and will prospectively be used against American troops, into Iraq from Iran.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The idea that we are saying that in this piece of the budget we cannot plan for interdiction of those items, of those weapons that are moving across the border, that we can't plan, for example, for Special Forces operations that we might need to implement or to move into action, to preempt this movement of deadly devices across the border, that we can't plan to extract hostages if they should be taken by Iranian militia or Iranian members of the armed forces is just not practical and it's not  reasonable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>You have an Iranian military and intelligence body which has decided to become involved in the war in Iraq. They have moved across the border, and they have moved effective weapons across the border that are being used against American troops. I think it is not wise for us to advertise to our adversaries and to the world that we are establishing a policy that we will not even use money to contemplate or to plan for a reaction against us. I think we have to let them know that we have license,  as Americans, to take any actions that might be necessary to protect American troops.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would object very strongly to this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400008" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I reciprocate the respect expressed by my friend, the ranking member from California, and respectfully disagree with his interpretation of the amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In a situation where we would want to interdict IEDs, there are two ways  that this bill makes it clear we could do so. The first is, under all of the other titles of this bill that fund all the other operations of our Armed Forces we would have the authority to do so. And second, such an example is not a major contingency operation in Iran under the contemplation of the bill. So we would absolutely have the ability to interdict the creation or transport  of IEDs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second, with respect to a hostage situation, rescuing hostages is not planning a major contingency operation in Iran. Nothing would preclude our military personnel from executing such a mission should the need arise, either under this title or under the other titles of the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So as I said in my opening remarks, it is clear to me that under emergency or self-defense circumstances, there are no limitations whatsoever. What this amendment does is to properly assert the constitutional authority of this coequal branch of government that if this country is to initiate hostilities, is to conduct a major contingency operation in Iran, the President must come to this body and ask for our permission.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I would yield to my friend from Rhode Island.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400215" topic="">
    <paragraph>I support the gentleman's amendment, and I would just point out if this country has learned anything from the last 6 years, it has learned that there must be checks and balances in our government.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have a war that has been proclaimed based upon lies. We have had a war that has been proclaimed based upon faulty intelligence. And we have had a war that has been proclaimed upon intelligence that has been manufactured. Now we have a public that has repeatedly felt that it has been lied to, and that they want to be heard by their Congress. All we are asking in this amendment is that their Congress have a chance to voice their own through the Representative's opinion before a Commander in  Chief throws this country back into another war headlong without the American people having a voice in it.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400008" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I would yield to the gentleman from Missouri, the chairman of the committee.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="">
    <paragraph>I understand that the gentleman from California requires additional time; is that correct?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Would the gentleman yield an additional 3 minutes?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield to the gentleman.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank my friend for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I would just respond to my friend from New Jersey in this way: It says that you can't plan for a major contingency. I am looking at scenarios, and if you have a scenario where you have convoys of IED material being moved from Iran into Iraq and you want to send a team over and make a strike and close a canyon or close a mountain pass or hit that convoy with a major strike, I think many people would classify that as a major action, a major contingency.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>So I think that we blurred the line here in that we may have to take what I would consider and many Members here would consider to be major contingencies. The problem is, you have to take those things very quickly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This war against terror is an era when time is truly of the essence, when hours are important, when minutes are important, when days are important. The idea we have to come back, if you have got to close a pass to keep IEDs that are killing Americans in Iraq from going across that line, we have to come back and get permission from Congress to do that, I think that is not a good advertisement or a good statement of impunity to communicate to the other side, where they think they now have an insulation  between an immediate reaction by American Armed Forces.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is the essence of our resistance to this amendment, and I think it is still very solid.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 1 minute to the gentleman from Rhode Island (Mr. Kennedy).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400215" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I think this amendment ought to be called the "George W. Bush Amendment," because if it were any other President, I don't think we would have to worry about this. But this President has so undermined the confidence of the institution of the Presidency, it has brought this amendment to the floor; because I think this President has so jeopardized the confidence in the Presidency of the United States that the people, after the experience of this President, have become  so distrustful that this President is going to drag them into another war under unwarranted circumstances that they would support an amendment like the one of the gentleman from New Jersey. And that is why I would call it the "George W. Bush Amendment," for no other reason than it is because of George W. Bush that this amendment seems to be necessary.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, let me just say to my friend, I just reviewed it the other day, and I don't need to look at any statements by George W. Bush about whether or not we should have gone into Iraq, because the most damning statements about Saddam Hussein and his weapons of mass destruction, the most conclusive statements that indeed he must have them and that he must be brought to justice quickly, were not made by George W. Bush. They were made by people with the last name of Clinton, of Gore, of Kerry.  I reviewed all of the videotapes of their speeches in which they absolutely laid out a case against Saddam Hussein.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I hope we don't replow the ground of who shot John here in terms of statements with respect to the state of Iraq and its weapons of mass destruction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think we need to get back to the substance of this debate, and that is, are we foreclosing an immediate response if it is necessary.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, will the gentleman yield?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield to the gentleman from Missouri.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="">
    <paragraph>All you have to do, Mr. Chairman, is read the amendment. This amendment does not preclude any effort of expending funds from the base Defense authorization appropriation. This merely makes sure that the moneys meant for Afghanistan, meant for Iraq, go to those soldiers, marines, sailors and airmen there. It is that simple.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As my old law school professor once said: read it. What does it say?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield myself 30 seconds to explain again why I think it is impractical to put this dividing line between this funding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If there has to be a strike, if there has to be preemption because IED material is moving across the border that could injure our soldiers, our sailors, our airmen, our marines, probably the reactive force is going to be led by one of the combatant commanders who is in the Iraqi theater and who is being funded by money under OEF or OIF. It is probably not going to come. And the idea you can't have uniformed personnel expending his time and his staff's time planning what it is going to take to  defend his soldiers, sailors, airmen or marines from interference from the Iranian side of the border, is, in my estimation, not practical.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Those are the forces that are going to be responding, and I think we have to let them put together that contingency plan.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="NOTICE TO ALTER ORDER OF CONSIDERATION OF AMENDMENTS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, pursuant to sections 3 and 4 of House Resolution 403, and as the chairman of the Committee on Armed Services, I request that during further consideration of <bill type="h" number="1585">H.R. 1585</bill> in the Committee of the Whole and following consideration of amendment No. 38, the following amendments be considered in this order: amendments en bloc No. 2 and amendments numbered 20, 49, 31, 15 and 32.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from New Jersey (Mr. Andrews) has 3 minutes remaining.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400008" topic="NOTICE TO ALTER ORDER OF CONSIDERATION OF AMENDMENTS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 2 minutes to the gentleman from Washington (Mr. McDermott).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400262" topic="NOTICE TO ALTER ORDER OF CONSIDERATION OF AMENDMENTS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, this President has used the resolution that we passed some years ago as a blank check to take us into a disastrous situation in Iraq, leaving Afghanistan half done.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What we are trying to do with this amendment is simply say to the President, you have to stay where we put the money. If you want to come out and go after Iran in a preemptive way, as you did against Iraq when you had no evidence, when you came to this floor and presented evidence that  turned out not to be true, and use that as a pretext for going into war, we are heading for in Iran, in my view, another Gulf of Tonkin kind of situation, where you cook  up a situation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This administration took down the border between Iran and Iraq and now complains to us everywhere that we are getting all kinds of weapons coming in from Iran. Using that as a pretext, the Arab press yesterday reports that the Vice President was in the Middle East telling people that war is coming, telling them that the problems in Iraq don't keep us out of anything. They won't be any hindrance to us going into Iran.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment is simply an attempt to put a minor block in the way of this administration's desire to widen this war, probably to get people's minds off how bad it is in Iraq.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is supposed to be winding down in Iraq because of the escalation. But in fact that is not what is happening. We are losing more soldiers every day. We have had the bloodiest months in this war.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment is simply to say the United States Congress will decide where this country goes to war, not the President, who wants to go out and create whatever situation he wants in the world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge the adoption of this amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400008" topic="NOTICE TO ALTER ORDER OF CONSIDERATION OF AMENDMENTS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I think we have had a healthy, robust debate on this question, and I urge a "yes" vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the amendment offered by the gentleman from New Jersey.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="NOTICE TO ALTER ORDER OF CONSIDERATION OF AMENDMENTS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I demand a recorded vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 6 of rule XVIII, further proceedings on the amendment offered by the gentleman from New Jersey will be postponed.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400100" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I offer an amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will designate the amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400100" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield myself 2 minutes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, to address criticisms raised on the first amendment, this would not prevent retaliation for an attack upon U.S. troops. It would not prevent going into Iran to retrieve captured troops. But what it would do is say that we have not authorized, as some in this administration allege, a preemptive war against Iran because of the Iraq resolution or the 9/11 resolution. That simply is not true. They were not that all encompassing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Further, it would also challenge a letter I had on April 18, 2002, from then-White House counsel, the esteemed Mr. Gonzales, who claims that the President has unilateral war-making authority under the Constitution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>No. This simply restates the Constitution of the United States and the War Powers Act. It is law, 93-148, and article I, section 8, of the Constitution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is not about whether or not military action against Iran is wise or necessary. Regardless of how you come down on that question, I urge you to support the amendment. It is not about binding the President's hands so he couldn't retaliate if they are involved in attacking our troops or capturing our troops in the area. It allows, as does the War Powers Act, in the event of any attack by Iran on the United States, its territories or possessions or Armed Forces, it is fully within the President's  purview to respond.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are many who are concerned about the growing nuclear capability of Iran, and I share those concerns. But the question that some day possibly in the future they might have a missile that could work, they might have nuclear weapons, does not dictate that we should have a preemptive war now; and if the President wants to make the case that that warrants a preemptive war, he should come to the war-making body, the Congress of the United States, make that case, present his evidence and have  a lawful vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Plain and simple, that is all this amendment does, although I am certain other allegations will be made.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in opposition to the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from California is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in strong opposition to this amendment. We have been at war with the radical Islamic jihadists ever since they supported and fomented that storming of our embassy in 1979. They held Americans hostage and they held them for 444 days, and every President since President Carter has renewed the national emergency with respect to Iran, most recently on March 8 of this year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If you look at the War Powers Act, Mr. Chairman, it states that a national emergency does justify the President utilizing his constitutional powers as Commander in Chief. My reading of this amendment is that this proposal, this amendment, changes the War Powers Act and extracts that power from the President of the United States. We have had Democrat and Republican Presidents renewing that finding and that national emergency status with respect to Iran.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Just to say further, Mr. Chairman, we all know, and I just talked about this, we know that Iran through its proxies helped and aided in the attack against Americans at Khobar Towers, which killed 19 Americans and injured 372 other Americans and other people who were in that area. We know that the Iranian-backed insurgents are killing American troops with IEDs, and some of that IED expertise and the materials themselves are being transferred from Iran. We know that they are assisting in attacks  against Americans in Afghanistan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A couple of weeks ago the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs, General Pace, said, "We have intercepted weapons in Afghanistan headed for the Taliban that were made in Iran. The arms included mortars and C-4 plastic explosives."</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>So, Mr. Chairman, every Member of this body should be strongly opposed to this particular amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I would like to yield 1 1/2  minutes to the gentlewoman from Nevada (Ms. Berkley).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400024" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in opposition to this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is no denying that Iran's bloodthirsty regime would gladly destroy the United States, annihilate Israel and destabilize Iraq. Iran's hand in terrorist activities around the Middle East is clear. Iran's President continues to threaten Israel. I believe he stated he would wipe Israel off the map. And he continues to pursue nuclear weapons so he can dominate the Middle East and threaten his neighbors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have tried to stop Iran from obtaining those weapons. We have increased sanctions on firms that do business with this dangerous regime. We have worked with our allies and the United Nations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And yet with all of these efforts, just yesterday, we learned that the sanctions have done precious little to impede Iran's march towards obtaining nuclear weapons.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>According to the IAEA, and by Iran's own bravado, Iran is now beginning to enrich uranium on a far larger scale than ever before.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, this is not the time to be tying our hands on Iran. We all seek a peaceful solution. No one wants another war. But if we don't take a tough stance on Iran and maintain the threat of military action, Iran will get the message that we don't care if it gets nuclear weapons. It will allow the most dangerous regime in the world to continue its quest for regional and world domination, and destroy the only democratic country and the United States' most reliable ally in the region, Israel.  I urge opposition to this amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400100" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 1 minute to the gentlewoman from California (Ms. Lee).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="LEE" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I thank the gentleman from Oregon for yielding, and also for your leadership on this issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am very concerned with Iran's efforts to acquire nuclear weapons, like I am concerned about any country's efforts to acquire nuclear weapons. Preventing this, though, will not happen through military action.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, the President's saber rattling against Iran is only increasing and is eerily similar to the march to war with Iraq. We must act to prevent another war of preemption, this time against Iran.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is why this amendment is so important. It would clarify that no previous authorization constitutes an authorization to use force against Iran.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Secondly, this amendment would make certain that no funds would be used to take military action against Iran in the absence of specific congressional authority or a direct attack as defined by the War Powers Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Beyond this, we must make certain that the United States is not funding covert action intended to cause regime change in Iran. Unfortunately, the Rules Committee did not rule in order an amendment that I would have that allowed for this sort of debate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this amendment and also to recognize that this is a critical first step this body can take in preventing war with Iran.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400100" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 1 minute to the gentleman from New York (Mr. Hinchey).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400178" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, we all realize that it is the responsibility of every Congress to ensure that the current administration adheres to the Constitution and the rule of law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Most of us understand how this administration used the policy office within the Pentagon to falsify intelligence and to provide the Congress with false information in an attempt to justify the illegal invasion of Iraq and the subsequent disastrous military occupation which has been going on there now for more than 4 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment makes perfect sense. It simply ensures that kind of behavior by this administration is not extended now into another country in the Middle East, Iran, based upon the same falsification of information and failure to adhere to its obligations under the Constitution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment must be passed. It makes perfect sense, and it ensures the security of our country and makes sure that our military personnel are not exposed to the kinds of danger that they have been exposed to as a result of the falsification of intelligence by this administration. Let's pass this amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield myself the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would just offer to my colleague who just spoke and my other colleagues that there are the strongest statements for invasion of Iraq that took place before President Bush came into office, and those were the now famous speeches that were made by three Senators by the name of Kerry, Clinton, and Gore.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, the War Powers Act clearly calls for the ability of the Commander in Chief to introduce American military force where an emergency with respect to a nation has been declared. That emergency with respect to Iran has been declared by every American President since President Carter in 1979. This is not extra-constitutional. The law as it presently exists is consistent with the Constitution. This would infringe. In fact, this would roll back the War Powers Act. Every Member should vote  against this amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400100" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield myself the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The President is not reading in full the War Powers Act. It says the President's constitutional powers "are exercised only pursuant to (1) a declaration of war, (2) specific statutory authorization, or (3) a national emergency created by attack upon the United States, its territories or possessions, or its armed forces."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My amendment actually allows that exact language. If our troops are attacked, if we are attacked, if our territories are attacked, then the President could retaliate. So I am restating the war powers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In this case we also heard about a declaration of war from the gentlewoman from Nevada. The Congress has the authority to take up a declaration of war tonight, tomorrow, anytime it deems fit against Iran. Nothing in this amendment would prevent a Congress from declaring war.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is just saying if you want to have a preemptive war under the Constitution of the United States, a preventive war, then you need to come to Congress under article I, section 8.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If you believe in the Constitution of the United States and the powers of this branch, vote for this amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the amendment offered by the gentleman from Oregon (Mr. DeFazio).</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I demand a recorded vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 6 of rule XVIII, further proceedings on the amendment offered by the gentleman from Oregon will be postponed.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400436" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I offer an amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will designate the amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400436" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield myself 2 minutes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, it is our job in Congress to make tough decisions. So given the quagmire in Iraq which is costing $273 million every day, and our troops still don't have the training and equipment they need, and given we have critical needs at home that aren't being fully funded, needs like children's health care, rebuilding the gulf coast, keeping our promise to veterans, repairing tornado-ravaged towns and collapsed bridges, and I could go on and on, and you know it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sadly, we are still spending at least $60 billion every year to build and  maintain weapons that were specifically designed to fight the Soviet Union. It is not exactly the threat we need to worry about in the year 2007. That's why I am offering this amendment to <bill type="h" number="1585">H.R. 1585</bill>, an amendment that would require the DOD to identify all weapon systems that are currently being produced that were designed to fight the Cold War, identify their usefulness, and evaluate  the cost of savings for eliminating these programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My amendment wouldn't eliminate a single program. Rather, it is simply asking the Department of Defense to take an inventory of what they are building that was designed to fight the Cold War and report back to Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This December will mark the 18th anniversary of a meeting in Malta where the first President Bush and Soviet President Mikhail Gorbachev declared an end to the Cold War. From there, it was another couple of years before the Soviet Union was disbanded, the Berlin Wall came down, and the Iron Curtain collapsed. The Cold War is over. It is time that the Department of Defense realized this and made the proper adjustments in their procurement programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in opposition to the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from California (Mr. Hunter) is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, we are in strong opposition to this amendment. In fact, the Armed Services Committee under the very able chairmanship of the gentleman from Missouri has finished a number of oversight hearings. The subcommittees that are involved in the Armed Services Committee and in Defense Appropriations Subcommittee have undertaken extensive hearings and analysis of every weapons system that we have. And, of course, you have many weapons systems that were built 20-30 years ago that  were highly relevant, like the C-130s that Members fly on, that are the backbone of the transportation system, the intratheater transportation system in Iraq and Afghanistan, the Bradley fighting vehicles, M-1 tanks. There is no weapon system that comes out of a production line with the word "Cold War" on it, so the relevance and the importance and the use of weapons has been carefully and closely analyzed by the important committees, the oversight committees,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I would just strongly oppose the gentlelady's amendment, and say I have great respect for the gentlelady.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 1 minute to the gentleman from Oklahoma (Mr. Boren).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400645" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in opposition to this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Department of Defense can and should review its weapon systems to ensure they are relevant to current threats. But by arbitrarily singling out Cold War systems, this amendment sends DOD the wrong signal.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The House Armed Services Committee has provided thorough and aggressive oversight in considering DOD's budget request. While fully funding the Department, the committee cuts billions of dollars from major programs we found to be outdated or irrelevant to current and future threats, shifting those funds to more urgent priorities such as the Mine Resistant Ambush Protected vehicle, MRAP vehicle. Every one of the weapons systems covered by the amendment has been reviewed during the three Quadrennial  Defense Reviews held since the Cold War ended.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>Many Cold War systems, like the Abrams tank, Bradley Fighting Vehicle and the B-52 bomber, have proven tremendously useful and effective in current operations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill reflects responsible weapons priorities for current and future conflicts. I oppose this amendment because it puts DOD priorities in the wrong place, and I thank the gentleman from California and our chairman.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400436" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 2 minutes to the gentlewoman from California (Ms. Lee).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="LEE" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, let me thank my friend and colleague, a great leader, Congresswoman Woolsey, for her leadership once again on a very, very important issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It has been 16 years since the collapse of the Soviet Union. Yet I find it mind-boggling that in the last decade-and-a-half the Pentagon has continued to waste tens of millions, and billions really, of dollars buying outdated Cold War-era weaponry for a national security threat that does not exist.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, our spending on security should address the current threat that we face. That's why this amendment is so important.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By identifying and evaluating the usefulness of Cold War weapons systems, the report from the Pentagon that this amendment would require will give us a good starting point for eliminating wasteful programs. Contrary to what has been said, this is not arbitrary. In fact, military experts have identified at least $60 million in these weapons systems.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By getting rid of these outdated programs, we'd not only make the much-needed investment in ensuring health care for all of our children, improving our public schools, ending our dependence on foreign oil, but also improving our homeland security.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When you think about it, really, domestic security is national security. We don't need to sacrifice our domestic needs to ensure that our Nation remains safe. This amendment will take steps towards making this balance possible.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I urge my colleagues to look at this amendment. It is very practical. It is very rational. It is very reasonable. And I want to thank my colleague from California for bringing this forward again so that we can really begin to have a full debate with regard to the taxpayer dollars.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We need to look at where our tax dollars are going in terms of the real threat that exists now in this 21st century. Certainly it has nothing to do with the Soviet Union. Certainly it has nothing to do with the Cold War era.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I would just say we strongly oppose this amendment, and I yield back the balance of our time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400436" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 1 minute to the gentleman from New York (Mr. Hinchey).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400178" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I thank my friend and colleague from California for raising this issue, which I think is very important.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are now confronting a situation in Iraq where the number of our military personnel who have been killed is approaching 3,400. Tens of thousands of others have been physically wounded, many of them very seriously. A good number of those deaths and wounds may be attributed to the lack of proper equipment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We went into that situation, this administration sent our military forces into that circumstance there, without properly preparing for what they had to confront. In fact, they didn't have any idea what they were likely to confront. Many of the issues are that we have not developed the kinds of protection, the kinds of equipment, including transportation equipment and personal protection equipment, a whole host of things that are relevant to this situation, while we spend billions of dollars on  materials that may have been necessary during the Cold War but which are no longer necessary now.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We need what this amendment calls for, a re-evaluation of those military activities and equipment, and this is a very simple thing, and it should be done.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the amendment offered by the gentlewoman from California (Ms. Woolsey).</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400436" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I demand a recorded vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 6 of rule XVIII, further proceedings on the amendment offered by the gentlewoman from California will be postponed.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400195" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I offer an amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will designate the amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400195" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I have drafted this amendment with the gentlewoman from California (Ms. Lee) to send a clear and unequivocal message to the Government of Sudan that we will proactively explore every option and bear the burdens necessary to help stop the genocide in Darfur.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>400,000 innocent people have been murdered in Darfur, 2 million refugees, and through it all, the Government of Sudan tests the will and the patience of the United States, the United Nations and the entire world. This amendment says that we have the will and we are running out of patience.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One hundred miles from Darfur in Chad is the Abeche Air Base. If diplomacy fails, if Sudan continues to defy the world and perpetuate this genocide, that air base can be used for potential NATO operations. It can be used for a possible U.N. peacekeeping force. It can be used for humanitarian missions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our amendment expresses the will of Congress to make the upgrades necessary to that air base and requires the Department of Defense to report within 90 days on specifically what upgrades may be necessary and what the costs will be.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It says to Sudan, we will not turn our backs, we will not close our eyes, we will prepare.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge passage of this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I'm not in opposition to the amendment, but I ask unanimous consent to claim the time in opposition.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the gentleman from California is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, if Mr. Israel had additional speakers, I'd be happy to defer to him and then take my time afterwards, if he has somebody ready to talk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400195" topic="">
    <paragraph>I very much thank the gentleman, and I yield 2 minutes to the gentlewoman from California (Ms. Lee).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="LEE" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, first, I want to thank the gentleman from New York for your leadership and for your commitment to ending this horrific genocide.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is an issue that we have worked on together for a while. This issue has been bipartisan, and once again, this is one step forward to hopefully end the carnage that's taking place in Darfur. So I thank Mr. Israel again for your commitment to end this.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment is really very simple. It seeks to expand the delivery of humanitarian assistance and to speed the deployment of peacekeepers to the Darfur region of Sudan by exploring the possibility of upgrading a nearby airfield in Abeche, Chad.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The amendment expresses the sense of Congress that we should work with the Government of Chad to upgrade this airfield. It also requests that the Pentagon provide Congress with a report on the current operational status of the airfield, including recommendations and cost estimates for upgrading it to accommodate the enhanced operations and increased air traffic.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have spoken out repeatedly on this floor in condemnation of the ongoing genocide in Darfur, but it bears repeating that nearly 3 years ago, on July 22, 2004, under the leadership of a great leader, Congressman DON PAYNE, Congress declared that genocide was taking place in Darfur. To date, estimates indicate that nearly 450,000 people have been killed, and 2.5 million innocent civilians have been displaced.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Quite simply, genocide is happening on our watch, and we have a responsibility to utilize every tool at our disposal to put a stop to it. This is another effort in that direction, and so I want to thank Mr. Israel for your leadership.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Not only must we do this. We must pursue divestment for companies doing business in Khartoum. We must lean on China to leverage their influence with Sudan to help stop the violence, and we must continue to urge all parties, the rebels and the government, to lay down their arms and come to the table to negotiate a political situation, but we cannot and we should not hold a cease-fire declaration hostage to a peace agreement or vice versa.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So please support this amendment. I thank Mr. Israel again for your leadership.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I want to thank Mr. Israel and Ms. Lee for bringing this amendment. We all have our eyes focused on the warfighting theaters in Iraq and Afghanistan, and if we turn our focus to Darfur and look at the history and the number of deaths which number, and the estimates I have seen are between 250,000 and 400,000, many of them inflicted by this so-called janjaweed militia which comes into villages in Darfur and ravages the village, burns them, we have seen the pictures  that have been circulated by our own Member, Mr. Wolf, and by Senator Brownback from their recent trips, which show burned-out villages with the women abused, with many of the villagers killed, some of them killed by strafings, by helicopter</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I'd ask Mr. Israel, my colleague, of your take on this very difficult situation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400195" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, will the gentleman yield?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield to the gentleman from New York.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400195" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I appreciate it. The gentleman is correct. That is, in fact, exactly what we are trying to get at, and that is embodied in this resolution, and I want to thank the gentleman.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is an example of where Republicans and Democrats can agree. We argue about a lot on this floor, but let there be no mistake. When there is genocide, when there are massacres, Republicans and Democrats will stand together in opposition to that genocide.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Talking about it is not enough. We need to prepare for all contingencies, and that's what this resolution does.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman, and let me make an offer to this gentleman.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>You have got this great idea of using this airfield, which is about 100 miles from the border, to bring in nongovernmental organizations which can bring  in food, bring in medicine to the displaced villagers. We work in my office with a number of groups, one of them called Rescue Task Force, which has built medical centers around the world and brought in food and medicine in many very difficult situations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I'd like to offer to work with the gentleman with this nongovernmental organization, Rescue Task Force, and others to bring in food and medicine to that particular location. Let's see if we can't maybe help lead out by getting some NGOs to start using this particular airfield. And I'll be happy to join the gentleman; I know Mr. Saxton will be happy to join in this, Mr. Wolf and others.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let's get a letter, maybe a meeting with the State Department, with the administration, see if we can't get this review of this airfield immediately and start getting some supplies into it, and maybe we can lead the world, the humanitarian world, as Americans, as we do so often, in moving supplies into the airfield that you have identified.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I support this very, very strongly. And I didn't know if Mr. Saxton wanted to involve himself in this discussion, but I know he wants to help here, too. If the gentleman would take me up on that offer, and if he's got a nongovernmental organization in mind, let's move out on this one. It looks like an excellent, excellent opportunity for cooperating and helping.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400195" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 2 minutes to the distinguished gentlewoman from Texas (Ms. Jackson-Lee).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400199" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I thank the distinguished gentleman from New York (Mr. Israel) for yielding and thank you for the leadership given.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We join you and we thank Congresswoman Barbara Lee as well. We have been working, Congressman Payne, members of the Congressional Black Caucus, and this entire caucus have been working on this issue, and want to thank you for, I think, what is a holistic, bipartisan approach.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would call it an undiscovered airfield, but it is not. Obviously, it is an airfield that represents a strategic location for the goals of your amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think it's important to note that the slaughter still continues in Darfur; the slaughter still continues in Sudan. And I was told just recently, and I appreciate the Save Darfur Coalition that we have all worked with that repeatedly come to your offices and tell you that the slaughter still goes on, that humanitarian workers have also been put in jeopardy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Women who are trying to get firewood, and isn't it a simple task? And many of us don't understand, they are still getting firewood, and that is, women who are leaving villages, even in Chad, where I have gone to the refugee camps, women will leave those refugee camps to get, if you will, the firewood for their income, for their survival, and will be raped and sometimes beaten as they go to do that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>To have a place for the humanitarian workers and the airlift that is necessary, both in Darfur and also in other regions of Sudan, can be lifesaving.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I hope, as the ranking member of the full committee indicated his interest of collaboration, that we too can collaborate and work with you and work with this final solution. I like to call it final, because, as you well know, the deaths are peaking.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to say to the ranking member, Mr. Hunter, as I also thank the chairman of the full committee, because this is a unique amendment. Both of you, of course, had to agree on the uniqueness of this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But the idea of it is that humanitarian workers are not safe. Therefore, it is important for those humanitarian workers to be safe. I simply say this is an excellent amendment. I thank you, and I encourage everyone to support and vote for this amendment in order to save lives in the Sudan.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400195" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I will wrap up. We have heard this evening that this resolution enjoys bipartisan support and support with Members with different ideologies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The cosponsor of this amendment, the gentlewoman from California (Ms. Lee), and I have different ideologies. I tend to lean to the right on national security issues, she tends to lean to the left. But we are united in sending a message around the world that we will not allow genocide to occur.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After the Holocaust, the world embraced the slogan, "Never Again." What this resolution does is say that we will explore every option to keep our promise to that slogan so that it is not just words.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also want to point out that the resolution, in addition to having the support of the distinguished ranking member of the House Armed Services Committee, Republicans and Democrats, also was supported by Citizens for Global Slogans, Enough, the Project to Abolish Genocide and Mass Atrocities, the Genocide Intervention Network, the Save Darfur Coalition and the Truman National Security Project. This is something that we can all agree on. I am grateful to the chairman of the Armed Services Committee.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Would the gentleman yield?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400195" topic="">
    <paragraph>I will yield to my friend.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me offer we have these great nongovernmental organizations, we have a lot of people who have been displaced and abused in Darfur. They desperately need food and medicine. I will commit to the gentleman that we will try to work with these NGOs that we know of and let's try to work together in a partnership and try to get a plane load of supplies into that airfield or another one by the first of July. That's a little more than a month from now.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let's work together. We will start working today to try to get this done. Let's prod the good old State Department and DOD to get out there and survey that airfield.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400195" topic="">
    <paragraph>Reclaiming my time, I appreciate the gentleman's exuberance. I certainly will work with him and with the chairman of the Armed Services Committee to work on a truly bipartisan effort that genocide will not be tolerated, and we will explore every option and push every button we need to.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman. We will work with him.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the amendment of the gentleman from New York (Mr. Israel).</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 2 minutes to the gentleman from Georgia (Mr. Johnson), a member of the Armed Services Committee.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412199" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I would like to begin by thanking Chairman Skelton and Ranking Member Hunter for constructing such an impressive bill. We in Congress have no greater duty than that of taking care of our soldiers, marines, sailors and airmen when they are serving both abroad and at home.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our wounded heroes face a system which, while it provided extraordinary service to many, has undergone serious challenges in the proper treatment of some who have given us so much. This amendment would provide necessary facility improvements at both the National Naval Medical Center, Bethesda, and DeWitt Army Medical Center to support commercial medical standards.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Furthermore, this would provide the necessary consolidation of medical activities to ensure high standards of care, or to ensure that high standards of care are available to our wounded soldiers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It would also renovate existing semi-private bedrooms to create additional single-occupant rooms, which ensure greater privacy, improved infection control, and space for families to room in.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 3 minutes to the gentleman from New Jersey (Mr. Saxton).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400359" topic="">
    <paragraph>Thank you very much, Mr. Hunter, for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, one of the provisions that is contained in this en bloc amendment is a provision that will help provide a higher level of security for our military personnel in the continental United States. As most of you probably read in the newspaper, a terrorist cell was apprehended in Cherry Hill, New Jersey, a short time ago.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>They had been planning a small arms attack on soldiers, Reservists, actually, who were preparing to be deployed to Iraq and Afghanistan at Fort Dix.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One of the elements of this planning involved a pizza delivery man. The pizza delivery man would access the base to deliver pizza to soldiers in the  evening who had completed their day's training.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As the apprehension was made, it was disclosed that this individual had actually entered onto the base, memorized the roads and the buildings on the base, and had actually drawn a map to provide to the other members of the cell who would take part in the attack.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This provision that's in this en bloc amendment would provide some extra tools for base commanders to be sure that people who enter onto Federal installations would have a background check done through the FBI, as well as through the Department of Homeland Security where immigration records are kept.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank Mr. Andrews for his high level of cooperation on this, and also to express my thanks to the chairman for agreeing to make this provision part of this en bloc amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I understand there are some questions about it. Mr. Andrews and I, I won't speak for him, as we work through this, between now and the time we get a conference report, there may be some changes that are necessary. The last thing we want to do is to unduly restrict civilian activities, legitimate civilian activities on and around military bases.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I look forward to working with the chairman, the ranking member and Mr. Andrews and others who may be interested to make sure that we do not do something that is harmful to morale or stymies activities on or around military bases.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 2 minutes to the gentleman from Louisiana (Mr. Boustany).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400636" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the ranking member.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, the purpose of the amendment that we have is plain and simple. It's to protect the privacy of America's fallen heroes and their families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Along with my colleague and friend from Oklahoma, Congressman Boren, I introduced this measure at the request of mothers of Marine Private David Burridge and Army Corporal Joseph Thibodeaux, both of Lafayette, Louisiana, who lost their lives in Iraq in September of 2004. While still recovering from the shock and the loss of their children, these mothers were appalled to discover the names of their sons had been printed on the back of T-shirts and sold for profit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment before us today requires that our military men and women, or their surviving relatives, be the sole decisionmaker in consenting to use their name or image for commercial purposes. While there is no way to ever express in words the significance of their sacrifice, we have a duty to honor and protect their memories and, most importantly, their rights.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>No one can dispute that Americans, and particularly Members of this body, have fundamental differences over the war in Iraq. All Americans certainly have a right to express these views in public, but Americans, and particularly our fallen heroes and their families, also have a right to protect their names and images from commercial exploitation. This amendment accomplishes just that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank Chairman Skelton, our Ranking Member Hunter, as well as the Rules Committee for allowing this amendment to come to the floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge our colleagues to support this nonpartisan legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 1 minute to a member of the Armed Services Committee, my friend from Oklahoma (Mr. Boren).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400645" topic="">
    <paragraph>Thank you, Mr. Skelton. I also want to thank our colleague from Louisiana (Mr. Boustany) and our ranking member, Mr. Duncan Hunter.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, this amendment prohibits the commercial use of our troops' names and images without permission.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The need for this protection was first brought to my attention by Judy Vincent, a constituent who lost her son, Marine Corporal Scott Vincent, to a suicide bomber in Fallujah in April of 2004. Since that time, Judy has found Internet vendors using the name and likeness of her son and other fallen soldiers on their merchandise.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Bills were signed into law in Oklahoma and Louisiana last year to address this abuse, but Judy's story made it clear that there were hundreds, perhaps thousands of American families out there facing the same problem, and only a Federal law will offer the protection that they deserve.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment isn't about financial restitution, stifling debate on the war, even putting people in prison. It's about respecting the privacy of our soldiers and their families. I urge my colleagues to support this amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 1 minute to my colleague and friend, the gentleman from Pennsylvania (Mr. Altmire).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412231" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, ongoing military engagements and extended deployments impact not only our troops, but also the families of our brave men and women in uniform. Military families are struggling to balance everything from their financial obligations to child care responsibilities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I offer this amendment to address this and provide military families with some relief. This amendment allows the immediate family of military personnel to use Family Medical Leave Act time for issues directly arising from deployment and extended deployments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The wife of a recently deployed military servicemember could use the Family Medical Leave Act to arrange for child care. The husband of a servicemember could use the Family Medical Leave Act to attend predeployment briefings and family support sessions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The parents of a deployed servicemember could take Family Medical Leave Act time to see their raised child off or welcome them back home.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment does not expand eligibility to employees not already covered by the Family Medical Leave Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, how much time do we have on this?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from California has 5 remaining minutes, and the gentleman from Missouri has 6 1/2  minutes remaining.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Thank you. I just wanted to say that we strongly support this amendment on this side. We think it's an excellent amendment. We thank both of the authors, the gentleman from Louisiana and the gentleman from Oklahoma, for bringing this amendment to us. We support it very strongly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of our time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400396" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 1 minute to my friend and colleague, the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Lipinski).</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400630" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I would like to thank Chairman Skelton and Ranking Member Hunter for placing this amendment en bloc. It is a bipartisan amendment that I offered along with Mr. Inglis, Mr. Markey, and Mr. Kirk.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment simply requires the Department of Defense, where feasible, to begin using high-efficiency light bulbs whenever a light bulb is installed. Currently, compact fluorescent light bulbs, known as CFLs, are the most energy efficient. CFLs use about 75 percent less energy than standard bulbs, last 8 to 10 times longer and can save over $74 over the lifetime of a single bulb.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When you consider that the DOD has over 240,000 buildings in the U.S. alone, it is clear that this requirement is a practical way to make significant progress in lowering energy consumption, reducing greenhouse gas emissions, and promoting energy independence while at the same time saving millions of taxpayer dollars.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At a time when we struggle with a new energy plan, this is a rare win-win-win opportunity, and I ask for your support.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise to claim the time in opposition to this, although I do not oppose the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the gentleman from California reclaims the time that he yielded back.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Thank you, Mr. Chairman. That's exactly what I wanted to do.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I just wanted to get on the record that I support this amendment very strongly, the idea of saving energy. I would hope that the gentleman would agree that, wherever possible, the energy-saving devices, these light bulbs, should be made in the United States.  They are paid for with Department of Defense funds. The average American worker spends over $1,000 a year out of his or her paycheck to support the defense function of government, and it is appropriate  that American workers be allowed to make the new, innovative, energy-saving devices that we are using at bases throughout the country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield to the gentleman to ask him if he wouldn't agree with me that, wherever it is practical, that American-made bulbs should be used in this replacement program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield to the gentleman.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400630" topic="">
    <paragraph>I certainly agree with the gentleman, and I think we need to do more to make sure we are enforcing our Buy America provisions that we currently have in law, and certainly we need to do it here.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400396" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 2 minutes to my friend and colleague, the gentlewoman from Texas (Ms. Jackson-Lee).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Ms. JACKSON-LEE asked and was given permission to revise and extend her remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400199" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the distinguished speaker, chairman, and gentlelady from California.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise to offer and to support the en bloc amendments, and to speak particularly to amendment No. 23 which regards the emotional and financial impact of multiple deployments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment is simple. It requires the Secretary of Defense to study and report back to Congress the financial and emotional impact of multiple deployments on the families of those soldiers who serve multiple tours. We all are concerned about our soldiers and, likewise, their families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In a report by Dr. Hoge, a study indicated that 94 percent of soldiers in Iraq reported receiving small arms fire, 86 percent of soldiers in Iraq reported knowing someone who has been seriously injured or killed, and 68 percent reported seeing dead or seriously injured Americans; 51 percent reported handling or uncovering human remains; and the majority, 77 percent of soldiers deployed to Iraq, reported shooting or directing fire at the enemy. All of this impacts their families, and we found  anxiety, fatigue, stress, and other aspects that impact the wives and children as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The National Military Families have indicated a series of recommendations for the Department of Defense. I believe this study will help the entire entity of the military make us stronger and certainly respond to the needs of our military and their families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My amendment No. 24 recognizes that in 1948 the military was desegregated; integration had increased the percentage of African Americans in the enlisted ranks. We see high numbers of Hispanics and Asians and others. This amendment simply acknowledges the existence of the ROTC scholarship and asks that there be an outreach to ensure that this information be given to Hispanic-serving institutions and African American-serving institutions, historically black colleges.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The importance of this amendment is to ensure the outreach and the opportunities for our young people who are placed around the Nation. Patriotism is certainly not guided by region or colleges to which you go. I ask my colleagues to support these amendments, one to take a holistic view of the redeployment and the impact on our families, and, two, to outreach to our young people no matter where they attend college and where they live for the established ROTC and other military scholarships.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank the chairman and ranking member for allowing me to explain my amendments to <bill type="h" number="1585">H.R. 1585</bill>, the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008. There is no greater champion of our men and women in uniform than my good friend Mr. SKELTON, the gentleman from Missouri, and distinguished chair of the Armed Services Committee. That is why I appreciate the chairman's support for my amendments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, in light of the fact that our Nation is in the midst of an ugly war, and in the context of the ongoing fight against terrorism, this piece of legislation is probably the most important piece of legislation that the 110th Congress will pass. It is in that spirit that I offer my amendments today. Each of my amendments plays a vital role in ensuring that our courageous troops maintain their status as the best in the world. Accordingly my amendments also reinforce the message to our  troops that they are our most precious resource, and we do not take their efforts for granted.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment requires the Secretary of Defense to take the necessary steps to ensure that Army National Guard and Reserve ROTC scholarships are available to students attending historically black colleges and universities, and Hispanic serving institutions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The military is the American institution that has done more than any other to recognize that it does not have a person to waste. It is therefore no surprise that the Armed Forces of the United States, which were completely segregated 60 years ago and riven by racial strife 30 years ago during the Vietnam war, is today the finest fighting force in the history of the world and enjoys more racial peace, harmony, and integration than any other major institution, including higher education and organized  religion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After being desegregated in 1948, by the 1970s, integration had increased the percentage of African-Americans in the enlisted ranks, but the percentage of minorities comprised less than 3 percent of the officer corps and perceptions of discrimination were pervasive. The deficiency in the officer corps and the discrimination perceived to be its cause led to low morale and heightened racial tension. The danger this created was not theoretical. As the Vietnam war continued, the Armed Forces suffered  racial polarization, severe disciplinary problems, and racially motivated incidents in Vietnam and on posts around the world. In Vietnam, racial tensions reached a point where there was an inability to fight and the lack of minority officers substantially exacerbated the problem.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The absence of minority officers seriously threatened the military's ability to function effectively and fulfill its mission to defend the Nation. To eliminate that threat, the armed services moved aggressively to increase the number of minority officers and to train officers in diverse educational environments. The Pentagon set recruitment goals for the service academies and the ROTC programs and worked hard to expand the pool of highly qualified minority candidates in a variety of explicitly  race-conscious ways. They also employ race as a factor in recruiting and admissions policies and decisions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These efforts have substantially increased the percentage of minority officers. Today, among active duty officers, 81 percent are white, and the remaining 19 percent are minority, including 8.8 percent African-American, 4 percent Hispanic, 3.2 percent Asian-American, and .6 percent Native American. The military recognizes that its officer corps must continue to be diverse or the cohesiveness essential to the military mission will be critically undermined. After all, for people who fight wars  to preserve the peace, it can be a matter of life and death.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Presently the military, unlike any other industry including corporate America and the entertainment industry, offers a realistic opportunity for young people of color and women to make career advancements. In an industry that truly judges you on merit and not the color of your skin, the military is a leader in the practice of diversity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment ensures that people of color and women continue their great legacy in the greatest military in the world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment requires the Secretary of Defense to study and report back to Congress the financial and emotional impact of multiple deployments on the families of those soldiers who serve multiple tours overseas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Words cannot explain the pain and the sense of pride that some families feel when they say good-bye to a loved one. Behind those brave smiles, hugs, and kisses is an undying and unnerving uncertainty about what can happen to a spouse, child, father, or mother. Depending on the extent of that soldier's injury, a family can suffer serious economic consequences as a result, not to mention the emotional impact of seeing a loved one in that state. Even under the best of circumstances, where a soldier  serves multiple terms and returns with no major injuries, valuable time is lost between a parent and child and between spouses that can never be returned.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The mental health of our soldiers will have a lasting effect on not only these soldiers but their families as well. The current conflicts in Afghanistan and Iraq are the most continuous combat operations since Vietnam. Only one comprehensive study has examined the mental health impact of the wars in Afghanistan and Iraq, and that was performed by Charles W. Hoge, MD. This study looked at the experience of soldiers in the war zone and symptoms of psychological distress. Soldiers in Iraq are at  risk for being killed or wounded themselves, are likely to have witnessed the suffering of others, and may have participated in  killing or wounding others as part of combat operations. All of these activities have a demonstrated association with the development of PTSD. Dr. Hoge's study indicated that 94 percent of soldiers in Iraq reported receiving small-arms fire. In addition, 86 percent of soldiers in Iraq reported knowing someone who was seriously injured or killed, 68 percent</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As my colleague from Arizona, GABRIELLE GIFFORDS, mentioned this morning, one in five soldiers is suffering from depression, anxiety or stress. Likewise 20 percent face marital problems including divorce or legal separation from their spouse.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Military families need greater psychological, emotional, and organizational assistance according to the results of a new survey released March 28 of this year by the National Military Family Association, NMFA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The study, "Cycles of Deployment Report," which focused on the needs of military families, shows service members and military families are experiencing increased levels of anxiety, fatigue, and stress. In response, NMFA outlined recommendations for meeting these challenges amid multiple and extended deployments, increased rates at which service members are called upon for service, and the heavy reliance on National Guard and Reserve forces.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This report clearly shows the range of support programs for families has expanded since the start of the war on terror. However, multiple deployments and a high operations tempo mean different types of support are needed for families' continued success before, during, and after deployment. The survey results provide the Department of Defense a detailed roadmap for making sure families are taken care of during this important time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me share with you some of the key findings from this study about the impact of deployment includes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Almost half of respondents reported they have used or would use counseling services such as anger management classes and family counseling. Three quarters of those who stated they were better able to deal with subsequent deployments found counseling services to be helpful.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Two-thirds of military families surveyed did not have contact with their unit or unit network volunteer during the critical pre-deployment stage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Less than one-half reported a consistent level of family support through the pre-deployment, deployment, and post-deployment phases. Seventeen percent reported no support was available.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many respondents are concerned that volunteers who help families adjust to life during deployment and what to expect after the reunion are becoming fatigued and subject to "burn-out." They stated that the leaders of unit family groups should be paid or have paid professional support personnel assigned.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Military family members with civilian jobs face pressure to avoid taking time off before, during, or after deployment. Sixty percent of military</paragraph>
    <paragraph>spouses are employed outside the home and many have either quit their jobs or are considering it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Military families are worried about how the reunion will go with their deployed family member even as they are worrying about their service member's safety in the field. Unfortunately, many families are not taking advantage of specific return and reunion briefings and activities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many respondents expressed that when entering a second or third deployment, they carry unresolved anxieties and expectations from the last deployments. While they may have gained knowledge of resources available to them, respondents whose service member deployed multiple times reported being more fatigued and increasingly concerned about their family relationships.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although challenged by the demands of deployment, families noted they are proud of their service member and their service to our country. They understand that family support is primarily their personal responsibility, but they expect "The Military" to provide support as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The National Military Families Association has developed a series of recommendations for how the Department of Defense, DOD, can better train and support military staff and civilian volunteers to assist military families. Let me discuss some of them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Expand program and information outreach. Create formats for families to access support services and maintain touch with their commands and unit family group that live too far from either the unit or from other military families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Assist families in developing realistic expectations, and then meet them. Educate military families about what to expect before, during, and after deployments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Direct more resources to support family volunteers. Increase the level of resources and paid professionals, both counselors and administrative, to support the logistics of family support and conducting family readiness activities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Address return and reunion challenges throughout the deployment cycle. Help with the reintegration of a service member with the family after deployment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Recognize that family time is important. Encourage service leaders to give family time a higher priority when planning operational activities, especially for service members who have only been back from deployment for a few months.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Continue deployment briefings throughout the year. Never assume families have all the information they need. Ongoing deployment briefings can especially help new spouses or the parents of new recruits. Experienced family members also may find new challenges during a subsequent deployment or find the accumulated stress from multiple deployments creates the need for re-engagement with the family readiness/support group or for accessing different support personnel.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By requiring the Secretary of Defense to conduct this study we are taking a crucial step in ensuring that future troops are adequately taken care of physically, mentally, and emotionally.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Allow me to conclude by stating that I rise in strong support of the underlying legislation <bill type="h" number="1585">H.R. 1585</bill>. This legislation addresses several critical issues such as troop readiness, troop safety, troop family needs, and a comprehensive internal review of the Department of Defense.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With regards to troop readiness this bill authorizes $1 billion for the Strategic Readiness Fund to fix equipment shortfalls, $1 billion to provide the National Guard and Reserves equipment from their unfunded requirements list, $250 million to improve training, and the establishment of a Defense Readiness Production Board to mobilize the defense industrial base to speed up the production of military equipment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With regards to troop safety this bill provides $1.2 billion for body armor, $2.5 billion for up-armored humvees, $1.2 billion for vehicle add-on armor, $509.7 million for the Armored Security Vehicle, ASV, and requires comprehensive testing of all helmet pad systems.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With regards to meeting the needs of the families of our troops this bill authorizes a 3.5 percent across-the-board pay raise for all service members. This bill restores approximately 490 medical personnel positions and recommends the establishment of a Military Mental Health Initiative that would coordinate all mental health research and development for the Department. Also this bill directs the establishment of a Traumatic Brain Injury Initiative to provide the opportunity for emerging technologies  and treatments to compete for funding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally this bill requires a much needed internal review of the Department of Defense. This bill requires a review of the roles and missions of the Department of Defense every 4 years; identifies the core competencies of the military departments, the Office of the Secretary of Defense, each defense agency, and each defense field activity; directs a review of the capabilities that each of the military departments, the Office of the Secretary of Defense, each defense agency, and each defense field  activity is maintaining or developing; and requires the Joint Requirements Oversight Council, JROC, to organize its review of requirements according to the core mission areas, provide the military services with clear guidance on the priority assigned to each requirement, and make clear the expected resources allocated to fulfill each requirement.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400396" topic="NOTICE TO ALTER ORDER OF CONSIDERATION OF AMENDMENTS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, pursuant to section 3 and 4 of House Resolution 403, and as the designee of the chairman of the Committee on Armed Services, I request that during further consideration of <bill type="h" number="1585">H.R. 1585</bill> in the Committee of the Whole, and following consideration of amendment 49, the following amendments be considered in the following order: amendment No. 30; amendment No. 11; amendment No. 31; amendment No. 41; amendment No. 15; amendment No. 42; amendment No. 43; en bloc No. 3.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, it is my pleasure to yield 3 minutes to my friend and colleague, the gentleman from New Jersey (Mr. Andrews).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Mr. ANDREWS asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400008" topic="NOTICE TO ALTER ORDER OF CONSIDERATION OF AMENDMENTS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I thank my friend for yielding, and I rise in strong support of the amendment offered by my friend and neighbor from New Jersey (Mr. Saxton), and I thank him for his decisive and quick action in dealing with the problem of protecting our servicemembers and employees and visitors to our military bases. I am proud to join with him in this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At this time, I yield to the gentlewoman from Arizona for the purpose of a colloquy.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412188" topic="NOTICE TO ALTER ORDER OF CONSIDERATION OF AMENDMENTS">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise today to raise serious concerns about the amendment to <bill type="h" number="1585">H.R. 1585</bill> that would require background checks for all civilians entering military installations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I certainly appreciate the need to secure our installations, especially considering the recent events in your home State of New Jersey. But I would like to bring a unique situation to your attention.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My southern Arizona district is home to Fort Huachuca, a critical national asset that is home to Army Intelligence and Electronic Testing and was recently designated the Joint Center of Excellence for Human Intelligence Training.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Fort Huachuca occupies over 73,000 acres of rugged desert terrain. The geography of the area forces the citizens of Elgin and Canelo, along with the surrounding communities, to rely on access through the fort to get to their ranches and homes. This amendment would cause significant hardship to the surrounding community that has had access to the installation for decades. I believe that this is not a unique situation, and there may be other circumstances where the restrictions placed on military  installations could be onerous.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400008" topic="NOTICE TO ALTER ORDER OF CONSIDERATION OF AMENDMENTS">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentlewoman for raising this important issue. I assure the gentlelady that I recognize her concerns about the specific military installation in her district and do not want this legislation to cause hardship on its surrounding communities.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412188" topic="NOTICE TO ALTER ORDER OF CONSIDERATION OF AMENDMENTS">
    <paragraph>I would like to ask that the gentleman work with me to address the unique circumstances of the Army installations in southern Arizona.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400008" topic="NOTICE TO ALTER ORDER OF CONSIDERATION OF AMENDMENTS">
    <paragraph>I am aware of the extraordinary burden that this requirement could impose on residents of rural and remote areas of southern Arizona. I look forward to working with the gentlelady to find an appropriate accommodation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412188" topic="NOTICE TO ALTER ORDER OF CONSIDERATION OF AMENDMENTS">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for his support.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400008" topic="NOTICE TO ALTER ORDER OF CONSIDERATION OF AMENDMENTS">
    <paragraph>Reclaiming my time, I again thank Mr. Skelton, Mr. Hunter, and Mr. Saxton for this, I think, excellent effort to improve upon a very real problem that we saw in acute relief last week in New Jersey. I would urge adoption of the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400098" topic="NOTICE TO ALTER ORDER OF CONSIDERATION OF AMENDMENTS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, my amendment to extend for three years the Information Technology Exchange Program--also known as the Digital Tech Corps--has been included in this en bloc amendment, and I thank the Chairman and Ranking Member for accepting this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 2002, I included language in the Electronic Government Act of 2002 creating the Digital Tech Corps program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The program gives mid-level federal IT managers the opportunity for intensive, on-the-job training in how the private sector manages complex IT projects. Too many complex federal IT procurements fail because of improper management. The Tech Corps gives employees insight and experience in how the best companies in the world are successfully managing IT so they can bring this knowledge back to government.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Tech Corps works in reverse as well, giving private sector IT employees the opportunity to volunteer for rewarding public service. In tackling some of the world's toughest IT problems, they can return to their companies understanding the challenges facing the world's largest employer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Tech Corps program is a relatively new vision for public service in this century, enabling broader public-private sector exchanges of talented IT professionals. It builds on the successes of other successful personnel exchanges, such as the 1970 Intergovernmental Personnel Act (IPA).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>All Tech Corps participants must adhere to strict federal employee ethics rules, and they must abide by the laws and rules of the agency and Federal Government. Participants do not receive any special privileges, pay, or incentives--all participants retain pay and benefits from their respective employers while participating in the program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Electronic Government Act of 2002 required the Office of Personnel Management to issue guidance for agencies engaging in the Tech Corps program. Agencies had 5 years from the date of enactment in December 2002 to implement the program. OPM issued its guidance in 2005, making it difficult for agencies to receive the full benefits of implementing the program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since the issuance of OPM's guidelines in 2005 and the approval of DOD's Tech Corps policy in 2006, the agency has worked aggressively to get its Tech Corps program off the ground. Nearly a dozen DOD components have expressed interest in participating in the program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My amendment would extend the authorization period of the Information Technology Exchange Program (ITEP) by 3 years for the Department of Defense (DOD) so it can achieve the intended benefits of the program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In particular, the benefits of the Tech Corps program include: (1) participants learn new job skills; (2) the private sector employees can learn about government procedures and processes; (3) the public and private sectors can share best practices; (4) participating organizations are infused with new ideas; and (5) participants gain perspective from others, improve personal competencies and skills, and close skill gaps within the government organizations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also express my support for language included in this en bloc amendment offered by my colleague, Mr. MORAN, which would require that the transportation infrastructure necessary to accommodate the large influx of military personnel and civilian employees to be assigned to Fort Belvoir, VA, as part of the BRAC realignment of the installation, be substantially completed before the relocation of these employees.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The 2005 BRAC Commission recommended relocating 22,000 Department of Defense personnel to Fort Belvoir by 2011. That is a workforce equal to that of the Pentagon. Due to the magnitude of the BRAC realignment, the existing congestion in the Springfield area, and the potential impact on the surrounding community--and indeed all of Northern Virginia--BRAC implementation has to be done right.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I voted against the BRAC recommendations for several reasons, including my belief DoD had not adequately considered the ramifications of transferring 22,000 new personnel to Fort Belvoir within a 6-year timeframe.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since the recommendations were approved, I have worked diligently with my colleagues to ensure the Army is sensitive to the concerns of my constituents and devotes adequate time and resources to mitigate the impact of BRAC to the extent possible.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to commend my colleague for this amendment, because it gets to the heart of the matter: it ensures the necessary transportation infrastructure will be in place before personnel begin to relocate to Fort Belvoir. This only makes sense.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Without sufficient infrastructure, daily commutes could last for hours. In fact, it might simply be impossible for DoD personnel to even get to and from work, thereby preventing agencies from being able to accomplish their missions. It surely would mark a drastic reduction in quality of life for those employees stuck in what could be a traffic nightmare, and I would submit could easily lead to significant turnover.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would also like to take this opportunity to thank Chairman SKELTON and Ranking Member HUNTER for including language in the bill to require the Army and GSA to work out an agreement to allow the Army to use the GSA warehouse property in Springfield. This facility is located adjacent to an existing Metro and Virginia Railway Express station, yet it currently is used for warehouse space. I have long thought this federal property could be put to much better use than warehouses. With  this language, we will put this property to much better use, promote transit options, and take cars off the road. Again, I am most grateful this provision has been included.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In closing, I would like to thank Mr. MORAN for this amendment and for his continued hard work on behalf of Northern Virginians. I urge my colleagues to support this language and the en bloc amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400380" topic="NOTICE TO ALTER ORDER OF CONSIDERATION OF AMENDMENTS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, after scouting possible targets in New Jersey and Pennsylvania, the six members of a terrorist cell arrested in New Jersey last week chose to attack Fort Dix due to the access one member had to that installation. As a pizza delivery man, he was able to get on the base, survey the infrastructure and personnel, draw maps, and determine the best locations for the highest kill rate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If not for a citizen's tip and a thorough and aggressive law enforcement team led by U.S. Attorney Chris Christie, who through a 16-month surveillance effort dotted every "i" and crossed every "t," terrorists could have infiltrated the base with the sole intent of killing as many people as possible.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, my South Jersey colleagues and I have been arguing for years that easy civilian access to our military bases--across the Nation--could leave them vulnerable to those wishing to do us harm.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 2004, we passed a modified version of my bill, the Military Bases Security Act, <bill type="h" number="3695">H.R. 3695</bill>, and mandated a pilot program in which the Department of Defense could test and increase the vetting of civilians who worked on our bases as employees of private contractors. Because the greatest vulnerability exists when contractors are brought in to complete major construction and facility maintenance jobs, my bill also instructed DOD to use the pilot program to test and implement the best value contracting  process instead of the lowest bidder process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the best value process, contractors are given points for their staffing plans and employee training programs--two effective means for vetting and eliminating unqualified and even undocumented workers from construction jobs. The thought is that by rewarding contractors who vet, train, and hire experienced workers, another layer of protection would be put in place as we attempt to secure our bases.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Regrettably, DOD has yet to issue its final analysis on the pilot program and an interim report indicates that their implementation of the program has been feckless at best. And despite the insistence by the Department of Defense that they are doing everything possible to ensure our bases are employing qualified and legal workers, we consistently learn of Immigration and Customs Enforcement personnel arresting dozens of illegal aliens "working" on military bases around the country. In January  of this year, the International Herald Tribune ran a story that stated nearly 40 illegal aliens were arrested on military installations in Georgia, Virginia and Nevada. And one arrested in Nevada was a member of MS-13, one of the most dangerous gangs in the U.S.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I remain convinced that through best value contracting we can and will do a better job of ensuring that those who obtain contracts on our bases are employing legal and qualified workers. And I am committed to ensuring that DOD gives more than lip service to the pilot program and its provisions to vet unqualified workers and attain the best workmanship and better security at our bases.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The amendment offered today by my colleague Jim Saxton also seeks to vet civilians who enter or conduct business on our bases. Specifically, the Saxton amendment, which is part of an en bloc amendment, requires FBI criminal background checks and clearance from the Department of Homeland Security for any "unescorted civilian seeking access to a military installation or facility or any civilian who is an employee of a contractor or vendor of a military installation." Without the background  check, these civilians will be blocked from entering a base.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, we cannot hermetically seal our military bases--many of which have great activities for the general public--but we can and must make every effort to provide greater protection. The Saxton amendment is another positive step in this direction and I urge my colleagues to support it.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400396" topic="NOTICE TO ALTER ORDER OF CONSIDERATION OF AMENDMENTS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the amendments en bloc offered by the gentleman from Missouri (Mr. Skelton).</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400391" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I offer an amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will designate the amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400391" topic="MODIFICATION TO AMENDMENT NO. 20 OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, communities across our Nation have felt the effects of the ongoing wars in Iraq and Afghanistan, but rural communities have been hit especially hard. A recent Associated Press story reported that nearly half the casualties in Iraq have come from towns of fewer than 25,000 people, and one in five come from towns of 5,000 or less. Rural States have had some of the highest per capita loss rates.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have certainly seen this in my own district. Each loss from a small town affects not only the family but the entire community. In light of these facts, we need to make sure that we are taking care of all the families who have lost loved ones in military service, whether those families live in cities or in small rural communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the past year, I have encountered several disturbing cases in my own district in which families had to fight to have the remains of their loved one flown to an airport near the intended place of burial. The military advised the families that the bodies of their loved one would be flown to the nearest major urban airport, which in some cases, as in my district, are hundreds of miles away.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In order to meet the remains at the airport, one of the families would have been required to drive over 4 hours each way through a snowstorm. There is no reason to impose these kinds of burdens on a family that has already made the ultimate sacrifice. This kind of treatment is disrespectful and unfair. Families should not have to bargain with the military in order to have the remains of their loved ones flown to a location where they can meet their fallen hero.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In many cases, veterans organizations and other community groups want to show their respect when a fallen soldier arrives at an airport. We  should encourage these demonstrations of respect, instead of discouraging them by forcing community members to drive to urban airports hours away from home.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last year, as part of the fiscal year 2007 Defense authorization, the House passed a similar provision that would have required the military to fly the remains of a fallen soldier to the military airfield nearest the place of burial. Unfortunately, this provision was not included in the final conference version of the bill; however, I think it was a good provision, and Members of the House were right to support it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My amendment would provide greater flexibility. It would require that, whenever possible, the Department of Defense fly the remains to the nearest military or civilian airport. The amendment would allow the military to use any of the numerous small airports that exist in rural districts, so long as the remains are delivered to a place that is acceptable to the family of the fallen soldier.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, the problems I speak of are not only in my district, but we have seen reports from New York to California where this has occurred in the smaller rural districts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As Americans, we owe a tremendous debt to those families who have given up a loved one in war to protect our freedom. This amendment will eliminate an unfair situation that those families have faced and will help to show our respect and gratitude for the sacrifice they have made.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask Members to support my amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="MODIFICATION TO AMENDMENT NO. 20 OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, although I don't oppose the amendment, I ask unanimous consent to claim the time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the gentleman from California is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="MODIFICATION TO AMENDMENT NO. 20 OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Thank you, Mr. Chairman.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank the gentleman for his amendment. I think it is absolutely appropriate. We support it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, this is the provision that we put into the law last year when we saw that American fallen service personnel were being transported in what we thought was a less than dignified manner and escorted in a less than dignified manner to their final resting places.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Of course, I went to the Department of Defense initially and had them involved in discussions with the committee with respect to effecting informally a policy that would have dedicated aircraft and would have a dedicated honor guard and military escort that would complete the transport of fallen American service personnel from Dover to their final resting places. We couldn't work something out, so we ended up putting that in law, and having the full support of the other body, that, indeed, is  the practice.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have been around the country now to various places where American heroes have come home, and there has been an outpouring of gratitude from a number of communities and families that in fact the system is working well now with dedicated military aircraft, with the appropriate honor guard escorting the fallen American heroes, and the families now feel much better about the process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>Now, I would hope that, in practice, the U.S. military is not, as a rule, taking people to a home of record when in fact their final resting place may be hundreds of miles away, but I understand that the gentleman has two cases where that, in fact, would have taken place if they hadn't made contact with the DOD and the DOD hadn't sorted that out.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And so I think this is absolutely appropriate to put into statute what, essentially, they've been doing, as I understand, as a matter of practice in carrying out the mandate that we gave them last year with the new law that came from this committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I support the gentleman. I thank him for offering this amendment, and we certainly support it on this side.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400391" topic="MODIFICATION TO AMENDMENT NO. 20 OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I appreciate the words of the ranking member, Mr. Hunter. The difference between what I'm doing here tonight and an amendment we did last year, last year was the closest military airfield. There are no military airfields in my district. My district is 600 miles from one end to the other, and when they want to bring the remains of our soldiers to Detroit or Milwaukee, it is 4, 5, 6 hours for people, for my constituents to go to greet this fallen hero back on  U.S. soil. And you have your local groups, your American Legions, your veterans who'd like to welcome that fallen soldier back home, but to drive 4, 5, 6 hours, and one we had last winter was through a terrible snowstorm.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have had to intervene. We have worked with DOD and others, and they've been pretty good about trying to accommodate everyone. We realize it's hard and it's difficult.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So the only difference is this amendment goes a little farther, not just military airfield but civilian airfields. We have plenty of civilian airfields throughout my district and rural America that can accommodate the planes necessary to bring home our fallen soldiers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I would like to thank Mr. Skelton, Mrs. Tauscher, Mr. Hunter and Mr. Saxton for their help and support. This is an amendment that we're glad we can do to honor those service men and women and also their families and the local communities when they've fallen in service in honor to their country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the amendment offered by the gentleman from Michigan (Mr. Stupak), as modified.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412234" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I offer an amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will designate the amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412234" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield myself 3 minutes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I am here today in support of our Nation's veterans. As a lieutenant commander in the Navy Reserve, I know how important our veterans are. I know how critical our National Guard and Reserve are to the Nation's security.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Montgomery GI bill has provided education to many of our Nation's fine and honorable men and women. After World War II, the GI bill was signed into law and paved the way for many returning soldiers to attain their degrees. In fact, my father earned both his bachelor's and his master's degrees using the GI bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, for our National Guard and Reserve, this is not the case. There's a provision which excludes our National Guard and Reserve from receiving their GI bill after they have left the military.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment, which I am proud to introduce, will express the sense of Congress that we need to lengthen the period of time that Guard and Reserve members have to take advantage of the GI bill. Once they return home they would have up to 10 years to complete their education.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We owe it to our National Guard and Reserve members to have this time. They are very busy in war right now, and they are having a difficult time  completing their degrees. How can we expect them to fight the battles and simultaneously pursue a degree?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many of us know someone who's in the National Guard or Reserve and they're playing an ever increasing role in combat operations. We salute their service, and offering them the additional time to obtain their educational goals is a benefit that we should show them that we do appreciate all their efforts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, we must think of the future of our Armed Forces. It really has saddened me to learn that the National Guard and Reserves has missed the recruitment goals for both 2005 and 2006. We know that the military does provide immense benefits to those that sign up, but it cuts off the Guard and Reserve when it comes to educational benefits. What better way to ensure our military remains an all volunteer force by encouraging more people to join?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Taking care of our troops and making education affordable are two of my top priorities in Congress. As a former professor at Penn State, I understand the value of an education, and believe that an educated work force is a better work force for all America. Extending the education benefit to our National Guard and Reserves will do just that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our troops are serving their country honorably, and the Guard and Reserve should have access to the higher education when they are finished. We owe it to our troops and to our families back home.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge all Members of Congress who care about our troops and the military families to vote in favor of this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I'd like to thank Chairman Skelton for his work on this issue. He is truly a champion for our veterans and our military families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, we support this amendment and think it will be very useful, and thank the gentleman for offering such an outstanding amendment, and we support it.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the amendment offered by the gentleman from Pennsylvania (Mr. Carney).</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Members are advised there are 2 minutes remaining on this vote.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 5-minute vote.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400189" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I move that the Committee do now rise.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The motion was agreed to.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Accordingly, the Committee rose; and the Speaker pro tempore (Mr. Capuano) having assumed the chair, Mr. Pastor, Acting Chairman of the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union, reported that that Committee, having had under consideration the bill (<bill type="h" number="1585">H.R. 1585</bill>) to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2008 for military activities of the Department of Defense, to prescribe military personnel strengths for fiscal year 2008, and for other purposes, had come to no  resolution thereon.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
