<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1173114004" ordinal="15" title="COLORADO NORTHERN FRONT RANGE MOUNTAIN BACKDROP PROTECTION STUDY ACT">
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="903">H.R. 903</bill>) to provide for a study of options for protecting the open space characteristics of certain lands in and adjacent to the Arapaho and Roosevelt National Forests in Colorado, and for other purposes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) and the gentleman from Utah (Mr. Bishop) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Arizona?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today I rise, Mr. Speaker, in strong support of <bill type="h" number="903">H.R. 903</bill>, introduced by my colleague on the Natural Resources Committee, the gentleman from Colorado, Representative MARK UDALL.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation would require the Forest Service to review lands in or adjacent to the Arapaho and Roosevelt National Forests and report to Congress on the present ownership of the lands, and which undeveloped lands may be at risk of development, as well as apprising Congress of appropriate actions that could be taken to preserve the open and undeveloped character of these lands.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rapid population growth in the northern Front Range area of Colorado is spreading west from Denver, pushing homes and shopping centers up the valleys and along the highways. This development then spreads out along the ridges and mountaintops that make up this backdrop. New homes and businesses in the wildland urban interface also create new liabilities for first responders and a more complicated management framework for forest managers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The result of these changes is the potential loss of many of the very qualities that attract new residents and contribute to the quality of life of the region. <bill type="h" number="903">H.R. 903</bill> is designed to help provide a better understanding of what steps might be done to lessen the risk.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I want to commend and congratulate my colleague, Mr. Udall, for his commitment and leadership on this matter. A hearing was held on a nearly identical measure last Congress, and the bill was approved by the Natural Resources Committee and passed the House by voice vote last September.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, we strongly support <bill type="h" number="903">H.R. 903</bill> and urge its adoption by the House today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400029" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="903">H.R. 903</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, <bill type="h" number="903">H.R. 903</bill> would require the Forest Service to review non-Federal lands in or adjacent to the Arapaho-Roosevelt National Forest and recommend strategies to maintain open space. Republicans do not object to this legislation, but considering the current budget constraints on the Forest Service, we believe funds would be better used to tackle the enormous risk of catastrophic wildfire in Colorado. Currently, 42 percent of Colorado's forests are suffering from bark beetle infestation,  which continues to spread and will likely kill thousands of acres of trees. These dead and dying trees pose extremely high wildfire risks to Colorado's forests. Surely funds would be better spent on removing dead and dying trees that pose a tremendous threat to homes and communities, watersheds and wildlife habitat.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Moreover, we believe that local and State governments should address open space and smart growth options rather than Federal Government agencies based here in Washington, D.C. While we commend Mr. Udall's good intentions, we believe recommendations and solutions to these problems should come from the counties and the States, not from the Federal Government.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400412" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I rise in strong support of <bill type="h" number="903">H.R. 903</bill>, the Colorado Northern Front Range Mountain Backdrop Protection Study bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is identical to a measure that passed the House last year but on which the Senate did not complete action. I appreciate the actions of Chairman Rahall, Ranking Member Don Young, and the staff of the Natural Resources Committee for making it possible for the House to consider it today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill is intended to help local communities identify ways to protect the Front Range Mountain Backdrop in the northern sections of the Denver-metro area, especially the region just west of what will soon be the Rocky Flats National Wildlife Refuge.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Arapaho-Roosevelt National Forest includes much of the land in this backdrop area, but there are other lands as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rising dramatically from the Great Plains, the Front Range of the Rocky Mountains provides a scenic mountain backdrop to many communities in the Denver metropolitan area and elsewhere in Colorado.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The portion of the range addressed in this bill also includes a diverse array of wildlife habitats and provides many opportunities for outdoor recreation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Its open-space character is an important esthetic and economic asset for adjoining communities, making them attractive locations for homes and businesses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But rapid population growth in the northern Front Range area of Colorado is increasing recreational use of the Arapaho-Roosevelt National Forest and is also placing increased pressure for development of other lands.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We can see this throughout Colorado and especially along the Front Range.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Homes and shopping centers are spreading up the valleys and along the highways. This development then spreads out along the ridges and mountain tops that make up the backdrop.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The result is potential loss of many of the very qualities that attract new residents.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill is designed to help provide a better understanding of what steps might be done to lessen that risk.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Already, local governments and other entities have provided important protection for portions of this mountain backdrop.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill acknowledges their good work and aims to assist further efforts along the same lines.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill does not interfere with the authority of local authorities regarding land use planning.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And it does not infringe on private property rights.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Instead, it will bring the land protection experience of the Forest Service to the table to assist local efforts to protect areas that comprise the backdrop.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under the bill, the Forest Service will work in collaboration with local communities, the state, nonprofit groups, and other parties.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think this is in the national interest.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The backdrop both beckoned settlers westward and was a daunting challenge to their progress. Their first exposure to the harshness and humbling majesty of the Rocky Mountain West helped define a region, and the pioneers' independent spirit and respect for nature still lives with us to this day.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We need to work to maintain the mountain backdrop as a cultural and natural heritage for ourselves and generations to come.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill is intended to assist in that effort, and I urge its approval.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400029" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no further requests for time, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no further requests for time, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="903">H.R. 903</bill>.</chair>
</record>
