<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1184731200" ordinal="21" title="PROVIDING FOR FURTHER CONSIDERATION OF H.R. 3043, DEPARTMENTS OF LABOR, HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES, AND EDUCATION, AND RELATED AGENCIES APPROPRIATIONS ACT, 2008">
  <narrative>PROVIDING FOR FURTHER CONSIDERATION OF <bill type="h" number="3043">H.R. 3043</bill>, DEPARTMENTS OF LABOR, HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES, AND EDUCATION, AND RELATED AGENCIES APPROPRIATIONS ACT, 2008 -- (House of Representatives - July 18, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H8036]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400300" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that, during further consideration of <bill type="h" number="3043">H.R. 3043</bill> in the Committee of the Whole pursuant to House Resolution 547, notwithstanding clause 11 of rule XVIII, no further amendment to the bill may be offered except:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Pro forma amendments offered at any point in the reading by the chairman or ranking minority member of the Committee on Appropriations or their designees for the purpose of debate;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Pascrell regarding funding for Traumatic Brain Injury programs;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Nadler regarding eligibility for 9/11 health programs;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Nadler regarding funding for 9/11 health programs;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Barton of Texas regarding funding for the National Institutes of Health;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Garrett of New Jersey regarding funding for certain autism programs;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Holt regarding funding for math and science partnerships;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Cooper regarding funding for Historically Black Colleges and Universities and Historically Black Graduate Institutions;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Flake reducing funding for the Corporation for National and Community Service;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Conaway limiting funds for the LIHEAP program until certain conditions are met;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Conaway regarding use of reductions made through amendment for deficit reduction;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Dingell regarding the Deputy Commissioner of the Social Security Administration;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Gingrey limiting funds for Social Security totalization agreements with Mexico;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Hare regarding Critical Access Hospitals;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Jordan of Ohio reducing funds in the bill by 4.6 percent, which shall be debatable for 30 minutes;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Ms. Moore of Wisconsin, Mr. Scott of Virginia, Mr. Cole of Oklahoma or Ms. Shea-Porter regarding the Upward Bound program;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mrs. Musgrave reducing funds in the bill by 0.5 percent, which shall be debatable for 30 minutes;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Price of Georgia reducing funds in the bill by 1 percent, which shall be debatable for 30 minutes;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Campbell of California reducing funds in the bill by 0.25 percent, which shall be debatable for 30 minutes;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Obey regarding earmarks;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Scott of Virginia regarding funding for student drug testing;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Lewis of Georgia, Mr. Welch of Vermont, or Mr. Weller of Illinois regarding certain Medicare regulations;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Ms. Jackson-Lee of Texas regarding the Office of Civil Rights at the Department of Education;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Ms. Jackson-Lee of Texas regarding Education for the Disadvantaged;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Upton or Ms. Harman regarding use of Energy Star certified light bulbs;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Pence limiting funds for Planned Parenthood;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Ehlers regarding funding for math and science partnership programs;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Gingrey or Mr. Jordan of Ohio limiting funds regarding requirements for HPV vaccinations for school admittance;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Ryan of Wisconsin limiting funds for certain Centers for Disease Control Activities;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Garrett of New Jersey limiting funds for certain international conferences;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. King of Iowa limiting the use of funds to employ workers described in section 274A of the Immigration and Nationality Act;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. King of Iowa limiting the use of funds to sponsor certain events at the Sundance Film Festival;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Davis of Kentucky limiting performance bonuses  for certain employees of the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services and the Social Security Administration;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Davis of Kentucky limiting performance bonuses for certain employees of the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services and the Social Security Administration unless certain requirements related to Medicare part D are met;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mrs. Schmidt limiting funds for title X grantees;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Flake limiting funds for the American Jazz Museum in Kansas City, Missouri;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Flake limiting funds for the American Ballet Theatre in New York;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Flake limiting funds for the Portugese and Lusophone studies at Rhode Island College;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Flake limiting funds for the Shedd Aquarium in Chicago;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Flake limiting funds for the Kansas Regional Prisons Museum;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Flake limiting funds for the Corporation for Jefferson's Poplar Forest in Virginia;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Flake limiting funds for the South Carolina Aquarium;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Flake limiting funds for the Burpee Museum in Rockford, Illinois;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Flake limiting funds for a college preparatory pilot program at Missouri State University;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Flake limiting funds for the Exploratorium in San Francisco, California;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mrs. Musgrave limiting funds for attachment therapy;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Souder limiting CMS funds for certain Medicare payment activities related to hospital transplant programs;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Souder limiting funds of the National Labor Relations Board to recognize a union as the exclusive bargaining representative of employees that has not been elected by a secret-ballot election;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Hensarling reducing funding for the Centers for Disease Control;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Westmoreland limiting funds for the publication of certain student loan applications;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Campbell of California limiting funds for the Charter School Development Foundation;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Campbell of California limiting funds for the City College of New York;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Campbell of California limiting funds for all projects requested by Members of Congress and disclosed pursuant to the rules of the House, which shall be debatable for 20 minutes;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Camp of Michigan regarding the Medicare Advantage program;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Crowley limiting funds for the North Carolina Technology Association Education Foundation;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Crowley limiting funds for Alleghany Memorial Hospital;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Crowley limiting funds for Caldwell Community College and Technical Institute;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Crowley limiting funds for the North Carolina Center for Emerging Technologies;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Crowley limiting funds for the Southeastern Center for Emerging Biologic Threats;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Hensarling regarding education for Native Hawaiians;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Barrett of South Carolina regarding Byrd Honors Scholarship program;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Lamborn regarding the Corporation of Public Broadcasting;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Hensarling regarding Twin Cities Public Television for the Minnesota Digital Public Media Archive;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Hensarling regarding West Los Angeles College, Culver City, California;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Hensarling regarding Families in Schools, Los Angeles, California; and</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment or amendments by Mr. Obey regarding funding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Each such amendment may be offered only by the Member named in this request or a designee, shall be considered as read, shall not be subject to amendment (except that the chairman and ranking minority member of the Committee on Appropriations and its Subcommittee on Labor, Health and Human Services, Education, and Related Agencies in each such capacity each may offer one pro forma amendment for the purpose of debate); and shall not be subject to a demand for division of the question in the House  or in the Committee of the Whole.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Except as otherwise specified, each amendment shall be debatable for 10 minutes, equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent. An amendment shall be considered to fit the description stated in this request if it addresses in whole or in part the object described.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Wisconsin?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
</record>
