<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1188956525" ordinal="16" title="MINORITY SERVING INSTITUTION DIGITAL AND WIRELESS TECHNOLOGY OPPORTUNITY ACT OF 2007">
  <narrative>MINORITY SERVING INSTITUTION DIGITAL AND WIRELESS TECHNOLOGY OPPORTUNITY ACT OF 2007 -- (House of Representatives - September 04, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H10021]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400011" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="694">H.R. 694</bill>) to establish a digital and wireless network technology program, and for other purposes, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="694">H.R. 694</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "Minority Serving Institution Digital and Wireless Technology Opportunity Act of 2007".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. ESTABLISHMENT OF PROGRAM.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Section 5 of the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (15 U.S.C. 3704) is amended by inserting the following after subsection (b):&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(c) Minority Serving Institution Digital and Wireless Technology Opportunity Program.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(1) IN GENERAL.--The Secretary shall establish a Minority Serving Institution Digital and Wireless Technology Opportunity Program to assist eligible institutions in acquiring, and augmenting their use of, digital and wireless networking technologies to improve the quality and delivery of educational services at eligible institutions.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(2) AUTHORIZED ACTIVITIES.--An eligible institution may use a grant, cooperative agreement, or contract awarded under this subsection--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(A) to acquire equipment, instrumentation, networking capability, hardware and software, digital network technology, wireless technology, and infrastructure to further the objective of the Program described in paragraph (1);&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(B) to develop and provide training, education, and professional development programs, including faculty development, to increase the use of, and usefulness of, digital and wireless networking technology;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(C) to provide teacher education, including the provision of preservice teacher training and in-service professional development at eligible institutions, library and media specialist training, and preschool and teacher aid certification to individuals who seek to acquire or enhance technology skills in order to use digital and wireless networking technology in the classroom or instructional process, including instruction in science, mathematics, engineering, and technology subjects;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(D) to obtain capacity-building technical assistance, including through remote technical support, technical assistance workshops, and distance learning services; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(E) to foster the use of digital and wireless networking technology to improve research and education, including scientific, mathematics, engineering, and technology instruction.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(3) APPLICATION AND REVIEW PROCEDURES.--</narrative>
  <narrative> "(A) IN GENERAL.--To be eligible to receive a grant, cooperative agreement, or contract under this subsection, an eligible institution shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require. Such application, at a minimum, shall include a description of how the funds will be used, including a description of any digital and wireless networking technology to be acquired, and a description of how the institution  will ensure that digital and wireless networking will be made accessible to, and employed by, students, faculty, and administrators. The Secretary, consistent with subparagraph (C) and in consultation with the advisory council established under subparagraph (B), shall establish procedures to review such applications. The Secretary shall publish the application requirements and review criteria in the Federal Register, along with a statement describing the availability of funds.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(B) ADVISORY COUNCIL.--The Secretary shall establish an advisory council to advise the Secretary on the best approaches to encourage maximum participation by eligible institutions in the program established under paragraph (1), and on the procedures to review proposals submitted to the program. In selecting the members of the advisory council, the Secretary shall consult with representatives of appropriate organizations, including representatives of eligible institutions, to ensure  that the membership of the advisory council includes representatives of minority businesses and eligible institution communities. The Secretary shall also consult with experts in digital and wireless networking technology to ensure that such expertise is represented on the advisory council.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(C) REVIEW PANELS.--Each application submitted under this subsection by an eligible institution shall be reviewed by a panel of individuals selected by the Secretary to judge the quality and merit of the proposal, including the extent to which the eligible institution can effectively and successfully utilize the proposed grant, cooperative agreement, or contract to carry out the program described in paragraph (1). The Secretary shall ensure that the review panels include representatives  of minority serving institutions and others who are knowledgeable about eligible institutions and technology issues. The Secretary shall ensure that no individual assigned under this subsection to review any application has a conflict of interest with regard to that application. The Secretary shall take into consideration the recommendations of the review panel in determining whether to award a grant, cooperative agreement, or contract to an eligible institution.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(D) INFORMATION DISSEMINATION.--The Secretary shall convene an annual meeting of eligible institutions receiving grants, cooperative agreements, or contracts under this subsection to foster collaboration and capacity-building activities among eligible institutions.</narrative>
  <narrative> "(E) MATCHING REQUIREMENT.--The Secretary may not award a grant, cooperative agreement, or contract to an eligible institution under this subsection unless such institution agrees that, with respect to the costs incurred by the institution in carrying out the program for which the grant, cooperative agreement, or contract was awarded, such institution shall make available, directly, or through donations from public or private entities, non-Federal contributions in an amount equal to  one-quarter of the grant, cooperative agreement, or contract awarded by the Secretary, or $500,000, whichever is the lesser amount. The Secretary shall waive the matching requirement for any institution or consortium with no endowment, or an endowment that has a current dollar value lower than $50,000,000.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(F) AWARDS.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(i) LIMITATION.--An eligible institution that receives a grant, cooperative agreement, or contract under this subsection that exceeds $2,500,000 shall not be eligible to receive another grant, cooperative agreement, or contract.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(ii) CONSORTIA.--Grants, cooperative agreements, and contracts may only be awarded to eligible institutions. Eligible institutions may seek funding under this subsection for consortia which may include other eligible institutions, a State or a State education agency, local education agencies, institutions of higher education, community-based organizations, national nonprofit organizations, or businesses, including minority businesses.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(iii) PLANNING GRANTS.--The Secretary may provide funds to develop strategic plans  to implement such grants, cooperative agreements, or contracts.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(iv) INSTITUTIONAL DIVERSITY.--In awarding grants, cooperative agreements, and contracts to eligible institutions, the Secretary shall ensure, to the extent practicable, that awards are made to all types of institutions eligible for assistance under this subsection.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(v) NEED.--In awarding funds under this subsection, the Secretary shall give priority to the institution with the greatest demonstrated need for assistance.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(G) ANNUAL REPORT AND EVALUATION.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(i) ANNUAL REPORT REQUIRED FROM RECIPIENTS.--Each institution that receives a grant, cooperative agreement, or contract awarded under this subsection shall provide an annual report to the Secretary on its use of the grant, cooperative agreement, or contract.</narrative>
  <narrative> "(ii) INDEPENDENT ASSESSMENT.--Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Secretary shall enter into a contract with the National Academy of Public Administration to conduct periodic assessments of the program. The Assessments shall be conducted once every 3 years during the 10-year period following the enactment of this subsection. The assessments shall include an evaluation of the effectiveness of the program in improving the education and training  of students, faculty and staff at eligible institutions that have been awarded grants, cooperative agreements, or contracts under the program; an evaluation of the effectiveness of the program in improving access to, and familiarity with, digital and wireless networking technology for students, faculty, and staff at all eligible institutions;</narrative>
  <narrative> (2) such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2009 through 2012. &lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Washington (Mr. Baird) and the gentleman from Texas (Mr. Hall) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Washington.</chair>
  <chair/>
  <speaking speaker="400011" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and to include extraneous material on <bill type="h" number="694">H.R. 694</bill>, the bill now under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Washington?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400011" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="694">H.R. 694</bill>, the Minority Serving Institution Digital and Wireless Opportunity Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill creates a program to improve computer networks at minority-serving educational institutions. The program will award cost-shared grants to eligible campuses to buy networking equipment and train students and teachers in how to use it. The grants will be awarded by the Secretary of Commerce, and the program will be reviewed by the National Academy of Public Administration every 3 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In today's digital world, computer networks are a key part of the educational experience. But many campuses, especially minority-serving institutions, do not have the resources to build those networks on their own. That hurts the students and makes them less prepared to find jobs when they graduate. <bill type="h" number="694">H.R. 694</bill> will help fix that problem and enable many students to get the skills they need to compete in the digital economy. I urge my colleagues to support the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400165" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today on <bill type="h" number="694">H.R. 694</bill>, the Minority Serving Institution Digital and Wireless Technology Opportunity Act of 2007, and I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation has been an initiative of my colleague, Mr. Forbes, for several years and I congratulate him and Representative Towns and my colleague, Representative Johnson, on getting the legislation brought to the floor for a vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill requires the Secretary to establish a program to provide grants to increase the use of digital and wireless networking technology for institutions of higher education that primarily serve minorities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Having been on the board of a minority institution in Texas for many years, I like the intent of the legislation and I want to say a few words about it. The grants may be used for training, education and professional development programs to increase the use of digital and wireless technology or to obtain capacity-building technical assistance and distance learning services.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Additionally, the grants may be used to foster the use of digital and wireless networking technology to improve research and education, including scientific mathematics, engineering and technology instruction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="694">H.R. 694</bill> will help to provide grants to promote crucial development and educational programs for minority-serving institutions. It will help to ensure that minority students will not fall behind in education on critical digital and wireless networking technology. It will also help to ensure access to the technology and the training programs on the use of these technologies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While I am a longtime supporter of grants to improve education and training on digital and wireless networking technology, and I commend my colleagues on this very important initiative, I would be a little bit remiss if I didn't raise some concerns about the process of bringing this bill up and the price tag associated with it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill was referred to the Committee on Science and Technology in February of this year and received an additional referral to the Committee on Education and Labor in June of this year; yet neither of these committees has had a chance to really review the legislation and to hold hearings and to go through the markup process. I am a strong believer in proper order and the  important role that committees of jurisdiction play to make improvements to legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to my concerns about the process, I am concerned about the authorization levels in the bill and the fact that it does not contain any opportunities for grants for rural colleges and universities which experience similar equipment shortages and could benefit from the use of distance learning.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill authorizes $250 million for fiscal year 2008 and then such sums as may be necessary from 2009 to 2012. There is no CBO score, but I think we can look at the authorization levels and determine that this is a lot of money for a very limited group of institutions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Despite these feelings and despite these problems, and because of my longtime support of these types of programs, I will be supporting the passage of the bill and will vote for it, but I hope my colleagues on the other side of the aisle will address my concerns and the concerns others have as we move forward.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400011" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no further speakers at this time, and I ask the gentleman if he has any other speakers.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400165" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400011" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would just like to conclude by thanking my colleague from Texas. This has truly been a bipartisan bill. I want to sing the praises of Congressman Towns from New York for his steadfast leadership on this and Mr. Forbes' leadership prior to that. I urge a "yes" vote for passage of this fine piece of legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400364" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, today I rise in strong support of the Minority Serving Institution Digital and Wireless Opportunity Act of 2007. This bill authorizes grants to Minority Serving Institutions for technology improvements and infrastructure. Given the large gap in technology between MSI campuses and other American universities, this legislation is critical to improving MSI's educational advancements.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is important to note that MSI's educational contributions are significant. For example, in 2000 at least 40 percent of all African American students who received a baccalaureate degree in physics, chemistry, astronomy, environmental sciences, mathematics and biology graduated from a historically Black college and university. Given their contributions to our society, we must do all we can to make sure that MSIs receive the most modern technology to keep up with other universities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, at the current time, there is a "digital divide" between MSIs and other schools in technology infrastructure and programming. Less than half of the students attending Minority Serving Institutions own computers. Sadly, the majority of historically Black colleges and universities do not provide high speed access to the Internet [according to a Feb. 2004 report by the Alliance for Equity in Higher Education]. We also see this trend in minority communities around the country. Over  60 percent of the U.S. population uses the Internet at home, while only 46 percent of African Americans and 37 percent of Hispanics have Internet access at home [according to a Feb. 2004 report by the Alliance for Equity in Higher Education].</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Minority Serving Institution Digital and Wireless Opportunity Act of 2007 will help eliminate the technological disparities at MSIs by establishing a grant program. These grants will help MSIs purchase equipment, make upgrades and improve their technology infrastructure as well as provide technology education services. In addition, these grants will promote the use of information communications technology to strengthen engineering, math and science research.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to thank Mr. Towns and Mr. Forbes for their efforts to bring this bill before Congress and their commitment to rectify this disparity. I urge my colleagues to support <bill type="h" number="694">H.R. 694</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400011" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Washington (Mr. Baird) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="694">H.R. 694</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this motion will be postponed.</chair>
</record>
