<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1185768000" ordinal="33" title="HONORING 50TH ANNIVERSARY OF STAN HYWET HALL &amp; GARDENS">
  <narrative>HONORING 50TH ANNIVERSARY OF STAN HYWET HALL &amp; GARDENS -- (House of Representatives - July 30, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H8837]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform be discharged from further consideration of the concurrent resolution (<bill type="hc" number="143">H. Con. Res. 143</bill>) honoring the 50th anniversary of Stan Hywet Hall &amp; Gardens, and ask for its immediate consideration in the House.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the concurrent resolution.</narrative>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Illinois?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the concurrent resolution, as follows</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="hc" number="143">H. Con. Res. 143</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas Stan Hywet Hall was built between 1912 and 1915 by Franklin `F.A.' Augustus Seiberling and his wife, Gertrude;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Franklin Seiberling hired architect Charles S. Schneider of Cleveland to design the home, landscape architect Warren H. Manning of Boston to design the grounds, and Hugo F. Huber of New York City to decorate the interior;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Stan Hywet Hall is one of the finest examples of Tudor Revival architecture in the United States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Alcoholics Anonymous, an organization that continues to help millions of individuals worldwide recover from alcohol addiction, was founded on Mother's Day 1935 following a meeting between Mr. Bill Wilson and Dr. Bob Smith and hosted by Henrietta Seiberling at Stan Hywet Hall;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, in 1957, in keeping with the Stan Hywet Hall crest motto of `Non Nobis Solum (Not for Us Alone)', the Seiberling family donated Stan Hywet Hall to a nonprofit organization, which came to be known as Stan Hywet Hall &amp; Gardens, so that the public could enjoy and experience part of a noteworthy chapter in the history of the United States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Stan Hywet Hall &amp; Gardens is identified as a National Historic Landmark by the Department of the Interior, the only location in Akron, Ohio, with such a designation and one of only 2,200 nationwide;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Stan Hywet Hall &amp; Gardens is one of Ohio's top 10 tourist attractions, is a Save America's Treasures project, and is accredited by the American Association of Museums;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas more than 5,000,000 people from around the world have visited Stan Hywet Hall &amp; Gardens, with the number of visitors annually averaging between 150,000 and 200,000 since 1999;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Stan Hywet Hall &amp; Gardens contributes over $12,000,000 annually to the greater Akron economy;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Stan Hywet Hall &amp; Gardens is a recipient of the Trustee Emeritus Award for Excellence in the Stewardship of Historic Sites from the National Trust for Historic Preservation, only the fourth recipient of the Award after George Washington's Mount Vernon, Thomas Jefferson's Monticello, and Washington, DC's Octagon House; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Stan Hywet Hall &amp; Gardens relies on more than 1,300 volunteers to ensure that its doors remain open to the public, including the Women's Auxiliary Board, the Friends of Stan Hywet, the Stan Hywet Gilde, the Stan Hywet Needlework Guild, the Stan Hywet Flower Arrangers, the Stan Hywet Garden Committee, the Carriage House Gift Shop, the Conservatory, Vintage Base Ball, Vintage Explorers, the Akron Garden Club, and the Garden Forum of Greater Akron: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved by the House of Representatives (the Senate concurring), &lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; That Congress--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) congratulates Stan Hywet Hall &amp; Gardens on its 50th anniversary;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) honors Stan Hywet Hall &amp; Gardens for its commitment to sharing its history, gardens, and art collections with the public; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) directs the Secretary of the Senate to transmit a copy of this resolution to Stan Hywet Hall &amp; Gardens.</narrative>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>Amendment offered by Mr. Davis of Illinois</narrative>
  <narrative>Strike all after the resolving clause and insert the following:</narrative>
  <narrative>That Congress--</narrative>
  <narrative>(1) recognizes that National Historic Landmarks are places where significant historical events occurred or where prominent Americans worked or lived; and</narrative>
  <narrative>(2) directs the Secretary of the Senate to transmit a copy of this resolution to the Stan Hywet Hall &amp; Gardens in Akron, Ohio.</narrative>
  <narrative>The concurrent resolution, as amended, was agreed to.</narrative>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>Amendment to the preamble offered by Mr. Davis of Illinois</narrative>
  <narrative> Strike the preamble and insert the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas National Historic Landmarks are nationally significant historic places, designated by the Secretary of the Interior because they possess exceptional value or quality in illustrating or interpreting the heritage of the United States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Congress recognizes that Stan Hywet Hall, located in Akron, Summit County, Ohio, has been designated as a National Historic Landmark since December 21, 1981;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Stan Hywet Hall was built between 1912 and 1915 by Franklin "F.A." Augustus Seiberling and his wife, Gertrude;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Franklin Seiberling hired architect Charles S. Schneider of Cleveland to design the home, landscape architect Warren H. Manning of Boston to design the grounds, and Hugo F. Huber of New York City to decorate the interior;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Stan Hywet Hall is one of the finest examples of Tudor Revival architecture in the United States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Alcoholics Anonymous, an organization that continues to help millions of individuals worldwide recover from alcohol addiction, was founded on Mother's Day 1935 following a meeting between Mr. Bill Wilson and Dr. Bob Smith which was hosted by Henrietta Seiberling at Stan Hywet Hall;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas in 1957, in keeping with the Stan Hywet Hall crest motto of "Non Nobis Solum" (or "Not for Us Alone"), the Seiberling family donated Stan Hywet Hall to a nonprofit organization, which came to be known as Stan Hywet Hall &amp; Gardens, so that the public could enjoy and experience part of a noteworthy chapter in the history of the United States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas we are honoring and congratulating Stan Hywet Hall &amp; Gardens on its 50th anniversary and for its commitment to sharing its history, gardens, and art collections with the public; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Stan Hywet Hall &amp; Gardens is identified as a National Historic Landmark by the Department of the Interior, the only location in Akron, Ohio, with such a designation and one of only 2,200 nationwide;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Stan Hywet Hall &amp; Gardens is one of Ohio's top 10 tourist attractions, is a Save America's Treasures project, and is accredited by the American Association of Museums;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas more than 5,000,000 people from around the world have visited Stan Hywet Hall &amp; Gardens, with the number of visitors annually averaging between 150,000 and 200,000 since 1999; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Stan Hywet Hall &amp; Gardens contributes over $12,000,000 annually to the greater Akron economy;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Stan Hywet Hall &amp; Gardens is a recipient of the Trustee Emeritus Award for Excellence in the Stewardship of Historic Sites from the National Trust for Historic Preservation, only the fourth recipient of the Award after George Washington's Mount Vernon, Thomas Jefferson's Monticello, and Washington, DC's Octagon House; and</narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas Stan Hywet Hall &amp; Gardens relies on more than 1,300 volunteers to ensure that its doors remain open to the public, including the Women's Auxiliary Board, the Friends of Stan Hywet, the Stan Hywet Gilde, the Stan Hywet Needlework Guild, the Stan Hywet Flower Arrangers, the Stan Hywet Garden Committee, the Carriage House Gift Shop, the Conservatory, Vintage Base Ball, Vintage Explorers, the Akron Garden Club, and the Garden Forum of Greater Akron: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, National Historic Landmarks are significant places designated by the Secretary of the Interior because they possess exceptional value or quality in illustrating the heritage of the United States. The U.S. Congress recognizes that Stan Hywet Hall, located in Akron, Ohio as a National Historic Landmark since December 21, 1981. Stan Hywet Hall was built between 1912 and 1915 by Franklin "F.A." Augustus Seiberling and his wife, Gertrude. This landmark is one  of the finest examples of Tudor Revival architecture in the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are honoring Stan Hywet Hall and Gardens on its 50th anniversary and for its commitment to sharing its history, gardens, and art collections with the public.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I commend my colleague Representative Betty Sutton for seeking to honor the 50th anniversary of Stan Hywet Hall and Gardens and urge the swift passage of this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the amendment to the preamble is considered as read.</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <chair>The amendment to the preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The title was amended so as to read: "Concurrent resolution honoring National Historic Landmarks.".</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
