<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1168016404" ordinal="28" title="STATUS REPORT ON CURRENT SPENDING LEVELS OF ON-BUDGET SPENDING AND REVENUES FOR FY 2007 AND THE 5-YEAR PERIOD FY 2007 THROUGH FY 2011">
  <chair> Under a previous order of the House, the gentleman from South Carolina (Mr. Spratt) is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am transmitting a status report on the current levels of on-budget spending and revenues for fiscal year 2007 and for the five-year period of fiscal years 2007 through 2011. This report is necessary to facilitate the application of sections 302 and 311 of the Congressional Budget Act and sections 401 and 501 of <bill type="hc" number="376">H. Con. Res. 376</bill>, which is currently in effect as a concurrent resolution on the budget in the House under <bill type="hr" number="6">H. Res. 6</bill>. This status report is current through January 1, 2007. An additional  report will be filed to reflect any changes in committee jurisdictions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The term "current level" refers to the amounts of spending and revenues estimated for each fiscal year based on laws enacted or awaiting the President's signature.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The first table in the report compares the current levels of total budget authority, outlays, and revenues with the aggregate levels set by <bill type="hc" number="376">H. Con. Res. 376</bill>. This comparison is needed to enforce section 311(a) of the Budget Act, which creates a point of order against measures that would breach the budget resolution's aggregate levels. The table does not show budget authority and outlays for years after fiscal year 2007 because appropriations for those years have not yet been considered.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The second table compares the current levels of budget authority and outlays for discretionary action by each authorizing committee with the "section 302(a)" allocations made under <bill type="hc" number="376">H. Con. Res. 376</bill> for fiscal year 2007 and fiscal years 2007 through 2011. "Discretionary action" refers to legislation enacted after the adoption of the budget resolution. This comparison is needed to enforce section 302(f) of the Budget Act, which creates a point of order against measures that would breach the  section 302(a) discretionary action allocation of new budget authority for the committee that reported the measure. It is also needed to implement section 311(b), which exempts committees that comply with their allocations from the point of order under section 311(a).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The third table compares the current levels of discretionary appropriations for fiscal year 2007 with the "section 302(b)" suballocations of discretionary budget authority and outlays among Appropriations subcommittees. The comparison is also needed to enforce section 302(f) of the Budget Act because the point of order under that section equally applies to measures that would breach the applicable section 302(b) suballocation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The fourth table gives the current level for 2008 of accounts identified for advance appropriations under section 401 of <bill type="hc" number="376">H. Con. Res. 376</bill>. This list is needed to enforce section 401 of the budget resolution, which creates a point of order against appropriation bills that contain advance appropriations that are: (i) not identified in the statement of managers or (ii) would cause the aggregate amount of such appropriations to exceed the level specified in the resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The fifth table provides the current level of the nondefense reserve fund for emergencies established by section 501 of <bill type="hc" number="376">H. Con. Res. 376</bill>. The table is required by section 505 of the budget resolution, and is needed to determine whether an increase in the reserve fund, allocations and aggregates will be necessary for any pending legislation that contains emergency-designated discretionary budget authority.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enactment of measures providing new budget authority for FY 2007 in excess of $17,027,000,000 (if not already included in the current level estimate) would cause FY 2007 budget authority to exceed the appropriate level set by <bill type="hc" number="376">H. Con. Res. 376</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enactment of measures providing new outlays for FY 2007 in excess of $52,438,000,000 (if not already included in the current level estimate) would cause FY 2007 outlays to exceed the appropriate level set by <bill type="hc" number="376">H. Con. Res. 376</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enactment of measures that would reduce revenue for FY 2007 (if not already included in the current estimate) would cause revenues to fall further below the appropriate level set by <bill type="hc" number="376">H. Con. Res. 376</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enactment of measures resulting in revenue reduction for the period of fiscal years 2007 through 2011 in excess of $106,160,000,000 (if not already included in the current level estimate) would cause revenues to fall below the appropriate levels set by <bill type="hc" number="376">H. Con. Res. 376</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Appropriate Level &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;23,565&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Current Level &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;0&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Elk Hills &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;0&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Corporation for Public Broadcasting &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;0&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Employment and Training Administration &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;0&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Education for the Disadvantaged &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;0&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;School Improvement &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;0&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Children and Family Services (Head Start) &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;0&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Special Education &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;0&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Vocational and Adult Education &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Transportation (highways, transit, Farley Building) &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;0&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Payment to Postal Service&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;0 &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Section 8 Renewals&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;0 &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Total&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;0</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Current Level over (+)/under (-) Appropriate Level</paragraph>
    <paragraph>-23,565 &lt;p&gt;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Appropriate Level&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;6,450 &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Current Level &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;0&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Current Level over (+)/under (-) Appropriate Level</paragraph>
    <paragraph>-6,450</paragraph>
    <paragraph>U.S. CONGRESS,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>CONGRESSIONAL BUDGET OFFICE,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington, DC, January 4, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR CONGRESSMAN: The enclosed report shows the effects of Congressional action on the fiscal year 2007 budget and is current through January 1, 2007. This report is submitted under section 308(b) and in aid of section 311 of the Congressional Budget Act, as amended.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The estimates of budget authority, outlays, and revenues are consistent with the technical and economic assumptions of <bill type="hc" number="376">H. Con. Res. 376</bill>, the Concurrent Resolution on the Budget for Fiscal Year 2007, as approved by the House of Representatives. Although the House and the Senate have not reached agreement on a concurrent budget resolution for 2007, pursuant to House Resolution 818, <bill type="hc" number="376">H. Con. Res. 376</bill> has the force and effect in the House for all purposes of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 as  though adopted by the Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Pursuant to section 402 of <bill type="hc" number="95">H. Con. Res. 95</bill>, the Concurrent Resolution on the Budget for Fiscal Year 2006, and section 402 of <bill type="hc" number="376">H. Con. Res. 376</bill>, the Concurrent Resolution on the Budget for Fiscal Year 2007, provisions designated as emergency requirements are exempt from enforcement of the budget resolution. As a result, the enclosed current level report excludes certain amounts that affect 2007 spending (see footnote 2 of the report).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since my last letter, dated November 15, the Congress has cleared and the President has signed the following acts that affect budget authority, outlays, or revenues for fiscal year 2007:  an act making further continuing appropriations for the fiscal year 2007 (Public Law 109-383);</paragraph>
    <paragraph>an act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to revise certain repayment contracts (Public Law 109-386);  the Tax Relief and Health Care Act of 2006 (Public Law 109-432);</paragraph>
    <paragraph>the Postal Accountability and Enhancement Act (Public Law 109-435);  the Blunt Reservoir and Pierre Canal Land Conveyance Act of 2006 (Public Law 109-458);</paragraph>
    <paragraph>the Veterans Benefits, Health Care, and Information Technology Act of 2006 (Public Law 109-461); and  the Social Security Trust Funds Restoration Act of 2006 (Public Law 109-465).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, the Congress has cleared for the President's signature the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Reauthorization Act of 2006 (<bill type="h" number="5946">H.R. 5946</bill>) and the National Institutes of Health Reform Act of 2006 (<bill type="h" number="6164">H.R. 6164</bill>).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Donald B. Marron,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enclosure.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
