<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1175097624" ordinal="39" title="OLDER AMERICANS REAUTHORIZATION TECHNICAL CORRECTIONS ACT">
  <speaking speaker="412209" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent to take from the Speaker's table the Senate bill (<bill type="s" number="1002">S. 1002</bill>) to amend the Older Americans Act of 1965 to reinstate certain provisions relating to the nutrition services incentive program, and ask for its immediate consideration in the House.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the Senate bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Iowa?</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the Senate bill, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412209" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this bill makes technical corrections to the Older Americans Reauthorization Act of 2006. The bill would restore language regarding the administration of the Nutrition Services Incentive Program that existed prior to the Older Americans Act Reauthorization of 2006.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Prior to the reauthorization, this nutrition program provided cash or USDA commodities to states to supplement meals for the elderly. Six states chose to receive USDA commodities through the program--Massachusetts, Kansas, Connecticut, Oklahoma, Nevada, and Delaware. However, while attempting to relieve administrative burdens for USDA during the last reauthorization, Congress inadvertently denied states the ability to directly purchase essential USDA commodities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This was not the intent of Congress. The states that receive USDA commodities run tremendous programs that help provide nutritious meals to seniors. Many states reported that they were able to double the value of their appropriated funds by purchasing USDA commodities and Massachusetts reported that because of this program they were able to avoid waiting lists for meals for 17 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I've heard from my fellow Iowans on the importance of this program as well. Iowa has participated in this program and recognizes its benefits. We never received much money for commodities--only about $155,000--but the money goes a long way. Our Area Agencies on Aging often have a hard time meeting their budgets, but USDA commodities allowed them to serve more meals at a higher quality. Iowa fully intends to take advantage of USDA commodities again once we pass this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill hasn't strayed from Congress' original intent either. The bill reduces the administrative burden on USDA, and streamlines the transfer of funds between the Department of Health and Human Services, to which funds are appropriated, and the Department of Agriculture, which purchases commodities for the states.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We must pass this bill today so that states wishing to take some or all of their NSIP allotment in commodities may place their order with the Department of Agriculture for FY 2008 by April 7th.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It's time to fix the mistakes that were made and allow these state to continue to serve seniors the most effective way possible.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senate bill was read a third time and passed, and a motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
