<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1201539602" ordinal="17" title="RICHARD B. ANDERSON FEDERAL BUILDING">
  <narrative>RICHARD B. ANDERSON FEDERAL BUILDING -- (House of Representatives - January 28, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H463]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400204" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="4140">H.R. 4140</bill>) to designate the Port Angeles Federal Building in Port Angeles, Washington, as the "Richard B. Anderson Federal Building".</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="4140">H.R. 4140</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. RICHARD B. ANDERSON FEDERAL BUILDING.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Designation.--The Federal building located at 138 West First Street, Port Angeles, Washington, shall be known and designated as the "Richard B. Anderson Federal Building".</narrative>
  <narrative> (b) References.--Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the Federal building referred to in subsection (a) shall be deemed to be a reference to the "Richard B. Anderson Federal Building".&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from Texas (Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson) and the gentleman from Wisconsin (Mr. Petri) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentlewoman from Texas.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400204" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days within which to revise and extend their remarks and to include extraneous materials on <bill type="h" number="4140">H.R. 4140</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from Texas?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400204" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, <bill type="h" number="4140">H.R. 4140</bill> is a bill to designate the Federal building located at 138 West First Street, Port Angeles, Washington, as the Richard B. Anderson Federal Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Private First Class Richard Anderson was born in 1921 in Tacoma, Washington. He joined the Marine Corps on July 6, 1942, and received his Marine Corps training in San Diego, California.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He died at the young age of 22 during World War II and on Roi Island, part of the Marshall Islands in the Pacific. He was awarded the Purple Heart and the Medal of Honor. His heroism is marked by his actions on Roi Island when he hurled himself on a live grenade in a shell hole to save the lives of many people. He was severely injured and died of his injuries on February 1, 1944. He was buried at sea with full military honors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1945, the U.S. Navy destroyer USS Richard B. Anderson was named in honor of Medal of Honor recipient Anderson.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is both fitting and proper to honor the life and courageous actions of Richard B. Anderson in this designation. I support this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of our time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400318" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill before us designates what is a Federal building in Port Angeles, Washington, as the Richard B. Anderson Federal Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Richard Beatty Anderson served in the United States Marines during World War II in the Marshall Islands. He sacrificed his life to save three other marines by throwing his body on a live grenade and taking the full impact of the explosion. Private First Class Anderson was evacuated to a ship where he died of his wounds on February 1, 1944.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>His heroism and loyalty in the face of certain death earned him the Medal of Honor. The United States Navy destroyer USS Richard B. Anderson was  named in his honor in 1945 and went on to serve in both the Korean and Vietnam Wars, earning 15 battle stars.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill is a fitting tribute to Private First Class Anderson's sacrifice and service to his country. I support this measure and urge my colleagues to do the same.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400109" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="4140">H.R. 4140</bill>, a bill to designate the Port Angeles Federal Building in Port Angeles, Washington, as the "Richard B. Anderson Federal Building."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Private First Class Richard B. Anderson was born in Tacoma, Washington on June 26, 1921 and graduated from Sequim High School in Sequim, Washington. Private Anderson entered the Marine Corps in 1942 and eventually joined his last unit, Company E, 2nd Battalion, 23rd Marines in San Diego, California. He departed for Roi-Namur, an island in the northern part of the Kwajalein atoll in the Marshall Islands, with his unit in January 1944.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While hunting enemy snipers on Roi-Namur, PFC Anderson, a member of the invasion force, hurled himself on a live grenade in a shell hole to save the lives of three Marines. Anderson was evacuated to a ship, where he died of his wounds on February 1, 1944. For his heroic actions, PFC Anderson was posthumously awarded the Congressional Medal of Honor and the Purple Heart.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the House is now considering legislation that will honor PFC Anderson for his heroic efforts on Roi Island. Specifically, this legislation would rename the Federal Building in Port Angeles, Washington after Richard B. Anderson. I urge the House to adopt this important legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, <bill type="h" number="4140">H.R. 4140</bill> designates the Port Angeles Federal Building located at 138 West First Street, Port Angeles, Washington, as the "Richard B. Anderson Federal Building."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Private First Class, PFC, Richard B. Anderson was born on June 26, 1921, in Tacoma, Washington. Anderson grew up in Port Angeles, Washington, and attended Sequim High School.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On July 6, 1942, Anderson joined the United States Marine Corps. He received his basic and infantry training at the Marine Corps Recruit Depot in San Diego, California, and was promoted to the rank of Private First Class on April 12, 1943.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Following his promotion, PFC Anderson was assigned to the East Company, 2nd Battalion, of the 23rd Marines. PFC Anderson's unit was deployed to the Marshall Islands in January 1944. On February 1, 1944, his company was part of an invasion force fighting to take control of Rio Island from the Japanese.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>During the assault, Anderson and three other Marines jumped into a shell crater to escape enemy flre. As Anderson prepared to throw a grenade from inside the crater, the grenade slipped from his hands and began to roll toward the other three marines in the crater. In an act of selfless heroism, Anderson lunged on top of the live grenade and absorbed the full impact of the blast, saving the lives of his fellow soldiers. Anderson died from his wounds shortly thereafter.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After his death, PFC Anderson was awarded the Purple Heart and the Medal of Honor for his acts of bravery and service to his country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On October 26, 1945, the United States Navy commissioned a DD-786 destroyer battleship as the USS Richard B. Anderson in honor of the fallen hero. The ship began active service in January 1947, and was used in combat for the Vietnam and Korean wars. The ship remained in active service until December 20, 1975.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I strongly urge my colleagues to join me in supporting <bill type="h" number="4140">H.R. 4140</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400318" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no further speakers, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400204" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no requests for time, and I yield back my time and urge passage.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from Texas (Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="4140">H.R. 4140</bill>.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400204" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this motion will be postponed.</chair>
</record>
