<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1185768000" ordinal="21" title="RECOGNIZING VIRGINIA'S JAMES RIVER AS &quot;AMERICA'S FOUNDING RIVER&quot;">
  <narrative>RECOGNIZING VIRGINIA'S JAMES RIVER AS "AMERICA'S FOUNDING RIVER" -- (House of Representatives - July 30, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H8830]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Natural Resources be discharged from further consideration of the resolution (<bill type="hr" number="16">H. Res. 16</bill>) recognizing Virginia's James River as "America's Founding River," and ask for its immediate consideration in the House.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the resolution.</narrative>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from the Virgin Islands?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the resolution, as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="hr" number="16">H. Res. 16</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas Virginia's James River is considered a great natural asset of the United States for its historical, environmental, and economic significance;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the first permanent English settlement in America was founded on the banks of the James River at Jamestown, Virginia, in 1607;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, prior to European settlement, the James River was known as Powhatan River, a name associated with Chief Powhatan, who was a key figure in the relationship between the Native American tribes and the Jamestown settlement;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, for thousands of years, the James River provided a source of nourishment and enrichment to the Native American tribes that lived along its course;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the James River played a critical role in the founding of America by sustaining the early settlers with its bounty, providing valuable commodities to build the emerging economy of a new colony, and serving as a strategic transportation corridor that shaped the settlement and commerce of the region;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the James River is one of America's most historic rivers with over 1,100 historic landmarks within its watershed;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the James River watershed is home to the first colonial capital in America and to numerous founding fathers and presidents, including Thomas Jefferson, Patrick Henry, James Monroe, James Madison, William Henry Harrison, and John Tyler;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the James River's natural resources, scenic beauty, and recreational opportunities continue to enhance the quality of life of visitors and the people living along it;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Congress passed the Chesapeake Bay Restoration Act of 2000, committing the Federal Government to achieve improved water quality and improvements in the productivity of living resources in the James River, as a tributary to the Chesapeake Bay;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the year 2007 marks the 400th anniversary of the founding of Jamestown; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, throughout 2006 and 2007, many events are planned as part of America's 400th Anniversary, which is an 18-month commemoration of the historic events that occurred on and around the James River in 1607 and the enduring world-wide significance of those historic events: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, &lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; That the House of Representatives--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) recognizes Virginia's James River as "America's Founding River";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) recognizes the extraordinary historic, economic, recreational, and environmental importance of the James River;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) encourages the people of the United States to observe and celebrate the James River's contribution to our Nation's history with appropriate ceremonies and activities during America's 400th Anniversary; and</narrative>
  <narrative> (4) recommits itself to protecting and restoring the James River for the enjoyment and prosperity of current and future generations.&lt;ul&gt;</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, <bill type="hr" number="16">H. Res. 16</bill> would grant the recognition of the House to Virginia's James River as "America's Founding River."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The resolution was introduced by our colleague, Representative Jo Ann Davis of Virginia.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The James River rises in the Allegheny Mountains and flows to the Chesapeake Bay. It is one of the longest rivers in our country to lie in a single state.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, Native Americans gave the name of their great chief Powhatan to the river that nourished the tribes along its banks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1607, when English colonists established their first permanent settlement in America, they named the river--and their new town--after King James the First.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The James River sustained those early settlers, supported the growth of the first colonial capital in American, and provided a route for the first westwardbound pioneers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The land along the James was home to many of our founding fathers and presidents, and great mansions still grace its shores.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, <bill type="hr" number="16">H. Res. 16</bill> would grant the recognition of the House to the historic, economic, recreational and environmental importance of the James River and encourages the people of the U.S. to celebrate the contributions of the river to our Nation's history as part of the ceremonies and activities during Jamestown's 400th anniversary.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The resolution also reminds us of our commitment in 2000, as part of the Chesapeake Bay Restoration Act, to improving water quality in the bay's tributaries, including the James, and calls on us to recommit ourselves to protecting and restoring that great river.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, we have no objection to <bill type="hr" number="16">H. Res. 16</bill>, and urge its passage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The resolution was agreed to.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
