<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1206979203" ordinal="13" title="NATIONAL FISH AND WILDLIFE FOUNDATION ESTABLISHMENT ACT AMENDMENT OF 2008">
  <narrative>NATIONAL FISH AND WILDLIFE FOUNDATION ESTABLISHMENT ACT AMENDMENT OF 2008 -- (House of Representatives - March 31, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H1783]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400001" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="3891">H.R. 3891</bill>) to amend the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation Establishment Act to increase the number of Directors on the Board of Directors of the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="3891">H.R. 3891</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "National Fish and Wildlife Foundation Establishment Act Amendment of 2008".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. BOARD OF DIRECTORS OF THE FOUNDATION.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Section 3(a) of the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation Establishment Act (16 U.S.C. 3702(a)) is amended by striking paragraph (1) and inserting the following:</narrative>
  <narrative> "(1) IN GENERAL.--The Foundation shall have a governing Board of Directors (referred to in this Act as the `Board'), which shall consist of 30 Directors appointed in accordance with subsection (b), each of whom shall be a United States citizen.".&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Hawaii (Mr. Abercrombie) and the gentleman from Utah (Mr. Bishop) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Hawaii.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400001" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Hawaii?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400001" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, <bill type="h" number="3891">H.R. 3891</bill>, introduced by my colleague from South Carolina (Mr. Brown), expands the size of the Board of Directors of the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation from 25 to 30 members.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The National Fish and Wildlife Foundation was established by Congress in 1984 as a charitable nonprofit corporation. The foundation was formed to further the conservation and management of fish, wildlife, plants, and other natural resources by the United States Fish and Wildlife Service and the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While the foundation and its conservation programs continue to grow and fundraising for these programs keeps pace, it is considerably more difficult to meet the increasing administrative expenses of the foundation. Expanding the size of the board of directors will improve the ability of the foundation to raise private funds, to cover its administrative expenses, and to improve the implementation of its conservation programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I commend Congressman Henry Brown, again, a good friend of many of us here in the Congress and a friend of the Natural Resources, for introducing this bill, and urge all Members to support it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400029" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="3891">H.R. 3891</bill>. It does increase by five members the Board of Directors on the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since its inception, this foundation has financed more than 9,500 conservation projects to sustain, restore, and enhance fish wildlife population and their essential habitat. Under current law, the Secretary of the Interior may  appoint 25 individuals to serve on the Board of Directors. These members have expertise in fish, wildlife, natural resources, and conservation. They serve as conservation ambassadors, and they approve projects submitted to the  foundation, and raise funds for the operation of this successful organization. The additional five members will help to enhance that job description. I urge my colleagues to vote favorably on <bill type="h" number="3891">H.R. 3891</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400001" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, before yielding back the balance of my time, and I will do so, I have a brief closing insert that I would like to read from Congresswoman Bordallo who, as I indicated, finds it impossible to be here today at this time. She says as follows:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, as Chairwoman on the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, I reiterate that the Natural Resources Committee supports this bill as a means to maximize community participation in the activities of the Fish and Wildlife Foundation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is our expectation, that is to say Congresswoman Bordallo's expectation, that the foundation will view this expansion of its Board of Directors as an opportunity to increase the diversity of professional backgrounds and views that board members bring to the foundation, and also that the Secretary of the Interior will appoint qualified individuals, hopefully with conservation experience in the offshore territories.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400049" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I rise today to speak on <bill type="h" number="3891">H.R. 3891</bill>, a bill I introduced with Fisheries, Oceans and Wildlife Subcommittee Chairwoman Madeleine Bordallo. The fundamental purpose of this legislation is to increase from 25 to 30 the number of members who may serve on the Board of Directors of the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The National Fish and Wildlife Foundation was created by Congress in 1984. Since that time, it has financed more than 9,500 conservation projects throughout the United States and in other countries. By using a partnership and challenge grant approach, the Foundation has provided $1.3 billion in critical funding to accomplish its strategic goals of sustaining, restoring and enhancing fish, wildlife and plant populations and their essential habitat.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under current law, the Secretary of the Interior may appoint up to 25 individuals to serve on the Foundation's Board of Directors. The members of this Board have expertise in fish, wildlife and natural resource conservation; they serve as conservation Ambassadors throughout the world; they review and approve projects submitted to the Foundation and they raise funds for the operation of this highly successful organization.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By increasing the size of the Board, we will greatly enhance the Foundation's ability to finance additional meritorious projects in the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to vote "yea" on <bill type="h" number="3891">H.R. 3891</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400001" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Hawaii (Mr. Abercrombie) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="3891">H.R. 3891</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the bill, as amended, was passed.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
