<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1191945602" ordinal="31" title="EXPRESSING SUPPORT FOR IMPLEMENTATION OF AGREEMENT RELATING TO REUNIFICATION OF CYPRUS">
  <narrative>EXPRESSING SUPPORT FOR IMPLEMENTATION OF AGREEMENT RELATING TO REUNIFICATION OF CYPRUS -- (House of Representatives - October 09, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H11350]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400423" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution (<bill type="hr" number="405">H. Res. 405</bill>) expressing the strong support of the House of Representatives for implementation of the July 8, 2006, United Nations-brokered agreement between President of the Republic of Cyprus Tassos Papadopoulos and Turkish Cypriot leader Mehmet Ali Talat relating to the reunification of Cyprus, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the resolution.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the resolution is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="hr" number="405">H. Res. 405</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas, in recognition that any future efforts for a solution of the Cyprus problem need to be carefully prepared, President of the Republic of Cyprus Tassos Papadopoulos and former United Nations Secretary-General Kofi Annan met on February 28, 2006, in Paris, and reiterated that, "the resumption of the negotiating process within the framework of the Secretary General's Good Offices must be timely and based on careful preparation";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas on July 8, 2006, President Papadopoulos and Turkish Cypriot leader Mehmet Ali Talat, agreed, under the auspices of United Nations Under Secretary-General Ibrahim Gambari, to a set of principles to begin a process of bi-communal discussions;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the set of principles agreed to are--</narrative>
  <narrative>(1) commitment to the unification of Cyprus based on a bi-zonal, bi-communal federation and political equality, as set out in the relevant United Nations Security Council resolutions;</narrative>
  <narrative>(2) recognition of the fact that the status quo is unacceptable and that its prolongation would have negative consequences for the Turkish and Greek Cypriots;</narrative>
  <narrative>(3) commitment to the proposition that a comprehensive settlement is both desirable and possible, and should not be further delayed;</narrative>
  <narrative>(4) agreement to begin a process immediately, involving bi-communal discussion of issues that affect the day-to-day life of the people and concurrently those that concern substantive issues, both of which will contribute to a comprehensive settlement; and</narrative>
  <narrative>(5) commitment to ensure that the "right atmosphere" prevails for this process to be successful; in that connection, confidence-building measures are essential, both in terms of improving the atmosphere and improving the life of all Turkish and Greek Cypriots; and also in that connection, an end must be put to the so-called "blame game";</narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas, according to the agreement, technical committees and working groups would be set up to examine and discuss issues that affect day-to-day life of the people of Cyprus and concurrently those that concern substantive issues, thus contributing to a comprehensive settlement of the Cyprus problem;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas on March 27, 2007, the United Nations Security Council in a statement on Cyprus indicated that, "the members of the Security Council urge both communities to work with the United Nations to implement the 8 July 2006 agreement, in particular through the immediate creation of bi-communal working groups and technical committees in order to prepare the ground for full-fledged negotiations leading to a comprehensive and durable settlement";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the United States has long supported fostering the reunification of Cyprus within a bi-zonal, bi-communal federation, and within a process that is led by the United Nations, thereby consistent with the intended aim of the July 8, 2006, agreement, and as set out in the relevant United Nations Security Council resolutions;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas several meetings have been held between the Greek and Turkish Cypriot members of the coordination committee, consulting on the implementation of the July 8, 2006, agreement, but no technical committees or working groups have been set up;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas on June 15, 2007, the United Nations Security Council adopted Resolution 1758 which "expresses full support for the July 8, 2006 process, notes with concern the lack of progress, and calls upon all parties to immediately engage constructively with the United Nations efforts, as described in Under Secretary General Gambari's letter of 15 November 2006, to demonstrate measurable progress in order to allow fully fledged negotiations to begin"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas on September 5, 2007, President Papadopoulos and Mr. Talat "agreed on the need for the earliest start of the [Gambari] process" and to "continue their contact through the UN and to meet again when appropriate": Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, &lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; That the House of Representatives--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) expresses its support for the immediate implementation of the July 8, 2006, agreement as the way forward to prepare for new comprehensive negotiations leading to the reunification of Cyprus within a bi-zonal, bi-communal federation as set out in the relevant United Nations Security Council resolutions; and</narrative>
  <narrative> (2) calls upon the United States Government to fully support the immediate implementation of the July 8, 2006, agreement in its entirety and without deviation from that process.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from California (Ms. Watson) and the gentleman from Florida (Mr. Bilirakis) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentlewoman from California.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400423" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the resolution under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from California?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400423" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in strong support of this resolution and yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me first thank our colleague from Florida (Mr. Bilirakis) for introducing this important resolution. For years, the United Nations has attempted to reduce the potential for conflict on Cyprus and to heal and reunify that long-divided island.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last year, Under Secretary of the United Nations Ibrahim Gambari potentially made progress towards resolving this issue. Thanks to his efforts, the Greek and Turkish Cypriots signed an agreement on July 8, 2006, that sets out principles forming the basis for a future permanent agreement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, these important principles include, first and foremost, recognition that the status quo, with a divided island, is unacceptable. They also include a commitment to unification based on a bizonal, bicommunal federation; a commitment to form intercommunal working groups aimed at achieving confidence-building measures to improve daily lives on both sides of the island; and a commitment to promote a positive atmosphere that would allow negotiations to thrive.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>All of us hope that the July 8, 2006, agreement between the Greek and the Turkish Cypriot communities will prove to be an important step on the road to reunification of Cyprus as a bizonal, bicommunal federation. The pace of the progress must accelerate. To date, it has been, at best, halting. But both parties have at least renewed their pledge to work towards a negotiated agreement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, U.N. Security Council Resolution 1758 expresses full support for the July 8, 2006, agreement. I hope the Members of this body will reinforce that message by backing this bill, and thereby backing the unification of Cyprus. The resolution before us, <bill type="hr" number="405">H. Res. 405</bill>, expresses its support for the immediate implementation of the July 8, 2006, agreement, and it calls on the administration to support it as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the people of Cyprus deserve our encouragement and our support in their efforts to prepare for new talks aimed at reunification, and that is exactly what this resolution seeks to do. I strongly support it, and I encourage my colleagues to do likewise.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412250" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would like to thank the gentlewoman from California for her strong support of <bill type="hr" number="405">H. Res. 405</bill>. I rise today to urge my colleagues to support <bill type="hr" number="405">H. Res. 405</bill>, which expresses the strong support of the U.S. House of Representatives for the immediate implementation of the July 8, 2006, United Nations-brokered agreement between President Papadopoulos of Cyprus and the Turkish Cypriot community leader, Mr. Mehmet Ali Talat.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>More than 33 years after the invasion and occupation of Cyprus by Turkish troops, the country remains divided and has the longest running peacekeeping force in the history of the United Nations. It is important that there is forward movement on properly preparing the grounds for serious negotiations that will lead to sustainable and lasting peace.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The international community has helped shepherd an agreement on a process, the Gambari process, that points the way forward to comprehensive negotiations that will lead to the reunification of the island, its people, institutions and economy in a bi-zonal, bi-communal federation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The United Nations Security Council, the European Union, and the United States have all played key roles in trying to bring a lasting and fair resolution to the division of the island.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On July 8, 2006, President Papadopoulos and Mr. Talat agreed, under the auspices of the United Nations, to the establishment of technical committees and working groups to examine the issues affecting the daily lives of the Greek and Turkish Cypriot people, as well as issues of substance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="hr" number="405">H. Res. 405</bill> recognizes the fact that the status quo is unacceptable and that its prolongation would have negative consequences for the Turkish and Greek Cypriots. It also reinforces the proposition that a comprehensive settlement is both desirable and possible and should not be further delayed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In an effort to jump-start the July 8 agreement, President Papadopoulos invited Mr. Talat to a meeting that took place this year on September 5. The two leaders agreed on the need for the earliest start of the Gambari process and to continue their contact through the U.N. and to meet again when appropriate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a member of the European Union, the Republic of Cyprus has proven itself a committed and influential partner in Europe. Despite its forced division, Cyprus's successful social and economic integration into the European Union is a testament to its focus and dedication to democratic values and regional cooperation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, Cyprus has a long history of working cooperatively with the United States on issues of international defense and security and continues to do so in the global war on terror. Cyprus is also a good friend to this country. In the summer of 2006, Cyprus served as the principal transit for 15,000 Americans evacuating Lebanon. Our citizens were provided with food, shelter, and medical care.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is now time for Congress to demonstrate its strong support of efforts toward the reunification of Cyprus by passing <bill type="hr" number="405">H. Res. 405</bill>, calling for the immediate implementation of the July 8 agreement in its entirety and without deviation from the process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="hr" number="405">H. Res. 405</bill> gives a strong message of support for a reunified Cyprus under a bi-zonal, bi-communal federation with a single sovereignty, single international personality, and single citizenship with respect to human rights and fundamental freedoms of all Cypriots.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I wish to thank Chairman Lantos and Ranking Member Ros-Lehtinen and all of my colleagues who have cosponsored <bill type="hr" number="405">H. Res. 405</bill>. I thank them for recognizing what a significant step this great representative body is taking by telling the world community that the sad and tragic division of Cyprus should be no longer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400423" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 2 minutes to the gentlewoman from Nevada (Ms. Berkley), member of the Veterans' Affairs Committee and Ways and Means Committee.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400024" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentlewoman from California.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of this resolution of which I am a proud cosponsor. In the summer of 2006, we witnessed a major breakthrough in the troubled history of this divided island. After years of conflict, both sides committed themselves to the reunification of Cyprus based on a bi-zonal, bi-communal federation and political equality. By agreeing to these principles, they recognize the status quo is unacceptable and that continuing it only hurts both the Turkish and Greek Cypriot communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In connection with this agreement, we are all pleased to see the Cypriot Government take a number of confidence-building measures, demolishing walls and even providing free health care to Turkish Cypriots.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This summer, my family and I traveled to Cyprus and had the pleasure of enjoying the legendary Cypriot hospitality. While I enjoyed the beauty and serenity of the island, I was most struck by the openness and warmth of the people there, who treated my family and me with the greatest regard. It is cruel that such a warm and hospitable people should continue to be subjected to this conflict.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We were simply appalled by the state of the "green line" area. It is a blot on an otherwise breathtaking country. It is time that the Turkish troops remove themselves from this island so that, at our next visit, Cyprus will once again be a peaceful and unified island free of occupation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, it is time for both sides to come together to execute the July 2006 agreement. The principles have been laid out and all that we need now is implementation. I urge support for this resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412186" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, today I rise in support of <bill type="hr" number="405">H. Res. 405</bill>, which expresses strong support for the implementation of the July 8, 2006 agreement between the President of the Republic of Cyprus and the Turkish Cypriot  leader. Since the invasion of Cyprus over 30 years ago, the Greek and Turkish Cypriot communities have been divided. There have been over 13 million crossings by Greek and Turkish Cypriots into each other's communities without incident.  The reunification of Cyprus would improve relations between the communities, commerce, and the everyday lives of Cypriots on the island. It is in the best interest of the Cypriot people, the United States and our allies, Greece and Turkey, to urge the immediate implementation</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412250" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400423" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no further requests for time, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from California (Ms. Watson) that the House suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, <bill type="hr" number="405">H. Res. 405</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the resolution, as amended, was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
