<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1209657603" ordinal="5" title="INTRODUCTION OF REV. GARY STRICKLAND">
  <narrative>INTRODUCTION OF REV. GARY STRICKLAND -- (House of Representatives - May 01, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H2951]</narrative>
  <narrative>(Mr. McINTYRE asked and was given permission to address the House for 1 minute.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400266" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I'm pleased today to introduce the Reverend Gary Strickland who just delivered the invocation for the U.S. House as we, as a Nation, begin this National Day of Prayer, a time when communities across America will be joining in prayer for our country today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And what better person to begin this day than a man whose ministry has carried him across North Carolina, touching people from all walks of life, from the booming coastal city of Wilmington to rural communities like Pikeville, Wilson, and Little Washington, North Carolina, to the All-American cities of Fayetteville and Lumberton.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The former Christian Education Director for the North Carolina Conference of the International Pentecostal Holiness Church, Gary now pastors a vibrant, nondenominational, multicultural church named Kingdom Place that is growing exponentially and has a wide-ranging ministry that shares God's love and the redeeming power of Jesus Christ.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Born and reared in Southeastern North Carolina, he is married to my sister, Karon McIntyre Strickland, who's with us today, and they have two children, Joel and Amy; two grandsons, Bailey and Bentley; and a son-in-law, Steve.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Gary is a graduate of the University of North Carolina at Pembroke where he served as student body president. He received his master's in religious education at Duke and his master's of divinity from Southeastern Baptist Theological Seminary.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As my brother-in-law, I'm particularly honored to have had him open us today on the National Day of Prayer.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
