<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1207756802" ordinal="45" title="PERSONAL EXPLANATION">
  <narrative>PERSONAL EXPLANATION -- (House of Representatives - April 09, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H2122]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400233" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I regret that I was not present to vote on rollcall votes 164, 165, 166, 167, 168, 169, 170, 171, 172, 173, 174, 175, 176, and 177 due to a family medical matter. Had I been present, I would have voted:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>"Yea" on rollcall vote No. 164 on ordering the previous question on <bill type="hr" number="1084">H. Res. 1084</bill>, Providing for consideration of the bill <bill type="h" number="2016">H.R. 2016</bill>, to establish the National Landscape Conservation System, and for other purposes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>"Yea" on rollcall vote No. 165 on <bill type="hr" number="1084">H. Res. 1084</bill>, Providing for consideration of the bill <bill type="h" number="2016">H.R. 2016</bill>, to establish the National Landscape Conservation System, and for other purposes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>"Yea" on rollcall vote No. 166 on <bill type="hr" number="1077">H. Res. 1077</bill>, calling on the Government of the People's Republic of China to end its crackdown in Tibet and to enter into a substantive dialogue with His Holiness the Dalai Lama to find a negotiated solution that respects the distinctive language, culture, religious identity, and fundamental freedom of all Tibetans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>"Yea" on rollcall vote No. 167 on agreeing to the amendment to <bill type="h" number="2016">H.R. 2016</bill>, to reiterate that nothing in the bill shall impede efforts by the Department of Homeland Security to secure the borders of the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>"No" on rollcall vote No. 168 on agreeing to the amendment to <bill type="h" number="2016">H.R. 2016</bill>, to strike the purposes of the National Landscape Conservation System.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>"No" on rollcall vote No. 169 on agreeing to the amendment to <bill type="h" number="2016">H.R. 2016</bill>, to strike the existing management objectives of the National Landscape Conservation System and inserts language directing the Interior Secretary to manage the system in accordance with each applicable law (including regulations) relating to each component of the system included under subsection (b).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>"No" on rollcall vote No. 170 on agreeing to the amendment to <bill type="h" number="2016">H.R. 2016</bill>, to provide that nothing in the bill additionally restricts or hinders energy development within the National Landscape Conservation System.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>"No" on rollcall vote No. 171 on agreeing to the amendment to <bill type="h" number="2016">H.R. 2016</bill>, to provide that the bill does not in any way limit access for hunting, fishing, trapping or recreational shooting on the 27 million acres administered by the Bureau of Land Management. It also provides that <bill type="h" number="2016">H.R. 2016</bill> does not in any way infringe on a State's right to manage, control or regulate its hunting, fishing, trapping and recreational shooting activities on these lands.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>"No" on rollcall vote No. 172 on agreeing to the amendment to <bill type="h" number="2016">H.R. 2016</bill>, to provide that inclusion in the National Landscape Conservation System does not affect existing grazing rights or operations on those Bureau of Land Management Lands.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>"No" on rollcall vote No. 173 on the motion to recommit <bill type="h" number="2016">H.R. 2016</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>"No" on rollcall vote No. 174 on agreeing to the passage of <bill type="h" number="2016">H.R. 2016</bill>, to establish the National Landscape Conservation System, and for other purposes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>"Yea" on rollcall vote No. 175 on motion to construct the conferees on <bill type="h" number="2419">H.R. 2419</bill>, to provide for the continuation of agricultural programs through fiscal year 2012, and for other purposes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>"Yea" on rollcall vote No. 176 on agreeing to the passage of <bill type="h" number="5489">H.R. 5489</bill>, to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 6892 Main Street in Gloucester, Virginia, as the "Congresswoman Jo Ann S. Davis Post Office" suspension bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>"Yea" on rollcall vote No. 177 on agreeing to the passage of <bill type="h" number="5472">H.R. 5472</bill>, to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 2650 Dr. Martin Luther King Jr. St., Indianapolis, Indiana, as the "Julia M. Carson Post Office Building" suspension bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
