<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1216310404" ordinal="7" title="WELCOMING RABBI STUART BERMAN">
  <narrative>WELCOMING RABBI STUART BERMAN -- (House of Representatives - July 17, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H6677]</narrative>
  <chair> Without objection, the gentleman from New York (Mr. Crowley) is recognized for 1 minute.)</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400087" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, it is indeed a pleasure and an honor for me today to welcome our guest chaplain, Rabbi Stuart Berman, and to thank him for such a wonderful prayer this morning.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>New York, and my community in particular, have been fortunate to have had someone so dedicated presiding in our area. Most recently, Rabbi Berman served at the Woodside Jewish Center. However, he has had a very accomplished and profound career throughout his lifetime.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The rabbi nobly served on the Presidential Inaugural Committee, the Presidential Transition Committee, the White House Conference on Children and Youth Drug Abuse Panel, as well as the White House Conference on Aging.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1985, Rabbi Berman made history in the State of Florida and became the first rabbi to ever be appointed a prison chaplain.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In New York, he again placed the community first and was appointed police-clergy liaison, City of New York Police Department, and Sanitation Department Chaplain. He is also a prolific author of numerous publications and articles, and he previously hosted a weekly television talk show on FAN-TV.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would also point out that Rabbi Berman offered a prayer at the dedication of the post office renaming for my predecessor and his friend, our mutual friend, Congressman Tom Manton, when it was being named in his honor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rabbi Berman is joined today by his son, Nathaniel, and his sister, Zell. Audrey, his wife, who is an early childhood specialist with the New York City Board of Education, unfortunately could not be here with us and with him today. But we all know that she is very, very proud of her rabbi.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thank you, Rabbi, for being here.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
