<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1173200403" ordinal="40" title="COMMENDING AND CONGRATULATING VIRGINIA STATE UNIVERSITY ON ITS 125TH ANNIVERSARY">
  <speaking speaker="400364" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution (<bill type="hr" number="182">H. Res. 182</bill>) commending and congratulating Virginia State University on the occasion of its 125th anniversary, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Virginia (Mr. Scott) and the gentlewoman from North Carolina (Ms. Foxx) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400364" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I request 5 legislative days during which Members may insert material relevant to <bill type="hr" number="182">H. Res. 182</bill> into the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Virginia?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400364" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, <bill type="hr" number="182">H. Res. 182</bill> is a resolution commending and congratulating Virginia State University on the occasion of its 125th anniversary. <bill type="hr" number="182">H. Res. 182</bill> was introduced by my colleague from Virginia from the Fourth Congressional District of Virginia, Mr. Forbes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Virginia State University was founded on March 6, 1882, as the Virginia Normal and Collegiate Institute, making it the first fully State-supported 4-year institution of higher learning for African Americans. Today, it is one of Virginia's two land-grant institutions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The first president of Virginia State University was John Mercer Langston who upon his election to Congress in 1890 was the first African American elected to Congress and, until my election in 1992, had been the only African American elected from Virginia.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1935, Virginia State University founded a 2-year satellite school at Norfolk, Virginia. That school today is known as Norfolk State University.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, Virginia State has an enrollment of nearly 5,000 students who live and learn on a 236-acre main campus overlooking the Appomattox River in Chesterfield County, Virginia. The school also has a 416-acre agricultural research facility.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The University's academic programs include the "Bridges to Baccalaureate" program for students transferring from 2-year colleges who want to major in science, as well as the Honda Campus All-Star Challenge and the Ronald E. McNair Scholars Program for students planning to pursue doctoral degrees.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Virginia State has helped set the standard for minority-serving institutions in Virginia and across the Nation by providing quality higher education opportunities for 125 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My family has a proud Trojan tradition. My mother attended Virginia State, my older brother is a graduate of Virginia State, and I am honored to have an honorary degree from Virginia State.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I congratulate Virginia State University on its 125th anniversary and wish them another successful 125 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400643" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself as much time as I might consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="hr" number="182">H. Res. 182</bill>, a resolution to recognize the contributions of Virginia State University on the occasion of its 125th anniversary.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank the gentleman from Virginia (Mr. Forbes) and my colleague on the Education and Labor Committee, Mr. Scott, for introducing this resolution and recognizing the important role that Virginia State University plays in educating young people from all over the world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a historically black college and university, or HBCU, Virginia State University is one of a diverse community of institutions. Historically black colleges and universities include 2- and 4-year institutions, public and private institutions, as well as single-sex and coed institutions. To be designated a historically black college or university, an institution must have been established prior to 1964 with a primary mission of educating African Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, HBCUs have a long, proud and well-established heritage. These institutions have been educating the students of this Nation for over 100 years. While comprising fewer than 3 percent of the country's 2-and 4-year institutions, HBCUs are responsible for producing a significant number of all bachelor's, master's and professional degrees earned by African Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress has repeatedly recognized the importance of the historically black colleges and universities. Between 1995 and 2006, congressional funding for the Strengthening Historically Black Colleges and Universities Program rose from $109 million to $238 million, a 118 percent increase. What is more, funding for the HBCU Grad Program increased from $19.6 million to $57.9 million, an increase of 195 percent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Virginia State University, located in Petersburg, VA, was originally founded on March 6, 1882, as the Virginia Normal and Collegiate Institute and was the first fully State-supported 4-year institution of higher education for African Americans and one of Virginia's two land-grant institutions. VSU's first president, John Mercer Langston, went on to become the first African American Member of Congress from the Commonwealth of Virginia.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This school offers 43 undergraduate degree programs and 15 graduate degree programs. The campus is composed of more than 50 buildings, which include a 416-acre agricultural research facility. Since its founding, VSU has grown from a small HBCU to an institution that enrolls just over 5,000 students, 96 percent of whom are African American.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, it is for all of these reasons and more that I urge my colleagues to honor the 125th anniversary of Virginia State University and support <bill type="hr" number="182">H. Res. 182</bill></paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I now yield as much time as he needs to my colleague from Virginia (Mr. Forbes).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400137" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would like to begin by thanking Chairman Miller and Ranking Member McKeon for their work in getting this resolution to the floor. I also want to thank my friend and colleague, Congressman Scott, for his hard work and the work of his staff in getting the bill here and also Congresswoman Foxx for her efforts and her staff in helping to get <bill type="hr" number="182">H. Res. 182</bill> on the floor today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today, as do my colleagues, to commend Virginia State University on the celebration of their 125th anniversary. This resolution honors Virginia State University's continued resolve to provide an excellence in education since March 6, 1882.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, today we just pause and we say to all of the current students of Virginia State University, to the alumni, to the faculty and to the administration, thank you for a job well done in the pursuit of excellence that you have done for these last 125 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As you may know and you have heard mentioned today, Mr. Speaker, Virginia State University is located in my district in Chesterfield County, and it is warmly embraced by the neighboring city of Petersburg. It was the first university to be fully funded by the Commonwealth of Virginia as an institution of higher learning for African Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Currently, Virginia State University offers 45 baccalaureate and master's degree programs and introduced their first doctoral program in 2003. This campus includes 236 acres and an additional 416-acre agriculture research facility. They host nearly 5,000 students and continue to grow.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It fills me with pride to stand on the House floor today to present this resolution. We have had a long-standing relationship with Virginia State University and look forward to continuing this through the years to come.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this resolution comes before the House floor cosponsored by the entire Virginia congressional delegation. Though I cannot speak for my colleagues, I believe I can say we are proud of the progress Virginia State University has provided through its 125 years of service to the students in Virginia and beyond. This anniversary represents a significant milestone in the Commonwealth of Virginia's history.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The university is more than worthy of this distinguished recognition for the impressive advancements and accomplishments in their 125-year history, and we are honored to acknowledge their achievements today</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400643" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400364" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, 125 years ago, Virginia State University was founded. I want to thank my colleague from Virginia for his leadership in introducing this resolution, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Virginia (Mr. Scott) that the House suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, <bill type="hr" number="182">H. Res. 182</bill>, as amended.</chair>
</record>
