<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1195059601" ordinal="37" title="CONFERENCE REPORT ON H.R. 1429, IMPROVING HEAD START FOR SCHOOL READINESS ACT OF 2007">
  <narrative>CONFERENCE REPORT ON <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>, IMPROVING HEAD START FOR SCHOOL READINESS ACT OF 2007 -- (House of Representatives - November 14, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H13876]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400216" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, pursuant to House Resolution 813, I call up the conference report on the bill (<bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>)  to reauthorize the Head Start Act, to improve program quality, to expand access, and for other purposes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to House Resolution 813, the conference report is considered read.</chair>
  <narrative>(For conference report and statement, see proceedings of the House of November 9, 2007, at page H13462.)</narrative>
  <chair> The gentleman from Michigan (Mr. Kildee) and the gentleman from California (Mr. McKeon) each will control 30 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Michigan.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400216" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I'm pleased to be here today to reauthorize Head Start. And I know that everyone agrees that it has been far too long since we have authorized the Head Start Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Head Start has served millions of our most vulnerable children and families well for 42 years. More recently, Early Head Start has done the same for infants and toddlers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These are our country's premiere early childhood programs, Mr. Speaker. Head Start works, and this bill will make it work even better.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nothing is more critical to a child's success than a great teacher, and this bill will ensure that by 2013, half of Head Start teachers nationwide will have bachelor's degrees. This will improve professional development so that teachers can keep up with the best practices in early childhood education.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill increases funding for Early Head Start so that children will receive comprehensive services during the most critical stages of brain development.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, our predecessors 42 years ago initiated Head Start even before we realized, as we do today, that early and regular stimulation was critical to the very physical development of the brain.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Head Start requires the Secretary to update early learning standards using the best science, and puts an end to the ill-advised National Reporting System.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It authorizes significant increases in resources so that we can expand access. And I want to work with our friends on the Appropriations Committee to do just that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It enhances the quality of Head Start boards, while maintaining a shared governance structure that empowers parents.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And it is especially important to me that the bill prioritizes significant resources for Indian and migrant and seasonal Head Start programs, both to expand existing programs and create new programs, so that these children, whose communities face such terrific challenges, can grow up to help their communities overcome those challenges.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In closing, Mr. Speaker, I want to thank Chairman Miller and Senator Kennedy, Senator Dodd, Ranking Members MCKEON and CASTLE, and Senator Enzi and Senator Alexander, my staff and theirs, and all the conferees and their staffs for their hard work. I especially want to thank Lloyd Horwich, who has worked so hard with me to produce this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We do our best work in this Congress when we work in a bipartisan way, and we do our best work, especially in education, when we work in a bipartisan way. It's been my pleasure through the years to have the advantage of working with Mr. McKeon from California. We've grown to really commit ourselves to education and we trust one another and like one another, which is very important.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I was privileged, Mr. Speaker, to introduce this bill in March with Chairman Miller, Governor CASTLE, Mr. McKeon and many others, and look forward to its becoming law very soon.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since 1965, the Head Start program has been instrumental in our efforts to close the gap between disadvantaged children and their peers. This program provides health, developmental and educational services to low-income and at-risk children before they enroll in school in order to help close the readiness gap. Head Start helps establish a foundation for these children's future success.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This conference report is the product of a bipartisan collaboration and compromise. I'd like to thank Chairman Miller, along with Mr. Castle and Mr. Kildee. And I appreciate Mr. Kildee's words, and I appreciate the opportunity I've had to get to know him and work with him closely over the years. I thank them for their work to strengthen and improve Head Start.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I'd also like to acknowledge the staff on both sides for their instrumental role in developing this legislation. Their work was critical to producing such a strong, widely supported measure. On my staff, I'd like to recognize Kirsten Duncan, along with Susan Ross and James Bergeron, for their tireless efforts on this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Studies have shown that children enrolled in Head Start do make some progress. We also know that even greater results are possible.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With this in mind, the Improving Head Start for School Readiness Act will strengthen Head Start's academic standards by emphasizing cognitive development and the results of scientifically valid research in topics critical to children's school readiness. The conference report will improve teacher quality by ensuring a greater number of Head Start teachers have degrees and are adequately trained in early childhood development, particularly in teaching the fundamentals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Despite the many successes of the Head Start program, it's reputation has, unfortunately, been marred in recent years by instances of financial abuse and mismanagement. In communities across the country, we've heard reports of taxpayer dollars being squandered. A March 2005 report from the Government Accountability Office warned the financial control system in the Head Start program is flawed and failing to prevent multimillion dollar financial abuses that cheat poor children, taxpayers and law-abiding  Head Start operators.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This conference report builds on efforts of Republicans in the 109th Congress to address weaknesses in the Head Start financial control system in order to better protect taxpayers and ensure funds are being used to help prepare disadvantaged children for school.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I'm particularly pleased that the conference report includes strong protections to ensure Head Start dollars are not used to pay excessive salaries to program executives. The House voted unanimously last week to instruct conferees to include clear, unambiguous protections in this area. Thanks to that vote, we were able to visit the negotiations and agree to even stronger language.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the Improving Head Start for School Readiness Act is a solid reauthorization bill built on bipartisan collaboration. Head Start is a good program capable of achieving even greater results, and the bill before us will help achieve that goal.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I support passage of this conference report so we can send the bill to the President.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400216" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker I yield 3 minutes to the gentleman from Kentucky (Mr. Yarmuth).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412211" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank my colleague.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, we must acknowledge that America's continued success will not be ensured unless we equip the leaders of tomorrow with the tools they need today. This means cultivating not just the most privileged and brightest students but the students who grow up with disadvantages. We must nurture the potential of all our children from the very beginning of their lives. We don't have one mind to waste or one citizen to waste. We need everyone to have the greatest ability and preparation to live  productive, meaningful lives in our society.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For a million students, Head Start is the answer. For those who work hard but remain stuck just above the poverty level, the reauthorization of this program will give their children a chance to soar. I am proud to say that just as we did by increasing the minimum wage, doubling college assistance, and providing health care to uninsured children, this Congress continues to put working families first.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With nine in 10 Americans reporting no increase in income the last 6 years, cynicism has replaced hope for too many. We are in a position to restore faith in the future. And as we pass the  reins of our Nation to future generations, we must invest in that future by guaranteeing every child a chance to succeed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I know that in my hometown of Louisville, Kentucky, thousands and thousands of young children have gotten adequate preparation for schooling that they might not otherwise have gotten because of the wonderful training they received in Head Start. It is not just a head start; it is a very strong foundation to success in education and success in whatever careers our young children may select.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I'm proud to stand here in the House of Representatives, the people's House, and urge my colleagues to support a program which will help ensure that the people we represent are able to enjoy the prosperity and the happiness that our Founding Fathers hoped they would have.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With that, I urge my colleagues to join me in supporting Head Start and begin restoring faith in the future for millions of American families.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I am happy now to yield 3 minutes to the gentleman from Delaware (Mr. Castle), the ranking member on the subcommittee and at the same time thank him for the key role he played in getting this legislation to this point.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400070" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the distinguished gentleman from California for yielding and for his work on this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I do rise to ask my colleague to support this bipartisan conference report before us today. Like almost every other Member of this body, I believe strongly in the benefits of this program. I trust that the conference report on <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>, the Improving Head Start for School Readiness Act, will improve Head Start by emphasizing that every child, regardless of his or her economic status, should have the best possible chance to succeed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As Mr. McKeon stated, this report is a byproduct of bipartisan collaboration and compromise. I would also like to thank Chairman Miller, along with Mr. Kildee and Mr. McKeon, as well as the committee staff for their work on Head Start. I see Ms. Woolsey in the room. I have worked with her on this issue before, too, and thank her.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation builds upon efforts made in the past several Congresses to address weaknesses in the Head Start program and improves upon language contained in the bill to help make the program even stronger. Specifically, this report preserves and enhances the vital role of parents in ensuring the success of Head Start by establishing both a governing body and a policy council, each with specific detailed responsibilities. This conference report also maintains the current income eligibility  requirement to provide services to those who need them the most. Additionally, this legislation ensures that curriculum and other materials used in Head Start classrooms are based on the principles of scientific research and scientifically valid research. Equally important, this conference agreement ensures that a greater number of Head Start</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the Improving Head Start for School Readiness Act builds upon the success of the Head Start program and will assist in having the program achieve even greater results. I urge my colleagues to support the passage of this conference report.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400216" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 3 minutes to the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Davis).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>I want to thank the gentleman from Michigan for yielding and I also want to commend him for introducing this legislation, <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>, the Head Start for School Readiness Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I applaud the leaders in both Chambers for crafting such a strong bill that builds on the accomplishments of Head Start and promotes the success of young children. It is clear from this product that you and your staffs have toiled long and hard to strengthen the quality of the Head Start program, and I say to you, well done.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Foremost, let me thank you for maintaining the role of parents in governing Head Start. For more than 40 years, one of the most unique and important aspects of the Head Start program has been its emphasis on parental involvement. I worked actively with Mr. Souder and Mr. Payne, along with 88 other Members of the House, to advocate for maintaining this hallmark of equal responsibility for parents in governing Head Start.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am also pleased that the bill strikes a balance between the House and Senate versions on the issue of program eligibility. In high cost-of-living areas such as Chicago, low-income families can lose access to this critical child development program not due to lack of need but because we fail to adequately consider the cost of living when calculating the poverty level. The conference report grants local programs flexibility in opening the eligibility while also requiring them to demonstrate the  need.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am especially grateful that the final report includes so many issues near and dear to me, such as recruiting minority male teachers, emphasizing children's social and emotional well-being, recognition of the expanding role of grandparents and kinship caregivers in children's lives, incorporating the best practices from the field of home visitation into the Early Head Start program, and increasing funds for salaries and education for Head Start teachers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, in addition, I am very pleased that this bipartisan bill preserves the anti-discrimination history of Head Start advocated so ardently by the Head Start and religious communities. Federal funds are not meant to support discrimination of any type, and I applaud the Members on both sides for maintaining this fundamental commitment to justice and fairness.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill expands access, improves teacher quality, expands accountability, and strengthens school readiness. I am proud to be a member of the Education Committee and proud to serve in a Congress that will pass this bill into law.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I am pleased to yield 6 minutes at this time to the gentleman from Indiana, a member of the committee (Mr. Souder).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400385" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank our distinguished ranking member.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am very supportive of this bill, but I want to share some vague uncomfortability with what I think is potentially happening here in Head Start, and I think it's very important to clarify for this administration and for future administrations what this bill is intended to do and not intended to do.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>From the time the Republicans took over in Congress, I remember then Subcommittee Chairman Frank Riggs had a number of hearings talking about the lack of an academic focus to Head Start. There was a big debate about what the original role was, but it was supposed to certainly prepare kids who didn't have the same opportunities for their ability to be prepared when they started school.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But there's a reason that Head Start, while it was in the old Department of HEW, didn't move with the Department of Education and stayed with HHS. If it was intended to be merely another education program run by educational bureaucrats, run the same way that every other education program was run, it would be over in the Department of Education. It wouldn't have been a grassroots Head Start program with parent councils that voted and participated and ran it. It would have been part of a pre-K  program or a kindergarten program run by the public schools. Increasingly, we see this pressure where the public schools are trying to take over the Head Start program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The original origins of the Head Start movement came out of the sixties. Saul Alinsky was an organizer in Chicago. The populist movement and the community action organizations led to a wave of saying, we need programs where local low-income groups are empowered to make their own decisions. What this meant many times was it didn't exactly meet the professional goals or standards of where the public schools thought it should be, necessarily where the professionals in Washington thought it should  be, but they were engaged at the community level, participating in a way that we have tried to reach in kindergarten and public schools forever. We can't get  low-income parents engaged. It's one of the biggest challenges we have. Yet in the Head Start program, they were engaged all over the country, whether it</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, we had wide support in this body, 91 Members, including Mr. Davis and Congresswomen Loretta Sanchez and Maxine Waters, myself and Ric Keller and many conservatives on the right, who share the concept of empowerment. None of us want malfeasance in office or funding problems, people who aren't accounting. All of us would like to see more professional development. All of us would like to see quantified goals. But in this drift towards trying to use the word</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The fact is when you get groups of parents and give them votes, they're going to make some judgment mistakes. We need to have accountability. I am for accountability. We need to have measurement. We need to empower those people. But this can't be a typical takeover project, because I believe that the major reason Head Start has, in fact, worked in communities across the country is it's engaged with the people at the grassroots level. And sometimes when we use some of the language here, what we  really mean is we're going to take it away from these people because they're not quite as skilled and that we don't quite trust their judgments as much.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, I appreciate that there was a strong compromise to the side of parents in the conference committee, that, in fact, the language keeping the voting powers to the parents is still there. And it still says that in any major decision, they get a vote. It still says that when there is a conflict with the other people who are governing this, it has to be resolved. There was an additional clause added that seemed to potentially demean the parent councils, where it says "meaningful consultation  and collaboration." Now, that was originally going to replace the vote just like we saw in HIDTAs, the High Intensity Drug Trafficking Areas, where we tried to have the Federal Government, initially in the proposal of the Bush administration, take voting power</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What's great about this bill is we left the voting power there and no future administration or this one should mistake that the parents still have the voting power. Any meaningful decision, they have a right to have a vote, and there has to be a resolution with the policy councils. This additional language that was Senate language is supplemental and did not alter the policy council. Of course, parent councils should be a meaningful consultation and collaboration, not just as a "term" but real  meaningful consultation. They should also have the vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank the leadership on the Democratic side and the Republican side in the House and Senate in leaving the real vote to parents. It was a huge victory, a grassroots, bipartisan, liberal-conservative victory that should stand and hopefully will not be undone by administrative interpretation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400216" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 3 minutes to the gentleman from New York (Mr. Bishop).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400031" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in strong support of <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>, the Improving Head Start Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I represent part of Suffolk County, New York, where over 20 Head Start and three Early Head Start centers have been serving the community since 1966. I am also proud to say that my wife's first teaching job was as a Head Start teacher, and that she remains today an early childhood teacher.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Parents, teachers, and many of my colleagues can all agree that Head Start is one of our Nation's most prominent and successful early education programs. This bill continues to build on Head Start's success by ensuring that kids are prepared for school, by improving teacher and classroom quality, strengthening the focus on school readiness, increasing accountability, and boosting coordination.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Research has found that children who attend Head Start enter school better prepared than their low-income peers who do not attend the program, and that children who do attend Head Start make significant learning gains.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If we are serious about achieving the goals set forth by NCLB, then passing Head Start reauthorization is a down payment on achieving these goals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I was proud to offer an amendment during the Education and Labor Committee's consideration of this bill to allow Head Start programs to use up to 10 percent of their quality improvement funds for transportation costs. This amendment was in response to concerns brought to me by my constituents, as many Head Start programs are being forced to choose between providing transportation to children or sacrificing the quality of their program. This is a decision that no Head Start program should have  to make.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With this amendment, and with so many other worthwhile improvements to Head Start, I strongly encourage my colleagues to support this balanced reauthorization for the benefit of our children and future generations of Americans.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, may I inquire as to the time we have left, please.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from California has 19 minutes. The gentleman from Michigan has 18 1/2  minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400216" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield now 3 minutes to the gentlelady from California, a member of the committee and a very active worker on this bill, Ms. Woolsey.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400436" topic="">
    <paragraph>I want to thank Chairman Kildee and Chairman Miller and Ranking Member McKeon, who was the Chair when we were working on this, and Ranking Member Castle for a bipartisan success. We can be proud of ourselves today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Anyone who has been around small children knows that they're sponges for information, they just sop it up if you make it available to them. And it's widely accepted that early childhood education is absolutely critical to their development and directly tied to their success when they get into school, elementary school, and their ongoing future. So getting children in a structured classroom environment earlier in their young lives provides a critical window of opportunity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Head Start provides our Nation's poorest children with a quality start that puts them on a level playing field with others when they start elementary school. No matter where a child comes from or what his or her background is, Head Start provides an equal opportunity to succeed by starting with a quality early childhood education. That's why I'm glad I'm here today as we authorize Head Start, reaffirming our commitment to this valuable program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill expands access to Head Start, it improves teacher and classroom quality, and it strengthens the services children and their families receive when they enroll in the program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The administration, however, can and should do better when it comes to funding. Too many eligible children are still denied an opportunity to participate in a Head Start program because there isn't enough funds. Well, if this administration wasn't spending $500 billion in Iraq, we would have the necessary resources to increase funding to allow for program improvement to give every child the Head Start experience and to increase teacher quality and salaries. It just depends on where we put our  priorities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Children are 25 percent of our population, Mr. Speaker, but they are 100 percent of our future. We must provide them with the best possible beginning to their lives. So, Mr. Speaker, I look forward to working with my colleagues to increase our Nation's commitment to education for all of our children and to ensure that Head Start remains the successful experience that it is.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I am happy to yield 1 minute to the gentleman from Ohio, the Republican leader, former chairman of our committee, Mr. Boehner.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400036" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker and my colleagues, let me thank Mr. McKeon for yielding time and take a moment to congratulate Mr. Miller and Mr. Kildee, Mr. McKeon and Mr. Castle, the two Republican rankers on the committee, for a job well done.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have been at this reauthorization for a number of years, and I think that the work that is represented in this reauthorization of Head Start is very important for our Nation's children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Those of us who have worked in the area of education for a long time know that for low-income children, having some type of early childhood development is critically important to their success. Head Start is among a number of programs, both public and private, that are out there that supply this type of early childhood development for these children. The reforms that are included in this bill I think are critically important so that Head Start can really be all that many of us want it to be.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are some tremendous Head Start programs around the country, I have visited a number of them, but there are also some programs that don't fulfill the promise that we're making to parents and to their children of what this program could be.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We all know that if we're serious about educating all of America's kids, we will never get there unless we find a way to help low-income children get the development they need that many of us take for granted, things that happen in our homes, for those who have means, things that happen in our communities that these children are not exposed to. And so to make sure that they do have an equal chance to get a good education, that early childhood development for these 3- and 4-year-olds is very,  very important.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I do want to congratulate my colleagues for the bipartisan way this bill has come together. This is a great example of what Congress can do in a bipartisan way when it chooses to.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have been on the floor a lot this year, being critical of the fact that there was some partisan bill on the floor of the House that was going nowhere. But here is an example of Members on both sides of the aisle working together for the interests of America's low-income kids, and I just wanted to come to the floor and say, job well done.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400216" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, first of all, I appreciate the very kind words of the Republican leader and my former Chair on this committee. His work through the years on this bill has been very, very helpful.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself the remainder of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am pleased to be here in support of a conference report that will make Head Start even stronger. This program serves nearly 1 million underprivileged children and eases the divide between the haves and the have-nots when it comes to preparing them for kindergarten. The bipartisan support we've seen today should lend all of us confidence that the program will remain on a solid foundation for generations to come.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By reauthorizing Head Start, we're going to strengthen academic standards by emphasizing cognitive development using scientifically valid research, improve teacher quality by ensuring more Head Start teachers have degrees and are adequately trained in early childhood development, increase financial disclosure requirements by Head Start operators as custodians of Federal Head Start grants, and require local governance boards to actively oversee grantees. These are commonsense reforms that I wholeheartedly  support.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to join the Republican leader and my other colleagues who have spoken here today in commenting on the bipartisanship with which this bill was brought to this point. It's one that the President will sign. It's one that will bring good reforms to a good program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to join me in supporting this conference report.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400216" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, again, I thank Mr. McKeon, Mr. Castle, and all those on the other side of the aisle who have worked so hard on this bill to produce a very good bill. I also want to thank Ruth Friedman, with Chairman Miller, for her tireless work on this bill over the last 5 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, America can watch this Congress at work today on this bill, Head Start, and feel good about its Congress, and that's very important. This process in working on Head Start has shown Congress at its best, and I think we owe that to the American people. And we can feel a certain pride in having demonstrated to the American people what Congress can do. This is one of our better days, one of our better bills, and it's been a process that we've enjoyed. We've had differences. We resolved  those differences. We produced a very good bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And people do make a difference. People in this Congress make a difference. And I want to especially, again, commend my friend, my colleague, Mr. McKeon from California, who has worked tirelessly on this bill. This bill is better because of his input.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400663" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in strong support of the Improving Head Start Act of 2007 Conference Report.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1964, President Lyndon Johnson laid out his domestic agenda, one that made Americans reevaluate what it means to be a Great Society. We learned much from that time in our Nation's rich history: that we must all fight together for civil rights, for equality, for peace and security, against poverty, and for future generations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One year later, the Head Start program began as a product of Lyndon Johnson's vision of a Great Society. Now, over 40 years later, Head Start is truly one of our Nation's most successful programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Head Start takes a holistic approach to ensuring that our country's most at-risk children are educated and healthy. Kids who are vibrant and in school are put on a path to success. The program provides grants to local public and private agencies to offer comprehensive child development services to disadvantaged children and families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank Chairman MILLER and Chairman KILDEE and all of the conferees for their important work on this conference agreement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am glad to see that this agreement authorizes 7.35 billion dollars for the program. Unfortunately, a number of residents in my hometown of Sacramento are eligible for enrollment in Head Start, but are currently on a waiting list because the program does not have enough funds. This funding authorization will help correct this urgent problem. It will help put Head Start back on track to ensuring that all eligible children will be able to participate in the program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Also important is the expansion of the Early Head Start program. This program serves low-income youth from birth to age 3. It puts special focus on helping preschoolers develop the early reading and math skills they need to be successful in school. It recognizes that starting our children's education early is crucial to their long-term achievement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Conference Report also includes an increase in income eligibility. This is especially important in California due to my State's high cost-of-living. I want to thank the conferees for recognizing the growing needs in communities across the Nation by increasing income eligibility.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Study after study confirms that early education is the key to success later in life. And I am glad that Leadership has made educating our children a priority. With passage of this bill today, the 110th Congress indeed becomes the Children's Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, no child should be without early education. The Head Start program provides access to education for all of our children, regardless of their parents' economic status.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As Lyndon Johnson said, "The purpose of protecting the life of our Nation and preserving the liberty of our citizens is to pursue the happiness of our people. Our success in that pursuit is the test of our success as a Nation."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe that reauthorizing the Head Start program reaffirms our commitment to the Great Society that Lyndon Johnson envisioned. I am proud to support the rule and the Head Start Improvement Act.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, more than 40 years ago, we recognized that poverty was robbing millions of children of the opportunity to do well in school and succeed in life.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a nation, we made a decision to help poor children reach school age ready to succeed by creating the Head Start early childhood program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the last four decades, it has helped nearly 25 million children by providing them with high-quality, comprehensive education, health, and nutrition services.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Head Start remains a cornerstone in this country's efforts to help all children learn, to  combat poverty, and to provide all Americans with the opportunity to meet their fullest potential.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We know that Head Start works. Research shows that not only do Head Start students make important educational gains while they attend the program, they also continue to gain ground after they leave Head Start.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Research shows that by the end of kindergarten, Head Start graduates are "essentially at national norms in early reading and writing" and have further narrowed the achievement gap in vocabulary, general knowledge and early math.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In other words, Head Start is doing what we expect and demand that it should do--help prepare children to succeed in school and in life.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We also know that there are ways we can improve Head Start.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is why I am so pleased to be here today with a bipartisan conference report to reauthorize and reinvigorate Head Start.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bipartisan legislation improves teacher and classroom quality, expands access to Head Start for more children, improves comprehensive services that help children and their families, and ensures that taxpayer dollars only fund Head Start centers that are well-run and high quality.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, this legislation builds on Head Start's success by integrating the best available science on child development to inform classroom instruction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Each year we learn more and more about how children's brains develop. This legislation ensures that we improve teacher quality and update classroom practices based on what the research tells us.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to re-evaluate and update early learning standards and use of assessments with the best available science, including a forthcoming study from the National Academy of Sciences.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And it terminates further use of an inappropriate and ineffective testing regime for 4-year-olds. This wasteful testing regime cost taxpayers over $25 million dollars, it took up valuable classroom time and hasn't been useful for improving program quality.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Of course, Head Start is much more than an educational program. Head Start provides health, nutrition and parent education services in addition to a strong educational curriculum.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The conference report recognizes this by also strengthening Head Start's role in meeting these important needs of the children it serves.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation takes important steps to ensure that Head Start centers are well-run and effectively managed. This will ensure that taxpayer dollars are used wisely and that every Head Start center is high quality.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The report allows the Secretary of Health and Human Services to more quickly take funding away from bad programs. It requires that new and detailed fiscal management protocols be included in program reviews.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, the legislation also expands access to Head Start in many important ways.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Expansion of Early Head Start is prioritized so more infants and toddlers can attend Head Start during the years their brains are growing the fastest.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And expansion of Migrant and Indian programs is prioritized so more of these children can have access to this important program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, before I close, I'd like to take a minute to thank Congressman MCKEON, Chairman KILDEE, Congressman CASTLE, Chairman KENNEDY, Senator ENZI, Senator DODD, and Senator ALEXANDER for their hard work in getting us to this point.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I'd also like to thank the staff for their work and expertise.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In particular, I'd like to thank Liz King and Jean Harmann with Legislative Counsel; Lloyd Horwich with Mr. KILDEE; James Bergeron, Susan Ross, Kirsten Duncan, and Jessica Gross with Mr. MCKEON and Mr. CASTLE; Roberto Rodriguez and David Johns with Senator KENNEDY; Catherine Hildum with Senator DODD; Lindsay Hunsicker and Beth Buehlmann with Senator Enzi; David Cleary and Sara Rittling with Senator Alexander; and from my own staff--Lamont Ivey,  Molly Carter, Kate Scully, Stephanie Moore, and Ruth Friedman.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill will build on Head Start's past successes to create an even stronger program to provide Head Start children with a better future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am pleased that we are about to send this legislation to the President for his signature.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank my colleagues for their efforts.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400119" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of the Head Start conference report and I thank Representatives MCKEON, CASTLE, MILLER and KILDEE for their work on producing an agreement with the Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For several years, I have worked to improve Head Start's academic and Migrant and Seasonal Head Start provisions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For thousands of children, Head Start serves as their first formal learning experience. Three- and four-year-olds are open to learning about the world around them, and they should be presented with a wide range of early academic concepts. I am very pleased that this conference agreement includes provisions to ensure that these children are exposed to math and science. I certainly do not intend for Head Start to teach "rocket science," but rather for its teachers to equip Head Start preschoolers  with the extremely basic concepts of math and science. Perhaps it will spark the imagination of some kids, and lay the foundation for them to become rocket scientists many years later.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With regard to Migrant and Seasonal Head Start, I joined with Representatives GRIJALVA, HINOJOSA and SANCHEZ in securing a 5 percent funding floor for Migrant and Seasonal Head Start in the House version of the bill. For far too long, funding for Migrant and Seasonal Head Start has lacked parity with other Head Start programs. I am disappointed that the conference report abandoned the House- and Senate-passed 5 percent floor, but I recognize the difficulty conferees had in finding  a workable formula. I hope that Members will join me in supporting funding for Migrant and Seasonal Head Start in the future since it is a sorely needed program for workers of our fields and their children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge Members to support the conference report.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400253" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of this conference report.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me start by commending the chairman of the subcommittee, the distinguished gentleman from Michigan, Mr. KILDEE, and the chairman of the full committee, the gentleman from California, Mr. MILLER for their work on this bill. I offer my thanks to the House and Senate conferees for bringing forth this important piece of legislation today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1965, with a great deal of hard work, Head Start was created. It soon became a "legislative Lamborghini" of social programs, going from 0 to 561,000 thousand participants in only a few months. In the 42 years since its inception, Head Start has become the educational foundation for more than 20 million American children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Education serves as both a ladder of opportunity and an investment in our future. Our Nation's security, economy, and position in the world all depend on the success of our education system. We must take advantage of this opportunity to fund our future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Head Start and Early Head Start are linchpins in the effort to prepare our country's most disadvantaged children to succeed in school and life. Many studies indicate that children enrolled in Head Start make significant progress in closing the readiness gap to their more advantaged peers as they enter kindergarten.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The congressionally mandated impact study recently published its results, which noted that after less than 1 year in the program, children in Head Start had narrowed the readiness gap by 45 percent in reading skills and 28 percent in writing skills. This momentum continues well beyond the ages of 3, 4, and 5, as another large academic study has noted that Head Start graduates continue to mount academic gains well after leaving the program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill we see before us today helps to raise the academic standards of American children and ensures that every child in our country has an equal opportunity to a high quality education. It aims to improve teacher quality by requiring a greater number of Head Start teachers to have a bachelor's degree and be adequately trained in early childhood development. This is clearly good news for the children that will be participating in Head Start in the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On multiple occasions, the President has advocated that all 3- and 4-year-old participants in Head Start should take standardized tests to assess their improvement. For President Bush, No Child Left Behind means no child left untested. I am happy that this conference report terminates the further use of the National Reporting System, an inappropriate, ineffective, and expensive testing regime.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This conference report notes that Head Start is not without the opportunity for evaluation, however, and there is strengthened program accountability at the Federal, regional, and local levels included in the legislation. The report also requires the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services to initiate classroom evaluations, thereby ensuring optimal teacher-child interactions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have known for some time that when children are not provided high-quality day care and early childhood services, once in school, their academic achievement and limited language proficiencies become cumulatively worse over time, over grade levels, and across all subject areas. By passing this conference report, we build on the past 42 years of success for this program and help ensure that both Head Start children as well as our Nation as a whole have a brighter tomorrow.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400636" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I supported this measure as a member of the conference committee that drafted the final version of the  bill. I'm proud to have served on the committee of House and Senate leaders that negotiated the final version of this legislation. This important bill will help prepare Louisiana's neediest children for kindergarten by improving their access to medical, nutritional, and educational services.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400160" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, Head Start is a critical part of this country's effort to combat the effects of poverty and ensure that all of our children have the opportunity and skills they need to thrive.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since its creation in 1965, it has proven to be our most valuable school readiness program in the history of this country--especially, now that we know more about the importance of early-childhood education.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Study after study demonstrates that by age 6, a child's capacity to learn is largely formed, and time after time, we have seen reports that prove students who attend Head Start perform better than those who don't.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By doing this, Head Start is helping to close the achievement gap between students of differing socio-economic status across our country, and helping the children in our communities by providing opportunities that they might not otherwise have.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Additionally, people often forget the wonderful things that this program does for the parents.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The key to Head Start's approach is its level of actively involving parents and the community in all aspects of the program--and this reauthorization would further this goal.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Parents are a child's first teachers, and Head Start helps build and foster a person's parenting skills in various ways.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Parents are also urged to improve their literacy skills, obtain adult basic education, and make their homes a place where reading is part of everyday life.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Head Start also tackles a wide range of poverty issues through its family and community partnerships, including: substance abuse, violence, HIV, homelessness, single-parent households, inadequate child care, unemployment, and numerous other stressors that challenge families' resources.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This program is clearly instrumental to our country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Improving Head Start for School Readiness Act of 2007 will reinvigorate Head Start and help more children arrive at kindergarten ready to succeed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this report.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400415" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in strong support of the Improving Head Start for School Readiness Act, to strengthen and expand Head Start programs across the country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last Spring, we held a National Summit on America's Children here at the Capitol. We heard from leading experts on child development and neuroscience, who emphasized the vital importance of early childhood education. Early interventions can dramatically increase a child's chances for future success.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Head Start is based on this idea and it works. For more than 40 years, it has been helping to close the achievement gap and teach our children that they can succeed, regardless of background or family income. More than 20 million children and families have benefited from its services. With this bill today, we will open the door to more children to enter both Head Start and Early Head Start and will ensure that they are better prepared for kindergarten and elementary school.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today's bill also recognizes the importance of early childhood educators, targeting new funding to improve teacher salaries and professional development. It ensures that teachers are highly qualified and able to meet the needs of children with disabilities and improves accountability for Head Start programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also urge my colleagues to support the funding necessary to continue Head Start's success. Last week, we sent the President a bill increasing Head Start funding by 2.2 percent to simply help it keep pace with inflation. The President vetoed this funding. I encourage my colleagues to vote to override the President's veto to prevent Head Start program closures and ensure that children get the services they were promised.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank Chairman Miller, Chairman Kildee, and the Conference Committee for putting together this bipartisan piece of legislation, and urge its passage today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400259" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in strong support of the conference report on <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>, the Head Start for School Readiness Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a member of the Education and Workforce Committee for 6 years, I was pleased to have the opportunity to work on this important issue. While visiting Head Start centers in the Fourth District, I was able to see firsthand the difference Head Start makes to children and families. In addition, the Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis published a study in 2004 showing that investment in early education has a rate of return of 12 percent. Even with all the evidence showing the social, educational  and economic value of this program, the Republican-controlled Congress was unable to pass an acceptable bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thanks to the hard work of Chairman Miller and Speaker Pelosi, the bill before us today is a bipartisan, bicameral agreement that does what earlier reauthorization bills did not--it focuses on preparing children for school. This agreement includes an increased emphasis on teacher quality and compensation, maintains parent involvement in the governing structure of Head Start, and increases coordination with other early childhood programs. It also maintains Head Start's commitment  to comprehensive services and places greater emphasis on identification of child and family mental health needs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill> terminates the inappropriate high stakes testing system for Head Start students implemented by the Bush Administration and replaces it with best practices for early learning. It also strengthens monitoring of Head Start programs, allows quicker action against failing or fraudulent programs and rejects a proposal to allow discrimination in hiring with Head Start funds.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress still faces the critical issue of providing enough resources to Head Start to serve all the children who are eligible to participate. The Head Start for School Readiness Act authorizes increased funding, as well as some flexibility in funding, to allow more children to access this important education. As a member of the Appropriations Committee, I will continue to work towards improving our investment in children, families and communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am pleased to vote in support of <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill> because this bill will make a real difference in the lives of children and families, and for our economy. I urge all my colleagues to support this investment in our future.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400230" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in strong support of the conference report on <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>, the Improving Head Start for School Readiness Act. This bipartisan legislation provides services to one of our most vulnerable populations--children from low-income families. By passing this measure today, over 900,000 disadvantaged children ages 3 to 5--including over 3,000 in Rhode Island--will have access to health services, the necessary tools to enter kindergarten, and a foundation for their success  later in life.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Studies show that low-income children often lack the richness of books in the home, proper nutrition, or access to a continuum of health services. For over 40 years, Head Start has provided comprehensive early childhood development services to low-income children, with strong emphasis on the involvement of families and the local community. <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill> would increase funding for quality improvements to Head Start and requires that by 2013 at least half of Head Start teachers nationwide have at least  a baccalaureate degree in early childhood education.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, half of the children enrolled in Head Start are from working poor families. For this reason, I am pleased that this conference agreement increases the income eligibility to 130 percent of the poverty level so that families struggling with work and childcare will have another option. I also believe that stopping the program's National Reporting System is essential until proper testing methods for these young children are carefully developed. <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill> also establishes a set of procedures  to improve accountability in the Head Start program, which will lead to improvements for all those served by Head Start.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Earlier in the year, <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill> passed both the House and the Senate with overwhelming support. I am proud that the 110th Congress is on the verge of passing this conference report after nearly a decade of failing to reauthorize Head Start. For all the children who benefit from this program, I look forward to sending this bill to the President for his signature.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400120" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of the conference report for <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>, the Improving Head Start for School Readiness Act. Since 1965, Head Start has provided 22 million American children with the education and health and social services to lead productive lives. It is the most successful school readiness program in the Nation and has always enjoyed bipartisan support.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, we are continuing this tradition by passing strong bipartisan legislation to reauthorize this vital program. In fact, this legislation marks the first time in almost a decade that Congress has reauthorized Head Start.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Improving Head Start for School Readiness Act will invest in America's future by providing children and their teachers with the resources they need to take advantage of the opportunities that the Head Start program has offered America's youth for over 40 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to providing additional resources for increasing teachers' salaries and State Advisory Councils, this reauthorization will expand the reach of both Head Start and Early Head Start by providing greater funding and flexibility. The increases in funding will enable tens of thousands more children to have access to the program. <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill> will also improve Head Start by providing the Secretary of Health and Human Services and local teams  with  tools to hold teachers and programs accountable and requires the implementation of best practices for family service workers. Head Start has served America's children well since 1965, and this legislation will expand the reach and ability of this program to positively impact lives across the country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank Chairman Miller for his dedication to Head Start and to education in general. Head Start is an investment in America's future. Thanks to Head Start, we can give our children the best start possible so they can lead productive lives and grow up to be outstanding citizens. I am proud to support these efforts to continue the legacy of Head Start, and I urge all of my colleagues to join me in voting for <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400653" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I am proud to support the Conference Report on <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>, the Improving Head Start for School Readiness Act of 2007. This bipartisan legislation takes significant steps to strengthen the Head Start program so that children will be better prepared and ready to succeed when they begin kindergarten. <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill> increases funds targeted at improving teacher quality and provides additional support for the program's extensive monitoring process and the comprehensive  services offered to the students' families. In addition, it expands access to Head Start for more children, increases coordination efforts with State and local programs, and eliminates any further development of the controversial and ineffective National Reporting System.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For over 40 years, the Head Start program has worked to break the cycle of poverty by providing access to early childhood education for low-income children and families. In the House budget for FY 2008, the State of Texas is estimated to receive approximately $490 million in Head Start funding which will go towards providing services for over 68,000 students. Since it first began in 1965, the program has served more than 20 million children, and it continues to play a major role in our Nation's  efforts to close the achievement gap, reduce poverty, and ensure that all Americans have the opportunity to succeed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Studies have shown that students with a high quality pre-Kindergarten education enjoy greater success in academics as well as their overall lives. The Head Start program goes a long way in addressing educational inequity by aiding low income children in their social and cognitive development. I am a firm supporter of this program and the lifelong benefits it provides. It is only by addressing this critical need that we will be able to ensure a better future for all our Nation's children.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400080" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, Head Start has been the premiere early childhood education program in the United States since 1965. Since that time, it has benefited 20 million children and families and has become one of the cornerstones of this country's efforts to close the achievement gap, combat poverty, and provide all Americans with the opportunity to thrive. By passing the conference report to <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>, the Improving Head Start for School Readiness Act of 2007, we will reinvigorate Head Start  and help more children arrive at kindergarten ready to succeed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The fact is that quality education and early engagement, from both parents and teachers, are essential for our kids' success. Recent findings from the congressionally mandated impact study found that after less than 1 year, Head Start narrowed the achievement gap by 45 percent in pre-reading skills and 28 percent in prewriting skills. Another large study found that Head Start graduates continue to gain ground after they leave the program. Furthermore, Head Start graduates are less likely to need  special education services, to be left back a grade or to get into trouble with the law. They are more likely to go on to college and to have professional careers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bipartisan reauthorization improves teacher and classroom quality, strengthens Head Start's focus on school readiness, expands access to Head Start for more children, ensures that centers are well-run, boosts coordination between Head Start and State and local programs, and improves comprehensive services that help children by helping their families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I commend and thank Congressmen KILDEE, CASTLE, and Chairman MILLER for their leadership on this critical legislation. Head Start has proven its self as a strong and effective program. The growth and success of millions of American children and families is living proof. We have a responsibility to embrace their success, support it, and strengthen it for years to come. I know that my colleagues will join me in sending this critical reauthorization to ensure the Head Start program  meets its full potential.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400125" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, as the only former State superintendent of schools serving in Congress, I have devoted my life to the well-being and development of children, and I strongly support Head Start. I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>, the Head Start for School Readiness Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the global economy of the 21st century, lifelong learning is the pathway to the American Dream, and for many of our Nation's children, learning begins with Head Start. Over 20,000 children in North Carolina get prepared for school in Head Start or Early Head Start.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This act takes and builds on the success of Head Start, expanding and enhancing this fundamental initiative that has served over 20 million children and families nationwide since 1965. <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill> extends the benefits of Head Start to more of our Nation's low-income children, and raises the bar so that we can attract highly qualified Head Start providers through performance accountability, greater compensation, and higher standards.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Research continues to show that the first few years of a child's life are critical to a child's mental development: their brains grow exponentially and learning patterns are set. We must invest in these youngsters so that they may take full advantage of one of the premier education systems in the world by ensuring their school-readiness by age 5. Head Start successfully provides the stepping stones to lifelong learning.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This act provides the parents and children of our country an additional 4 years of this vital service, guaranteeing a 20 percent increase in funding by 2012. Education is the best investment we can make for our children, grandchildren, country, and world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill> updates, improves, and expands the successful services of Head Start. I commend Chairman MILLER for his leadership on this bipartisan legislation, and I urge my colleagues to join me in voting to pass it.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400216" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no further requests for time, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the previous question is ordered on the conference report.</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <chair> The question is on the conference report.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and the Speaker pro tempore announced that the ayes appeared to have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400216" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX, this 15-minute vote on adoption of the conference report will be followed by 5-minute votes on motions to suspend the rules with regard to <bill type="h" number="3845">H.R. 3845</bill> and <bill type="h" number="719">H.R. 719</bill>.</chair>
  <chair>The vote was taken by electronic device, and there were--yeas 381, nays 36, not voting 15, as follows:</chair>
  <chair>[Roll No. 1090]</chair>
  <chair>Abercrombie</chair>
  <chair>Ackerman</chair>
  <chair>Aderholt</chair>
  <chair>Alexander</chair>
  <chair>Allen</chair>
  <chair>Altmire</chair>
  <chair>Andrews</chair>
  <chair>Arcuri</chair>
  <chair>Baca</chair>
  <chair>Bachmann</chair>
  <chair>Bachus</chair>
  <chair>Baird</chair>
  <chair>Baker</chair>
  <chair>Baldwin</chair>
  <chair>Barrow</chair>
  <chair>Bartlett (MD)</chair>
  <chair>Barton (TX)</chair>
  <chair>Bean</chair>
  <chair>Becerra</chair>
  <chair>Berkley</chair>
  <chair>Berman</chair>
  <chair>Berry</chair>
  <chair>Biggert</chair>
  <chair>Bilbray</chair>
  <chair>Bilirakis</chair>
  <chair>Bishop (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Bishop (NY)</chair>
  <chair>Bishop (UT)</chair>
  <chair>Blackburn</chair>
  <chair>Blumenauer</chair>
  <chair>Blunt</chair>
  <chair>Boehner</chair>
  <chair>Bonner</chair>
  <chair>Bono</chair>
  <chair>Boozman</chair>
  <chair>Boren</chair>
  <chair>Boswell</chair>
  <chair>Boucher</chair>
  <chair>Boyd (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Boyda (KS)</chair>
  <chair>Brady (PA)</chair>
  <chair>Brady (TX)</chair>
  <chair>Braley (IA)</chair>
  <chair>Brown (SC)</chair>
  <chair>Brown, Corrine</chair>
  <chair>Brown-Waite, Ginny</chair>
  <chair>Buchanan</chair>
  <chair>Burgess</chair>
  <chair>Butterfield</chair>
  <chair>Buyer</chair>
  <chair>Calvert</chair>
  <chair>Camp (MI)</chair>
  <chair>Cannon</chair>
  <chair>Cantor</chair>
  <chair>Capito</chair>
  <chair>Capps</chair>
  <chair>Capuano</chair>
  <chair>Cardoza</chair>
  <chair>Carnahan</chair>
  <chair>Carney</chair>
  <chair>Carter</chair>
  <chair>Castle</chair>
  <chair>Castor</chair>
  <chair>Chabot</chair>
  <chair>Chandler</chair>
  <chair>Clarke</chair>
  <chair>Clay</chair>
  <chair>Cleaver</chair>
  <chair>Clyburn</chair>
  <chair>Cohen</chair>
  <chair>Cole (OK)</chair>
  <chair>Conaway</chair>
  <chair>Conyers</chair>
  <chair>Cooper</chair>
  <chair>Costa</chair>
  <chair>Costello</chair>
  <chair>Courtney</chair>
  <chair>Cramer</chair>
  <chair>Crenshaw</chair>
  <chair>Crowley</chair>
  <chair>Cuellar</chair>
  <chair>Cummings</chair>
  <chair>Davis (AL)</chair>
  <chair>Davis (CA)</chair>
  <chair>Davis (IL)</chair>
  <chair>Davis (KY)</chair>
  <chair>Davis, David</chair>
  <chair>Davis, Lincoln</chair>
  <chair>Deal (GA)</chair>
  <chair>DeFazio</chair>
  <chair>DeGette</chair>
  <chair>Delahunt</chair>
  <chair>DeLauro</chair>
  <chair>Dent</chair>
  <chair>Diaz-Balart, L.</chair>
  <chair>Dicks</chair>
  <chair>Dingell</chair>
  <chair>Doggett</chair>
  <chair>Donnelly</chair>
  <chair>Drake</chair>
  <chair>Dreier</chair>
  <chair>Edwards</chair>
  <chair>Ehlers</chair>
  <chair>Ellison</chair>
  <chair>Ellsworth</chair>
  <chair>Emanuel</chair>
  <chair>Emerson</chair>
  <chair>Engel</chair>
  <chair>English (PA)</chair>
  <chair>Eshoo</chair>
  <chair>Etheridge</chair>
  <chair>Everett</chair>
  <chair>Fallin</chair>
  <chair>Farr</chair>
  <chair>Fattah</chair>
  <chair>Feeney</chair>
  <chair>Ferguson</chair>
  <chair>Filner</chair>
  <chair>Forbes</chair>
  <chair>Fortenberry</chair>
  <chair>Fossella</chair>
  <chair>Frank (MA)</chair>
  <chair>Frelinghuysen</chair>
  <chair>Gallegly</chair>
  <chair>Gerlach</chair>
  <chair>Giffords</chair>
  <chair>Gilchrest</chair>
  <chair>Gillibrand</chair>
  <chair>Gingrey</chair>
  <chair>Gohmert</chair>
  <chair>Gonzalez</chair>
  <chair>Goode</chair>
  <chair>Goodlatte</chair>
  <chair>Gordon</chair>
  <chair>Granger</chair>
  <chair>Graves</chair>
  <chair>Green, Al</chair>
  <chair>Green, Gene</chair>
  <chair>Grijalva</chair>
  <chair>Gutierrez</chair>
  <chair>Hall (NY)</chair>
  <chair>Hall (TX)</chair>
  <chair>Hare</chair>
  <chair>Harman</chair>
  <chair>Hastings (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Hastings (WA)</chair>
  <chair>Hayes</chair>
  <chair>Heller</chair>
  <chair>Herger</chair>
  <chair>Herseth Sandlin</chair>
  <chair>Higgins</chair>
  <chair>Hill</chair>
  <chair>Hinchey</chair>
  <chair>Hinojosa</chair>
  <chair>Hirono</chair>
  <chair>Hobson</chair>
  <chair>Hodes</chair>
  <chair>Hoekstra</chair>
  <chair>Holden</chair>
  <chair>Holt</chair>
  <chair>Honda</chair>
  <chair>Hooley</chair>
  <chair>Hoyer</chair>
  <chair>Hulshof</chair>
  <chair>Hunter</chair>
  <chair>Inslee</chair>
  <chair>Israel</chair>
  <chair>Issa</chair>
  <chair>Jackson (IL)</chair>
  <chair>Jackson-Lee (TX)</chair>
  <chair>Jefferson</chair>
  <chair>Johnson (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Johnson (IL)</chair>
  <chair>Johnson, E. B.</chair>
  <chair>Jones (NC)</chair>
  <chair>Jones (OH)</chair>
  <chair>Kagen</chair>
  <chair>Kanjorski</chair>
  <chair>Kaptur</chair>
  <chair>Keller</chair>
  <chair>Kennedy</chair>
  <chair>Kildee</chair>
  <chair>Kilpatrick</chair>
  <chair>Kind</chair>
  <chair>King (IA)</chair>
  <chair>King (NY)</chair>
  <chair>Kingston</chair>
  <chair>Kirk</chair>
  <chair>Klein (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Kline (MN)</chair>
  <chair>Knollenberg</chair>
  <chair>Kucinich</chair>
  <chair>Kuhl (NY)</chair>
  <chair>LaHood</chair>
  <chair>Lampson</chair>
  <chair>Langevin</chair>
  <chair>Lantos</chair>
  <chair>Larsen (WA)</chair>
  <chair>Larson (CT)</chair>
  <chair>Latham</chair>
  <chair>LaTourette</chair>
  <chair>Lee</chair>
  <chair>Levin</chair>
  <chair>Lewis (CA)</chair>
  <chair>Lewis (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Lewis (KY)</chair>
  <chair>Linder</chair>
  <chair>Lipinski</chair>
  <chair>LoBiondo</chair>
  <chair>Loebsack</chair>
  <chair>Lofgren, Zoe</chair>
  <chair>Lowey</chair>
  <chair>Lucas</chair>
  <chair>Lungren, Daniel E.</chair>
  <chair>Lynch</chair>
  <chair>Mahoney (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Maloney (NY)</chair>
  <chair>Manzullo</chair>
  <chair>Markey</chair>
  <chair>Marshall</chair>
  <chair>Matheson</chair>
  <chair>Matsui</chair>
  <chair>McCarthy (CA)</chair>
  <chair>McCarthy (NY)</chair>
  <chair>McCaul (TX)</chair>
  <chair>McCollum (MN)</chair>
  <chair>McCotter</chair>
  <chair>McCrery</chair>
  <chair>McDermott</chair>
  <chair>McGovern</chair>
  <chair>McHugh</chair>
  <chair>McIntyre</chair>
  <chair>McKeon</chair>
  <chair>McMorris Rodgers</chair>
  <chair>McNerney</chair>
  <chair>McNulty</chair>
  <chair>Meek (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Meeks (NY)</chair>
  <chair>Melancon</chair>
  <chair>Mica</chair>
  <chair>Michaud</chair>
  <chair>Miller (MI)</chair>
  <chair>Miller (NC)</chair>
  <chair>Miller, George</chair>
  <chair>Mollohan</chair>
  <chair>Moore (KS)</chair>
  <chair>Moore (WI)</chair>
  <chair>Moran (KS)</chair>
  <chair>Moran (VA)</chair>
  <chair>Murphy (CT)</chair>
  <chair>Murphy, Patrick</chair>
  <chair>Murphy, Tim</chair>
  <chair>Murtha</chair>
  <chair>Musgrave</chair>
  <chair>Myrick</chair>
  <chair>Nadler</chair>
  <chair>Napolitano</chair>
  <chair>Neal (MA)</chair>
  <chair>Nunes</chair>
  <chair>Obey</chair>
  <chair>Olver</chair>
  <chair>Ortiz</chair>
  <chair>Pallone</chair>
  <chair>Pascrell</chair>
  <chair>Pastor</chair>
  <chair>Payne</chair>
  <chair>Pearce</chair>
  <chair>Perlmutter</chair>
  <chair>Peterson (MN)</chair>
  <chair>Peterson (PA)</chair>
  <chair>Petri</chair>
  <chair>Pickering</chair>
  <chair>Pitts</chair>
  <chair>Pomeroy</chair>
  <chair>Porter</chair>
  <chair>Price (NC)</chair>
  <chair>Pryce (OH)</chair>
  <chair>Putnam</chair>
  <chair>Radanovich</chair>
  <chair>Rahall</chair>
  <chair>Ramstad</chair>
  <chair>Rangel</chair>
  <chair>Regula</chair>
  <chair>Rehberg</chair>
  <chair>Reichert</chair>
  <chair>Renzi</chair>
  <chair>Reyes</chair>
  <chair>Reynolds</chair>
  <chair>Richardson</chair>
  <chair>Rodriguez</chair>
  <chair>Rogers (AL)</chair>
  <chair>Rogers (KY)</chair>
  <chair>Rogers (MI)</chair>
  <chair>Ros-Lehtinen</chair>
  <chair>Roskam</chair>
  <chair>Ross</chair>
  <chair>Rothman</chair>
  <chair>Ruppersberger</chair>
  <chair>Rush</chair>
  <chair>Ryan (OH)</chair>
  <chair>Ryan (WI)</chair>
  <chair>Salazar</chair>
  <chair>S&#xE1;nchez, Linda T.</chair>
  <chair>Sanchez, Loretta</chair>
  <chair>Sarbanes</chair>
  <chair>Saxton</chair>
  <chair>Schakowsky</chair>
  <chair>Schiff</chair>
  <chair>Schmidt</chair>
  <chair>Schwartz</chair>
  <chair>Scott (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Scott (VA)</chair>
  <chair>Sensenbrenner</chair>
  <chair>Serrano</chair>
  <chair>Sestak</chair>
  <chair>Shays</chair>
  <chair>Shea-Porter</chair>
  <chair>Sherman</chair>
  <chair>Shimkus</chair>
  <chair>Shuler</chair>
  <chair>Shuster</chair>
  <chair>Simpson</chair>
  <chair>Sires</chair>
  <chair>Skelton</chair>
  <chair>Slaughter</chair>
  <chair>Smith (NE)</chair>
  <chair>Smith (NJ)</chair>
  <chair>Smith (TX)</chair>
  <chair>Smith (WA)</chair>
  <chair>Snyder</chair>
  <chair>Solis</chair>
  <chair>Souder</chair>
  <chair>Space</chair>
  <chair>Spratt</chair>
  <chair>Stark</chair>
  <chair>Stupak</chair>
  <chair>Sullivan</chair>
  <chair>Sutton</chair>
  <chair>Tanner</chair>
  <chair>Tauscher</chair>
  <chair>Taylor</chair>
  <chair>Terry</chair>
  <chair>Thompson (CA)</chair>
  <chair>Thompson (MS)</chair>
  <chair>Thornberry</chair>
  <chair>Tiahrt</chair>
  <chair>Tiberi</chair>
  <chair>Tierney</chair>
  <chair>Towns</chair>
  <chair>Tsongas</chair>
  <chair>Turner</chair>
  <chair>Udall (CO)</chair>
  <chair>Udall (NM)</chair>
  <chair>Upton</chair>
  <chair>Van Hollen</chair>
  <chair>Vel&#xE1;zquez</chair>
  <chair>Visclosky</chair>
  <chair>Walden (OR)</chair>
  <chair>Walsh (NY)</chair>
  <chair>Walz (MN)</chair>
  <chair>Wamp</chair>
  <chair>Wasserman Schultz</chair>
  <chair>Waters</chair>
  <chair>Watson</chair>
  <chair>Watt</chair>
  <chair>Waxman</chair>
  <chair>Weiner</chair>
  <chair>Welch (VT)</chair>
  <chair>Wexler</chair>
  <chair>Whitfield</chair>
  <chair>Wicker</chair>
  <chair>Wilson (NM)</chair>
  <chair>Wilson (OH)</chair>
  <chair>Wilson (SC)</chair>
  <chair>Wolf</chair>
  <chair>Woolsey</chair>
  <chair>Wu</chair>
  <chair>Wynn</chair>
  <chair>Yarmuth</chair>
  <chair>Young (AK)</chair>
  <chair>Young (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Akin</chair>
  <chair>Barrett (SC)</chair>
  <chair>Broun (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Burton (IN)</chair>
  <chair>Campbell (CA)</chair>
  <chair>Coble</chair>
  <chair>Culberson</chair>
  <chair>Doolittle</chair>
  <chair>Duncan</chair>
  <chair>Flake</chair>
  <chair>Foxx</chair>
  <chair>Franks (AZ)</chair>
  <chair>Garrett (NJ)</chair>
  <chair>Hensarling</chair>
  <chair>Inglis (SC)</chair>
  <chair>Johnson, Sam</chair>
  <chair>Jordan</chair>
  <chair>Lamborn</chair>
  <chair>Mack</chair>
  <chair>Marchant</chair>
  <chair>McHenry</chair>
  <chair>Miller (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Miller, Gary</chair>
  <chair>Neugebauer</chair>
  <chair>Pence</chair>
  <chair>Poe</chair>
  <chair>Price (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Rohrabacher</chair>
  <chair>Royce</chair>
  <chair>Sali</chair>
  <chair>Shadegg</chair>
  <chair>Stearns</chair>
  <chair>Tancredo</chair>
  <chair>Walberg</chair>
  <chair>Weldon (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Westmoreland</chair>
  <chair>Boustany</chair>
  <chair>Carson</chair>
  <chair>Cubin</chair>
  <chair>Davis, Tom</chair>
  <chair>Diaz-Balart, M.</chair>
  <chair>Doyle</chair>
  <chair>Hastert</chair>
  <chair>Jindal</chair>
  <chair>Mitchell</chair>
  <chair>Oberstar</chair>
  <chair>Paul</chair>
  <chair>Platts</chair>
  <chair>Roybal-Allard</chair>
  <chair>Sessions</chair>
  <chair>Weller</chair>
  <chair> Members are advised there are 5 minutes remaining in this vote.</chair>
  <chair/>
  <chair>Messrs. POE and HENSARLING changed their vote from "yea" to "nay."</chair>
  <chair>So the conference report was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The result of the vote was announced as above recorded.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
  <chair>Stated for:</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400321" topic="NOT VOTING--15">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on rollcall No. 1090, I was inadvertently absent from the floor at the time the Head Start for School Readiness Act [H.R. 1429] was voted. Had I been present, I would have vote in favor of said Act.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400636" topic="NOT VOTING--15">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I was unavoidably detained during rollcall vote No. 1090 on <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>, the Improving Head Start Act. I supported this measure as a member of the conference committee that drafted the final version of the bill and if I had been able to vote, I would have voted "aye."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
