<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1216224002" ordinal="18" title="DIPLOMATIC PRESSURE ON IRAN IS WORKING">
  <narrative>DIPLOMATIC PRESSURE ON IRAN IS WORKING -- (House of Representatives - July 16, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H6581]</narrative>
  <narrative>(Mr. PENCE asked and was given permission to address the House for 1 minute and to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400315" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, no one wants war with Iran, but America and our allies in Europe have been exerting increased diplomatic and economic pressure to move the nation of Iran and its government away from developing a nuclear program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In May, Congressman Gary Ackerman and I introduced bipartisan legislation, <bill type="hc" number="362">H. Con. Res. 362</bill>, urging this administration to impose expanded economic sanctions on key sectors of the Iranian economy. It appears as though it's having its good effect. In what's being reported today as what will be the "closest contact between the two countries since the Iranian revolution of 1979," this weekend, U.S. Ambassador William Burns will meet with top arms negotiators from Tehran. It will be more  of a listening session and should not be overstated.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, I would offer that this glimmer of hope in these negotiations is precisely because of the resolve of the United States and the European community to economically and diplomatically isolate Iran over its nuclear ambitions. But now is not the time for us to shrink from renewed diplomatic pressure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge all of my colleagues to join Congressman Gary Ackerman and me and cosponsor <bill type="hc" number="362">H. Con. Res. 362</bill> before this weekend. Let's send a deafening message to the negotiators in Iran that the American people stand for diplomatic and economic isolation until they abandon their nuclear ambition.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
