<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1170867604" ordinal="46" title="AMNESTY FOR U.S. BORDER PATROL AGENTS RAMOS AND COMPEAN">
  <chair> Under a previous order of the House, the gentleman from North Carolina (Mr. Jones) is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400209" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, 3 weeks ago, two U.S. Border Patrol agents entered Federal prison. Agents Ramos and Compean never should have been sent to prison.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These agents were convicted last spring for shooting a Mexican drug smuggler who brought 743 pounds of marijuana across our southern borders into Texas. Members of Congress and countless American citizens have repeatedly petitioned President Bush to pardon these agents. At the House Democratic Caucus last week, the President said, and I quote the President, "We want our Border Patrol agents guarding the borders from criminals and drug dealers and terrorists."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Agents Ramos and Compean were protecting the American people from an illegal drug dealer. Mr. President, we are calling on you today, as you pledged you would last month, to take a sober look at this case.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many Members of Congress have warned that if these two border agents enter prison, their safety would be threatened by those who hate law enforcement officers. Madam Speaker, tragically this happened last Saturday evening to Agent Ramos who was beaten in prison by a group of Mexican nationals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, the safety of these men is in jeopardy and time is running out. You alone have the authority to correct this injustice by pardoning these two men. Mr. President, please do not delay your review of the facts of this case.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, my colleagues and I will soon be sending a fifth letter to the President concerning these agents. We are asking the President to please expedite his consideration of a pardon for these two men and help these families realize that America is a country that believes in justice. Madam Speaker, I want to repeat that phrase very quickly: America is a country that believes in justice.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, please help these two Border agents. They deserve our praise, not to be in prison. Please, Mr. President, help them out now.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
