<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1185163200" ordinal="27" title="NATIONAL UNDERGROUND RAILROAD NETWORK TO FREEDOM AMENDMENTS ACT OF 2007">
  <narrative>NATIONAL UNDERGROUND RAILROAD NETWORK TO FREEDOM AMENDMENTS ACT OF 2007 -- (House of Representatives - July 23, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H8203]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="1239">H.R. 1239</bill>) to amend the National Underground Railroad Network to Freedom Act of 1998 to provide additional staff and oversight of funds to carry out the Act, and for other purposes, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="1239">H.R. 1239</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "National Underground Railroad Network to Freedom Amendments Act of 2007".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. AUTHORIZING APPROPRIATIONS FOR SPECIFIC PURPOSES.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; The National Underground Railroad Network to Freedom Act of 1998 (16 U.S.C. 469l et seq.) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) by striking section 3(d);&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) by striking section 4(d); and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) by adding at the end the following new section:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;"SEC. 5. AUTHORIZATION OF APPROPRIATIONS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(a) Amounts.--There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act $2,500,000 for each fiscal year, to be allocated as follows:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(1) $2,000,000 is to be used for the purposes of section 3.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(2) $500,000 is to be used for the purposes of section 4.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(b) Restrictions.--No amounts may be appropriated for the purposes of this Act except to the Secretary for carrying out the responsibilities of the Secretary as set forth in this Act.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 3. EFFECTIVE DATE.</narrative>
  <narrative> The amendments made by section 2 shall take effect at the beginning of the fiscal year immediately following the date of the enactment of this Act.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) and the gentlewoman from Washington (Mrs. McMorris Rodgers) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Arizona.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Arizona?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1239">H.R. 1239</bill>, introduced by the gentleman from Florida (Mr. Hastings), seeks to further the commitment made by Congress with the passage of the National Underground Railroad Network to Freedom Act of 1998 by reconfiguring the authorization of funds to carry out the act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the Underground Railroad was a historic protest movement against slavery which helped escaped slaves find freedom in Northern States and Canada prior to the Civil War.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The National Underground Railroad Network to Freedom Act of 1998 established the Underground Network to Freedom Program administered by the National Park Service. Today the program carries out important activities in more than 27 States and the District of Columbia.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would like to commend my friend and colleague from Florida (Mr. Hastings) for his work on this legislation. He has been a real leader in this bipartisan effort to enhance the Underground Railroad Network to Freedom Program. We support passage of <bill type="h" number="1239">H.R. 1239</bill>, as amended, and urge its adoption by the House today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mrs. McMorris Rodgers. Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="1239">H.R. 1239</bill>, and yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to commend the sponsor, the gentleman from Florida (Mr. Hastings), as well as the chairman of the subcommittee Mr. Grijalva, for explaining this bill. We appreciate the work that has been done to improve the bill, and look forward to see the program succeed. I urge Members' support.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield such time as he may consume to the gentleman from Florida (Mr. Hastings), the author and sponsor of this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400170" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in strong support of <bill type="h" number="1239">H.R. 1239</bill>, the National Underground Railroad Network to Freedom Reauthorization Act. I introduced this legislation with my good friend, the gentleman from Delaware (Mr. Castle).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The widespread bipartisan support this legislation has received with 67 cosponsors and endorsement by the National Parks Conservation Association has demonstrated that black history is synonymous with American history as life experience shared by all citizens of America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to thank Chairman Rahall and Mr. Don Young of the Natural Resources Committee for bringing this important legislation to the floor, and I would especially like to thank the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva), the subcommittee chairman, and his counterpart, Representative Rob Bishop, for their support. And my congratulations to Mrs. McMorris Rodgers on her recent addition to her family and her finding time to come and support this legislation  as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With passage of this legislation, I hope that the National Park Service will give the National Underground Railroad Network to Freedom its due priority with adequate staffing to maintain the growing network. Toward that end, I would also like to thank the staff of the respective committees who helped to expedite this matter.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, when I joined my esteemed former colleague, as did many other Members, and the person to whom I am referring is Representative Lou Stokes, in 1998, he led the effort to establish the National Underground Railroad to Freedom. I don't think any of us could have foreseen the emergence of the National Park Service as one of the largest stewards of black history in the United States. Nor could we have predicted the rapidly expanding support and interest for one of the most intriguing  multicultural collaborations in the history of our Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Network to Freedom is a key feature that diversifies engagement in interpretive opportunities of our National Park System. It has grown to 300 programs, sites, and partners in 28 States and the District of Columbia. This network is a national treasure of historic buildings, routes, programs, projects, and museums with thematic connections to the Underground Railroad.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation before us today appropriately adjusts the authorization levels for the Network to Freedom to reflect the growth of interest nationally, and the resulting expansion of opportunities. These adjustments will help to resolve the financial challenges facing the Network to Freedom that include the lack of consistent development grants and administrative support for affiliates.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this bill protects the interpretive interests of our National Park System by providing the necessary support staff and oversight for  the Network to Freedom to exist in perpetuity. It is time to take a stand for the future of our national parks and American history.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this bill and preserve a vital asset to the history of our Nation, the Underground Railroad.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in strong support of <bill type="h" number="1239">H.R. 1239</bill>, the National Underground Railroad Network to Freedom Reauthorization Act. I introduced this legislation in February with my good friend Representative Castle of Delaware as one contribution to the celebration of Black History Month.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The widespread bi-partisan support this legislation has received with 67 cosponsors and endorsement by the National Parks Conservation Association has demonstrated that Black history is synonymous with American history as a life experience shared by all citizens of America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to thank Chairman Rahall and Ranking Member Young of the Natural Resources Committee for bringing this important legislation to the floor. I would also like to thank Subcommittee Chairman Grijalva and Representative Rob Bishop for their support and minor adjustments to this legislation to meet the needs of the National Park Service administration. With passage of this legislation, I hope that the National Park Service will give the National Underground  Railroad Network to Freedom its due priority with adequate staffing to maintain the growing network.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, when I joined my esteemed former colleague Representative Louis Stokes in 1998 to establish the National Underground Railroad Network to Freedom, I do not think we could have foreseen the emergence of the National Park Service as one of the largest stewards of black history in the United Sates. Nor could we have predicted the rapidly expanding support and interest for one of the most intriguing multicultural collaborations in the history of our Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In this polarized historical moment of American politics, remembering the Underground Railroad as a unifying narrative in our history could not be timelier. The sacrifice at the risk of death made by conductors and travelers of the Underground Railroad was an unprecedented contribution to the abolition of slavery. The contributors to this network included the members of the Society of Religious Friends, commonly referred to as the Quakers, as well as other concerned individuals. Thus, the Underground  Railroad was one of the first synergistic partnerships that fostered the development of the thriving multicultural society that is the United States of America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the Network to Freedom is a key feature that diversifies engagement in interpretive opportunities of our national park system. It has grown to 300 programs, sites, and partners in 28 states and the District of Columbia. This network is a national treasure of historic buildings, routes, programs, projects, and museums with thematic connections to the Underground Railroad.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation before us today appropriately adjusts authorization levels for the Network to Freedom to reflect the growth of interest nationally and the resulting expansion of opportunities. As a part of a concerted movement to overcome the funding challenges that threaten all national parks, this legislation moderately expands the operating funds of Network to Freedom to an authorization for appropriations up to $2 million and establishes appropriate oversight for grant funds. These adjustments  will help to resolve the financial challenges facing the Network to Freedom that include the lack of consistent development grants and administrative support for affiliates.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this bill will protect the interpretive interests of our National Park System by providing the necessary support staff and oversight for the Network to Freedom to exist in perpetuity. It is time to take a stand for the future of our National Parks and American history.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this bill and join me in preserving a vital asset to the history of our Nation: the Underground Railroad.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="1239">H.R. 1239</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the bill, as amended, was passed.</chair>
  <chair>The title was amended so as to read: "A bill to amend the National Underground Railroad Network to Freedom Act of 1998 to authorize additional funding to carry out the Act, and for other purposes.".</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
