<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1190736002" ordinal="42" title="PERSONAL EXPLANATION">
  <narrative>PERSONAL EXPLANATION -- (House of Representatives - September 25, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H10776]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400405" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on September 24, I was unavoidably detained and missed rollcall vote Nos. 891, 892, 893 and 894.</paragraph>
    <paragraph> Rollcall vote No. 891 was to suspend the Rules and agree to <bill type="hc" number="193">H. Con. Res. 193</bill>. Had I been present, I would have voted "yea."</paragraph>
    <paragraph> Rollcall vote No. 892 was to suspend the Rules and agree to <bill type="hr" number="668">H. Res. 668</bill>. Had I been present, I would have voted "yea."</paragraph>
    <paragraph> Rollcall vote No. 893 was to suspend the Rules and agree to <bill type="h" number="1199">H.R. 1199</bill>. Had I been present, I would have voted "yea."</paragraph>
    <paragraph> Rollcall vote No. 894 was to suspend the Rules and agree to <bill type="hr" number="340">H. Res. 340</bill>. Had I been present, I would have voted "yea."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, on September 25, I was unavoidably detained and missed rollcall vote Nos. 895, 896, 897, and 898.</paragraph>
    <paragraph> Rollcall vote No. 895 was to suspend the Rules and agree to <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill>. Had I been present, I would have voted "yea."</paragraph>
    <paragraph> Rollcall vote No. 896 was to suspend the Rules and agree to <bill type="hr" number="584">H. Res. 584</bill>. Had I been present, I would have voted "yea."</paragraph>
    <paragraph> Rollcall vote No. 897 was to suspend the Rules and agree to <bill type="hc" number="210">H. Con. Res. 210</bill>. Had I been present, I would have voted "yea."</paragraph>
    <paragraph> Rollcall vote No. 898 was to suspend the Rules and agree to <bill type="hr" number="663">H. Res. 663</bill>. Had I been present, I would have voted "yea."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would ask that my statement appear in the appropriate location in the CONGRESSIONAL RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
