<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1189440002" ordinal="23" title="ROBERT MERRILL POSTAL STATION">
  <narrative>ROBERT MERRILL POSTAL STATION -- (House of Representatives - September 10, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H10331]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="2778">H.R. 2778</bill>) to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 3 Quaker Ridge Road in New Rochelle, New York, as the "Robert Merrill Postal Station".</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="2778">H.R. 2778</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. ROBERT MERRILL POSTAL STATION.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Designation.--The facility of the United States Postal Service located at 3 Quaker Ridge Road in New Rochelle, New York, shall be known and designated as the "Robert Merrill Postal Station".</narrative>
  <narrative> (b) References.--Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the facility referred to in subsection (a) shall be deemed to be a reference to the "Robert Merrill Postal Station".&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Davis) and the gentleman from Idaho (Mr. Sali) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Illinois.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days in which to revise and extend their remarks.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Illinois?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, it is my pleasure to yield such time as she might consume to the distinguished gentlelady from New York, who is the author of this legislation, Representative NITA LOWEY.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400246" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in strong support of this legislation, which would rename the Wykagyl Post Office in New Rochelle, New York after Robert Merrill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank Chairman Waxman for his support of this bill and for placing it on the suspension calendar today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Born on June 4, 1919, Robert Merrill spent his life performing from the grand stages of the world's opera houses to Broadway and music and television. He set the standard for theatrical and musical excellence.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Robert Merrill was a favorite of U.S. Presidents, performing at the invitation of Franklin Delano Roosevelt, Harry Truman and Ronald Reagan. He was the only singer to perform before Congress, the Cabinet and the Supreme Court, and Mrs. Roosevelt at the Franklin Delano Roosevelt memorial service held in the U.S. Capitol.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1968, President Johnson appointed him to the National Council on the Arts, and President Clinton awarded him the National Medal of Arts in 1993.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Throughout his career, Merrill performed as a soloist with every major orchestra in the United States and many of the world's great conductors, including Arturo Toscanini, Leonard Bernstein and Herbert von Karajan. His annual coast-to-coast recitals included performances at such venues as Wolf Trap, the Hollywood Bowl, Philadelphia's Mann Music Center.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Often referred to as "America's Star Spangled Baritone," he was well known for singing the "Star Spangled Banner" at Yankee Stadium. In 1969, Merrill began singing the national anthem on opening day for the New York Yankees, a tradition that continued for over 25 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to his dedicated singing career, Robert Merrill also lent his talent and presence to community and local charities, including volunteer work at the New Rochelle Hospital and New Rochelle Public Library.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For over 50 years, Robert and his wife, Marion, made New Rochelle, New York their home and were active supporters of West Chester Community College, the West Chester Arts Council and the New Rochelle Arts Council.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, Robert Merrill spread his talents and love for the arts all over the country, enriching all who experienced his performances. I urge my colleagues to join me in honoring this great American by passing this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412201" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We do rise today to honor a truly great artist in the field of opera. Robert Merrill, the highly acclaimed baritone singer was well known for his remarkable career with the Metropolitan Opera.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He was born and raised in Brooklyn, New York, son of Polish immigrants, and he was first inspired to perform as a singer after watching a performance of Il Trovatore as a teenager. His mother guided him through his early musical training, which he paid for by working as a semiprofessional baseball pitcher.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An avid baseball fan, he became widely known for his annual singing of the national anthem at Yankee Stadium on opening day and for special events, a tradition he carried on for over 30 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>His legendary performances at the Metropolitan Opera brought him national fame and recognition in the arts and the opportunity to perform with other notable singers and entertainers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He performed for numerous presidents, including Franklin D. Roosevelt, Harry S. Truman, Dwight D. Eisenhower and John F. Kennedy. Throughout his career, he performed as a soloist with some of the world's greatest conductors, made numerous recordings, and appeared at several worldwide music festivals. Outside of the stage performances, he also ventured into radio and television.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Robert Merrill enjoyed a successful career in performing music for over 30 years. His velvety smooth voice was said to have improved with every performance. He retired from the opera in 1976, and made one final performance in 1983 for its centennial.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1968, he was appointed to the National Council on the Arts by President Johnson and was awarded the National Medal of the Arts in 1993.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He died at the age of 85 while watching his favorite pastime, baseball, at his home in New Rochelle, New York. It is appropriate that we honor him with the naming of a post office in his beloved hometown.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I might consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, as a member of the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, I'm pleased to join my colleague in the consideration of <bill type="h" number="2778">H.R. 2778</bill>, which names the postal facility in New Rochelle, New York after Robert Merrill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2778">H.R. 2778</bill>, which was introduced by Representative Nita Lowey on June 19, 2007, was reported from the Oversight Committee on August 1, 2007, by voice vote. This measure has the support of the entire New York congressional delegation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, Mr. Robert Merrill was born on June 14, 1917, in the New York City borough of Brooklyn. As a teenager, he dreamed of either playing professional baseball or becoming one of America's top singers. In 1944, he made his professional debut singing Amonasro in "Aida" on a Trenton, New Jersey stage. A year later, he signed with the Metropolitan Opera, where he would sing more than 500 performances over the course of 3 decades.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Throughout Mr. Merrill's career, he sang with popular stars ranging from Frank Sinatra to Louis Armstrong and appeared worldwide at music festivals. He performed as a soloist with many of the world's great conductors, including Leonard Bernstein.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Merrill performed for several presidents, including President Franklin D. Roosevelt, President Harry S. Truman, President Dwight D. Eisenhower and President John F. Kennedy.  He died on October 23, 2004, at the age of 85.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I commend my colleague, Representative Nita Lowey, for introducing this legislation that highlights the career of one of America's most talented artists. I commend her for this introduction and urge its passage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412201" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Davis) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="2778">H.R. 2778</bill>.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the bill was passed.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
