<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1173114004" ordinal="32" title="TEXAS INDEPENDENCE DAY">
  <speaking speaker="400160" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, last Friday, March 2, 2007, marked Texas Independence Day. 171 years ago that day the Texas Declaration of Independence was ratified by the Convention of 1836 at Washington-on-the-Brazos in Texas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Texas Declaration of Independence was produced literally overnight. Its urgency was paramount because while it was being prepared, the Alamo in San Antonio was under siege by Santa Anna's army of Mexico.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Immediately upon the assemblage of the Convention of 1836 on March 1, a committee of five delegates were appointed to draft the document. The committee consisted of George C. Childress, Edward Conrad, James Gaines, Bailey Hardeman, and Colin McKinney. It was briefly reviewed then adopted by the delegates the following day.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It started off echoing the lines of the American counterpart with the words: "When a government has ceased to protect the lives and liberty and property of the people ..... "</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It spoke of numerous injustices inflicted upon the people of the State,  then known as Coahuila y Tejas: the elimination of the State's legislative body; the denial of religious freedom; the elimination of the civil justice system; and the confiscation of firearms, which was one particularly intolerable act among Texans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, it stated that because of the injustice of Santa Anna's tyrannical government, Texans were severing their connection with the Mexican nation and declaring themselves "a free, sovereign, and independent republic ..... fully invested with all the rights and attributes" that belong to independent nations; and a declaration that they "fearlessly and confidently" committed their decision to "the Supreme Arbiter of the destinies of nations."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I hope that Congress and this whole country join all Texans in honoring these brave men who stood up for liberty and freedom 171 years ago.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
