<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1193673602" ordinal="43" title="HONORING LIEUTENANT MICHAEL P. MURPHY">
  <narrative>HONORING LIEUTENANT MICHAEL P. MURPHY -- (House of Representatives - October 29, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H12135]</narrative>
  <chair> Under a previous order of the House, the gentleman from Pennsylvania (Mr. Dent) is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400648" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I just want to follow up on what my friend Mr. Bishop of New York has just said.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We all learned about Lieutenant Michael Murphy's bravery. And, of course, last week, as was just stated, he received the Congressional Medal of Honor from President Bush on October 22.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also want to share with you an experience over the weekend prior to the  Penn State/Ohio State game on Saturday evening. We had a ceremony on the field of Beaver Stadium, 110,000 people. Of course Lieutenant Murphy is a Penn State alumnus and graduated from the university in political science, as I did about 17 years earlier. And we had a ceremony. It was touching to be with his parents, Dan and Maureen, to recognize his gallantry, his bravery. As  Abraham Lincoln said, he had given that "last full measure of devotion."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But we joined his parents on the field, myself along with our colleagues, Tim Murphy of Pennsylvania, Bill Shuster of Pennsylvania and Todd Platts of Pennsylvania. We escorted them on the field, along with the president of the university, Graham Spanier. And just prior to the playing of the national anthem, which was dedicated in memory of Lieutenant Murphy, the university presented a certificate that read: "Pennsylvania State University recognizes Lieutenant Michael  Murphy as the recipient of the Medal of Honor, for his gallantry and bravery, serving as a United States Navy SEAL while under enemy attack in Afghanistan. Lieutenant Murphy represents the highest ideal of the university as an alumnus and patriot."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And, again, I would just like to share with my colleagues from New York, and certainly all Americans, the sense of deep loss we feel for the Murphy family and so many others who have paid the ultimate price in this war, in both Afghanistan and Iraq.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
