<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1212595202" ordinal="30" title="THOMAS JEFFERSON CENSUS BUREAU HEADQUARTERS BUILDING">
  <narrative>THOMAS JEFFERSON CENSUS BUREAU HEADQUARTERS BUILDING -- (House of Representatives - June 04, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H4890]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400204" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="5599">H.R. 5599</bill>) to designate the Federal building located at 4600 Silver Hill Road in Suitland, Maryland, as the "Thomas Jefferson Census Bureau Headquarters Building".</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="5599">H.R. 5599</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. FINDINGS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Congress finds that--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) Thomas Jefferson, as Secretary of State in 1790, supervised the first modern census in world history;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) the 1790 census was the first national census in the United States and the first periodic census in the modern nation-state era;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) Jefferson urged President Washington to veto the first apportionment bill presented by Congress on the grounds that it was unconstitutional, and Jefferson's own apportionment formula was adopted and used until 1840;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) Jefferson's mastery of numbers and statistical analysis helped alert the Nation to the importance of accuracy in the numbers used to describe the society and pointed to methods that later improved census taking;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) Jefferson offered population corrections to the European diplomatic community to more accurately convey the fast-growing United States population, which had been undercounted in previous census taking;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (6) Jefferson believed in the importance of territorial expansion and insisted on equal representation for the territories that were to join the Union as States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (7) Jefferson supervised the first census in world history that gave to the people more than it took from them, being designed less to extract taxes or raise a militia than to apportion political power to the people of the United States according to their numbers; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (8) Jefferson's role in establishing a republic based on principles of representation underscores the historical significance of the United States census and the way the Government views and governs itself today.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. DESIGNATION.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; The Federal building located at 4600 Silver Hill Road in Suitland, Maryland, shall be known and designated as the "Thomas Jefferson Census Bureau Headquarters Building".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 3. REFERENCES.</narrative>
  <narrative> Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the Federal building referred to in section 2 shall be deemed to be a reference to the "Thomas Jefferson Census Bureau Headquarters Building".&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from Texas (Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson) and the gentleman from New York (Mr. Kuhl) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentlewoman from Texas.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400204" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days within which to revise and extend their remarks and to include extraneous materials on <bill type="h" number="5599">H.R. 5599</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from Texas?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400204" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield myself such time as I might consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, <bill type="h" number="5599">H.R. 5599</bill> is a bill to designate the Federal building in Suitland, Maryland, as the Thomas Jefferson Census Bureau Headquarters Building. The bill has bipartisan support.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although Thomas Jefferson is best remembered as the third President of the United States, as the author of the Declaration of Independence, he also is considered by some to be the first director of the U.S. census.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1790, while Secretary of State, Jefferson conducted the first national census. Although the practice of performing a census has been in practice for thousands of years, the U.S. census in considered to be the first modern periodic census. Several European countries followed suit shortly after in the early 19th century.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, the results of the census are used to determine the size of congressional districts, the allocation of seats allotted to each State in the U.S. House of Representatives, as a factor in the allocation of Federal resources, and perhaps most importantly as a research tool to track economic and population trends in the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is most fitting and proper that we support this designation and honor one of Jefferson's numerous contributions to our Nation's history. I support <bill type="h" number="5599">H.R. 5599</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400642" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="5599">H.R. 5599</bill> names the new Census Bureau headquarters building in Suitland, Maryland, as the Thomas Jefferson Census Bureau Headquarters Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As the first Secretary of State, Thomas Jefferson was a strong advocate of a national census, and he supervised the first census in 1790. Early population estimates misjudged the number of Americans in many areas, unfortunately, and it resulted in underrepresentation in many areas of this country in the first Congress. Under Jefferson's leadership, however, the census developed into a more useful and accurate process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thomas Jefferson's advocacy for a complete and accurate census land laid the foundation for the Census Bureau we have today. He believed that an accurate census was essential to ensure that the government represented its people effectively. So it is fitting that the new census building bear his name, and I support the bill and urge its adoption and applaud my colleague, Representative Maloney, on bringing it before the House for its adoption today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But while we debate these matters, the issue persists, and that is the high cost of gasoline. And this Congress continues to ignore the rising cost of gasoline. American workers are struggling to fill up their tanks, and this Congress has done nothing to ease that burden. The Democratic majority has failed to provide the real leadership in addressing the high cost of fuel which requires an increased supply, American supply.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thank you, Madam Speaker, for an opportunity to speak on this.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400204" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield 3 minutes to the gentlelady from New York (Mrs. Maloney).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400251" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I thank my colleague for yielding and for her leadership in this Congress, and I rise in strong support of my bill <bill type="h" number="5599">H.R. 5599</bill>, a bill to designate the Census Bureau headquarters Federal building for Founding Father Thomas Jefferson.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Census Bureau has just been relocated to a modern state-of-the-art building in Suitland, Maryland. I want to thank Chairman Oberstar and Congresswoman Holmes Norton for their help in moving this bill forward.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I introduced this legislation along with colleagues that have been strong supporters of an accurate census--Holmes Norton, Hoyer, Davis, Turner, Ruppersberger, Honda, Gonzalez, Wynn, Cohen, and Cannon--to honor Thomas Jefferson's contributions to the modern census and the Founding Fathers' vision of a truly representative government in which every American counts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Jefferson's role in establishing a republic based on the principle of fair  representation emphasizes the historical significance of the American census and the way our government views and governs itself today. Jefferson's significant contributions to the early American census include his alerting the Nation to the importance of accuracy in census taking and his recognition of the need to fully represent newly acquired territories in the census.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Historically, census taking was a negative thing. It was used for raising taxes for the militia. Thomas Jefferson, as Secretary of State, oversaw the first census in history, which was positive, which gave the people more than it took away by empowering those counted with a voice in their government.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As we have heard in recent weeks, the 2010 census has some very serious challenges. Although much work remains to be done to ensure its successful implementation, naming this building for Thomas Jefferson underscores this Congress' commitment to getting it right and making sure that every citizen is counted.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>A fair and accurate census, putting political power in the hands of the people, is a uniquely American invention. Let us honor our Founding Fathers' legacy by celebrating Thomas Jefferson, the father of the modern census.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="5599">H.R. 5599</bill>, a bill to designate the Federal building located at 4600 Silver Hill Road in Suitland, Maryland, as the "Thomas Jefferson Census Bureau Headquarters Building".</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The United States census is a count of the Nation's population, conducted every 10 years. The results are used for various purposes, including allocation of congressional seats and impacting Government program funding for States and localities. The U.S. Census Bureau is responsible for conducting the census and serves "as the leading source of quality data about the Nation's people and economy," according to its mission.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The census is our Nation's longest continuous scientific project. In 1790, while Secretary of State, Thomas Jefferson conducted the first official count of the Nation's population. Census Day was August 2, 1790. The national census has several colonial predecessors with eight of the original 13 colonies having conducted their own census.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>President Jefferson not only was one of our Founding Fathers and the third President of the United States, but he was also an early demographer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Therefore, it is fitting and proper that we designate this Federal building as the "Thomas Jefferson Census Bureau Headquarters Building".</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to join me in supporting <bill type="h" number="5599">H.R. 5599</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400642" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time and encourage my colleagues to vote in support of this resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400204" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I have no further requests for time, and I move the passage of this resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from Texas (Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="5599">H.R. 5599</bill>.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the bill was passed.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
