<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1196787602" ordinal="22" title="VALIDATING CONVEYANCES MADE BY THE UNION PACIFIC RAILROAD COMPANY">
  <narrative>VALIDATING CONVEYANCES MADE BY THE UNION PACIFIC RAILROAD COMPANY -- (House of Representatives - December 04, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H14095]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="2246">H.R. 2246</bill>) to validate certain conveyances made by the Union Pacific Railroad Company of lands located in Reno, Nevada, that were originally conveyed by the United States to facilitate construction of transcontinental railroads, and for other purposes, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="2246">H.R. 2246</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. RAILROAD LANDS DEFINED.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; For the purposes of this Act, the term "railroad lands" means those lands within the City of Reno, Nevada, located within portions of sections 10, 11, and 12 of T.19 N., R. 19 E., and portions of section 7 of T.19 N., R. 20 E., Mount Diablo Meridian, Nevada, that were originally granted to the Union Pacific Railroad under the provisions of the Act of July 1, 1862, commonly known as the Union Pacific Railroad Act.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. RELEASE OF REVERSIONARY INTEREST.</narrative>
  <narrative>  Any reversionary interests of the United States (including interests under the Act of July 1, 1862, commonly known as the Union Pacific Railroad Act) in and to the railroad lands as defined in section one of this Act are hereby released.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from Guam (Ms. Bordallo) and the gentlewoman from Washington (Mrs. McMorris Rodgers) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentlewoman from Guam.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from Guam?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the Union Pacific Railroad operates a rail line through downtown Reno, Nevada. Like similar corridors across the West, the rail line was created on Federal land in the 19th century to facilitate development of a transcontinental rail system. The grant to the railroad includes a requirement that the land revert back to Federal ownership should it ever be abandoned by the railroad.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The City of Reno has undertaken a massive project to move approximately two miles of the rail line into a concrete trench constructed alongside the existing track to improve safety and traffic flow through downtown. As part of the project, the railroad apparently conveyed portions of the right-of-way to the city for construction of the trench. It is not clear whether Union Pacific had authority to make such a conveyance given the Federal reversionary interest. <bill type="h" number="2246">H.R. 2246</bill>, as amended, would simply  release any Federal reversionary interest in the specific parcels involved in the project. So given the City's enormous investment in this project and that the parcels in question will continue to be used for purposes related to the operation of the rail line, clearing title to these parcels is appropriate. So I urge all of our colleagues to support <bill type="h" number="2246">H.R. 2246</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mrs." name="RODGERS, McMORRIS" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the gentlewoman from Guam has explained the bill very well. I thank her, as well as Chairman Grijalva, for working with us to move this legislation out of committee and through the House.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to recognize the sponsor of this legislation, Congressman DEAN HELLER from Nevada, and yield him such time as he may consume.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="412218" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of <bill type="h" number="2246">H.R. 2246</bill>, which will resolve outdated Federal reversionary interests in land important to the City of Reno, Nevada, which I represent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The reversionary interest concerns a rail line that goes through downtown Reno. The City of Reno and the Union Pacific/Southern Pacific join together to submerge a portion of the track below street level as a result of merger between the two railroads.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As part of the project, known as RETRAC, the railroad agreed to grant the City of Reno title to the land immediately surrounding the right-of-way for the project within the city. This bill assists in the revitalization and economic development in this community.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Title for these lands was originally granted to the railroad in 1866 to facilitate construction of a transcontinental rail system. However, when the United States granted the right-of-way to the railroad, it retained a reversionary interest in the land to ensure that it was, in fact, used to facilitate the building of the railroad. This purpose obviously was satisfied many years ago.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This reversionary interest is an obsolete restriction on the title of the land granted to the City of Reno, and <bill type="h" number="2246">H.R. 2246</bill> instructs the Secretary of the Interior to release the reversionary interest originally created in 1866.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I appreciate the chairman of the committee, and also Chairman Grijalva and his staff, for the work they have done on this legislation. I also want to thank Reno Mayor Cashell, who came out to Washington to testify on this piece of legislation, and the City of Reno for their continued support and the efforts by their citizens. I would encourage all of my colleagues to support this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mrs." name="RODGERS, McMORRIS" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time, and I want to thank the gentlewoman from Washington (Mrs. McMorris Rodgers) for co-managing our bills today from the Resources Committee.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from Guam (Ms. Bordallo) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="2246">H.R. 2246</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the bill, as amended, was passed.</chair>
  <chair>The title was amended so as to read: "A bill to provide for the release of any reversionary interest of the United States in and to certain lands in Reno, Nevada.".</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
