<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1197910803" ordinal="21" title="CONVEYANCES UNDER FLORIDA NATIONAL FOREST LAND MANAGEMENT ACT OF 2003">
  <narrative>CONVEYANCES UNDER FLORIDA NATIONAL FOREST LAND MANAGEMENT ACT OF 2003 -- (House of Representatives - December 17, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H15475]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400316" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="1374">H.R. 1374</bill>) to amend the Florida National Forest Land Management Act of 2003 to authorize the conveyance of an additional tract of National Forest System land under that Act, and for other purposes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="1374">H.R. 1374</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. CONVEYANCES UNDER FLORIDA NATIONAL FOREST LAND MANAGEMENT ACT OF 2003.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Additional Conveyance Authorized.--Subsection (b) of section 3 of the Florida National Forest Land Management Act of 2003 (Public Law 108-152; 117 Stat. 1919) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) by striking "and" at the end of paragraph (17);&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) by redesignating paragraph (18) as paragraph (19);&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) by inserting after paragraph (17) the following new paragraph:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(18) tract W-1979, located in Leon County consisting of approximately 114 acres, within T. 1 S., R. 1 W., sec. 25; and"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) in paragraph (19), as so redesignated, by striking "(17)" and inserting "(18)".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Additional Use of Proceeds.--Paragraph (2) of subsection (i) of such section (117 Stat. 1921) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) by striking "and" at the end of subparagraph (A);&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) by striking the period at the end of subparagraph (B) and inserting "; and"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(C) acquisition, construction, or maintenance of administrative improvements for units of the National Forest System in the State.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Limitations on Use of Proceeds.--Subsection (i) of such section is further amended by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(3) GEOGRAPHICAL AND USE RESTRICTION FOR CERTAIN CONVEYANCE.--Notwithstanding paragraph (2), proceeds from the sale or exchange of the tract described in subsection (b)(18) shall be used exclusively for the purchase of inholdings in the Apalachicola National Forest.</narrative>
  <narrative> "(4) RESTRICTION ON USE OF PROCEEDS FOR ADMINISTRATIVE IMPROVEMENTS.--Proceeds from any sale or exchange of land under this Act may be used for administrative improvements, as authorized by paragraph (2)(C), only if the land generating the proceeds was improved with infrastructure.".&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Minnesota (Mr. Peterson) and the gentlewoman from North Carolina (Ms. Foxx) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Minnesota.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400316" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="1374">H.R. 1374</bill>. <bill type="h" number="1374">H.R. 1374</bill>, introduced by Representatives Allen Boyd of Florida and Ander Crenshaw of Florida, would amend the Florida National Forest Land Management Act of 2003 and permit a land conveyance in Leon County. This bill would allow the United States Forest Service to sell a 114-acre parcel in the Apalachicola National Forest known as the "Flea Market Tract." The parcel is surrounded by commercial development, including a major highway to the  north, a power line easement to the south, and private land primarily developed to the east and west.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The configuration and development makes adequate land management difficult and the tract unsuitable as managed forest land. <bill type="h" number="1374">H.R. 1374</bill> specifies that the proceeds of the sale of the tract be used for the purpose of acquiring private lands within the Apalachicola National Forest.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1374">H.R. 1374</bill> is supported by the United States Forest Service, the City of Tallahassee, and Leon County, as well as by local businesses, church and civic groups. It is a project that is worthy of congressional support.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400643" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would like to echo the sentiments of my colleague and express support for <bill type="h" number="1374">H.R. 1374</bill>, which authorizes the sale of 114 acres in the Apalachicola National Forest in Florida, the proceeds of which can be used only to purchase private inholdings from willing sellers. <bill type="h" number="1374">H.R. 1374</bill> passed the Agriculture Committee last week by a voice vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The land proposed for sale is a small tract that is extremely difficult for the U.S. Forest Service to manage, given its proximity to the City of Tallahassee and the surrounding development. Properties such as this, which contribute little to meeting the Forest Service mission, unfortunately diverts scarce resources from other lands that need management.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to relieving the Forest Service of the management problems this tract creates, the bill will also help the agency reduce the number of private inholdings within the forest if the private owners are interested in selling. Inholdings are a common problem throughout many national forests in the East and create significant access and management issues for the landowners and the agency.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge adoption of this bipartisan legislation, and reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400316" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I now would yield such time as he may consume to the author of the bill, Mr. Boyd from Florida.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Mr. BOYD of Florida asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400044" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I want to thank my friend, the distinguished chairman of the House Agriculture Committee, Mr. Peterson, for granting me time to speak on behalf of this legislation and also thank him and the ranking member, Mr. Goodlatte,  and his representative for supporting this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the Apalachicola National Forest is the largest of Florida's three national forests. It contains 564,000 acres, and its rivers and streams provide a steady freshwater flow to some of the most productive coastal bays and estuaries known for shellfish and other commercial seafood. Portions of the forest are in wet lowlands and they abound with cypress, oak and magnolias. Watching wildlife, hunting and fishing are popular recreation activities in this beautiful national forest. Visitors  to the forest also enjoy swimming, picnicking, boating, and camping.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Apalachicola National Forest is truly a national treasure, and I am very proud that this legislation will help strengthen and sustain one of our Nation's most valuable natural assets.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As the chairman and the ranking member have said, this enables the national forest to sell a piece of property that really lies right on the south side of Tallahassee, Florida, in Leon County. It actually comes up to the beltway, or what we call the Capital Circle and is surrounded on three sides by commercial development. It is detached from the rest of the national forest, and so it is really, as you have heard earlier, an unmanageable piece of land. And with those proceeds, we are going to  use the proceeds to go and purchase some privately held holdings within the confines of the 564,000 acres, what we commonly know as "inholdings," and that is the only purpose that those funds can be used for. There are about 2,000 acres of inholdings, privately held lands within the Apalachicola National Forest, and that is what those funds, Mr. Speaker, would be used for.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank Mr. Joe Baca, the Forestry Subcommittee chairman, and his staff director, Lisa Shelton, for helping guide this legislation through the subcommittee process. And also I want to thank my friend, the majority leader, Mr. Hoyer, for scheduling. I encourage our colleagues to pass this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400643" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400316" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Minnesota (Mr. Peterson) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="1374">H.R. 1374</bill>.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the bill was passed.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
