<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1179871463" ordinal="32" title="AUTHORIZING THE PRINTING OF A COMMEMORATIVE DOCUMENT IN MEMORY OF THE LATE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES, GERALD RUDOLPH FORD">
  <speaking speaker="400047" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and agree to the concurrent resolution (<bill type="hc" number="128">H. Con. Res. 128</bill>) authorizing the printing of a commemorative document in memory of the late President of the United States, Gerald Rudolph Ford.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the concurrent resolution.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Pennsylvania (Mr. Brady) and the gentleman from Michigan (Mr. Ehlers) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400047" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members have 5 legislative days within which to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on this concurrent resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Pennsylvania?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400047" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this resolution provides for the printing of a memorial tribute to honor our late 38th President, Gerald R. Ford. A former minority leader of this House, President Ford died on December 26, 2006, at the age of 93. Our distinguished colleague from Michigan (Mr. Ehlers), who now represents Gerald Ford's former district, introduced this resolution. The measure takes the same form as that passed after President Reagan's death in 2004. I support the gentleman's resolution, and  I thank him for sponsoring it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, since President Ford's death, Americans have expressed their respect and gratitude for his remarkable career that took him into the Navy during World War II, to this House, to the Vice Presidency, and then to the White House. In the aftermath of the ordeal of Watergate, many consider President Ford, then and now, as the right man at the right time. It is fitting that Congress provide for this customary tribute, and I urge the House to adopt the concurrent resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400119" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in strong support of House Concurrent Resolution 128, authorizing the printing of a commemorative document in memory of the late President of the United States, Gerald R. Ford.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It was an honor for me to serve as a scientific adviser to Congressman Ford in the late 1960s and early 1970s, and I then came to know President Ford in many capacities throughout the years. I now have the privilege of serving the people of Grand Rapids and western Michigan in the exact seat he held from 1949 until 1973, and I am now most pleased to recognize one of the great sons of the State of Michigan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although President Ford's life ambition was to become Speaker of this esteemed body, fate and the Lord had other plans for Jerry Ford. While he was not a man who sought the Presidency, Ford was a tireless public servant who did not shrink from duty when his country needed him most. He bore the mantle that had been thrust upon him with great humility, never forgetting the solid Michigan values that were his compass in the most trying of times.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When he ascended to the Presidency upon President Nixon's resignation in 1974, Ford served with honor and dignity, telling us that "our long national nightmare is over." He was recommended and approved for his position by people in Congress who knew him very well. In fact, I believe he is the only President of the past one and a half centuries who served as the choice of the Members of Congress. Their trust in him aided him in governing and leading our Nation out of that nightmare. In pardoning  President Nixon, he essentially gave up any chance he had of a second term as  President; but, in doing so, he literally healed the Nation. And I recall a very personal discussion with him one time where he said he knew full well that he would likely lose the election, because of the pardon, but he saw no alternative but to pardon President Nixon in order to put the whole Watergate episode behind us and get the Nation moving again.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am privileged, and I have always felt a sense of honor, to be serving in the same House seat that Congressman Ford served. By publishing this book, we will educate future generations about the contributions of a great man who came from ordinary beginnings yet found himself performing well in extraordinary circumstances. Jerry Ford personified the many good traits that west Michigan has to offer our Nation, with his honesty, his forthrightness, and his hard work. And I urge my colleagues to  support the creation of this commemorative volume. I urge strong support of this resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400047" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I join my colleague from Michigan in support of this fitting tribute for our late President Ford. I urge the House to support the resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400119" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Pennsylvania (Mr. Brady) that the House suspend the rules and agree to the concurrent resolution, <bill type="hc" number="128">H. Con. Res. 128</bill>.</chair>
</record>
