<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1196960402" ordinal="11" title="HONORING THE LIFE OF JONI HERSCHEDE">
  <narrative>HONORING THE LIFE OF JONI HERSCHEDE -- (House of Representatives - December 06, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H14254]</narrative>
  <narrative>(Mrs. SCHMIDT asked and was given permission to address the House for 1 minute and to revise and extend her remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412010" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today to honor the life of Joni Herschede, a true icon of Cincinnati.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Joni understood the Second Congressional District. You see, she grew up in Portsmouth in rural southern Ohio, one of eight siblings. She came to Cincinnati in the 1960s where she met and married Mark Herschede. She will always be best known for her passion and generosity to this community.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Joni never forgot her humble beginnings. Whenever Joni got behind a cause or an issue, others always followed because they knew if you didn't follow, you might as well get out of the way because she would succeed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is nearly impossible to find an organization in southern Ohio to which Joni did not give her time or her energy. Her son Donald said, "Mother wasn't happy unless she was doing something for someone else."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Her true passion was the University of Cincinnati. As an avid Bearcats fan, Joni's hats and outfits always proudly displayed her beloved red and black. But that passion went beyond just trappings of her clothing. It went to the philanthropy that she did for the University of Cincinnati as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, southern Ohio and Cincinnati will always be grateful for the kindness that Joni showed to so many and to so many organizations, the arts, the zoo, education, and her beloved Bearcats.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Joni's life should paint a path for future generations. Joni's legacy of public service will not be easily surpassed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>May she rest in peace.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
