<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1182182403" ordinal="19" title="DR. FRANCIS TOWNSEND POST OFFICE BUILDING">
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the Senate bill (<bill type="s" number="1352">S. 1352</bill>) to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 127 East Locust Street in Fairbury, Illinois, as the "Dr. Francis Townsend Post Office Building".</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the Senate bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Davis) and the gentleman from Idaho (Mr. Sali) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days in which to revise and extend their remarks.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Illinois?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself as much time as I might consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a member of the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, I am pleased to join my colleague in consideration of <bill type="s" number="1352">S. 1352</bill>, which names a postal facility in Fairbury, Illinois, after Dr. Francis Townsend.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="1352">S. 1352</bill>, which was introduced by Senator RICHARD DURBIN on May 10, 2007, was reported from the Oversight Committee on June 12, 2007 by a voice vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dr. Francis Townsend was born in 1867 into an impoverished Illinois farming family. Shortly after he was born, his family moved to Nebraska, where he graduated from high school and began a varied career. He tried farming and selling in Kansas, land speculation in Los Angeles, and worked as a laborer in Colorado.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1899, he enrolled in the Omaha Medical College, and graduated in 1903 at the age of 36. He served as an Army doctor in World War I and during the Great Depression, and took a job as the assistant director of the City Health Office in Long Beach, California. At the age of 66, Dr. Townsend lost his job and found himself both poor and out of work.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There were millions of elderly people just like him who were barely making ends meet. One day he had a vision of how to help the elderly and the country as a whole. He wrote a letter to a newspaper outlining his "old-aged pension plan for seniors." This plan created a Federal pension of $200 a month paid to every citizen 60 and older on the condition that the pensioner spend the entire sum within 30 days in order to stimulate the economy. His efforts influenced the passage of President Franklin  D. Roosevelt's Social Security Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I commend my colleague from Illinois, Senator RICHARD DURBIN, for introducing this legislation, and I urge swift passage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412201" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today to honor one of Fairbury, Illinois' most famous citizens, and that was Dr. Francis Townsend. He was an American physician best known for creating the Townsend Old-age Revolving Pension plan and for spurring social movement that advocated for benefits for the elderly during the 1930s.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dr. Townsend, the son of a farmer, grew up in Fairbury, Illinois, and attended Omaha Medical College in 1917. Shortly after becoming a physician, he served in the Army Medical Corps during World War I. After leaving the Army, he began a medical practice in Long Beach, California. When this was not successful, he obtained employment as the assistant city health director. Sadly, due to the Great Depression, he lost that job and was forced into retirement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1933, Dr. Townsend witnessed something extremely heartbreaking but not uncommon during the Great Depression when he saw three old ladies searching through trash cans in his back alley for food. This became a watershed moment for the doctor. In response to what he observed, and his inner drive to help others, he decided to become involved in politics. Later that year he created the Townsend Plan, which proposed creating a Federal pension of $200 a month for every citizen 60 years old and older  on the condition that the money would be spent within 30 days in order to stimulate the economy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By 1934, through his leadership and determination to help the downtrodden, the plan generated a great deal of support and gave rise to the establishment of at least 5,000 "Townsend clubs" nationwide. At the height of popularity, membership in the clubs totaled over 2 million people.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By 1935, an additional 25 million Americans signed petitions to Congress  and the White House supporting the implementation of Dr. Townsend's plan. He became such a national celebrity by this time that he testified before Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thanks to Dr. Townsend's efforts, his social crusades sparked a national antipoverty movement in 1933 that likely contributed to the expedited passage of Franklin D. Roosevelt's Social Security Act of 1935, one of the major initiatives of the New Deal.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dr. Townsend was a steadfast leader and original thinker. His efforts to fight poverty during our Nation's worst economic crisis and his exemplary civic activism are an example for us all.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Naming the Fairbury, Illinois, post office after one of its most famous citizens during the sesquicentennial anniversary of Fairbury is a fitting celebration of both Dr. Townsend's contributions to the city and to this important milestone.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would just close by noting that here is an excellent example of a citizen with an idea, an idea that was promulgated into legislation, legislation that all of us, if we live to be 65 or somewhat close to, benefit from. And so I think it is indeed appropriate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, I want to thank Senator Durbin for introducing this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Davis) that the House suspend the rules and pass the Senate bill, <bill type="s" number="1352">S. 1352</bill>.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this question will be postponed.</chair>
</record>
