<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1214409602" ordinal="67" title="A REVISION TO THE BUDGET ALLOCATIONS, AGGREGATES, OR OTHER APPROPRIATE LEVELS FOR FISCAL YEARS 2008 AND 2009 AND THE PERIOD OF FISCAL YEARS 2009 THROUGH 2013">
  <narrative>A REVISION TO THE BUDGET ALLOCATIONS, AGGREGATES, OR OTHER APPROPRIATE LEVELS FOR FISCAL YEARS 2008 AND 2009 AND THE PERIOD OF FISCAL YEARS 2009 THROUGH 2013 -- (House of Representatives - June 25, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H6086]</narrative>
  <chair> Under a previous order of the House, the gentleman from South Carolina (Mr. Spratt) is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, under section 207 of <bill type="sc" number="70">S. Con. Res. 70</bill>, the Concurrent Resolution on the Budget for fiscal year 2009, I hereby submit for printing in the Congressional Record a revision to the budget allocations, aggregates, or other appropriate levels for certain House committees for fiscal years 2008 and 2009 and the period of fiscal years 2009 through 2013. This revision represents an adjustment to certain House committee budget allocations, aggregates, and other appropriate  levels for the purposes of sections 302 and 311 of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974, as amended, and in response to consideration of the bill <bill type="h" number="6275">H.R. 6275</bill>, Alternative Minimum Tax Relief Act of 2008. Corresponding tables are attached.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under section 323 of <bill type="sc" number="70">S. Con. Res. 70</bill>, this adjustment to the budget allocations and aggregates applies while the measure is under consideration. The adjustments will take effect upon enactment of the measure. For purposes of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974, as amended, a revised allocation under section 323 of <bill type="sc" number="70">S. Con. Res. 70</bill> is to be considered as an allocation included in the resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Any questions may be directed to Ellen Balis or Gail Millar.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
