<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1181145609" ordinal="58" title="AFGHANISTAN FREEDOM AND SECURITY ACT OF 2007">
  <chair> Pursuant to House Resolution 453 and rule XVIII, the Chair declares the House in the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union for the further consideration of the bill, <bill type="h" number="2446">H.R. 2446</bill>.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> When the Committee of the Whole rose earlier today, amendment No. 10 printed in House Report 110-174 by the gentleman from Maryland (Mr. Van Hollen) had been disposed of.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 5-minute vote.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400315" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Yes, I am in its current form.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will report the motion to recommit.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> The gentleman from Indiana is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400315" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in strong support of this motion to recommit with instructions. Part of my responsibilities here in the Congress are that I serve as the ranking Republican member on the Middle East Subcommittee on the Committee on Foreign Affairs. As such, I have been intimately involved in the development of the underlying legislation and am strongly supportive of it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But I think it is also imperative that we adopt this motion to recommit and add language that addresses an issue of great concern to the United States of America, to Afghanistan, and to the free world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, we are receiving numerous reports that Iranian-made arms are being shipped to Afghanistan and transferred to the Taliban and other radical Islamic forces that seek to kill U.S. troops and Afghan forces.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>This past April, General Peter Pace, the chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, confirmed that, "We have intercepted weapons in Afghanistan headed for the Taliban that were made in Iran."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This past Monday, on a visit to Kabul, Defense Secretary Robert Gates noted that the weapons are flowing not only to the Taliban but to drug traffickers as well. "There have been indications over the past few months of weapons coming in from Iran. Some weapons," he said, "are coming into Afghanistan destined for the Taliban, but perhaps also for criminal elements involved in the drug trafficking coming from Iran."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The arms transferred reportedly include mortars, rocket-propelled grenades, C-4 explosives, surface-to-air missiles reportedly supplied by the Iranian Revolutionary Guard, and rockets with a 30-mile range.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Most disturbingly, an explosively formed projectile, an EFP, similar in characteristics to the Iranian-made ones that have killed our soldiers in Iraq, were recently discovered in Kabul.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Given Iran's unceasingly hostile rhetoric and actions in opposition to the United States, our interests and our allies, and given that these weapons were made in Iran, it is very reasonable to draw the conclusion that the Iranian regime transferred these arms to the Taliban.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We cannot allow Iran to undermine U.S. efforts and kill our soldiers in Afghanistan or to return that country to the status of a failed State and pave the way for increased terrorism against the West.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What we must do, simply, is to confront and respond to any efforts to subvert our efforts and kill our troops in Afghanistan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As General Pace noted, "I think we should continue to be aggressive inside of Iraq, and aggressive inside of Afghanistan, in attacking any element that's attacking U.S. and coalition forces, regardless of where they come from."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If we are to be vigilant in protecting the lives of our soldiers and our allies' soldiers and security forces, we cannot tie the hands of our President and our commanders in the field. They need to have every option at their disposal and opportunity to combat an insidious threat from Iran that appears to be supplying weapons to our enemies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Accordingly, we offer this motion to recommit which explicitly states that the Afghanistan Freedom and Security  Support Act does not limit America's ability to respond to attacks that Iran supports or facilitates against our forces or interests in Afghanistan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As the United States begins to engage Iran diplomatically, we must also make it clear that we will defend our allies and our interests in Afghanistan with all the means at our disposal.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, our relationship with Iran should be described as follows: one hand extended in diplomatic negotiation and another hand resting lightly on the holster of the arsenal of democracy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, in support of our troops, in support of freedom and stability in Afghanistan, I call on my colleagues on both sides of the aisle to strongly support this motion to recommit.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400231" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent to claim the time in opposition to this motion, although I'm not opposed to the motion.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the gentleman from California is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400231" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this has been a bipartisan bill from the very beginning. We have incorporated ideas from both sides of the aisle into this legislation. The recommittal motion has no practical effect whatsoever.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nothing in the legislation before the House would prohibit the United States from responding to an Iranian military attack on the United States forces or interests in Afghanistan. In fact, no statute prohibits the President from ordering a response to military attacks upon our Nation or upon our Armed Forces.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, this motion does not provide for taking any military action outside Afghanistan, nor should it. Therefore, I will support this motion to recommit.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the previous question is ordered on the motion to recommit.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400315" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I demand a recorded vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 and clause 9 of rule XX, this 15-minute vote on the motion to recommit will be followed by 5-minute votes, if ordered, on further proceedings in recommittal; passage of the bill; and suspension of the rules with respect to <bill type="h" number="2560">H.R. 2560</bill>.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400231" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, pursuant to the instructions of the House in the motion to recommit, I report <bill type="h" number="2446">H.R. 2446</bill> back to the House with an amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will report the amendment.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from California?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400231" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I demand a recorded vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 5-minute vote.</chair>
</record>
