<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1197997209" ordinal="72" title="HONORING THE LIFE OF JULIA CARSON">
  <narrative>HONORING THE LIFE OF JULIA CARSON -- (House of Representatives - December 18, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H16810]</narrative>
  <chair> Under a previous order of the House, the gen-&#xD0;   tleman from Connecticut (Mr. LARSON) is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400233" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, let me join and thank my colleague and classmate STEPHANIE TUBBS JONES for organizing this tribute to JULIA CARSON.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>President Kennedy was fond of saying that communities reveal an awful lot about themselves in the memorials they create and in the people that they honor. This evening my colleagues, led by STEPHANIE TUBBS JONES and the Speaker of the House, the majority leader, and the delegation from Indiana have stood tall in honoring the memory of JULIA CARSON. </paragraph>
    <paragraph>Memory is what distinguishes us from every other creature on the face of the Earth. It's humbling listening to the reminiscing that took place this evening.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have lost a number of people since I have been in Congress, wonderful, remarkable, dedicated citizens to this great country of ours. JULIA brought that warmth and dignity to this office. It was an honor to be with her and know her.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I often think at services such as this it's a shame she wasn't here to hear us all talk about her, and for those of us in this body who didn't get the opportunity to say good-bye, it's principally the ability to reminisce and the memories that so many of our colleagues have brought to this floor that make her come to life and live on. Not in memorials, though I am sure memorials will be created. Not in buildings named, because I'm sure that those things will follow. But those memorials that mean  the most are those that are principally carried in our hearts. And listening to BARON and STEVE talk earlier and all the Members who spoke here, what a rich, rich life. What a wonderful person.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>She has gone home to Indiana, but she will never leave us. God bless JULIA. God bless this country. I thank everyone here for the memorial that you created this evening.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
