<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1173114004" ordinal="13" title="SOUTHERN IDAHO BUREAU OF RECLAMATION REPAYMENT ACT OF 2007">
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="467">H.R. 467</bill>) to authorize early repayment of obligations to the Bureau of Reclamation within the A&amp;B Irrigation District in the State of Idaho, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) and the gentleman from Utah (Mr. Bishop) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 days to revise and extend their remarks.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Arizona?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of <bill type="h" number="467">H.R. 467</bill>, as amended, introduced by our colleague Congressman Simpson, is to authorize early repayment of landowner obligations to the Bureau of Reclamation within the A&amp;B Irrigation District in southeastern Idaho.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The A&amp;B Irrigation District receives part of its irrigation water supply from the Bureau of Reclamation's Minidoka Project. <bill type="h" number="467">H.R. 467</bill>, as amended, will provide administrative consistency between the landowners within the A&amp;B Irrigation District and those within other districts served by the Minidoka Project.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this legislation simply allows landowners to pay off their financial obligations related to the Bureau of Reclamation's Minidoka project. We believe this legislation is appropriate and, in fact, may provide a slight financial benefit to the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the 109th Congress, the Subcommittee on Water and Power held a hearing on similar legislation. This legislation was subsequently passed by the House. We have no objection to this noncontroversial bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400029" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="467">H.R. 467</bill>. <bill type="h" number="467">H.R. 467</bill>, sponsored by our colleague Mike Simpson, allows for the early repayment of capital costs associated with a Federal water project in Idaho.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under existing law, landowners who benefit from this water project cannot prepay the capital costs they owe to the Federal Government. But this bill gives the Bureau of Reclamation the ability to accept prepayment from these landowners. This legislation benefits the American taxpayer because it allows early revenue to flow into the U.S. Treasury and allows local landowners to reduce their debt.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this very good, commonsense bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no further requests for time, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no further requests for time, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="467">H.R. 467</bill>, as amended.</chair>
</record>
