<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1190131202" ordinal="51" title="A TRIBUTE TO VICKI ANN SUMMERS">
  <narrative>A TRIBUTE TO VICKI ANN SUMMERS -- (House of Representatives - September 18, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H10498]</narrative>
  <chair> Under a previous order of the House, the gentleman from North Carolina (Mr. Hayes) is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400172" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I want to pay tribute to Vicki Ann Summers, 59, of Pinehurst, North Carolina, who died on Monday, July 23, 2007, at her home. She was born February 19, 1948, in Stanly County to the late Rudy Lamar Summers and Margaret Ewing Lisk Summers. Vicki was a talented newspaper reporter with a long history in journalism who was most recently employed by The News-Journal in Hoke County. Throughout her career, she spent most of her time covering local government, but she also wrote  human interest stories, covered the crime beat and was a photographer. She was recognized for her writings by the North Carolina Press Association.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Vicki grew up in Fayetteville and attended Pine Forest High School before graduating from the North Carolina School of the Arts, which she attended on a full scholarship. She later attended Miami-Dade Junior College in Florida and East Carolina University.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In early 1970, she was a director of public relations for Sheraton Hotels Corporation and the Fountain Bleu Resort in Miami Beach. Around the same time, she worked as a celebrity correspondent for the National Enquirer, as a lifestyle writer for the Miami News, and as a trends writer and garden editor for the Sun Sentinel in Fort Lauderdale. Before coming to the News-Journal, she worked for the Harnett County News in Lillington and the Erwin Times in Erwin, North Carolina.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Vicki was very diligent and really cared about her local community. She took great pride in reporting about the economic development of the county and downtown Raeford streets' redevelopment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A memorial service was held on Monday, July 30, at 7 p.m. at Northwood Temple in Fayetteville. She is survived by her mother, Margaret Ewing Pope, of Fayetteville, three sisters, Carla S. Merritt and Jan Hernandez, both of Fayetteville, and Lydia Aldridge of Raleigh, and one brother, Eric Summers of Linden.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
