<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1179871463" ordinal="37" title="FEDERAL HOUSING FINANCE REFORM ACT OF 2007">
  <chair> Pursuant to House Resolution 404 and rule  XVIII, the Chair declares the House in the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for the further consideration of the bill, <bill type="h" number="1427">H.R. 1427</bill>.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> When the Committee of the Whole rose on the legislative day of Thursday, May 17, 2007, a request for a recorded vote on amendment No. 1 printed in the Congressional Record by the gentleman from Texas (Mr. Neugebauer) had been postponed.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400207" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, on rollcall No. 386 I was inadvertently detained. Had I been present, I would have voted "yea."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(By unanimous consent, Mr. Boren was allowed to speak out of order.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400645" topic="CONGRESSIONAL SPORTSMEN'S CAUCUS SHOOTOUT">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, yesterday an historic event occurred. Yesterday, in Prince George's County, the Congressional Sportsmen's Caucus held its annual shootout, and the Democrats were victorious. I want to congratulate my fellow caucus members: MIKE THOMPSON, who is our Top Gun. Overall, COLLIN PETERSON was the top Democrat.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to congratulate some Members on the other side of the aisle: Mr. JOHN KLINE, the top Republican.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to mention, Mr. Chairman, there was a little bit of confusion yesterday. At the trophy presentation, it was noted that the Republicans had beaten the Democrats by seven shots. It was later found out that there was a mysterious Member who did not actually shoot in the competition on the Republican side; so the trophy was then taken from Congressman Ryan's office to my office, and the Republicans can come visit it and see it often.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, 2-minute voting will continue.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
</record>
