<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1169571615" ordinal="85" title="JOINT SESSION OF THE HOUSE AND SENATE HELD PURSUANT TO THE PROVISIONS OF HOUSE CONCURRENT RESOLUTION 38 TO HEAR AN ADDRESS BY THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES">
  <chair> The Chair appoints as members of the committee on the part of the House to escort the President of the United States into the Chamber:</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="" name="The Vice President" of="">
    <paragraph>The President of the Senate, at the direction of that body, appoints the following Senators as members of the committee on the part of the Senate to escort the President of the United States into the House Chamber:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senator from Nevada (Mr. Reid);</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senator from Illinois (Mr. Durbin);</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senator from New York (Mr. Schumer);</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senator from Washington (Mrs. Murray);</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senator from North Dakota (Mr. Dorgan);</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senator from Michigan (Ms. Stabenow);</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senator from Kentucky (Mr. McConnell);</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senator from Mississippi (Mr. Lott);</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senator from Arizona (Mr. Kyl);</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senator from Texas (Mr. Cornyn);</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senator from Texas (Mrs. Hutchison);</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senator from Nevada (Mr. Ensign); and</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senator from Alaska (Mr. Stevens).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Deputy Sergeant at Arms announced the Dean of the Diplomatic Corps, His Excellency Roble Olhaye, Ambassador from the Republic of Djibouti.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Dean of the Diplomatic Corps entered the Hall of the House of Representatives and took the seat reserved for him.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Deputy Sergeant at Arms announced the Chief Justice of the United States and the Associate Justices of the Supreme Court.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Chief Justice of the United States and the Associate Justices of the Supreme Court entered the Hall of the House of Representatives and took the seats reserved for them in front of the Speaker's rostrum.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Deputy Sergeant at Arms announced the Cabinet of the President of the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The members of the Cabinet of the President of the United States entered the Hall of the House of Representatives and took the seats reserved for them in front of the Speaker's rostrum.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At 9 o'clock and 7 minutes p.m., the Sergeant at Arms, the Honorable Wilson Livingood, announced the President of the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The President of the United States, escorted by the committee of Senators  and Representatives, entered the Hall of the House of Representatives and stood at the Clerk's desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <narrative>(Applause, the Members rising.)</narrative>
  <chair> Members of the Congress, I have the high privilege and the distinct honor of presenting to you the President of the United States.</chair>
  <narrative>(Applause, the Members rising.)</narrative>
</record>
