<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1193068802" ordinal="20" title="HOPEWELL CULTURE NATIONAL HISTORICAL PARK BOUNDARY ADJUSTMENT ACT">
  <narrative>HOPEWELL CULTURE NATIONAL HISTORICAL PARK BOUNDARY ADJUSTMENT ACT -- (House of Representatives - October 22, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H11786]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="2197">H.R. 2197</bill>) to modify the boundary of the Hopewell Culture National Historical Park in the State of Ohio, and for other purposes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="2197">H.R. 2197</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "Hopewell Culture National Historical Park Boundary Adjustment Act".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. BOUNDARY EXPANSION.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Section 2 of the Act entitled "An Act to rename and expand the boundaries of the Mound City Group National Monument in Ohio", approved May 27, 1992 (106 Stat. 185), is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) by striking "and" at the end of subsection (a)(3);&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) by striking the period at the end of subsection (a)(4) and inserting "; and";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) by adding after subsection (a)(4) the following new paragraph:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(5) the map entitled `Hopewell Culture National Historical Park, Ohio Proposed Boundary Adjustment' numbered 353/80,049 and dated June, 2006."; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) by adding after subsection (d)(2) the following new paragraph:</narrative>
  <narrative> "(3) The Secretary may acquire lands added by subsection (a)(5) only from willing sellers.".&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) and the gentleman from Alaska (Mr. Young) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Arizona.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Arizona?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, <bill type="h" number="2197">H.R. 2197</bill> was introduced by the gentleman from Ohio (Mr. Space). The legislation would modify the boundaries of the Hopewell Culture National Historical Park in south central Ohio to add two tracts, totaling almost 360 acres.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Hopewell Culture was a pre-European civilization best known for the numerous mounds and earthworks found throughout the Ohio Valley. The current park boundary encompasses five sites totaling 1,174 acres. <bill type="h" number="2197">H.R. 2197</bill> would add two tracts, the 177-acre Spruce Hill Works unit and the 180-acre addition to the existing Seip Earthworks unit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the National Park Service has testified in support of the legislation, and it was approved by the Resources Committee by unanimous consent. This addition to our National Park System will preserve important sites from our Nation's past.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I commend the gentleman from Ohio (Mr. Space) for his diligence in bringing this bill to the House. Representative Space is on his way back from his district this afternoon, but will submit a statement for the Record.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the gentleman from Texas (Mr. Gohmert) will control the time.</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400651" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I believe the National Parks Subcommittee chairman has adequately explained this bill, and we have no objection.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412229" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, it is with great excitement that I share my support for <bill type="h" number="2197">H.R. 2197</bill>, the Hopewell Culture National Historical Park Boundary Adjustment Act, with the House today. Passage of this legislation will help to ensure the protection of a national archaeological treasure in Ohio's 18th Congressional District.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to begin by offering my thanks to Chairmen RAHALL and GRIJALVA for their gracious assistance in assuring this legislation was heard both by the Committee and the House of Representatives. The House is fortunate to have the service of both of these Members.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2197">H.R. 2197</bill> permits the expansion of the boundaries of Hopewell Culture National Historical Park in two areas. Hopewell Culture National Historical Park is home to historical remains of the Hopewell Culture, a culture of Native Americans that thrived between the years of 200 BC and 500 AD. This culture was known for the creation of large enclosures characterized by earthen walls, many of which still stand today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The proposed border expansion is not an arbitrary one. Earlier this year, a parcel of land known as Spruce Hill became available for sale. Spruce Hill is home to many archaeological remains of interest to historians and archaeologists, and significant natural phenomena that piqued the interest of the environmental community. In fact, legislation passed by Congress in 1980 ordered the Department of the Interior to perform a study on the relevance of Spruce Hill to the Hopewell culture for the  purposes of a possible expansion. The report, released in 1998, found that Spruce Hill is an "outstanding example of a particular class of Hopewellian monumental architecture," confirming the importance of adding this land to the Park.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Spruce Hill was scheduled for public auction by the owner last June. I, like many of the residents of Ross County, were concerned that this land might be transferred to an owner uninterested in preserving its historical treasures. Fortunately, a land trust created by a group of concerned citizens and other interested parties were successful in raising enough funds to purchase the land before it was put up for auction. I am pleased to say that the land is currently in safe hands.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2197">H.R. 2197</bill> will allow the federal government to expand the borders of Hopewell Culture National Historical Park to include Spruce Hill, ensuring it takes it proper place within the boundaries of a park meant to commemorate an important chapter in the history of America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Historians will tell you that the Hopewell culture is a chapter of American history in need of further exploration. Dr. Brad Lepper of the Ohio Historical Society testified before the Subcommittee on National Parks in June that Spruce Hill was an untapped resource that could offer answers to many historical questions about this culture, and even raise new questions of interest.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to join me in passage of <bill type="h" number="2197">H.R. 2197</bill> today. Its passage is both timely and critical to the protection of our culture.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400651" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="2197">H.R. 2197</bill>.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the bill was passed.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
