<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1194454802" ordinal="4" title="WELCOMING RABBI IRWIN N. GOLDENBERG">
  <narrative>WELCOMING RABBI IRWIN N. GOLDENBERG -- (House of Representatives - November 07, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H13209]</narrative>
  <chair> Without objection, the gentleman from Pennsylvania (Mr. Platts) is recognized for 1 minute.</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400321" topic="">
    <paragraph>Thank you, Madam Speaker.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise here today to welcome as guest chaplain on the floor of the House of Representatives Rabbi Irwin N. Goldenberg, a constituent, friend, well-liked and well-respected religious leader in my home community. Rabbi Goldenberg has served at Temple Beth Israel in York, Pennsylvania, since 1973.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With Rabbi Goldenberg's retirement set for June 2008, numerous members of Temple Beth Israel approached my office and suggested he be invited as a guest chaplain. I was very pleased to have forwarded the request along to Father Coughlin and am grateful that Rabbi Goldenberg was able to give the opening prayer this morning.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rabbi Goldenberg is a graduate of Rutgers University and Hebrew Union College. He is married to Joyce Meschmar and has two grown children, Rachel and Dahlia.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to his general rabbinic duties, Rabbi Goldenberg has taught countless adults, children and teens at Temple Beth Israel and its religious school. He has also taught at York College and Gettysburg College, both located in the 19th Congressional District. Rabbi Goldenberg has also been extensively involved in his community, from being a member of the board of the York Jewish Community Center to teen pregnancy mentoring at the YWCA to serving on the task force on domestic violence.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is a true honor to have Rabbi Goldenberg with us here today. I thank him for the prayer that he offered and I wish him the best for an enjoyable and relaxing retirement in the years to come.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
