<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1185768000" ordinal="61" title="PROHIBITION ON COLLECTION OF COPAYMENTS FOR ALL HOSPICE CARE FURNISHED BY DEPARTMENT OF VETERANS AFFAIRS">
  <narrative>PROHIBITION ON COLLECTION OF COPAYMENTS FOR ALL HOSPICE CARE FURNISHED BY DEPARTMENT OF VETERANS AFFAIRS -- (House of Representatives - July 30, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H8897]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400133" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="2623">H.R. 2623</bill>) to amend title 38, United States Code, to prohibit the collection of copayments for all hospice care furnished by the Department of Veterans Affairs, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="2623">H.R. 2623</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. PROHIBITION ON COLLECTION OF COPAYMENTS FOR ALL HOSPICE CARE FURNISHED BY DEPARTMENT OF VETERANS AFFAIRS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Title 38, United States Code, is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in section 1710(f)(1), by inserting "(except if such care constitutes hospice care)" after "nursing home care"; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) in section 1710(g)(1), by inserting "(except if such services constitute hospice care)" after "medical services"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) in section 1710B(c)(2), by striking subparagraph (B) and inserting after subparagraph (A) the following new subparagraph (B):</narrative>
  <narrative> "(B) to a veteran being furnished inpatient or outpatient hospice care by the Department; or".&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from California (Mr. Filner) and the gentleman from Florida (Mr. Miller) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from California</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400133" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank Mr. Miller for bringing us this bill, because working with Mr. Michaud of Maine, we have an important piece of legislation that most people would have thought dealt with a problem that didn't exist.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, hospice and palliative care is a continuum of comfort-oriented and supportive services provided across settings, including hospitals, extended facilities, outpatient clinics and private residences. The VA offers a complement of hospice and palliative care options as part of a comprehensive health care benefit of provided to all veterans who are enrolled in our system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under current law, a veteran receiving hospice care in a nursing home is exempt from any applicable copayments. However, if the hospice care is provided in any other setting, such as an acute-care hospital or at home, the veteran may be subject to an in-patient or out-patient primary care copayment. This policy penalizes a veteran who chooses to remain at home for their hospice care or who, out of medical necessity, receives hospice care in an acute care setting.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Miller recognizes this injustice, and through <bill type="h" number="2623">H.R. 2623</bill>, corrects the inequity by exempting all hospice care provided through VA from copayment requirements. It would also align VA with the Medicare program, which does not impose copayments for hospice care. At the end of life, veterans should not have to worry about paying for the comfort that the hospice care provides.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It's the right thing to do, and I am pleased that my colleague from Florida has taken leadership on this</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400279" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the chairman again for his willingness to quickly move this legislation to the floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, <bill type="h" number="2623">H.R. 2623</bill>, as amended, is a bill that I am a sponsor of. It prohibits the collection of copayments for all hospice care furnished by the Department of Veterans Affairs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Hospice and palliative care is a continuum of comfort-oriented and supportive services provided across settings, including hospitals, extended care facilities, as the chairman said, outpatient clinics, and private residences. Under current law, a veteran receiving care in a nursing home is exempt from any copay. However, if they choose to take that care in their own home or in an acute-care facility, they could be charged a copayment. VA's current policy would penalize a veteran who chooses to  remain in their own home for their end-of-life care or, out of medical necessity, receives their care in an acute-care setting.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bipartisan support of this bill is greatly appreciated. I urge my colleagues to join me in support of this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400133" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days in which to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on <bill type="h" number="2623">H.R. 2623</bill>, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from California?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400133" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, once again, I would state that with bipartisan working arrangements we have brought forward a package of bills today from the Veterans Committee which deals not only with our older veterans, but with our returning veterans from Iraq and Afghanistan, and that's what we will continue to do.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support <bill type="h" number="2623">H.R. 2623</bill>, as amended</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from California (Mr. Filner) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="2623">H.R. 2623</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the bill, as amended, was passed.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
