<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1194627601" ordinal="49" title="REVISIONS TO THE 302(a) ALLOCATIONS AND BUDGETARY AGGREGATES ESTABLISHED BY THE CONCURRENT RESOLUTIONS ON THE BUDGET FOR FISCAL YEARS 2008 THROUGH 2012">
  <narrative>REVISIONS TO THE 302(a) ALLOCATIONS AND BUDGETARY AGGREGATES ESTABLISHED BY THE CONCURRENT RESOLUTIONS ON THE BUDGET FOR FISCAL YEARS 2008 THROUGH 2012 -- (House of Representatives - November 09, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H13513]</narrative>
  <chair> Under a previous order of the House, the gentleman from South Carolina (Mr. Spratt) is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, under section 303(b) of <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>, the Concurrent Resolution on the Budget for fiscal year 2008, I hereby submit for printing in the CONGRESSIONAL RECORD a revision to the budget allocations and aggregates for the House Committee on Ways and Means for fiscal year 2008, and the period of 2008 through 2012. This revision represents an adjustment to certain House committee budget allocation and  aggregates for the purposes  of section 302 and 311 of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974, as amended, and in response to the bill <bill type="h" number="3996">H.R. 3996</bill>, The Temporary Tax Relief Act of 2007. Corresponding tables are attached.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under section 211 of <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>, this adjustment to the budget allocations and aggregates applies while the measure is under consideration. The adjustments will take effect upon enactment of the measure. For purposes of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974, as amended, a revised allocation made under section 211 of <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill> is to be considered as an allocation included in the resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Any questions may be directed to Ellen Balis or Gail Millar.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
