<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1188956525" ordinal="22" title="AUTHORIZING THE USE OF THE ROTUNDA AND GROUNDS OF THE CAPITOL FOR A CEREMONY TO AWARD THE CONGRESSIONAL GOLD MEDAL TO TENZIN GYATSO, THE FOURTEENTH DALAI LAMA">
  <narrative>AUTHORIZING THE USE OF THE ROTUNDA AND GROUNDS OF THE CAPITOL FOR A CEREMONY TO AWARD THE CONGRESSIONAL GOLD MEDAL TO TENZIN GYATSO, THE FOURTEENTH DALAI LAMA -- (House of Representatives - September 04, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H10038]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400047" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent to discharge the Committee on House Administration and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure from further consideration of House Concurrent Resolution 196, and ask for its immediate consideration in the House.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the concurrent resolution.</narrative>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Pennsylvania?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the concurrent resolution, as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="hc" number="196">H. Con. Res. 196</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Resolved by the House of Representatives (the Senate concurring),&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. USE OF ROTUNDA FOR GOLD MEDAL CEREMONY FOR DALAI LAMA.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Use of Rotunda.--The rotunda of the Capitol is authorized to be used on October 17, 2007, for a ceremony to award the Congressional Gold Medal to Tenzin Gyatso, the Fourteenth Dalai Lama, in accordance with Public Law 109-287.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Preparations.--Physical preparations for the ceremony referred to in subsection (a) shall be carried out in accordance with such conditions as the Architect of the Capitol may prescribe.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. USE OF CAPITOL GROUNDS IN CONNECTION WITH CEREMONY.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) In General.--The International Campaign for Tibet (in this resolution referred to as the "sponsor") shall be permitted to sponsor a public event on the Capitol Grounds (in this resolution referred to as the "event") on October 17, 2007, in connection with the ceremony to be held in the rotunda of the Capitol under section 1.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Terms and Conditions.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) IN GENERAL.--Under conditions to be prescribed by the Architect of the Capitol and the Capitol Police Board, the event shall be--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) free of admission charge and open to the public; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) arranged not to interfere with the needs of Congress.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) EXPENSES AND LIABILITIES.--The sponsor shall assume full responsibility for all expenses and liabilities incident to all activities associated with the event.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Event Preparations.--Subject to the approval of the Architect of the Capitol, the sponsor is authorized to erect upon the Capitol Grounds such stage, sound amplification devices, and other related structures and equipment, as may be required for the event.</narrative>
  <narrative> (d) Enforcement of Restrictions.--The Capitol Police Board shall provide for enforcement of the restrictions contained in section 5104(c) of title 40, United States Code, concerning sales, advertisements, displays, and solicitations on the Capitol Grounds, as well as other restrictions applicable to the Capitol Grounds, in connection with the event.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <narrative>The concurrent resolution was agreed to.</narrative>
  <narrative>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</narrative>
</record>
