<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1182528003" ordinal="16" title="LEGISLATIVE BRANCH APPROPRIATIONS ACT, 2008">
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="SCHULTZ, WASSERMAN" of="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, at this time I would like to yield 1 minute to the distinguished chair of the House Administration Committee, the gentleman from Pennsylvania (Mr. Brady).</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400047" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I just want to say a few quick things.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We had a problem in House Administration when Chairwoman Millender-McDonald passed away. There was a void. But taking over as chairman, I have a great working relationship with my ranking minority member, Mr. Ehlers. I have a great working relationship with the ranking minority member of this subcommittee, ZACH WAMP. I also have tremendous respect for and a great working relationship with the chairwoman.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have had some conversations that we did not need to discuss here. I have been assured and am extremely comfortable with the fact that we will be together working out our jurisdictional problems. I thank the gentlewoman for stepping in at a time when it was needed. Again, with my ranking minority member, we have a great relationship. We probably have the best committee in that we get along all the time. We are going to continue to do that. I thank, again, the ranking member.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I look forward to working with you, and I have your assurance that we will be doing that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I want to express my appreciation for the work of the gentlelady from Florida to craft the FY08 appropriations bill for the Legislative Branch. As we are well aware in the Committee on House Administration, working on this bill may not be very glamorous, but it is essential to keeping the House running.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Committee on Appropriations has done a good job of balancing the many needs of the House--paying our employees, keeping the physical plant running, and operating the various agencies that serve Capitol Hill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am particularly pleased to see in this bill an additional $5 million toward upgrading the radio systems of the Capitol Police. Establishing a secure communications system for our police force is essential to the security of the Hill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also appreciate the Committee's commitment of funds for the "Green the Capitol" initiative. According to the House Chief Administrative Officer's calculations, we can eventually recoup these costs from savings on our utility bills when we make the House more energy-efficient.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I look forward to continuing our strong working relationship in the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, as Chairman of the Joint Committee on Printing, I urge the Members to reject the amendment by the gentleman from Arizona [Mr. Flake]. It is essential that the Congressional Printing and Binding Appropriation be funded at least at the level recommended by the Appropriations Committee. The Government Printing Office must have enough resources to provide Congress with the printing and digital services fundamental to our legislative process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The congressional printing account has been flat-funded since 2005. As a result, in order to deliver what we require to do our jobs in Congress, GPO has had to reach into its own working capital. When GPO depletes it working capital, it consumes funds otherwise available to keep pace with technology, train employees, even to maintain plant and equipment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>GPO receives no salaries-and-expenses appropriation for its printing operations. GPO runs just like a business, and the Congressional Printing and Binding Appropriation is Congress' prepayment for its own orders. As a GPO customer, like many other Federal agencies, Congress has to pay its way and cannot expect GPO to underwrite printing needs, especially as we increase congressional activity in this 110th Congress. If Congress continues to underfund its own printing, GPO will eventually face  a financial crisis that we caused, threatening its ability to operate for any of its agency customers. Let's reject the Flake amendment to keep that from happening.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400421" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I continue to reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="SCHULTZ, WASSERMAN" of="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, at this time I yield 3 minutes to the distinguished gentlewoman from the District of Columbia (Ms. Norton).</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400295" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I thank the gentlewoman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank her for her excellent work on her maiden voyage as chair.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have come to say a few words that I think need saying about the performance of GAO with respect to the grand experiment that our committee allowed on pay for performance. We allowed it. We have not tried to interfere with it. But the actions taken by the Comptroller General where you would at least have expected it has produced nothing short of a revolution within, of all places, the GAO workforce.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>They were chosen for this grand experiment because they were a fairly upscale part of the Federal workforce. And what have we got? How would you feel if you had worked at or above performance, and yet you were among 300 employees of, what is it, 2 million Federal employees who did not receive the across-the-board pay increase that everybody else receives? Well, some of you might have sued or filed a claim with the Personnel Appeals Board within the GAO. And those employees, all 12 of them, have  received their COLA, have been promoted, and have had their retirement fixed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But there are 300 employees from 2006, 130 from 2007 who have been punished as to their pensions and pay because the Comptroller did not keep his promise with the Congress, which was that nobody's across-the-board pay would be affected. In fact, what he did was to insert a market-based study without informing the subcommittee, an unvalidated study, and now he has a whole racial claim on top of it because the African Americans have been disproportionately affected by his action.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If the Comptroller wanted some help, he could have gone to the OPM. Instead, he used a market-based study from a consultant. If he wanted to know how to deal with unionization which is now upon him, he could have gone to the OPM. He could have gone to the Federal Labor Relations Authority. Instead, he is spending taxpayer funds in order to try to beat a union within the Federal sector, the first time ever. If we allow taxpayer funds to be used that way, then it seems to me we ought to be called  to account.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400421" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I continue to reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="SCHULTZ, WASSERMAN" of="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, at this time I yield 3 minutes to the distinguished gentlewoman from California (Ms. Linda T. S&#xE1;nchez).</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="T, LINDA" of="">
    <paragraph>S&#xC1;NCHEZ of California. Madam Chair, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="2771">H.R. 2771</bill>, the legislative branch appropriations bill. I want to thank Chairwoman Wasserman Schultz, Ranking Member Wamp, and the appropriations staff for their hard work in crafting this fiscally responsible bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill on the floor today is "lean and mean," providing just the resources that we need to serve the people in an honest, transparent manner.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I strongly believe that as our Nation's elected leaders, we have a responsibility here in the people's House to lead the Nation in creating an environmentally friendly workplace. This is why I crafted two amendments for today's bill that would have directed the Architect of the Capitol to take small but significant steps toward "greening" the Capitol complex.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am pleased that Subcommittee Chairwoman Wasserman Schultz shares my support for the Speaker's Greening of the Capitol Initiative. Since she has enthusiastically agreed to consider them during conference, I won't be offering them today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But I would like to draw the House's attention to these two initiatives because they demonstrate how small investments can reap large rewards.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Both initiatives were drawn from the Greening of the Capital report recently  completed by the Architect of the Capitol, and both are endorsed by the American Society of Landscape Architects.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The first initiative would study the feasibility of constructing a "green roof" on the Ford House Office Building. A green roof is a rooftop that is carefully planted with vegetation. It can be anything from a simple plot of grass to a park-like setting.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Green roofs have proved to be tremendous economic and environmental benefits. They are great insulators, reducing heating and cooling costs often by as much as 25 percent. And they save on maintenance costs as well since they are more protective than traditional roofs. Green roofs cool the surrounding neighborhood by reducing the amount of heat that is reflected back into the surrounding atmosphere, the so-called urban heat island effect. Vegetation on green roofs celebrates our natural heritage  and also absorbs rainwater, reducing contaminated runoff.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Even with all these benefits, green roofs have not caught on. They are not very popular yet in the United States. And as Members of Congress, we now have the opportunity to lead by example. A successful demonstration of the economic benefits of green roofs right here in the Capitol Complex can help promote green roofs across the Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My second proposal concerns the planting of more trees around parking lots in the Capitol Complex. My colleagues who closely follow environmental issues already know that trees have a remarkable ability to reduce the air temperature in our urban areas. Trees remove carbon from our atmosphere, shade our buildings and cars, and even reduce asthma by filtering out air pollutants. According to the nonpartisan Congressional Budget Office, this proposal would even save the taxpayers money.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Without action this year, many of the Speaker's Greening of the Capitol Initiatives, including the two I have just discussed, won't get funding until 2009 or 2010. These proposals would get us started modestly but promptly and don't require additional funds.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I look forward to working with Chairwoman Wasserman Schultz to incorporate these projects into the legislative branch's plans for 2008.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="SCHULTZ, WASSERMAN" of="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I yield myself 30 seconds.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank the gentlewoman from California for her leadership on environmental issues and look forward to working with her on continuing the Speaker's leadership on the Green the Capitol Initiative, both in terms of planting of the trees and the greening of roofs, and I look forward and appreciate her input.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At this time, Madam Chairman, I yield 3 minutes to the gentlewoman from Texas (Ms. Jackson-Lee).</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <narrative>(Ms. JACKSON-LEE of Texas asked and was given permission to revise and extend her remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400199" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, this place, this House is always at its best when Members of the United States Congress work together. And I want to congratulate the chairwoman of this committee and the ranking member of this committee for working together.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Most people don't understand that the legislative branch creates an atmosphere of hospitality in this place. As I look and see the number of visitors that we have, your responsibility is to secure them and to welcome them. Let me thank you personally for the task that you have undertaken.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank you for the increase in the House Child Care Center, and I hope that our community does not criticize the fact that we are family friendly so that employees have the opportunity to have child care.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank you for supporting the Speaker's Green Initiative because we, too, must do what we ask Americans to do.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And, of course, the brave men and women that serve us, I welcome the increase in the Capitol Police, and I also look forward to their continuing to address the questions of discrimination and equality as they increase the numbers of police.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me join in the words of Congresswoman Eleanor Holmes Norton and hope that we will challenge, if you will, the GAO to be responsible in its dealings with its employees and unionization.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But I came today to be able to offer to the American public the sense of pride and the sense of humbleness that I am now experiencing because of your grand leadership and that of the Appropriations Committee. And my good friend Congressman Jesse Jackson and, of course, members of the Congressional Black Caucus signed a letter, which I was proud to sign, because this picture reflects something that is near and dear to Texas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My good friend comes from Tennessee. He knows that we have a lot of continuity or connection between Tennessee and Texas and the good State of Florida.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But we celebrated this week the Emancipation Proclamation. We celebrated, in particular, Juneteenth. Those of us in the South remember Major General Gordon Granger coming 2 years late to indicate that we might be free. Isn't it wonderful that now we will name the Visitors Center, and we hope for our good friends in the other body to be as reasonable, the Emancipation Hall.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I went through the hall just outside this door before I came to the floor, and I saw the name of William Jennings Bryan. I saw the name Wheeler of Alabama, Huey Pierce Long, Lew Wallace, Sequoyah, Sam Houston.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>I met a woman who told me about her grandfather, Levi Coffin, who had helped slaves in the Underground Railroad. Her name was Ms. Holt. She was just standing there talking to me.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That's what naming the Emancipation Hall means to America. It reflects the wholeness of America, the wonderment of our history, the dignity of our history. Yes, slaves built this place, but all Americans will be able to go into Emancipation Hall, and it will symbolize the freedom of this Nation. I am so grateful that we have come to this place at this time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask my colleagues to support this legislation, Emancipation Hall.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="2771">H.R. 2771</bill>, the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act of 2008 and to commend Chairwoman Wasserman Schultz for her leadership in shepherding this bill though the legislative process. This legislation funds the House, Senate and various entities in the legislative branch, including the Library of Congress, the Capitol Police, the Government Accountability Office, and the Government Printing Office.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But it does more than that, Madam Chairman. The bill provides funding for "Greening the Capitol" to reduce carbon emissions from the operations of House buildings and the Capitol. It makes the necessary investments for critical health and safety needs by funding security upgrades and addressing health hazards and safety requirements in law. In short, this legislation demonstrates a commitment by the new Democratic majority to increased oversight, accountability and fiscal responsibility.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2771">H.R. 2771</bill> appropriates $3.1 billion for legislative branch entities, including $1.2 billion for House operations and $1.9 billion for legislative branch agencies and other offices. The total provided is $275.7 million (8 percent) less than requested by legislative offices and agencies and only $122.2 million (4 percent) more than comparable FY 2007 funding. Nearly 25 percent of this increased funding is directly attributable to costs associated with the 2008 presidential election and subsequent  inauguration.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Following the long-established practice that each house of Congress determines its own housekeeping requirements without interference from the other body, the bill contains no funding for Senate operations. The bill appropriates $1.2 billion for operations of the House of Representatives, which is $36.5 million (3 percent) less than requested, but $54.1 million (5 percent) more than current funding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The total for the House includes $581 million for members' offices, also known as MRA's, 5 percent more than current funding, but 5 percent less than requested and $162.8 million for House committees, 8 percent more than current funding and 4 percent more than requested. The bill also provides $169.4 million for the various House officers and employees, including the Clerk of the House, the Sergeant at Arms, and the Chief Administrative Officer (CAO), 8 percent more than current funding, but  3 percent less than requested.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2771">H.R. 2771</bill> provides $21.1 million for joint House-Senate items, 13 percent less than current funding and 23 percent less than requested, when the recent June 8 supplemental request for the Capitol guides is taken into account. The appropriated amount includes $9.4 million for the Joint Committee on Taxation, 7 percent more than current funding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, <bill type="h" number="2771">H.R. 2771</bill> provides a total of $1.9 billion for other offices and legislative branch agencies that directly or indirectly support congressional operations. This funding is $71.2 million (4 percent) more than current levels but $232.8 million (11 percent) less than requested. Among the agencies this bill funds are the Architect of the Capitol; the Capitol Police; the Library of Congress; the Government</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Printing Office, the Congressional Budget Office, and the Government Accountability Office.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For the Architect of the Capitol, the bill provides $348.4 million, 9 percent less than current funding and 12 percent less than requested. Included in the bill is $27.5 million for the Capital Visitors Center. I cite with particular approval that the bill renames the center's Great Hall as "Emancipation Hall" in remembrance of the slave labor that created this mighty edifice.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Earlier this week, the House passed <bill type="hc" number="155">H. Con. Res. 155</bill>, which recognized the historical significance of June 19, 1865, or "Juneteenth," the oldest known celebration of the ending of slavery. On June 19, 1865, Union soldiers, led by Major General Gordon Granger, landed at Galveston, TX, with news that the war had ended and that all slaves were now free. But this was 2 1/2  years after President Lincoln's Emancipation Proclamation--which had become official January 1, 1863.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I suppose it may just be another irony of life that the U.S. Capitol was rebuilt during the Civil War and completed around the time of Juneteenth. This magnificent symbol of democracy, freedom, and equality could not have been brought in to being without the blood and sweat and unrequited toil of slave labor. For much of our history the contributions to our country by slaves and their descendants has not been fully acknowledged. But in renaming the Great Hall to the Capitol Visitor  Center as "Emancipation Hall," we begin to rectify this error. It is a wonderful thing we are doing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also provides $3.9 million to implement the "Green the Capitol" initiative, including $2.7 for shifting from coal to natural gas for heating in the Capitol power plant, and the report requires the House CAO to purchase carbon credits. The bill also requires the hiring of an inspector general.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill provides the Capitol Police $286 million, which is $13.1 million (4 percent) less than requested, but $20.3 million (8 percent) more than current funding. The Library of Congress is slated to receive $572.5 million, $63.8 million (13 percent) more than the current level, but $89.1 million (13 percent) less than requested. There is $125.8 million for the Government Printing Office; $37.8 million for the Congressional Budget Office (CBO); and $503.3 million in net funding for the Government  Accountability Office (GAO). The bill does not contain any earmarks as defined under House rules.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To conclude, Madam Chairman, I strongly support <bill type="h" number="2771">H.R. 2771</bill> because it makes the necessary investments for critical health and safety needs by funding security upgrades and addressing health and safety hazards. I support this legislation because it reflects the commitment by the new Democratic majority to increased oversight, accountability and fiscal responsibility.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank Chairwoman WASSERMAN SCHULTZ for her fine work in bringing this exceptional legislation to the House floor where it should receive an overwhelmingly favorable vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="SCHULTZ, WASSERMAN" of="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400421" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, with the understanding that the distinguished Chair from Florida will close, I would like to yield myself 1 minute before yielding the balance of our time to the gentleman from Georgia (Mr. Kingston).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I congratulate our chairwoman for just working really hard, having a lot of hearings, digging in, learning a lot, and then finding a way to work together through the process, and I'm grateful.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Also, I want to say, with regard to the GAO issue and outside counsel, using outside counsel is actually commonplace; even the House itself has used it, the legislative branch agencies have used that. And then also to say about the greening of the Capitol issue, what we've heard today should remind us to use great caution because we are all for greening and environmental efficiency, but we need to be careful that the Congress itself is not a guinea pig to try a whole lot of things just to see  how they work.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With that, Madam Chairman, I yield the balance of my time to the gentleman from Georgia, the former chairman of the subcommittee, Mr. Kingston.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400221" topic="">
    <paragraph>Thank you, Mr. Wamp. And I thank the Chair and congratulate both of you on your work for this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to say, however, I do not support it. I am very disappointed that after the bill left the Appropriations Committee and went to the Rules Committee, a funny thing happened. All this transparency and all this promise of open government and open rules seemed to fade away in a dark corner room up on the third floor of this building, because there were 23 amendments offered, and yet only three of them were accepted.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We talk about bipartisanship and we talk about sunshine in the process, and yet this is the very bill that basically funds and perhaps even governs our own body, our own congressional branch, and yet it has the closed rule. And 20 amendments won't get the sunshine, will not get the debate because of the Rules Committee under Democrat leadership. I would say you need to go back to your campaign brochures and look at all the promises that you made before you pass another rule like this.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One of the casualties of this closed process was an amendment that I offered that deals with contractors who deal with the Federal Government, who work for the Federal Government. I'll give you some examples. December 2005, 22 Mexican nationals were found illegally working in Kirtland Air Force Base in Albuquerque, New Mexico. January 27, 2001, illegal aliens were found working at Fort Benning, Georgia. March 2007, the Golden State Fence Company was actually fined because, in building a border  security fence, they had hired 10 illegal aliens.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It doesn't stop there. In Louisiana, December 2005, a local company was busted working on a Veterans Administration hospital because they had illegal aliens. This is absurd. Now, I've heard from many people the theme of "leading by example." Perhaps one thing we could do and absolutely should do is require that if you are contracting for the Federal Government, that you have a Social Security verification process going in your business, more than the sham, more than the, Yeah, but we have an  I-9 kind of approach that we're seeing. And this would actually say you need to be in the ICE, which is the Customs and Immigration Enforcement Service, you need to be in the ICE Basic Pilot Program, which is a way to know that your employees have correct and legal Social Security numbers. That's all the amendment would have done.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would predict that this amendment would get lots of bipartisan support because we see that the biggest issue facing America, besides Iraq and perhaps energy, is the issue of illegal immigration. And here was an opportunity for us to make a definitive statement, to have a significant amendment added to the bill, and the Democrats said no.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I hope they'll reconsider on future legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="SCHULTZ, WASSERMAN" of="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, I think it's unfortunate that the gentleman from Georgia, the distinguished former chairman of this committee, has chosen this opportunity as a message opportunity, as opposed to working together in a bipartisan way, like the ranking member and I have done, to make sure that we can provide for the safety and security of the facilities of this institution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He knows full well that the Capitol Visitors Center and the employees of the subcontractors that have been engaged to build that facility, while moving entirely too slowly, and we certainly have decried the cost overruns, are required to hire people who legally may work in this country and are required to ensure that a background check and a security check has been done on them. So his remarks are unfortunate, but everybody makes their own choices.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In conclusion, Madam Chair, I am really proud of the work that the subcommittee and I have engaged in. We offer this legislation to the House and ask for their support. We have endeavored to make sure that this bill is fiscally responsible, provides for the life, safety and security of the needs of the people who work here as well as the people who visit us here, and make sure that we can engage in Congress's oversight role and provide for accountability for the American people.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I look forward to continuing to work with Mr. Wamp from Tennessee on making sure that we can consistently  provide those initiatives for the American people.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400189" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I rise today to express concerns about GAO's response to GAO employees' petition for a union election, which was filed on May 8 of this year. As a legislative branch agency it is imperative that GAO conduct its labor relations in a manner that is a model for all Federal agencies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am particularly concerned by GAO's decision to challenge the eligibility of one-third of the employees covered by the union petition. GAO is asserting that these employees are not eligible for representation because they perform a supervisory role.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The facts of their employment status at GAO strongly suggests otherwise. If these employees are in fact determined to be supervisors, then they are supervisors in name only because they are prohibited from performing supervisory functions. Moreover, GAO would have a 1:3 ratio of supervisors to nonsupervisors. That would be one of the smallest ratios in any public or private organization.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am deeply concerned that GAO's challenge is an attempt to delay balloting until the end of the year, one that will entail a considerable expenditure of resources that will only distract the agency from carrying out critical investigatory and oversight work for the U.S. Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I strongly urge GAO to reconsider its challenge, which will be costly, undermine agency morale, and distract it from its mission.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400438" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, today I rise to express my concerns with Government Accountability Office, GAO, management's response to the GAO employees' petition seeking a union election.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It should be noted that applicable law strictly prohibits the GAO management from expressing any personal view, argument, opinion, or statements relating to a union election except to: publicize election and encourage employees to vote; correct the record with respect to any false or misleading statement; or inform employees of the Government's policy relating to labor-management relations and representation as long as these statements do contain a threat or reprisal or promise of benefit and  are not made under coercive conditions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Despite these restrictions, Comptroller General Walker was quoted in a January 23, 2007 publication as stating that he "will present to the employees [his] views on the advantages and disadvantages of unionization."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Shortly after this statement was published, attorneys for the union sent a letter advising Comptroller General Walker of his obligation to remain "neutral" during the employees' deliberations regarding unionization.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The GAO's General Counsel responded acknowledging GAO management's legal obligation to maintain strict neutrality during a union organizing campaign.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Further, the Comptroller General met with me shortly before I sent a letter to him regarding his response to the union organizing activities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In that meeting, the Comptroller General tried to discourage me from sending the letter, and promised not to interfere with the unionization effort. I informed Mr. Walker that I appreciated his assurances but that would be sending the letter all the same.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have the letter dated February 23rd of this year, and signed by a bipartisan group of 19 House Members and 3 Senators with me and wish to submit it for the RECORD.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am sorry to say that despite these assurances, and since the union filed the election petition on May 8, 2007, the Comptroller General has made additional statements that are at odds with his obligation to remain neutral.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am very concerned that I have received reports from GAO employees that Mr. Walker has used his staff meetings to make statements that are seen by employees as a breach of GAO management's neutrality obligation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For example, they report that Mr. Walker has urged employees to "get all the facts", that a union could "make things different ..... seriously impact agency decision-making", and "slow things down."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He refers to the GAO employees who seek to form a union as a "vocal minority in GAO" and that "[d]ue to union organizing efforts, labor law prevents [him] from helping employees unilaterally. Both of [my] hands are tied due to the union organizing efforts....."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By implication, Mr. Walker asserts that if employees reject union-representation, Mr. Walker will "help" them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Walker's statements are not neutral. I find it hard to believe that GAO analysts need to be reminded to "get all the facts" and the very purpose of a union is to "impact" the employer's decision-making.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Further, it cannot be clearer that the reference to potentially "slowing things down" is intended as a negative reference about unionization.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise today not only to call on Mr. Walker to stop interfering with GAO employees' right to organize and petition for a union election, but to call on my colleagues to stand together with these GAO employees who serve Congress and the public.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let us do all we can to help these dedicated public servants get a vote on their union election petition this summer.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400415" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I am grateful for the opportunity to add my voice of support to our valued public servants at the Government Accountability Office, GAO. Just as Congress relies on the GAO for the gold standard of fair and even-handed analysis, so too must we ensure that our GAO workforce receives that same standard of fairness and even-handedness when it comes to matters of their own employment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The issues that gave rise to the language in today's underlying Legislative Branch Appropriations bill are not new to the Government Oversight Committee on which I sit, or to the Federal employee community I am privileged to serve. Like many of my colleagues on the committee, I have received reports expressing concern about the process surrounding the recent Band II Restructuring Project, as well as the methodology used in the 2004 Watson Wyatt Worldwide, WWW, compensation study. In that regard,  I am particularly troubled that the WWW study is being cited as the reason over 300 hard-working GAO employees who met or exceeded their performance expectations have been denied annual cost of living adjustments, notwithstanding public commitments to the contrary.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a majority of GAO analysts have now exercised their employment rights to organize a union, it is critical that the requisite election process go forward expeditiously and without interference. I thank my colleagues for this opportunity to voice my support for the GAO workforce and the rest of our valued Federal employee community.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400413" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I want to begin by taking the time to congratulate Chairwoman WASSERMAN SCHULTZ for her excellent work on this bill as well as in the subcommittee the past couple of months. It has been a pleasure to work with you and I look forward to working with all other Members as we continue to address the concerns of all people working in and visiting the Nation's Capitol.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would also like to commend Ranking Member Wamp for his work. Together the chairwoman and ranking member have fostered a collegial bipartisan atmosphere.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill before us is a good bill, a bill that brings us necessary security upgrades, that shows a commitment to increased oversight, and does it in a fiscally responsible manner.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Among the bill's many important provisions is funding for the Greening the Capitol Initiative. This initiative will enable us to start switching from coal to cleaner burning natural gas for the running of the Capitol powerplant. Pages live in the shadow of the Capitol powerplant. It will allow us to purchase energy efficient light bulbs, and will allow us to begin other energy savings operations throughout the Capitol Complex.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill includes necessary funding for the Office of Compliance, which will allow that office to conduct oversight of the utility tunnel improvement efforts and health and safety issues. During hearings in the subcommittee, I have raised concerns, along with several of my colleagues, about the utility tunnels and workers and I am pleased to see that the Office of Compliance will receive the resources it needs to oversee the ongoing situation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill also includes funding for the Library of Congress and several of its extremely important programs, such as the Books for the Blind Program, which provides services to blind and physically handicapped patrons including the production and distribution of books and magazines in Braille and electronic media.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, I urge my colleagues to support this bill and thank Chairwoman WASSERMAN SCHULTZ and Ranking Member WAMP for the efforts they have put in to the subcommittee this year to ensure that the Capitol Complex and various agencies around us are run well and efficiently.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="SCHULTZ, WASSERMAN" of="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> All time for general debate has expired.</chair>
  <narrative>(INCLUDING TRANSFER OF FUNDS)</narrative>
  <chair> No amendment to the bill shall be in order except those printed in House Report 110-201. Each amendment may be offered only in the order printed in the report, by a Member designated in the report, shall be considered read, shall be debatable for the time specified in the report, equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent, shall not be subject to amendment, and shall not be subject to a demand for division of the question.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400649" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I offer an amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will designate the amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400649" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentlelady.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise with the support of several Members of this amendment. The gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Lipinski), the gentlelady from California (Ms. Harman), and the gentleman from Michigan (Mr. Upton) and I are offering an amendment that would require that light bulbs purchased in the Leg Branch appropriations would comply with the ENERGY STAR and Federal Energy Management Program identifications. The idea here is to save some money easily and to save a lot of energy, and  of course energy is money.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Most Americans are still using, and most of the light bulbs in my house are incandescent bulbs that Thomas Edison invented more than 100 years ago. But only 10 percent of the energy of those light bulbs turns out to be light; 90 percent is wasted as heat. So we've got something better. And like many, I'm switching to CFLs. Those lights provide much more efficient lighting. And it's amazing to think that if every American just switched one incandescent bulb to an energy-efficient alternative,  we would collectively save more than $8 billion in energy costs, prevent the burning of 300 billion pounds of coal, and remove 2 million cars' worth of greenhouse gas emissions from our atmosphere.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This small step in this amendment is part of something else that Mr. Lipinski and I are working on, which is a Bulb Replacement in Government and High Efficiency Technology, BRIGHT we call it, Energy Savings Act, along with Representative Harman, that would require GSA to replace burned out light bulbs with more efficient options like compact fluorescent lighting.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The BRIGHT Act has 82 cosponsors, and we look forward to its adoption. This amendment is a good step toward that goal.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, I am happy to yield to the gentlelady from California (Ms. Harman).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400166" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for yielding, and commend him for the role that he is playing on a bipartisan basis to assure that existing standards, the ENERGY STAR standards and the Federal Energy Management Program standards are adhered to. This effort that we're making on every appropriations bill will ensure that our practice complies with our law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I agree with him that CFLs offer much more efficiency. There are also LEDs. And hopefully the incandescent bulb makers in America will adjust their own manufacturing so that they produce efficient light bulbs as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Another bill that we're all cosponsoring that's pending in the Energy Subcommittee of Energy and Commerce will provide incentives to U.S. manufacturers to produce more efficient lighting and set proper goals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, I want to say that bipartisanship has been hailed all morning. It takes 270 Members of Congress and 60 Members of the Senate and hopefully one willing President to change the light bulb policy, and I think we're proceeding that way this morning.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400649" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, I yield to the gentleman from Michigan (Mr. Upton).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400414" topic="">
    <paragraph>I would just like to compliment the gentleman for his leadership on this issue, Mr. Lipinski and Ms. Harman. We are seeing efforts move. And we've learned already that if everyone did this across the country, we would save 65 billion kilowatts of energy, which is the equivalent of 80 coal-fired plants. Obviously this is something we want the Federal Government to do.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I compliment Chairman Obey and Ranking Member Lewis on the floor for allowing us to proceed without a lot of debate, knowing that we have strong support for this. I look forward to having this adopted.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400421" topic="">
    <paragraph>Will the gentleman yield?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400649" topic="">
    <paragraph>I would be happy to yield to the gentleman from Tennessee.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400421" topic="">
    <paragraph>I just want to commend the authors, commend the ENERGY STAR Program. This is the kind of greening initiative that actually resonates. We will accept the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400649" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, we appreciate very much the committee's willingness to accept this amendment. It is a good step forward.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400273" topic="">
    <paragraph>Will the gentleman yield?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400649" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield to the gentleman from Florida.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400273" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, I'm pleased to see we're doing something about this, but the Members should be aware of the procedure in the House of trying to change a light bulb. I tried to change one. It took filling out forms. This is to get an energy efficient one. Then two people appeared several days later, one with a form, one with a light bulb; an incredible waste of time, energy and taxpayer money to put in one fluorescent light bulb. I hope the procedure improves in the House.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400649" topic="">
    <paragraph>I agree with the gentleman. I certainly hope that we can improve that procedure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the meantime, we're improving the bulbs, making us more energy efficient here in the Capitol, and hopefully throughout these appropriations bills in this season.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="SCHULTZ, WASSERMAN" of="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, I ask unanimous consent to claim the time in opposition even though I am supportive of the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> Without objection, the gentlewoman from Florida is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="SCHULTZ, WASSERMAN" of="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, very briefly, I fully support this amendment and appreciate the bipartisan cooperation that was endeavored in moving it forward.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I do want to express some concern about how the light bulbs will be adapted to the historical lighting that we have in this facility, in the Capitol complex.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I look forward to working with the sponsors of the amendment as we move this legislation through conference to ensure that that occurs.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400166" topic="">
    <paragraph>Will the gentlewoman yield?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="SCHULTZ, WASSERMAN" of="">
    <paragraph>I would be happy to yield to the gentlewoman from California.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400166" topic="">
    <paragraph>We do have language in our bill that I just described, the one pending in the Energy and Commerce Committee to exempt historical lighting from the new goals. Hopefully we can invent light bulbs for historical lighting that are more efficient too, but we're trying to be reasonable here.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In response to earlier comments by Mr. Peterson, the goal is to help the domestic industry be able to produce efficient lighting. And the goal is also to set tough enough standards so that we save the enormous amount of energy that Mr. Upton was just mentioning.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400414" topic="">
    <paragraph>Will the gentlewoman yield?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="SCHULTZ, WASSERMAN" of="">
    <paragraph>I am happy to yield to the gentleman from Michigan.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400414" topic="">
    <paragraph>We just want to be on the record for this. Working with the Parliamentarians to make sure that the amendment is germane, we were not able to use the words "or equivalent" when we said "ENERGY STAR or equivalent." We would like to see that happen in the conference, but we know that that is legislating on an appropriation bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We would also like to have a provision for historical lighting. Again, that needs to happen in conference, it cannot happen on the House floor, and that's why we proceeded in that way. We look forward to working with all parties to make sure those concerns are addressed.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400649" topic="">
    <paragraph>Will the gentlewoman yield?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="SCHULTZ, WASSERMAN" of="">
    <paragraph>Reclaiming my time, I would be happy to yield to the gentleman from South Carolina.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400649" topic="">
    <paragraph>I think that, as Ms. Harman just pointed out and as the Chair of the committee has pointed out, there are some issues involving the aesthetics. You've got to choose the right light bulb, that's for sure. We've heard some discussion this morning about how they glow moon glow, or whatever. Well, if you pick the wrong kind, they do glow moon glow. I've got some in my garage, and it's a really freaky kind of look in there. But I've got some in the house that  look yellow and nice.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So you've got to pick the right bulbs. And of course in the historical context we have to pick the right bulbs. And we do have to deal with the recycling of these. Just like we don't have a sufficient program for recycling lead batteries around, we toss those in the trash, we have a problem with the mercury in these. But we can get there. We start by saving an awful lot of money and a lot of energy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="SCHULTZ, WASSERMAN" of="">
    <paragraph>I yield to the gentlewoman from California.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400166" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I did not mention earlier and would like to say that the Speaker's initiative, her Green Initiative, does also address this issue of trying to move away from inefficient incandescent bulbs. One more time, our goal would be to make incandescent bulbs, as well as other bulbs, more efficient.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are not choosing winners in this effort. But surely, everyone must understand that it takes 18 seconds to change a light bulb. This is something all of us can do quite quickly, except you have to comply with the House procedures that we just heard about.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am very excited about the notion that we are setting an example in this House and in this Congress about more efficient lighting.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="SCHULTZ, WASSERMAN" of="">
    <paragraph>I look forward to working with all of my colleagues and Mr. Wamp as we move through the conference process and commend them, as well as Speaker  Pelosi, for including the shifting from the light bulbs we use now to energy-efficient and environmentally friendly light bulbs as part of the initiative of the greening of the Capitol.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield back my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The question is on the amendment offered by the gentleman from South Carolina (Mr. Inglis).</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400134" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I offer an amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will designate the amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400134" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the Chair.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I brought with me today a stack of Congressional Records. All of us are familiar with these. We used to use them quite a bit, but today not so much. Today most of us just simply go on the computer and have a searchable version that is much faster, searchable back to 1989. With the click of a button, you can find what you are looking for. So we don't use these as much. Unfortunately, we haven't caught up with the times.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These are just a few of the thousands and thousands that are delivered that are never read. This was just from one office, the Legislative Research Center in the Cannon Building near my office. These are those that are just going to be thrown away today. One office that collects a few of these will throw these away just today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This year alone these records will cost the American taxpayer over $25 million. Recently my office did an informal survey of about 100 offices. We went in and said, "What do you do with the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Congressional Record that comes?" Virtually all of them, nearly every one of those 100 offices, said, "We throw them away. We wish they would stop delivering them." We had some offices say that they had requested that they stop being delivered. They are still delivered.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So they stack up. They are thrown away. They fill up landfills. I believe the figure is something like 57 tons of paper each year are thrown away just here.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Before the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Congressional Record was put on line, as I mentioned, they were useful, but they are not now. We obviously do have to have some paper copies. We simply don't need so many.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our amendment would simply do this, and I should add, this amendment was offered by myself and Mr. Blumenauer 2 years ago and was accepted by the then majority. It was simply taken out in the conference. I think we would do well to accept it again today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment would simply save $3.2 million annually by instructing the Government Printing Office to print only half as many copies. Today only 5,600 are printed. Half would do us just fine. That amendment would not reduce the funding for preparation, data collection or other aspects of the Record. It would simply reduce the ink-and-paper copies for half of what we print. So those who might oppose this amendment might say that it is going to cut deep and cut personal and others. It  won't as long as fewer records are printed. The costs will go down.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is simply a good way to save taxpayer money. It will show the country that we are interested ourselves in cleaning up our own house, making sure that we move ahead in a fiscally responsible manner.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400421" topic="">
    <paragraph>Will the gentleman yield?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400134" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield to the gentleman from Tennessee.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400421" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>You know, when we were in the majority, we supported and accepted this approach. I believe this is part, or should be part, of the Speaker's Green the Capitol Initiative. This is a lot of trees. It is a space efficiency issue. They are storing all this paper. It is a government efficiency issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Why don't we, Madam Chair, just accept this amendment, as we have in previous years, address this issue in conference, move right along and get Members on their way this afternoon?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for offering this amendment. I certainly support it.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400134" topic="">
    <paragraph>I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="SCHULTZ, WASSERMAN" of="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, I claim the time in opposition.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The gentlewoman from Florida is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="SCHULTZ, WASSERMAN" of="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, I rise in opposition to this amendment for a number of reasons.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While I support the gentleman, who is from the same generation that I am, in his endeavor to make sure that we can communicate and receive information in an electronic format, the approach that the gentleman is taking is absolutely inappropriate and won't accomplish his goal.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have crafted a tight and fiscally responsible bill. As I outlined in general debate, we have held the bill to a 4.1 percent increase. We actually held it to $276 million below the total request.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In their traditional views, the minority agreed. They said that, on balance, the funding provided in this bill to operate the legislative branch agencies is fiscally responsible. This amendment would add to existing shortfalls. It would add to what is already a growing funding shortfall in this account.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To be fiscally responsible, we have had to make some tough choices, including funding levels for GPO. The bill already, our colleagues should know, holds congressional printing and binding $62,000 below what was provided in fiscal year 2007. GPO is expecting an $8 million shortfall in this account in fiscal year 2007 in addition to a $3 million shortfall in fiscal year 2006. These shortfalls are due to the flat funding provided to this account since fiscal year 2007, in spite of increasing costs  and workloads. These shortfalls will continue in fiscal year 2008. Eventually they are going to have to be paid.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment would make that situation even worse. Most of the appropriation for congressional printing and binding goes towards Congress' printing requirements. I want to point out that the gentleman is incorrect when he states that there is a statute. While there is a statutory number in the Code that the GPO is told to print, they only print the number that is requisitioned. In other words, they only print, on a daily basis, the number that they are asked for. We have a deficit in the account  that allows them to print the number that is asked for. GPO has no control over those requirements. It's required by law to produce the information.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If the gentleman is concerned about the number of printed materials being produced, he should take it up with the authorizing committee, the Joint Committee on Printing, and seek reductions in the amount of material that GPO is required to print in the Code.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Simply gratuitously cutting out and leaving people with the impression that we are doing something, when we are not, and all we are doing here is cutting $3.2 million when GPO will still be required to print the Code, is the wrong approach. The suggestion that this amendment was accepted previously but then cut out in conference also leads people to believe that we have done something when we have not.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I refuse to be disingenuous when it comes to being forthright with the American people. We do need to make sure that in the future the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Congressional Record is produced electronically. This is not the right way to do it. It is irresponsible. I urge my colleagues to oppose this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400134" topic="">
    <paragraph>May I inquire as to the time remaining.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman controls 1 1/2  minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400134" topic="">
    <paragraph>Before yielding 1 minute to the gentleman from Oregon, let me point out, here is the Code. The Code states that we are supposed to print 30,000 a day, yet we only print 5,600. So, it is not the case that the GPO has to follow what the statute says. They are  required to do by demand. And they already do under; they can simply do less and save a lot of money.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield 1 minute to the gentleman from Oregon (Mr. Blumenauer).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400033" topic="">
    <paragraph>I appreciate the opportunity to join with my colleague again in this effort to try and reduce this output. I respect my friend, the chairwoman of the subcommittee, but I do think it is time for us to take a more aggressive action to reduce what is a gratuitous waste of resources and is a signal, I think, for us all to find ways to be able to deal with the electronic era.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a holdover. We have attempted in the past to be able to scale it down. I have also checked with legislative counsel to find out what we need to repeal. But I have been told that simply by enacting our amendment today, we will, in fact, achieve that objective in terms of reducing the number of unnecessary printed copies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="SCHULTZ, WASSERMAN" of="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, I just want to point out that the amendment offered by Mr. Flake does not say anything about reducing the number of copies printed of the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Congressional Record. It simply cuts $3.2 million out of the Congressional Printing and Binding account. It provides no direction. It simply cuts that funding. There is no assumption that any of what the gentleman is suggesting would occur. It would simply further add to the deficit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400134" topic="">
    <paragraph>Will the gentlelady yield, since I am out of time?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="SCHULTZ, WASSERMAN" of="">
    <paragraph>I believe the gentleman has his own time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The gentleman's time has expired.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="SCHULTZ, WASSERMAN" of="">
    <paragraph>How much time do I have left?</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The gentlewoman controls 1 1/2  minutes.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="SCHULTZ, WASSERMAN" of="">
    <paragraph>I yield the gentleman 30 seconds.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400134" topic="">
    <paragraph>Thank you. I appreciate the courtesy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me point out, just as with any program that is not an entitlement, everything is subject to appropriation. The Government Printing Office is not bound, no pun intended, to print as many copies as they think they need. They can print as many as they have money for. We were very careful in taking $3.2 million, to take only the printing costs for half of the number that are printed already. I think that is reasonable.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="SCHULTZ, WASSERMAN" of="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, I really believe that we should approach this in the appropriate way. If we want to change the statute and go to electronic production of the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Congressional Record, that is what we should do. We should not simply hamstring the GPO by requiring them to print a &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Congressional Record and not ensuring they have adequate funds to do that, when they are already in a deficit situation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to oppose the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400033" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, this amendment is simple: by instructing the Government Printing Office (GPO) to print half the number of CONGRESSIONAL RECORDS daily, we will save $3.2 million in taxpayer dollars and 57 tons of paper annually.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An unofficial survey of House offices revealed that many swiftly discard their daily copy of the CONGRESSIONAL RECORD. And why shouldn't they? The full, easily searchable text of the RECORD is available online back to the year 1989. As electronic viewing of this resource becomes more widespread, we must continue to adjust the number of printed copies accordingly. In fact, since 1995 we have reduced the number of daily printed CONGRESSIONAL RECORDS from 18,000 to 5,600 per  day.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have an opportunity to save millions of dollars by taking advantage of paperless technology and pushing House operations into the 21st Century. I commend Speaker PELOSI in her recent effort to "Green the Capitol" and this is a common-sense amendment that is consistent with that initiative.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="SCHULTZ, WASSERMAN" of="">
    <paragraph>I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The question is on the amendment offered by the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Flake).</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400134" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I demand a recorded vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 6 of rule XVIII, further proceedings on the amendment offered by the gentleman from Arizona will be postponed.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412226" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I offer an amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will designate the amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412226" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the Chair.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank the Chair of the committee and the ranking member for their good work and the committee's work. I know for the Chair in particular, I want to congratulate her on the first bill coming through her subcommittee, a very important subcommittee of the Appropriations Committee. So I appreciate the fine work done there and the oversight of the visitors center. The passion with which the ranking member spoke about Emancipation Hall I thought was right on target. So I appreciate the work  done.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment, just like the amendment I offered last night to the Foreign Operations bill, simply says this: instead of increasing spending by 4 percent, let's hold the line. I articulated reasons last night in the long debate that this body had over why that is appropriate, why that makes sense. Because there is in fact a crisis looming for this country if we don't get control of the spending here in the United States Congress, in the United States Senate and the United States Government.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is important that we recognize that. I articulated last night too, don't take my word for it. Yesterday's Washington Post talked about this growing problem that is coming in the very near future, and it is important we understand that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I won't go through all the arguments again here, because I know we have had a long debate and people want to get on their way and get back to their district.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I will just say this: ever-increasing spending inevitably leads to ever-increasing taxes. The American families, the American people are overtaxed because our government spends too much. It has been a problem for both parties. We need to get it under control.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Millions of families, millions of families across this country are going to live on last year's budget. It is not too much to ask the United States Government, in particular the United States Congress, to do the same.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="SCHULTZ, WASSERMAN" of="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, I rise in opposition to the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The gentlewoman from Florida is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="SCHULTZ, WASSERMAN" of="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, this is a fiscally responsible bill. Again, we have held the bill to a 4.1 percent increase, only $122 million over actual spending in fiscal year 2007, and if you take into consideration the $50 million rescission in the CR, we are at a 2.3 percent increase. That is $276 million below the total budget request.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, I want to point to the minority views, where the minority agreed this bill is fiscally responsible. They say, "On balance, the funding provided in this bill to operate the legislative branch agencies is fiscally responsible."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill funds the must-have's, not the nice-to-have's, by targeting increases towards keeping the agencies running, providing Congress with the tools it needs to perform its oversight responsibility, and funding critical security and life safety projects.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The amendment, if adopted, would eliminate $50 million worth of critical health and safety and security projects that we would be unable to fund if a 4 percent across-the-board reduction were adopted.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment would eliminate funding for things like the $5 million we have in this bill to ensure that the Capitol Police have interoperable radios. According to the new police chief, a new radio system is their number one priority. The existing radio system is 20 years old. It is antiquated and outdated. It is not encrypted nor secure, and it is not interoperable. Hurricane Katrina showed the importance of interoperable communications during a crisis.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It also would eliminate funding potentially monitoring the utility tunnel abatement. We had tunnel workers who were subjected to horrendous conditions and have been exposed to asbestos, and we are endeavoring to make sure that we can make up for that and provide the funding for the abatement. That would be impossible if this amendment were adopted.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We provide $1.2 million for escape hoods for our Library visitors, $1 million for emergency exit signs and lighting in the capital, and emergency lighting upgrades in Rayburn.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The amendment would also impair our agency's work. It would put the legislative branch agencies back to a fiscal year 2006 funding level since there was no increase in 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In practical terms, the impact of this would be less capability on the part of GAO to assist Congress in its oversight responsibilities; fewer and less timely products from CRS to assist Members in their legislative duties, a further reduction in CBO's ability to score Member bills, which was pointed out in the Rules Committee as already being a problem; elimination of the digital talking book conversion program for the blind; a reduced ability for the Office of Compliance to pursue health safety  issues around the Capitol complex, even as we get ready to add new space with the approaching opening of the CVC; the Architect's operations would be strained to keep up with increases in utility costs; and, finally, since 77 percent of this bill is labor costs, as is most of the increase, this amendment would surely result in a reduction in our workforce.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is irresponsible. Mr. Wamp and I have endeavored to put forward a bill that is fiscally responsible, fiscally tight, and ensures the life, safety and security needs of the people who work and visit here.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="412226" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield 30 seconds to the gentleman from Tennessee (Mr. Wamp), the distinguished ranking member of the committee.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400421" topic="">
    <paragraph>I wasn't going to say anything, but I just want to say that because we have not accepted commonsense amendments like the previous amendment, and because the Rules Committee only granted three amendments in order, we are losing a lot of support for this bill on this side of the aisle unnecessarily because I do think we worked hard to make it fiscally responsible. But they are making a strong case, and we have closed the process down instead of opening it up.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412226" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield 2 minutes to the distinguished gentleman from Texas (Mr. Hensarling), the chairman of the Republican Study Committee.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400175" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for yielding, and I want to thank him for his outstanding leadership on the issue of fiscal responsibility, coming to the floor and offering this series of amendments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I do want to thank the chairman of the subcommittee and the ranking member. Certainly relative to many other appropriations bills that we have seen and will see on this floor, relatively speaking, this is a more fiscally responsible bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But we can never forget that this is not our money; this is the people's money. And every time we are increasing some aspect of the Federal budget, we are taking it away from some family budget. We are taking it away from some family that had a dream of having a down payment on their first home. We are taking it away from some family who was putting that money away for college tuition for one of their children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So contrary to the debate we hear and the rhetoric about cuts, what this amendment does is say, you know, let's lead by example. In the big scheme of the Federal budget, I know this isn't a huge amount of money. But when you think about having to save us from the single largest tax increase in history that the Democrat majority put in their last budget, shouldn't we lead by example? Is this apocalyptic vision that we hear, is this going to happen if we give the legislative branch the same money  they had last year? Somehow there are families all across America who are having to make do on the same income they had last year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, again, relative to other bills, this is more fiscally responsible. But it comes down to a simple choice: Do you want to put us on the path for the largest single tax increase in American history that would impose $3,000 of additional tax burden on American families, or do you want to put us on the path of fiscal responsibility? We should support the gentleman's amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="SCHULTZ, WASSERMAN" of="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, how much time do I have left?</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The gentlewoman controls 2 minutes. The gentleman from Ohio controls 1 minute.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="SCHULTZ, WASSERMAN" of="">
    <paragraph>I would ask that he speak for 1 minute and then we will close in opposition.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="412226" topic="">
    <paragraph>I will be brief and just point out this: we heard some of the terrible things that are going to happen if we keep the spending at the same level we had last year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The American people need to understand this, Madam Chair: $3.1 billion is what this bill spends. My amendment would say $3 billion, $3 billion to run the United States Congress. You ask American families that, they would probably say, you know, that is probably enough. They can probably get by on $3 billion versus $3.1 billion. That is all this does. As the gentleman from Texas pointed out, in the course of the appropriation bills we have been dealing with, this is fairly fiscally responsible.  But $3 billion is enough to run the United States Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is all this amendment would do, keep us where we are right now. Things are working fine now. Why can't we do that in the future?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="SCHULTZ, WASSERMAN" of="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chair, at this time I yield the balance of our time to the gentleman from Virginia (Mr. Moran), the former ranking member of this subcommittee.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The gentleman from Virginia is recognized for 2 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400283" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the Chair, and I particularly want to congratulate Chairman Wasserman Schultz, because she took on a very difficult responsibility and she has performed in a conscientious, extraordinarily fiscally responsible manner.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a bill that all of the Members have an interest in, and all of the Members have issues within this bill that they would particularly like to see increased, and some decreased. But it is a difficult one.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>She has told me how much she appreciates the ranking member, Mr. Wamp, and I hope Mr. Wamp is listening, how much she appreciates Mr. Wamp's cooperation in coming up with a bill that was acceptable to the overwhelming number of the full Appropriations Committee members when they reported it out to the floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, this bill is $276 million below the President's request. That is extraordinary, and it is the first time that the Legislative Branch appropriations bill has reflected that deep a cut versus the President's request. So if you are looking for fiscal responsibility, you will find it in this bill, more than any other appropriations bill. We congratulate Mr. Wamp, as well as the chairwoman, for coming up with a bill that accomplishes that kind of fiscal responsibility.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But if anybody else wants to cut another $100 million, which this amendment would do, below that, then it is concomitant upon the proponent of that amendment to say exactly where you would make those cuts. Because this is the result of a lot of give and take, a lot of compromise, a lot of very conscientious investigation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the amendment offered by the gentleman from Ohio (Mr. Jordan).</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412226" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I demand a recorded vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 6 of rule XVIII, further proceedings on the amendment offered by the gentleman from Ohio will be postponed.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400290" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, on Friday, June 22, 2007, I was absent during rollcall vote No. 545. Had I been present, I would have voted "no" on agreeing to the Flake of Arizona amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 5-minute vote.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400290" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, on Friday, June 22, 2007, I was absent during rollcall vote No. 546. Had I been present, I would have voted "no" on agreeing to the Jordan of Ohio Amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Under the rule, the Committee rises.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400221" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>I am in its current form.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will report the motion to recommit.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> The gentleman from Georgia is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400221" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I offer this amendment to bring something to the Members' attention that I think is very important.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are about to create a fourth building for the House of Representatives. We have Cannon, we have Rayburn, we have Longworth. We are about to put on another 200,000-square-foot building. I think you should know about it, and I think we deserve a vote on it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Number one, this is an earmark. Now, we have been talking weeks and weeks and months and months about transparency and ending earmarks. Yet if you will look in the report on page 20, there is a $16 million earmark for a new House office building. There is no explanation of the project, no total cost, there have been no hearings and no oversight, and it is not in the Democrat budget. It was not requested by the Architect of the Capitol, and, yet, it's in the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, looks like a duck, walks like a duck, could be an earmark. That's where we are on this.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Number two, I think Members have the right to vote on a fourth office building. As former chair of this committee, one of the big frustrations I have about the Capitol Visitors Center is none of us owned the project. There wasn't one person that you could say it's his or her fault. It was all diluted and by committee. We never had a vote on it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Indeed, when I was a chairman of this committee, a staffer put in $18 million to renovate the House floor, which none of us knew about. I took the money out of it, as did Chairman Lewis last year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But things get stuck in the bills that we don't know about that we deserve a vote on. This gives you an opportunity, unlike the CVC, which started out as a $260 million project, with partial private funding, and now is up to $600 million.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This motion to recommit gives you the opportunity to vote on something and say no to something that has already cost this House $140 million. This is a 200,000-square-foot building. That's the size of 15 House floors. It's the size of four White Houses. It's five football fields big. This isn't incidental swing space.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What is this needed for? In case we renovate the Cannon House Office Building. Now, don't you want to vote on that? I haven't had a debate on renovating the Cannon Office Building, but I want to know about it. This is a big building of substance, and you deserve a vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Incidentally, this isn't going to be the only new building. We are adding 580,000 square feet in the form of the Capitol Visitors Center.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This building is huge. To move forward, it's going to cost us not the $16 million that's in the bill, but actually $56 million, and then another $12 million to lease it, plus $18 million for furniture for it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Think about it. How many times have we heard from some Members in a rather preachy fashion, we need to control our carbon footprints? Ladies and gentlemen, all of those of you who want to reduce our carbon footprint, here is your opportunity. Say "no" to a 200,000-square-foot boondoggle which we are about to put in.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This has not had the proper oversight, it has not had the proper hearings. The contracts have all been verbal. That's why we are all in the situation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="SCHULTZ, WASSERMAN" of="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I claim the time in opposition.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The gentlewoman from Florida is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="SCHULTZ, WASSERMAN" of="">
    <paragraph>I want to point out and remind my colleagues that Mr. Wamp and I are proud to report to you that we have brought the legislative branch appropriations bill in at $276 million below the request. The easiest thing in the world to do is jump on the table and to cry waste.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to also point out that this is a security upgrade, funding for security upgrades requested by former Speaker Hastert and continued by Speaker Pelosi so that we can ensure that we provide swing space for our very cramped space so that we can properly renovate the Cannon and Longworth House Office Buildings.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask my colleagues to come over and look at these pictures of the deterioration of our facilities. These are pictures of the 100-year-old Cannon House Office Building. If you take a look at the deterioration and life, safety and security upgrades that this facility needs, we can no longer wait to make these upgrades, and to make sure that we can protect the people who work here and the people who visit us. They are deteriorating and badly in need of renovation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What the gentleman from Georgia's motion to recommit would do is delay for years, if not make it impossible, for us to begin renovation and repairs on our aging House facilities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My colleagues, this committee does not deal with the sexiest of subjects that confront us every day, and I have only been here for 2 years and the chair of this subcommittee for the last 5 months. You don't earn a reputation as an institutionalist in that short period of time, but it is my hope to be able to do that over time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are stewards of this great institution, but we are also stewards just as much of these facilities. My colleague on the Appropriations Committee, Jos&#xE9; Serrano of New York, recently made a wonderful suggestion to remind us of the history embedded even in what may seem mundane, the space we occupy each day. He suggested that we each have plaques in our offices with the names of our predecessors in Congress who occupied that space before us. My own office, I was thrilled to learn,  was once occupied by former Congressman Lyndon Johnson.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My point is they may seem like buildings and office space to the outside world, but we know better. How many of us countless times have found ourselves approaching this beautiful building we are now in and marveling privately to ourselves, wow, I work here, what an incredible privilege.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But with privilege comes responsibility. We must think about the institution, but we must also think about our hard-working staff. The number of hours they toil in these facilities is mind-boggling. You might be surprised to learn that the average work space for each of our staff is about 36 square feet. And I want to show you what 36 square feet is. This is 36 square feet. That is how much space that we allot, on average, to our employees.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>GSA recommends an average of 100 square feet of space per employee. We need to renovate so that we can make sure we are not cramming our staff into unreasonable boxes for hours on end. Our staff make incredible sacrifices to serve the public, our constituents, and they help us do our job. We must make sure that we keep these facilities, the place they work every day and night, safe for them. We must make sure we keep these facilities safe and in good condition for our constituents and our successors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Kingston's amendment is well-meaning, but it is not responsible, and it is not an eye toward the future with respect for our past. I strongly urge you to vote against the motion to recommit.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400189" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Would the gentlelady yield?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="SCHULTZ, WASSERMAN" of="">
    <paragraph>I would be happy to yield to the gentleman.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400189" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>It was my understanding you indicated this is the initiative of Speaker Hastert; am I accurate?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="SCHULTZ, WASSERMAN" of="">
    <paragraph>Yes, it is. It is an initiative from former Speaker Hastert.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I strongly urge you to vote against the motion to recommit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> Without objection, the previous question is ordered on the motion to recommit.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400221" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I demand a recorded vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 9 of rule XX, the Chair will reduce to 5 minutes the minimum time for any electronic vote on the question of passage.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400139" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, on rollcall No. 547, had I been present, I would have voted "aye."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Stated against:</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400290" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, on Friday, June 22, 2007, I was absent during rollcall vote No. 547. Had I been present, I would have voted "no" on the motion to recommit on <bill type="h" number="2771">H.R. 2771</bill>, Legislative Branch Appropriations for FY 2008.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the passage of the bill.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400290" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, on Friday, June 22, 2007, I was absent during rollcall vote No. 548. Had I been present, I would have voted "yea" on passage <bill type="h" number="2771">H.R. 2771</bill>, Legislative Branch Appropriations for FY 2008.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
