<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1179158403" ordinal="17" title="S/SGT LEWIS G. WATKINS POST OFFICE BUILDING">
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="1335">H.R. 1335</bill>) to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 508 East Main Street in Seneca, South Carolina, as the "S/Sgt Lewis G. Watkins Post Office Building".</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Davis) and the gentleman from Georgia (Mr. Westmoreland) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days in which to revise and extend their remarks.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Illinois?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I might consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a member of the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, I am pleased to join my colleague in consideration of <bill type="h" number="1335">H.R. 1335</bill>, which names a postal facility in Seneca, South Carolina, after Lewis G. Watkins.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1335">H.R. 1335</bill>, which was introduced by Representative J. Gresham Barrett on March 6, 2007, was reported from the Oversight Committee on May 1, 2007, by a voice vote. This measure has been cosponsored by the five members of the South Carolina congressional delegation, which represents the delegation indeed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Staff Sergeant Lewis G. Watkins served in action during the Korean conflict. He heroically sacrificed his life in combat on October 7, 1952, in Korea. He was a recipient of the Congressional Medal of Honor for his conspicuous gallantry and intrepidity at the risk of his life beyond the call of duty while serving as a guide of a rifle platoon of Company I, 3rd Battalion, 7th Marines, 1st Marine Division.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Staff Sergeant Watkins' extraordinary heroism, inspiring leadership, and resolute spirit of self-sacrifice reflected the highest credit upon himself and enhances the finest traditions of the U.S. naval service. He gave his life for his country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, Mr. Speaker, I commend my colleague Representative Barrett for introducing this legislation and urge swift passage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400627" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself as much time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We often come to the floor to talk about our brave soldiers fighting in Iraq and Afghanistan; but today I am proud to speak about a hero, a highly decorated Korean War veteran, Lewis G. Watkins.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Staff Sergeant Lewis G. Watkins was born in Seneca, South Carolina, on June 6, 1925. After graduating from Greenville High School, he joined the Greenville Police Department. Furthering his public service, he enlisted in the United States Marine Corps in 1950. After his training in Camp Lejeune and Camp Pendleton, he was sent to serve in Korea.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Staff Sergeant Watkins fought valiantly during his only tour of duty. On October 7, 1952, his unit was attempting to take an outpost from the enemy. While leading his men up a hill and fighting off heavy small-arms fire and grenades, he was severely injured. Pushing through the pain, he successfully led his team further up the hill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It was then that he noticed a grenade had landed nearby. Pushing his comrades aside to protect them, he instinctively grabbed the grenade to throw it out of harm's way. Unfortunately, the bomb exploded in his hand and he was mortally wounded. His heroic actions on that hill saved the lives of his fellow soldiers; and it was for this act of bravery and courage he deservedly, albeit posthumously, was awarded the Nation's highest military decoration, the Medal of Honor. His other awards include  the Purple Heart, the United Nations Service Medal, and the Korean War Service Medal with two bronze stars.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Staff Sergeant Lewis G. Watkins' life and military achievements are to be commended. He fought and died for his country; and today we honor his heroism, his self-sacrifice, and his inspiring leadership by naming this post office after him.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I commend my colleague Mr. Barrett for bringing this to our attention.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400627" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield as much time as he may consume to my very distinguished colleague from the great State of South Carolina (Mr. Barrett).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400016" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I thank the gentleman from Georgia for yielding and also for Representative Davis today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would also like to thank Chairman Henry Waxman and Ranking Member Tom Davis of the House Oversight and Government Reform Committee for facilitating such swift consideration of this bill that recognizes such an honorable man.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of <bill type="h" number="1335">H.R. 1335</bill>, a bill that honors the life and sacrifices of Staff Sergeant Lewis Watkins who gave his life for his country in the Korean War. Lewis Watkins was born on June 6, 1925, in Seneca, South Carolina. He graduated from Greenville High School in South Carolina in 1949.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He was a member of the Greenville Police Department where he enlisted in the United States Marine Corps on September 12, 1950. After training at Parris Island, South Carolina, he served at Camp Lejeune, North Carolina, and Camp Pendleton, California, before being deployed to Korea.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On October 7, 1952, Sergeant Watkins' platoon was assigned to retake an outpost from the enemy. Even though Sergeant Watkins had been wounded during the fight, he continued to lead his men and return gunfire on the enemy machine gun position holding up the assault. At one point, an enemy grenade landed among his men. Selflessly and without thinking, he pushed his men out of harm's way and picked up the grenade. While attempting to throw the grenade back toward the enemy, it exploded in his hand,  fatally wounding him.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sergeant Watkins heroically sacrificed his life to save the lives of his fellow marines under his command, and in doing so, helped contribute to the overall success of his unit's mission during the Korean War.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank Sergeant Watkins and his family for his service. Every American owes a debt of gratitude for his service and his sacrifice.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, every member of the South Carolina delegation cosponsored this legislation as a way to say thank you and honor a man who gave his life for his country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, Staff Sergeant Lewis Watkins is the only known native Oconee County resident to receive a Medal of Honor. To designate the post office facility located at 508 East Main Street in Seneca, South Carolina, as the S/Sgt Lewis G. Watkins Post Office Building is one way we can pay tribute to his life. It will allow all who enter the post office and view the dedication plaque a unique opportunity to be  mindful of the sacrifices our military have  made and continue to make today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to the Medal of Honor, Watkins' decorations include the Purple Heart Medal; Korean Service Medal with two bronze stars; and the United Nations Service Medal.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>Lewis Watkins made the ultimate sacrifice for his country, and I am honored that this country is about to bestow upon his memory and his family yet another recognition.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is a verse that says, "No greater love hath he," and Lewis Watkins proved that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I urge swift passage of <bill type="h" number="1335">H.R. 1335</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400627" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Let me say that it has, indeed, been a pleasure to work with the gentleman from Georgia (Mr. Westmoreland) and I thank him, and I urge swift passage of this resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of our time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Davis) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="1335">H.R. 1335</bill>.</chair>
</record>
