<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1204045202" ordinal="45" title="VICTIMS OF CRIME ACT">
  <narrative>VICTIMS OF CRIME ACT -- (House of Representatives - February 26, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H1057]</narrative>
  <chair> Under a previous order of the House, the gentleman from Texas (Mr. Poe) is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400652" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I want to talk about one of the novel concepts that Congress has come up with over the years. It goes back to the Reagan administration and a bipartisan bill signed by President Reagan, the VOCA Act was established. It is called the Victims of Crime Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So what is the problem? The problem is, Mr. Sp eaker, that that fund, every year, that's administered by the Federal Government continues to be robbed by other bureaucrats and continues to be less money that's available for crime victims. This year we have $1.7 billion in the fund. Last year $635 million of that was used for crime victims, but this year the fund is being cut by the bureaucrats to $590 million. That's not a lot of money, but it means that victims shelters throughout the country</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So why is that happening, Mr. Speaker? I do not know.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I do know that the Justice Department now is going to charge a surcharge on the victims fund of 5.5 percent to administer the fund. They are doing so without the approval of Congress. They have no right to take $30 million to pay for their own bureaucracy. That's not authorized by Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We also know that the administration wants to take part of that money and apply it to other prog rams out there.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Once again, this is not taxpayer money. It's money that belongs to victims. And the Federal Government and, specifically, the Justice Department and the Federal bureaucrats need to keep their hands off that money, because it's not their money. It belongs to victims of crime.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, victims of crime do not have a lobbyist up here in Washington, DC, a high-dollar lobbyist advocating on their behalf. They expect us, Members of Congress, to be their lobbyist, and it's important tha t we do not let the bureaucrats, the robber barons take money out of that VOCA fund and apply it to other programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Find that money somewhere else. This money belongs to crime victims. It should not be robbed by the bureaucrats. It should be left alone. And, if anything, we ought to raise how much money we take out of that fund for victims of crime.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It's $1.7 billion this year. Next year it's going to be $1.9 billion criminals contribute to that fund. And yet our government continues to let less and</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Victims of Crime Act is a good idea. Let's leave it alone and quit robbing it to pay for other Federal programs. And if the Federal Government needs money to pay for these other programs, take money out of foreign aid or something. But leave victims alone.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Victims are a unique breed of people in our country, Mr. Speaker, and it's our responsibility to take care of  them and make sure that they get the compensation they need, paid for by criminals who commit crimes against them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And that's just the way it is.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
