<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1181059208" ordinal="27" title="LOWER RIO GRANDE VALLEY WATER RESOURCES CONSERVATION AND IMPROVEMENT ACT OF 2007">
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="361">H.R. 361</bill>) to amend the Lower Rio Grande Valley Water Resources Conservation and Improvement Act of 2000 to authorize additional projects and activities under that Act, and for other purposes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from the Virgin Islands (Mrs. Christensen) and the gentleman from Utah (Mr. Cannon) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from the Virgin Islands?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would like to first commend our colleague from Texas, and my classmate, Representative Hinojosa, for his dedication to and hard work on this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of <bill type="h" number="361">H.R. 361</bill> is to amend the Lower Rio Grande Valley Water Resources Conservation and Improvement Act of 2000 to authorize additional projects and related activities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="361">H.R. 361</bill>, when enacted, would authorize limited Federal assistance for 19 projects aimed at conserving water or improving water supply. This would include the replacement of irrigation canals and lateral canals, the lining of channels and the installation of water level, flow measurement, pump control, and remote control systems.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation would help to accomplish a more sustainable water supply by enhancing existing water distribution systems and monitoring water resources.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank Mr. Hinojosa for his efforts on this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would like to ask unanimous consent to have his remarks inserted into the Record, and I urge my colleagues to join me in supporting <bill type="h" number="361">H.R. 361</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="361">H.R. 361</bill> and yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The gentlewoman from the Virgin Islands has appropriately explained the bill, which has passed the bill in the last two Congresses in one form or another. I support the bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400179" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="361">H.R. 361</bill>, a bill that will authorize a number of projects which will improve irrigation and water conservation throuhgout the Rio Grande Valley. I want to thank Chairman Rahall and Chairwoman Napolitano as well as my colleagues from the Texas Border Region, Congressmen Ortiz, Reyes, Rodriguez, and Cuellar for their support in bringing this vitally important legislation onto the House floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I represent a region of the country that is experiencing phenomenal population growth yet is subject to severe periodic droughts. The 2000 Census showed that the population of Hidalgo County, in my district, increased by 48 percent. On the Mexican side of the border, millions have come to work in the maquiladoras and to take advantage of the economic boom that has come from NAFTA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This growth has placed an enormous strain on water delivery systems throughout the Texas-Mexico border region. Water intended for irrigating crops flows through open dirt ditches where much of the precious water supply is lost to seepage and evaporation. Municipalities also rely on the water from these inefficient and outdated irrigation delivery systems to meet the water needs of growing communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="361">H.R. 361</bill> will authorize 19 projects that will allow border water districts to continue upgrading and modernizing our antiquated water delivery systems through the installation of water pipes and canal linings. Similar projects were authorized in the 106th and 107th Congresses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Rio Grande Valley has already made a great deal of progress because this has been a collaborative effort. The irrigation district have provided matching funds. The Texas Water Development Board and Texas A&amp;M University have paid for many of the engineering studies. Federal appropriators have provided more than $10 million. As a result, we are seeing water savings of almost 80 percent in the projects that have been completed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Most importantly, Federal authorization has allowed us to tap into the resources of the North American Development Bank. To date, NADBank has approved almost $24 million for these projects and passage of <bill type="h" number="361">H.R. 361</bill> will make these new projects eligible for NADBank assistance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These funds are being put to good use. Numerous projects are already underway and some are almost completed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When the metering system is fully installed, irrigation districts will have a much clearer picture of water usage and water savings. This data will be vital to improving water management throughout the region.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from the Virgin Islands (Mrs. Christensen) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="361">H.R. 361</bill>.</chair>
</record>
