<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1185163200" ordinal="22" title="BAY AREA REGIONAL WATER RECYCLING PROGRAM AUTHORIZATION ACT OF 2007">
  <narrative>BAY AREA REGIONAL WATER RECYCLING PROGRAM AUTHORIZATION ACT OF 2007 -- (House of Representatives - July 23, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H8196]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="1526">H.R. 1526</bill>) to amend the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Bay Area Regional Water Recycling Program, and for other purposes, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="1526">H.R. 1526</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "Bay Area Regional Water Recycling Program Authorization Act of 2007".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. PROJECT AUTHORIZATIONS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) In General.--The Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act (Public Law 102-575, title XVI; 43 U.S.C. 390h et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;"SEC. 16xx. MOUNTAIN VIEW, MOFFETT AREA RECLAIMED WATER PIPELINE PROJECT.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(a) Authorization.--The Secretary, in cooperation with the City of Palo Alto, California, and the City of Mountain View, California, is authorized to participate in the design, planning, and construction of recycled water distribution systems.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(b) Cost Share.--The Federal share of the cost of the project authorized by this section shall not exceed 25 percent of the total cost of the project.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(c) Limitation.--The Secretary shall not provide funds for the operation and maintenance of the project authorized by this section.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(d) Authorization of Appropriations.--There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $5,000,000.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;"SEC. 16xx. PITTSBURG RECYCLED WATER PROJECT.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(a) Authorization.--The Secretary, in cooperation with the City of Pittsburg, California, and the Delta Diablo Sanitation District, is authorized to participate in the design, planning, and construction of recycled water system facilities.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(b) Cost Share.--The Federal share of the cost of the project authorized by this section shall not exceed 25 percent of the total cost of the project.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(c) Limitation.--The Secretary shall not provide funds for the operation and maintenance of the project authorized by this section.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(d) Authorization of Appropriations.--There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $1,750,000.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;"SEC. 16xx. ANTIOCH RECYCLED WATER PROJECT.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(a) Authorization.--The Secretary, in cooperation with the City of Antioch, California, and the Delta Diablo Sanitation District, is authorized to participate in the design, planning, and construction of recycled water system facilities.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(b) Cost Share.--The Federal share of the cost of the project authorized by this section shall not exceed 25 percent of the total cost of the project.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(c) Limitation.--The Secretary shall not provide funds for the operation and maintenance of the project authorized by this section.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(d) Authorization of Appropriations.--There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $2,250,000.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;"SEC. 16xx. NORTH COAST COUNTY WATER DISTRICT RECYCLED WATER PROJECT.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(a) Authorization.--The Secretary, in cooperation with the North Coast County Water District, is authorized to participate in the design, planning, and construction of recycled water system facilities.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(b) Cost Share.--The Federal share of the cost of the project authorized by this section shall not exceed 25 percent of the total cost of the project.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(c) Limitation.--The Secretary shall not provide funds for the operation and maintenance of the project authorized by this section.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(d) Authorization of Appropriations.--There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $2,500,000.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;"SEC. 16xx. REDWOOD CITY RECYCLED WATER PROJECT.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(a) Authorization.--The Secretary, in cooperation with the City of Redwood City, California, is authorized to participate in the design, planning, and construction of recycled water system facilities.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(b) Cost Share.--The Federal share of the cost of the project authorized by this section shall not exceed 25 percent of the total cost of the project.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(c) Limitation.--The Secretary shall not provide funds for the operation and maintenance of the project authorized by this section.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(d) Authorization of Appropriations.--There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $1,100,000.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;"SEC. 16xx. SOUTH SANTA CLARA COUNTY RECYCLED WATER PROJECT.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(a) Authorization.--The Secretary, in cooperation with the South County Regional Wastewater Authority and the Santa Clara Valley Water District, is authorized to participate in the design, planning, and construction of recycled water system distribution facilities.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(b) Cost Share.--The Federal share of the cost of the project authorized by this section shall not exceed 25 percent of the total cost of the project.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(c) Limitation.--The Secretary shall not provide funds for the operation and maintenance of the project authorized by this section.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(d) Authorization of Appropriations.--There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $7,000,000.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;"SEC. 16xx. SOUTH BAY ADVANCED RECYCLED WATER TREATMENT FACILITY.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(a) Authorization.--The Secretary, in cooperation with the City of San Jose, California, and the Santa Clara Valley Water District, is authorized to participate in the design, planning, and construction of recycled water treatment facilities.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(b) Cost Share.--The Federal share of the cost of the project authorized by this section shall not exceed 25 percent of the total cost of the project.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(c) Limitation.--The Secretary shall not provide funds for the operation and maintenance of the project authorized by this section.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(d) Authorization of Appropriations.--There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $8,250,000.".</narrative>
  <narrative> (b) Conforming Amendments.--The table of sections for Public Law 102-575 is amended by inserting after the last item relating to title XVI the following:&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <narrative>"Sec..16xx..Mountain View, Moffett Area Reclaimed Water Pipeline Project.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;"Sec..16xx..Pittsburg Recycled Water Project.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;"Sec..16xx..Antioch Recycled Water Project.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;"Sec..16xx..North Coast County Water District Recycled Water Project.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;"Sec..16xx..Redwood City Recycled Water Project.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;"Sec..16xx..South Santa Clara County Recycled Water Project. &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;"Sec..16xx..South Bay Advanced Recycled Water Treatment Facility.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 3. SAN JOSE AREA WATER RECLAMATION AND REUSE PROJECT.</narrative>
  <narrative> It is the intent of Congress that a comprehensive water recycling program for the San Francisco Bay Area include the San Jose Area water reclamation and reuse program authorized by section 1607 of the Reclamation Projects Authorization and Adjustment Act of 1992 (43 U.S.C. 390h-5). &lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) and the gentlewoman from Washington (Mrs. McMorris Rodgers) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Arizona.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members have 5 legislative days to revise and extend and include extraneous material on the bill under legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Arizona?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would first like to recognize Representative George Miller's hard work and dedication to this legislation, and for his leadership in California water policy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation would authorize the Secretary of the Interior to participate in seven important water supply projects as part of the Bay Area Regional Water Recycling Program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>The projects authorized by the enactment of <bill type="h" number="1526">H.R. 1526</bill>, as amended, will eventually produce 37,600 acre feet of recycled water annually. The water will be critical as California communities work to protect their water supply from future droughts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I thank Congressman George Miller for his hard work on the legislation. I urge my colleagues to join me in supporting <bill type="h" number="1526">H.R. 1526</bill>, as amended.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mrs." name="RODGERS, McMORRIS" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the chairman has adequately explained the bill. I note that this is another water recycling bill which will make the $328 million funding backlog in the program worse because the majority did not fully fund it in the Energy and Water appropriations bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr Speaker, this water recycling legislation, <bill type="h" number="1526">H.R. 1526</bill>, enables local agencies across California's Bay-Delta region to invest in sustainable and reliable new water supplies. I urge my colleagues to support the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Bay Area Regional Water Recycling Program Authorization Act will provide Federal assistance for an ambitious and forward-thinking regional water recycling program that will reduce demand on the Bay-Delta and drought-proof our regional municipal water supplies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation will assist efforts in Pittsburg, Antioch, Palo Alto, Mountain View, Pacifica, South Santa Clara County, Redwood City, and San Jose.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The city of Pittsburg and the Delta Diablo Sanitation District, in my congressional district, have been leading the charge on this effort, investing time, energy, and local funds in developing water recycling projects to help meet regional water needs. Water recycling is good for the environment and for local budgets.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In Pittsburg, for example, instead of using fresh water from the Delta, recycled water will be applied to city parks, golf courses, medians, and other green spaces. As the Contra Costa Times wrote about the bill, "There is no good reason to flush wastewater into rivers, bays, estuaries, and the ocean if it can be treated and used again for other purposes such as irrigating parks and golf courses."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank Chairman Nick Rahall and Chairwoman Grace Napolitano, and the staff of the Natural Resources Committee and the Subcommiteee on Water and Power, for their assistance in this effort, and I encourage my colleagues to support this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400124" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, first all my thanks to Representative GEORGE MILLER for his leadership and vision for sponsoring this legislation which I'm proud to be an original cosponsor of.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation authorizes a total of seven new projects, including two in my district: the Mountain View Moffett Area Recycled Water Distribution Project and the Redwood City Recycled Water Project.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since the 1990's a partnership of 17 local Bay Area governments, water, and wastewater agencies, the Bureau of Reclamation, and the California Department of Water Resources have worked to maximize water recycling around the Bay under the auspices of the Bay Area Regional Water Recycling Program (BARWRP). They have been found by the Bureau of Reclamation to be feasible or close to achieving feasibility, and they're now ready to move into construction with significant local funding commitments  consistent with the Bureau of Reclamation's Title XVI water recycling program. Under the bill, the federal government may provide up to 25% of the cost of the planning, designing, and building each project, and the local sponsors will be responsible for securing at least 75 percent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Despite the significant investments that communities have already made to these projects, they have not been able to secure federal funds because of a lack of investment by the Bureau of Reclamation in the Title XVI program and because of a lack of a specific Congressional authorization for these projects. This legislation addresses the question of authorization so that the funding may follow.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There's a clear federal interest in these water recycling projects since other federal water projects already contribute significant portions of the water supply to communities throughout the Bay Area. Taken together, the projects authorized in <bill type="h" number="1526">H.R. 1526</bill> will conserve 5,000 acre-feet of potable water per year in the near-term (the first five years of operation) and more than 9,000 acre-feet per year over the long term (10 to 15 years). This represents 9,000 acre-feet which will not have to be  extracted from the San Francisco Bay Delta, the Hetch Hechy system, and other sensitive areas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, in coming years water supplies in California are going to be stretched and stressed by population growth, environmental stress, and supply reductions in water caused by the loss of snow pack due to global warming. If we're going to meet the challenge and relieve the stress on the existing system, we're going to need projects like these.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to vote for <bill type="h" number="1526">H.R. 1526</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mrs." name="RODGERS, McMORRIS" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="1526">H.R. 1526</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the bill, as amended, was passed.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
