<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1185985401" ordinal="38" title="PROVIDING FOR CONSIDERATION OF H.R. 3162, CHILDREN'S HEALTH AND MEDICARE PROTECTION ACT OF 2007">
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="SESSIONS" of="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that the text of the amendment, which I will offer to the rule if the previous question is defeated, and extraneous material be printed just prior to the vote on the previous question.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Texas?</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="SESSIONS" of="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield the balance of my time to the ranking member of the Select Committee on Intelligence, the gentleman from Michigan (Mr. Hoekstra).</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="HOEKSTRA" of="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I think we all know the context of the world that we live in today. America is under heightened threat.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We also know that, if we go back to May 21, the Director of National Intelligence has said our intelligence agencies must obtain a court order to monitor the communications of foreigners suspected of terrorist activity who are physically located in foreign countries. Foreign intelligence, foreign terrorists in foreign countries, and we need to get a court order.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The end result is we have significant gaps in gathering the information that we need to keep America safe. That is why we need to vote against this previous question, and why we need to do an update of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But in light of these threats and this context, what has been the response? What's been the response of this Congress and the other side?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Only a couple of weeks ago, we decided that we would give al Qaeda more information about our Intelligence Community. We decided that Congress would mandate that we declassify the top line. In the intelligence authorization bill that we did earlier this year, we said we want a national intelligence estimate, not on al Qaeda, not on Iran, not on Syria, not on North Korea, but we want it on global climate change. We gutted some of our key funding for intelligence operations, and we have done absolutely  nothing on updating FISA, even though we are under heightened threat and we are talking about foreign targets, foreign intelligence from individuals who are located overseas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We need to update FISA, and we need to do it before we go home. Weakening our national security and weakening our intelligence effort in these times is the wrong thing to do.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We used to talk about our inability to connect the dots. What we now have is a majority that is unwilling and unable to give our Intelligence Community even the capabilities to go out and connect the dots that keep us safe.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Make no doubt about it. We are weakening our intelligence. We are making this country more vulnerable, and we need to act, and we need to act before we go on recess.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="NADLER" of="">
    <paragraph>Will the gentleman yield?</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="HOEKSTRA" of="">
    <paragraph>No, I will not yield. And I know that this colleague has been very sympathetic to making us and fixing this problem, and I appreciate his efforts in this area.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But if we go back to knowing that we have had this information for more than 6 months, we have not dealt with this information. Go back to the "op ed" that the Director of National Intelligence wrote in May. And this bill that we are dealing with today concerns children. But, as the DNI has said, this surveillance saves lives, the lives of our children and grandchildren. That is what we are talking about.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What do we do to keep the homeland safe? What do we do to keep our troops safe? Because we are talking about gathering intelligence from foreign targets in places like Pakistan, Afghanistan and Iraq.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The gentleman's time has expired.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="SESSIONS" of="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I would ask unanimous consent for 2 additional minutes for the gentleman.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Texas?</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="CASTOR" of="">
    <paragraph>I object.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="HOEKSTRA" of="">
    <paragraph>I encourage my colleagues to vote "no" on this previous question. Deal with the issue of FISA and deal with it now.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The gentleman's time has expired.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="CASTOR" of="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, for today we are here on the Children's Health and Medicare Act, the CHAMP Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And, Madam Speaker, I hope the American people know there are many champions for America's kids standing up for our hardworking families in the Nation's Capitol today; and we are joining with Republican and Democratic Governors from across the country fighting for a new direction, for a healthier and economically sound America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It was only 8 months ago when Speaker  Nancy Pelosi accepted the gavel as the first female Speaker of the House of Representatives. She accepted that gavel on behalf of America's children, and we're going to keep our promise to America's kids today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There's another champion in the Chair of the Rules Committee, Ms. LOUISE SLAUGHTER, who has helped us fight through these delaying tactics to bring this bill to the floor, and we will vote on it today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the Energy and Commerce Committee, Chairman JOHN DINGELL continues to be a voice of clarity and advocacy for America's children; and he is joined by the voices, the loud voices, of Congressman Frank Pallone and Congresswoman DIANA DEGETTE and the members of that committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the Ways and Means Committee, where PAYGO means something now in this new Congress, Chairman CHARLIE RANGEL has led our effort to pay for this Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And I salute the subcommittee Chair, Mr. PETE STARK, and the members of that committee and many, many more on the floor of this House, who are not just Members of Congress, but we are also parents and we are grandparents.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The real champions, however, are the parents across America working to make ends meet and provide their children with a healthy and successful life. We are on their side today and every day, even in the face of resistance from the White House, where the President suggests that the health care for America's kids can be found in the emergency rooms of local hospitals. That is wrong.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Instead, through the SCHIP program and children's health care and this innovative partnership between communities, States and Federal Government, we will make important investments in our kids and their health today that will pay dividends down the road for our economy. It will reduce the strain on our emergency rooms, our crowded local emergency rooms, and it will reduce the strain on moms and dads.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is, indeed, a historic day, a day for a new direction, a day full of hope for the health of our children and a better America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge a "yes" vote on the previous question and on the rule.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The material previously referred to by Mr. Sessions is as follows:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Amendment to <bill type="hr" number="594">H. Res. 594</bill> Offered by Mr. Sessions of Texas</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At the end of the resolution, add the following:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sec. 3. That immediately upon the adoption of this resolution the House shall, without intervention of any point of order, consider the bill (<bill type="h" number="3138">H.R. 3138</bill>) to amend the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 to update the definition of electronic surveillance. All points of order against the bill are waived. The bill shall be considered as read. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill to final passage without intervening motion except: (1) one hour of debate on the  bill equally divided and controlled by the chairman and ranking minority member of the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence; and (2) one motion to recommit.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <narrative>(The information contained herein was provided by Democratic Minority on multiple occasions throughout the 109th Congress.)</narrative>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="CASTOR" of="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time, and I move the previous question on the resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The question is on ordering the previous question.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="SESSIONS" of="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 9 of rule XX, the Chair will reduce to 5 minutes the minimum time for any electronic vote on the question of adoption of the resolution.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="CASTOR" of="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I demand a recorded vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 5-minute vote.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="JORDAN" of="Ohio">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I was absent from the House Floor during today's rollcall vote on ordering the previous question on House Resolution 594.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Had I been present, I would have voted "no."</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
</record>
