<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1176998405" ordinal="25" title="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRIES">
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, parliamentary inquiry.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman may state his inquiry.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, isn't it true that the result of waiving a rule of the House for a specific bill means that rule does not apply for that bill?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Would the gentleman repeat his parliamentary inquiry.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, isn't it true that waiving a particular rule of the House for a specific bill means that rule does not apply for that bill?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> A rule may be waived in favor of a particular bill.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>Further inquiry, Mr. Speaker.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman may state his parliamentary inquiry.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>Isn't it true, Mr. Speaker, that <bill type="hr" number="317">H. Res. 317</bill>, the rule for <bill type="h" number="1905">H.R. 1905</bill>, the bill we just considered, waived clause 10 of rule XXI?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> With regard to <bill type="h" number="1905">H.R. 1905</bill>, <bill type="hr" number="317">H. Res. 317</bill> did waive clause 10 of rule XXI.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>Further inquiry, Mr. Speaker.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman may state his parliamentary inquiry.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>Isn't it further true, Mr. Speaker, that clause 10 of rule XXI requires the PAYGO provision to be in effect?</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Clause 10 of rule XXI is informally referred to as pay-as-you-go.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>Further parliamentary inquiry, Mr. Speaker.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman may state his parliamentary inquiry.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>Isn't it true then, Mr. Speaker, that the PAYGO rule adopted by this House was waived for the bill that we just considered, <bill type="h" number="1905">H.R. 1905</bill>?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Clause 10 of rule XXI was waived with regard to that bill.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>Further inquiry, Mr. Speaker.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman may state his parliamentary inquiry.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>So the rule of this House that relates to PAYGO was waived for <bill type="h" number="1905">H.R. 1905</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Clause 10 of rule XXI was waived with regard to <bill type="h" number="1905">H.R. 1905</bill>.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400189" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have a parliamentary inquiry.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman will state his parliamentary inquiry.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400189" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, am I not correct that by adoption of the rule, we ensured that 1905 will not pass through the door to the Senate without PAYGO being attached to it?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Chair will read section 3(a) of the rule. "If either <bill type="h" number="1905">H.R. 1905</bill> or <bill type="h" number="1906">H.R. 1906</bill> fails of passage or fails to reach the question of passage by an order of recommital, then both such bills, together with <bill type="h" number="1433">H.R. 1433</bill>, shall be laid on the table."</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400189" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, further parliamentary inquiry.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from Maryland may state his parliamentary inquiry.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400189" topic="">
    <paragraph>Am I correct that the interpretation of that language means that if the D.C. enfranchisement bill does not have PAYGO added to it, it will not pass this House?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> If either bill fails of passage, then both bills are laid on the table.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400189" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the Speaker for the clarification.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
