<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1176998405" ordinal="9" title="TRIBUTE TO THE LATE RAYMOND G. MURPHY">
  <speaking speaker="400620" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I stand today to honor the life of a great American.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Lt. Col. Raymond Gerald Murphy was born on January 14, 1930, in Pueblo, Colorado. He graduated from Pueblo Catholic High School and attended Fort Lewis Junior College in Durango, then Adams State College in Alamosa.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After graduation, Jerry Murphy joined the Marine Corps Reserve and entered Officers Candidate School. In 1952, he was sent to Korea where he served with the 5th Marines, 1st Marine Division.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In February 1953, Raymond Gerald Murphy was cited for "Conspicuous Gallantry at the risk of his life and above and beyond the call of duty as a Platoon Commander."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although painfully wounded by fragments from an enemy mortar shell, Second Lieutenant Murphy steadfastly refused medical attention and continued to lead his men up the hill through a withering barrage of hostile mortar and small-arms fire. Wounded a second time, he again refused assistance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>His resolute and inspiring leadership, exceptional fortitude and great personal valor reflect the highest credit upon Lt. Col. Murphy and enhance the finest traditions of the United States military service.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Raymond Gerald Murphy was the 39th United States Marine to be awarded the Medal of Honor for Heroism in the Korean War. In addition to the Medal of Honor, Lt. Col. Murphy was awarded the Silver Star, Purple Heart, Korean Service Medal with two Bronze Stars, the United Nations Service Medal and the National Defense Service Medal.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On Good Friday, Lt. Col. Raymond Jerry Murphy died in the Veterans Administration nursing home in Pueblo at the age of 77, Mr. Speaker, but his spirit and heroism will live forever.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
