<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1173200403" ordinal="37" title="SANTIAGO E. CAMPOS UNITED STATES COURTHOUSE">
  <speaking speaker="400295" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="544">H.R. 544</bill>) to designate the United States courthouse at South Federal Place in Santa Fe, New Mexico, as the "Santiago E. Campos United States Courthouse".</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from the District of Columbia (Ms. Norton) and the gentleman from Missouri (Mr. Graves) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400295" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members have 5 legislative days within which to revise and extend their remarks and to include extraneous material concerning <bill type="h" number="544">H.R. 544</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from the District of Columbia?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400295" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, in the 107th, 108th and 109th Congresses, Congressman Tom Udall introduced legislation to designate the Federal courthouse in Santa Fe, New Mexico, as the Santiago E. Campos United States Courthouse. No action was taken during the past Congress. Therefore, it is with great pleasure that the 110th Congress finally moves forward with this bill to honor an outstanding American.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Judge Campos was a life-long resident of the United States and graduated first in his class from the University of New Mexico. He served the people of New Mexico and his country with honor and great distinction. He was a World War II veteran, serving the United States Navy as a seamen first class from 1944 to 1946. After leaving the Navy, Judge Campos attended the Central College in Fayette, Missouri, and received his law degree from the University of New Mexico in 1953, graduating first in his  class again. From 1954 to 1957, he worked as an assistant attorney general and subsequently as first assistant attorney general for the State of New Mexico. After 14 years in private practice, Judge Campos was elected district judge for the First Judicial District of New Mexico in 1971 and served in that capacity until 1978.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>President Jimmy Carter appointed him to the Federal bench in 1978. Judge Campos was the first Hispanic appointed to the Federal bench in New Mexico. He served as chief judge from 1987 until 1989. Known for his compassion, quick wit and inquisitive mind, Judge Campos was a role model for students, fellow jurists and professional colleagues. He was well liked among peers and judicial staff as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I strongly support Congressman Udall and his efforts on behalf of this bill, and I urge my colleagues to join in support of <bill type="h" number="544">H.R. 544</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400158" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, <bill type="h" number="544">H.R. 544</bill>, introduced by Representative Udall of New Mexico, designates the United States courthouse at South Federal Place in Santa Fe, New Mexico, as the Santiago E. Campos United States Courthouse. The bill honors Judge Campos, who was the first Hispanic to be appointed to the U.S. District Court of New Mexico.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Judge Campos served in the United States Navy during World War II and graduated first in his law class at the University of New Mexico. His career in public service included serving as the assistant and first assistant attorney general in New Mexico, and serving as a district court judge in New Mexico's First Judicial District, and culminated in his appointment to the Federal bench.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Judge Campos was appointed by President Carter in 1978 to the District Court of New Mexico. He served as chief judge from 1987 to 1989 and became a senior judge on December 26, 1992. He served with distinction on the bench, and on January 20, 2001, Judge Campos passed away.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I support this legislation, and I encourage my colleagues to do the same.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400295" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman. And I concur and strongly support this legislation as well.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in strong support of <bill type="h" number="544">H.R. 544</bill>, a bill to designate the United States Courthouse at South Federal Place, Santa Fe, New Mexico, as the "Santiago E. Campos United States Courthouse".</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I commend the Gentleman from New Mexico (Mr. UDALL) for his steadfast support of this bill to honor an outstanding jurist.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. UDALL introduced identical legislation in three previous Congresses--H.R. 5083 in the 107th Congress, <bill type="h" number="2274">H.R. 2274</bill> in the 108th Congress, and <bill type="h" number="984">H.R. 984</bill> in the 109th Congress. Regrettably, the House never considered those bills. I am pleased that we are moving forward on this legislation today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Santiago E. Campos was born on December 25, 1926, in Santa Rosa, New Mexico. He served in the United States Navy as a Seaman 1st Class from 1944 to 1946. After leaving the Navy, Judge Campos attended Central College in Fayette, Missouri, and received his law degree from the University of New Mexico in 1953, graduating first in his class.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>From 1954 until 1957, he worked as an Assistant Attorney General and subsequently as First Assistant Attorney General for the State of New Mexico. After 14 years in private practice, Judge Campos was elected District Judge for the 1st Judicial District of New Mexico in 1971, and served in that capacity until 1978. In 1978, Judge Campos was appointed to the Federal Bench by President Jimmy Carter and began serving on July 20, 1978.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Judge Campos was the first Hispanic American to serve as a Federal Judge in the District Court of New Mexico, as well as the first Hispanic American to serve as its Chief Judge. He held the title of Chief U.S. District Judge from February 5, 1987, to December 31, 1989, and took senior status on December 26, 1992. Judge Campos died on January 20, 2002, after suffering a long bout with cancer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>During his career, Judge Campos was named an honorary member of the Order of the Coif. He also received the Distinguished Achievement Award of the State Bar of New Mexico in 1993, and in the same year the University of New Mexico honored him with a Distinguished Achievement Award.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="544">H.R. 544</bill> has received the unanimous endorsement of the Judges of the 10th Circuit Court in New Mexico and the district judges of the District of New Mexico.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In honor of Judge Campos's trailblazing legal career in New Mexico and his outstanding contributions to the legal profession, it is both fitting and proper to designate the courthouse located at South Federal Place in Santa Fe, New Mexico, as the "Santiago E. Campos United States Courthouse".</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to join me in supporting <bill type="h" number="544">H.R. 544</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400295" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from the District of Columbia (Ms. Norton) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="544">H.R. 544</bill>.</chair>
</record>
