<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1228928403" ordinal="43" title="ENSURING THAT THE COMPENSATION AND OTHER EMOLUMENTS ATTACHED TO THE OFFICE OF SECRETARY OF STATE ARE THOSE WHICH WERE IN EFFECT ON JANUARY 1, 2007">
  <narrative>ENSURING THAT THE COMPENSATION AND OTHER EMOLUMENTS ATTACHED TO THE OFFICE OF SECRETARY OF STATE ARE THOSE WHICH WERE IN EFFECT ON JANUARY 1, 2007 -- (House of Representatives - December 10, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H10944]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent to take from the Speaker's table <bill type="sj" number="46">S.J. Res. 46</bill> and ask for its immediate consideration in the House.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the Senate joint resolution.</narrative>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Illinois?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400196" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the right to object. If I could inquire of the gentleman: Would this bill, in fact, proactively cover the Secretary of State if it is Senator Hillary Clinton?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Yes, it covers whoever is nominated.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400196" topic="">
    <paragraph>A further inquiry: Would this cover anyone in the House or in the Senate who had voted on a pay package in the House or in the Senate so that they could then become the Secretary of State?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>As written, it does not.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400196" topic="">
    <paragraph>So who would it be limited to?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>It would be limited to those in the position of Secretary of State.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400196" topic="">
    <paragraph>So it would be limited to the Secretary of State. Regardless of where they came from, they would be frozen at this year's pay as a result of this bill?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>That is correct.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400196" topic="">
    <paragraph>A last inquiry: If I understand correctly then, in every way possible, this piece of legislation passed in this Congress would, by definition, by freezing the pay, actually be, though relatively small, a savings to the taxpayers?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Correct, it would.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400196" topic="">
    <paragraph>With that, I withdraw my reservation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Illinois?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <chair>The text of the Senate joint resolution is as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sj" number="46">S.J. Res. 46</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair> Resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. COMPENSATION AND OTHER EMOLUMENTS ATTACHED TO THE OFFICE OF SECRETARY OF STATE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) In General.--The compensation and other emoluments attached to the office of Secretary of State shall be those in effect January 1, 2007, notwithstanding any increase in such compensation or emoluments after that date under any provision of law, or provision which has the force and effect of law, that is enacted or becomes effective during the period beginning at noon of January 3, 2007, and ending at noon of January 3, 2013.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Civil Action and Appeal.--</chair>
  <chair> (1) JURISDICTION.--Any person aggrieved by an action of the Secretary of State may bring a civil action in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia to contest the constitutionality of the appointment and continuance in office of the Secretary of State on the ground that such appointment and continuance in office is in violation of article I, section 6, clause 2, of the Constitution. The United States District Court for the District of Columbia shall have exclusive  jurisdiction over such a civil action, without regard to the sum or value of the matter in controversy.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) THREE JUDGE PANEL.--Any claim challenging the constitutionality of the appointment and continuance in office of the Secretary of State on the ground that such appointment and continuance in office is in violation of article I, section 6, clause 2, of the Constitution, in an action brought under paragraph (1) shall be heard and determined by a panel of three judges in accordance with section 2284 of title 28, United States Code. It shall be the duty of the district court to advance  on the docket and to expedite the disposition of any matter brought under this subsection.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) APPEAL.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) DIRECT APPEAL TO SUPREME COURT.--An appeal may be taken directly to the Supreme Court of the United States from any interlocutory or final judgment, decree, or order upon the validity of the appointment and continuance in office of the Secretary of State under article I, section 6, clause 2, of the Constitution, entered in any action brought under this subsection. Any such appeal shall be taken by a notice of appeal filed within 20 days after such judgment, decree, or order is entered.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) JURISDICTION.--The Supreme Court shall, if it has not previously ruled on the question presented by an appeal taken under subparagraph (A), accept jurisdiction over the appeal, advance the appeal on the docket, and expedite the appeal.</chair>
  <chair> (c) Effective Date.--This joint resolution shall take effect at 12:00 p.m. on January 20, 2009.&lt;p&gt;</chair>
  <chair>The Senate joint resolution was ordered to be read a third time, was read the third time, and passed, and a motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
