<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1177603218" ordinal="15" title="PROVIDING FOR CONSIDERATION OF H.R. 249, WILD FREE-ROAMING HORSES AND BURROS SALE AND SLAUGHTER PROHIBITION">
  <speaking speaker="412228" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, by direction of the Committee on Rules, I call up House Resolution 331 and ask for its immediate consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the resolution, as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> The gentlewoman from Ohio is recognized for 1 hour.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412228" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, for the purpose of debate only, I yield the customary 30 minutes to the gentleman from Florida (Mr. Lincoln Diaz-Balart). All time yielded during consideration of the rule is for debate only.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members be given 5 legislative days within which to revise and extend their remarks on House Resolution 331.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from Ohio?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412228" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, House Resolution 331 provides for consideration of <bill type="h" number="249">H.R. 249</bill>, to restore the prohibition on the commercial sale and slaughter of wild free-roaming horses and burros, under an open rule with a preprinting requirement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The rule provides 1 hour of general debate, equally divided and controlled by the chairman and the ranking minority member of the Committee on Natural Resources. The rule waives all points of order against consideration of the bill except clauses 9 and 10 of rule XXI. The rule requires that any amendments to the bill must be preprinted in the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Congressional Record prior to their consideration. The rule provides one motion to recommit, with or without instructions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, <bill type="h" number="249">H.R. 249</bill> is a bipartisan bill that restores important protections for wild horses and burros from sale and slaughter. This bill is necessary because these long-standing protections were stripped by a rider inserted into the 2005 omnibus spending bill without a hearing or debate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The transportation practices faced by these wild horses and burros are cruel and inhumane. They are transferred hundreds or thousands of miles in cramped quarters, just so their meat can be consumed in foreign markets. <bill type="h" number="249">H.R. 249</bill> bans the sale of wild horses and burros by the Bureau of Land Management, as well as the transfer of these animals for the purpose of processing into commercial products.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over the last 2 years, the House has voted twice on this issue, and these passed either unanimously or overwhelmingly. But they have never been signed into law. It is time we end this inhumane practice once and for all.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since the enactment of these protections through the passage of the Wild Free-Roaming Horses and Burros Act in 1971, we have seen wild horse populations fall by more than 50 percent. These animals cannot wait any longer for us to reaffirm our commitment to the protections we promised 34 years ago.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As an animal lover, I am deeply disturbed and opposed to suffering inflicted on animals and will work against practices that lead to their torture or injury. That is why we must pass this rule and pass <bill type="h" number="249">H.R. 249</bill>. These animals need protection, and it is time we restored it for them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400107" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I thank my friend, the gentlewoman from Ohio (Ms. Sutton) for the time, and I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, in 1971 Congress passed the Wild Free-Roaming Horse and Burro Act. That law established as national policy that wild free-roaming horses shall be protected from capture, branding, harassment and death; and to accomplish this, they are considered in the area where presently found as an integral part of the natural system of the public lands. The law also directed that no wild free-roaming horse or its remains may be sold or transferred for consideration for processing into commercial  products. However, the fiscal year 2005 Consolidated Appropriations Act directed that wild horses over 10 years old or that were not adopted after three attempts must be sold unconditionally.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While "excess" wild horses have been cited as the reason for the recent changes in law, there are fewer wild horses on the public lands today than there were a quarter of a century ago. In 1980, there were approximately 62,000 wild horses on public lands. Today, there are approximately 28,000. The underlying bill, <bill type="h" number="249">H.R. 249</bill>, would undo the current practice and would prohibit the commercial sale of wild horses by the Bureau of Land Management.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With regard to process, again the majority likes to proclaim that they have offered another bill under what they are describing as an open rule. But it really is not an open rule. According to a survey of activities of the House Committee on Rules from the 104th Congress, an open rule is defined as "one under which any Member may offer an amendment that complies with the standing rules of the House and the Budget Act." A modified open rule requiring preprinting in the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Congressional  Record is defined as a type of rule that permits the offering only of those amendments printed in the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Congressional Record.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because Members under this rule that bring the underlying legislation to the floor today must submit their amendments prior to floor consideration, they are prohibited from offering amendments on the floor as the debate progresses. So if a Member, for example, Mr. Speaker, is watching the debate and has an idea to improve the bill pursuant to the debate, he or she has an idea, this rule prevents that Member from offering their amendment. So by its very nature, the rule is restrictive. It is not  an open rule. So for the sake of clarity and specificity, we would point that out for the record, and we think the majority should stop calling it an open rule.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also want to point out that once again the majority offers this modified open rule on noncontroversial, bipartisan bills such as the one that we bring to the floor today, bills that really should be considered under suspension of the rules or under a genuinely open rule. If the majority really wants to live up to their campaign promise of a more open and bipartisan Congress, they should offer open rules, for example on this bill, and on bills where there is some controversy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412228" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I thank the gentleman for his support of the underlying measure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This House, in a bipartisan manner, has demonstrated its strong support for our wild horses and burros twice over the last 2 years. There is no reason we cannot continue this strong commitment to protecting these animals here again today. This is a commonsense issue that must be addressed. No longer can we ignore the inhumane treatment inflicted upon these wonderful and beautiful animals. I urge a "yes" vote on the previous question and on the rule.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time, and I move the previous question on the resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The previous question was ordered.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The resolution was agreed to.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
