<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1193673602" ordinal="19" title="SUPPORTING THE OBSERVANCE OF BREAST CANCER AWARENESS MONTH">
  <narrative>SUPPORTING THE OBSERVANCE OF BREAST CANCER AWARENESS MONTH -- (House of Representatives - October 29, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H12122]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400013" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and agree to the concurrent resolution (<bill type="hc" number="230">H. Con. Res. 230</bill>) supporting the observance of Breast Cancer Awareness Month, and for other purposes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the concurrent resolution.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the concurrent resolution is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="hc" number="230">H. Con. Res. 230</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas every 3 minutes a woman is diagnosed with breast cancer;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas another 180,510 new cases of breast cancer are expected to be diagnosed in the United States in 2007;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas breast cancer is the leading cause of death among women between the ages of 45 and 54;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas 1 out of every 8 women who live to the age of 85 will develop breast cancer in her lifetime;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the survival rate of women who have breast cancer is 98.1 percent when detected in the early stages;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas mammograms and monthly breast self-examinations are the key components of early detection; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas observing a Breast Cancer Awareness Month would provide a special opportunity to offer education on the importance of monthly breast self-examinations and annual mammograms: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved by the House of Representatives (the Senate concurring), That Congress--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) supports the observance of Breast Cancer Awareness Month in order to provide a special opportunity to offer education on the importance of monthly breast self-examinations and annual mammograms;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) salutes the more than 2.4 million breast cancer survivors in the United States and the efforts of victims, volunteers, and professionals who combat breast cancer each day;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) recognizes and applauds the national and community organizations for their work in promoting awareness about breast cancer, providing information, and offering treatment to its sufferers; and</narrative>
  <narrative> (4) urges organizations and health practitioners to use this opportunity to promote awareness about breast cancer, to support monthly self-examinations, and to encourage annual mammograms.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from Wisconsin (Ms. Baldwin) and the gentlewoman from Florida (Ms. Ginny Brown-Waite) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentlewoman from Wisconsin.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400013" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the resolution now under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from Wisconsin?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400013" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in strong support of <bill type="hc" number="230">H. Con. Res. 230</bill>, a resolution supporting the observance of Breast Cancer Awareness Month. As an original cosponsor of this resolution, I am proud to speak out in favor of greater support for breast cancer awareness and prevention. Through my work with Congresswoman Sue Myrick in reauthorizing the National Breast and Cervical Cancer Early Detection Program, I am well aware of the challenges that lie ahead in preventing and ultimately finding  a cure for breast cancer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As my colleagues may know, breast cancer is the leading cause of death among women between the ages of 45 and 54. Many of us have witnessed a family member or a friend struggle with the devastating effects of breast cancer. We must ensure that these women do not suffer alone.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With this resolution, we affirm our solidarity with the 2 million-plus breast cancer survivors as we seek to find a cure for this and other cancers. We also pay tribute to the volunteers and health care professionals who work to combat breast cancer every day.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>H. Con. Resolution 230 supports the observance of Breast Cancer Awareness Month, a time to reemphasize the importance of monthly breast self-examinations and annual mammograms. As in the case of many diseases, early detection goes a long way toward ensuring survival. As many of my colleagues know, approximately 98 percent of women who are able to detect breast cancer in its most early stage survive. We must use this opportunity to educate women, all women, to ensure that they take the necessary  steps to protect themselves from this potentially fatal disease.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also rise to pay tribute to our friend and our colleague, Congresswoman Jo Ann Davis, who lost her life to breast cancer earlier this month. We are reminded that breast cancer can strike anyone. This resolution also expresses our gratitude to national and community organizations, such as the Susan G. Komen Breast Cancer Foundation, that have made us all aware of the power of the pink ribbon, been on the forefront in raising awareness about this disease and provided information to better understand  this disease.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also want to thank my colleague Representative Ginny Brown-Waite and the Congressional Caucus for Women's Issues for their leadership on this resolution, and I urge my colleagues to join me in support of its adoption.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400051" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I am proud to offer my resolution on the House floor today, House Concurrent Resolution 230, supporting the observance of Breast Cancer Awareness Month.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The effects of breast cancer have touched almost every American, whether through losing a loved one, as I did, or going through the pain of chemotherapy and a long recovery, as millions of individuals have done.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I introduced this resolution to support the breast cancer education and outreach efforts that have taken place this October. We all know that every 3 minutes, a woman is diagnosed with breast cancer and that this is the leading cause of death among women between the ages of 15 and 54. However, if this disease is detected early, the breast cancer survival rate is 98 percent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress must continue to promote breast cancer awareness and support efforts to defeat this disease. My resolution expresses support for the observation of Breast Cancer Awareness Month, which is this month of October. The resolution provides a special opportunity to offer education on the importance of monthly breast self-examinations and annual mammograms. My resolution also salutes the 2.4 million breast cancer survivors in the United States and the efforts of victims, volunteers and professionals  who combat breast cancer every day.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, this measure applauds the national and community organizations for their work in promoting awareness about breast cancer. A woman's risk for developing breast cancer increases if family members have a history of breast cancer, particularly at an early age. However, 85 percent of women who develop breast cancer have no known family history of the disease.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It cannot be stressed enough that early detection is the best chance for survival of a person who has a breast cancer diagnosis. Women must take care of their health and be aware of their risk factors, perform self-examinations and get annual checkups. While breast cancer predominately affects women, we are regularly reminded that a significant number of men are diagnosed with breast cancer each year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My colleague, Ms. Baldwin, mentioned Jo Ann Davis. Jo Ann Davis certainly was a very, very brave lady who fought breast cancer. Actually, she fought it twice. She won the first time, and it came back. We all remember her in this Chamber and we remember her desire to make sure that a cure is found. If Jo Ann Davis were here today, she would not only vote in favor of this, but she also would be speaking on behalf of it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I want to thank Representative Baldwin and the 129 Members who co-signed this very important piece of legislation with me. I certainly urge all Members to support <bill type="hc" number="230">H. Con. Res. 230</bill> to ensure that the House continues to bring awareness to this important issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With that, Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400013" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, in closing, I urge my colleagues to support this very important resolution. Observing Breast Cancer Awareness Month gives us an opportunity to educate the  public on the importance of monthly breast self-exams and annual mammograms. It also gives us an opportunity to salute those who work every day in raising awareness about breast cancer and our health care professionals who work with patients to fight it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, I want to commend the work of my colleague, Representative Ginny Brown-Waite, for her work on this important issue, and I urge all my colleagues to join me in supporting this resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no further requests for time and yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from Wisconsin (Ms. Baldwin) that the House suspend the rules and agree to the concurrent resolution, <bill type="hc" number="230">H. Con. Res. 230</bill>.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the concurrent resolution was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
