<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1197910803" ordinal="31" title="DOCK M. BROWN POST OFFICE BUILDING">
  <narrative>DOCK M. BROWN POST OFFICE BUILDING -- (House of Representatives - December 17, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H15483]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400295" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="4210">H.R. 4210</bill>) to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 401 Washington Avenue in Weldon, North Carolina, as the "Dock M. Brown Post Office Building".</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="4210">H.R. 4210</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. DOCK M. BROWN POST OFFICE BUILDING.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Designation.--The facility of the United States Postal Service located at 401 Washington Avenue in Weldon, North Carolina, shall be known and designated as the "Dock M. Brown Post Office Building".</narrative>
  <narrative> (b) References.--Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the facility referred to in subsection (a) shall be deemed to be a reference to the "Dock M. Brown Post Office Building".&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from the District of Columbia (Ms. Norton) and the gentleman from California (Mr. Issa) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentlewoman from the District of Columbia.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400295" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days within which to revise and extend their remarks.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from the District of Columbia?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400295" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I'm pleased to rise in support of <bill type="h" number="4210">H.R. 4210</bill>, a bill designating the facility of the United States Post Office located at 401 Washington Avenue in Weldon, North Carolina, as the Dock M. Brown Post Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="4210">H.R. 4210</bill>, which was introduced by Representative G.K. Butterfield of North Carolina on November 15, 2007, was reported from the Oversight Committee on December 12. This measure has been cosponsored by 12 Members and has the support of the entire North Carolina congressional delegation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dock Brown was a dutiful and loyal public servant to the City of Weldon, North Carolina. He was a teacher and served as principal for more than 30 years in the school system. In addition to his dedication to strengthening academia, Dock Brown also served 8 years as a Halifax County Commissioner, 2 years in the North Carolina House of Representatives for District Seven, 8 years as Commissioner on the Weldon town board, and served also on the State Agriculture Committee. The City of Weldon is greatly  touched by his good work, his dedication and his efforts to strengthen their community.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I urge swift passage of this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400196" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise in support of the naming of this post office the Dock M. Brown Post Office Building. Dock Brown was a dedicated public servant, a member of the community, and a shining example as a local leader.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A veteran of the Korean war, Mr. Brown served his community as an educator and a politician. During a more than 30-year tenure as a teacher and principal at Halifax County, North Carolina, he also served on the community health board, chaired the county election board and served 19 years on the mental health board. Truly, this was a community leader and appropriate for naming of a post office in his hometown.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400295" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield such time as he may consume to the gentleman from North Carolina (Mr. Butterfield).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400616" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I want to thank the gentlelady from the District of Columbia for her friendship  and thank her for yielding me this time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I want to very briefly comment on <bill type="h" number="4210">H.R. 4210</bill>. This is a bill that I introduced to name the post office located at 401 Washington Avenue in Weldon, North Carolina, after a very dear friend of many, many years, Mr. Dock M. Brown.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are seeking to name this post office as the Dock M. Brown Post Office Building. Dock Brown, Mr. Speaker, has been a friend and supporter for many years. He is a pillar of leadership in the Halifax County community and throughout our congressional district. And I might say parenthetically, Mr. Speaker, that the gentlewoman from the District of Columbia also has roots in Halifax County, North Carolina, and it is just ironic that she happens to be on the floor at this very moment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, Dock Brown was born on January 30, 1929, in Halifax County to a wonderful couple, Nelson and Vilvie Brown. Dock Brown's father, as was my father, was a veteran of World War I. Dock would soon follow in his father's footsteps by also serving our country as a sergeant in the United States Army.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Brown graduated from J.A. Chaloner High School in 1948 and entered historic Shaw University in Raleigh, North Carolina, that fall. In 1951, just 1 year before he was to graduate from that institution, Dock Brown was drafted into the United States Army and was given orders to fight in the Korean War.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dock Brown served 12 long months in Korea before returning to Fort Bragg, North Carolina, his native home State, to serve out the remainder of his tour. Immediately after his discharge, Dock Brown resumed his education at Shaw University, where he received his undergraduate degree in history.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To fulfill his dream of becoming a school teacher, Dock attended another great institution, which was my alma mater, North Carolina Central University in Durham, North Carolina, where he received a master's degree in sociology and school administration.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dock Brown is an extraordinary educator. He taught history at Weldon High School and Eastman High School for 24 years and served as principal of Pittman High School for 10 years. His positive impact on the youth in Halifax County cannot be measured. He touched so many young lives, and it was Dock Brown's encouragement that has served as a catalyst and foundation that propelled many of those young people to grow into well-established, productive, progressive citizens.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dock Brown also served as an appointed official in Halifax County. He served on the County Board of Health. And for 19 years he served on the Board of Mental Health, where he served as chairman for the last 4 years of his tenure. He was honored with the Lifetime Achievement Award from the State Mental Health Association for his tireless dedication to the issue of mental health.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He served 7 years as a trustee at Elizabeth City State University and 2 years as an appointee to the Governor's Commission to evaluate superior court judges.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, Dock Brown has also served, as we do, as an elected official. For 8 years he served as a county commissioner in Halifax County; 2 years in the North Carolina House of Representatives, representing District 7; 8 years as a commissioner on the Weldon Town Board.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For his untiring service to the State of North Carolina, Dock Brown was awarded the Order of the Long Leaf Pine by then Governor James B. Hunt, Jr. This is the highest civilian honor granted to a citizen in North Carolina.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Religion has played a major part in the life of Dock Brown. He has been an active member of the First Baptist Church in Roanoke Rapids since the age of 11, where he served in many capacities including that of ordained deacon for more than 50 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He has been married to his devoted wife, Helen Brooks Brown, for 54 years. Together they have reared two children: Dock Brown, Jr. and Ivy Brown Singlton. Ivy is married to Lieutenant Colonel Terance Singlton, II, who proudly serves us in the United States Army.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am so proud, Mr. Speaker, to have authored this legislation to honor this individual. Dock Brown has dedicated his entire life to serving others and has touched entire generations of young people.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation has the entire support, bipartisan support, of my delegation. I urge my colleagues to vote "yes" on <bill type="h" number="4210">H.R. 4210</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400196" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400295" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from the District of Columbia (Ms. Norton) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="4210">H.R. 4210</bill>.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the bill was passed.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
