<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1193760002" ordinal="45" title="MAKING PERMANENT THE AUTHORITY TO ISSUE SPECIAL POSTAGE STAMP TO SUPPORT BREAST CANCER RESEARCH">
  <narrative>MAKING PERMANENT THE AUTHORITY TO ISSUE SPECIAL POSTAGE STAMP TO SUPPORT BREAST CANCER RESEARCH -- (House of Representatives - October 30, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H12195]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400074" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="1236">H.R. 1236</bill>) to make permanent the authority of the United States Postal Service to issue a special postage stamp to support breast cancer research, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="1236">H.R. 1236</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. EXTENSION OF AUTHORITY.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Section 414(h) of title 39, United States Code, is amended by striking "2007" and inserting "2011".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. REPORTING REQUIREMENTS.</narrative>
  <narrative> The National Institutes of Health and the Department of Defense shall each submit to Congress and the Government Accountability Office an annual report concerning the use of any amounts that it received under section 414(c) of title 39, United States Code, including a description of any significant advances or accomplishments, during the year covered by the report, that were funded, in whole or in part, with such amounts.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Missouri (Mr. Clay) and the gentleman from Tennessee (Mr. Duncan) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Missouri.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400074" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days within which to revise and extend their remarks.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Missouri?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400074" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, as a sponsor of <bill type="h" number="1236">H.R. 1236</bill>, the bill would make permanent the breast cancer research stamp, which first went on sale on July 29, 1998.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After several discussions with the Postal Service, I offered an amendment in the nature of a substitute to <bill type="h" number="1236">H.R. 1236</bill> during the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, Postal Service and the District of Columbia markup on September 18, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The amendment retained the Postal Service's flexibility by reauthorizing the breast cancer stamp for an additional 4 years and strengthens the bill's reporting requirements. The new reporting requirements would assess the breast cancer stamp's effectiveness and appropriateness and the cost to the Postal Service for administering the program to find a cure for breast cancer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The amendment was agreed to by voice vote. <bill type="h" number="1236">H.R. 1236</bill>, as amended, was reported from the Oversight Committee on September 20, 2007, by a voice vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In America, breast cancer is reported as the second leading cause of cancer deaths among women after lung cancer. The American Cancer Society estimated 178,480 women will be diagnosed this year with invasive breast cancer. In the U.S., approximately 40,000 will die.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Postal Service has sold over 785.6 million breast cancer research stamps from which $54.626 million have been transferred to the National Institutes of Health and DOD for breast cancer research and awareness.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I encourage my colleagues to support <bill type="h" number="1236">H.R. 1236</bill> and urge the swift passage of this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400116" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First of all, I want to commend my good friend, the gentleman from Missouri (Mr. Clay), for his remarks and his work on this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise today to urge passage of <bill type="h" number="1236">H.R. 1236</bill>, to extend the authority of the U.S. Postal Service to issue a stamp to support breast cancer research.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Those of us in Congress received a tragic reminder of the need for continued research into this disease with the passing of our beloved colleague, Jo Ann Davis; and we thank the majority, in particular Mr. Clay, for taking the opportunity to honor her memory.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nearly 180,000 people, mostly, but not all, women, will learn that they have invasive breast cancer this year alone. About 40,000 people will die from this disease. Women who are white and over the age of 40 are more likely to suffer from breast cancer, but its victims run the gamut of age, race and socioeconomic background. We have made some progress in recent years thanks to early detection and increased awareness and availability of mammograms.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But in the past 3 years, both mammograms and incidence of breast cancer have decreased. This doesn't mean things are getting better. It means ominously and unfortunately that fewer cases are being detected.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As I am sure Jo Ann Davis would tell us if she were still with us here today, early detection, early treatment, constant vigilance and public awareness are key to putting this disease in its place. For example, incidence rates of both invasive and in-situ breast cancer rise and fall with the percentage of women who receive mammograms.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After two decades of progress, both the use of mammograms and the rates of detection have begun to slip in recent years. As early detection increased, so did survival rates; but they will fall, too, if we can't improve public awareness of the importance of early detection.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That's where the measure that is before us comes in. This bill would reauthorize the Postal Service to issue the 55-cent stamp for first class mail, with 14 cents of each stamp going to breast cancer research and awareness programs for an additional 4 years. Since the program began in 1998, the Postal Service has sold more than 785 million of these stamps and raised $54.6 million for breast cancer research.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This disease preys on women such as Jo Ann Davis and on so many others, women on whom others have come to depend. They are mothers, grandmothers, business owners, teachers, researchers, even Members of this great body. We need these women and the invaluable contributions they make to our life and society. We need this measure to help save their lives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have had the privilege of attending every single Race for the Cure for the past 11 years, every single one that has been held in my hometown of Knoxville.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>This is a very worthwhile cause that I am sure all of our colleagues on both sides of the aisle can support very enthusiastically.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400074" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, let me thank the gentleman from Tennessee (Mr. Duncan), my friend, who is certainly committed to this cause and who has joined with me in what I think is a worthwhile cause for the people of this country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also want to dedicate <bill type="h" number="1236">H.R. 1236</bill> in memory of the late Congresswoman Jo Ann Davis. Jo Ann's courageous battle with breast cancer further inspires us to expand efforts to secure more research dollars and find a cure for this devastating disease.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I commend everyone who has championed this issue in Congress, including former Representative Vic Fazio for introducing the first Breast Cancer Research Stamp Act in 1996, and Senator Dianne Feinstein, Representative Joe Baca and the late Juanita Millender McDonald who pioneered the idea of a permanent breast cancer stamp, research stamp in 2001. And I ask my colleagues to support the passage of <bill type="h" number="1236">H.R. 1236</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400116" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no additional speakers, and I urge passage of this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400074" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no additional speakers, and I urge my colleagues to vote in favor of this worthwhile effort.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield back my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Missouri (Mr. Clay) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="1236">H.R. 1236</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the bill, as amended, was passed.</chair>
  <chair>The title was amended so as to read: "A Bill to amend title 39, United States Code, to extend the authority of the United States Postal Service to issue a semipostal to raise funds for breast cancer research.".</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
