<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1173114004" ordinal="14" title="PIEDRAS BLANCAS HISTORIC LIGHT STATION OUTSTANDING NATURAL AREA ACT OF 2007">
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="276">H.R. 276</bill>) to designate the Piedras Blancas Light Station and the surrounding public land as an Outstanding Natural Area to be administered as a part of the National Landscape Conservation System, and for other purposes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) and the gentleman from Utah (Mr. Bishop) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members have 5 legislative days to revise and extend and include extraneous material related to this bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Arizona?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Piedras Blancas Light Station is one of only a handful of tall, seacoast lighthouses built on the West Coast. It is located in San Luis Obispo County in Southern California.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Completed in 1875, the lighthouse was manned by the Coast Guard until 1975, when it was automated. The Coast Guard transferred the lighthouse and the surrounding public land to the Bureau of Land Management in 2001. This area is not only historically significant, but it is also home to a population of gulls, cormorants and an elephant seal colony, numbering 10,000 animals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="276">H.R. 276</bill>, sponsored by my committee colleague Representative Lois Capps, would establish the Piedras Blancas Historic Light Station Outstanding Natural Area to be managed by the Bureau of Land Management as part of the existing National Landscape Conservation System. This area would be managed by the BLM to conserve the significant historical and natural resources found there.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, Representative Capps has worked tirelessly on behalf of this legislation, and we commend her for her efforts. Identical legislation was approved by the House in the last Congress, and we urge our colleagues to support this measure once again.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400029" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="276">H.R. 276</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last year the Republican majority was supportive of this measure, and this bill was passed in the House of Representatives. This year, we once again support this bill and commend Representative Capps for her work to recognize this historic site in her district.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no further requests for time, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, Representative Capps is traveling back from her district in California and could not be here on the floor. She has submitted a statement which we will be submitting for the Record today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400062" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in strong support of <bill type="h" number="276">H.R. 276</bill>, the Piedras Blancas Historic Light Station Outstanding Natural Area Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, I want to thank the chairman of the Natural Resources Committee, Mr. Rahall, and chairman of the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands, Mr. Grijalva, as well as the ranking members of the full Committee and Subcommittee for expediting the consideration of this legislation and for bringing <bill type="h" number="276">H.R. 276</bill> before us today. This bill was passed by the House of Representatives last year but was never acted on by the Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="276">H.R. 276</bill> would designate the Piedras Blancas Historic Light Station--located in my congressional district--as an Outstanding Natural Area within the BLM's National Landscape Conservation System.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Piedras Blancas Light Station is located on an 18-acre parcel of BLM administered land along the Pacific Coast in San Luis Obispo County. The property is adjacent to Pacific Coast Highway and the Hearst Castle State Historic Monument, and it looks over a pristine coastal area that includes the southern portion of the Monterey Bay National Marine Sanctuary and California Coastal National Monument. It is also nationally recognized as an important monitoring point for migrating whales, and is  used by the U.S. Geological Survey, the National Marine Fisheries Service and a number of universities and colleges for marine wildlife and plant research.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Light Station and the surrounding area are also important for tourism. For example, the national historic Light House--built in 1879--is a main destination focal point on the central coast, and the peninsula is very popular for viewing sea otters, elephant seals, and sea lions from shore. The elephant seal colony at Piedras Blancas attracts an estimated 400,000 visitors annually.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 2001, BLM assumed ownership and management of the Light Station from the U.S. Coast Guard. Since then, BLM, State and local agencies, community stakeholders and conservation groups have developed a very successful partnership to preserve the Light Station.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Some of these partners include: the Piedras Blancas Light Station Association; California State Parks; San Luis Obispo County; the cities of Cambria and San Simeon; the California Coastal Conservancy and Coastal Commission; NOAA; and the Hearst Corporation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a result of their hard work, the site was re-opened to public tours in 2003--for the first time in 128 years. These partners continue to work together on a series of environmental education,  historical restoration and resource protection programs; and, I'm confidant they will each support and showcase this national designation if enacted.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My legislation tracks the successful model of designating the Oregon Coast's Yaquina Head as an Outstanding Natural Area, which was signed into law in 1980. Yaquina Head was later included in the National Landscape Conservation System.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Like Yaquina Head, the addition of the Piedras Blancas Light Station to the NLCS would be an important step in protecting and preserving this valuable natural and historic resource. It will also focus attention on the restoration of the Light Station and surrounding area, specifically the three on-site National Register properties; and, it will serve as a means to increase public awareness of the Light Station's scientific, cultural and educational values.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Specifically, <bill type="h" number="276">H.R. 276</bill> stresses long-term conservation of the Light Station by requiring timely completion of a management plan. The management plan would be developed through a public process and include guidelines for restoration of the National Register of Historic Places buildings, including the Light House; public access; ecological and cultural resource management; and, fostering scientific study and research opportunities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the Piedras Blancas Light Station is a wonderful resource. It has the potential to serve as a model for future resource management, and therefore would be an appropriate addition to the BLM's National Landscape Conservation System.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, I would like to thank the Committee on Natural Resources for supporting this bill to designate Piedras Blancas Historic Light Station as an Outstanding Natural Area, and urge its immediate passage.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no further requests for time, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="276">H.R. 276</bill>.</chair>
</record>
