<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1201021201" ordinal="14" title="MASTER SERGEANT KENNETH N. MACK POST OFFICE BUILDING">
  <narrative>MASTER SERGEANT KENNETH N. MACK POST OFFICE BUILDING -- (House of Representatives - January 22, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H357]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400295" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="3988">H.R. 3988</bill>) to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 3107 Altamesa Boulevard in Fort Worth, Texas, as the "Master Sergeant Kenneth N. Mack Post Office Building".</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="3988">H.R. 3988</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. MASTER SERGEANT KENNETH N. MACK POST OFFICE BUILDING.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Designation.--The facility of the United States Postal Service located at 3701 Altamesa Boulevard in Fort Worth, Texas, shall be known and designated as the "Master Sergeant Kenneth N. Mack Post Office Building".</narrative>
  <narrative> (b) References.--Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the facility referred to in subsection (a) shall be deemed to be a reference to the "Master Sergeant Kenneth N. Mack Post Office Building".&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from the District of Columbia (Ms. Norton) and the gentleman from Connecticut (Mr. Shays) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentlewoman from the District of Columbia.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400295" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days in which to revise and extend their remarks.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from the District of Columbia?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400295" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a member of the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, I am pleased to join my colleagues in consideration of <bill type="h" number="3988">H.R. 3988</bill>, which names the postal facility in Fort Worth, Texas, after Master Sergeant Kenneth N. Mack.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="3988">H.R. 3988</bill>, which was introduced by Representative Kay Granger of Texas on October 29, 2007, was reported from the Oversight Committee on December 12, 2007, by voice vote. This measure, which has been cosponsored by 31 Members, has the support of the entire Texas congressional delegation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Master Sergeant Mack was both a U.S. Marine and a postal employee for over 20 years before being killed in Iraq on February 5 during combat operations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I am pleased to join my colleague and to urge the swift passage of this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400370" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, today we honor the life of Marine Corps Master Sergeant Kenneth Mack, a soldier who strongly believed in the fight for freedom and was a true American hero.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1982, shortly after graduating from Southwest High School, Master Sergeant Mack joined the Marines, where he served honorably for 23 years. Master Sergeant Mack was a Postal Service mechanic and Master Sergeant in the Marine Reserve assigned to the  Second Marine Expeditionary Force out of Camp Lejeune, North Carolina.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In March of last year, this dedicated soldier was called to duty in Iraq for the second time and once again had to leave his family to serve his country. On the morning of May 5th of that year, a roadside bomb struck Master Sergeant Mack's vehicle in Al Anbar Province, Iraq. In a flash, an outstanding 23-year Marine Corps career was over and he was killed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A passionate family man, Sergeant Mack's wife remembers him as a person who put his family first and made sure the family participated in many activities together. His primary goal in life was to be a mentor for his children and to all children, according to his wife. He leaves behind his wife, mother and two children. I might just add, obviously he put his country first, too.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, in recognition of his service to his community and country as a Postal Service mechanic and Marine, we feel it is fitting to name the postal facility located at 3701 Altamesa Boulevard in Forth Worth, Texas, in honor of Master Sergeant Kenneth Mack.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400295" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I want to take note of the fact that this was probably a member of the Reserve or National Guard, because for over 20 years he had been a member of the Postal Service, which also comes under the jurisdiction of this committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think it bears underlining how much of the armed services of the United States today is made up of the post office, civil servants, first responders, often needed at home, but always willing to go where their country needs them. I find this a particularly deserving measure and urge passage of the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from the District of Columbia (Ms. Norton) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="3988">H.R. 3988</bill>.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the bill was passed.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
