<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1185249600" ordinal="31" title="AUTHORIZING PRINTING OF CERTAIN PUBLICATIONS">
  <narrative>AUTHORIZING PRINTING OF CERTAIN PUBLICATIONS -- (House of Representatives - July 24, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H8301]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400047" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I send a concurrent resolution (<bill type="hc" number="190">H. Con. Res. 190</bill>) to the desk and ask unanimous consent for its immediate consideration in the House.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the concurrent resolution.</narrative>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Pennsylvania?</chair>
  <chair/>
  <speaking speaker="400119" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, reserving the right to object, will the gentleman explain the resolution, please.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400047" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, this concurrent resolution provides for printing additional copies of three congressional publications that our constituents frequently request from us and of which supplies are nearly exhausted. Two of the publications are about the U.S. Constitution. With Constitution Day, September 17, approaching fast, we need to replenish our supplies so that Members can fulfill the requests from schools, civic organizations and others.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I know of no controversy and urge an "aye" vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400119" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, under my reservation, I would simply comment that these are remarkably good documents. We make great use of them in the United States. Frankly, I would like to see the dollar limit removed, because these are very valuable documents for students in the schools. I know we receive many, many requests for them, frequently more than we can handle.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I strongly support the resolution with the one reservation that I wish we could increase the allocation; however, I don't want to stop the flow of democracy here.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I withdraw my reservation of objection.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Pennsylvania?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the concurrent resolution, as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="hc" number="190">H. Con. Res. 190</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Resolved by the House of Representatives (the Senate concurring),&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. HOW OUR LAWS ARE MADE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) In General.--An edition of the brochure entitled "How Our Laws Are Made", as revised under the direction of the Parliamentarian of the House of Representatives in consultation with the Parliamentarian of the Senate, shall be printed as a House document under the direction of the Joint Committee on Printing.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Additional Copies.--In addition to the usual number, there shall be printed the lesser of--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) 550,000 copies of the document, of which 440,000 copies shall be for the use of the House of Representatives, 100,000 copies shall be for the use of the Senate, and 10,000 copies shall be for the use of the Joint Committee on Printing; or&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) such number of copies of the document as does not exceed a total production and printing cost of $479,247, with distribution to be allocated in the same proportion as described in paragraph (1), except that in no case shall the number of copies be less than 1 per Member of Congress.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. DOCUMENT-SIZED, ANNOTATED UNITED STATES CONSTITUTION.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) In General.--The 2007 edition of the document-sized, annotated version of the United States Constitution shall be printed as a House document under the direction of the Joint Committee on Printing.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Additional Copies.--In addition to the usual number, there shall be printed the lesser of--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) 550,000 copies of the document, of which 440,000 copies shall be for the use of the House of Representatives, 100,000 copies shall be for the use of the Senate, and 10,000 copies shall be for the use of the Joint Committee on Printing; or&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) such number of copies of the document as does not exceed a total production and printing cost of $535,853, with distribution to be allocated in the same proportion as described in paragraph (1), except that in no case shall the number of copies be less than 1 per Member of Congress.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 3. POCKET VERSION OF THE UNITED STATES CONSTITUTION.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) In General.--The 23rd edition of the pocket version of the United States Constitution shall be printed as a House document under the direction of the Joint Committee on Printing.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Additional Copies.--In addition to the usual number, there shall be printed the lesser of--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) 550,000 copies of the document, of which 440,000 copies shall be for the use of the House of Representatives, 100,000 copies shall be for the use of the Senate, and 10,000 copies shall be for the use of the Joint Committee on Printing; or</narrative>
  <narrative> (2) such number of copies of the document as does not exceed a total production and printing cost of $188,462, with distribution to be allocated in the same proportion as described in paragraph (1), except that in no case shall the number of copies be less than 1 per Member of Congress.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <narrative>The current resolution was agreed to.</narrative>
  <narrative>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</narrative>
</record>
