<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1174320004" ordinal="19" title="NATURAL RESOURCE PROTECTION COOPERATIVE AGREEMENT ACT">
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="658">H.R. 658</bill>) to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to enter into cooperative agreements to protect natural resources of units of the National Park System through collaborative efforts on land inside and outside of units of the National Park System, and for other purposes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) and the gentleman from Utah (Mr. Bishop) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Arizona?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="658">H.R. 658</bill> is an administration proposal introduced by Representative JON PORTER of Nevada. The bill would authorize the National Park Service to enter into cooperative agreements to spend Park Service funds outside of existing Park boundaries.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>According to a report from the Government Accountability Office, the National Park Service is the only Federal land management agency that does not currently have that authority.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While there are several areas in which such cooperative agreements would be useful, the ability to participate in coordinated plans to eradicate invasive species in and around national parks is the primary reason that the National Park Service is seeking this authority.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under the terms of this legislation, the National Park Service could enter into such agreements with State, local or tribal governments, with other public entities, educational institutions, private nonprofit organizations, or participating private landowners. The legislation requires that any such cooperative agreements provide clear benefits to park resources.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I would note this legislation does not authorize any new funding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank my colleague from Nevada for his effort, and we support passage of <bill type="h" number="658">H.R. 658</bill> by the House today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400029" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="658">H.R. 658</bill>, and I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="658">H.R. 658</bill> was introduced by the very effective Congressman from Nevada, JON PORTER, and would authorize the National Park Service to enter into a cooperative agreement with willing partners to protect park natural resources through collaborative efforts on land inside and outside of units of the National Park System. This was recommended by the Government Accountability Office, as the Park Service is still the only land management agency without this particular authority. So we expect this  will help control the spread of invasive species and increase the protection of parks and wildlife.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At this point, Madam Speaker, I would like to engage the majority bill manager, Mr. Grijalva, in a colloquy to clarify an issue related to this bill, if he would.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I understand that the International Association of Fish and Wildlife Agencies has brought to the committee's attention their concern that <bill type="h" number="658">H.R. 658</bill> not be interpreted to give the National Park Service authority to manage fish and wildlife outside park boundaries.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Management authority for fish and wildlife resources within State boundaries has customarily been held in trust by the respective States. Congress has repeatedly affirmed this. This trust responsibility has been implemented primarily through State fish and wildlife agencies. In general, these principles are expressed in relevant fish and wildlife policies of the Department of the Interior found in volume 43 of the Code of Federal Regulations, part 24.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Can the chairman of the subcommittee please clarify that the States' existing authority to manage fish and wildlife is not affected by <bill type="h" number="658">H.R. 658</bill>?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, will the gentleman yield?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400029" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield to the gentleman from Arizona.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman, and I agree with the gentleman from Utah on his description of Federal and State authorities to manage fish and wildlife resources.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also agree that we should promote better coordination and cooperation between the Federal Government and the States to enhance our fish and wildlife resources for future generations, especially for the control of invasive species. I assure my colleague that nothing in <bill type="h" number="658">H.R. 658</bill> diminishes or enlarges the authority of the Federal Government or any State for the conservation and management of fish and wildlife.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400029" topic="">
    <paragraph>Reclaiming my time, I thank the gentleman for his assurances, and with that, I urge adoption of the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400029" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I am pleased to yield such time as he may consume to the gentleman from Nevada (Mr. Porter), the author of this very good piece of legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400324" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, invasive animal and plant species know no boundaries. That is why I introduced <bill type="h" number="658">H.R. 658</bill>, the Natural Resource Protection Cooperative Agreement Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The passage of this legislation today has significance to my district, given the recent infestation at Lake Mead of quagga mussels. These are a species capable of causing massive destruction and billions of dollars in damages. The quagga mussel is a resilient species that multiplies at exponential rates and can cause enormous ecological, recreational, and economic damage. In recent years, the mussel has caused an estimated $5 billion in damages to the Great Lakes region.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As the law currently exists, the National Park Service does not have the legal authority to enter into cooperative agreements with neighboring States and local governments or private entities. Rather, the Park Service  must wait until invasive species cross into their lands and waterways before they can be dealt with.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Part of responsible stewardship of our local environment is being proactive and not merely responsive to new ecological challenges. <bill type="h" number="658">H.R. 658</bill> enables the National Park Service to take preventative measures in order to preserve our lands and natural resources.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By entering into cooperative agreements with State and local experts, we will be able to eradicate invasive species before they encroach onto Federal lands. We have an obligation to our children and to our community to be responsible stewards of our local environment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank my colleagues on both sides of the aisle for working in a bipartisan manner on this very important issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also want to thank my constituent Ann Schreiber in Nevada who has worked so hard to eradicate invasive plant life in my district and recognizes the importance of meeting these challenges head-on.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400029" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, we have no further speakers, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield back the balance of our time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="658">H.R. 658</bill>.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this question will be postponed.</chair>
</record>
