<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1171299603" ordinal="20" title="RECOGNIZING THE HISTORICAL SIGNIFICANCE OF THE PINEDALE ASSEMBLY CENTER">
  <speaking speaker="400025" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution (<bill type="hr" number="109">H. Res. 109</bill>) recognizing the historical significance of the Pinedale Assembly Center, the reporting site for 4,823 Japanese Americans who were unjustly interned during World War II.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from California (Mr. Berman) and the gentleman from California (Mr. Issa) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400025" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from California?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400025" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of House Resolution 109. We have been discussing in the previous resolution Executive Order 9066. When President Roosevelt signed that order, approximately 120,000 Japanese Americans were forced into internment camps, leading to the loss of their livelihoods, homes, and jobs. This action was the largest relocation of Americans in our history. Before being deported to permanent camps in desolate areas and behind barbed wires, thousands of Japanese Americans were  temporarily held at assembly centers. Close to 5,000 Japanese Americans reported to the Pinedale Assembly Center in Fresno, California.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Pinedale Assembly Center Memorial Project Committee will establish a memorial at that site, marking the tragedy that occurred there. The groundbreaking ceremony for the memorial will take place in just a few days, on February 19, 2007, 65 years after the signing of Executive Order 9066 and a day that the Japanese American community most appropriately recognizes as a national day of remembrance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="hr" number="109">H. Res. 109</bill> recognizes the historical significance of the site. The site is a symbol of the injustices suffered by Japanese Americans during World War II and a reminder of how fragile our civil liberties are in the face of fear, prejudice, and paranoia. I particularly want to commend my colleague, Representative Costa of California, for introducing this resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400196" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="hr" number="109">H. Res. 109</bill>, recognizing the historical significance of the Pinedale Assembly Center, the reporting site for over 4,823 Americans of Japanese ancestry who were unjustly interned during World War II.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Pinedale Assembly Center is located 8 miles north of downtown Fresno, California, on vacant land. It is a stark place, as was the policy that was supported by Executive Order 9066 signed by President Franklin Delano Roosevelt to authorize the tragic internment of Japanese Americans at the beginning of World War II.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The assembly center was encircled by a high chain-link fence, topped with three rows of barbed wire, and it caged American citizens whose only crime was their ancestry. Soldiers gave orders to citizens who should have been free; livelihoods were put on hold; uncertainty and fear punctuated each day. Thousands of law-abiding citizens who loved America and contributed to its strength had been trapped in endless rows of drab cell blocks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The center serves as a symbol of America's stumbling. But our country has regained its footing. It has appropriately apologized for the tragic mistake of President Roosevelt's Executive Order 9066, and it is reaffirming its commitment, through this resolution before us today, to never forget its mistakes lest they be repeated.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400025" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I am pleased to yield 3 minutes to my colleague from California (Mr. Honda).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400185" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I want to thank Mr. Berman for his leadership.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise today in support of <bill type="hr" number="109">H. Res. 109</bill>, which recognizes the historical significance of the Pinedale Assembly Center, and I want to thank House leadership for bringing two resolutions on the floor today recognizing the important historical aspects of the Japanese American internment. I also want to thank Congressman Costa for his leadership in introducing this very important resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Executive Order 9066 authorized the exclusion and internment of all Japanese Americans living on the west coast during World War II. As we recognize the Pinedale Assembly Center, I want us to place the internment period into a broader historical context rather than just focus on the plight of the Japanese Americans during World War II.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>Our Nation has always battled the dueling sentiments of openness and freedom on the one hand and apprehension and fear of perceived outsiders on the other. Due to apprehension and fear when our economy took a downturn in the 1880s, the Asian community became the target of politicians looking for someone to blame.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1882 the Congress passed the Chinese Exclusion Act to keep out people of all Chinese origin. During World War II, Japanese Americans were the well-known target of the government's submission to apprehension and fear.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>During this time, 10,000 Italian Americans were forced to relocate; 3,278 were incarcerated, while nearly 11,000 German Americans were incarcerated. German and Italian Americans were restricted during World War II by measures that branded them enemy aliens and required identification cards, travel restrictions, seizure of personal property as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our Federal Government has made amends for the fundamental violations of the basic rights of those of Japanese ancestry that took place pursuant to Executive Order 9066, but we must continue to learn from these events. In the post-9/11 world, we need to protect our Nation and our civil liberties more than ever.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As political leaders we must not fail to uphold constitutional principles.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400196" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself 1 minute.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to associate myself with the comments of Mr. Honda. I think it is very clear that you can't remember 65 years ago with the resolution and  not have a permanent, physical site for people to go to every day and realize what internment meant. So I join with my colleagues in supporting this resolution, urge its passage and recognize that this pairing of resolutions means a great deal, because it is only with something that the public  can visit 365 days a year that we will, in fact, prevent this from happening again.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400025" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I am pleased to recognize our new colleague, the gentlelady from Hawaii (Ms. Hirono) for 5 minutes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412200" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for yielding time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today to speak in support of House Resolution 109. Today we will be taking action on two related measures, House Resolution 122, earlier debated, and this resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One of the lowest points in American history occurred 65 years ago when the Constitution and civil rights of 120,000 persons of Japanese ancestry were trampled upon by their own government. Under the cloud of war, hysteria, false rumors and racial bigotry fueled official misconduct that led to the uprooting of innocent aliens and citizens alike in one of the worst wholesale infringements of constitutional rights in the 20th century.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a consequence, thousands of persons of Japanese ancestry were forced by their own government to dispose of their property, businesses, farms and possessions for pennies on the dollar, if anything at all. Families were split up and sent to different relocation camps. Educations were disrupted, and careers abruptly terminated on only a few days' notice. Wholesale violations of basic constitutional rights were committed in the name of national security. Yet not a single act of sedition or espionage  by any of the evacuees was ever proven in any court of law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To the contrary, the historic exploits of AJA in the 100th Battalion and 442nd Regimental Combat Team in Europe and the MIS in the Pacific and Asia proved that patriotism was not skin deep. The psychological and emotional pain of this experience was so deep that many evacuees never talked about their experiences for decades.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many who were directly affected by the order live and work among us still. A member of my own congressional staff, my deputy chief of staff, Susan Kodani, was born in the Manzanar Relocation Camp. Her family was then relocated to Michigan, ironically to permit her college-educated father to assist in the war effort.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many more, of course, suffered personal losses and tragedies more traumatic and devastating. By recognizing the historic significance of the Pinedale Assembly Center and by observing the Day of Remembrance as called for in earlier House Resolution 122, we say to the Nation and our fellow citizens that America can never forget this horrible tragedy. While it directly affected one segment of our population, the ramifications to all Americans are profound and no less relevant today as we wage war  in Iraq.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The constitutional rights of all Americans are in jeopardy if any group of citizens can be persecuted without legal justification. We must all stand vigilant and alert for any attempt by any group, whether a small power clique or the majority of Americans, to overstep the bounds of the law for momentary expediency or even for claims of national security during war. The protection of our constitutional rights of all of our citizens require continued vigilance from all of us.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400199" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="hr" number="109">H. Res. 109</bill>, to recognize the historical significance of the Pinedale Assembly Center in Fresno, California, the reporting site for 4,823 Japanese Americans who were unjustly interned during World War II.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is fitting that a memorial will be established at this historical location, especially on this year's National Day of Remembrance. On that same day in 1942, President Franklin D. Roosevelt signed Executive Order 9066, requiring 120,000 people of Japanese ancestry to be removed forcibly from their homes and placed in internment camps--two-thirds of these were American citizens, none of which had ever shown disloyalty to the American cause. Forced to live under harsh conditions, the last internment  camp closed four long years later.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These innocent Americans were treated unjustly by their own government during a time of war, simply because of their national origins, and such an injustice must not go unremembered. It is absolutely essential to remember the past mistakes of our government in an effort to avoid future ones.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In times of war it may be easy to get carried away and put labels on those around us, imputing disloyalty to persons of different national origins or religious backgrounds. But as we saw in World War II, such assumptions are frequently wrong, unjust, and can lead to disastrous consequences for a group of individuals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank my colleague, Representative Costa, for introducing this important legislation. We must never let such unjust practices occur in this great Nation again. I urge my colleagues to join me in supporting <bill type="hr" number="109">H. Res. 109</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400025" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from California (Mr. Berman) that the House suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, <bill type="hr" number="109">H. Res. 109</bill>.</chair>
</record>
