<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1181059208" ordinal="23" title="RECOGNIZING THE IMPORTANCE OF THE OUACHITA NATIONAL FOREST ON ITS 100TH ANNIVERSARY">
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution (<bill type="hr" number="390">H. Res. 390</bill>) recognizing the importance of the Ouachita National Forest on its 100th anniversary.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the resolution.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from the Virgin Islands (Mrs. Christensen) and the gentleman from Utah (Mr. Cannon) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from the Virgin Islands?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, House Resolution 390 was introduced by my colleague, the gentleman from Arkansas, Representative Mike Ross.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill would express recognition by the House of Representatives of the importance of the Ouachita National Forest on its centennial.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Ouachita is the largest and the oldest national forest in the southern region of the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On December 18, 1907 President Theodore Roosevelt proclaimed the establishment of what he called Arkansas National Forest. Nineteen years later, by Executive order, President Calvin Coolidge changed the name of the forest to the Ouachita National Forest, reflecting the name of both the local mountains and the main river running through the forest.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The forest encompasses six wilderness areas, seven scenic areas and 11 shooting ranges, as well as 35 recreational areas, including the 26,445-acre Winding Stair National Recreation Area.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, Ouachita is a noteworthy unit of our National Forest System, and it is appropriate that we take this action today to celebrate the forest's centennial.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to commend and congratulate my colleague, Representative Ross, for his commitment and leadership on this matter. We support the passage of House Resolution 390 and urge its adoption by the House today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of House Resolution 390, and yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>House Resolution 390 has been adequately explained by the majority, and I urge its adoption.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield such time as he may consume to the sponsor of the bill, the gentleman from Arkansas, Mike Ross.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="ROSS" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of House Resolution 390, a resolution honoring and recognizing the importance of Ouachita National Forest on its 100th anniversary. I am very fortunate to represent a good part of the Ouachita National Forest within the Fourth Congressional District of Arkansas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I'm also pleased that the entire Arkansas Congressional Delegation, Congressmen John Boozman, Vic Snyder and Marion Berry have joined me in supporting and cosponsoring this bipartisan bill honoring one of our Nation's true national treasures.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This marks the 100th birthday or anniversary, if you will, of one the largest and oldest national forests in the  southern region of the United States, the Ouachita National Forest.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As Chairwoman CHRISTENSEN indicated, in 1907 President Theodore Roosevelt created the Arkansas National Forest on reserved public lands south of the Arkansas River. And by 1926 President Calvin Coolidge issued an Executive order to change the name of the forest to the Ouachita National Forest, named after the Ouachita Mountains, which stretch from near the center of Arkansas to southeast Oklahoma, and after the principal river which drains the national forest, the Ouachita River.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For the past 100 years, the Ouachita National Forest has remained a vast, magnificent region that offers spectacular recreation, scenic and wilderness areas for numerous visitors from throughout the world. The forest provides an array of activities, ranging from ATV recreational activities and opportunities, to hiking and to mountain biking to horseback riding trails and swimming. The forest also contains five lakes, often referred to as "Diamond Lakes," which are known for their crystal clear  quality and beautiful scenery.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to the scenic views and outdoor activities the forest has to offer, the Ouachita National Forest is also one of the only places in the United States that contains an incredible crater area which allows visitors and rock collectors to dig for real diamonds and quartz crystals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today the Ouachita National Forest also includes more than 1.8 million acres in Arkansas and eastern Oklahoma, and provides timber and forestry products throughout the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And while the word "Ouachita" is the French spelling of the Native American word for "good hunting ground," the forest also contains six locations that have been designated as wilderness areas covering 65,000 acres. These areas provide environmentally safe habitats for wildlife and fish, including many threatened and endangered species, as well as watershed protection and improvement and wilderness area management.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This resolution honors and recognizes all the important services and contributions that the Ouachita National Forest continues to make available to visitors all across our country and throughout the world who come here to visit and to the spirit and practice of ensuring that our natural resources remain sources of pride for our citizens, our communities and, yes, our Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I'm proud to sponsor a resolution commemorating its 100th anniversary, and I urge my colleagues to vote in favor of House Resolution 390 today and honor Ouachita National Forest's centennial celebration.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no further speakers on this matter, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from the Virgin Islands (Mrs. Christensen) that the House suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, <bill type="hr" number="390">H. Res. 390</bill>.</chair>
</record>
