<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1178812804" ordinal="20" title="COMMEMORATING THE 100TH BACH CHOIR FESTIVAL">
  <speaking speaker="400648" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today to commemorate the distinguished Bach choir of Bethlehem, Pennsylvania, our Nation's oldest choir dedicated to the performance and celebration of musical masterpieces composed by Johann Sebastian Bach. Founded in 1898 under the direction of J. Fred Wolle, the organist of the Bethlehem Moravian Church, the choir is celebrating the 100th anniversary of the annual Bach Festival this month.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1900, the Bach choir presented their first performance of "The Mass in B Minor" in the Moravian Church in Bethlehem during the Bach Festival. Although the next Bach Festival was not held again until 1912, the Festival has blossomed into a long-standing cultural tradition in Bethlehem, attracting visitors from all around the Nation and the world each year. During the festival, the choir will once again breathe life into Bach's Mass in B Minor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since its inception, the choir has been a shining star in the city of Bethlehem. Today, the choir is comprised of 95 volunteer members and performs under the leadership and direction of Greg Funfgeld. This unique ensemble has gained international acclaim for their artistry. The choir has been welcomed to perform on some of the most renowned stages in the world, including the Kennedy Center, Carnegie Hall, Munich's Royal Residence, as well as London's Royal Albert Hall as part of a concert tour  in the United Kingdom.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Furthermore, countless listeners have tuned in across the globe to listen to the choir on National Public Radio and the BBC World Service. The discipline and talent that ushers this choir around the world is also shared with children and the young musicians in Lehigh Valley through music education programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would just like to commend all the good people at the Bach choir and congratulate them on this 100th anniversary of the Bach Festival.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
