<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1174320004" ordinal="16" title="RECOGNIZING IMPORTANCE OF HOT SPRINGS NATIONAL PARK ON ITS 175TH ANNIVERSARY">
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution (<bill type="hr" number="138">H. Res. 138</bill>) recognizing the importance of Hot Springs National Park on its 175th anniversary.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the resolution.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) and the gentleman from Utah (Mr. Bishop) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Arizona?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>House Resolution 138, introduced by my colleague, the gentleman from Arkansas, Representative MIKE ROSS, would express a recognition by the House of Representatives of the importance of the Hot Springs National Park on its 175th anniversary.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Most people know that Yellowstone is our first national park, but more than 40 years before Yellowstone was established as a park, Congress set aside 2,529 acres in the Ouachita Mountains of Arkansas to preserve 47 hot springs located there.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The law was enacted at the request of the General Assembly of the Territory of Arkansas and signed by President Andrew Jackson on April 20, 1832. That made the Hot Springs Reservation the first nationally protected parkland.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The reservation was turned over to the Department of the Interior when  that Department was established in 1849. However, it took another quarter of a century, a ruling from the U.S. Supreme Court, and the protection of Federal troops to settle the bogus land claims and chase off overeager entrepreneurs seeking to make profit from the springs. Notably, the 1916 Organic Act which established the National Park Service mentioned only the Hot Springs Reservation  by name, even though by that time several other national parks and monuments had been designated by Congress. The Organic Act placed all these units under the supervision, management, and control of the new agency.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On March 4, 1921, Congress elevated Hot Springs to a national park status, apparently with the personal interest of the first director of the National Park Service, Stephen Mather.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Bathhouse Row, the Hot Springs street lined with opulent bathhouses and hotels, was added to the National Register of Historic Places on November 13, 1974. The most elegant of these bathhouses, the Fordyce, has since been adapted to use as a visitor center and museum.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The park currently totals 5,550 acres and attracts over 1 million visitors a year. The park plans a 175th anniversary celebration on Friday, April 20; and this resolution will be a fitting commemoration of the role Hot Springs played in National Park history.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I want to commend and congratulate my colleague, Representative Ross, for his commitment and leadership on this matter. We strongly support the passage of House Resolution 138 and urge its adoption by the House.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400029" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>House Resolution 138 was adequately explained by the majority, and we support this resolution and we urge its adoption.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, at this time I would like to yield as much time as he may consume to my colleague from Arkansas (Mr. Ross).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="ROSS" of="">
    <paragraph>Thank you, Chairman Grijalva.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I rise today in support of House Resolution 138, a resolution honoring and recognizing the importance of Hot Springs National Park on its 175th anniversary. I am pleased that the entire Arkansas congressional delegation is supporting and cosponsoring this bipartisan bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>April 20, 2007, will mark the 175th anniversary of Hot Springs National Park in Hot Springs, Arkansas. This resolution will write into history the important role that Hot Springs National Park has played in the formation of the Department of the Interior and the National Park System.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The very idea of setting aside special places in the United States for the future enjoyment of its citizens originated in Hot Springs, Arkansas, when on April 20, 1832, President Andrew Jackson and the United States Congress established Hot Springs Reservation to protect the 47 hot springs in Garland County, Arkansas. That year, Hot Springs Reservation became the first protected area in the Nation and was the only Federal area mentioned by name in the act that established the National Park System.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Hot Springs Reservation was then officially renamed Hot Springs National Park on March 4, 1921, becoming America's 18th national park, joining many other national landmarks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For more than 200 years, Hot Springs National Park has remained an area of exceptional beauty and magnificence. People have used the hot spring water and therapeutic baths to treat a variety of ailments, and the reservation eventually developed into a well-known resort nicknamed "the American Spa." Well, today Hot Springs National Park protects eight historic bathhouses, and the Bathhouse Row area in Hot Springs National Park is a national historic landmark district that contains the largest  collection of bathhouses of its kind in North America. It provides visitors from around the country and the world with leisure activities such as hiking, picnicking, and scenic drives and remains a national treasure to be enjoyed by generations of Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>Hot Springs National Park has played a crucial role in the formation of the United States National Park System. I am proud to sponsor a resolution commemorating its 175th anniversary, and I urge my colleagues to vote in favor of House Resolution 138 today.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400029" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) that the House suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, <bill type="hr" number="138">H. Res. 138</bill>.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this question will be postponed.</chair>
</record>
