<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1194973204" ordinal="40" title="COMMENDING ED BLOCK COURAGE AWARD FOUNDATION AND DESIGNATING NOVEMBER 2007 AS NATIONAL COURAGE MONTH">
  <narrative>COMMENDING ED BLOCK COURAGE AWARD FOUNDATION AND DESIGNATING NOVEMBER 2007 AS NATIONAL COURAGE MONTH -- (House of Representatives - November 13, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H13813]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and concur in the Senate concurrent resolution (<bill type="sc" number="45">S. Con. Res. 45</bill>) commending the Ed Block Courage Award Foundation for its work in aiding children and families affected by child abuse, and designating November 2007 as National Courage Month.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the Senate concurrent resolution.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the Senate concurrent resolution is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="sc" number="45">S. Con. Res. 45</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas the Ed Block Courage Award was established by Sam Lamantia in 1978 in honor of Ed Block, the head athletic trainer of the Baltimore Colts and a respected humanitarian;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas each year in Baltimore, Maryland, the Foundation honors recipients from the National Football League who have been chosen by their teammates as exemplifying sportsmanship and courage;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Ed Block Courage Award has become one of the most esteemed honors bestowed upon players in the NFL;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Ed Block Courage Award Foundation has grown from a Baltimore-based local charity to the Courage House National Support Network for Kids operated in partnership with 17 NFL teams in their respective cities; and</narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas Courage Houses are facilities that provide support and care for abused children and their families in these 17 locations across the country: Baltimore, Maryland, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, Chicago, Illinois, Miami, Florida, Detroit, Michigan, Dallas, Texas, Westchester County, New York, Oakland, California, Seattle, Washington, Charlotte, North Carolina, Cleveland, Ohio, Atlanta, Georgia, St. Louis, Missouri, Indianapolis, Indiana, Buffalo, New York, San Francisco, California, and Minneapolis,  Minnesota: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved by the Senate (the House of Representatives concurring), That it is the sense of Congress that--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) National Courage Month provides an opportunity to educate the people of the United States about the positive role that professional athletes can play as inspirations for America's youth; and</narrative>
  <narrative> (2) the Ed Block Courage Award Foundation should be recognized for its outstanding contributions toward helping those affected by child abuse.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Davis) and the gentleman from California (Mr. Issa) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Illinois.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days in which to revise and extend their remarks.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Illinois?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge passage of this resolution commending professional football players for their work against child abuse.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a member of the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, I am pleased to join my colleague in the consideration of <bill type="sc" number="45">S. Con. Res. 45</bill>, a bill that commends the Ed Block Courage Award Foundation for its work in aiding children and families affected by child abuse.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="sc" number="45">S. Con. Res. 45</bill> was introduced by Senator Benjamin L. Cardin, on September 17, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="sc" number="45">S. Con. Res. 45</bill> was reported from the Oversight Committee on November 8, 2007, by voice vote. Mr. Speaker, the Ed Block Courage Award Foundation is a Baltimore, Maryland based local charity that formulated the Courage House National Support Network for Kids. The Courage House represents a partnership effort between the Foundation, National Football League Charities, the Professional Football Athletic Trainers Society, the National Football League Players Association, National Football League  Films, the Pro Football Hall of Fame and National Football League Alumni. This partnership promotes the prevention of child abuse by raising awareness of the epidemic and assisting agencies who provide for the care and treatment of abused children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Ed Block Courage Award Foundation honors recipients from the National Football League who have been chosen by their teammates as exemplifying sportsmanship and courage. Currently, the Ed Block Courage Awards event is heralded as one of the most prestigious in the National Football League.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I commend my colleague Senator Cardin for seeking to commend the Ed Block Courage Award Foundation and urge the swift  passage of this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400196" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today to urge passage of <bill type="sc" number="45">S. Con. Res. 45</bill> because there is in fact nothing, nothing more despicable than those who prey upon children. Whether that abuse is physical, psychological or sexual, this crime destroys lives, harms families, and all too often is perpetrated with a cruelty that is unreported and unseen.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I support the work of this foundation and its recognition that the National Football League players can off the field make a real contribution to making America a better, safer place.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>Whether it is John Elway or Joe Montana or any of the other past recipients of this award, they have in fact worked long and hard, not for millions of dollars or thousands of dollars, but for the good of the young people who are our future in this country. Therefore, I too join my colleague and urge the House to unanimously support this resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today to urge passage of <bill type="sc" number="45">S. Con. Res. 45</bill>, which commends the Ed Block Courage Award Foundation for its work to prevent child abuse.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, there is nothing sadder in this country than the specter of children being abused by adults. Whether it's physical, psychological or sexual abuse, these crimes destroy lives, harm families and, all too often, perpetuate cruelty and crime for generations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The award, named for the longtime head athletic trainer of the Baltimore Colts, recognizes the NFL player whose off-the-field efforts have done the most in that year to raise awareness of this often hidden crime. Past winners include Dan Marino, Tedy Bruschi, Joe Klecko, John Elway, Joe Montana and Ronnie Lott.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, we thank Baltimore for crabcakes and Billie Holliday and Camden Yards and Cal Ripken. And today, we thank Charm City for this.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The award was the vision of Sam Lamantia Jr., a Baltimore hair stylist.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The courage award concept was initiated by Ernie Accorsi, a longtime NFL executive who served as general manager in Baltimore in the early 1980s. Larry Harris, then assistant sports editor of the Baltimore Evening Sun, had the idea to name the award for Block, a forward-thinking, innovative trainer who had a lifelong passion for preventing and addressing child abuse.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The NFL's athletic trainers worked to take the award to a national level.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, it represents a cooperative effort of the foundation, the NFL, the NFL Players Association, the NFL Alumni Association, NFL films, the Professional Football Athletic Trainers Society and the Pro Football Hall of Fame. Pete Rozelle, the league's late commissioner, was among its biggest supporters.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The foundation has helped open Courage Houses, sanctuaries for abused children, in 14 NFL cities. Its annual awards ceremony attracts speakers from the highest levels of the sport.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It's been a great partnership, Mr. Speaker, between pro football and the Ed Block Foundation, and it is worthy of our commendation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Davis) that the House suspend the rules and concur in the Senate concurrent resolution, <bill type="sc" number="45">S. Con. Res. 45</bill>.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the Senate concurrent resolution was concurred in.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
