<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1185768000" ordinal="14" title="ALLOWING YSLETA DEL SUR PUEBLO TRIBE TO DETERMINE BLOOD QUANTUM REQUIREMENT">
  <narrative>ALLOWING YSLETA DEL SUR PUEBLO TRIBE TO DETERMINE BLOOD QUANTUM REQUIREMENT -- (House of Representatives - July 30, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H8826]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent for the immediate consideration in the House of the bill (<bill type="h" number="1696">H.R. 1696</bill>) to amend the Ysleta del Sur Pueblo and Alabama and Coushatta Indian Tribes of Texas Restoration Act to allow the Ysleta del Sur Pueblo tribe to determine blood quantum requirement for membership in that Tribe.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from the Virgin Islands?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the bill, as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="1696">H.R. 1696</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. BLOOD QUANTUM REQUIREMENT DETERMINED BY TRIBE.</narrative>
  <narrative> Section 108(a)(2) of the Ysleta del Sur Pueblo and Alabama and Coushatta Indian Tribes of Texas Restoration Act (25 U.S.C. 1300g-7(2)) is amended by striking "if the descendant" and all that follows through the end of the paragraph and inserting "if the descendant is enrolled by the tribe".&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, one of the greatest exercises of tribal sovereignty is the ability of a tribe to determine their tribal membership. This measure would allow a Texas Tribe to determine the blood quantum requirement for membership in that tribe.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congressman REYES of Texas introduced <bill type="h" number="1696">H.R. 1696</bill> to restore the Tribe's right to determine its own membership requirements by deleting a blood quantum requirement specified in a 1987 law. Passage of this legislation would extend to the Tribe the same sovereign right possessed by all other Indian tribes--the ability to determine who is and is not a member of the Tribe.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This measure is long overdue. Similar legislation has been introduced every Congress since the 106th Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this measure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill was ordered to be engrossed and read a third time, was read the third time, and passed, and a motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
