<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1197997209" ordinal="76" title="PAYING TRIBUTE TO HONORABLE JULIA CARSON">
  <narrative>PAYING TRIBUTE TO HONORABLE JULIA CARSON -- (House of Representatives - December 18, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H16811]</narrative>
  <chair> Under a previous order of the House, the gentlewoman from California (Mrs. Capps) is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400062" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I join my colleagues this evening in honoring the life of our dear friend, JULIA CARSON. And I want to say a word in keeping with the comments by our colleague, our leader, JOHN LARSON from Connecticut, who spoke of the sacredness, really, of this hour that we can spend with one another to lift up the life of a colleague such as JULIA CARSON.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>JULIA entered Congress the same year as my husband, Walter, in 1996. And the reason I honor this time together is that I have a poignant memory. My husband died suddenly, and my daughter and I found ourselves on the floor here listening to his colleagues, now my colleagues, speak of his life. And it was a tradition that I wasn't familiar with, but it touched me in a way that I know blesses the memory of those who have gone, who have served with us. And in this case, for someone as special  as JULIA CARSON, it is a moment that this place becomes what it should be, and is treasured by me.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, this Member of Congress became my colleague, JULIA CARSON, when I joined Congress in 1998. One of the first events I attended as a Member was an event held by domestic violence advocates, a coalition, a national coalition of the kind of grassroots organizations that I know JULIA CARSON represented in Indianapolis, but I also, in my previous life as a nurse in my community, knew very well at the community level. I wasn't as experienced when I came to Congress as JULIA  was when she did. And I listened to her. We were kind of lined up, Members of Congress, to address this coalition on domestic violence. I could speak from my professional experience. But she spoke before me. And she dazzled that crowd because she spoke as a survivor and as someone who had experienced every single thing that they themselves were here in</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On that day that I listened to JULIA as a brand new Member, I knew that I was in a very special crowd if it included someone like JULIA CARSON. She knew how to take her experiences and become such a role model and strong advocate; civil rights, victims of domestic violence. She improved the lives of countless individuals, and she did so by fixing things that were broken, but also by inspiring people to not give up.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And then, as we moved along and as has been referenced, her style and her elegance, I used to love to see her here and to see her bearing and to see her fitting the word "queen" in every sense of that word. What a delight to serve with JULIA CARSON. And we saw her, as her illness began to show its effects on her body, never on her spirit, never on her soul, never once dampened her smile, her dazzling beautiful smile. And when I would see her moving slowly, and then with assistance, even  in a wheelchair, to come and move about, she never gave an indication of weakness or that she was down. She was always up and inspiring me when I would see her. I wanted to spend time with her.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This was a tough time for her. She never let us know it. She kept fighting for all of the issues she cared so much about. And now I want to just close by saying, you know, JULIA, we owe you to continue the legacy that you began.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think of JULIA's suffering with lung cancer. And I think about the fact that three of her colleagues, four, now, of our colleagues this year have died of cancer from this place. And JULIA, I make a pledge to you and to the others that we need to not rest. We need to follow your courage and your endurance and not rest until we do something about this dreaded disease, and do something here, and do it in your memory, and do some other things in your memory as well. And so, I make  that pledge to you, JULIA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And I also join my colleagues in remembering you forever for your wit, your elegance, your perseverance, and of course always, JULIA, your smile. I will always love you and treasure your memory.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
