<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1213718403" ordinal="32" title="LEADVILLE MINE DRAINAGE TUNNEL REMEDIATION ACT OF 2008">
  <narrative>LEADVILLE MINE DRAINAGE TUNNEL REMEDIATION ACT OF 2008 -- (House of Representatives - June 17, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H5430]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="5511">H.R. 5511</bill>) to direct the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Reclamation, to remedy problems caused by a collapsed drainage tunnel in Leadville, Colorado, and for other purposes, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="5511">H.R. 5511</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. LEADVILLE MINE DRAINAGE TUNNEL REMEDIATION.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Short Title.--This section may be cited as the "Leadville Mine Drainage Tunnel Remediation Act of 2008".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Tunnel Remediation.--The Reclamation Projects Authorization and Adjustment Act of 1992 (Public Law 102-575) is amended as follows:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) By striking section 705.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) In section 708(a)--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) by striking "(a)" and inserting "(a)(1)";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) by striking "The Secretary shall have" and inserting "Except as provided by paragraph (2), the Secretary shall have"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) by adding at the end the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(2) The Secretary shall participate in the implementation of the operable unit 6 remedy for the California Gulch Superfund Site, as such remedy is defined in the Environmental Protection Agency's 2003 Record of Decision for such operable unit, by--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(A) treating water behind any blockage or bulkhead in the Leadville Mine Drainage Tunnel, including surface water diverted into the Tunnel workings as part of the remedy; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(B) managing and maintaining the mine pool behind such blockage or bulkhead at a level that precludes surface runoff and releases and minimizes the potential for tunnel failure due to excessive water pressure in the tunnel.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) In section 708(f), by striking "and 708" and inserting ", 708, and 709".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) By adding at the end of title VII the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;"SEC. 709. TUNNEL MAINTENANCE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "The Secretary shall take such steps to repair or maintain the structural integrity of the Leadville Mine Drainage Tunnel (LMDT) as may be necessary in order to prevent tunnel failure and to preclude uncontrolled release of water from any portion of the tunnel.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) In the table of sections contained in section 2--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) by striking the item relating to section 705; and</narrative>
  <narrative> (B) by inserting after the item relating to section 708 the following new item:&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <narrative>"Sec..709..Tunnel maintenance.".&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from Guam (Ms. Bordallo) and gentleman from Utah (Mr. Bishop) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentlewoman from Guam.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days in which to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from Guam?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="5511">H.R. 5511</bill> was introduced by our colleague, Congressman Doug Lamborn of Colorado. The bill, as amended, would direct the Bureau of Reclamation to remedy problems caused by collapses in the Leadville Mine Drainage Tunnel. Due to structural deterioration, contaminated water has backed up in the tunnel posing a grave public health and environmental threat.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill has received bipartisan support. We have no objection to this noncontroversial bill. And I ask my colleagues to support its passage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400029" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in strong support for the bill that was introduced by our committee colleague, Doug Lamborn of Colorado. The Leadville Mine Tunnel was supposed to be used for a nearby Federal water project but has ended up becoming a public danger. It has been on the verge of bursting and sending what is presumed to be chemical-laden water toward local homes. The Bureau of Reclamation owns the tunnel and must be responsible for resolving the situation. And that is what this bipartisan  bill accomplishes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Leadville Mine, addressed in this bill, was used during World War II and the Korean War to supply critical metals to help our Nation. Years ago, our Nation smartly invested in mining our natural resources. Yet today, the mining industry is under attack by some and by many. And the net effect, of course, has been to outsource U.S. jobs to countries that have commonsense environmental regulations and an increase in consumer prices to those here at home. It would be nice if Congress would promote  our own mining industry and not destroy it by 1,000 cuts. America does deserve better.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill, though, solves a particular problem that is faced in Colorado. It is a bipartisan bill. And I urge its adoption.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, today is, an important day for the citizens of Lake County and all residents of Colorado. They deserve to see what the federal government will do to correct problems associated with the Leadville Mine Drainage Tunnel.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Leadville Mine Drainage Tunnel was originally constructed by the federal Bureau of Mines in the 1940's and 1950's to facilitate the extraction of lead and zinc ore for the World War II and the Korean War efforts. The Bureau of Reclamation acquired the Tunnel in 1959 hoping to use the tunnel as a source of water for the Frying pan-Arkansas Project. Although the tunnel was never used for the Fryingpan-Arkansas Project, water that flows out of the tunnel is considered part of the natural flow  of the Arkansas River.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With the passage and subsequent signing into law of <bill type="h" number="429">H.R. 429</bill> during the 102nd Congress (1992), the Bureau of Reclamation constructed and continues to operate a water treatment plant at the mouth of the Tunnel.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Groundwater levels at the tunnel have fluctuated in recent years. In addition, a collapse in the tunnel has increased the tunnel's mine pool significantly, leading to new seeps and springs in the area. Estimates suggest that up to 1 billion gallons of water may have built up within the mine pool.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In November 2007, the Environmental Protection Agency sent a letter to the Bureau of Reclamation expressing concerns over a catastrophic blowout, and in February 2008, the Lake County Commissioners declared a state of emergency.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We know that the Bureau of Reclamation is completing a risk assessment in the area, and we look forward to reviewing that report. Additionally, some emergency measures are currently being undertaken by the Environmental Protection Agency and the Bureau of Reclamation to relieve water pressure in the vicinity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But many of the problems reported at this site are not new. Legislation addressing this matter and authorizing the Secretary of the Interior to rehabilitate this tunnel dates back to at least 1976.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In response to the request for action from the local community, I worked together with Congressman Mark Udall from Colorado and introduced <bill type="h" number="5511">H.R. 5511</bill>. This bill would direct the Bureau of Reclamation to relieve water pressure behind certain blockages in the tunnel, permanently manage the mine pool behind any blockage to prevent releases of contaminated water, and manage the tunnel in such a way to prevent failure of the structure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I look forward to seeing this situation remedied so that concerns about human safety and environmental integrity may be appropriately and responsibly addressed. I encourage all members to support passage of this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400331" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I submit the following letters for inclusion in the Record on the consideration of <bill type="h" number="5511">H.R. 5511</bill>, the Leadville Mine Drainage Tunnel Act of 2008.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>House of Representatives, Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, </paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington, DC, June 12, 2008.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR CHAIRMAN RAHALL: I write to you regarding <bill type="h" number="5511">H.R. 5511</bill>, a bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior to remedy problems caused by a collapsed drainage tunnel in Leadville, Colorado.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="5511">H.R. 5511</bill> contains provisions that fall within the jurisdiction of the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure. I recognize and appreciate your desire to bring this legislation before the House in an expeditious manner and, accordingly, I will not seek a sequential referral of the bill. However, I agree to waive consideration of this bill with the mutual understanding that my decision to forego a sequential referral of the bill does not waive, reduce, or otherwise affect the jurisdiction  of the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure over <bill type="h" number="5511">H.R. 5511</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Further, the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure reserves the right to seek the appointment of conferees during any House-Senate conference convened on this legislation on provisions of the bill that are within the Committee's jurisdiction. I ask for your commitment to support any request by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure for the appointment of conferees on <bill type="h" number="5511">H.R. 5511</bill> or similar legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Please place a copy of this letter and your response acknowledging the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure's jurisdictional interest in the Committee Report on <bill type="h" number="5511">H.R. 5511</bill> and in the Congressional Record during consideration of the measure on the House Floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I look forward to working with you as we prepare to pass this important legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>James L. Oberstar, M.C.,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>&lt;pre&gt;--&lt;/pre&gt;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>COMMITTEE ON NATURAL RESOURCES,</paragraph>
    <paragraph> Washington, DC, June 16, 2008.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR MR. CHAIRMAN: Thank you for your willingness to expedite floor consideration of <bill type="h" number="5511">H.R. 5511</bill>, a bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior to remedy problems caused by a collapsed drainage tunnel in Leadville, Colorado.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I appreciate your willingness to waive rights to further consideration of <bill type="h" number="5511">H.R. 5511</bill>, notwithstanding the jurisdictional interest of the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure. Of course, this waiver does not prejudice any further jurisdictional claims by your Committee over this legislation or similar language. Furthermore, I agree to support your request for appointment of conferees from the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure if a conference is held on this matter.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This exchange of letters will be placed in the committee report and inserted in the Congressional Record as part of the consideration of the bill on the House floor. Thank you for the cooperative spirit in which you have worked regarding this matter and others between our respective committees.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With warm regards, I am</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nick J. Rahall II,</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400029" topic="">
    <paragraph>Once again, I have no other speakers on this particular bill. Does the gentlelady have any other speakers?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>I have no other speakers.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400029" topic="">
    <paragraph>I will yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no further speakers, and I yield back.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from Guam (Ms. Bordallo) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="5511">H.R. 5511</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I object to the vote on the ground that a quorum is not present and make the point of order that a quorum is not present.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this motion will be postponed.</chair>
  <chair>The point of no quorum is considered withdrawn.</chair>
</record>
