<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1194973204" ordinal="31" title="EFFECTIVE CHILD PORNOGRAPHY PROSECUTION ACT OF 2007">
  <narrative>EFFECTIVE CHILD PORNOGRAPHY PROSECUTION ACT OF 2007 -- (House of Representatives - November 13, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H13591]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400080" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="4120">H.R. 4120</bill>) to amend title 18, United States Code, to provide for more effective prosecution of cases involving child pornography, and for other purposes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="4120">H.R. 4120</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "Effective Child Pornography Prosecution Act of 2007".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. FINDINGS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Congress makes the following findings:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) Child pornography is estimated to be a multibillion dollar industry of global proportions, facilitated by the growth of the Internet.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) Recent data has shown that 83 percent of child pornography possessors had images of children younger than 12 years old, 39 percent had images of children younger than 6 years old, and 19 percent had images of children younger than 3 years old.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) Child pornography is a permanent record of a child's abuse and the distribution of child pornography images revictimizes the child each time the image is viewed.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) Child pornography is readily available through virtually every Internet technology, including Web sites, email, instant messaging, Internet Relay Chat, newsgroups, bulletin boards, and peer-to-peer.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) The technological ease, lack of expense, and anonymity in obtaining and distributing child pornography over the Internet has resulted in an explosion in the multijurisdictional distribution of child pornography.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (6) The Internet is well recognized as a method of distributing goods and services across State lines.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (7) The transmission of child pornography using the Internet constitutes transportation in interstate commerce.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 3. EFFECTIVE CHILD PORNOGRAPHY PROSECUTION.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Section 2252.--Section 2252 of title 18, United States Code, is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in subsection (a)(1), by inserting "or affecting" after "ships in";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) in subsection (a)(2), by striking "knowingly" and all that follows through "mails" and inserting "knowingly receives, distributes, or reproduces for distribution, in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce, any visual depiction";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) in subsection (a)(3)(B), by inserting "or affecting" before "interstate"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) in subsection (a)(4)(B)--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) by inserting "in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce" after "possesses"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) by striking "that has been" and all that follows through "by computer".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Section 2252A.--Section 2252A of title 18, United States Code, is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in paragraphs (1) through (4) and (6) of subsection (a), by inserting "or affecting" before "interstate or foreign commerce" each place it appears; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) in subsection (a)(5)(b)--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) by inserting "in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce" after "possesses"; and</narrative>
  <narrative>(B) by striking `that has been" and all that follows through "by computer" the second place it appears.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Michigan (Mr. Conyers) and the gentleman from Virginia (Mr. Goodlatte) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Michigan.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400080" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days in which to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Michigan?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400080" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Members of the committee, <bill type="h" number="4120">H.R. 4120</bill>, the Effective Child Pornography Prosecution Act, addresses a truly unfortunate and, in my view, wrongly decided decision by the 10th Circuit Court of Appeals in the case of United States v. Schaefer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, while the defendant was found to be in the possession of child pornography, the court nevertheless reversed his conviction because it concluded that the statute required, and the government had failed to prove, that the contraband had actually crossed State lines. This statute in question makes it illegal to possess child pornography "in commerce."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The court held that this phrase, "in commerce," meant that Congress intended that the contraband had to actually cross State lines. Had the statute instead used the phrase "in or affecting interstate commerce," the court held, the conviction would have been upheld, as that phrase is well understood as reflecting Congress' intent to use the full reach of its constitutional commerce clause power.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="4120">H.R. 4120</bill> makes clear that the Congress intends that the prohibitions against child pornography reach the full extent of its constitutional authority. And as hearings in the Judiciary Committee hearing demonstrated, the child pornography business is no respecter of national or international borders. Even conduct that may appear to be wholly localized in its manifestation can nevertheless have an unmistakable effect in interstate commerce.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So let there be no mistake that Congress intends to use its full commerce clause authority to reach activities concluded by this odious business. And we want to make it so clear that even the 10th Circuit Court of Appeals cannot be mistaken by that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And so I urge my colleagues to fully support this bill, as I expect that they will.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400154" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="4120">H.R. 4120</bill>, the Effective Child Pornography Prosecution Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill responds to a recent decision by the 10th Circuit United States Court of Appeals in United States v. Schaefer, in which the court ruled that the transmission of child pornography on the Internet did not satisfy the interstate requirement in child pornography laws.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The proposed legislative fix will allow the government to satisfy the interstate requirement by proving beyond a reasonable doubt that the material moved in or affected interstate foreign commerce, which would expand the jurisdiction to prosecute these crimes when the Internet is used. This is the broadest assertion of interstate commerce power that the Congress can make consistent with the Constitution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, this bill, and the majority's package of bills, does not include a needed modification to existing law which would require a 2-year mandatory minimum for possession of child pornography. At an October 17, 2007, full committee hearing on the subject, the Justice Department witness outlined why such a measure was needed. Deputy Assistant Attorney General Laurence Rothenberg explained that child pornography fueled the victimization of children and led to sexual assaults against children.  He also noted that Federal judges were routinely giving out lenient sentences to child pornographers below levels established by the Federal sentencing guidelines.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While the fix proposed today in <bill type="h" number="4120">H.R. 4120</bill> is a good step forward, it is a limited step in comparison to other measures that are needed, including a mandatory minimum for child pornography crimes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400080" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I want to again extend my compliments and express my gratefulness to the gentleman from Virginia for his support on this measure. And as usual, he points out perhaps small items that only a person with his experience would want to bring to the attention of the Members of the House.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The author of this bill is NANCY BOYDA of Kansas, our distinguished colleague, to whom I am proud to yield as much time as she may consume.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412210" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the Department of Justice estimates last year that one in five children between the ages of 10 and 17 had received a sexual solicitation or approach while they were using the Internet. With so many threats out there, Congress must provide a unified message that we, as a society, together, will stand strong for Internet safety.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What we will do today is good; it's very good. We will pass five pieces of legislation that will help keep our children safe. And I'm so proud that my legislation, <bill type="h" number="4120">H.R. 4120</bill>, the Effective Child Pornography Prosecution Act of 2007, is going to be part of that message.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>In September of this year, a man that I am sorry to say was from Kansas, William Schaefer, was found guilty of both "knowingly receiving" and "knowingly possessing" child pornography that had "been transported in interstate commerce, by any means including by computer." Sadly, the 10th Circuit Court of Appeals overturned the decision and that offender was acquitted. The Court ruled that just because images are obtained on the Internet doesn't mean that they were necessarily transmitted  across State lines. The Court essentially then asked Congress to clarify its intent that the Internet is, in fact, interstate commerce, and we will do that with the passage of the Effective Child Pornography Prosecution Act of 2007. This legislation closes the judicial loophole that allowed a guilty man who hurt our children and was allowed to go free.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As concerned citizens, as parents, and as Members of Congress, Mr. Speaker, we must do all that we can to keep our children safe. That means we must make a commitment to being tough on crime, and to make sure those who violate the law are fully prosecuted, to ensure that the law is so clear that it deters such heinous crimes from ever happening again.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400154" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself 30 seconds to thank the chairman of the Judiciary Committee for his gracious comments regarding my involvement on issues related to the Internet, particularly as it relates to fighting child pornography, but also to point out that a mandatory minimum sentence of 2 years for these child pornographers is not a small thing. What is a small thing are the sentences that many judges unfortunately are imposing upon child pornographers much, much less than 2  years, and a mandatory minimum sentence would go a long way towards curing this problem and keeping more of these pornographers off of the Internet.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400080" topic="">
    <paragraph>I couldn't agree with the gentleman more.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400154" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the chairman.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is now my pleasure to yield for such time as she may consume the gentlewoman from Illinois (Mrs. Biggert) who has been a leading advocate on this issue and a strong supporter of this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400027" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today to express my strong support for <bill type="h" number="4120">H.R. 4120</bill>, the Effective Child Pornography Prosecution Act. I am very pleased to be the lead Republican cosponsor, and I thank the gentlewoman from Kansas for all of her hard work, but I am proud to be part of this important bill which will close an unacceptable loophole in the Federal criminal code.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As my colleagues have already pointed out, the U.S. Court of Appeals for the 10th Circuit handed down a decision this year which freed a defendant who had been convicted of receiving and possessing child pornography. The case of U.S. v. Schaefer was not overturned for lack of evidence but rather because the prosecution failed to prove that images downloaded from the Internet moved across State lines in "interstate commerce."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The judges who decided this case pointed out that the use of the phrase "in commerce" instead of "affecting commerce" in the law signaled Congress' intent to limit Federal jurisdiction in the prosecution of child pornographers. As cochair of the Missing and Exploited Children's Caucus, I can assure you, Mr. Speaker, nothing could be further from the truth. We in Congress know the horrible consequences that result from the sexual exploitation of children used to create these images. We also  take very seriously our duty to do everything in our power to protect children, punish predators and deter future acts of abuse.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is why the bill we are considering today deserves our full support. It will close the loophole in current law by replacing the phrase "in commerce" with the phrase "affecting commerce" in the child pornography statute. It classifies the intent of Congress and will ensure that predators that use the Internet to transmit child pornography end up behind bars where they belong.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to take this opportunity to again thank the gentlewoman from Kansas, my good friend, NANCY BOYDA,  for introducing this legislation. I also would like to thank the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children for their assistance and counsel in drafting the bill. Mr. Speaker, as a mother of four and grandmother of seven, I know there is nothing more important than safeguarding our children from predators. We must not allow those  who sexually exploit children to avoid prosecution because of a technicality.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge all my colleagues to support <bill type="h" number="4120">H.R. 4120</bill> to help close this egregious loophole in the law.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400080" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield to the gentlewoman from Kansas.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412210" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank my esteemed colleague from Illinois for her help. I know the fathers in this room are just as concerned as the mothers, but as we mothers stick together and stand up to keep our children safe, this bill will go a long way, and I certainly appreciate the wonderful help that we have had on this bill. Thank you so much.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400080" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the author (Mrs. Boyda) and her Republican cosponsor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I return the balance of our time. There are no further speakers.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400154" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no further speakers, and I yield back.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Michigan (Mr. Conyers) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="4120">H.R. 4120</bill>.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400080" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this motion will be postponed.</chair>
</record>
