<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1184731200" ordinal="7" title="CONGRATULATING SHAW FARMS ON THEIR 200TH ANNIVERSARY">
  <narrative>CONGRATULATING SHAW FARMS ON THEIR 200TH ANNIVERSARY -- (House of Representatives - July 18, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H7998]</narrative>
  <narrative>(Mrs. SCHMIDT asked and was given permission to address the House for 1 minute and to revise and extend her remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412010" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today to congratulate Shaw Farms on their 200th anniversary. Shaw Farms, located along State Route 131 in Miami Township, Claremont County, Ohio, is home to the region's finest summertime produce. It is best known for its sweet corn, tomatoes, melons, beans, squash and cucumbers. Shaw Farms began operating during the tenure of Thomas Jefferson. Think about that, the tenure of Thomas Jefferson, and has continually operated as a family farm since 1807. It is one  the oldest family farms in Ohio.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today the family farm is run by Jerry and Jean Shaw, with the help of their children and grandchildren. Through the hard work of the Shaw family, much of greater Cincinnati relies on them for their produce.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Summertime produce is not the only thing the Shaw family is known for. Each October, thousands of visitors, including many eager school children come to the family's Fall Festival, which is known for its pumpkins, hayrides and farm animals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This weekend the Shaws are hosting a bicentennial bash to help celebrate their amazing accomplishment. In the spirit of the Shaw family, they have invited everyone in the area to enjoy their success. Of course many of the items for which they are well known will be on their menu.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Shaw family's fresh produce and family entertainment is truly an asset to all the communities in southern Ohio.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, please join me in wishing the Shaw Farms a happy 200th anniversary, continued success, and let's wish them at least 200 more years in Ohio.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
