<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1178640003" ordinal="44" title="CONCURRENT RESOLUTION ON THE BUDGET FOR FISCAL YEAR 2008">
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, pursuant to House Resolution 370, I call up the Senate Concurrent Resolution (<bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>) setting forth the congressional budget for the United States Government for fiscal year 2008 and including the appropriate budgetary levels for fiscal years 2007 and 2009 through 2012, and ask for its immediate consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the Senate concurrent resolution.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to House Resolution 370, the amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of House Concurrent Resolution 99, as adopted by the House, is adopted and the Senate concurrent resolution, as amended, is considered read.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="MOTION TO GO TO CONFERENCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, pursuant to House Resolution 370, I offer a motion.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will report the motion.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to House Resolution 370, the previous question is ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400351" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I offer a motion to instruct conferees.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Wisconsin?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400351" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the motion we are offering today reflects a very simple up or down choice: One, rejecting the largest tax increase in our Nation's history, which is contained in the House budget; two, insisting on the lowest possible level of taxes available in the budget conference; and three, stopping the raid on Social Security's cash surpluses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Both the House and the Senate Democrat budgets call for historic tax increases, and we in the minority can't do anything to prevent that. But we hope that, with this vote, we can at least minimize the damage that these tax hikes will bring.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me take a moment to describe the options that we have to work with as a minority. The House-passed budget would impose a tax hike of $392 billion from such things as reimposing  the tax penalty on married couples, cutting in half the child tax credit, and raising marginal income tax rates on low- and middle-income working families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This would increase the average family's tax bill by roughly $2,900 a year and likely reverse the economic progress we have achieved over the past few years. So, right along with their higher tax bill, Americans would see fewer jobs and slower wage growth.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This massive tax increase was the only way the House Democrats could accomplish their massive increase in spending. Their budget makes no effort, none, to moderate the growth of spending. It simply requires taxpayers to send more of their money to make the Democrats' budget numbers add up.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In our debate a few weeks ago, the Democrats tried gamely to assert that their budget doesn't increase taxes after all. And as proof, they pointed to the novel policy language that claims that they will extend some of the tax relief provisions enacted in 2001 and 2003. They have these reserve funds that say they don't really want to raise taxes. But if you read the fine print, this would only happen later and only if they hike some other taxes by the same amount. So even with the flowery reserve  fund language, the goal, the preference of not raising taxes can only be met if they raise taxes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But the numbers in this budget tell a very different story. By the numbers, which is what a budget is all about, the House budget raises taxes nearly $400 billion, and numbers do not lie.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The other option is the Senate budget, which raises taxes by about $216 billion, the second largest tax increase in American history. This will include higher taxes on middle-income earners because the Senate budget still raises marginal income tax rates across the board. But at least it attempts to protect the marriage penalty relief, child tax credit and estate tax relief.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, the other Chamber, like their Democrat counterparts in the House, also call for large spending increases. And as a consequence, their budget will continue to raid the Social Security trust funds in fiscal year 2012, something the House-passed budget and the Republican substitute did not do.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So while the Democrat budget in the Senate didn't raise as many taxes, it did raid the Social Security trust fund, and the House Republican and the House Democrat budget resolution did not.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, what we are simply trying to do is get the best of both products such that it can be had. Accordingly, our motion would simply direct the conferees to do two things: First, reject the House's $392 billion tax increase, again, the largest tax increase in American history, and keep their tax hike to the lowest possible level permitted under the rules. Second, insist on the lowest possible level of taxes between the House-passed and Senate-passed Democrat budgets. This language is included because  the motion is required to stay within the scope of the two budgets. We wish we could do more, but this is the scope we have been dealt. Third, it would direct the conferees to stop raiding Social Security for the government's operating budget. They should do this by running a unified surplus, including Social Security, of $96 billion in fiscal year 2012, which is equal to the Social Security cash surplus for that year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We know that this is possible because we proved it could be done in our own budget. Our Republican budget not only balanced the budget without raising anyone's taxes, we ran a surplus that ensured the Social Security trust funds would not be raided.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, again, today we are simply asking our Democratic colleagues to do the following: one, reject the largest tax increase in American history; and two, stop the raid of the Social Security cash surplus.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a simple choice. A "yes" vote supports these objectives. A "no" vote rejects them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And with that, Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself 4 minutes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, let me say from the outset what we said yesterday in the debate of this bill. But let me refer to third parties, independent, disinterested third parties like the Concord Coalition. They took a look at our budget, and they said unequivocally, and I'm quoting, "Thus, to be clear, the budget resolution does not call for or require a tax increase."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Center on Budget and Policy Priorities, excellent analytical work, they took a look at our budget and they said, "The House budget does not include a tax increase."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And then, finally, the Hamilton Project of the Brookings Institution, independent, disinterested said, plainly, simply, "This budget would not raise taxes."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have included in the budget resolution not one place, but twice, in different parts of the resolution, our wholehearted endorsement, our commitment, our pledge, our determination to see that these middle-income tax cuts are preserved and enacted and carried forward when they expire per their terms.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The budget resolution does not cause them to expire. They were designed to expire, written to expire when they were offered and passed. At that particular time, that was part of the provision.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>In addition, I am making clear again that our budget resolution allows all of the deductions, credits, exemptions and exclusions that are provided in the 2001 and 2003 tax cuts. All of them are provided and allowed to stay in place this year, next year, and for the next 4 years. So there is very little disagreement about us except I am wondering about the arithmetic.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Budget resolution motions to instruct are nonbinding. They are a valid part of the process. But they do present a problem. They single out specific elements of a budget resolution without looking at how one goal, such as tax reduction, interacts with another goal, such as deficit reduction. In that respect, what my colleagues on the other side of the aisle have offered is a resolution that calls for support of all of the tax cuts they laid out plus a surplus of $96 billion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Could I ask the gentleman from Wisconsin, what does this assume about the bottom line before the tax cuts? How big a surplus would you have to have in 2012 in order for there to be, after taking these tax cuts, a $96 billion remaining surplus?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400351" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, will the gentleman yield?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>I yield to the gentleman from Wisconsin.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400351" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>This assumes a $96 billion unified budget surplus after those tax cuts are extended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>How much?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400351" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>A $96 billion cash surplus unified budget after the extension of those taxes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>So what is the surplus before these tax cuts are taken?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400351" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>I don't know off the top of my head.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>It would have to be pretty substantial. Isn't the cost of these tax cuts in the first year $180 billion or more?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400351" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>The gentleman's budget resolution that passed the House had, I think, about a $150 billion cash surplus and raised all those taxes; so he had a sizable surplus.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>It's my understanding, roughly speaking, that the cost of these tax cuts, the revenue impact of these tax cuts, in the first year was about $180 billion. If you take that kind of charge against the surplus and still have a surplus left of $96 billion, then you've got about a $276 billion surplus in that year.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400351" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>If the gentleman will yield, not only did the Republican budget substitute accommodate for that, it accommodated for an extension of all of the tax cuts that expire in 2010 in addition to having a surplus equal to or greater than the unified Social Security cash surplus. So the Republican budget substitute accommodated all of these tax cuts and stopped the raid on Social Security.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Is this the CBO number?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400351" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Yes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>CBO's projection.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400351" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Yes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>And what you would then expect is a $276 billion surplus before the tax cuts?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400351" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>I can't speak to that number. I don't know that number off the top of my head.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The time of the gentleman has expired.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400351" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>At this time, Mr. Speaker, I would like to yield 2 minutes to the vice ranking member of the Budget Committee, Mr. Barrett from South Carolina.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400016" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of the Republican motion to instruct conferees on the fiscal year 2008 budget. This budget motion rests on one simple premise: to reject the largest tax increase in American history contained in the Democrats' House-passed budget.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By not addressing the Bush tax cuts, the Democratic budget resolution calls for a $393 billion tax hike, Mr. Speaker. In my home State of South Carolina, approximately 1.5 million people will see an average $2,400 increase in their tax bills. In my district alone, about 2,448 people will be forced to pay higher taxes, and estimates indicate a $182 million loss to the local economy, which translates in about 2,200 jobs being lost.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the government spends too much money as it is. I can't imagine what it would be like with an additional $400 billion of spending. We have serious challenges facing this Nation and more money is not the solution. Instead of increasing the burden on American citizens, we have an obligation to find real workable solutions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Republican motion to instruct calls for a simple up-or-down vote on whether Congress should increase taxes on working Americans by $393 billion, as the House Democrat budget does. It directs conferees to commit to two things: Number one, reject the massive tax increase in the House budget that increases marginal tax rates, reimposes the marriage penalty, reimposes the death tax, cuts the child credit in half, and raises a range of other taxes as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And, number two, stop the raid on Social Security cash surpluses. Conferees should produce a budget with a surplus sufficient to halt the raid on cash surpluses in the Social Security trust funds by fiscal year 2012.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, these challenges aren't going to go away, and delaying addressing them just makes them worse and burdens future generations. The Republican alternative offers solutions, and for this reason I urge my colleagues to support the Republican motion to instruct.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 3 minutes to the gentleman from New Jersey (Mr. Andrews).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Mr. ANDREWS asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400008" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>I thank the chairman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, it's not surprising to me why there is such disorientation from the erstwhile majority about the budget resolution that will be going to conference. It's because it contains a principle that they don't understand, which is called deficit reduction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The erstwhile majority made a living out of borrowing money, spending more, taxing less, borrowing more; spending more, taxing less, borrowing more. They turned a huge projected budget surplus into an immense budget deficit and debt, which will be paid for by the children and grandchildren of the Members of this institution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, here are the facts about the budget resolution the House passed: The fact is not one dollar of taxes is raised on anyone in the fiscal year covered by the first year of this resolution or the second year. Now, we get to a point at the end of 2009 where the tax cuts which the erstwhile majority enacted a few years ago expire. They passed a law that said that those tax cuts expire. We say let's pause at that point and decide what is in the best interest of the country. And there are  options. Perhaps the surplus will have grown to the point where we can finance all of those tax cuts and not increase the deficit. Perhaps there will be greater revenues that have been projected under our conservative revenue estimates and we will be able to afford to extend all the tax cuts. Perhaps</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The erstwhile majority practiced the principle of leap first and look later. This resolution says look before you leap. It says when we reach the point where the tax cuts expire, we will make a judgment about whether spending cuts, tax cut renewal, or some other strategy is in the best interest of the country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Not one dollar of taxes is raised in the first fiscal year covered by this budget, and nothing in this resolution necessitates the raising of any taxes on anyone. It simply says, Mr. Speaker, that Congress should do something the erstwhile majority never did: Look before you leap. Make decisions based on good economic evidence, not blind faith.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400351" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, at this time I yield myself 30 seconds.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I say to my articulate friend from New Jersey, I think what he mentioned was a real good highlight on the philosophical differences between our two parties. The question is, who is first in line, the taxpayer or the government? We believe that the taxpayer ought to be first in line by keeping more of their hard-earned money, not the government. The State of New Jersey, which is a high tax-paying State, on average under these tax increases will pay an average of $3,780 more under Democrat-passed  budget per taxpayer in the State of New Jersey.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would like to yield 2 minutes to the gentleman from Florida (Mr. Diaz-Balart).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400108" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I listened to the terms of the gentleman from New Jersey speaking about not leaping first. It's kind of a very aesthetic way to say to it. No, what he's taking about is leaping on the American taxpayer. That's what the Democratic budget does. It does leap on the American taxpayer because it does increase $392 billion on the American taxpayer. This budget does. And all Americans are going to be paying for this. Middle-income families, low-income earners,  families with children, and small businesses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And we have heard again that they don't want to raise taxes in this budget. But if that's true, Mr. Speaker, then let's instruct the conferees to extend these popular tax provisions, these tax relief provisions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, at the committee markup, Mr. Speaker, the Republicans offered several amendments to do just that, aimed at helping the hardworking American taxpayers. Not one single Democrat voted in favor of these commonsense tax cut provisions. And what were they, Mr. Speaker? Because they always like to say, oh, it's tax cuts for the rich. No. Let's talk about what they are, what they voted against in committee, without one dissenting vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>They voted against extending the $1,000 per child tax credit. Not only the wealthy have kids in this country, Mr. Speaker. They voted against extending the marriage penalty tax relief. Not only the wealthy get married, at least not in the State of Florida that I represent. They voted against elimination of the death tax. That's right. They want dead people to pay more taxes. And they voted against extending the State and local tax deduction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>How does this affect regular middle-class Americans? Mr. Speaker, a middle-income family of four earning $60,000 will look at over a 60 percent tax increase by the year 2011. One hundred and fifteen million taxpayers will see their taxes increase an average of $1,700 by 2011. In Florida that I am privileged to represent, over 6.7 million taxpayers will see their taxes increase increased by over $3,000.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 4 minutes to the gentleman from Oregon (Mr. Blumenauer).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400033" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I appreciate the gentleman's courtesy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is an interesting debate that is going on here today because in terms of the motion to instruct, there really isn't that great a difference of opinion. We are, in fact, going to be able to meet the objectives. We are working hard in our budget to make sure that we deal meaningfully with tax relief for those who need it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The difference between the Republicans and the Democrats is that they are not willing to make any distinction. For them it is Paris Hilton who is first in line. We have made it clear that we are going to work to make sure that  real priorities for American families are adopted. We have proven that in terms of what we have stood for in the past as well as what we are working for in the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Democrats have repeatedly voted for a lowered tax bracket on lower-income people, the expansion of the earned income tax credit, marriage penalty relief, increase in the child tax credit, acceleration of the expansion of the 10-percent bracket, increased expensing for small businesses. These were things that people here on the floor who are on our side of the aisle offered up as a responsible alternative when our friends on the other side were engaged in a rather extensive and unfocused effort  to try to provide tax benefits for those who need them the least while ignoring the needs of those who need it the most.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>They have given some modest bones to a few in America. Those that merit our support will, in fact, be continued. And, more important, we are going to deal with what is the largest tax increase in American history, which the Bush administration and my Republican friends on the other side of the aisle have set the stage for, and that is the tsunami of the alternative minimum tax. That is going to cost $1 trillion over the next 10 years, and we have made it clear that that is our number one priority  to solve, as in the House Committee on Ways and Means we working on this.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We don't have to accede to every single detail for Paris Hilton in order to make sure that we deal with the needs of working Americans and the tax tsunami of the alternative minimum tax, which has been ignored session after session after session by the Republicans when they were in charge.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I find no small amount of irony to hear my good friend from Wisconsin talking about how he has proven it is possible to have a unified budget surplus when for 12 consecutive years of ironclad Republican control they wrote all the fiscal rules, wrote the budgets, wrote the tax policy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>I invite anybody to look at what the now minority proved that they could do. It's a pretty sorry record of fiscal irresponsibility.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, my point is simply that the budget resolution that we brought forward is a reasonable, meaningful approach to deal with these fiscal problems.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Independent observers agree that there is no tax increase this year or the next. And we are on a path allowed for in our budget resolution and the work we are doing in the Ways and Means Committee right now to make sure that we solve the tax tsunami of the alternative minimum tax.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I look forward to our getting past this type of discussion here, as my friends on the other side of the aisle seek to substitute rhetoric for their sorry record of non-accomplishment, and look forward to moving forward.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400351" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, at this time I would like to yield 3 minutes to a distinguished member of the Budget Committee, Mr. Hensarling from Texas.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400175" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have listened very carefully to the previous speaker talk about rhetoric. And indeed, the rhetoric I hear from the other side of the aisle is pure Orwellian; up is down, black is white, victory is defeat and the largest tax increase in American history is somehow actually tax relief.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>You cannot state good intentions and then instead act with cruel actions. The numbers of this budget lead to the largest single tax increase in American history. And Mr. Speaker, let me quote from the Washington Post again, not exactly a bastion of conservative thought, I will quote from their March 29th edition, "And while House Democrats say they want to preserve key parts of Bush's signature tax cuts, they project a surplus in 2012 only by assuming that all these cuts expire on schedule in  2010." And then they somehow say that we contrive temporary tax relief. Well, as the chairman knows, he has had plenty of opportunities to make this tax relief permanent, but he and everyone else on that side of the aisle have declined that opportunity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And again, it's a matter of priorities. Democrat friends decide to prioritize the Federal budget over the family budget. But let's look at how their single largest tax increase in American history is going to impact family budgets. Let's hear from Joan from Mesquite, who wrote, "An additional $2,200 raise in taxes for my husband and me would mean that we would not be able to meet our budget obligations. I drive an 11-year-old car. And sometimes it breaks. And it costs me more to fix than what  it's worth. I was hoping to buy a newer car, but if taxes go up, I won't be able to do that."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let's hear from Robert of Garland. "I'm unemployed on Social Security and my wife works. At this point, between taxes and utilities, we're at the breaking point of being able to keep our home. If we have an increase of over $2,000 per year, it may well mean the straw that broke the camel's back; we would lose our home." That's how the single largest tax increase in American history is affecting that family.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let's see how it affects Linda in Rowlett. "It would mean the difference of whether my daughter or husband would be able to purchase a car or not. For my husband and I, it helps us continue with his radiation treatments for his prostate cancer and allows us to continue providing in-home assistance for my elderly parents. Please allow us to retain this money for our needs. Please don't let government take additional tax dollars from us."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That's the cruel actions. It's not the Orwellian rhetoric that we want to somehow preserve the tax relief. They are imposing the single largest tax increase in American history, a cruel hoax on American families as they try to meet their education budgets and their transportation budgets.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400351" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, may I inquire how much time is remaining on either side.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from Wisconsin has 17 1/2  minutes, and the gentleman from South Carolina has 19 minutes remaining.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>I yield 3 minutes to the gentleman from Virginia (Mr. Scott).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400364" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think it's important to put up a chart so we will know who's saying what about fiscal responsibility, because this chart shows what happened in the nineties when, with President Clinton's veto vetoing Republican bills after the Democrats set the budget off in the right direction, we were able to create a surplus that when this administration came in in 2001, we had a projected $5.5 trillion surplus. As a result of Republican initiatives, that surplus looks like it's going to come in, a 10-year  surplus, at about a $3 trillion deficit, a swing of $8.5 trillion. And to put that in perspective, we've spent about $500 billion in Iraq; $8.5 trillion deterioration of the budget, $500 billion in Iraq, that is $0.5 trillion; $8.5 trillion deterioration, $0.5 trillion attributable to the war. And the Democratic budget, again, responsibly digs us out of this mess.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The important thing to note is, we talk about 9/11. We were broke. We spent the surplus, other than Social Security and Medicare, before 9/11. So you can't blame 9/11 for the fiscal decline that has happened here.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This budget is responsible. It shows how we can dig ourselves out. Unfortunately, we have, first of all, no leadership from the White House. Even the Republican budget pretty much ignores the President's budget. The President's budget had us in a ditch, never coming into surplus. At least the Republican budget has us coming out of the deficit and into surplus in 2012, but it does it in such a way that is not responsible and not predictable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Republicans' budget assumes that we're going to whack about $250 billion out of Medicare and Medicaid, about $250 billion cut out of health care. This is at a time when doctors are telling us now that they can't absorb the cuts. We are having situations now when States are not paying dentists enough for dentists to even take Medicaid. $250 billion cut. It's not going to happen. We're not going to go into surplus under the Republican budget.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The main factor that we have to look at is, who's talking? The Democrats dug us out of the ditch; Republicans put us back in the ditch; and the Democrats are digging us out again with a responsible budget. The Republicans have a budget that is so draconian on health care that 40 Republicans even voted against the Republican budget.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And so we have a responsible plan. Let's stick with the responsible plan, dig us out of the mess again, and have fiscal responsibility.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400351" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>At this time, Mr. Speaker, I would like to yield 2 minutes to the distinguished gentleman from New Jersey (Mr. Garrett).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400145" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, despite the hopes of the other side of the aisle, the constituents in my district are pretty smart people. When they were paying a little over $2 a gallon for gasoline a year or so ago and now they're paying upwards of $3 per gallon, they know that's an increase out of their pocket. Likewise, when it comes to taxes, when they see that they are paying so much for their taxes now on the Federal level now, and after this package goes through on the other side  of the aisle, they will be paying upwards to $3,000 or more. They know, they're smart enough to realize that's a tax increase as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My colleagues on the other side of the aisle have to look to outside nonpartisan groups they call them, really nonpartisan liberal think tanks I think is the best term, for those think tanks to say that these are not tax increases when they really are. When your taxes go up from this year to the next year to the next year, that is a tax increase.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>They talk about the budget planning process and say, don't worry, it only comes at the end of the budget. Well, you know, regular families plan during the entire budget. If you have a weekly budget for your food allotment, you want to make sure you have food at the end of the week. If you're doing a monthly budget, you plan the entire month. If you have a yearly budget or a 5-year budget as this is, you do it in the entire 5 years. And under the Democrats' budget, your taxes during the course  of that time will go up. In New Jersey, you're looking at a $3,000 or more tax increase.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When it comes to Social Security, my constituents are also very smart and loud when they say, "Keep your hands off of my Social Security." The Republican plan does that. The Republican plan stops the raid on Social Security, and it does so without a tax increase.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, there is some rumor I am hearing by some Democrats on the other side of the aisle that they may support our motion to recommit. But mind you, mark my words, if they support this motion to recommit, it will be as disingenuous as their support and their comments and other things they have done in the past this year. When they said that they were going to curtail spending, what did they actually do? They increased spending by over 11 percent in this budget. When they said they weren't going  to raise your taxes, what did they do? They increased your taxes by $392 billion. And when they said that they were going to solve the AMT problem, what did they do? They did not solve it at all.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Support this motion to recommit.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself 5 minutes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, in response to the last speaker, if we support this resolution, it's because we originally provided in our budget resolution, in two different aspects of our budget resolution, our full, wholehearted support for these middle-income tax cuts. We still have, I will have to confess, concern about your arithmetic here, but we supported it in the budget resolution we filed, which passed the House. We endorsed and pledged that we would seek to the extension of the 10 percent individual  tax bracket, the child tax credit, research and experimentation tax credit, all of these things. Read the resolution. They're there. We were there before you were, saying that, over the next 3 or 4 years, we need to see that when December 31, 2010, comes along, these tax cuts will survive and be preserved. We are committed to that, black and white print, budget resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400145" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, will the gentleman yield?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>I will yield for one question.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400145" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Because you referred to my comments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When you said that you planned this in the budget, are your comments referring to reserve accounts?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>No. I'm talking about statements in our budget resolution which state emphatically and clearly, "It is the policy of this budget resolution to preserve, defend and protect the middle-income tax cuts adopted in 2001 and 2003, which will expire in 2010."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, we do believe, and this also is in our budget resolution, we believe in the PAYGO principle. We believe that the Tax Code is full of deductions and credits and exemptions and exclusions, and you can go through a closet cleaning in the Code and come up with enough offsets to provide for the extension of many of these tax cuts, maybe not all but many, without any adverse impact on the bottom line budget deficit.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400145" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>If the gentleman will yield.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>I will yield.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400145" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>I understand what you're saying, the first part, that those are the heart-felt policy statements of your budget. But are you referring then to the other side of the equation, to the reserve accounts that are spoken of in the budget as far as, I will use the term, for paying for those?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>There was a provision that allowed for reserve accounts so that we could provide for these tax cuts. But basically we took the position that this decision does not have to be made now, and indeed it can be better made closer in time to December 31, when we see what is the bottom line then. How much debt have we accumulated? What is the total deficit? What is the forecast for the future? At that point in time, we can consider the tax cuts, extension of them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By my understanding, if you extend all of the 2001 and 2003 tax cuts that expire on December 31, the cost over 10 years is about $2 trillion. That's a big decision. We think you should make it deliberately and closer in point of time to when these tax cuts actually expire.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me say also that not only did we put these tax cuts and state our support for them in the budget resolution, but in addition, when the tax cuts were passed in 2001, we either had substitutes or occasionally voted for independent free-standing provisions like the marriage penalty relief. Democrats were there when that passed the House. I voted for it the first time it came up and voted for it again repeatedly. In our substitutes, we had a 12 percent bracket and then a 10 percent bracket. We  had a child tax credit, which we continually increase, and we had the R&amp;E tax credit extension. We had expensing for small businesses. Many, if not all, of the things you are talking about here we voted for, maybe not on your bills but on our bills because these are tax policies favoring middle-income Americans for whom we think tax relief is well in order.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Secondly, we have a problem still with the arithmetic that you've got here.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>According to my information, looking at CBO's most recent report, the Social Security surplus for 2012 is $255 billion. If you want to stay out of Social Security, you have got to have a surplus of at least $255 billion, a unified surplus of at least $255 billion, am I correct?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400351" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, if the gentleman will yield, the $96 billion unified surplus reflects the cash surplus, meaning the amount of overpayments on FICA taxes, payroll taxes for Social Security, that gets spent on other government programs that ought to go to Social Security. The interest on top of that is the number that the gentleman from South Carolina is talking about. That reflects past borrowing, past raiding of the Social Security surplus. We would like to fix that, too.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We think that is a good start. Let's say from now on if you pay FICA taxes to Social Security, let's not spend it on all these other government programs. So the cash surplus that occurs in 2012, that is what we are talking about with that $96 billion, not the interest on top that reflects all of the past borrowing and raiding of the Social Security trust fund.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, reclaiming my time, I understand that. But the Social Security surplus is $255 billion.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400351" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>That is the cash surplus, plus interest. We are talking about the cash surplus.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on the other hand, if you look at the surplus you are claiming, $96 billion, and also provide for these tax cuts, my information is that these tax cuts have a revenue impact of at least $180 billion.  That would mean in the year 2012 there has to be a bottom line surplus of $276 billion before the tax cuts are taken.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400351" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, that is not all in the year 2012, I believe. There is a problem with the numbers here.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>$180 billion I believe is 1 year.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400351" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>We seem to have a difference of opinion. But let me make one point: We showed you how to do it.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>But you haven't shown us the arithmetic. We are not sure your arithmetic is correct.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400351" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>We showed you with our budget substitute, we do not raise taxes on the American economy and family, and we can also stop raiding the cash surplus of Social Security. And the reason I can tell you we showed you is that is exactly what the Republican budget resolution substitute did, as scored by CBO.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400351" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself 1 1/2  minutes to make a couple of comments before I yield to the gentleman from Texas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I think I made the point on the Social Security cash surplus. We are talking about how much overpayments people pay in their payroll taxes in any given year. We don't want to keep spending that on other government programs. That is point number one.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Point number two: The very fact that the gentleman from South Carolina is suggesting that they are going to accept this motion to instruct, that they are going to accept this, means they agree there are tax increases in this budget.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>They are saying right now, I just heard him say it, we don't want to raise taxes on the middle-class. We don't want to get rid of the child tax credit. We don't want to bring back the marriage penalty. We don't want to do away with the 10 percent bracket. So we will accept this motion to instruct. I.e., the other tax increases in this budget are just that, tax increases. Death tax, the marginal income tax rates across-the-board, capital gains, dividends.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me just make the point more clearly, by not quoting a think tank that may be left of center, right of center, whatever of center. Let me quote the Washington Post, clearly no paragon of right-wing thinking.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Washington Post, right after the Democrat budget came out: "And while House Democrats say they want to preserve key parts of Bush's signature tax cuts, they project a surplus in 2012 only by assuming that all of these tax cuts expire on schedule in 2010."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>They further go on to say about the Democratic budget plan, "The budget plan expresses support for certain cuts, including the extended child tax credit, elimination of the marriage penalty, and the 10 percent bracket, that would require another reserve fund to be filled with hundreds of billions of dollars in tax increases to cover the cost."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 2 minutes to the distinguished member of the House Budget Committee, the gentleman from Texas (Mr. Conaway).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400655" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>I thank the ranking member.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I think to the other Members in the House listening to this debate this sounds like a school yard kind of struggle: Yes, you are; no, you're not; yes, you are; no, you're not. We are back and forth. We are both using the same set of facts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But the truth of the matter is, in 2011 and 2012, however it happens, under the current code the revenues of the government will go up $400 billion. The rhetoric on the other side of the aisle that this does not represent a tax increase would have a lot greater credibility with me and those on our side of the aisle if in fact our colleagues on the Budget Committee hadn't spent that $400 billion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The chairman mentioned earlier about waiting until December 31, 2011, to fix these things. The problem with that is that at the end of 2010, maybe that is the date he was referencing, the estate tax goes from a zero tax rate to a 55 percent tax rate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I spent a career helping folks comply with a very complex code, and estate planning requires generally a lot longer period of time to react and put plans in place than from one year to the next. So, to keep estates out there hung up with the idea that the tax is going to come back fully at 55 percent, I think is unfair.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The other thing that has to be said is that all of the tax increases go in fully. So the 33 percent bracket goes to a 39.6 percent bracket. If in fact the Democrats do want to protect the 10 percent bracket from going to 15 percent, as they have said, they are going to have to raise taxes on the top brackets. They are going to have to raise taxes in other places in order to stay within this bill's definition of PAYGO.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I am going to speak in favor of the motion to instruct, but just for full and fair disclosure, I voted twice, since we did vote on this bill twice, against the Democrats' budget.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400351" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself 2 minutes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One additional point I wanted to make, Mr. Speaker, is the point about PAYGO that the gentleman from South Carolina mentioned. As it is well known, we have a problem with their version of PAYGO. When PAYGO is designed to raise taxes, we don't like it. When PAYGO is designed to control spending, we like it. That is why we are for PAYGO on spending, not on raising taxes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But if this amendment is accepted, if this motion to instruct is accepted, let's just be very clear, it does violate their PAYGO. Because the Baucus amendment, which is what we are referring to, which is the amendment that passed in the Senate, uses their surpluses, quote-unquote, to pay for these tax cuts. PAYGO says if you are going to reduce taxes, you have to offset them with either a tax increase or a spending cut, not with surpluses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So this amendment, we believe if you are going to have a surplus, it should either go back to the Social Security trust fund and pay down debt, or reduce taxes. That is what we are proposing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But just so we are very clear with ourselves here, this Baucus amendment, this acceptance of this policy of not raising all of these taxes, just some of them, which is the best choice we have between the two options as the minority, does violate their own PAYGO rule by dedicating their surpluses towards this tax relief, rather than having offsets, either coming from spending cuts or tax increases.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 3 minutes to the gentleman from Virginia (Mr. Scott).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400364" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, PAYGO is a very simple concept. If you are going to increase spending, you pay for it. If you are going to cut taxes, you pay for it. You don't go into the ditch. If you have a tax cut, you have to pay for it either with increases of other taxes or spending cuts to pay for it. If you have spending increases, you have to pay for it with cutting spending somewhere else or increasing taxes to pay for it. It is a very simple concept.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400351" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, will the gentleman yield?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400364" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>I yield to the gentleman from Wisconsin.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400351" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>If you are going to reduce taxes, you have to pay for it by either raising taxes or cutting spending. That is what your PAYGO is, correct?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400364" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>That is correct.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400351" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Well, you are violating it if you accept this amendment then.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400364" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>That is the concept, and that is how we got out of the ditch that we got into. If you build up a surplus, then you have something to spend. That is consistent with PAYGO.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But the point is that we got out of the ditch with fiscal responsibility, and as soon as 2001 came along, you let PAYGO expire, passed tax cuts that we couldn't afford and put us right back into the ditch. The fact is that the only way the Republican budget makes any sense is if you have $250 billion in cuts, mostly in Medicare and Medicaid, at a time when we can't even afford the cuts that are already in effect.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To put that $250 billion in context, there are plans out there, including the All Healthy Children Act, which can cover all children with healthcare for $15 billion a year. You are talking about cutting healthcare $250 billion. Obviously, you are not going to do it and so obviously the budget is not realistic.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But what are your priorities? Tax cuts that we can't afford at a time when we need to cover children? We can't even afford the Medicaid program we have got now. In most States, you can't find a dentist because the reimbursement rates aren't high enough, and here we are cutting Medicare and Medicaid $250 billion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would hope that we would adopt the Democratic budget and reject the motion to recommit, because it requires us to assume $250 billion in cuts that we are not going to make. We have a responsible budget. It digs us out of the ditch that the Republicans put us in starting in 2001.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would hope again we would reject the motion and adopt the Democratic budget as we passed it in the House.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400351" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 2 minutes to the gentleman from Texas (Mr. Hensarling).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400175" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I listened very carefully to my friend from Virginia. The only thing that is being cut here is the family budget, and it is being cut by the Democrats. If you look at the numbers of the Republican budget, government grows each and every year. Now, it doesn't grow as fast as the Democrat budget. And the way the Democrat budget grows is by imposing the single largest tax increase in American history on hard-working Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An average in my district, the Fifth Congressional District of Texas, an average of $2,700 a year, Mr. Speaker, is going to be imposed on those hard-working people as they try to send their children to college, as they struggle to try to meet the healthcare payments for elderly parents, as they try to make payments on their healthcare premiums, as they try to put together that capital to launch their American dream and to buy their first home.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The cutting that is going on here is the cutting out of the heart of the family budget by the Democrat budget, imposing the single largest tax increase in American history. And as bad as that tax increase is, $392 billion over 5 years, it is a pittance compared to the taxes that they are going to impose on the next generation, because, Mr. Speaker, their budget is silent, absolutely silent, on the number one fiscal challenge facing America, out-of-control entitlement spending.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Republicans are being responsible in trying to ensure that the next generation doesn't see a doubling of their taxes, which we all know will happen.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So this is the kick-the-can-down-the-road budget of the Democrats, when they know that our children and grandchildren will see their taxes doubled from roughly 20 percent of the economy to 40 percent. Now, how many of our children and grandchildren will ever be able to own a home, start a business or send their children to college?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is the idea of the Democrats' fiscal responsibility, doubling taxes on the American people? I want no part of it.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, Mr. Speaker, I yield 30 seconds to the gentleman from Virginia (Mr. Scott).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400364" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I think it is important to note that when you talk about average tax cuts, this is an average $250 a family tax cut, average $250 for a family of four. But you notice who gets it? This is involving personal exemptions and standard deductions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If you make a $1 million, $17,000; $650 if you make $200,000 to $1 million; $11 if you make $100,000 to $200,000; if you make less than $100,000, you get on average of zero.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is what you call an average $250 a family tax cut.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself 2 minutes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have here a copy of the President's budgetary proposals for fiscal year 2008 published by the Congressional Budget Office. If you turn to page 6, you will see that the cost of the tax cuts, extending the tax cuts, which the motion proposes, the cost or the revenue impact of that in the year 2012 is $231 billion. That is what CBO says.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If you now add $96 billion to that, the surplus that year must be $327 billion. The surplus, $327 billion. Last year the deficit was $248 billion. If we move to a surplus of $327 billion in the year 2012, that requires a movement in the right direction of $575 billion which is hard to believe.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400351" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, will the gentleman yield?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>I yield to the gentleman from Wisconsin.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400351" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>I wish we were talking about all of the tax cuts. Unfortunately, what we have in the Baucus amendment, that is only $132 billion in 2012 because the Baucus amendment only extends some of the tax cuts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The point we are making is, if we want to stop raising taxes and raiding Social Security, we are going to have to control spending. That is what we propose to do; and sadly, that is not what the majority budget does.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>The point, I am sure, is you are supportive of all of the 2001 and 2003 tax cuts. You are limited by procedural rules to only dealing with that which is in the scope of the two resolutions. But, in fact, I am sure you are supportive of that. If that is true, you have to acknowledge that the number is $231 billion. That is the revenue impact of extending all of the tax cuts. If you add 96, which is the surplus you project, you get a big, big number.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400351" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 3 minutes to the gentleman from California (Mr. Campbell), a member of the House Budget Committee.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412011" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have been listening to all of this debate, and I guess what I don't really understand is, why? I mean, why the Democrats here on the other side of the aisle want to oppose this motion to instruct.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I mean, do you want to raid the Social Security surplus? Do you like telling people that they are paying money for their own Social Security and retirement and then taking it and using it for other things? Do you like that? Do you want to do that? I mean, do you want to enact the biggest tax increase in American history? Do you want really to tax people more on capital gains and dividends when over 50 percent of Americans now own some sort of stock? Do you want to go back to penalizing married  couples and having them pay more taxes after they get married than two people would when they were single? Do you really want to reduce the child care tax credit? Do you want to stifle economic growth?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I know some of you say you don't think that these tax cuts caused this economic growth. Let's assume they didn't cause it all. It can't be a coincidence that since the tax reductions went into place, we have had enormous economic growth, enormous job growth and enormous revenue growth to the Federal Government.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Do you really want to do all that? Do you really want to pass the largest tax increase in American history; and for what? So you can raise spending a lot over the next 5 years because if you just didn't increase spending, you could do all of this. You could allow Americans to keep their own money.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But no, you want to take their money from them and spend it on your priorities. Now I guess that is what you want to do. I still don't understand it. I don't understand why the government having money is so much more a priority, but I guess it is because you look at all money as the government's, and you allow people to keep some. We look at money as belonging to the people who earned it, and we allow the government to take that which is necessary.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But understand that if all you did was keep spending level or increase it a little bit over the next 5 years, then you wouldn't have to raise taxes and then you wouldn't have to raid the Social Security surplus. But apparently that is what you want to do.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself 3 minutes. Mr. Speaker, this goes back to something that our President called fuzzy math. And if I seem hung up on the topic of math, it is because arithmetic is important when you are putting together a budget.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What they are telling us is they can run a $96 billion surplus in the year 2012 even though they are taking tax cuts that will take $231 billion in revenues out of the Federal Treasury. It is a stretch, to say the least. That involves assuming that we will have a surplus in the year 2012 of $327 billion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>How far from that are we today? Last year we had a deficit of $248 billion. If  we are to move to a surplus of $327 billion by the year 2012, there has to be a movement in the right direction, a positive movement of $575 billion. Let's hope it happens, but I wouldn't bet the farm on it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>They then say and just said we are raiding Social Security. How absurd can you get? Here it is right here. The Social Security surplus is $255 billion. They do not even claim more than $96 billion on the surplus. If they left the tax cut out, they would indeed have enough bottom line, 96 plus 231, to cover the surplus, but they haven't done that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Here on the bottom line, the back of an envelope, is a simple chart that I bring down to the well with me every time I talk because we need to be reminded. When President Bush came to office, the national debt was $5.7 trillion. Six years later, the national debt is $8.8 trillion, an increase of $3.1 trillion over the last 6 years. That is a 60 percent increase in the debt of the United States. We have not seen anything like it since the Second World War.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Are we worried about fuzzy math? You better believe we are because this is the consequence of it. What the Republican budget resolution would have done had it been adopted is it would have extended again and again the policy of borrow and spend, leaving the tab to our children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Here is what the tab looked like, in addition to the $8.8 trillion: You can cut taxes today, but what you leave in the wake of what you have done is a debt tax, the one tax that has to be paid because it is the amount of money we have to levy and raise every year to pay interest on our national debt, which is obligatory. It cannot be avoided. It has to be paid.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Here is the difference between interest on the national debt, which is well over $200 billion, headed to $300 billion within the foreseeable future, and look what it does to other priorities, things that are pressing and important like veterans health care, homeland security, and education. All of those things are dwarfed by the increase in interest payments on the debt.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a debt tax we have to pay today. All Americans have to pay it. Our children will have to pay it because of our irresponsible fiscal policy. This is why we need to clear up this fuzzy math and put the country back on a firm path to fiscal responsibility.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400351" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 2 minutes to the gentleman from Nebraska (Mr. Smith).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412217" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today with great concern for our economy. I rise because we hear about the debt and certainly my concern is that if we are not careful, we will make the debt even worse than it is now because an economy can turn south with overtaxation. Right now we are headed to tax increases that concern me a great deal.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In Nebraska, the average tax increase per taxpayer is almost $2,400 a year as proposed. More than that though, I am concerned about small businesses, farmers and ranchers who face tax increases whether it is the estate tax or other taxes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When I have a small business person come up to me and say, we need to do something about the estate tax, the death tax because it will devastate their business, that gets my attention.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My concerns are that we have available capital in our economy because, with available capital, we see good things happening, whether it is investing in the stock market or whether it is expanding a small business or whether it is putting money away for a child or grandchild heading to college. The fact is, available capital does great things, and that is why I rise with extreme concern about our budget because the budget calls for a tax increase, and that is what concerns me so much because tax  increases are bad for economic growth. Tax increases lead to a downturn in the economy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I not only believe we can do better than this proposed budget, but we must do better.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>For the clarification of Members, let me give you my take on what is before us right now. This motion to instruct conferees calls for us to recede, back off the revenue levels in the House amendment and insist on, listen to this, policy statement in section 401 of the House amendment. That is our budget resolution, the Democratic budget resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is the place in our resolution where one time we have insisted, pledged our support for the extension of these middle-income tax cuts passed in 2001 and 2003. That is paragraph A. It is hard for us to disagree with the enforcement of the language that we put in the budget resolution in the first place.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Secondly, paragraph B, insist on the lowest possible levels of revenue within the scope of the conference.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is hard to tell what that level might be, whether or not it is consistent with the one above, but we certainly will give some consideration to that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And finally, set forth a unified surplus of at least $96 billion in fiscal year 2012. I hope we can do it, but you have heard me go through the arithmetic out here, and I think it is a reach to even imply that these three variables can be integrated and solved in this one multi varied equation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If you can do it, fine. If you can come out of all this still having these tax cuts and still having a $96 billion surplus, great. But I have to tell you, I think it is fuzzy math.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But we are wholeheartedly in support of the middle-income tax cuts that are enumerated here. Indeed, they have been lifted straight out of the Democratic budget resolution, and that is why we are supportive of them.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400351" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, let me concur that the resolution does say what the chairman says it does. The reason it points to the words in the House budget resolution, which say that the policy of the House is to keep these tax cuts, but we refer to the deeds of the Senate is because the House didn't pay for those tax cuts, didn't extend those tax cuts. The Senate extended those tax cuts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The House used the words that said, we hope, we wish, we would like to extend these tax cuts, but they didn't do that. They raised the taxes. It is the Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The mere fact that the Senate passed the Baucus amendment in the first place is a repudiation of the claim by the House that they are actually not raising taxes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senate looked at the House budget resolution and said, you know what, this thing is the largest tax increase in American history. We don't want to raise taxes on middle-income earners, child tax credit, marriage penalty, 10 percent bracket; and therefore, they passed the Baucus amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What we are saying is we wish we could extend all of the tax cuts. Since the scope is limited, we are saying, let's stick with the Senate and actually put numbers where the words are in the House by actually lowering the revenue number.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, the chairman is right. He is saying it is a reach to reach these surpluses. It is too tough to do it to reach these surpluses if you accept his premise. And the premise of the chairman's budget is do nothing to control spending.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, we don't have a revenue problem in Washington. Just the last 7 months alone we had 11 percent revenue growth. That is 3 straight years of double-digit revenue growth at these lower tax rates. We have plenty of money coming in from taxpayers. The problem is we are spending it too fast. That is the problem in Washington, not a revenue problem, a spending problem.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If you accept the premise of the chairman, the esteemed gentleman from South Carolina (Mr. Spratt), that there is no spending problem in Washington, which I don't accept, then he is correct, you can't balance the budget. You can't stopped the raid on Social Security and you can't extend tax relief.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>We disagree. How tough is it to do it? Let me tell you what our budget accomplished, the Republican substitute. We simply said in order to stop the raid of the Social Security surplus and make all these tax cuts permanent, spend $14.977 trillion over the next 7 years instead of the current projection, $15.286 trillion. That is what we are saying. We are saying instead of spending over the next 5 years $15.286 trillion, spend $14.977 trillion. Instead of growing mandatory spending by 5.2 percent,  grow it at 4.3 percent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Is this Draconian, is this crazy, is this hard core? No. It's what families do around a kitchen table every day.  We are simply saying put taxpayers first. Don't make people wait for 3 years to see if they're going to have their per-child tax credit, if they're going to have the marriage penalty, if the estate taxes are going to be higher, lower or somewhere in between. Tell them now. Let's tell taxpayers, first you get to keep your money; then we're  going to tighten our belt here in Washington by controlling spending.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the taxpayers deserve this respect. They don't deserve to be jerked around. We should control spending, and by golly, we need to prepare for the retirement of these baby boomers. We need to reform these entitlement programs so we can extend their solvency, extend their reliability, and that is the biggest shame of all.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Not only does this budget have the largest tax increase in American history; it proposes that we do nothing for the next 5 years to control and reform entitlements to do anything to control spending. That's a shame. That's why we should pass this motion to instruct.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> All time has expired.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400351" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX, further proceedings on this question are postponed.</chair>
</record>
