<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1181664006" ordinal="42" title="CHILD LABOR PROTECTION ACT OF 2007">
  <speaking speaker="412204" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="2637">H.R. 2637</bill>) to amend the Fair Labor Standards Act, with respect to civil penalties for child labor violations.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Hare) and the gentleman from Tennessee (Mr. David Davis) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412204" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I request 5 legislative days during which Members may insert materials relevant to <bill type="h" number="2637">H.R. 2637</bill> into the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Illinois?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412204" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Mr. HARE asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412204" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of <bill type="h" number="2637">H.R. 2637</bill>, the Child Labor Protection Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bipartisan legislation is designed to address the most serious child labor violations, deter repeat occurrences, and strengthen the enforcement of laws to protect our Nation's most vulnerable workers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill would increase the maximum penalty for child labor violations that lead to the death or serious injury of a minor from the current cap of $11,000 to $50,000 per violation. The bill would also permit the penalty to be doubled to $100,000 if it is determined that the violation was repeated or willful.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Additionally, the legislation amends the Fair Labor Standards Act to reflect the increases in penalties for child labor violations and for minimum wage and overtime violations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The current language in the FLSA provides limits of $10,000 for child labor violations, $1,000 for minimum wage and overtime violations. These penalties were increased to $11,000 and $1,100, respectively, by the Federal Civil Penalties Inflation Act of 1990, as amended by the Debt Collection Improvement Act of 1996. The legislation before us today would simply conform the language of the FLSA to reflect these changes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The increase in maximum penalties for violation of child labor laws is an important first step in our efforts to protect the health and safety of the estimated 3.2 million workers under the age of 18. The National Institute For Occupational Safety and Health Administration estimates that every year 230,000 youth under the age of 18 sustain workplace injuries, and between 60 and 70 die from occupational accidents.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>This translates into a youth worker injury every 2 days and a fatality every 5 days.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Current penalties do not communicate an adequate level of governmental concern for the health and safety of the working young and do not provide sufficient motivation for employers to ensure a safe and legal workplace for youth.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Given the pervasiveness of youth employment and injuries and the fact that the current maximum penalties are too low to demand compliance with child labor laws, this legislation represents an important improvement in our laws that will help provide a safer occupational environment for young workers</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the Child Protection Act of 2007 was proposed by the administration and is supported by Education and Labor Committee Chairman Miller and Ranking Republican MCKEON, as well as Chairwoman Woolsey and Ranking Republican JOE  WILSON of the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections. This bill represents an important first step in improving working conditions for our Nation's youth, and I urge all Members to support  the legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412235" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="2637">H.R. 2637</bill>, the Child Labor Protection Act of 2007, and I encourage my colleagues to do the same. I appreciate the work of Chairman Miller and Chairwoman WOOLSEY, as well as the gentleman from California (Mr. McKeon) and the gentleman from South Carolina (Mr. Wilson) in crafting this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is no one more vulnerable in our workforce than its youngest members. While the employment of young workers is essential to instilling in them the work ethic and the value of a dollar, their collective safety must be the highest priority of our Nation's employers and, indeed, the Nation as a whole.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With this in mind, the measure before us would amend the Fair Labor Standards Act by increasing to $50,000 the civil penalty for any type of child labor violation that causes a death or serious injury of an employee under the age of 18. The current maximum civil penalty is $11,000, and it is low by any reasonable estimation. So this update is both prudent and necessary.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Moreover, the legislation would allow the $50,000 penalty to be doubled up to a maximum of $100,000 for the willful and repeat violations that cause the death or serious injury of any child employed in violation of the Federal child labor standards. Once again, such an increase is both prudent and necessary.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The measure before us is essential for the continuation of the Department of Labor's ongoing focus on workplace safety for youth, and I commend President Bush for his work in this issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Earlier this year, the Department submitted draft legislation similar to <bill type="h" number="2637">H.R. 2637</bill>, and before that, the Department proposed new labor standards rules to cover nonagricultural occupations for employment of 14- and 15-year-olds, as well as occupations that place the well-being of employees under 18 years of age at risk.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, we are making undeniable, bipartisan progress on updating our child labor laws. As the Bush administration continues its work, the Child Labor Protection Act would provide it with additional tools to address serious child labor violations, decrease repeat occurrences and strengthen the overall enforcement of critical child labor laws.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, I thank my colleagues for their work on this measure and urge passage of this bill in the House.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>MR. HARE. Mr. Speaker at this time I am honored to yield such time as she may consume to the gentlewoman from California (Ms. Woolsey), the sponsor of this very important piece of legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400436" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I thank the gentleman from Illinois and thank our ranking member for making this possible this morning.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a member of the Committee on Education and Labor and as Chair of the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections, I truly am proud to have brought <bill type="h" number="2637">H.R. 2637</bill> to the floor today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Child Labor Protection Act of 2007 is a narrowly drafted, bipartisan bill that increases penalties substantially for violations of child labor protection provisions that actually cause death or serious injury. Although this legislation does not make the imposition of penalties mandatory, it leaves the decision of whether or not to assess penalties up to the Secretary of Labor, and it provides the Department with an additional enforcement tool to address the most serious labor violations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is much more that must be done, Mr. Speaker, to strengthen our child labor laws, but this bill is a small first step. It is a beginning.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412235" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412204" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Hare) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="2637">H.R. 2637</bill>.</chair>
</record>
