<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1185768000" ordinal="34" title="MASTER SERGEANT SEAN MICHAEL THOMAS POST OFFICE">
  <narrative>MASTER SERGEANT SEAN MICHAEL THOMAS POST OFFICE -- (House of Representatives - July 30, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H8838]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform be discharged from further consideration of the bill (<bill type="h" number="2765">H.R. 2765</bill>) to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 44 North Main Street in Hughesville, Pennsylvania, as the "Master Sergeant Sean Michael Thomas Post Office," and ask for its immediate consideration in the House.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Illinois?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the bill, as follows</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="2765">H.R. 2765</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. MASTER SERGEANT SEAN MICHAEL THOMAS POST OFFICE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Designation.--The facility of the United States Postal Service located at 44 North Main Street in Hughesville, Pennsylvania, shall be known and designated as the `Master Sergeant Sean Michael Thomas Post Office'.</narrative>
  <narrative> (b) References.--Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the facility referred to in subsection (a) shall be deemed to be a reference to the `Master Sergeant Sean Michael Thomas Post Office'.&lt;ul&gt;</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, Master Sergeant Sean Michael Thomas died on March 27, 2007 in Baghdad, Iraq. He was serving with the Harrisburg-based 28th Division Support Command. Master Sergeant Thomas joined the Pennsylvania National Guard in 1998 after 6 years in the Army Reserve. He had planned to attend Officer Candidates School in October and wanted to be a teacher when he returned to civilian life. His unit's commander, Colonel Jesse Deets, called Master Sergeant Thomas a model officer  and friend.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I commend my colleague Representative CHRISTOPHER CARNEY for introducing this legislation and urge the swift passage of this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill was ordered to be engrossed and read a third time, was read the third time, and passed, and a motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
