<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1191513602" ordinal="7" title="WELCOMING THE REVEREND DR. CLAY EVANS">
  <narrative>WELCOMING THE REVEREND DR. CLAY EVANS -- (House of Representatives - October 04, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H11254]</narrative>
  <narrative>(Mr. RUSH asked and was given permission to address the House for 1 minute.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400350" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today to welcome our guest chaplain, the Reverend Dr. Clay Evans, the pastor emeritus of the Fellowship Baptist Church of Chicago, Illinois.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dr. Evans, the son of A. Henry and Estanauly Evans, was born on June 23, 1925, in Brownsville, Tennessee. Ordained a Baptist minister in 1950, the illustrious founding pastor of the affectionately called "SHIP" has been responsible for launching the ministerial careers of 93 men and women.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, he was my catechizer at my own ordination.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dr. Evans has been a leader in the civil rights movement since 1965. He was a staunch supporter in the Chicago crusade of Dr. Martin Luther King. That staunch support caused funding for his new church to be cut off, and the structure stood unfinished for 8 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>From 1971 to 1976 he was the founding national board chairman of the Rainbow PUSH Coalition. Rev. Evans was the founding president and chairman of the African American Religious Connection, the founding president of the Broadcast Ministers of Chicago, and was a board member of the National Baptist Convention, U.S.A., Inc.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This radio and television minister, who reached listeners weekly in more than 20 States, has been happily married to the former Lutha Mae Hollingshed for more than 60 years, and they are the proud parents of five children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although Rev. Evans retired as pastor on December 8, 2000, he remains a man of faith, a man of vision, and one who emphatically believes: "It is no secret what God can do."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
