<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1179158403" ordinal="19" title="COMMENDING THE JUNIATA COLLEGE VOLLEYBALL TEAM FOR WINNING THE NCAA DIVISION III WOMEN'S VOLLEYBALL CHAMPIONSHIP">
  <speaking speaker="412211" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution (<bill type="hr" number="216">H. Res. 216</bill>) commending the Juniata College volleyball team for winning the NCAA Division III Women's Volleyball Championship.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the resolution.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Kentucky (Mr. Yarmuth) and the gentleman from Louisiana (Mr. Boustany) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412211" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I request 5 legislative days during which Members may insert material relevant to <bill type="hr" number="216">H. Res. 216</bill> into the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Kentucky?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412211" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Mr. YARMUTH asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412211" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I want to congratulate Juniata College for winning the NCAA Division III Women's Volleyball Championship.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On November 18, 2006, the Juniata College women's volleyball team won the 2006 NCAA Division III championship by beating the Washington University-St. Louis Bears in Salem, Virginia.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to extend my congratulations to head coach Larry Bock, assistant coach Heather Pavlik, Juniata College president Thomas Kepple, Jr., and the student athletes on a wonderful season.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Eagles had an exceptional record of 41 wins with just one loss. They were undefeated in Division III competition, with their only loss coming to a Division I school. The team also had an exceptional player in Stephanie Kines who was named Division III women's volleyball player of the year. Coach Larry Bock also added to his extraordinary record of 1,100 wins and 172 losses over 30 years of coaching, the most wins of any coach in NCAA women's volleyball history.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also want to extend my congratulations to the Washington University-St. Louis Bears. The Bears had a record of 38 wins and 2 losses. The Bears won the University Athletic Association title for 2006 and had four women receive AVCA All-America honors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Winning the Division III national championship and finishing the season with a 41-1 record has brought positive national attention to Juniata College, and I know the fans of the university will cherish this moment as they look forward to the 2007 season.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, once again I congratulate Juniata College for their success.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400636" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of House Resolution 216, commending Juniata College for winning the NCAA Division III Women's Volleyball Championship.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On November 18, 2006, the Juniata College women's volleyball team defeated their longtime rival, Washington University of St. Louis, in a thrilling five-game championship match that might possibly be described as the best championship match in the history of Division III volleyball.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Juniata College women's volleyball team is one of the great little-known dynasties in college sports today. The program has a remarkable record of 1,100 wins to only 172 losses over 30 seasons.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In fact, during the 2006 season, Juniata College did not lose a single match to any of their Division III opponents all season and the team's only 2006 loss was to Division I's Princeton University. The 41 win-1 loss record tied the program record for the fewest losses in a season and was the team's first 40-win season since 1997.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>During the season, senior Stephanie Kines was named the Division III women's volleyball player of the year, making her only the second Juniata player in the college's history to earn that honor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sophomore Amber Thomas also played a vital role in Juniata's second Division III national championship. Thomas was chosen as the tournament's most outstanding player as she piled up 54 kills in the final three tournament matches, 25 of which came in the championship victory.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would also like to recognize head coach Larry Bock who is one of the most recognizable names in collegiate volleyball. His list of accomplishments and awards places him among the most successful volleyball coaches in the country at any level.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I extend my congratulations to head coach Larry Bock, all of the hardworking players, the fans and to Juniata College. I am happy to join my good friend and colleague, Representative Yarmuth, in honoring this exceptional team and all of its accomplishments and wish all involved continued success.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask my colleagues to support this resolution, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412211" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman from Louisiana.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With that, I strongly urge my colleagues to pass this important resolution and recognize the Juniata College women's volleyball team for their great achievement. We should all join these great athletes in celebration of a hard-fought 2006 NCAA Division III championship.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="409888" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today to congratulate the Lady "screaming eagles" of Juniata College on winning the 2006 NCAA Division ill Woman's Volleyball Championship.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In a thrilling win, the Eagles found themselves down two games to one to Washington University. Down, but not out the Lady Eagles came storming back with a brilliant offensive effort to capture the Title 3-2. The Eagles found their momentum in the fourth game where the team went on a 4 to 1 run. After claiming the lead, the Eagles never looked back. At the end of the day, the Eagles walked away with 90 kills and a championship.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Juniata College's Volleyball Team's championship is a great example of sportsmanship and achievement in college sports. Over 30 seasons, Juniata's volleyball program has built a 1,100 win and 172 loss record. The team's coach, Larry Bock, has the most wins of any coach in the history of NCAA women's volleyball. Also, during their championship season, senior player Stephanie Kines was named Division III Women's Volleyball Player of the Year. Stephanie is the second Juniata player to earn that  honor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I congratulate all of the players and coaches of the Juniata College Women's Volleyball Team: Erin Albert, Brittany Carr, Cassie Dickmann, Kristi Fitzsimmons, Jess Fox, Paige Johnston, Stephanie Kines, Beth Kozak, Megan Lamens, Mariel Little, Michelle Morchesky, Aly Pompeani, Jessica Ritchey, Rachael Schatz, Megan Sollenberger, Molly Sollenberger, and Amber Thomas Head Coach Larry Bock, and assistant Coaches Heather Pavlik, Casey Dale and Erin Dodson. To all of the Screaming Eagles,  congratulation on most successful season and a well earned championship.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412211" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Kentucky (Mr. Yarmuth) that the House suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, <bill type="hr" number="216">H. Res. 216</bill>.</chair>
</record>
