<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1185163200" ordinal="25" title="MULTINATIONAL SPECIES CONSERVATION FUNDS REAUTHORIZATION ACT OF 2007">
  <narrative>MULTINATIONAL SPECIES CONSERVATION FUNDS REAUTHORIZATION ACT OF 2007 -- (House of Representatives - July 23, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H8201]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="50">H.R. 50</bill>) to reauthorize the African Elephant Conservation Act and the Rhinoceros and Tiger Conservation Act of 1994, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="50">H.R. 50</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "Multinational Species Conservation Funds Reauthorization Act of 2007".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. REAUTHORIZATION AND AMENDMENT OF AFRICAN ELEPHANT CONSERVATION ACT.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Notice of Approval of Project Proposal.--Section 2101(c) of the African Elephant Conservation Act (16 U.S.C. 4211(c)) is amended by striking "and to each country within which the project is proposed to be conducted".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Administrative Expenses.--Section 2306(b) of the African Elephant Conservation Act (16 U.S.C. 4245(b)) is amended by striking "$80,000" and inserting "$100,000".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Authorization of Appropriations.--Section 2306(a) of the African Elephant Conservation Act (16 U.S.C. 4245(a)) is amended by striking "2001, 2002, 2003, 2004, 2005, 2006, and 2007" and inserting "2007 through 2012".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 3. REAUTHORIZATION AND AMENDMENT OF RHINOCEROS AND TIGER CONSERVATION ACT OF 1994.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Notice of Approval of Project Proposal.--Section 5(c) of the Rhinoceros and Tiger Conservation Act of 1994 (16 U.S.C. 5304(c)) is amended in the third sentence by striking ", to the Administrator, and to each country within which the project is to be conducted" and inserting "and to the Administrator" .&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Administrative Expenses.--Section 10(b) of the Rhinoceros and Tiger Conservation Act of 1994 (16 U.S.C. 5306(b)) is amended by striking "$80,000" and inserting "$100,000".</narrative>
  <narrative> (c) Authorization of Appropriations.--Section 10(a) of the Rhinoceros and Tiger Conservation Act of 1994 (16 U.S.C. 5306(a)) is amended by striking "2001, 2002, 2003, 2004, 2005, 2006, and 2007" and inserting "2007 through 2012".&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) and the gentlewoman from Washington (Mrs. McMorris Rodgers) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Arizona.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members  have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Arizona?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, let me begin by commending Congressman Don Young, the ranking Republican on the Committee on Natural Resources, for introducing <bill type="h" number="50">H.R. 50</bill>, the Multinational Species Conservation Funds Reauthorization Act of 2007. This bill would authorize two important international wildlife conservation laws, the African Elephant Conservation Act and the Rhinoceros and Tiger Conservation Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, illegal poaching, habitat loss and other factors have pushed African elephants, rhinoceroses and tigers dangerously close to extinction. <bill type="h" number="50">H.R. 50</bill> authorizes funding through fiscal year 2012 for scientific research, management, law enforcement and public education activities used to conserve and protect these keystone wildlife species and their habitat.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress has provided $26.9 million, which has been leveraged through matching funds and in-kind contributions to generate more than $96.1 million for international species conservation. This has been an excellent investment for the Federal Government.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We support this noncontroversial bill, and urge all Members on both sides to vote for this important conservation bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mrs." name="RODGERS, McMORRIS" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in strong support of <bill type="h" number="50">H.R. 50</bill>. This legislation, introduced by the distinguished ranking Republican on the Natural Resources Committee, the Honorable Don Young, will extend the African Elephant Conservation Act and the Rhinoceros and Tiger Conservation Act. This legislation builds upon the proven success of these two conservation funds and allows the Secretary of the Interior to continue to approve badly needed conservation grants for the next 5 years. These acts have  been two of the most effective conservation laws ever approved by the United States Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I urge adoption of this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="50">H.R. 50</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the bill, as amended, was passed.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
