<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1209052802" ordinal="30" title="PROVIDING ADDITIONAL AMOUNTS FOR EXPENSES OF SELECT COMMITTEE ESTABLISHED UNDER HOUSE RESOLUTION 611">
  <narrative>PROVIDING ADDITIONAL AMOUNTS FOR EXPENSES OF SELECT COMMITTEE ESTABLISHED UNDER HOUSE RESOLUTION 611 -- (House of Representatives - April 24, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H2737]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400092" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent for the immediate consideration of the resolution (<bill type="hr" number="1148">H. Res. 1148</bill>) providing additional amounts for the expenses of the select committee established under House Resolution 611.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the resolution.</narrative>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Alabama?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <chair>The text of the resolution is as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="hr" number="1148">H. Res. 1148</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair> Resolved,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. EXPENSES OF SELECT COMMITTEE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Payment of Expenses.--In addition to the amounts authorized under House Resolution 723, as agreed to October 10, 2007, there shall be paid out of the applicable accounts of the House of Representatives not more than $150,000 for the expenses of the select committee established under House Resolution 611, as agreed to August, 3, 2007 (hereafter referred to as the "select committee").&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Vouchers.--Payments under this resolution shall be made on vouchers authorized by the select committee, signed by the chairman of such committee, and approved in the manner directed by the Committee on House Administration.</chair>
  <chair> (c) Regulations.--Amounts made available under this resolution shall be expended in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Committee on House Administration.&lt;p&gt;</chair>
  <chair>The resolution was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
