<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1182355236" ordinal="32" title="MOMENT OF SILENCE IN MEMORY OF THE LATE ROBIN BEARD">
  <speaking speaker="400032" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise to make the body aware of the loss of our colleague and friend, Robin Beard, former Congressman from the old Sixth District, who passed away last Saturday. His district basically overlapped with the current Seventh District of Tennessee. He served in this body from 1973 until 1983.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Robin Beard really had a storied and amazing life in which he dedicated himself to public service, and he did love it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He received a B.A. in history from Vanderbilt in 1962. He was a veteran, serving 4 years in the Marine Corps, where he was a Marine Corps officer in charge of the Gemini IV offshore recovery mission, and attained the rank of lieutenant colonel.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While in Congress, he served on the Armed Services Committee. He was a strong supporter of and friend to Fort Campbell, which was located in both his district and mine.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He was appointed by the House Speaker as a congressional advisor to the Strategic Arms Negotiations in Geneva and the U.N. General Assembly Special Session on Disarmament.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He also served as an assistant Republican whip, was cochairman of the Republican Research Committee on Defense, and an executive committee member of the Republican Study Committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>His expertise extended to domestic issues, and he served as an executive committee member of the Congressional Task Force on Economic Policy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After leaving Congress, he continued to serve the public, twice named as NATO Deputy Secretary General.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He is being laid to rest today in the Protestant French Huguenot Church in Charleston, South Carolina.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He is survived by his wife, Cathy, two children and five grandchildren.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield to the gentleman from Tennessee (Mr. Tanner).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400395" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I'd like to thank Mrs. Blackburn for bringing this to our attention.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Robin Beard was a friend of all of ours from Tennessee, and many of you, both professionally and personally. I actually got to know him when he served two stints as Assistant Secretary General in NATO parliamentary, or the NATO organization in Brussels.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He had a keen sense of humor, and he was a man who enjoyed the collegiality of the House. He was a House man, and he served his country well, both in uniform and out, when he was with NATO.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And so I join on behalf of all of our Members from Tennessee and, really, all of the House and Mrs. Blackburn in this tribute to our fallen colleague, Mr. Beard.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400032" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would ask that the body join our Tennessee delegation in a moment of silence in remembrance of our former colleague, Robin Beard.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
