<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1191513602" ordinal="11" title="SUPPORT THE MENTAL HEALTH SECURITY FOR AMERICA'S FAMILIES ACT">
  <narrative>SUPPORT THE MENTAL HEALTH SECURITY FOR AMERICA'S FAMILIES ACT -- (House of Representatives - October 04, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H11254]</narrative>
  <narrative>(Mr. TIM MURPHY of Pennsylvania asked and was given permission to address the House for 1 minute.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400285" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, last April, 33 students were killed at Virginia Tech. That tragedy exposed problems with Federal laws that are a barrier to schools communicating with parents when a student has a serious problem. The Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 states that students' records cannot be released except "to protect the health and safety of the student and others."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, the interpretation of that law is so unclear that schools are fearful of being sued.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The just-released report from the National Association of Attorneys General Task Force on Campus Safety calls for an update of the FERPA law that would allow for protection from liability if schools make good-faith efforts to protect students, faculty and staff.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is precisely what my bill, <bill type="h" number="2220">H.R. 2220</bill>, offers, a way to allow schools to communicate with parents when a student has significant mental health problems that increase the risk for suicide, homicide or violent acts while we still protect the confidentiality of records.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask that all my colleagues join me and Representative GRACE NAPOLITANO in cosponsoring our bill, the Mental Health Security for Families in Education Act, and work to protect our students.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let's take down the walls between parents and schools. Let's take action now to save lives tomorrow.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
