<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1182182403" ordinal="31" title="SBA VETERANS' PROGRAMS ACT OF 2007">
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from New York (Ms. Vel&#xE1;zquez) and the gentleman from Tennessee (Mr. David Davis) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412235" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of the request to suspend the rules and pass <bill type="h" number="2366">H.R. 2366</bill>, the SBA Veterans Programs Act of 2007. I would like to thank Chairwoman Vel&#xE1;zquez for working in a cooperative, bipartisan manner to bring this bill, authored by Mr. Buchanan, a freshman member of the committee, to the House floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>No one can debate the sacrifice that America's veterans have made and continue to make in defense of our country. While the repayment of that debt may never occur, we can certainly provide them with the needed assistance to prosper in civilian life. <bill type="h" number="2366">H.R. 2366</bill> is a modest contribution to repaying the debt and helping them make a smooth transition into civilian life.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill recognizes that veterans learn a variety of critical skills. Recruitment advertisements for the armed services highlight the various technical skills that they can obtain through the military. These skills clearly are valued in civilian companies. In addition, the military inculcates its members with other important skills such as leadership, decision- making, teamwork, and the drive to win. All of these are critical to success as a small business  owner.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The military does not teach its members how to take these skills and transfer them to starting a business. They require additional training to understand the key components of operating their own business without first having to serve a sort of "apprenticeship" working with others.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1999 Congress recognized that more services should be directed to help the 25 million veterans start and grow their small businesses. Those efforts succeeded because a number of small businesses owned by veterans have grown to 14 percent of all small businesses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Despite this success more must be done to assist our veterans in the startup and operation of their businesses. Outreach must improve to ensure that veterans wishing to start their own businesses will have the training and advice needed to transfer their skills to entrepreneurship.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The technical advice and assistance are not limited to veterans leaving the service. Reservists who operate their own small businesses have their own unique set of operational problems associated with their call-up to duty. They may not know how long their call-up will last, and they may need assistance in ensuring that they have in place a plan to operate their businesses while they are on Active Duty.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2366">H.R. 2366</bill> represents an effort to expand the focus of the SBA entrepreneurial assistance programs to our veterans. Of most significant importance is the need to create more Veteran Business Outreach Centers. These centers operate as cooperative agreements between the Small Business Administration and the non-profit entities. These centers provide entrepreneurial development services, such as business training, counseling, mentoring and referrals. They also conduct entrepreneurial business development  workshops focusing on self-development and self-employment. Counseling services may range from development of business plans to identifying government procurement opportunities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are only four Veteran Business Outreach Centers. To serve our military men and women, more are obviously needed, and title III requires the establishment of two more centers in each of the next two fiscal years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Another important element of the bill is the recognition of the changing nature of the military with a greater involvement of women. Title I of the bill requires the administrator to establish within the Office of Veterans Business Development a program to provide assistance to women veterans. Given the rapid expansion and success of women-owned businesses, it makes sense to ensure that the needs of women veterans are met when they seek to start and operate small businesses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our fighting men and women are the best in the world. Let us help them become the best entrepreneurs in the world by enacting <bill type="h" number="2366">H.R. 2366</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With that, Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ms. VEL&#xC1;ZQUEZ. Mr. Chairman, I yield 1 minute to the gentleman from Georgia (Mr. Johnson), a member of the Small Business Committee.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412199" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="2366">H.R. 2366</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By now, every American should know who our Greatest Generation is. Our Greatest Generation was made up of the returning heroes of the Second World War. This generation was responsible for one of the greatest periods of economic growth in our Nation's history, leading to the creation of the lone superpower which now has become the world's leader in almost every conceivable category. But it is because we empowered our returning veterans with educational, business and social opportunities which  helped create an environment in which success was attainable for those who wanted it. The Greatest Generation went on to become small business owners and operators, driving the very engine which is critical for the sustained economic growth of our Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are now witnessing the emergence of another great generation, a generation of volunteer warriors who have sacrificed so much in defense of our Nation's interest. We would be negligent if we did not grant to this generation the same opportunities to succeed as we have done with past generations. That is why I support <bill type="h" number="2366">H.R. 2366</bill>, and I move for its passage.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412235" topic="">
    <paragraph>I would like to yield to the gentleman from Florida (Mr. Buchanan) as much time as he may consume.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412196" topic="">
    <paragraph>I would like to thank my colleague, the gentleman from Tennessee, for yielding, and also the gentleman from Georgia (Mr. Johnson).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would also like to commend Chairwoman Vel&#xE1;zquez and Ranking Member Chabot for their proving that leadership and bipartisanship is alive and well in the United States Congress. The Madam Chair has worked very hard on this bill, and I appreciate her effort.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, my bill, <bill type="h" number="2366">H.R. 2366</bill>, would create an important program within the Small Business Administration that gives our veterans not just a chance in a business enterprise but provides them with all the help and assistance a grateful Nation can offer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation is intended to help veterans through grants, information services and contacts with professionals in their field of endeavor. This Federal program will enhance the ability of a veteran to become an entrepreneur in his or her own right.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My bill puts an emphasis on providing veterans with market research, financial options and technological training important to become a successful small business owner.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2366">H.R. 2366</bill> not only expands the number and the scope of Veteran Outreach Centers, it ensures the opening of more doors and opportunities for our women veterans. Assisting our veterans returning from combat has been an area long overlooked, and it is high time we did something about it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am encouraged by the unanimous consent that this bill received in the committee and by the spirit of bipartisanship that is symbolic of its passage. Today, the House will pass a bill that will help individuals make an important transition from a veteran to a small business entrepreneur.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support <bill type="h" number="2366">H.R. 2366</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ms. VEL&#xC1;ZQUEZ. Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent to withdraw the motion.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the motion is withdrawn.</chair>
</record>
