<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1179871463" ordinal="38" title="PERSONAL EXPLANATION">
  <speaking speaker="400024" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, during rollcall vote amendment No. 388 on the Sessions Amendment on <bill type="h" number="1427">H.R. 1427</bill>, I mistakenly recorded my vote as "aye" when I should have voted "no."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400080" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in support of passage of <bill type="h" number="1427">H.R. 1427</bill>, "The Federal Housing Finance Reform Act."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe this legislation is one of the most cost-effective ways to provide cities across the country with desperately needed federal funding so they can construct or renovate housing stock for working families on public housing waiting lists, homeless veterans, homeless Katrina victims, and homeless working families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe that passage of this legislation is a "historic" moment in this Congress, and makes me proud to be a member of this body.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In Detroit, there are thousands of working individuals and families living in homeless shelters or staying with friends and extended family members because they cannot afford the skyrocketing costs of private market housing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have a homeless shelter in Detroit where hundreds of veterans live each year, and most are working minimum wage jobs, or work in low to moderate wage employment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is a moral outrage that soldiers who have fought in wars and served their country honorably come home to cities like Detroit, only to find out that they cannot afford an apartment or a home.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill will help reduce these problems, and provide decent affordable housing to more veterans and working families without raising taxes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It will also help victims of Katrina who are currently living in hotels or homeless shelters in other cities to return to the Gulf Coast, or remain where they are, because there will be expanded housing opportunities due to passage of <bill type="h" number="1427">H.R. 1427</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Passage of "The Federal Housing Finance Reform Act" will provide billions of dollars to cash-starved cities across the Nation to successfully build new affordable housing units for working families by utilizing existing non-profit housing developers, public housing agencies, and for-profit housing developers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Passage of <bill type="h" number="1427">H.R. 1427</bill> will help hundreds of thousands of Americans across this Nation who are currently on waiting lists for public housing to be able to get out of homeless shelters and into homes or apartments, since there will now be more federal funding for affordable housing production.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If America is ever to be a great Nation, we must ensure that all Americans, as a basic human right, have decent and affordable housing. Passage of <bill type="h" number="1427">H.R. 1427</bill> will get our Nation on the road to having a real national affordable housing policy, which we currently do not have.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The United States, the wealthiest country in the world, shamefully has one million homeless children, and over 40 percent of those living in homeless shelters are working in jobs. Our current affordable housing problem is building more homeless shelters where there is a lack of affordable housing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask this question Mr. Chairman. How many Members of Congress would want to come home after a hard day's work, and sleep in a homeless shelter? Probably nobody! We need affordable housing for all now.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge this body to pass <bill type="h" number="1427">H.R. 1427</bill> with all deliberate speed.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400427" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, while I believe that Government Sponsored Enterprise, GSE, reform is absolutely necessary, I cannot support <bill type="h" number="1427">H.R. 1427</bill>, the Federal Housing Finance Reform Act, in its current form.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is important for Congress to promote home-ownership for all Americans by giving citizens access to affordable housing. However, this bill, under the Affordable Housing Fund, AHF, section, requires that GSEs set aside nearly $3 billion over the next 4 years into a special fund. <bill type="h" number="1427">H.R. 1427</bill> essentially represents a $3 billion tax on those seeking to purchase homes. These new fees will simply be passed along to those purchasing homes. I'm not sure how a $3 billion tax increase is going to make  homes more affordable. When given the opportunity to ensure that these costs would not be passed along to homeowners, supporters of the AHF voted against the amendment that would have protected homeowners. Clearly, this is designed to be a hidden tax on homebuyers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This newly created AHF would make grants to states and Indian tribes, which would then make grants to third-party housing-related entities. <bill type="h" number="1427">H.R. 1427</bill> fails to provide adequate oversight of these third-party grantees and the funds could easily fall into the hands of politically motivated groups. Also, while using grant money for lobbying or other political activities is not permitted under the bill, there is nothing preventing groups from displacing their other funds for these activities while  still receiving grant money. One such third party group that stands to benefit financially from this new grant program is ACORN. ACORN is notorious for partisan voter registration drives. Allegations of voter fraud have plagued ACORN political activities in Florida, Virginia, Ohio,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Adding more layers of bureaucratic waste and pandering to left-leaning groups will not help low-income buyers purchase the homes of their dreams. While we need GSE reform, we should not be forced to sign onto a $3 billion tax on homeowners. There are better, more financially responsible ways to address affordable housing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the amendment in the nature of a substitute, as amended.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400627" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I demand a separate vote on the Neugebauer No. 4 amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is a separate vote demanded on any other  amendment to the amendment reported from the Committee of the Whole?</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment on which a separate vote has been demanded.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400631" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRY">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have a parliamentary inquiry.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentlewoman will state her inquiry.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400631" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRY">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, is the gentleman from Georgia requesting a recorded revote on the bipartisan Bean-Neugebauer amendment which passed by voice vote last week?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Does the gentlewoman have a proper parliamentary inquiry?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400631" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRY">
    <paragraph>Thank you, Mr. Speaker. I just wanted to make sure this was the bipartisan Bean-Neugebauer amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400627" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRY">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I demand a recorded vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> The question is on the amendment in the nature of a substitute, as amended.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400060" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Yes, in its current form.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will report the motion to recommit.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> The gentleman from Virginia is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400060" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, for many hard-working families, the American Dream and homeownership are one and the same, but lately that dream appears increasingly elusive in the face of ballooning costs of homeowners' insurance and rising interest rates on home mortgages. Nowhere is this discomforting trend more profound than in States ravaged by natural disasters.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today we have the ability to help. Congress can enhance the way the law treats mortgage interest, giving American families more buying power when shopping for their dream home. We can also improve how it treats mortgage insurance, assisting those low-income families generally required to pay this insurance to afford better housing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill, Mr. Speaker, in its current form, however, has a glaring weakness. When it comes to disaster relief, it only names the victims of Hurricanes Katrina and Rita, which would help families stricken by hurricanes in Louisiana, Mississippi and Texas. There are countless Americans beset by the recent tornadoes and wildfires in other parts of the country. Their plight is indistinguishable from those families of hurricane-plagued regions. A disaster befalls an area, home insurance rates skyrocket,  and, together with the rise in mortgage interest rates, the American dream of owning a home is dashed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This motion to recommit sets aside funds for families in districts in Kansas, California, Colorado, Florida, Alabama, Georgia, Louisiana, New Mexico, Oklahoma, South Carolina and Texas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, in the past, the majority has described motions to recommit promptly rather than forthwith as an attempt to kill the underlying bill. In this case, this is categorically incorrect. The minority has in effect been prevented by the Democrat rule from offering this language as a forthwith amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As the majority knows, the housing fund in this bill, section 139 on page 127, is a violation of rule XXI, clause 4, because it is appropriating on an authorizing bill. The Democrat rule waives this rule for the underlying bill, but does not provide a waiver for the motion to recommit or any amendments. Therefore, the minority was given no other option than to offer a motion to recommit promptly and comply with House rules.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this motion is a genuine effort to improve this bill with the language we can all agree on ought to be included. In its current form, the bill is far too vague.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Starting brand new government grant programs to help fund more bureaucracies is not the way to go. Instead, policies that have already worked to create record levels of homeownership is preferable. This recommit inserts new language to offset the cost of subsequent legislation that would enhance, continue and expand policies promoting homeownership, such as the construction and rehabilitation of housing destroyed by natural disasters and wildfires. The motion would provide for programs to enhance,  continue, expand policies promoting home ownership by reducing the cost of mortgage insurance, reducing the cost of financing residences for veterans, reducing the cost of mortgage interest and reducing the costs of homeowner insurance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, while the underlying bill does provide that Affordable Housing Fund money can be used to help victims of Hurricanes Katrina and Rita, it is incumbent upon us to recognize the plight of families suffering from natural disasters recently affecting other areas of the country. Families in Kansas, California, Colorado, Florida, Alabama, Georgia, New Mexico, Oklahoma, South Carolina, Texas and Louisiana deserve no less.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this motion to recommit.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400140" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in opposition to the motion to recommit.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from Massachusetts is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400140" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I congratulate the minority for its persistence and tenacity, if nothing else. This will be the 11th time the House has been asked to vote to kill the Affordable Housing Fund since last Thursday. They have, as I have said, taken as their model apparently the TV pitchmen of yore. They have got a machine that slices and dices and cuts and shreds and chops and whatever. They have offered 10 amendments to kill the Affordable Housing Fund. This is number 11.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400060" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, will the gentleman yield?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400140" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>No, I will not yield, and I will explain why.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>We had an open rule. Any amendment that they wanted to offer could have been offered as long as it met the deadline, which was a very long deadline. Now we have ambush legislation again. There have been 10 tries at this.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, if they really wanted this to be debated thoughtfully, it would have been an amendment. It wouldn't have been held back for 5 and 5 with us having only a chance to read it now. It is just one more attempt to kill the bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400060" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Will the gentleman yield?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400140" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>No, I will not yield, Mr. Speaker. I will not be part of self-ambush. I will say to the gentleman from Virginia, offer an amendment when you have the right to offer an amendment, and we will debate the amendment at length as we debated many of these amendments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But to play this kind of ambush game, do not expect cooperation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The gentleman may say, well, it is unfair. We got the last word. That was his choice. The gentleman could have offered the amendment in a fashion that would have allowed a broad debate on it. But they chose to have the benefit of the ambush, but not pay the price of it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This kills the affordable housing fund. What it says is none of this money goes for rental housing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By the way, they list a lot of the States. They say "including." It can go to any State; so does the bill as it now stands. The bill as it now stands allows the money to be spent in any State. And the key is this: This amendment, if you take it at face value, I would advise that, but if you do, it kills rental housing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, homeownership is a good thing, but as we have seen from the subprime problem, if you ignore people who should be renting, if you try to shoehorn everybody into homeownership and don't build a single unit of affordable rental housing, and that is what this amendment says, this amendment says none of the funds go to build rental housing, it is all homeownership. Homeownership is useful, but it is not the exclusive answer and we have a problem of people being pushed into it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Then this says "promptly." Promptly means maybe not, as we know in parliamentary language. We got some explanation why it couldn't be "forthwith."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are some people who don't like this bill. They don't have the votes to kill it. They have tried every which way to do that.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400060" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Will the gentleman yield on that point?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400140" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, will you instruct the gentleman? When it becomes clear that I am not going to yield, this becomes, it seems to me, somewhat unparliamentary.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from Massachusetts controls the time.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400140" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Thank you, Mr. Speaker.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, we debated a long time on Thursday. I had to have my cast rewrapped because I was waving my arm so much. I did become unwrapped, I will tell the House.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But the point is this: We had ample opportunity to debate this with give-and-take. But you cannot, Mr. Speaker, it seems to me, expect to come in at the last minute with a very tough amendment that kills the housing fund  that we have already voted on 10 times because it says no rental housing can be built at all under this, says "promptly" rather than "forthwith" for no good reason except they don't like the bill and don't have the votes to kill  it, and then says you wouldn't give me a chance to go back and forth.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Yes, the rule did. The rule said that this amendment, if it was a thoughtful attempt to amend the bill, could have been offered as an amendment. Instead, it is held back. No one gets to see it until literally a minute before the debate starts. It is a 3-page amendment. It kills the affordable housing in a very limited debate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To put this forward under a procedure which Members know limits debate to 5 minutes and 5 minutes, and then to complain that there isn't enough back and forth, Mr. Speaker, that is the equivalent of accusing the Three Stooges of being silly, and I hope the recommital is defeated.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the previous question is ordered on the motion to recommit.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400060" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I demand a recorded vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 9 of rule XX, the Chair will reduce to 5 minutes the minimum time for any electronic vote on the question of passage.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400140" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I demand a recorded vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 5-minute vote.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400422" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on rollcall No. 396, had I been present I would have voted "aye." I returned to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism and Homeland Security to present my bill on "Stop AIDS in Prison."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400349" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on rollcall No. 396, I missed the vote on passage. I was chairing a briefing in the Intelligence Committee with NSA. I missed the vote by 30 seconds. Had I been present, I would have voted "yes."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
