<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1176912003" ordinal="7" title="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRIES">
  <speaking speaker="400367" topic="">
    <paragraph>Parliamentary inquiry, Madam Speaker.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman will state his inquiry.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400367" topic="">
    <paragraph>I understand that the procedure that the Chair just went through is known as Calendar Wednesday. Is it correct that any bill reported by a committee and placed on the Union or House calendar could have been called up by the chairman as the committee name was read?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> A non-privileged bill otherwise in order may be called up on formal authorization by the reporting committee.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400367" topic="">
    <paragraph>Further parliamentary inquiry, Madam Speaker.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman will state his inquiry.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400367" topic="">
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>, Head Start Reauthorization, was reported out of the Ed and Labor Committee on March 23, 2007. Would it have been in order for the chairman or his designee to call up <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill> at this time?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Clause 2(b) of rule XIII is sufficient authority for the chairman of a committee to call up a bill on Calendar Wednesday.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400367" topic="">
    <paragraph>Further parliamentary inquiry, Madam Speaker.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman will state his inquiry.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400367" topic="">
    <paragraph>Similarly, <bill type="h" number="493">H.R. 493</bill>, the Genetic Information Nondiscrimination Act, was reported by the Ed and Labor Committee on March 5, 2007. Would it have been possible to call up <bill type="h" number="493">H.R. 493</bill> at this time?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Yes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400367" topic="">
    <paragraph>Further parliamentary inquiry, Madam Speaker</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman will state his inquiry.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400367" topic="">
    <paragraph>Is it in order for Mr. McKeon, the ranking member of the Education and Labor Committee, to call up the bill under his committee's jurisdiction, Head Start?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> A committee member other than the chairman must have specific authorization of the committee to call up a bill on Calendar Wednesday.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400367" topic="">
    <paragraph>Further parliamentary inquiry, Madam Speaker.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman will state his inquiry.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400367" topic="">
    <paragraph>Is it in order for any member of the minority to call up a bill during the call of the committees?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> A committee member other than the chairman must have specific authorization  of the committee to call up a bill on Calendar Wednesday.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400367" topic="">
    <paragraph>Further parliamentary inquiry, Madam Speaker.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman will state it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400367" topic="">
    <paragraph>Is the chairman of the committee the only person that is in order to call up a bill during the call of the committees on Calendar Wednesday?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Calendar Wednesday business may only be called up on formal authorization by the reporting committee. Clause 2(b) of rule XIII is sufficient authority for the chairman of a committee to call up a bill on Calendar Wednesday.</chair>
</record>
