<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1181577623" ordinal="21" title="PROHIBITION ON SALE BY DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE OF PARTS FOR F-14 FIGHTER AIRCRAFT">
  <speaking speaker="412188" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="1441">H.R. 1441</bill>) to prohibit the sale by the Department of Defense of parts for F-14 fighter aircraft, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from Arizona (Ms. Giffords) and the gentleman from Arkansas (Mr. Boozman) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412188" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from Arizona?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412188" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise today in strong support of <bill type="h" number="1441">H.R. 1441</bill>, a bill that will put an end to military surplus sales that may inadvertently be helping to sustain Iran's Air Force.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, I would like to thank Chairman Lantos and Chairman Skelton for their leadership on this issue. I appreciate the opportunity to discuss this critical national security issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The background to this problem begins in the 1970s when our country sold F-14 Tomcats to Iran's pro-Western secular government. Iran was a close ally of the United States at the time and needed the capabilities of the F-14 in a dangerous part of the world. Times have changed, unfortunately. And Iran has now called for the destruction of Israel and is refining uranium in what many observers from the non-proliferation community believe is an attempt to develop the fuel necessary for an atomic weapon.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Iran is a state sponsor of terrorism and is likely responsible for arming insurgents in Iraq. Iran has ignored the calls of the international community for greater transparency in its nuclear power research and development, and the United Nations Security Council recently imposed stricter economic sanctions on Iran as a result.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When the United States Navy retired the F-14 fleet last September, that left Iran as the only nation still flying those aircraft. Iran has been trying to get around United States sanctions and export controls to secure the parts necessary to keep the F-14 flying. Recent  undercover investigations and reports have made it clear that Iran may have been successful.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Following an undercover investigation, the GAO reported in 2006 that acquiring surplus military hardware not properly demilitarized is disturbingly easy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In January of this year, the Associated Press reported that front companies were able to secretly purchase military parts for resale in Iran. Iran is the only nation still using the F-14. There are no other legitimate buyers overseas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In order to address this issue, I worked with my colleague from New Mexico, Mr. Pearce. And after a joint trip to Israel, we introduced <bill type="h" number="1441">H.R. 1441</bill>, which will prevent the United States Government from selling approximately 10,000 parts that are unique only to the F-14 Tomcat.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation will prohibit the military, as well as any other private company, from selling F-14-specific parts. It is also, Mr. Speaker, a complete ban on all international sales of parts specific to the F-14.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We cannot take the risk that components unique to the F-14 could be resold to Iran. The text of this bill was included in the fiscal year 2008 defense authorization bill, <bill type="h" number="1585">H.R. 1585</bill>, as section 1049.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The House Armed Services Committee approved the language in its markup of that bill, and the House Committee on Foreign Affairs has already marked up the specific bill and has reported it favorably.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, we must take the responsibility to ensure that our military hardware never falls into the hands of nations hostile to the United States and can never be used against our men and women in uniform and not used against our allies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support <bill type="h" number="1441">H.R. 1441</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I include for the Record an exchange of letters related to this bill between Chairman Skelton of the Armed Services Committee and Chairman Lantos of the Foreign Affairs Committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>June 8, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR MR. CHAIRMAN, On March 27, 2007, the Committee on Foreign Affairs ordered reported favorably <bill type="h" number="1441">H.R. 1441</bill>, "The Stop Arming Iran Act." This legislation contains subject matter within the jurisdiction of the House Committee on Armed Services, and thus, was sequentially referred to the Committee on Armed Services by the Parliamentarian for the House.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our Committee recognizes the importance of <bill type="h" number="1441">H.R. 1441</bill> and the need for the legislation to move expeditiously. Therefore, while we have a valid claim to jurisdiction over this legislation, the Committee on Armed Services will waive further consideration of <bill type="h" number="1441">H.R. 1441</bill>. I do so with the understanding that by waiving further consideration of the bill, the Committee does not waive any future jurisdictional claims over similar measures. In the event of a conference with the Senate on this bill, the Committee  on Armed Services reserves the right to seek the appointment of conferees.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would appreciate the inclusion of this letter and a copy of the response in your Committee's report on <bill type="h" number="1441">H.R. 1441</bill> and in the CONGRESSIONAL RECORD during consideration of the measure on the House floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Very truly yours,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ike Skelton</paragraph>
    <paragraph>June 8, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR MR. CHAIRMAN: Thank you for your letter regarding <bill type="h" number="1441">H.R. 1441</bill>, an Act to Strengthen Controls on the Export of Surplus F-14 Fighter Aircraft Parts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I appreciate your willingness to work cooperatively on this legislation. I recognize that the bill contains provisions that fall within the jurisdiction of the Committee on Armed Services. I acknowledge that your Committee will not seek a sequential referral of the bill and agree that the inaction of your Committee with respect to the bill does not in any way serve as a jurisdictional precedent as to our two committees.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Further, as to any House-Senate conference on the bill, I understand that your Committee reserves the right to seek the appointment of conferees for consideration of portions of the bill that are within the Committee's jurisdiction, and I agree to support a request by the Committee with respect to serving as conferees on the bill, consistent with the Speaker's practice in this regard.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I will ensure that our exchange of letters is included in any Committee report on the bill and in the CONGRESSIONAL RECORD at the time of consideration by the whole House. I look forward to working with you on this important legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Cordially,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Tom Lantos,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400040" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to thank Representative Giffords for her leadership on this issue, as well as Chairman Lantos for sponsoring the committee amendment clarifying the intent and impact of this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Earlier this year as a result of the Federal sting operation, Congress learned that Iran had illegally purchased parts for F-14 fighter planes from a U.S. military surplus store. According to investigators, the incident was just one piece of a larger ring of illegally sold military surplus parts that found their way to China and Iran.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The report prompted the Pentagon's Defense Logistics Agency to suspend sales of the F-14 components.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>Military surplus offices are supposed to demilitarize parts, which would render them useless for military purposes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>They are also allowed to auction the parts but only to buyers who promise to obey U.S. arms embargoes, export controls, and other laws. That was not the case, however, with these particular F-14 parts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As Members are aware, Tehran is in search of several key components for its aging fleet of F-14 Tomcat jets, which the United States sold to Iran prior to its 1979 Islamic revolution. This bill will add another layer of protection to the extensive array of export sanctions already imposed on Iran under the International Economic Emergency Powers Act and related executive orders.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The committee amendment recognizes these facts and adjusts the title of the bill to more accurately reflect the purpose of the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, given the clear and present danger Iran poses to the national security interests of the United States and to the broader peace and stability of the Middle East, this is an appropriate and timely measure for our consideration today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank again Ms. Giffords and Mr. Pearce, and I support the adoption of the resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412188" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would like to thank the gentleman from Arkansas for his comments, and I indeed think that this is an important piece of legislation that will further support our interests abroad and make sure that parts like the F-14 Tomcat are not sold to the Iranians.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400313" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, we must utilize every resource available while fighting the Global War on Terror. Currently, we are fighting two major combat operations in Iraq and Afghanistan which are critical to implementing democracy and peace throughout the Middle East. In both these areas we have a common enemy that continues to increase its forces. Recent reports have shown that Iran is supplying arms to both the terrorists in Iraq and the Taliban in Afghanistan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Every night on the news we see the price we pay in a two front war against a sinister and studious enemy. It is difficult enough to fight an insurgency inspired by hatred, let alone an enemy supported by a sovereign nation such as Iran.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Reports of Iranian weapons and funds surfacing both in Iraq and Afghanistan are indicators that Iran is willing to use other countries to attack American interests without having to sacrifice their own sons and daughters. We are fighting a cowardly enemy which uses others to do its dirty work for them. This is state sponsored terrorism and we must take steps to cut off the resources they use to fund our enemies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, under the guise of energy development, Iran continues a program that puts them closer and closer to developing weapons grade plutonium. I have severe reservations allowing this program continue until Iranian President Ahmadinejad can unequivocally prove that he does not have intentions of someday creating and using a nuclear warhead against the United States, Israel, Europe or other Allies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation is crucial in the Global War on Terror because it is a tangible indicator to Iran, and all other nations which harbor or sponsor terrorist tactics in any form, that we will not allow the violence to escalate any further. By preventing the sale of F-14s in whole or part to Iran we will be cutting off the supply of arms that may someday be used to kill American soldiers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I congratulate my colleague and Congressional neighbor from Arizona for her hard work and dedication to this issue. It is important for our safety as a country, as well as the world's freedom from terrorism, that we cut off the supply of F-14 parts to Iran. I call to my friends on both sides of the aisle for overwhelming bipartisan support of this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412188" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no further requests for time, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400040" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from Arizona (Ms. Giffords) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="1441">H.R. 1441</bill>, as amended.</chair>
</record>
