<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1221494402" ordinal="12" title="JACKSON GULCH REHABILITATION ACT OF 2008">
  <narrative>JACKSON GULCH REHABILITATION ACT OF 2008 -- (House of Representatives - September 15, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H8052]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="3437">H.R. 3437</bill>) to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to carry out the Jackson Gulch rehabilitation project in the State of Colorado, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="3437">H.R. 3437</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "Jackson Gulch Rehabilitation Act of 2008".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. DEFINITIONS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; In this Act:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) ASSESSMENT.--The term "assessment" means the engineering document that is--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) entitled "Jackson Gulch Inlet Canal Project, Jackson Gulch Outlet Canal Project, Jackson Gulch Operations Facilities Project: Condition Assessment and Recommendations for Rehabilitation";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) dated February 2004; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) on file with the Bureau of Reclamation.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) DISTRICT.--The term "District" means the Mancos Water Conservancy District established under the Water Conservancy Act (Colo. Rev. Stat. 37-45-101 et seq.).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) PROJECT.--The term "Project" means the Jackson Gulch rehabilitation project, a program for the rehabilitation of the Jackson Gulch Canal system and other infrastructure in the State, as described in the assessment.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) SECRETARY.--The term "Secretary" means the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Commissioner of Reclamation.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) STATE.--The term "State" means the State of Colorado.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 3. AUTHORIZATION OF JACKSON GULCH REHABILITATION PROJECT.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) In General.--Subject to the reimbursement requirement described in subsection (c), the Secretary shall pay the Federal share of the total cost of carrying out the Project.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Use of Existing Information.--In preparing any studies relating to the Project, the Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable, use existing studies, including engineering and resource information provided by, or at the direction of--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) Federal, State, or local agencies; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) the District.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Reimbursement Requirement.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) AMOUNT.--The Secretary shall recover from the District as reimbursable expenses the lesser of--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) the amount equal to 35 percent of the cost of the Project; or&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) $2,900,000.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) MANNER.--The Secretary shall recover reimbursable expenses under paragraph (1)--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) in a manner agreed to by the Secretary and the District;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) over a period of 15 years; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) with no interest.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) CREDIT.--In determining the exact amount of reimburseable expenses to be recovered from the District, the Secretary shall credit the District for any amounts it paid before the date of the enactment of this Act for engineering work and improvements directly associated with the Project.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (d) Prohibition on Operation and Maintenance Costs.--The District shall be responsible for the operation and maintenance of any facility constructed or rehabilitated under this Act.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (e) Liability.--The United States shall not be liable for damages of any kind arising out of any act, omission, or occurrence relating to a facility rehabilitated or constructed under this Act.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (f) Effect.--An activity provided Federal funding under this Act shall not be considered a supplemental or additional benefit under--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) the reclamation laws; or&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) the Act of August 11, 1939 (16 U.S.C. 590y et seq.).</narrative>
  <narrative> (g) Authorization of Appropriations.--There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to pay the Federal share of the total cost of carrying out the Project $8,250,000.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from Guam (Ms. Bordallo) and the gentleman from Arkansas (Mr. Boozman) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentlewoman from Guam.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days in which to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from Guam?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Ms. BORDALLO asked and was given permission to revise and extend her remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>The Mancos Project delivers water from Jackson Gulch Dam to residents, farms and businesses in Montezuma County, Colorado. The project and the Jackson Gulch Dam provide supplemental agricultural water for about 8,650 irrigated acres and at least 237 agricultural businesses. The project is also a domestic water supply for the Mesa Verde National Park.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For almost 60 years, the project has outlived its expected life and is in dire need of rehabilitation. This bill will aid the repair and the rehabilitation of this vitally important project in southwestern Colorado.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to commend our colleague from Colorado, Congressman JOHN SALAZAR, for his hard work on  the bill before us today. I urge my colleagues to support its passage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400040" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the Democratic bill manager has adequately described <bill type="h" number="3437">H.R. 3437</bill>. We have no objection to the one-time solution in this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Federal water projects throughout the western United States are crumbling due to age and limited resources at all levels. The Jackson Gulch project is a frustrating symbol of what could happen to other projects. In the coming years, Congress and the next administration have to resolve this aging infrastructure problem to leverage government and private assistance and remove unnecessary red tape to keep our water running and our lights on. We look forward to working together to resolve this nonpartisan  problem.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I again urge Members to support the bill, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from Guam (Ms. Bordallo) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="3437">H.R. 3437</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400029" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I object to the vote on the ground that a quorum is not present and make the point of order that a quorum is not present.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this motion will be postponed.</chair>
  <chair>The point of no quorum is considered withdrawn.</chair>
</record>
