<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1204045202" ordinal="28" title="PROVIDING FOR CONSIDERATION OF H.R. 3521, PUBLIC HOUSING ASSET MANAGEMENT IMPROVEMENT ACT OF 2007">
  <narrative>PROVIDING FOR CONSIDERATION OF <bill type="h" number="3521">H.R. 3521</bill>, PUBLIC HOUSING ASSET MANAGEMENT IMPROVEMENT ACT OF 2007 -- (House of Representatives - February 26, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H1037]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400170" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, by direction of the Committee on Rules, I call up House Resolution 974 and ask for its immediate consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the resolution, as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="hr" number="974">H. Res. 974</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Resolved, That at any time after the adoption of this resolution the Speaker may, pursuant to clause 2(b) of rule XVIII, declare the House resolved into the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union for consideration of the bill (<bill type="h" number="3521">H.R. 3521</bill>) to improve the Operating Fund for public housing of the Department of Housing and Urban Developmen t. The first reading of the bill shall be dispensed with. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those</narrative>
  <narrative> Sec. 3.  House Resolution 955 is laid upon the table.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> The gentleman from Florida is recognized for 1 hour.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400170" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, for the purpose of debate only, I yield the customary 30 minutes to my friend, the gentleman from Texas, Representative Sessions. All time yielded during consideration of the rule is for debate only.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I also ask unanimous consent that all Members be given 5 legislative days in which to revise and extend their remarks and insert extraneous materials into the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Florida?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <chair/>
  <speaking speaker="400170" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, House Resolution 974 provides a structured rule for consideration of <bill type="h" number="3521">H.R. 3521</bill>, the Public Housing Asset Management Improvement Act of 2007. The rule provides 1 hour of general debate controlled by the Committee on Financial Services. The rule makes in order two amendments printed in the Rules Committee report</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I am especially pleased that the rule makes in order an amendment offered by my colleague from Florida, Representative Kendrick Meek. His amendment ensures that in extreme cases where HUD is forced to take over control of a housing authority, it must honor any and all existing agreements between the local housing authority and tenant associations. This amendment is needed in sou th Florida and throughout the country, and I urge my colleagues to support it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the skyrocketing number of foreclosures and the lack of affordable housing are some of the greatest financial problems our Nation faces today. In Broward County, the county in which I live in Florida, foreclosure rates tripled in 2007 alone. It is obvious this situation has grown beyond a crisis and extends into our entire economy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One group of service providers that is suffering significantly from this econo mic crisis is our public housing authorities. For this reason I support this rule and underlying legislation that will provide flexibility to public housing authorities during our Nation's housing crisis so that they are able to sufficiently meet the needs of our constituents.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are approximately 3,300 individual public housing authorities in the United States serving 1.2 million households. Low- and middle-income individuals and families making between 50 percent and 80 percent of the median income</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally and importantly, the legislation also reaffirms the role that tenants play in determining where they live and how those communities are governed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, unfortunately, the problems addressed in this legislation are</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In my district some housing units are literally falling apart. Roofs are leaking and in some instances even caving in. Appliances are broken and decades, not years, old. Units are deteriorating, unattractive, and lacking in some of the most basic amenities. Even more is that security in many of the public housing communities has been consistently disappearing. Residents in some public housing units in my</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Yes, we are working to address these and other public housing issues. But we will not be able to fully address these issues if the underlying legislation does not pass.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this housing bill was reported out favorably by the Financial Services Committee, the whole committee, by voice vote. The minority members of the committee did not offer any amendments during markup, and not one Republican amendment was submitted to</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is my sincere hope that the House will pass this rule and underlying bill with that same overwhelming bipartisan support. I urge my colleagues to support this rule and the Public Housing Asset Management Improvement Act of 2007 as we work to improve public housing throughout America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400367" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I appreciate the gentleman from Florida for yielding me this time, and I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill is real simple. It's real simple. For several years there was a negotiation with HUD to look at the best practices across this country from people who are in the housing industry to determine best how to go about and manage assets of housing units. This bill is all about taking away the best practices that exist for nongo vernment housing, the rest of the industry, because it will take money away from people who don't engage in best practices. Of course it will take money away from</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in opposition. I rise in opposition not only to the rule, which I believe is unnecessarily restrictive, but also to the provisions in this bill and the underlying legislation that unilaterally and at the last minute seeks to abuse the Congress's</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1998 Congress passed the Quality Housing and Work Responsibility Act, which among other things required a deliberate and negotiated rule-making proc ess to bring asset management at our Nation's public housing administrations up to a reasonable standard. What we are here to do today is to say we don't want that standard.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And you're right. The gentleman from Florida is right. Public housing units that cannot meet the standards would lose money. That's why we talk about waste, fraud, and abuse. People that do not use the money that has been given them by this Congress, by the taxpayer to work in the best interests, we thought, I think, as we vote to s pend money, of people who are in public housing, who, through some sometimes no fault of their own, have to end  up in public</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By adopting widespread private sector common practices such as project-based budgeting and accounting to ensure that costs are known, managed, and maintained at a reasonable level, which is what the current bill is about, which is what we're goin g to undo, Congress wisely gave public housing administrations the tools they needed, and just like private sector tools, to manage their own finances better, bringing them into line with every other operator of subsidized housing in this country and</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today's legislation would overturn these longstanding negotiations and turn back the clock for public housing administrations nationwide by eliminating any restrictions on the amount of management fees they could charge, promoting inefficiency, reducing the level of funding available to tenants, and decreasing oversight and accountability. In other words, making sure that these public housing agencies stay on the watch list for waste, fraud, and abuse rather than using  private sector standards</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I cannot understand why this self-proclaimed most honest, ethical, and open Congress in history would use this time today to bring this legislation to the floor to make financial management of mid-sized public housing administrations less transparent, less responsive, and not even following the standards established by the private sector and by unilaterally overturning a lengthy and fairly negotiated rule-making process. But he re we are.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In fact, if Speaker Pelosi really wanted to demonstrate her commitment to honest, open, and ethical government, she could be using this time instead to take up a resolution that I and over 150 of my Republican colleagues have cosponsored, authored by my good friend, Representative Jack Kingston from Georgia, which is a continuation of House Republicans' long-term commitment to reform the earmark process. Congressman Kingston's bill would create a Joint Committee on  Earmark Ref</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By the way, that's the people's money. That's the people's money that people really back home are worried about.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Instead, Mr. Speaker, this House, which r ecently tied the record as the most closed Congress in history, with 49 closed rules so far in the 110th Congress, will consider this legislation that will impede the successful transition to, and implementation of, asset management by overturning a long negotiated process that is consistent with proper standards of the private sector.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>I know that other bills like the bipartisan Senate legislation to give our Nation's intelligence services tools that they need to protect Americans against terrorists is also trying to be taken up by the House. But, instead, this Democrat leadership has chosen to miss yet another opportunity to provide Americans with greater security by instead allowing the Protect America Act to expire. If there is any question as to why the public holds Congress in such low regard, with only about one in f ive</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, at this time I would like to insert in the Record a Statement of Administrative Policy explaining their strong opposition to <bill type="h" number="3521">H.R. 3521</bill>'s passage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Executive Office of the President, Office of Management and Budget, </paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington, DC, February 12, 2008.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Statement of Administration Policy</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="3521">H.R. 3521</bill>--PUBLIC HOUSING ASSET MANAGEMENT IMPROVEMENT ACT</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Administration is strongly committed to the successful transition to and implementation of asset management for Public Hou sing Agencies (PHAs). Asset management will adopt widespread private sector practices, including project-based budgeting and accounting, to assure costs are known, managed, and maintained at reasonable levels--ensuring public housing tenants are the first priority. However, the Administration is deeply concerned that <bill type="h" number="3521">H.R. 3521</bill>, as reported by the House Financial Services</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="3521">H.R. 3521</bill> would exempt 88 percent of PHAs, those which own or operate fewer than 500 public housing units, from the requirement to convert to asset management. The increase of the threshold for exemption from asset management, from 250 to 500 public housing units, would directly contradict a fundamental element of the Operating Fund negotiated rulemaking process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also would eliminate any restriction</paragraph>
    <paragraph>PHAs would b e allowed to spend as much as 20 percent of their Capital Fund grant on central office costs related to the operation of public housing. The extra 20 percent is above and beyond the 10 percent of the Capital Fund grant that the PHA earns as a management fee, and on top of the normal management fees that a PHA earns for operating each project. The Administration strongly opposes this provision because it could lead to excessive Capital Fund diversions and expenditures on administrative</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under the bill, HUD is directed to ensure that PHAs encourage the reasonable efforts of resident tenant organizations to represent their members, and to issue guidance encouraging resident p articipation in the implementation of asset management. Although these provisions are well-intended, HUD's regulations already encourage resident and tenant participation, especially in the adoption of Annual Plans. Moreover, the provisions in <bill type="h" number="3521">H.R. 3521</bill> giving wide latitude to a PHA's determination and use</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Administration looks forward to working with the Congress to ensure that the long-awaited conversion of PHAs to asset management occurs smoothly and under the guidance of conventional business practices. However, <bill type="h" number="3521">H.R. 3521</bill> moves in the wrong direction and would undermine these efforts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge all my colleagues to vo te against the previous question and this rule so that today the House can actually take up legislation that will move America in a positive direction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I think it is bad policy when you stand up and try and pass a law that takes away more accountability, more opportunity for sunlight, but most of all a standard that exists everywhere else. The people we are really robbing, hurting, harming, and continuing to harm are the people that live in public housing. We believe transparency is importa nt. But we believe in responsibility. We believe that people who are in public housing are entitled to know that where they live that someone</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And today, what th is House wants to do is to lower the standards even lower. I am disappointed. But I remain optimistic, because we have got a vote in just a few minutes and we can change that pathway.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the tragic events of September 11 taught us many lessons, and one of the most basic lessons was that our Nation must remain aggressive, nimble, proactive, and adaptable in our fight against international terrorism. To accomplish this commonsense goal, and a goal that I think we, as Members of Congress,  when we raise our hand to say we will support and defend our country, Congress must give our intelligence agencies the tools that they need to stay one step ahead of terrorists who</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Telecommunications technology has changed greatly since 1978 when FISA was first written, and the modernization of foreign intelligence surveillance to adapt to the realities of the 21st century should be a critical national security priority. I am pleased that several of my colleagues on the other sid e of the aisle also agree.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On January 28, 21 members of the Blue Dog coalition sent a letter to Speaker Pelosi in support of the Rockefeller-Bond FISA legislation in the United States Senate. The letter states, "The Rockefeller-Bond FISA legislation creates satisfactory language addressing all of these issues which we fully support that would measure and should reach the House floor without substantial change. We believe these components will ensure a strong security apparatus that can thwart terr orism across</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, at this time, I will insert into the Record the letter by the Blue Dogs to Speaker Pelosi.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR MADAM SPEAKER: Legislation reforming the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act (FISA) is currently being considered by the Se nate. Following the Senate's passage of a FISA bill, it will be necessary for the House to quickly consider FISA legislation to get a bill to the President before the Protect America Act expires in February.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is our belief that such legislation should include the following provisions: Require individualized warrants for surveillance of U.S. citizens living or traveling abroad; Clarify that no court order is required to conduct surveillance of foreign-to-foreign communications that are routed through t he United States; Provide enhanced oversight by Congress of surveillance laws and procedures; Compel compliance by private sector partners; Review by FISA Court of minimization procedures; Targeted</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Rockefeller-Bond FISA legislation contains satisfactory language addressing all these issues and we would fully support that measure should it reach the House floor without substantial change. We believe these components will</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is also critical that we update the FISA laws in a timely manner. To pass a long-term extension of the Protect America Act, as some may suggest, would leave in place a limited, stopgap measure that does not fully address critical surveillance issues. We have it within our ability to replace the expiring Protect America Act by passing strong, bipartisan FISA modernizatio n legislation that can be signed into law and we should do so--the consequences of not passing such a measure could place</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is unfortunate that House Democrat leaders chose to allow the Protect America Act to expire instead of bringing to the House floor the bipartisan measure that passed the United States Senate by a vote of 68-29. To make our country safer, Congress needs to act immediately. Today, I will once again give all the Members of the House an opportunity to vote on a bipartisan long-term modernizatio n of FISA. I will call on all my colleagues, including members of the Blue Dog coalition that signed</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent to have the text of the amendment and extraneous material inserted in the Record prior to the vote on the previous question.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The SPEAKER pro tempore</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There was no objection.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to vote "no" on the previous question and in favor of a bipartisan permanent solution that closes the terrorist loophole.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400170" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I am hard put to move hurriedly, so I will yield myself such time as I may consume. I am also hard p ut, Mr. Speaker, to restrain myself and not get involved with the ongoing discussion and the numerous ads that I saw during the previous recess that were very much in error concerning the House of Representatives' actions on the FISA legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I served for 7 years on the House Select Committee on Intelligence. I find it hard to believe that my colleagues on the other side of the aisle, or that anyone, would believe that the distinguished Chair of the Intelligence Committee, Silvestre  Reyes, the distinguished Chair of the Judiciary Committee, John Conyers, the distinguished Chair of the Homeland Security Committee, Bennie Thompson, their counterparts in the United States Senate, all combined</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enough of the fearmongering. Enough of making people think that something is going to happen that is not going to happen. The simple truth is that there will be legislation that will be legislation fashioned by the House and by  the United States Senate and not by the United States Senate and not by this administration without those of us who have actual concerns about the United States Constitution having our say in that regard.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Civil liberties and civil rights are critical to America, and the foundational aspects of our country allow full airing before conclusions are made by people that have oriented the most secretive administration that I know of in the history of this country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I won't go much further on that score on  the previous question, Mr. Speaker. I return now to what we have heard about why we must pass this rule and the Public Housing Asset Management Improvement Act, which we are here about today. It is nice to have the nuances. It is nice to have the process. It is nice to have the procedural opportunities that the minority takes, and correctly they can bring up those matters which are not on the agenda today. I can assure my friends on the other side that</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the American people deserve an opportunity to improve their lives. Transitional  public housing opportunities have served this purpose for decades, nurturing families and yielding such leaders as some of us who serve in this Congress. Public housing authorities must be empowered to effectively and flexibly manage their assets with appropriate tenant oversight. My colleague on the other side mentioned private sector tools. I am fascinated by the notion that the private sector, which</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This morning, Mr. Speaker, and I take the liberty of doing this because occasionally we come to the floor and talk about different matters, but a distant cousin of mine in Fort Worth, Texas, called me. Her name is Sharon Samuels. And Sharon shared her story with me about her involvement with her mortgage company, Countrywide. She has been in her home since 1993, she said, and in addition, thereto, had ne ver taken out any of her equity out of her home. She has three children, all of them that</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I applaud my colleagues for joining together in this effort that will benefit the low-income families, the elderly and the disabled Americans who live in public housing. This bill has been endorsed by all the groups that represent not only public housing administrators and agencies but also te nant advocacy groups. The bill is supported by the Council of Large Public Housing Authorities, the Public Housing Authorities Directors Association, the National Association of Housing and Development</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But guess who doesn't support it? Some people on the other side of the aisle who had an opportunity in the Financial Services Committee to offer amendments if they so choose, and they chose not to do so, and yet the y will come here today and say that we are lacking on our side of the aisle in providing the necessary standards and providing the necessary tools for people to live in public housing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, 15 years ago, I ran for the United States Congress, and among the things that I said was I would try to improve public housing in my congressional district and throughout this Nation. I don't feel that I have succeeded. Twelve of those years have been spent under Republic administrations that were controlled  by Republicans, 12 years in the House, 8 years just now, ending soon, happily, in November so that these $18 billion backlogs and so that housing won't collapse and fall down</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is the same administration that didn't answer in New Orleans. But what have we done? In the limited time that we are here, and I continue to hear criticism about what we have not done. What we have done in the House, we passed the section 8 voucher reform program that increases the number of families, veterans,  and seniors that are able to afford safe homes by adding 20,000 new vouchers. We did expand the Homeownership Act of 2007 that allows the population of borrowers to have access to</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>They keep saying that the agenda isn't good. We passed the Housing Finance Reform Act and expanded the size of loans that can be issued by Freddie Mac and Fannie Mae. We passed the Mortgage Reform and Anti-Predatory Lending Act that increases transparency and heightens standards to keep brokers from practicing predatory lending. Save us from these people who argue that asset management is  a landmark program change now several years in the making? You bet it is.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What I don't understand is why is it poor people are always the ones that have to take it right on the chin every time this Nation gets itself in a crisis. The National Training and Information Center sponsored by La Raza; the Center for Community Change; the Chicago Rehab Network; Cleveland Housing Tenant Association; Fall River Housing Joint Tenants Council; Legal Aid Justice Center; Miami Workers Center, all sorts of organizati ons. I will include all of the letters of all of the organizations</paragraph>
    <paragraph>AND INFORMATION CENTER,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Chicago, IL, February 7, 2008.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR MADAM SPEAKER, The undersigned 150 democratic grassro ots resident organizing groups and allies would like to convey our strong support for protecting the rights of public housing residents to organize, as delineated in <bill type="h" number="3521">H.R. 3521</bill>, the Public Housing Asset Management Improvement Act of 2007. As the transition to a system of asset management is one of the most significant shifts facing the administration of public housing in many years, it is more important than ever that public housing</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In April of 2007, the National Training &amp; Information Center (NTIC) submitted a letter to Congress endorsed by local, statewide, and national organizations in protest of recent attempts to undermine the efforts of resident and community organizations to participate in the decisions around public housing that impact their communities and their lives. One of those attempts was a notice by HUD on March 1, 2007 to streamline the process to waive 24 CFR 964, which outlines the rights of resident s</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The NTIC network is of the perspective that residents must be central to the discourse around policies that impact them--both at the local and national level. Section 4 of this bill will ensure that the voices of public housing residents are not lost in the implementation of asset management. Ove r the past year, NTIC has brought together public housing residents and allies from 38 cities to identify the most pressing areas for reform of public housing policy. The right to organize and meaningful</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The undersigned 150 local, statewide, and national organizations would like to</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Access Living--Chicago, IL.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Annapolis Tenant Task Force--Boston, MA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Beacon Glen Resident Association--Cincinnati, OH.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Bethel New Life--Chicago, IL.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Bethune Village Resident Council--Daytona Beach, FL.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Border Fair Housing &amp; Economic Justice Center--El Paso, Texas</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Bowen Homes Resident Association--Atlanta, GA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Cabrini Green Rowhouse Council--Chicago, IL.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>Center for Community Change--National</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Central Advisory Council--Chicago, IL.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Central Illinois Organizing Project--Central Illinois</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Chicago Coalition for the Homeless--Chicago, IL.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Chicago Rehab Network--Chicago, IL.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Cleveland Housing Resident Association--Cleveland, TN.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Clinton Springs Resident Association--Cincinnati, OH.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Coalition to Protect Public Housing--Chicago, IL.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Communities United for Action--Cincinnati, OH.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Com munity Voices Heard--New York, NY.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Connecticut Legal Services--Connecticut State</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Consumer Action--National</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Crossroads Urban Center--Salt Lake City, UT.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Detroit United Organizing for Power--Detroit, MI.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>District of Columbia Grassroots Empowerment Project--Washington, DC.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Empower DC--Washington, DC.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Empowering &amp; Strengthening Ohio's People--Cleveland, OH.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Erie Tenant Council--Erie, PA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Everywhere &amp; Now Public Housing Residents Organizing Nationally Together--National</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Fall River Ho using Joint Tenants Council Inc.--Fall River, MA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Families United for Racial and Economic Equality--New York, NY</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Faneuil Tenant Task Force--Boston, MA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Findlater Gardens Resident Association--Cincinnati, OH.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Fuerza Laboral/Power of Workers--Providence, RI.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Good Old Lower East Side--New York, NY.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Grass Roots Organizing--Mexico, MO.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Guste Homes Resident Management Corporation--New Orleans, LA</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Hartford Organizing for Power &amp; Equality--Hartford, CT.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Homeline--Minnesota State</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Horizo n Hills Resident Association--Cincinnati, OH.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Housing Action Illinois--Illinois State</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Housing Choices Coalition--Santa Cruz, CA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Housing Rights Committee of San Francisco--San Francisco, CA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Housing Trust Fund Project--National</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Illinois Network of Centers for Independent Living--Illinois State</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Imagine Supported Living--Santa Cruz, CA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Iowa Citizens for Community Improvement--Iowa State</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Jane Addams Senior Caucus--Chicago, IL.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Janie Poe Residents Council--Sarasota, FL.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Jurisdiction-Wide Resident Advisory Board--Cincinnati, OH.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Just Cause Oakland--Oakland, CA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Kalamazoo Homeless Action Network--Kalamazoo, MI.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Lafayette Resident Advisory Board--Lafayette, WI.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Lake City House Council--Seattle, WA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Lake County Center for Independent Living--Lake County, IL.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Lake Park East Tenant Association--Chicago, IL.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>La Playa Resident Council--San Diego, CA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>La Raza Centro Legal--San Francisco, CA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Lawyers' Committee for Better Housing--Chicago, IL.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Lebanon Tenants Association--Lebanon, PA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Le Claire Court Community Development Corporation--Chicago, IL.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Legacy of Equality, Leadership and Organizing--Seattle, WA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Legal Aid Justice Center--Charlottesville, VA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Legal Aid Justice Center--Richmond, VA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Legal Assistance Resource Center of Connecticut--Connec ticut State.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Liberty Apartments Resident Association--Cincinnati, OH.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Livermore Tenants and Neighbors--Livermore, CA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Logan Square Neighborhood Association--Chicago, IL.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Los Angeles Coalition to End Hunger and Homelessness--Los Angeles, CA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Lowden Homes Local Advisory Council--Chicago, IL.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Low Income Families Fighting Together--Miami, FL.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madera Action Coalition--Madera, CA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Maine Association of Interdependent Neighborhoods--Maine State.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Maine Equal Justice Partners--Maine State</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Massachusetts Alliance of HUD Tenants--Massachusetts State</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Massachusetts Union of Public Housing Tenants--Massachusetts State.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mennonite Central Committee--National.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Metro Atlanta Task Force on Housing &amp; Homelessness--Atlanta, GA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Metropolitan Tenants Organization--Chicago, IL.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Miami Workers Center--Miami, FL.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Millvale Resident Association--Cincinnati, OH.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mineral Manor Resident Council--Reno, NV.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Minneapolis High  Rise Council--Minneapolis, MN.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mission Terrace Residents Association--San Jose, CA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mississippi Coalition for Citizens with Disabilities--Mississippi State.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mobilizing and Organizing for Victory and Empowerment--Minneapolis, MN.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mothers on the Move--New York, NY.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Myra Birch Manor Resident Council--Reno, NV.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>National Alliance of HUD Tenants--National.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>National Association for the Advancement of Colored People--Richmond, VA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>National Association of Consumer Advocates--National.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nati onal Association of Resident Management Corporations--National.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>National Economic and Social Rights Initiative--National.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>National People's Action--National.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>National Training &amp; Information Center--National.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>New Direction for Change--Chicago, IL.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>New Orleans Women's Health Clinic--New Orleans, LA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>New Orleans Women's Health &amp; Justic e Initiative--New Orleans, LA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Neill Resident Association--St. Paul, MN.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>North Valley Community Cooperative--North Valley, NM.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>North West Bronx Community &amp; Clergy Coalition--New York, NY.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>North West Side Housing Center--Chicago, IL.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>New York City AIDS Housing Network--New York, NY.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>New York City Public Housing Residents Alliance--New York, NY.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Oahu Housing Task Force--Oahu, HI.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Old Colony Tenant Task Force--Boston, MA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Organization of the North East--Chicago, IL.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Organizing Nei ghborhood Equity DC--Washington, D.C.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Peabody-Englewood Tenant Task Force--Boston, MA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>People for Community Recovery--Chicago, IL.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>People Organized for Westside Renewal--Los Angeles, CA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>People Organized to Win Employment Rights--San Francisco, CA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>People Organizing to Demand Environmental &amp; Economic Rights--San Francisco, CA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>People United to Secure Housing--Kalamazoo, MI.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Pittsburg Community Reinvestment Corporation--Pittsburg, PA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Portland Tenants Union--Portland, ME.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Praxis Pr oject--National.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Public Housing Association of Residents--Charlottesville, VA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Public Housing Residents of the Lower East Side--New York, NY.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Public Housing Residents of Trumbull Park Homes--Chicago, IL.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Resident Owned Business, Inc.--Gary, IN.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Residents of Salem United--Salem, OH.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rhode Island HUD Tenant Project--Rhode Island State</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Richland Resident Council--Richland County, MT.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rogers Park Section 8 Tenants Council--Chicago, IL.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rose Garden Apartment Association of Residents--Las</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Safe Streets/Strong Communities--New Orleans, LA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senior Action Council--Phoenix, AZ.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Seventy St. Botolph Street Tenant Taskforce--Boston, MA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Single Mothers on the Move--Hartford, CT.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>South Austin Coalition Community Council--Chicago, IL.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Southside Together Organizing for Power--Chicago, IL.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sunflower Community Action--Kansas State</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Survivors Village--New Orleans, LA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sutter View Resident Council--Cincinnati, OH.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Syracuse United Neighbors--Syracuse, NY.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Tenants  Union of Washington State--Washington State</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Tenants Rallying In Unity to Maintain Public Housing--New York, NY.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Transadvocacy Coalition--Hartford, CT.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Tri-City Resident Council--Southeastern Kentucky</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Union de Vecinos--Los Angeles, CA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>United Community Housing Coalition--Hartland, VT.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>United Residents for Housing Rights--Jackson, OH.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Upland Residents Association--Upland, CA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>West Broadway Tenant Task Force--Boston, MA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Whittier Street Tenant Task Force--Boston, MA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Winton Terrac e Resident Association--Cincinnati, OH.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>&lt;pre&gt;--&lt;/pre&gt;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>AND REDEVELOPMENT OFFICIALS,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington DC, February 1, 2008.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR REPRESENTATIVE SIRES: On behalf of the more than 22,000 members of the National</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We believe <bill type="h" number="3521">H.R. 3521</bill> contains provisions that will help ensure a responsible and practicable transition to asset management. The bill would establi sh a reasoned process for defining and determining management and related fees and a suitable transition period for implementing them. The bill also addresses concerns expressed by NAHRO and our industry colleagues with regard to the practicality and cost-effectiveness of asset management for local housing agencies with fewer than 500 public housing</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally the legislation reaffirms current statute with respect to the right of residents to provide input and participate in the development of local agency policies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>NAHRO maintains that the provisions contained in <bill type="h" number="3521">H.R. 3521</bill> are necessary and would, upon final enactment, resolve some of the more difficult and problematic concerns expressed by our members with regard to the transiti on to asset management as defined by recent HUD policies and directives. NAHRO has and will continue to work with the Department to ensure a smooth transition to public housing asset management, but strongly feels that congressional action providing clarity and certainty with respect</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We thank you for your leadership on this issue and stand ready to be of further assistance as appropriate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Respectfully,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>&lt;pre&gt;--&lt;/pre&gt;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>PUBLIC HOUSING AUTHORITIES,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington, DC, January 30, 2008.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR CHAIRMAN FRANK: On behalf of the Council of Large Public Housing Authorities (CLPHA), I am writing in support</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Asset management is landmark program change now several years in the making. CLPHA members have made the commitment to transition to a flexible asset management system, a shift involving sweeping management and accounting changes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Provisions in the legislation of most concern to our members are those relating to management and related fees</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Housing agencies and HUD to have an expanded formal process by April 1, 2009, the basis of which is already established in the Public Housing Operating Fund Final Rule,  enabling the negotiation of appropriate property management, bookkeeping and asset management fees. Once arrived upon, execution of those fees would commence in 2011; and</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Housing agencies to use a portion of their Capital Fund g rant towards eligible operating expenses. This provision was first established by Congress in 1996 and reinforced in the 2008 HUD appropriations bill in recognition of housing agencies' need for funding flexibility--a need which has only increased over time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We thank you for your leadership and support of public housing and look forward to working with you on passage of this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sunia Zaterman,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>&lt;pre&gt;--&lt;/pre&gt;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>NATIONAL HOUSING LAW PROJECT,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Oakland, CA, February 25, 2008.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR CONGRESSMAN SIRES: We are writing to convey our support for <bill type="h" number="3521">H.R. 3521</bill>, the Public Housing Asset Management Improvement Act. The focus of our support is based upon the resi dent participation provision.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The National Housing Law Project (NHLP) is a 40 year old national housing law and advocacy center whose mission is to advance housing justice for poor people. NHLP's goals are to increase and preserve the supply of decent affordable housing, improve housing conditions for very low-income persons and households, expand and enforce low-income tenants' and homeowners' rights and increase housing opportunities for racial and ethnic minorities. In pursuit of these goals, NHLP pr ovides support through</paragraph>
    <paragraph>HUD and public housing agencies (PHAs) are currently engaged in the very substantial effort of transitioning to and implementing asset management. This effort is having a substantial impact at the local level. PHAs that never applied for operating su bsidies are now doing so. Other PHAs are experiencing cuts in operating subsidies due to asset management and the new funding formula. All PHAs are making new staffing and program determinations because of the requirements of project-based management</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is also critical that Congress recognize the rights of public housing residents to organized and represent their members. Previously, Congress recognize these rights for residents of other federally assisted but privately owned housing. See 12 U.S.C. &#xA7;1715z-1b(4). It is important that Congress also recognize the same rights for the approxi mately 1.2 million public housing families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>CATHERINE M. BISHOP,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>&lt;pre&gt;--&lt;/pre&gt;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DIRECTORS ASSOCIATION,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington, DC, January 31, 2008.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR REPRESENTATIVE SIRES: On b ehalf of its members. PHADA thanks you for your support of the public housing program and for your efforts to ensure the workability of public housing asset management. Asset management is a landmark program change now several years in the making. During this time, PHADA has advocated for a cost-effective and practicable transition to asset management; a transition that would also enable smaller housing agencies (for whom the transition to individual project</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Public Housing Asset Management Improvement Act of 2008 (<bill type="h" number="3521">H.R. 3521</bill>) would authorize in statute recommendations long advocated for and broadly supported by PHADA's membership; recommendations that would accomplish this overall objective. PHADA is pleased to express its strong support for the passage of this important and necessary legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="3521">H.R. 3521</bill> will make possible the following:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>1. In 2009, housing agencies and H UD will have an expanded formal process, the basis of which is already established in the Public Housing Operating Fund Final Rule, enabling the negotiation of appropriate property management, bookkeeping and asset management fees. Further, once arrived upon, execution of those fees would commence in 2011.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>2. Small housing authorities that own and manage between 250 to 500 public housing units, 12 percent of all agencies, will gain regulatory relief in that the transition to asse t management will be optional for them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>3. The legislation upholds current statute by which public housing residents may organize and participate in the development of policies at public housing agencies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>PHADA believes these simple provisions will mitigate implementation impediments broadly identified by its members and would provide flexibility critical to housing agencies' survival in a time of dwindling resources.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>PHADA views these items as being essential to the fair,  efficient and effective implementation of asset management as currently defined by HUD. It welcomes the opportunity to continue to work with the Department and Members of Congress to ensure that the administration of asset management is handled in a responsible manner going forward. Thank you for the opportunity to express these views.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Respectfully,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>TIMOTHY G. KAISER,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I am prepared to yield back the balance of my time, but not before saying that I urge a "yes" vote on the previous question and the rule and remind people that this passed the Financial Services Committee by voice vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Oh, no, we are not here about FISA. We are not here about earmarks. We are here about public housing for poor people in a country that has dumped on them over and over and over again. We will get to earmarks. We will get to</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The material previously referred to by Mr. Sessions is as follows:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Amendment to <bill type="hr" number="974">H. Res. 974</bill></paragraph>
    <paragraph>Offe red by Mr. Sessions of Texas</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At the end of the resolution, add the following:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>SEC. 4. "That upon adoption of this resolution, before consideration of any order of business other than one motion that the House adjourn, the bill (<bill type="h" number="3773">H.R. 3773</bill>) to amend the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 to establish a procedure for authorizing certain acquisitions of foreign intelligence, and for other purposes, with Senate amendment thereto, shall be considered to have been taken from the Speaker's</paragraph>
    <paragraph>&lt;pre&gt;--&lt;/pre&gt;</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(The info rmation contained herein was provided by Democratic Minority on multiple occasions throughout the 109th Congress.)</narrative>
  <narrative>The Vote on the Previous Question: What It Really Means</narrative>
  <narrative>This vote, the vote on whether to order the previous question on a special rule, is not merely a procedural vote. A vote against ordering the previous question is a vote against the Democratic majority agenda and a vote to allow the opposition, at least for the moment, to offer an alternative plan.  It is a vote about what the House should be debating.</narrative>
  <narrative>Mr. Clarence Cannon's Precedents of the House of Representatives, (VI, 308-311) describes the vote on the previous question on the rule as "a motion to direct or control the consideration of the subject before the House being made by the Member in charge." To defeat the previous question is to give the opposition a chance to decide the subject before the House. Cannon cites the Speaker's ruling of January 13, 1920, to the effect that "the refusa l of the House to sustain the demand for the</narrative>
  <narrative>Because the vote today may look bad for the Democratic majority they will say "the vote on the previous question is simply a vote on whether to proceed to an immediate vote on adopting the resolution . . . [and] has no substantive legislative or policy implications whatsoever." But that is not what they have always said. Listen to the definition of the previous question used in the Floor Procedures Manu al published by the Rules Committee in the 109th Congress, (page 56). Here's how the Rules</narrative>
  <narrative>Deschler's Procedure in the U.S. House of Representatives, the subcha pter titled  "Amending Special Rules" states: "a refusal to order the previous question on such a rule [a special rule reported from the Committee on Rules] opens the resolution to amendment and further debate." (Chapter 21, section 21.2) Section 21.3 continues: Upon rejection of the motion for the previous question on a resolution reported from the Committee on Rules, control shifts</narrative>
  <narrative>Clearly, the vote on the previous question on a rule does have substantive policy implications. It is one of the only available tools for those who oppose the Democratic majority's agenda and allows those with alternative views the opportunity to offer an alternative plan.</narrative>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="INGS, HAST" of="Florida">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time, and I move the previous question on the resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The question is on ordering the previous question.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and the Speaker pro tempore announced that the ayes appeared to have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400367" topic="PUBLIC HOUSING AUTHORITIES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX, further proceedi ngs on this question will be postponed.</chair>
</record>
