<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1186086470" ordinal="34" title="AGRICULTURE RURAL DEVELOPMENT, FOOD AND DRUG ADMINISTRATION, AND RELATED AGENCIES APPROPRIATIONS ACT, 2008--Continued">
  <chair> The unfinished business is the demand for a recorded vote on the amendment offered by the gentleman from Texas (Mr. Sessions) on which further proceedings were postponed and on which the noes prevailed by voice vote.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="ELLISON" of="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, on August 2nd I inadvertently failed to vote on Sessions amendment to <bill type="h" number="3161">H.R. 3161</bill> (rollcall No. 803). Had I voted, I would have voted "no."</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="MCHUGH" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, on rollcall No. 805 I was detained off the floor on a matter involving the Intelligence Committee. Had I been present, I would have voted "no."</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mrs." name="DRAKE" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, on rollcall No. 805 I am reported as voting "yes"--It was my intention to vote "no."</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400285" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, on rollcall No. 806, I inadvertently voted "no" while I intended to vote "aye."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Stated against:</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="COLE" of="Oklahoma">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, on rollcall No. 806, I inadvertently voted "aye." I meant to vote "no."</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="MCHUGH" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, on rollcall No. 806, I was detained off the floor on a matter involving the Intelligence Committee. Had I been present, I would have voted "no."</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="KENNEDY" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, on rollcall Nos. 803-807, I missed votes due to my pager malfunction. Had I been present, I would have voted "no" on each of them.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
  <narrative>(By unanimous consent, Mr. Ellison was allowed to speak out of order.)</narrative>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="ELLISON" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, on behalf of all the Members of the Minnesota delegation, including our esteemed Chairman Jim Oberstar, Jim Ramstad, Collin Peterson, Betty McCollum, Congressman Kline, Congressman Bachmann and Congressman Walz, I would simply like to share with the body that we now know the identities of four of the members of our community in Minnesota who were lost at the collapsed bridge. Those individuals include Sheri  Lou Engebrelson of Shoreview, Minnesota; Julia Blackhawk of Savage, Minnesota; Patricia Holmes of Mounds View, Minnesota; and Artemo Trinidad Mena of Minneapolis, Minnesota. Eight of our fellow community members remain missing and are presumed to be lost and remain in submerged vehicles in the Mississippi River.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This morning, I was able to accompany Secretary of Transportation Peters, along with Senators Klobuchar and Coleman, where we met Mayor R.T. Rybak and Governor Pawlenty and many other responsive elected officials. And there, Members, I did see, no doubt, a collapsed bridge spanning about 2,000 feet, which fell 64 feet into the Mississippi River. I saw vehicles that had been crushed. I also saw, not just devastation, but true heroism, Mr. Chairman, people who ran without any  thought of their own safety to try to rescue people who had fallen into the Mississippi, rescue workers, first responders who, without any regard to their safety, came to the aid of their fellow community members. I saw unity of purpose, Mr. Chairman, and I saw responsive government meeting the needs of its people.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also saw members of the community who were looking in need of aid and assistance of their fellow members of the community.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I would like to ask that the Committee observe a moment of silence for those who we have lost, those who are suffering from injury, and the entire community which is struggling to recover at this time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> All Members will rise and we will observe a moment of silence.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="LEWIS" of="California">
    <paragraph>In its present form, I am.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The Clerk will report the motion to recommit.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> The gentleman from California is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="LEWIS" of="California">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, before going to the business at hand, let me say to my colleagues that that moment of silence earlier was something that each of us should take home with us in our hearts this evening. That which has happened in Minnesota is an obvious tragedy to the people affected, those who lost their lives, those who were injured, and, indeed, those we don't know about.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In turn, it is a reflection of the reality that across the country we have infrastructure exactly like that in Minnesota that we should all try to raise in terms of the priority of our attention. Indeed, that kind of crisis will come again, and we need to pay attention to it soon.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, with that, this motion to recommit would send the bill back to the committee and report the bill back promptly with an amendment that prohibits any funds in this act from being used to employ a person who is not authorized to be employed in this country and prohibits funds from being used for rental housing assistance to a person who is not authorized to receive such assistance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is nothing, Mr. Speaker, there is nothing dilatory about this motion. This is not a political piece of chicanery. It only requires that funds in this act be implemented in accordance with the current law and to ensure that sufficient diligence be employed by the USDA and its partners to ensure that these current requirements are followed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, we cannot afford to be allocating funds and subsidizing individuals who are not in our country legally.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Similar amendments have been adopted in several appropriations bills passed by the House this year. Had there been regular order on this bill, I am sure they would have been adopted on this bill as well, that is, those individuals who would suggest that we should not have people who are not legally in this country being subsidized.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, you are going to hear from my friends on the other side of the aisle that this will kill the bill. That is absolutely not the case. As has been demonstrated by their actions today, they can go to committee, pass these amendments, and then waive procedural issues to bring this bill back to the floor tomorrow.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I urge all Members to vote "aye" on this motion to recommit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="DeLAURO" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in opposition to the motion to recommit.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The gentlewoman from Connecticut is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="DeLAURO" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise to oppose this motion for several reasons, not the least of which is that it derails the bill. There is one word in this motion, "promptly," which, as my colleagues know, takes the bill from the floor without reaching the question of passage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me also add a critical point and be very clear: There are no funds in this bill which would authorize any actions for illegal aliens; not for rural housing, not for employment, not for any of the activities funded under this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The President today accused the Congress of stalling on appropriations bills, yet that is exactly what you are doing with this motion. You are adding to the delay with a motion that means nothing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As I have said earlier today during debate, this bill is the product of good, bipartisan cooperation and the result of many, many months of hard work; from hearings, to the subcommittee mark and up through the full committee. This bill strengthens rural America, it protects our public health, it improves nutrition in this Nation, it transforms our energy future, it supports conservation, it invests in research and it enhances all of society. We have every reason to move forward on this bill tonight.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me take the time to say thank you to the chair of the committee, Mr. Obey; yes, to the ranking member, Mr. Lewis; to the subcommittee ranking member, Mr. Kingston; to the staff, Martha Foley, Leslie Barrack, Diem-Linh Jones, Adrienne Simonson, Kelly Wade, Brian Ronholm, Ashley Turton, Leticia Mederos; on the Republican side, Martin Delgado, David Gibbons, Jamie Swafford, Merritt Myers, Meg Gilley; and on our side again, Rob Nabors, John Daniel, David Reich, Lesley  Turner. They did incredible work to make sure that this bill got passed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>Let me just say to you now that I have had a lot of Members who have come up to tell me that they will vote for whichever side stops talking first. So with that, I end my remarks. Defeat this motion to recommit and pass this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, parliamentary inquiry.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The gentleman may state his parliamentary inquiry.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Is the vote that is about to occur a 15-minute vote or a 5-minute vote?</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> It will be a 15-minute vote.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Further parliamentary inquiry. Would it be in order to ask a unanimous consent request to make it a 5-minute vote?</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The Chair cannot entertain that request without proper notice. Proper notice has not been given.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Further parliamentary inquiry. What would constitute proper notice?</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> All Members would have to be given adequate notice.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BARTON" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>I'm sorry, Mr. Speaker, I couldn't hear the answer. I am not being dilatory.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The Member may consult the leadership on standards of adequate notice.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BILBRAY" of="">
    <paragraph>Parliamentary inquiry, Mr. Speaker.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The gentleman may state his inquiry.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BILBRAY" of="">
    <paragraph>The most gracious gentlelady from Connecticut pointed out that the gentleman from California had cooperated here. Is there any reason that the gentlelady from Connecticut or the majority could accept the amendment and bring it back tomorrow morning at 9 a.m. so the American people could be assured that illegal aliens would not get this benefit, as the gentlelady from Connecticut has assured us?</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The Chair has recently addressed this. It is further in Deschler's Precedents, volume 7, chapter 23, section 32.25.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="LEWIS" of="California">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 9 of rule XX, the Chair will reduce to 5 minutes the minimum time for any electronic vote on the question of passage.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="HOYER" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent to vacate the vote that we have just taken.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BOEHNER" of="">
    <paragraph>I object.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="HOYER" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to reconsider the vote by which the previous vote was taken.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BOEHNER" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, parliamentary inquiry.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The Chair first will announce the result. The Chair prematurely announced that the motion was rejected on a tie vote of 214-214. After the cards already submitted in the well were entered in the computer, the result was the same, albeit by a different total, 212-216. The motion is not adopted.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="HOYER" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to reconsider the vote by which the previous motion to recommit failed.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The question is on the motion.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BOEHNER" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I demand a recorded vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 9 of rule XX this will be a 5-minute vote.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BOEHNER" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to adjourn.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The Chair would remind Members that the vote is on the motion to reconsider.</chair>
  <narrative>The motion to recommit was rejected.</narrative>
  <chair> The question is on the passage of the bill.</chair>
</record>
