<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1182528003" ordinal="31" title="DEDICATION OF VILLAGE HOMES OF WAYZATA, MINNESOTA">
  <chair> Under a previous order of the House, the gentleman from Minnesota (Mr. Ramstad) is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400332" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, tomorrow is a special day in our community of Minnesota. Tomorrow is the day we welcome four very special new families to our community. Tomorrow is the day we dedicate and cut the ribbon at Wayzata Village Homes, an affordable housing complex built by Twin Cities Habitat for Humanity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As we dedicate these beautiful new homes and welcome our new neighbors, I'm feeling deeply grateful to live in a community of compassionate, caring and committed people, people who care deeply about people suffering the ravages of poverty, homelessness and hunger, people who reach out to meet the housing needs of people in need, people like John and Nancy Berg.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>John and Nancy Berg started a family foundation several years ago to meet the affordable housing needs in our community and have contributed so generously time after time after time. People like Steve and Geri Bloomer, who donated the land for Wayzata Village Homes. People like Wayzata Mayor Andrew Humphrey, the members of the Wayzata City Council and the Wayzata Housing Authority, all of whom have a progressive, enlightened and generous approach to expanding access to affordable housing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am also deeply grateful to all the sponsors, donors and other partners, as well as LaDonna Hoy, Jill Kohler and Kim Vohs, and all the staff and volunteers at Interfaith Outreach and Community Partners. Interfaith Outreach and Community Partners is truly the conscience of our community. I am also deeply grateful to Sue Haig, Tony Beckstrom, and all of those with Twin Cities Habitat for Humanity. Habitat is truly the conscience of our entire Nation in meeting the huge need for affordable housing  in our country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1961, on the steps right here at the Capitol, in his celebrated inaugural address, President John F. Kennedy said: "Here on Earth, God's work must truly be our own." In Wayzata, each of these wonderful people answered President Kennedy's call. They helped make Wayzata Village Homes a reality. They answered our community's call. And tomorrow we will celebrate this great affordable-housing success story.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Tomorrow, we will celebrate four new families in our community and extend a special welcome to the proud new residents of Village Homes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nobody will give a more special welcome than Rachel Poss. Rachel is a fifth grader at Birchview School in Plymouth. Rachel certainly touched my heart this week with her community service project, which was written up in the Minneapolis Star Tribune, of providing baskets of household items to the new families of Village Homes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thank you, Rachel, and to all who made this Habitat project a reality. You showed us what public service is all about.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
