<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1168448402" ordinal="37" title="FAIR MINIMUM WAGE ACT OF 2007">
  <chair> Pursuant to section 508 of House Resolution 6, proceedings will now resume on the bill (<bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill>) to amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to provide for an increase in the Federal minimum wage.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> When proceedings were postponed earlier today, 10 minutes of debate remained on the bill.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself the balance of time. I appreciate the debate. I appreciate the job that you have done as Speaker.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This debate, Mr. Speaker, has been a good one, one marked by thoughtful dialogue on both sides of the aisle. Unfortunately, that thoughtful dialogue is limited to the last 3 hours, and only the last 3 hours. We didn't have any dialogue in the Committee on Education and Labor, we didn't have any dialogue at the Rules Committee, and because of the unprecedented terms for today's debate, the dialogue that did take place here on the floor certainly won't lead to any improvements in this legislation,  at least here in the House. However, I do hold out hope that in the weeks to come, as those on the other side of the Capitol take up this issue, we can build upon this unbalanced legislation and extend proper protections to small businesses and their workers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nevertheless, the measure we are poised to vote on in a few minutes is marked more by what is not in the bill than what is in it. Small businesses are the backbone of our economy. They create two-thirds of our Nation's new jobs, and they represent 98 percent of the new businesses in the United States. What protection does this bill provide them? None whatsoever.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The same small employers are looking for a more cost-effective way to offer health care benefits to their employees, just as large corporations and labor unions across our Nation can do because of economies of scale. What protections does this bill offer these same small employers? None whatsoever. They are the ones that are going to be providing these jobs that are going to be paying the higher wages, and they are getting no relief, no help. As a consequence, people, many people, one study says  1.6 million people, will end up losing their jobs as a result of this.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Working families, many of whom would benefit from a minimum wage increase and many of whom depend upon small businesses, are looking to Congress for innovative solutions that would improve their access to affordable health care. What protections does this bill provide them? None whatsoever.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My colleagues, we can do better. In the interest of sending the President a final measure that provides consideration for small businesses and their workers, the very men and women who are responsible for our economy's recent growth and strength, we must do better. And I believe, once Congress completes its work, we will do better. In the meantime, I urge my colleagues to oppose this unbalanced legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As this debate continues in the weeks to come, I am hopeful that all of us will be mindful of the concerns and the sacrifices of small businesses in each and every one of our districts. If we do that and if we provide them the protections they need and deserve, I am confident that the final product we send to the President's desk will be far superior to the unbalanced and scaled-down measure that we are about to vote on.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With that, Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I want to begin by commending you for the job you did in the chair today and the manner in which you conducted the debate on this issue; and I appreciate the professionalism with which you handled the gavel.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, Members of the House, I want to thank all of our colleagues who participated in the debate today. We have our differences of opinions, but I thought that the debate was well conducted.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have waited for over 10 years to have this vote on the minimum wage, a clean vote on the minimum wage for the poorest workers in this country who have worked at a wage that is 10 years old.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>You know, very often Members of Congress will take the floor and they will harken back to the time in their youth when they worked at the minimum wage and they will talk about the different jobs they had. Well, let me share with you that I, too, share those experiences.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I cleaned out oil tanks; I cleaned out ships; I drove trucks in the pear orchards; I picked fruit; I worked in the canneries; and sometimes I did two of those at the same time. I worked at night in the cannery and in the daytime in the oil refinery. I worked at the minimum wage. I wonder how I would have felt about that minimum wage if it had been 10 years old. If I was working at the minimum wage and my wages were 10 years into the past and everybody else working around me had current wages,  I wonder how angry I would have been if I would have had to support a family--at one point I was supporting a family with those minimum wage jobs--I would have been very angry. I would have thought this was a very unfair system, that my wages were stuck 10 years in the past and everybody else's wages were current.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Well, that is what has happened to these workers up until today. Today, we finally release them from being frozen in time, where their wages are from 10 years ago, but when they go to the supermarket, the food prices are higher; when they put gasoline in the car, the gasoline prices are higher; when they pay the utility bills, the utility bills are higher; when their kids get sick, the medical bills are higher. All of those things are higher. They are living in 2007, but in their wages they are  living in 1997. There is something terribly, terribly wrong with that picture.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is why overwhelmingly throughout the country the people support this effort now to raise the minimum wage. Eighty-nine percent of the people believe that we should do this, and they basically believe it as a matter of economic fairness, of economic justice to these people who are working so hard at minimum wage, who, as we say over and over again, but remember what they are, they are the poorest paid workers in America today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And when they turn on the TV, when they watch it on their lunch break, they see a CEO walk away with $210 million and a golden handshake after that CEO took a good corporation and ran it into the ditch. They see people backdating stock options, they see people defrauding the corporation for extra compensation, and yet their wages are back in time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a question of economic fairness that the American public overwhelmingly responded to in this past election; and it is this issue of economic fairness that our new speaker, Nancy Pelosi, said would be the subject of this hundred hours, that we would begin by trying to make America a fairer place for those who go to work and for those who try to provide for their families. We would make America a fairer place and we would begin by increasing the minimum wage, and that is what we  are going to do in the next few minutes, when we receive a strong and a bipartisan vote to increase the minimum wage for these workers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is terribly important that we do this. It says something about us as a Nation. When it is questioned all over the world about the economic disparities in American society, the unfairness of it, we get a chance to begin that process to change that dynamic.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>I think this is a wonderful moment for the House of Representatives, no matter what side of the aisle you sit on. We, the people's House, are going to address the needs of the people that we were elected to serve. They grant us, they grant us the authority and the ability and the honor to come to the Congress of the United States; and today, and today we are going to address their needs. Today, we are going to address the needs that have concerned them in their communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If I have any time left, I want to thank the new majority leader for his efforts over these 10 years to try to bring this vote to the floor when time  and time again he made that effort in the Appropriations Committee.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400189" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, will the gentleman yield?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield to the gentleman from Maryland.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400189" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We will celebrate Martin Luther King's birthday on Monday. I want to quote. He said this: "Equality means dignity, and dignity demands a job and a paycheck that lasts through the week."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is what this vote is about, and I thank the chairman for his leadership.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, today, the United States House of Representatives, the people's House, demonstrated that we are committed to addressing the needs of all of our people--including those who struggle to make ends meet on the Federal minimum wage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, the House will pass legislation, on a bipartisan basis, to increase the Federal minimum wage by $2.10 per hour over the next 3 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The minimum wage, of course, has not been increased since September 1, 1997, making this House action long overdue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Increasing the minimum wage is simply a matter of doing what's right, just and fair.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Eighty-nine percent of the American people support such an increase, according to a Newsweek poll.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>President Bush has expressed his support.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And a bipartisan majority of the Senate passed a minimum wage increase in June 2006.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, we urge our colleagues in the Senate to hold a clean up-or-down vote on this issue as soon as possible.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the United States of America, the richest nation on earth, workers should not be relegated to poverty if they work hard and play by the rules.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On Monday, we commemorate the life of a great American--Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And Dr. King once said: "Equality means dignity. And dignity demands a job and a paycheck that lasts through the week."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, we heed those words.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We must not ignore our citizens who are struggling.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We must get the legislation to the President's desk without delay.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400347" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, today I proudly stand with our new Speaker NANCY PELOSI and my Democratic colleagues as we live up to our promise to honor workers by passing the Fair Minimum Wage Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Increasing the minimum wage from $5.15 to $7.25 an hour over 2 years is badly needed and long overdue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The previous Republican-led Congress passed tax cuts for the wealthiest and ignored the needs of hard working Americans earning the Federal minimum wage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The result has been that our Nation's Federal minimum wage workers have been forced to support themselves and their families for nine years on a mere $5.15 an hour, while at the same time the cost of living has continued to climb. The severity of a mere $5.15 hourly wage is highlighted by what is happening in my home State of California, where the State minimum wage is $7.50 an hour. This is more than two dollars an hour more than the current Federal minimum wage. Yet many Californians, including  many in my own district, continue to live in poverty. How much greater a struggle for survival it must be for those in our country earning only $5.15 an hour.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Who are the workers in our country earning the Federal minimum wage? Most are full time hard-working American adults. Most have not had the educational and career opportunities of higher wage earners. Many of these workers are minorities and nearly all of these workers provide essential services, often in jobs that are dangerous and unreliable, yet essential to our American economy. An hour's pay, $5.15, will not buy a gallon of milk and a loaf of bread. A day's wages will barely fill their car's  tank with gasoline. And their monthly income may not be enough to cover their family's average monthly healthcare costs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is unforgivable that thousands of hard working Americans in this country live $4,000 below the poverty line and struggle even to provide the basics of food and shelter for their families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Fair Minimum Wage Act honors their hard work and significant contribution to our Nation's economy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, our consideration and approval of this bill as one of our first legislative actions is an important testament to this new Congress' commitment to hard-working low-income Americans who strive to provide for themselves and their families. The passage of this bill respects their work and their right to share in the American Dream.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to vote for the Fair Minimum Wage Act.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400110" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill>, a bipartisan measure to increase the minimum wage from $5.15 to $7.25 an hour over 2 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am proud to say that my home State of Michigan is ahead of the game on this issue. Governor Granholm and the State legislature have already passed legislation to increase the State minimum wage. A total of 28 States and the District of Columbia have a State minimum wage above the current Federal level.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I cannot understand why some of my colleagues are opposed to a measure that will directly benefit 5.7 million workers. Moreover, this measure clearly has the support of the American people. It is our job to represent the American people and I am proud that the new Democratic majority is getting the job done. We will succeed in raising the minimum wage during the first hundred hours of the 110th Congress--an accomplishment that the Republican majority could not--or shall I say cared not to--achieve  in 10 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is wrong to have millions of Americans working full-time and year-round and still living in poverty. At $5.15 an hour, a full-time minimum wage worker brings home $10,712 a year--nearly $6,000 below the poverty level for a family of three.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since 2000, America's families have seen their real income drop by almost $1,300, while the costs of health insurance, gasoline, and attending college have nearly doubled. Passing <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill> would mean an additional $4,400 per year for a full-time worker supporting a family of three--equivalent to 15 months of groceries, or over 2 years of health care--helping them to keep up with rising costs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this legislation is an important first step in a new direction for working families and I urge my colleagues to support it.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400351" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, after careful consideration of <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill>, it is with great regret that I announce my opposition to this version of a minimum wage increase.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe an increase in the minimum wage should be accompanied by small business relief to offset the burden placed on U.S. employers, so these businesses can absorb the costs of an increase.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last year, I supported an increase in the minimum wage because it also included tax relief measures for employers to offset the cost of the proposed minimum wage increase. It is unfortunate that House leadership, rather than bring this balanced approach to the floor for a vote, instead introduced what basically amounts to an unfunded mandate on our Nation's small businesses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>According to a 1999 study by the Small Business Administration, approximately 54 percent of our Nation's minimum wage earners are employed by firms who have less than 100 employees. This minimum wage increase will force our Nation's small businesses to make tough cost-cutting decisions in order to stay in business. When coupled with health care cost increases they are already facing, which the National Federation of Independent Businesses estimates at 15-20 percent, many employers will be forced  to either increase the costs of their products or lay-off lower skilled workers. Both options would have detrimental effects on the substantial progress our economy is making.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation also hurts job creation. Economists widely agree that an increase in the minimum wage without an offset for small business relief will result in much higher unemployment for workers. This is because an increase in the minimum wage also represents an increase in the costs faced by employers around the Nation. When our Nation's businesses face increases in their total cost per employee, they must often face the tough decision of either cutting jobs or reducing employee benefits  such as health care, day care or vacation time as they struggle to pay for the new wage requirements.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In short, it is essential that any increase in the minimum wage be accompanied by tax relief or health care savings for our Nation's small businesses. Because this legislation does not include any provisions that may offset the costs it levies on our Nation's employers, I cannot support it.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400270" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today to express my strong support for <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill>, which calls for an increase in the minimum wage to $7.25 per hour.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thirteen million of our Nation's lowest-paid workers have not had a pay raise for nearly 10 long years. It took the intervention of the voters to kick out the Republican do-nothing Congress, which loaded up past minimum wage legislation with special interest goodies, but today we are finally getting serious about helping this Nation's working people.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The typical American worker earning $5.15 per hour has been forced to bear the brunt of rising costs and stagnant wages; since the last minimum wage increase, the cost of health insurance, gasoline, food, electricity, and education has risen, yet wages have remained frozen.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Minimum wage today in Florida is $6.67 per hour. Yet, according to the Department of Labor in 2005, 117,000 Floridians earn at or below the $5.15 per hour Federal minimum  wage. Too many Floridians are stuck in this poverty trap.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge the Senate to move on this with the same speed and urgency that we have here in the House.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400080" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today to support <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill>, the Fair Minimum Wage Act. After the longest period since the enactment of this law without an increase--over 9 years--America's poorest working families must get the raise they need and deserve. During this period in which Congress has failed to act to raise the wage of America's poorest workers, CEO and top executive pay has soared: the average annual compensation for a CEO at a Standard &amp; Poor's 500 company rose from $3.7 to $9.1 million.  Meanwhile, 28 States have seen the light and raised their State minimum wage to a level higher than the current Federal minimum wage of $5.15.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A full-time minimum wage worker in 2006 earns only $10,712 before taxes--nearly $6,000 below the Federal poverty line for a family of three. This situation is unacceptable and immoral, as the wealth of our Nation, the richest in the world, continues to be built on the backs of the working poor. Working families in America are struggling to meet the rising costs of health care, gas, and housing, and $5.15 an hour is simply not enough.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It's time for Congress to stop turning a blind eye to the plight of those workers making minimum wage and to address their needs. That is why I supported increasing the minimum wage in the 109th Congress, and that is why I am an original co-sponsor of the Fair Minimum Wage Act in this the 110th Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill> will increase the Federal minimum wage to $7.25 per hour in three steps over 2 years. Sixty days after enactment of this legislation, the wage would rise from the current $5.15 per hour to $5.85 per hour. One year later, it would rise to $6.55. And a year after that, it would finally rise to $7.25 per hour.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The minimum wage needs to be raised not just for the goods and services it enables a person to buy but for the self-esteem and self-worth if affords. Wages must be adequate for workers to provide for themselves and their families with dignity.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400427" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today to express my concerns about the substance of the legislation before us as well as the manner in which it is being considered.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill before us will have virtually no impact on those living and working in the state of Florida. Florida voters 3 years ago approved a ballot initiative setting a minimum wage rate higher than the federal rate and indexing it for inflation. Assuming enactment of this bill later this spring, it is important to note that the federal rate is not likely to catch up to Florida's minimum wage until mid-2009 only to once again fall behind in January 2010.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Just six months ago, I joined 230 of my colleagues, including 34 Democrats, in passing a bill that increased the minimum wage to $7.25 per hour while also providing important tax relief to help small businesses transition to the higher wage. Unfortunately, that bill was filibustered by Senate Democrats. This marrying of a minimum wage increase with small business tax relief was modeled on the successful approach we took in 1996 when a bipartisan coalition of 160 Republicans and 193 Democrats,  including now Speaker Pelosi. I am pleased that Senate is pursing a bipartisan approach and building on this past success.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, the Democrat leadership in the House has chosen to break with tradition, choosing partisanship over partnership, by bringing to the House floor a minimum wage bill that excludes tax relief to help small businesses transition to the higher wage. Congressional Quarterly lamented on January 8 that "House Democrats have established rules for floor debate ..... that will block Republicans from offering any amendment. ....." The Congressional Budget Office puts cost of this bill at  over $16 billion for small business and nearly $1 billion for the federal government. Once again, Democrats break their opening day promise by excluding this $1 billion from their "pay-go" promises.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What has been absent from today's debate is a discussion about what the real downward pressure is on U.S. workers wages--illegal workers. After the federal government cracked down on illegal immigrants working at meat processing plants across the U.S., the company was forced to pay American workers a higher wage. Cracking down on illegal immigration, rather than granting amnesty to over 11 million illegal immigrants will do more to improve the wages of the working poor than a law increasing the  minimum wage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, some have suggested that raising the minimum wage is the best approach to helping those living in poverty. There are much better and more targeted approaches to assisting the working poor, a minimum wage increase is a very blunt tool in doing that. Consider these facts:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The average minimum wage earner lives in a household with income above $50,000/year</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Less than 1 in 25 minimum wage earners are single parents who work full-time--very few families rely on minimum wage job to support a family.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Only one in five minimum wage earners lives below the poverty level.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The least skilled and most disadvantaged workers are the first ones to lose jobs when the minimum wage is increased.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>68 percent of Americans live in states that have a higher minimum wage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>67 percent of minimum wage earners get a raise within the first year of employment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400360" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I rise today in support of <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill>, the Fair Minimum Wage Act. Nearly 15 million Americans, almost two-thirds of them women, go to work every day caring for our children and frail old people, cleaning up our messes, serving us food in restaurants, and for their efforts receive $5.15 an hour, the Federal minimum wage. If they work 52 forty-hour weeks, their annual income adds up to $10,712--$4,367 under the poverty level for a family of three.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Other Americans--the CEOs of the Nation's top companies--made on average $10,712 in the first two hours of the first workday of new year. According to a report by Americans United for Change, those CEOs make $5,279 an hour, $10,982,000 a year, or 1,025 times more than their minimum wage employees.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Those CEOs must really be special compared to the woman who changes their mothers' diapers or cleans their toilets. If she is a single mom with two children, she has to work 3 minimum wage jobs to provide for her family, according to Wider Opportunities for Women.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It didn't surprise me that a Newsweek poll found that 68 percent of Americans believed "increasing the minimum wage" should be one of the top priorities for the new Democratic Congress. And it's no wonder that women around the country and in my district are signing petitions, calling, sending e-mails calling on us to raise the minimum wage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Leta of Chicago wrote that "We need to increase the minimum wage," and Rebecca e-mailed to say that an increase "is shamefully overdue." Jacqueline in Skokie asked me to "Please restore a government which truly responds to the needs of the people."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It's hard to imagine any member of Congress objecting. After all, it's been 10 years, the longest span ever, since the minimum wage was raised. In that time, we members of Congress have received cost-of-living increases that have raised our salaries over $30,000.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today is the day we stand up for our lowest paid workers. Today is the day we give 15 million Americans a raise. And when we pass this modest increase, we should think of it as a down-payment on our commitment to assure that every hardworking American receives a living wage.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400324" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in opposition of <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill>, the Minimum Wage Increase Without Assistance for Small Business.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In Southern Nevada, we are fortunate to experience an extraordinary situation in regard to wage earnings and job growth. Since the tragedy of September 11, 2001, our economy has undergone a massive rebound with unemployment far below the national average and wages far exceeding the current federal minimum wage. The primary engine of this economic growth has been our small business community.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a representative of a state who mandates a dollar above the federal minimum wage, the small business community in Nevada will feel the effects of this increase stronger than most states. The Republican alternative to <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill> would provide the incentives our small businesses need to absorb the economic impact of a federally mandated increase in wages. Small businesses in my district, like Metro Pizza, operate on the smallest of profit margins. Sam Facchini, who has co-owned the business since  1987, had this to say about an additional increase to the minimum wage; "Our business is still adjusting to the most recent minimum wage increase. Small businesses are the backbone of our economy. We cannot continue to face unprecedented labor costs and be expected to prosper."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To meet an increased federal wage standard small businesses need the kinds of incentives for growth that the Republican alternative to <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill> provides. I would like to remind my colleagues that we can only create new jobs through growth in the private sector. To limit this growth for the sake of a sound bite is tempting, but will have a devastating impact on an economy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Certainly, our workers deserve the fairest compensation for their valuable labor. In Nevada, the State Constitution mandates that our minimum wage is one dollar above the federally prescribed level. Increases, however, must be carefully balanced with the ability of the business community to pay these increased wages. For these reasons, my voting record has remained clear, on July 29, 2006 I voted in favor of a similar bill that included a minimum wage increase as well as growth incentives for  small businesses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While the vast majority of American workers deserve higher wages, we must ensure that no jobs are lost as a result. I urge my colleagues to oppose <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill>, the Minimum Wage Increase Without Assistance for Small Business.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400208" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill>, the Fair Minimum Wage Act of 2007. This bill provides a long-awaited increase to the federal minimum wage by $2.10 over 2 years--from its present level of $5.15 an hour to $7.25 an hour.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am pleased that, in 2007, my home state of Ohio has joined the 27 states across the nation that have fully enacted a minimum wage above the federal level. Minimum wage female workers account for 60 percent of minimum wage workers in Ohio. Ohio Policy Matters reports that approximately 253,000 Ohio children have a parent who benefits from the states recently enacted increase. Even more will benefit 2 years from this bill's enactment, when the minimum wage is raised to $7.25.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While opponents of increasing the minimum wage often claim that minimum-wage workers are largely middle-class teenagers, recent reports from the U.S. Census demonstrate that among those workers who would benefit from this legislation, nearly half (48 percent) are the household's chief breadwinner. The Economic Policy Institute reports that 1.4 million working mothers would receive a direct raise and three million working mothers could be positively impacted by the Fair Minimum Wage Act. Nearly  4 million parents would benefit from an increase, including an estimated 623,000 single moms who would receive a direct raise under this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>According to the Center on Budget Policy Priorities, in 2006, the federal poverty line for a family of four was about $20,000, well below what most Americans would consider a decent standard of living to sustain a family. Currently, a family of four with one minimum-wage earner has a total income, including food stamps and the Earned Income Tax Credit, of only $18,950, $1,550 below the poverty line.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The minimum wage has been frozen at its current level for more than 9 years--the longest period without a minimum wage increase in U.S. history. Since its 1938 inception, there has been only one other period in which the minimum wage has remained unchanged for more than 9 years, from January 1981 until April 1990.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>History has proven that past increases in the minimum wage have not had a negative impact on the economy. In the four years after the last minimum wage increase, the economy enjoyed its strongest growth in more than three decades, adding nearly 11 million new jobs. Small business employment grew more in states with higher minimum wage rates than in states with the federal minimum wage states--9.4 percent versus 6.6 percent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am proud to support this bill. Its immediate consideration in these opening days of the 110th Congress is proof that when the Democrats have sway, working families have their way.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400253" topic="CLOSING REMARKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, today Democrats ae fulfilling a pledge to millions of working famllies who have struggled for too long to make ends meet with a minimum wage that has failed to keep pace with skyrocketing housing, health care, energy and other costs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>President Franklin Roosevelt told us, "The test of our progress is not whether we add more to the abundance of those who have much; it is whether we provide enough for those who have too little."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The federal minimum wage has remained unchanged for nearly 10 years, and its purchasing power has plummeted to the lowest level in more than half a century. It is unacceptable and immoral that millions of Americans have been working full-time and year-round while still being unable to afford the basic necessities of life.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By increasing the federal minimum wage by $2.10--from $5.15 to $7.25 an hour over 2 years--we are giving a long overdue pay raise to about 13 million Americans, which amounts to an additional $4,400 per year for a family of three. I am proud that my home state of Massachusetts already has taken similar action, increasing the Commonwealth's minimum wage to $7.50 effective January 1, 2007. A total of twenty-eight states along with the District of Columbia have a state minimum wage above the current  federal level. It is time for the federal government to catch up.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Raising the minimum wage will make an important difference in the lives of hardworking Americans across the country. The Senate should quickly pass similar legislation and President Bush should sign into law this much-needed increase as soon as it reaches his desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400230" topic="CLOSING REMARKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today as a proud cosponsor of the Fair Minimum Wage Act (<bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill>). This bill will bring a long-overdue measure of fairness to the paychecks of millions of hardworking Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have now reached the longest period of time without an increase in the federal minimum wage since its creation in 1938. While the minimum wage remains stagnant, the cost of living for countless Americans continues to skyrocket.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In my home state of Rhode Island, the average two-bedroom apartment costs over $1,147 per month. As a result, many people would need to obtain more than three full-time, minimum wage jobs just to afford a decent home, and that does not take into account other critical living expenses like food and medicine. This is an unacceptable reality that millions of hardworking Americans continue to face.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Raising the minimum wage is a critical first step in Congress's efforts to strengthen the economic security of our Nation's families. The Fair Minimum Wage Act will increase the federal minimum wage from $5.15 to $7.25 incrementally over a 2-year period.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Americans who work hard to make an honest living should not be forced to live in poverty, and by passing the Fair Minimum Wage Act, we will help ensure that all Americans have the ability to provide for their families and prosper. I urge my colleagues to join me in supporting the Fair Minimum Wage Act.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400413" topic="CLOSING REMARKS">
    <paragraph>I rise today to state my support for this legislation that would provide a long overdue increase in the minimum wage for millions of workers around the country. As many of my colleagues have stated today, Congress has failed to increase the minimum wage for more than 9 years. This is the longest period in the history of the minimum wage that it has not been increased. This is unacceptable and I am pleased we finally are taking action today to remedy this situation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>America's families have seen their real income drop by almost $1,300 since 2000, while the costs of health insurance, gasoline, home heating, and college attendance have increased by almost $5,000 annually. America's families have been squeezed for far too long. Increasing the minimum wage to $7.25 an hour, which this legislation would do over the period of 2 years, is not a panacea for the hard working men and women who earn the minimum wage in our economy. However, everyone can agree that additional  money in the pockets and savings accounts of these 13 million Americans will be of some help.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I strongly support <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill> and urge my colleagues to do the same.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400259" topic="CLOSING REMARKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in strong support of <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill>, the Fair Minimum Wage Act. I congratulate Speaker PELOSI, Majority Leader HOYER and Chairman MILLER for their recognition that this is a critical issue to our economy and for their success in making a real difference for families across America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Fair Minimum Wage Act will raise the federal minimum wage from $5.15 to $7.25 over 2 years. This pay raise is the first in more than 9 years and will affect 13 million Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This change is long overdue. Currently minimum wage employees working 40 hours a week, 52 weeks a year, earn only $10,700 a year--$6,000 below the poverty line for a family of three. The inflation-adjusted value of the minimum wage is 31 percent lower today than it was in 1979, and in real dollars a $5.15 an hour minimum wage is worth just $4.75. If the wage had just kept pace with inflation since 1968 when it was a $1.60 an hour, minimum wage would have been $8.46 last year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While in the Majority, Republicans repeatedly blocked this increase with the argument that fairness for our lowest paid workers will hurt small business. However, this summer, 650 economists, including 5 Nobel laureates, announced their support for increasing the minimum wage and their view that these arguments against such an increase are simply not valid.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, while denying this needed wage increase, Members of Congress have received pay raises of over $30,000. In addition, a recent study estimated that CEOs of top companies make in 2 hours what a minimum wage worker makes in a year. This inequity is not only an economic issue--it is a moral issue. American full-time, full-year workers should not be forced to raise their families in poverty.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A part of the hope and promise of America is that if you work hard, you will succeed. I am proud that the Democrats today are helping to make that dream a reality for millions of Americans.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400098" topic="CLOSING REMARKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in opposition to <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill>, and in support of the Republican motion to recommit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Americans deserve a decent minimum wage, but we cannot simply ignore the fact that somebody has to pay for it. In many cases, small businesses are the ones who must bear these costs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Democratic bill we consider today gives absolutely no consideration to small businesses at all. Small businesses are the backbone of our economy, providing two-thirds of  new job creation. They cannot, however, simply create money out of thin air. A small business might have been struggling to pay health care premiums for its workers. With this resolution, they may well now be unable to do so.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My Democratic colleagues frequently voice their strong support for small businesses. I don't understand why they cannot then acknowledge that this could be a burden and offer some help in the form of tax incentives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My vote for this motion to recommit and against the underlying bill is intended to send a message to the other body that a minimum wage increase is only half of the equation. I am confident the other body will work in more of a spirit of compromise and recognize the concerns I mention here today. Indeed, I look forward to considering legislation that does contain common sense provisions that will protect our small businesses' competitiveness.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to vote for the motion to recommit to and if necessary against final passage.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400251" topic="CLOSING REMARKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, today, 13 million Ameicans are getting a raise.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Later today, during the first 100 hours of the new Democratic Majority, we will vote to raise the federal minimum wage from $5.15 to $7.25 over the next 2 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nearly two-thirds of all minimum wage workers are women and women account for most of the full-time workers in some of the lowest paying jobs in our Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Including 87 percent of all housekeepers, 93 percent of all child careworkers, 75 percent of all cashiers and 66 percent of all food servers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Overall, women are twice as likely as men to work at the minimum wage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nearly 75 percent of female minimum wage workers are over 20 and 35 percent work full-time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With this raise in the minimum wage, 7.7 million women will get a raise, including 3.4 million parents and over a million single parents--who are overwhelmingly female.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Raising the minimum wage would provide an additional $4,400/year for a family of three, equaling 15 months of groceries, or over 2 years of health care--helping them to keep up with rising costs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Raising the minimum wage is supported by 89 percent of the American public in a recent Newsweek poll. Another recent poll showed 72 percent of Republicans support the minimum wage increase.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The minimum wage has not increased in more than 9 years--the longest period in the history of the law. The real value of the minimum wage has plummeted to its lowest level in 51 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A minimum wage increase is particularly important at a time when America's families have seen their real income drop by almost $1,300 since 2000, while the costs of health insurance, gasoline, home heating, and attending college have increased by almost $5,000 annually.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is wrong to have millions of Americans working full-time and year-round and still living in poverty. At $5.15 an hour, a full-time minimum wage worker brings home $10,712 a year--nearly $6,000 below the poverty level for a family of three.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Passing an increase in the minimum wage is the right thing to do and I commend the work of Chairman GEORGE MILLER and Speaker PELOSI for bringing this measure to the floor today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge all of my colleagues to support this vital legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400349" topic="CLOSING REMARKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill>, the Fair Minimum Wage Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This much needed increase in the minimum wage is long overdue. During the last 9 years since the minimum wage was last increased, 28 states and the District of Columbia have come to the aid of their citizens and passed laws implementing a higher minimum wage rate than the federal standard.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Increasing the federal minimum wage is not about giving high school students who work part-time a raise. It is about helping individuals and families meet their daily basic needs. Almost one-third of hourly workers earning less than $7.25 lived in families with incomes of $20,000 or less.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As prices for energy, health care, and daily living expenses including child care and college tuition continue to increase, the minimum wage has remained the same. This increase in the minimum wage is necessary to help families pay for the rising cost of these goods and services.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To understand what minimum wage earners are dealing with, imagine how much income you earned in 1997 and the cost of your daily expenses. For example, in Baltimore in January 1997, a gallon of whole milk was $2.87. In January 2006 a gallon of whole milk was $3.39, an increase of 18 percent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Imagine now earning what you earned in 1997, but forced to pay at least 18 percent more for your daily living expenses. For many people, an increase of 18 percent over 9 years would not be noticed because typically job salaries would also increase. But for people earning minimum wage, any increase in the price of goods and services is noticed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For a more dramatic example, consider the cost of a gallon of gasoline. In January 1997 a gallon of gas cost $1.22 and in January 2006, the same gallon cost $2.27, an increase of 94 percent. Increases of this magnitude impact the entire population but those who make the least will be hit the hardest.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>How can we expect people earning the current minimum wage to keep up with the increasing costs of everything?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An increase in the minimum wage is essential to helping all Americans achieve economic security and for working adults to be able to meet the basic needs of their families. For this reason, I support <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill> and raising the federal minimum wage.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400098" topic="CLOSING REMARKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in opposition to <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill>, and in support of the Republican motion to recommit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Americans deserve a decent minimum wage, but we cannot simply ignore the fact that somebody has to pay for it. In many cases, small businesses are the ones who must bear these costs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Democratic bill we consider today gives absolutely no consideration to small businesses at all. Small businesses are the backbone of our economy, providing two thirds of new job creation. They cannot, however, simply create money out of thin air. A small business might have been struggling to pay health care premiums for its workers. With this resolution, they may well now be unable to do so.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My Democratic colleagues frequently voice their strong support for small businesses. I don't understand why they cannot then acknowledge that this could be a burden and offer some help in the form of tax incentives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My vote for this motion to recommit and against the underlying bill is intended to send a message to the other body that a minimum wage increase is only half of the equation. I am confident the other body will work in more of a spirit of compromise and recognize the concerns I mention here today. Indeed, I look forward to considering legislation that does contain common sense provisions that will protect our small businesses' competitiveness.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to vote for the motion to recommit to and if necessary against final passage.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400381" topic="CLOSING REMARKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the debate on <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill>, the "Fair Minimum Wage Act of 2007," would benefit from a discussion of the facts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For example, increasing the minimum wage would not have a positive impact on all working and non-working Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The number of people who would benefit from raising the minimum wage is not nearly as large as some claim and those individuals who receive the minimum wage are not nearly as poor as some suggest.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>According to the Bureau of Labor Statistics, in 2005 only 2.5 percent of all hourly-paid workers earned the minimum wage. More than a quarter of those workers are teenagers and half are under 25.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Those who support a minimum wage increase should be forthright--some Americans will lose their jobs if the minimum wage is increased, especially youth and low-skilled workers. If the minimum wage is raised, businesses will incur additional costs and some will be forced to layoff employees.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Also, most individuals who receive the minimum wage have other sources of income, such as food stamps, government allowances, or earned income tax credits.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Still, we are confronted with the stark reality that over one million families must survive on little more than $1,000 a month. These families need food, clothes, housing, transportation, and hope.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Frankly, any person who engages in honest labor deserves a worthy wage and a dignified life.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Some say there are jobs Americans won't do. That demeans hard-working Americans who do work in every occupation. It especially demeans those who work at back-breaking and dangerous jobs for little pay. If we want more Americans to take those jobs, then let's pay them more.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And today is a good time to start.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400087" topic="CLOSING REMARKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill> to increase the minimum wage for working Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After years of providing tax cuts to the richest people in our country, and raise after raise to Members of Congress, I am pleased to see that in the first 100 hours of Democratic control of Congress, Democrats are giving a raise to the working poor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I firmly believe that increasing the minimum wage is a necessity to help working people provide for their families. In 6 years of Bush-onomics, gas prices have gone out of sight, college tuitions are unaffordable for millions of working families, and the price of homeownership is escaping far too many people.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The lack of a basic wage increase has put an even greater hardship on the lives of many of my constituents--people who are actually working every day and playing by the rules.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Just the other day a constituent of mine from Jackson Heights stated the obvious in  support of a minimum wage increase--an honest day's pay for an honest day's work.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I completely agree with him.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In fact, 90 percent of minimum wage workers in New York City are adults, and two-thirds of them work full-time. Over four out of five New York City minimum wage workers are people of color: 41 percent are Hispanic, 25 percent are Black non-Hispanic, and 16 percent are Asian.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Additionally, while women represent 49 percent of New York City workers, they are 59 percent of minimum wage workers. It's clear minimum wage earnings are vital to many low-income households in New York City. In fact, 60 percent of increased minimum wage earnings would go to the lowest-earning 40 percent of New York City households.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Furthermore, with 15.5 percent of my constituents living below poverty, it's long past due to raise the wages of working people.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After raise after raise for Congress and the White House, it is amazing to me that the Republicans do not think that people who actually work 5 days a week do not deserve a raise.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is why I urge my colleagues to support <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under the Democrats America really is going in a new direction--and that direction is forward.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="CLOSING REMARKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill>--increasing the minimum wage. This is an important piece of legislation and one that has been over due for many years. The Federal minimum wage has not been increased in 10 years and the buying power of the Federal minimum wage is at its lowest level in 51 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am proud to say that my district, the US Virgin Islands, has been ahead of the game by increasing the minimum wage to $6.15 an hour last year--the second increase in 2 years--affecting more than 14,000 workers in the territory. This increase was supported by private sector leaders, who indicated that they were prepared to take on the wage increase, acknowledging that while the increase does impact business, it was manageable--purporting the true American spirit of prosperity for all.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Minimum wage increase is important to all Americans but impacts women by greater proportions. Two-thirds of workers over age 16 who work at or below the minimum wage are women. Studies of low-wage workers show that the main beneficiaries of this increase would be working women, almost 1 million of who are single mothers. The minimum wage increase would help to reduce the overall pay gap between women and men.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, raising the minimum wage will help to raise the income of many low-income families, especially those headed by single mothers. I urge my colleagues to support <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill> and pass this long overdue increase in our national wages.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400218" topic="CLOSING REMARKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I am proud to stand before you today in support of <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill>, the Fair Minimum Wage Act of 2007. It is essential that we ensure that all Americans are able to maintain a decent standard of living, guaranteed in part by real living wages that reflect today's economic realities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With rising health care, energy, and education costs, America's hardworking families are being forced to do more with less. While Congress has failed to raise the minimum wage over the past 10 years, it hasn't failed to raise its own pay. Since 1997, congressional pay has increased $31,600. This is simply unjustifiable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>America is the most prosperous nation in the world. It is unconscionable that someone can work full-time and still live in poverty. Working full-time, a minimum wage earner will only bring home $10,712 this year. This is $6,000 below the poverty level for a family of three. More than 125,000 Wisconsin workers would directly benefit from this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While it is vital that we help the most vulnerable in our society, we must also ensure the livelihood of main street America's small businesses. These small businesses form the cornerstone of our economy and are essential to the well-being of our communities. That is why it is important that any increase in the minimum wage be implemented gradually.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill> accomplishes that by raising the minimum wage in a manner that will help the least fortunate while simultaneously protecting small business owners from sharp payroll increases. Sixty days after this legislation is enacted, the minimum wage would increase to $5.85 per hour. One year later, it would rise to $6.55 per hour and reach $7.25 a year after that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The American public supports raising the minimum wage. In November, six States passed minimum wage ballot measures. Currently, 28 States, including Wisconsin, have minimum wages above the Federal level. The time has come for Congress to listen to the States and the public and pass this important and overdue legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank you Mr. Speaker, and urge all of my colleagues to do the right thing and give America's minimum wage earners a well-deserved raise.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400216" topic="CLOSING REMARKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in strong support of <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill>, the Fair Minimum Wage Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The minimum wage has not been increased in nearly 10 years and its purchasing power is the lowest it has been in 50 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A full-time minimum wage worker earns just $10,700 per year, which is $6,000 below the Federal poverty level for a family of three.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill we consider today will benefit nearly 7.4 million workers directly, and another 5.6 million workers indirectly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>America's poorest working families must get the raise they need and deserve.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill is especially important given the fact that America's families have seen their real income drop by $1,300 over the past 6 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At the same time, the costs of health insurance, gasoline, home heating and attending college have increased enormously.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Increasing the minimum wage demonstrates our commitment to workers everywhere and exemplifies the value we place on a hard day's work.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to join me in supporting <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400311" topic="CLOSING REMARKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the announced purpose of <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill> is to raise living standards for all Americans. This is certainly an admirable goal, however, to believe that Congress can raise the standard of living for working Americans by simply forcing employers to pay their employees a higher wage is equivalent to claiming that Congress can repeal gravity by passing a law saying humans shall have the ability to fly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Economic principles dictate that when government imposes a minimum wage rate above the market wage rate, it creates a surplus "wedge" between the supply of labor and the demand for labor, leading to an increase in unemployment. Employers cannot simply begin paying more to workers whose marginal productivity does not meet or exceed the law-imposed wage. The only course of action available to the employer is to mechanize operations or employ a higher-skilled worker whose output meets or exceeds  the "minimum wage." This, of course, has the advantage of giving the skilled worker an additional (and government-enforced) advantage over the unskilled worker. For example, where formerly an employer had the option of hiring three unskilled workers at $5 per hour or one skilled</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Those who are denied employment opportunities as a result of the minimum wage are often young people at the lower end of the income scale who are seeking entry-level employment. Their inability to find an entry-level job will limit their employment prospects for years to come. Thus, raising the minimum wage actually lowers the employment opportunities and standard of living of the very people proponents of the minimum wage claim will benefit from government intervention in the economy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Furthermore, interfering in the voluntary transactions of employers and employees in the name of making things better for low wage earners violates citizens' rights of association and freedom of contract as if to say to citizens "you are incapable of making employment decisions for yourself in the marketplace."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I do not wish my opposition to this bill to be misconstrued as counseling inaction. Quite the contrary, Congress must enact an ambitious program of tax cuts and regulatory reform to remove government-created obstacles to job growth. However, Mr. Speaker, opponents of <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill> should not fool themselves into believing that adding a package of tax cuts to the bill will compensate for the damage inflicted on small businesses and their employees by the minimum wage increase. Saying that  an increase in the minimum wage is acceptable if combined with tax cuts assumes that Congress is omnipotent and thus can strike a perfect balance between tax cuts and regulations so that no firm, or worker, in the country is adversely affected by Federal policies. If the 20th Century taught us anything it was that any and all attempts to centrally plan an economy, especially one as large and diverse as America's, are doomed to fail.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In conclusion, I would remind my colleagues that while it may make them feel good to raise the Federal minimum wage, the real life consequences of this bill will be vested upon those who can least afford to be deprived of work opportunities. Therefore, rather than pretend that Congress can repeal the economic principles, I urge my colleagues to reject this legislation and instead embrace a program of tax cuts and regulatory reform to strengthen the greatest producer of jobs and prosperity in  human history: the free market.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400263" topic="CLOSING REMARKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, after a decade of inaction by the Republican majority, we stand to vote today on one of the most critical issues facing working Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For years, the chairman of the Education and Labor Committee, Mr. MILLER, led our efforts to bring the minimum wage more in line with this country's growing cost of living. We pushed for a clean, up or down vote. But instead, as the 109th Congress winded down, we were presented with a muddled package of bills, and once again, the will of the American people was pushed aside to accommodate corporate interests.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, I must commend Speaker PELOSI and Majority Leader HOYER for including this minimum wage increase in our first 100 hour commitment to working Americans. For the 6.5 million minimum wage earners throughout the country, this bill amounts to an additional $4,400 each year. That alone would cover: 15 months of groceries; over two years of health care; and two and a half years of college tuition at a public, 2 year college.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ultimately, up to 13 million low-wage workers will be helped by this increase.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Right now the average CEO of a Fortune 500 Company earns $10,712 in 1 hour and 16 minutes. It takes the average minimum wage worker 52 40-hour weeks--an entire year to earn the same $10,712. That's wrong, and we're going to fix it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And, let's be clear, there is no evidence to support the Republican claim that an increase in minimum wage leads to job loss. For proof, we only need to look at the twenty-eight states and the District of Columbia that have set minimum wages that are higher than the federal minimum wage. In fact, a May 2006 study released by the Center for American Progress and Policy Matters found that employment in small businesses grew more than 9.4% in states with higher minimum wage; and inflation-adjusted  business payroll growth was over 5% stronger in high minimum wage states. A 1998 study by the Economic Policy Institute found that unemployment and poverty rates actually dropped after the last increase in the federal minimum wage in 1997.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Working Americans are the backbone of our nation, and this increase is long overdue. I urge my colleagues on both sides of the aisle to join me in supporting this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400370" topic="CLOSING REMARKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill>, the Fair Minimum Wage Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The time is past due for a raise in the Federal minimum wage, which was last increased in 1996. Today, workers making the least should be heartened that this legislation will raise their wages by $2.10 an hour over two years to $7.25.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Some argue that raising the minimum wage increases unemployment and prices. This is true only if the minimum wage is set too high or phased in too quickly. If done properly, there should be little to no impact on employment or prices.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Several economic analyses point to an important dynamic that I believe is at work: When the minimum wage is increased, people have more of an incentive to work, and less of an incentive to collect welfare or remain idle.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is clear to me that increasing the minimum wage is a vital step toward ensuring work is more attractive than welfare.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I urge the support of this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400058" topic="CLOSING REMARKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in opposition to the bill before us that increases the federal minimum wage without providing tax relief to America's small businesses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I support a raise in the federal minimum wage. But, raising the minimum wage alone is missed opportunity to help American workers. Minimum wage legislation should include tax benefits for small business owners. The Democrat's bill increases the federal minimum wage from $5.15-per-hour to $7.25-per-hour over 2 years. This increase amounts to a 41 percent increase to employers. The Democrat bill does nothing to help these employers offset this huge increase--forcing employers to either reduce the  number of people they employ or pass on the cost to consumers by raising their prices.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>According to the most recent data from the Small Business Administration, an estimated 822,000 small businesses operate in my home state of Michigan. Under the Democrat's bill, 822,000 small business owners in Michigan can expect to pay 41 percent more over the next 2 years. In Michigan, where the unemployment rate is tops in the nation, workers and employers cannot afford higher taxes and added layoffs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Instead of <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill>, I support and am a cosponsor of <bill type="h" number="324">H.R. 324</bill>, the Working Families Wage &amp; Access to Health Care Act. This bill, authored by my colleagues Mr. McKeon and Mr. McCrery, offers a balanced mix of provisions that will raise the wage while softening the financial impact on small businesses who hire minimum wage workers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Working Families Wage &amp; Access to Health Care Act includes incentives for new restaurant construction, eliminates the 0.2 percent federal unemployment surtax on small business owners, and extends important small business expensing provisions Republicans enacted in 2003. Greater expensing limits mean that business owners will have more capital to expand, employ more workers, and invest more in their communities. The bill will also provide better health care coverage for workers. <bill type="h" number="324">H.R. 324</bill> establishes  Small Business Health Plans that allow small businesses to band together through associations and purchase quality health care for workers and their families at a lower cost.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to vote against <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill> and instead support legislation that protects America's workers and promotes continued economic growth.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400337" topic="CLOSING REMARKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would like to thank Congressman GEORGE MILLER for introducing this important legislation, and the 213 members who have joined me as original co-sponsors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise in strong support of <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill>, the Fair Minimum Wage Act of 2007, which would gradually raise the federal minimum wage to $7.25 per hour over two years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As you know, it has been ten years since we last increased the federal minimum wage, and when adjusted for inflation it is currently at its lowest level in 50 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Every single American who commutes to work has felt the financial pinch of the rising cost of gasoline, and none more so than those making minimum wage. According to the U.S. Department of Labor, when Congress last passed legislation raising the minimum wage, the national average price for gasoline was $1.32 per gallon. Today, the average price of gasoline is $2.39 per gallon, and millions of hard-working Americans are struggling to make ends meet at a wage of $5.15 per hour. The majority of  these workers are adults over the age of 20 and over 6 million kids are children of workers who will be helped by this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This proposed increase in the minimum wage would directly affect approximately 863,000 employees in Texas and at least 68,000, or more than 30 percent, of the workforce in my district of El Paso.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I know of many exceptional businesses in El Paso that have taken the initiative to pay their employees more than the proposed new minimum wage. I applaud them for their leadership, but we can and should do more by passing legislation to set the standard minimum wage of $7.25 per hour, so we can move closer to ensuring that all workers earn a living wage for themselves and their families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask all my colleagues to join me in supporting our Nation's working families by voting in favor of <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400387" topic="CLOSING REMARKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in strong support of <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill>, the Fair Minimum Wage Act. For far too long, working class Americans have been struggling to make ends meet at $5.15 an hour, a wage that leaves a family of three more than $6,000 below the poverty line. Today we can make a real difference in the lives of millions of Americans by increasing the minimum wage to $7.25 an hour.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1997, the last time the minimum wage was raised, $5.15 went a lot further than it does today. A gallon of gas cost $1.27 and a loaf of bread was only $0.88. It may not seem to most like $2.29 for a gallon of gas or $1.14 for a loaf of bread is too much, but tell that to the minimum wage worker with gross weekly income of only $206. They still have to drive to work and put food on the table, which is nearly impossible at $5.15 an hour without multiple incomes or a second job.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For years, states have responded to the inadequacy of the federal minimum wage by passing higher minimum wages. Those states haven't lost employers or faced higher than normal unemployment because of higher minimum wages. Small businesses in California, for example, haven't gone broke because of the high state minimum wage. The argument that small businesses can't afford to pay the minimum wage is fallacy. Organizations making that argument are probably paying a lot more than $7.25 an hour to  their snake oil salesmen.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Some argue that increasing the minimum wage is paramount to the government engaging in class warfare. One of the richest men in the world, Warren Buffet, doesn't see it that way. "There's class warfare, all right," Mr. Buffett said, "but it's my class, the rich class, that's making war, and we're winning." Failure to pass a minimum wage increase would be a huge victory in the class warfare by the wealthy against hard working Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since 1997, Members of Congress have increased our salaries by 24 percent. We can't look our hard working constituents in the eye and honestly say we deserve big pay raises and they don't. Today we can give a raise to someone other than ourselves for a change and have a positive impact on millions of working poor in this country. I strongly urge all my colleagues to vote yes on <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I'd also ask that the following article from the January 10 edition of the Washington Post be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Minimum Wage, Maximum Myth</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With Wall Street hot shots and corporate chiefs raking in obscene amounts of money, and with pay in the bottom half of the workforce barely keeping up with inflation, you'd think raising the minimum wage for the first time in a decade would be a political and economic no-brainer for the new Democratic Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But you'd be forgetting about Max Baucus.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Baucus is a Democratic senator from the Republican-leaning state of Montana, which means he is on the political equivalent of the endangered-species list. So you can understand Baucus's need to vote with his constituents on things like sugar subsidies and gun control and grazing fees on public lands.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But while Baucus is surely entitled to his opinions, and entitled to do what is necessary to assure his own political survival, he is not entitled to be chairman of the Senate Finance Committee, which handles such key Democratic issues as health care, trade and tax policy. That position ought to be reserved for a statesman with enough political confidence and backbone that he isn't constantly sacrificing the interests of his party and his country to the narrow interests of his subsidy-addicted  constituents.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>You'd think Baucus would have learned his lesson in 2001, when he won the enmity of Democrats everywhere by striking the deal that led to passage of the Bush tax cuts, including the phase-out of the estate tax. Apparently not. For on the very day the new Democratic House is set to push through a long-overdue minimum-wage increase, over in the Senate, Baucus has called a hearing on how to offset the "economic hardship" caused by the higher minimum wage with yet another round of business tax  breaks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Consider, for a moment, the economic logic that lies behind Baucus's hearing this morning, when senators will hear from a panel of witnesses that includes Dave Ratner, owner of Dave's Soda &amp; Pet City in Agawam, Mass.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>No doubt Ratner and the others will point out that workers making at or near the federal minimum wage are nearly all employed by small businesses. We will hear all the sob stories about how struggling small businesses with thin margins will be forced to cut back on hiring, pull back on expansion plans and, in some instances, close their doors. Moreover, this won't be a tragedy just for small-business owners and employees but for the economy as a whole, since everybody knows that small business  creates virtually all new jobs. Only another round of tax breaks can keep the great American jobs machine humming.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And here's the thing: Most of it is nonsense.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To begin, both economic theory and history suggest that small business will, in time, pass on its increased costs to its consumers. Small businesses that pay low wages tend to compete with other small businesses that pay low wages, so they will all face the same cost pressures and respond in similar fashion. The worst that can be said is that a higher minimum wage will add, very modestly, to overall inflation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is also general agreement among economists that a higher minimum wage, at the levels we are talking about, will have a minimal impact on adult employment. Slightly higher prices might reduce, slightly, the demand for Wendy's hamburgers, cheap hotel rooms and dog-walking services. But largely offsetting those effects will be the increased demand for goods and services by tens of millions of Americans who will finally be getting a raise. A higher minimum wage doesn't lower economic activity  so much as rearrange it slightly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The biggest lie of all is that small businesses have created most of the new jobs in America. This canard, perpetrated by the small-business lobby and embraced by politicians of both parties, has been used for decades to justify all manner of special subsidies for small business. But as economist Veronique de Rugy of the American Enterprise Institute reported in a paper last year, new jobs have been created by both large and small businesses in roughly the same proportion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In truth, the bulk of new jobs have always been created by a relatively small number of new firms that grow fast and get quite big--think of companies like Southwest Airlines, Google, CarMax. Most have little in common with the small-business lobby in Washington or fast-food restaurant chains or the members of the Kiwanis Club in Helena, Mont. As a rule, companies like these couldn't care less about the minimum wage or special tax breaks to offset it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Linking the minimum wage to small-business tax breaks is specious for other reasons, as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>During the last decade, when inflation-adjusted pay of minimum-wage workers was declining, tax rates for small businesses were also declining, thanks largely to the Bush cuts. If it is now imperative to reduce business taxes when the pay of minimum-wage workers is rising, you have to wonder if there will ever be a time when the small-business lobby thinks it doesn't deserve a tax cut.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It's also worth noting that, according to the Internal Revenue Service, small-business owners, sole proprietors and the self-employed are, as a group, the biggest tax cheats in America, responsible for $153 billion of the estimated $345 billion tax gap in 2001. What these folks deserve are more frequent visits from IRS auditors, not more tax breaks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Real Democrats know that raising the minimum wage is the right thing to do--economically, politically, morally. The question is why they have chosen a Senate Finance chairman who can't articulate that position without equivocation or apology even before the first vote is cast.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="JOHNSON, EDDIE-BERNICE" of="Texas">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today alongside my colleagues from the Women's Caucus to support this increase to the federal minimum wage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nearly two-thirds of all minimum wage workers are women.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And it's women that represent the majority of working poor in this country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The working poor are Americans who work 40 hours or more a week, but can't afford basic necessities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Each day, the working poor are faced with the decision of having to choose between: food, clothing, shelter, medicine, and utility bills.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>No American who works hard for a living should have to make these types of choices.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, more than 9 million women will benefit from this proposed increase to the minimum wage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These aren't just teenagers working part-time either.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Most of these workers are actually hard-working disadvantaged adults. Four million are parents.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This isn't simply an economic issue, it's an ethical and moral issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We cannot continue to look away while hard working Americans linger in poverty.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support these hardworking women and men by raising the federal minimum wage.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="ROSS" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today to share my strong support for raising the federal minimum wage. Today's legislation would increase the existing minimum wage from $5.15 to $7.25 an hour over two years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The minimum wage has not increased in more than nine years which is the longest period in the history of the law. The real value of the minimum wage has plummeted to its lowest level in 51 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At the current rate of $5.15 an hour, a full-time minimum wage worker brings home $10,712 a year--nearly $6,000 below the poverty level for a family of three. Increasing the minimum wage to $7.25 per hour would benefit up to 13 million Americans who struggle to raise a family.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last year the state of Arkansas, along with varying other states, realized the need for raising the minimum wage and did so. Now it is time for the Congress to accept this plan and move forward with passage of this important legislation, which can make a real difference in the lives of working families across this country.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400333" topic="CLOSING REMARKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill>, an increase in the minimum wage. It has now been a decade (i.e., 1996) since the minimum wage was last adjusted for inflation. The issue absorbed a considerable amount of attention during the 109th Congress--but no new legislation was adopted. Over 25 states (including the District of Columbia) have adopted a minimum wage in excess of the federal rate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The current Federal minimum wage rate leaves full-time workers in poverty. Thirty-seven million Americans live in poverty today--an increase of 5.4 million since 2001. Many of these individuals are full-time, full-year hard working Americans who are unable to lift themselves out of poverty because of the declining value of the federal minimum wage. Minimum wage earners working 40 hours per week, 52 weeks per year make $10,712--nearly $6,000 below the poverty line for a family of three.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, the value of minimum wage as a percentage of poverty has fallen to its lowest level on record--going way back to 1959. Earnings for full-year, full-time minimum wage work now equal less than 70 percent of the poverty level for a family of three.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Increasing the federal minimum wage would also raise the wages of low-income working families in general, not just those who fall below the official poverty line. Many families move in and out of poverty, and near-poor families are also important beneficiaries of minimum wage increases. In addition, raising the minimum wage will have a positive effect on lives of women and other minorities in this country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over one-half of workers paid less than $7.25 an hour lived in families with incomes of $40,000 or less. According to CRS estimates of low-wage workers in families with incomes of $40,000 or less were spouses in married-couple families (with or without children). Some 13.4 percent were single parents. Another 11.9 percent were teenagers. Hourly workers who earned less than $7.25 an hour in 2005 were more likely to live in poor families compared to workers paid at least $7.25 an hour (18.1 percent  versus 6.0 percent).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Women were overrepresented among low-wage workers in 2005: almost 7 million of the more than 11 million hourly workers who  earned under $7.25 an hour were women (60.1 percent); in contrast, women accounted for a smaller share of all hourly workers (50.2%). Further, Hispanic women were two times as likely as Hispanic men to earn $5.15 per hour or less.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It also appears that relatively more working women than men might gain from a higher federal minimum wage. An increase in the minimum wage would greatly benefit about 33 percent of African-American or Hispanic women.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over the last five years, the number of African Americans living in poverty has grown by 1.5 million, and the real median household income of African American families is down $2,676. Increasing the minimum wage to $7.25 an hour would affect more than 2.1 million hardworking African Americans in the minimum wage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over the last five years, the number of Hispanic Americans living in poverty has grown by more than 1.6 million and the real median household income of Hispanic American families is down $1,631. Over 2.3 million out of 12.5 million Hispanics employed on an hourly basis--or almost one in five earned less than $7.25 an hour in 2005. Hispanics comprised the largest share of workers paid below $7.25 an hour than they did of all hourly workers in 2005. Raising the minimum wage to $7.25 an hour would  have a positive effect on the lives of more than 2.3 million hardworking Hispanic Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over the last five years, the number of Asian American/Pacific Islanders living in poverty has grown by 243,000 and the real median household income of Asian American/Pacific Islander families is down $2,157. Lifting the minimum wage to $7.25 an hour would have a positive effect on the lives of an estimated 280,000 hardworking Asian American workers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over one-half of hourly workers paid below the proposed federal minimum wage were between 16 and 24 years old. A substantial percentage of young workers might be affected directly if the minimum wage increases. Nearly three out of five teenagers paid an hourly wage might see their earnings increase if the federal standard goes to $7.25 per hour.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We must do more to support families living in poverty and those who are vulnerable to falling into poverty. Increasing the wages is an important step toward reducing the high levels of poverty in this nation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400233" topic="CLOSING REMARKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in strong support of <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill>, legislation that will fulfill our promise to America's working families by providing a long awaited increase in the federal minimum wage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Passage of this bill today will increase the minimum wage for the first time in nearly a decade, from $5.15 to $7.25 per hour over 2 years. Inflation and increased demands on the wallets of American families have steadily chipped away at the purchasing power of our Nation's minimum wage earners, and the failure of the previous Congress to take action has left the federal minimum wage at its lowest value in more than half a century.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation is critical at a time when America's families have seen their real income drop by almost $1,300 since 2000, while the costs of health insurance, gasoline, home heating, and attending college have increased by almost $5,000 annually. At the current level, a full-time minimum wage worker will make only $10,712 a year, nearly $6,000 below the poverty level for a family of three. While some States, such as Connecticut, have already taken action to raise their minimum wage, many more  States still fall short of providing our hardest working Americans with the income they need to make ends meet.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In a Nation of abundant wealth and prosperity, we simply cannot be indifferent to the challenges faced by those struggling to make ends meet. This vote today sends the clear message that this Congress will be committed to America's working families. Passage of <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill> is a critical step towards ensuring that every American is able to earn a real living wage.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="CLOSING REMARKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill>, the Fair Minimum Wage Act of 2007, which proposes to increase the national minimum wage by a modest, but significant $2.10 over the course of roughly 2 years. I urge my colleagues to vote in favor of this legislation for three basic and important reasons.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, an increase in the national minimum wage will help bring a sense of dignity in the lives of the lowest wage earners and their families in our country. American workers deserve to earn fair, decent, and livable wages for their hard and honest labor. They deserve to earn wages that enable them to cope with the costs of the basic necessities in life. National labor statistics reveal that income levels for millions of American workers and their families across every State and territory in  the country have not kept pace with rising costs of home ownership, food, health insurance, gasoline, home heating, and college tuition. Setting a national minimum wage that reflects this reality and that will give families an income from which they can afford the basic necessities in life is a national priority that this Congress will act on today. The current national minimum wage of $5.15 does not measure up to the principle of ensuring hardworking Americans receive a livable wage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second, an increase in the national minimum wage is overdue. The last increase was over 9 years ago in September 1997. The time that has passed since this last increase represents the longest period in American history in which the national minimum wage has remained stagnant. Passage of this legislation today would be timely in the fact that it would set forth incremental increases over a 26-month period to raise the national minimum wage from $5.15 to $7.25.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last, raising the national minimum wage not only enjoys broad, bipartisan support in Congress, but also enjoys support from among average Americans. A majority of voters in six States agreed to measures on their ballots in November 2006 that raised the minimum wage in their State, for instance. Also, workers in 28 States and the District of Columbia earn a minimum wage that is above the current minimum wage provided for by Federal law. An effort to raising the minimum wage earned by American  workers, moreover, is supported by many labor, religious, and civil rights organizations from across the country. Support for increasing the national minimum wage can also be found in my community on Guam. A resolution was introduced in the 29th Guam Legislature this week, which carries the support of all Democratic members of the Guam Legislature, in support of this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am especially encouraged by the fact that the legislation we are considering on the floor today, <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill>, does not preempt Guam law for tipped employees as minimum wage increase legislation that was considered on this floor in the last Congress proposed. Current Guam law requires employers to pay their employees the local minimum wage and, on top of that, to allow them to keep the tips they receive from customers. Deferring to local Guam law that sets a standard minimum wage on our island and  that applies to all wage earners, whether or not they are working in a traditionally tipped field, is important to our workforce and especially important to the employees of our visitor industry.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On July 18, 2006, local legislation was enacted on Guam to increase the minimum wage from $5.15 per hour to $5.75 per hour by July 1, 2007. The legislation on the floor today would effectively raise this minimum wage by another 10 cents within 60 days after its enactment. Over 1,600 workers would receive an immediate and direct boost in their wages as a result of this increase according to local wage statistics compiled by the Guam Department of Labor. Passage of this legislation will allow our  island's workforce, especially those earning the minimum wage, to better meet their families' needs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One's work is something of which one should be proud. It is also something for which one should be fairly compensated. The effort to raise the federal minimum wage requirement is a strong signal of our support and recognition of those workers who earn the minimum wage and the contributions their work has for our society. Congress is overdue in fulfilling this responsibility to America's workers. I encourage continued bipartisan support for this effort to improve the economic prospects of and  livelihoods for America's workforce.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also encourage continued review and consultation with local government on one particular aspect of this legislation as it is considered in the remaining steps of the legislative process. I note that the legislation on the floor today proposes to apply the national minimum wage, for the first time in its history, to the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands (CNMI), which neighbors Guam. This is a significant proposal that should be carefully evaluated, especially in terms of its implementation  and consequences for the economy in the CNMI and the economy on Guam. The bill proposes to increase the current minimum wage in the CNMI from $3.05 to $7.25 through eight individual incremental increases of fifty cents made over the course of four years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The economy in the CNMI is interlinked with the economy on Guam. There will be unique challenges associated with implementing the ambitious schedule of increases to the minimum wage in the CNMI. A possible rise in unemployment and subsequent possible enrollment increases for social services and corresponding budgetary impacts for the Government of the CNMI and the Government of Guam as a result of a federally mandated, aggressive rise in the minimum wage in the CNMI are of concern to me and to  local officials. I share in the belief that the workers in the CNMI deserve a fair wage. I, however, also believe that more coordination with local officials in the CNMI on specific provision should be undertaken.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Resident Representative of CNMI, the Honorable Pedro A. Tenorio, and other locally  elected officials of the CNMI have asked Congress to consider other options that may include a more realistic schedule of increments or a federal wage review board to determine the timing and levels of incremental increases to the minimum wage in the CNMI. These proposals are designed to take into account the consequences for the economy of the CNMI of increasing the  minimum wage. It is important to consider the economic stability that is needed to support jobs and job growth overall in the territory. I support alternatives that would help to mitigate the adverse impact that may occur with the implementation of the federal minimum wage in the CNMI and I hope that this issue could be reviewed in conference on this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I take this opportunity to note the continued absence of representation in this body for the American citizens of the CNMI, and to call attention to the need for such representation. Legislation to grant the people of the CNMI a representative in this House has been introduced in this body in each of the last six Congresses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The House considers difficult issues regarding the CNMI, such as presented in the legislation before us today. This is precisely an example of why both this House and the people of the CNMI would benefit greatly from having a representative from the CNMI seated in this body. There are many issues with regard to the CNMI that deserve to be addressed by this Congress, and that inevitably will be taken up in the weeks and months ahead in committee and on the floor of this body. These issues and  the need to address them, when taken together, point to the need for a Delegate in Congress from the CNMI to represent the people of the CNMI during these important deliberations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I strongly believe that Congress should provide the CNMI a seat in this body. Representation should not be contingent upon good behavior by former or current elected officials. Representation also should not be contingent upon the specific policy positions held by former or current elected officials. Rather, representation for Americans in this House has, and should remain, based upon the traditions of American democracy and fairness. Representation in American democracy is an inalienable right  for American citizens and not one that is contingent upon a litmus test. Unfortunately, today, this House will vote on this legislation without the people of the CNMI having been afforded the democratic right of representation in this body to represent them and their views.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Inevitably, the challenges associated with these difficult issues and that relate to the applicability of federal law to the CNMI will never be overcome in a fair and equitable manner until such time as the Congress affords the people of the CNMI a voice in the legislative process. I urge this House to adopt <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill>, to continue to examine carefully in the legislative process its consequences for the economies of the CNMI and Guam, and to move in the near future to adopt legislation that would  allow for a Delegate from the CNMI to be seated in this body.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> All time for debate has expired.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>I am.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will report the motion to recommit.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> Is there objection to dispensing with further reading of the motion to recommit?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="POINT OF ORDER">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I make a point of order against the motion to recommit. The motion is not germane. For example, the motion contains tax provisions which are clearly outside the jurisdiction of the bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Does the gentleman from California wish to be heard on the point of order?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="POINT OF ORDER">
    <paragraph>Yes, Mr. Speaker, I wish to respond.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, my motion should be ruled germane. The bill before us, brought to the floor under unprecedented circumstances, circumstances that have not been "fair, open, and honest" by any means, would raise the minimum wage mandate by 41 percent, with small businesses and their workers left unprotected.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Considering that more than 7 million new jobs have been created in the last 3 1/2  years, and that two-thirds of all new jobs are provided by small businesses, I ask my colleagues, why in the world would we leave them unprotected and endanger this incredible momentum?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My motion provides a fair alternative that increases the minimum wage in exactly the same manner as the Democratic leadership's bill; expands access to affordable health care by establishing small business health plans; and extends important protections for small businesses and their workers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My motion should be considered not only germane but a proposal far superior to the Democratic leadership's unbalanced minimum wage proposal.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Does the gentleman wish to be recognized for further argument?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="POINT OF ORDER">
    <paragraph>I would simply press the point that the motion to recommit offered by the minority is not germane, and it contains tax provisions and others that are outside the scope of the jurisdiction of the bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Chair is prepared to rule.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="POINT OF ORDER">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to appeal the ruling of the Chair.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is, Shall the decision of the Chair stand as the judgment of the House?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="MOTION TO TABLE OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I object to the vote on the ground that a quorum is not present and make the  point of order that a quorum is not present.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Evidently a quorum is not present.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400270" topic="MOTION TO TABLE OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on rollcall No. 16, on the motion to table the Appeal of the Ruling of the Chair, had I been present, I would have voted "yea."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Stated for:</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400338" topic="MOTION TO TABLE OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on rollcall No. 16 I was unavoidably detained. Had I been present, I would have voted "nay."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is the gentleman opposed to the bill?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>I am, Mr. Speaker.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will report the motion to recommit.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from California?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this motion is straightforward in purpose, but for millions of uninsured Americans, it would be incredibly meaningful in practice. During today's debate, many of us, particularly those on this side of the aisle, have talked about the need to expand access to affordable health care. As I noted earlier, when discussing my comprehensive minimum wage package, I believe this debate presents us a tremendous opportunity, not only to impact wages, but to improve working  families' quality of life as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Therefore, I offer this motion in the same spirit as that comprehensive measure. It would ensure that if an employer offers health coverage to his or her workers, an incredibly costly yet incredibly important employee benefit, then this employer should not be further burdened with a 41 percent minimum wage mandate imposed by <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill>, a mandate thrust upon these employers without any protections at all for small business and their workers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, to speak about the benefits of this proposal, I yield the balance of my time to the gentlewoman from New Mexico (Mrs. WILSON), who has been working this very issue for many years.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400434" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, my colleagues, I would like to tell you about one of my constituents.  Her name is Mary Padilla, and she runs Roadrunner Transmission in Albuquerque, New Mexico. She has five employees, and she has been in business for 7 years, and she provides health insurance for every one of those five employees. Mary tells me that if we raise the minimum wage, she is going to have a tough time continuing to provide health insurance  for her employees, and she may have to make a choice that she doesn't want to make.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mary is not alone. More than 3 million Americans have gotten new jobs in the last 36 months with small businesses. The toughest thing for a small business person to do is to make the payroll and provide health insurance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This motion to recommit would add one provision into this bill on the minimum wage. It would say, if you are an employer who is providing health insurance for your employees, that benefit is worth more than the bump up in the minimum wage, and you would not have to comply with these new rules with respect to the minimum wage. It would stay where it is for your small business.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One of the biggest problems we face as a country is the uninsured population. In my State, about one in four people doesn't have health insurance. This provision would encourage more small and medium-sized businesses to provide health insurance for their employees. A paycheck matters, a paycheck that makes it through the whole week, but it also matters if you are a parent who has to worry every night whether the kids are going to get sick when you cannot pay for it, because you don't have insurance  with your job.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would encourage all of you to support the motion to recommit and support small business health insurance for every employee in America.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in opposition to the motion to recommit.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from California is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <narrative>(Mr. GEORGE MILLER of California asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, and Members of the House, today is a remarkable day, because after 10 years, we are going to have an up-and-down vote on whether the poorest people in our Nation, who are working every day and, at the end of the year, end up poor, deserve a raise. That is what we are going to do today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For 10 years, we have struggled to have this vote, and now we are finally going to have it. We have had a lot of excuses why we couldn't have it. We have had votes hijacked, and we have had votes pulled off the floor, but we could never have this vote. Today, the beginning of the 100 hours, we are going to have this vote. We are going to have this vote, because this is a major concern. This is a major concern to the American society.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What so many of my colleagues made clear today in the debate is that after you have stalled this vote for 10 years, this goes way beyond the dollars and cents of the minimum wage. It goes to the core values of America and economic justice and social justice and fairness and whether or not every American is going to get to participate in the American economic system and also be able to provide for their children and their families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But my colleagues didn't disappoint me today on the other side of the aisle. We have one more bump in the road. This last moment, they have offered us a motion to recommit where they say, if you offer your employees a health care plan, you can keep the minimum wage at $5.15. Now it doesn't say that health care plan has to be affordable. It doesn't say what the deductibles are, the copayments, which I am sure if you are a minimum wage worker at $5.15 today, a wage that is 10 years old, I am sure  you can pay the copayments and the deductibles and the premiums. That will not be a problem.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What is it you don't understand about being poor? What is it you don't understand? You are stuck at $5.15 in today's world. You can't buy the gasoline to go to work, the bread to put on the table, the milk out of the refrigerator. Your utilities are going up. The rent is going up.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now you say, by the way, if you can pay for a health care plan, you can stay at the minimum wage, you lucky ducky. I don't think that is what America was talking about when 89 percent of them said they want this Congress to raise the minimum wage, not trade it in, not trade it in.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>They didn't ask us to trade in the increase in the minimum wage for some phantom health care proposal. You know what the average premium is for a family? The average premium is $10,880. Okay. That is good plans and bad plans together. Cut it in half. You are at the minimum wage. You have got to pay $5,000? Cut it in half again. You are at the minimum wage. You can pay another $2,000 for your health care? I don't think so. I don't think so. Let us get on with the Nation's business, with the people's  business, and with the minimum-wage workers' business. Let us reject this motion and pass this bill now.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the previous question is ordered on the motion to recommit.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I demand a recorded vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 9 of rule XX, the Chair will reduce to 5 minutes the minimum time for any electronic vote on the question of passage.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400242" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I demand a recorded vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 5-minute vote.</chair>
</record>
