<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1205164802" ordinal="21" title="STEVE W. ALLEE CARRIER ANNEX">
  <narrative>STEVE W. ALLEE CARRIER ANNEX -- (House of Representatives - March 10, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H1424]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="4166">H.R. 4166</bill>) to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 701 East Copeland Drive in Lebanon, Missouri, as the "Steve W. Allee Carrier Annex".</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="4166">H.R. 4166</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative>Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,</narrative>
  <narrative>(a) Designation.--The facility of the United States Postal Service located at 701 East Copeland Drive in Lebanon, Missouri, shall be known and designated as the "Steve W. Allee Carrier Annex".</narrative>
  <narrative>(b) REFERENCES.--Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the facility referred to in subsection (a) shall be deemed to be a reference to the "Steve W. Allee Carrier Annex".</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Davis) and the gentleman from Georgia (Mr. Westmoreland) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Illinois.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Illinois?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield such time as he may consume to the honorable gentleman from Missouri (Mr. Skelton), the author of this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400377" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I certainly thank the gentleman for yielding and giving me this opportunity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It goes without saying that the United States Postal Service has an historic reputation for excellence and unyielding dedication to the people of our Nation. "Neither snow nor rain nor heat nor gloom of night stays these carriers from the swift completion of their appointed rounds" are the words engraved on the outside of the James A. Farley Post Office Building in New York City. Every day, thousands of postal employees proudly wear the uniform of the United States Postal Service with the understanding  of the enormity of this commitment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, Madam Speaker, I stand before the House in support of <bill type="h" number="4166">H.R. 4166</bill>, a bill I introduced to pay tribute to the life of one of those public servants, Mr. Steven W. Allee of Stoutland, Missouri, and a rural mail carrier for the citizens of Lebanon, Missouri.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since 1989, Mr. Steve Allee held a full-time position as a rural carrier at the Lebanon, Missouri, Post Office. He was a dedicated employee, a loving family man to his wife Debbie, his children and his grandchildren, a member of the Buffalo Prairie Baptist Church, and a friend to many.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Tragically, Madam Speaker, on August 20, 2007, Mr. Allee was killed in the line of duty when his vehicle was swept away by floodwaters in rural Lebanon. This flash flood was unprecedented in its magnitude. As Mr. Allee completed his route, he approached a country bridge under which a typically dry creekbed usually lies. However, on this day, the rapidly falling rainwater had overtaken the bridge. When Mr. Allee attempted to cross, his vehicle was swept away.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, I urge the House of Representatives to honor this man for his public service and his commitment to his community. Let us pay our respects to his personal and postal family by designating the facility, the United States Postal Service located at 701 East Copeland Drive in Lebanon, Missouri, as the Steve W. Allee Carrier Annex.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400627" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In his hometown of Lebanon, Missouri, Steve Allee was known not just as a rural postal carrier at the Lebanon Post Office, but also as a dear friend and loving family man. He came from a family of letter carriers. His father was a highway contract driver, and his cousin is the postmaster in Stoutland, Missouri.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Allee was a dedicated post office employee for over 15 years until the tragic loss of his life while on the job on August 20, 2007. On that tragic day, Mr. Allee was going about his daily routine of delivering mail until a torrential rainstorm began. He was attempting to cross a bridge over what is normally a dry creekbed, but due to the rainfall, the creek had become flooded. Mr. Allee perished as his vehicle was washed away in the rush of water. This serves as an example of how public servants  in the course of their everyday duties are sometimes thrust into dangerous and, in this case, deadly circumstances.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We acknowledge Mr. Allee's service and his sacrifice. He will be deeply missed by all the people's lives that he touched.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With this, I ask my colleagues to join me in support of this fitting tribute to a dedicated postal employee who lost his life in the line of duty.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, as a member of the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, I am pleased to join my colleagues from the great State of Missouri in the consideration of <bill type="h" number="4166">H.R. 4166</bill>, which names the postal facility in Lebanon, Missouri, after Steve W. Allee, a dedicated and long-serving United States postal worker.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="4166">H.R. 4166</bill>, which was introduced by Representative Ike Skelton of Missouri on November 13, 2007, was considered and reported from the Oversight Committee on February 26, 2008, by a voice vote. The measure has the support of the entire congressional delegation from Missouri and provides us with yet another opportunity to pay tribute to an American citizen whose life was taken while simply performing his professional duties of delivering the mail.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The story of Mr. Allee's tragic death begins on Monday, August 20, 2007, where, according to a Missouri State Highway Patrol report, at 2 p.m. in Laclede County, 10 miles east of Lebanon, Missouri, a 2003 Chevy Blazer driven by Steve Allee, 51, of Stoutland, Missouri, came upon a flooded roadway and was swept away as a result of flooding on the Missouri River.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>Allee, who was on duty during the accident, was found 2 miles downstream and pronounced dead at the scene.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At the urging of Representative Skelton, passage of <bill type="h" number="4166">H.R. 4166</bill> will allow Congress to make in order a small tribute to this big-hearted individual, a United States postal carrier himself. Mr. Allee had been delivering mail since 1989, when he succumbed to his death as a result of the Missouri River overrunning its banks last fall.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let us also remember and express our gratitude for the life of this dedicated postal worker, who was tragically taken from us by a force of nature while performing his vocation of delivering the mail, by passing <bill type="h" number="4166">H.R. 4166</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank Representative IKE SKELTON for moving to honor this gentleman for the work that he not only did but for the life that he gave.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Davis) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="4166">H.R. 4166</bill>.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400627" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this motion will be postponed.</chair>
</record>
