<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1182182403" ordinal="35" title="EXPANDING AND IMPROVING ASSISTANCE PROVIDED BY SMALL BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT CENTERS">
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from New York (Ms. Vel&#xE1;zquez) and the gentleman from Tennessee (Mr. David Davis) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412235" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, today I rise in support of the request to suspend the rules and pass <bill type="h" number="2284">H.R. 2284</bill>, a bill to provide additional Small Business Development Center resources focused on Native Americans, Alaskan Natives and Native Hawaiians. The bill, the product and dedicated effort of the author, Congressman Tom Udall, former Small Business Committee member, was passed without objection by voice vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to thank Chairwoman Vel&#xE1;zquez for working in a cooperative and bipartisan manner to bring this matter to the House floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ms. VEL&#xC1;ZQUEZ. Mr. Speaker, I yield such time as he may consume to the gentleman from New Mexico (Mr. Udall), the sponsor of the legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Mr. UDALL of New Mexico asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400413" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, before I begin, I would like to thank the gentlewoman from New York (Ms. Vel&#xE1;zquez) and the gentleman from Ohio (Mr. Chabot) for their work and commitment to expanding small business opportunities. I am especially grateful for their efforts to bring this bill to the floor today. I would also like to thank all my colleagues who supported this bill by joining me as cosponsors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This important legislation before us today, <bill type="h" number="2284">H.R. 2284</bill>, allows Small Business Development Centers to apply for an additional SBA grant to provide specified services assisting small business start-ups and expansions owned by Indian Tribal Members, Alaskan Natives or Native Hawaiians. My bill ensures those seeking to create, develop and expand small businesses have full access to the counseling and technical assistance available through SBDCs. The tools offered by the SBDCs can assist these entrepreneurs  with the information and opportunity to build sustainable businesses in their communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2284">H.R. 2284</bill> also ensures participation of governing bodies of Indian tribes, Alaskan Native entities and Native Hawaiian organizations by requiring grant recipients to request their advice on how best to provide assistance. Our intent is to ensure that these business development tools are provided in a culturally sensitive way.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Small businesses create 75 percent of all new employment opportunities and make up 99 percent of all employers. They anchor our neighborhoods, provide jobs and contribute to the overall economic development of many communities. That is why it is so imperative that we take steps to help ensure that small business development reaches the places in this country where economic prosperity has yet to be fully realized.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have the great honor of representing 14 Pueblos, the Jicarilla Apache Nation and a portion of the Navajo Nation. Many of these communities would greatly benefit by more economic development. It is clear we can do more to aid Native American entrepreneurs in my district and throughout the country. I hope to help rectify this situation with the passage of this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412235" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no further speakers, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ms. VEL&#xC1;ZQUEZ. Mr. Speaker, in closing, with unemployment rampant on Native American reservations, legislation that not only fights poverty but fosters the development of job creation is critical. I strongly urge my colleagues to vote for <bill type="h" number="2284">H.R. 2284</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of <bill type="h" number="2284">H.R. 2284</bill>, a bill to amend the Small Business Act to expand and improve the assistance provided by Small Business Development Centers to Indian tribe members, Alaska Natives, and Native Hawaiians. I commend the gentleman from New Mexico (Mr. Udall) for introducing this important legislation to address poverty and unemployment amongst these disadvantaged and underserved communities. I also thank my colleague from New York (Ms. Vel&#xE1;zquez),  Chairwoman of the Committee on Small Business, and the members of the Committee on Small Business for their continued leadership toward helping strengthen our country's small businesses and in addressing the socioeconomic challenges faced by our indigenous communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2284">H.R. 2284</bill> will enable small business development centers to assist Native American communities in the areas of job creation and economic growth. This bill helps individuals to utilize their own valuable business skills so that their small businesses, and in turn their community, may prosper.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a strong bill. But I believe that it can strengthened by expanding the eligible grant recipients to include small business development centers that work with the indigenous populations of the territories, particularly in Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and American Samoa. Pacific Islanders from the territories endure economic adversity similar to that experienced by Native Americans, Alaska Natives, and Native Hawaiians. I look forward to working with my colleagues  to ensure that either in conference on this legislation, or on a similar proposal, that we take action to address the small business development needs of the indigenous peoples of the U.S. territories.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill, if enacted, would provide for valuable federal assistance for Native Americans, and I urge my colleagues to support its passage and to support economic development for all indigenous communities throughout the United States.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412200" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="2284">H.R. 2284</bill>, which will amend the Small Business Act to improve the assistance provided by Small Business Development Centers to Indian tribe members, Alaska Natives and Native Hawaiians.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill will provide management, technical and research assistance to small businesses owned by Indian tribe members, Alaska Natives and Native Hawaiians and ensure them full access to existing business counseling and technical assistance available through the Small Business Development Center program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, in a recent report by the distinguished Visiting Senior Fellow at the East-West Center and Emeritus Professor at the University Hawaii, Dr. Seiji Naya, the poverty rate for Native Hawaiians was 15 percent in 2005 while the state average was 9.8 percent. Native Hawaiians accounted for 27 percent of the total State population in poverty. The per capita income for Native Hawaiians was only 67 percent of the state average. In terms of per capita income, 32 percent of Native Hawaiians  earned less than $10,000 in 2005 compared to only 18 percent for Non-Native Hawaiians.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Native Hawaiians are committed to changing these statistics through innovative educational and entrepreneurial programs. One of the most promising government programs that will enable them to do this is the Small Business Act, particularly Section 8(a) which has given Native Americans an opportunity to participate in the economy of this country by providing a fair chance to obtain federal contracts. As a result, hundreds of Native American, Alaska Native and Native Hawaiian entrepreneurs have  been given the opportunity to demonstrate their business capabilities, while providing valuable services and products to the government and the private sector.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Native Hawaiian organizations that have taken advantage of the 8(a) program have provided hundreds of new well-paying jobs for Native Hawaiians and Non-Native Hawaiians alike. Many Native Hawaiians have received training in new marketable skills. The profits from these enterprises have been plowed back into the Native Hawaiian communities to provide essential social, health and cultural benefits traditionally funded by government or not at all.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2284">H.R. 2284</bill> will provide the necessary assistance to help make sure that these worthy programs continue to grow and expand as much as possible by providing needed assistance and business expertise. I urge unanimous approval of this measure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ms. VEL&#xC1;ZQUEZ. Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time, and encourage adoption of the resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from New York (Ms. Vel&#xE1;zquez) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="2284">H.R. 2284</bill>.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400651" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this question will be postponed.</chair>
</record>
