<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1190044802" ordinal="17" title="EXTENDING THE AUTHORITIES OF THE OVERSEAS PRIVATE INVESTMENT CORPORATION">
  <narrative>EXTENDING THE AUTHORITIES OF THE OVERSEAS PRIVATE INVESTMENT CORPORATION -- (House of Representatives - September 17, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H10384]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400128" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="3527">H.R. 3527</bill>) to extend for two months the authorities of the Overseas Private Investment Corporation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="3527">H.R. 3527</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. TEMPORARY EXTENSION OF OPIC PROGRAMS.</narrative>
  <narrative> Section 235(a)(2) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (22 U.S.C. 2195(a)(2)) is amended by striking "September 30, 2007" and inserting "November 30, 2007".&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from American Samoa (Mr. Faleomavaega) and the gentleman from New Jersey (Mr. Smith) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from American Samoa.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400128" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that Members may have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on <bill type="h" number="3527">H.R. 3527</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from American Samoa?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400128" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in strong support of this legislation and yield myself as much time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This House recently approved legislation that would reauthorize the Overseas Private Investment Corporation for an additional 4 years. The bill would ensure that OPIC continues its critical mission of supporting private investment to accomplish important public sector goals in the developing world, while, at the same time, enhancing OPIC's transparency and accountability.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senate is considering similar legislation, Mr. Speaker, and the Foreign Affairs Committee looks forward to working with that body so that we can send the bill to the President for his signature.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While the Senate considers this legislation, OPIC's current authority expires at the end of this month. In order to provide the Senate with additional time to take up this legislation and ensure that the corporation continues its critical work, my friend and colleague, the good chairman of the subcommittee, Mr. Sherman from California, has crafted this proposed bill that provides OPIC with the authority to operate for an additional 2 months beyond September 30, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>I do want to commend our distinguished chairman of the committee, Mr. Lantos; and our senior ranking member, Ms. Ros-Lehtinen, for their support and leadership in bringing this legislation to the floor. I recommend this legislation for passage, and I urge my colleagues to support this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400380" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise in support of the bill, <bill type="h" number="3527">H.R. 3527</bill>, a bill that would extend the authorization of the Overseas Private Investment Corporation until November 30 of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on July 23, as my good friend Mr. Faleomavaega just said, the House passed <bill type="h" number="2798">H.R. 2798</bill>, a bill to reauthorize OPIC through September 30 of 2011. That measure had previously been favorably reported by the House Committee on Foreign Affairs by a vote of 26-5, totally bipartisan. To date, however, the other body has not acted, requiring us to take this stop-gap measure to continue the authorization for this legislation. We hope they act soon on the Senate side so that the President  can be sent a bipartisan bill that can be signed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400128" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no further requests for time, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from American Samoa (Mr. Faleomavaega) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="3527">H.R. 3527</bill>.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400627" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this motion will be postponed.</chair>
</record>
