<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1173114004" ordinal="22" title="BRIGADIER GENERAL FRANCIS MARION MEMORIAL ACT OF 2007">
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="497">H.R. 497</bill>) to authorize the Marion Park Project, a committee of the Palmetto Conservation Foundation, to establish a commemorative work on Federal land in the District of Columbia, and its environs to honor Brigadier General Francis Marion.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) and the gentleman from Utah (Mr. Bishop) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Arizona?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, Brigadier General Francis Marion commanded the Williamsburg Militia Revolutionary Force in South Carolina during the Revolutionary War.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He is distinguished for his innovative warfare techniques, his pivotal victory at Eutaw Springs in September 1781, and for his commanding the first racially integrated troop force. General Marion is perhaps even better known by the nickname given to him by an exasperated British commander, the Swamp Fox.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="497">H.R. 497</bill>, introduced by Representative JOE WILSON, would authorize a private entity, the Marion Park Project, to establish a commemorative work in Washington, D.C., to honor General Marion. The memorial is to be established pursuant to the Commemorative Works Act and is to be privately funded.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the House approved identical legislation in the last Congress, and we strongly support <bill type="h" number="497">H.R. 497</bill> today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400029" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume, and I rise to support <bill type="h" number="497">H.R. 497</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="497">H.R. 497</bill>, introduced by Congressman JOE WILSON of South Carolina, would  authorize the Marion Park Project to establish a commemorative work on Federal land in the District of Columbia to honor Brigadier General Francis Marion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The work authorized by this legislation will be completed with private funds provided by the Marion Park Project and not by the Federal Government. Congressman JOE WILSON and Congressman HENRY BROWN should be commended for sending us such an outstanding bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support <bill type="h" number="497">H.R. 497</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I am pleased to yield as much time as he may consume for this wonderful project honoring General Francis Marion, better known as the Swamp Fox in the Revolutionary War, to the distinguished gentleman from South Carolina (Mr. Brown).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400049" topic="">
    <paragraph>I certainly thank my good friend for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, <bill type="h" number="497">H.R. 497</bill> is an important bill for my constituents in South Carolina's First Congressional District. I thank my colleague and friend Congressman Joe Wilson for introducing this important piece of legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>General Francis Marion is an important part of the history of South Carolina, and the national forest bearing his name is located within my congressional district.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Francis Marion commanded the only Revolutionary force in South Carolina and was instrumental in delaying the advance of British forces by leading his troops in disrupting supply lines. General Marion's tactics, which were unheard of in rules of war at this time, commanded lightning raids on British convoys, and then he and his forces would retreat into the swamps to avoid capture.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>British General Tarleton stated that "as for this damned old swamp fox, the devil himself could not catch him." Thus, the legend of the Swamp Fox was born. His victory at the Battle of Eutaw Springs in September of 1781 was officially recognized by Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="497">H.R. 497</bill> seeks to authorize the Marion Park Project and the committee of the Palmetto Conservation Foundation to establish a statue of General Francis Marion on Federal lands in D.C. in Marion Park at no Federal Government expense.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I was proud to work with Natural Resources Chairman NICK RAHALL and Ranking Republican DON YOUNG to assist in the passage of this bill for my constituents of South Carolina's First Congressional District and for all of South Carolina, and I urge my colleagues to support <bill type="h" number="497">H.R. 497</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400029" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, anything that deals with some place called Eutaw Springs in South Carolina has to be a good project. I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, let me thank Congressman Wilson for this legislation, Mr. Brown as well, Mr. Clyburn, Mr. Spratt and Mr. Barrett from South Carolina for introducing the bill that we have just finished.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also want to, before I yield back, thank the gentleman from Utah, the ranking member, for assisting in bringing the pieces of legislation we had today forward.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400433" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I am pleased we are today considering the "Brigadier General Francis Marion Memorial Act". It is with the support of the entire South Carolina delegation that I reintroduced this legislation in January.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Brigadier General Francis Marion well represented the State of South Carolina and our fledgling Nation with his brave service in the Revolutionary War. As a South Carolinian, I am proud his legacy has been honored with a memorial park in Washington, DC. Yet, I feel strongly that a statue of the "Swamp Fox" should be erected on its premises. Passage of this bill is a crucial first step in making this dream a reality.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would specifically like to thank Ken Driggers and Nancy Stone-Collum of the Palmetto Conservation Foundation. Additionally, I would like to thank the South Carolina Humanities Council for supporting John McCabe, the historian who originally had the vision to honor the "Swamp Fox." John created the Francis Marion Park Project to assist with fundraising and planning once this bill is enacted. The National Park Service also deserves recognition for their guidance through this important process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The House of Representatives originally passed this bill in the 109th Congress, yet it failed to be considered by the Senate. It is my hope we can enact this legislation during the 110th Congress and erect a memorial befitting General Marion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today I was presented a copy of The South Carolina Encyclopedia, edited by the noted historian Walter Edgar. The book is a project of The Humanities Council, ably led by Director Randy Akers. Presenting the book was Bob Hazel of West Columbia who is former Council Board Chair who was elected to the board of the Federation of State Humanities Councils. South Carolina was the site of more battles and skirmishes than any other province during the American Revolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>General Francis Marion is a significant entry in the encyclopedia with highlights beginning on page 591:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Marion, Francis (1732-1792). Soldier. Marion, of Huguenot descent, was born in St. John's Berkley Parish, the youngest of six children born to Gabriel Marion and Esther Cordes. A planter, Marion in 1773 built his home, Pond Bluff, about four miles south of Eutaw Springs, a site now beneath the waters of Lake Marion. He commenced his military career in the parish militia in 1756 and joined the campaigns against the Cherokees (1759-1761), rising to the rank of first lieutenant. Having served in  local offices, he was elected in 1775 to the First Provincial Congress. Commissioned a captain in the state's Second Regiment in June, he participated in the capture of Fort Johnson in September. As a major, Marion distinguished himself at the Battle of Sullivan's Island (June 1776), after which he was commissioned a lieutenant colonel in the Continental army.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With a militia commission as a brigadier general, Marion organized a partisan force in the Pee Dee region. Between August and December 1780, in an otherwise dismal period for America, Marion gained national recognition for his actions at the Great Savannah (August 20), Blue Savannah (September 4), Black Mingo (September 29), Tearcoat Swamp (October 26), Georgetown (November 15), and Halfway Swamp (December 12-13). While some counts place the number of "Marion's Men" at more  than two thousand, his band generally consisted of considerably fewer than that and included Continentals. Marion's nickname, the "Swamp Fox," reportedly came from the infamous British officer Banastre Tarleton, who, unable to snare Marion, called him a "damned old fox" and swore that "the devil himself could not catch him."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Marion's small-scale hit-and-run tactics disrupted supply lines, intercepted communications, and hampered the enemy considerably. In December 1780 he established a camp on Snow's Island between Pee Dee and Lynches Rivers and Clark's Creek. Conditions improved by the spring of 1781, when Marion became a vital part of General Nathanael Greene's combined operations in South Carolina. In 1781 Marion's troops participated in the battles at Fort Watson (April 23), Fort Motte (May 12), Quinby Bridge</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After a penniless Marion, whose plantation had been ruined, was awarded a gold medal, a full Continental colonelcy, and command of Fort Johnson in Charleston harbor. He served in the S.C. Senate in 1783-1786, 1791, and 1792-1794 and was elected to the 1790 state constitutional convention.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support <bill type="h" number="497">H.R. 497</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="497">H.R. 497</bill>.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this question will be postponed.</chair>
</record>
