<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1181059208" ordinal="18" title="SUPPORTING THE GOALS AND IDEALS OF NATIONAL TRAILS DAY">
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution (<bill type="hr" number="401">H. Res. 401</bill>) supporting the goals and ideals of National Trails Day.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the resolution.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from the Virgin Islands (Mrs. Christensen) and the gentleman from Utah (Mr. Cannon) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the resolution under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from the Virgin Islands?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>House Resolution 401 was introduced by the gentleman from California (Mr. Thompson). It expresses the support of the House of Representatives of the goals and ideals of National Trails Day.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to commend Representative Thompson for his efforts to bring congressional recognition to this important annual event. This resolution is timely, given that the 15th anniversary celebration of National Trails Day was this past Saturday.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>National Trails Day is a long-standing event that is dedicated to celebrating, promoting, and protecting America's magnificent trail system. It was started by the American Hiking Society in 1993. Its goals are to raise awareness of trail, to celebrate our incredible national network of trails, and to honor and thank trail volunteers and partners.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>National Trails Day events take place in local, State, and Federal public lands from coast to coast. Activities include hiking, biking, horseback riding, trail dedications, workshops, park clean-ups, trail work projects, and much, much more.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last year, more than 100,000 trail enthusiasts across the country participated in over 1,000 National Trails Day events. At those events, volunteers contributed nearly 150,000 hours of labor to establishing, maintaining, and cleaning up trails across the country. Trail events take place in all 50 States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, Guam and my district, the U.S. Virgin Islands. Many Federal agencies, non-profits, local groups, and corporate sponsors are all proud partners in supporting  this annual event.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, House Resolution 401 honors the contributions that National Trails Day has made to inspire the public to discover, learn about, maintain and celebrate trails. I urge my colleagues to support this resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume and rise in support of House Resolution 401.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>House Resolution 401 has been adequately explained by the majority. I thank the gentlelady, and urge adoption of this resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from the Virgin Islands (Mrs. Christensen) that the House suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, <bill type="hr" number="401">H. Res. 401</bill>.</chair>
</record>
