<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1179331205" ordinal="24" title="PROVIDING FOR CONSIDERATION OF H.R. 1585, NATIONAL DEFENSE AUTHORIZATION ACT FOR FISCAL YEAR 2008">
  <chair> The time remaining in the debate on the rule, the gentlewoman from Florida (Ms. Castor) controls 4 minutes, the gentleman from Washington (Mr. Hastings) controls 9 1/2  minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400171" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I'd ask my friend from Florida how many speakers she has on her side.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412195" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I have one remaining speaker before the close, so I'll reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400171" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I'm pleased to yield 2 minutes to the gentleman from Kansas (Mr. Tiahrt).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400405" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I rise today to speak against this rule. There are two provisions in this bill regarding specialty metals that will make a bad situation worse. I offered two amendments to help correct this problem but, unfortunately, the majority did not allow either of the amendments. As a result, the Democrat majority will force high quality union jobs overseas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My amendment would have also addressed the problems with the specialty metals and the country of origin specialty metals problem.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Can you believe that today we simply exempt foreign suppliers from the specialty metals provisions. If a product containing specialty metals comes from 18 other countries like France, Germany or Canada, they simply do not have to comply.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This provision is a competitive disadvantage for American industry and American workers. And here's how it works today. Caterpillar makes diesel engines for the Army. These are very common, commercially available engines that operate in civilian construction and trucking industry all over the world. This engine is manufactured by American workers in their Greenville, South Carolina plant.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But Caterpillar also manufactures the very same engine in Belgium. Because of the world demand, Belgium is also a qualifying country. That means that if Caterpillar makes an engine for the MRAP in South Carolina, they must go through the expensive process of documenting the nation of origin of the specialty metals content of every component in the engine. Or they could simply shift the production to Belgium and avoid the process and save money. This puts American jobs at risk because of this  outdated legislation, and this rule denies us the ability to protect American workers in this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It's simply unconscionable that we would legislate a competitive disadvantage upon American companies and American workers. And it's even more disheartening that Congress refuses to address the unintended consequences of this decade old problem.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DOD should be leveraging the industrial might of the United States to provide the best technology for our soldiers. But we're denied that ability in this rule.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412195" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield 1 minute to the gentleman from Rhode Island (Mr. Langevin).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400230" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I rise in strong support of the rule and the underlying bill. I know Chairman Skelton and Ranking Member Hunter have worked exceptionally hard on this bipartisan measure, and I thank them for their leadership.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our operations in Iraq and Afghanistan have put great strain on our military, and this bill will reverse the decline in readiness. It adds funds for force protection programs such as mine resistant combat vehicles, IED countermeasures and body armor and a much deserved pay raise for the troops.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I'm also pleased that the measure recognizes the importance of submarines to our national security by adding $588 million to construct a second Virginia-class submarine as early as 2009, 3 years earlier than planned. This is welcome news to the men and woman at Electric Boat in Rhode Island, as well as Groton, Connecticut, as well as our entire submarine industrial base, which is threatened by an insufficient workload. The Navy's current shipbuilding plan would have our submarine fleet  drop to dangerously low levels in future years, just as other nations are increasing their naval capabilities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I've been working exceptionally hard for 6 years to address this important national security issue, and I thank Chairman Skelton and Seapower Chairman Taylor for their commitment to a robust submarine force.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a good bill and a good rule and, Madam Speaker, I urge its passage. And I thank my colleague for the time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The rule before us makes in order an amendment I am offering with the gentleman from Maine, Mr. MICHAUD, that would require military pharmacies to include emergency contraception in the basic core formulary. Access  to this contraception is important to our servicewomen--particularly those who have been the victims of sexual assault--and I urge my colleagues to support our amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We can show our appreciation for all the men and women who keep our Nation safe by voting for this rule and the defense authorization act.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400171" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I am pleased to yield 2 minutes to the gentleman from Oklahoma, a member of the Armed Services Committee, Mr. Cole.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400077" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I rise today in opposition to the rule. As a member of the House Armed Services Committee and having formerly served on the Rules Committee, I'm both disappointed and disturbed by the manner in which the rule has been reported to the floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let's be forthright about this, Madam Speaker. The committee authorized an enormous number of amendments. But numbers alone do not translate into meaningful policy options and good debate on the floor of this body.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let's look at a couple of things that the committee chose not to make in order. The committee did not make in order an amendment by Mr. Akin that addresses important concerns, including the evisceration of the Army's only modernization effort and reducing by $867 million the Future Combat System.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The committee did not make in order many of the amendments that were necessary to address the evisceration of our Missile Defense System and that, Madam Speaker, at a time when our intelligence tells us the North Koreans and the Iranians are continuing to develop dangerous missile capability.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With respect to the underlying legislation itself, Madam Speaker, Chairman Skelton was given an incredibly difficult job. He was not given enough money, in my opinion, enough authorizing authority to address all the needs that he faced.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nevertheless, he and Ranking Member Hunter and their subcommittee chairmen accomplished some important things that we should not lose sight of. One good thing that was accomplished was the increase in the end strength of both the Army and the Marine Corps, something many of us have long advocated, something the President now agrees to and something I'm glad to see underway.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Additionally, the legislation included the Wounded Warriors Act, and also included my language to create a program for pre- and post-deployment neurocognitive assessments of our servicemen. I think that was a very good thing, and I appreciate the chairman for working with us on that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The underlying legislation also addresses depot concerns and maintenance in a way that encourages me, that increased the amount of money in depot accounts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And finally, I was happy to see that the majority continues to recognize, as we do, the importance of developing the non-line-of-sight cannon and remains committed to the new field increase.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With that, I still remain disappointed the rule did not allow the options.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412195" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I am pleased to yield 1 minute to the distinguished gentleman from Massachusetts (Mr. Markey).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400253" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I thank the gentlewoman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a very important bill. Amongst other things it is because for the first time the Department of Defense is required to consider the effects of global warming on Defense Department facilities, capabilities, and missions. It requires that the Department of Defense in three central defense planning documents, the National Security Strategy, the National Defense Strategy, and the Quadrennial Defense Review, look at the impacts of global warming on the facilities and capabilities of the United  States military.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a central issue. I am the chairman of the Select Committee on Global Warming. We had testifying before us General Gordon Sullivan, representing 11 three-and four-star admirals and generals who are all very concerned that this issue of global warming has major national security implications for the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By including this requirement in this bill, we are beginning to focus upon the long-term needs that we have to focus on in order to protect our country and give the resources to the Department of Defense.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I rise today in support of this rule, and in strong support of a provision within the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008 which requires, for the first time, the Department of Defense to consider the effect of global warming on Department facilities, capabilities, and missions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I commend Chairman SKELTON for including this important language, which will allow our armed forces to begin preparing, in a strategic, Department-wide manner, for the impact that global warming could have on our national security.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This provision requires the threat of global warming to be assessed, and guidance for military planners to be issued, in the next versions of three central defense planning documents: The National Security Strategy, The National Defense Strategy, and the Quadrennial Defense Review.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The very first hearing of the new Select Committee on Energy Independence and Global Warming focused on the geopolitical and security consequences of our dependence on foreign energy and the looming threat of global warming. We heard from former Chief of Staff of the Army General Gordon Sullivan, who presented a report by eleven retired three- and four-star generals and admirals arguing that global warming is a grave national security threat, and must be treated as such by our defense establishment  and by this Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last month, Congressman BARTLETT and I introduced the Global Climate Change Security Oversight Act, with the intention of jump-starting our government's analysis of and preparation for the national security consequences of global warming. Our bill would require a National Intelligence Estimate on the impact of global warming, and last week exactly such an NIE was mandated by the Intelligence Authorization bill. Our bill also encourages the Department of Defense to integrate into our defense  planning the threats posed by global warming, and I am very pleased that this priority is being mandated in this year's Defense Authorization Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thinking about global warming as a national security issue is new for many Members, but with the speed that the major provisions of the Global Climate Change Security Oversight Act have been adopted by this House, I feel confident that the Congress is making progress in broadening how we think about global warming. It is crucial for the national security of this country that the Congress continue along this path. We must push our defense and intelligence communities to address this threat, and  we must offer, debate, and implement solutions to the underlying problem.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am also pleased to support and cosponsor an amendment that will be offered during debate on this bill by the gentleman from Illinois, Mr. LIPINSKI, which would require the use of high efficiency light bulb in Department of Defense buildings when new bulbs are installed or old bulbs are replaced. This amendment will help lower energy consumption in Defense Department facilities, reduce greenhouse gas emissions, help promote energy independence, and result in millions of dollars of savings  for the American taxpayer--all without impeding the operations of the U.S. military.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge adoption of the Rule.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400171" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I am pleased to yield 2 minutes to the gentleman from Iowa, a member of the Appropriations Committee (Mr. Latham).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400234" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I thank the gentleman from Washington for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise today in strong opposition to this rule, and there is one very good reason. Partisanship has reached an unconscionable level in this House.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Just for the simple fact that I am in the minority party, the Rules Committee did not allow an amendment which would have given a 9-year-old child from my district access to the death gratuity that her mother wanted her to have when she was killed in Iraq, just for partisan reasons.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Susan Jaenke, the mother of Jaimie Jaenke, who was killed in Iraq, along with her granddaughter, Kayla, came to Washington at great expense and trouble and testified before the Veterans' Affairs Subcommittee. There was broad bipartisan support for an amendment that would simply allow access to the death gratuity of Jaimie Jaenke by her daughter.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is outrageous, the fact that you would deny a 9-year-old child access. Her grandparents don't have the money to raise this child. She has no spouse. It would not cost a dime. It is the right thing to do. In the committee, on a bipartisan basis, people said they would do anything possible to help in this situation. I brought this before the Rules  Committee and explained what is going on, how this child is denied access to funding so that she can  have a decent life; and it was denied simply for partisan reasons. I would think you would be ashamed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And this is not just a single case. There are at least 143 cases exactly like this. And to deny a child access to this benefit is simply outrageous.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Vote against this outrageous rule.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412195" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400171" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I am pleased to yield 2 minutes to the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Flake).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400134" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise in opposition to the rule.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The authorizing committee saw fit to include some 680 earmarks that we got news of just yesterday in the bill. Yet I offered four amendments to debate these earmarks and wasn't allowed any of them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If they can allow 680 earmarks at the last minute in a bill, you would think that the Rules Committee could have seen fit to at least allow debate on a few of them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The earmarks include $5 million for Diminishing Manufacturing Sources for Automation Alley in Troy, Michigan; $2 million for the Physician Order Entry Initiative for Mission Hospitals, which is a private hospital in Asheville, North Carolina, and keep in mind this is a Defense authorization bill here; $10 million for Hunters Point Naval Shipyard, a former naval shipyard being economically revitalized with taxpayer dollars, defense dollars, for the city of San Francisco; and $500,000 for Rapid  Identification of Technology Sources for the San Diego East County Economic Development Council.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our role here should be to ensure that our Defense dollars are spent on defense, not economic revitalization, not nondefense private ventures. That is why these amendments were offered. Unfortunately, the only shot we might have at checking these amendments is in the appropriations process. By the time we get there, the Members will say these projects were authorized, implying that there was some sort of scrutiny given when there surely has not been.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, unfortunately, we cannot support this rule. It doesn't allow debate on any of the 680 earmarks in the bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400171" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield myself the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I will be asking for a "no" vote on the previous question so that I can amend section 2(c) of this rule after "shall not be subject to amendment" and insert "(except the amendment numbered 43 in the report, to be offered by Representative Michaud of Maine, or his designee)."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By defeating the previous question, Members will be able to offer amendments to the Michaud amendment, and a full and wide range of views can be discussed. Those rules were denied because we were not allowed to offer secondary amendments, at least, to the Rules Committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I ask unanimous consent to insert the text of the amendment and extraneous material immediately prior to the vote on the previous question.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Washington?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400171" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412195" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield myself the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To my colleagues on the Armed Services Committee, I thank you for your diligence and hard work. Great thanks also to the professional staff of the Armed Services Committee. And I think we all must salute the great leadership of Chairman Ike Skelton, who produced a bipartisan product that passed that committee 58-0.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I urge this Congress to chart a new direction today for a stronger and safer America. We will improve the readiness of our Armed Forces, including the National Guard and Reserves. We will put a stop on the blank check given to the White House by previous Congresses for the war in Iraq and, instead, require greater accountability for operations and contracting in the region. We will drive more strategic decisions and investments to better protect our national security.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With that, Madam Speaker, I urge a "yes" vote on the previous question and on the rule.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The material previously referred to by Mr. Hastings of Washington is as follows:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Amendment to <bill type="hr" number="403">H. Res. 403</bill> Offered by Mr. Hastings of Washington</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In section 2(c) after "shall not be subject to amendment" insert "(except the amendment numbered 43 in the report, to be offered by Representative Michaud of Maine, or his designee)".</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Pretty much the same as what Mr. Sessions offered last night)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412195" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time, and I move the previous question on the resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on ordering the previous question.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400171" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 9 of rule XX, the Chair will reduce to 5 minutes the minimum time for any electronic vote on the question of adoption of the resolution.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400171" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
</record>
