<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1185768000" ordinal="56" title="CONGRATULATING UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA, IRVINE, FOR WINNING THE 2007 MEN'S VOLLEYBALL NATIONAL CHAMPIONSHIP">
  <narrative>CONGRATULATING UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA, IRVINE, FOR WINNING THE 2007 MEN'S VOLLEYBALL NATIONAL CHAMPIONSHIP -- (House of Representatives - July 30, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H8881]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400227" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution (<bill type="hr" number="511">H. Res. 511</bill>) congratulating the men's volleyball team of the University of California, Irvine, for winning the 2007 NCAA Division I Men's Volleyball National Championship.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the resolution.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the resolution is as follows</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="hr" number="511">H. Res. 511</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas the men's volleyball team of the University of California, Irvine (UC Irvine), known as the Anteaters, achieved many historic accomplishments during the 2006-2007 season;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the UC Irvine men's volleyball team won the school's first ever National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA) Division I Men's Volleyball National Championship;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Matt Webber, a senior on the UC Irvine men's volleyball team, was selected as the tournament's most valuable player with 22 kills in the championship match;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas UC Irvine men's volleyball players Brian Thornton, Jayson Jablonsky, and David Smith were named to the All-Tournament Team;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas UC Irvine men's volleyball coach John Speraw is only the third coach in history to win a NCAA volleyball championship as both a player and as a head coach;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the UC Irvine men's volleyball team finished with 29 victories, the most victories in school history;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the UC Irvine men's volleyball team finished with the most wins in the Nation for the 2006-2007 season;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the UC Irvine men's volleyball team won the 2007 Mountain Pacific Sports Federation Men's Volleyball title;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the UC Irvine men's volleyball team had four players selected to the American Volleyball Coaches Association (AVCA) All-America Team, the most by any team in the Nation;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas middle blocker David Smith earned first-team accolades on the AVCA All-America Team;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Matt Webber, Jayson Jablonsky, and Brian Thornton earned second-team accolades on the AVCA All-America Team;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the UC Irvine men's volleyball team started the season as the preseason favorite in the CSTV/AVCA Division I Men's Coaches Top 15 Poll;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the UC Irvine men's volleyball team finished first in the CSTV/AVCA Division I Men's Coaches Top 15 Poll, released May 7, 2007; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the UC Irvine men's volleyball team accomplished these feats while playing a difficult schedule in the Mountain Pacific Sports Federation;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the title is UC Irvine's first Division I title since 1989; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas UC Irvine, under the leadership of Chancellor Michael V. Drake, M.D., has continued to establish itself as a world-class research university, and as one of the top universities in the Nation: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, &lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; That the House of Representatives--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) congratulates the men's volleyball team of the University of California, Irvine, and its Chancellor, Michael V. Drake, M.D., for winning the 2007 NCAA Division I Men's Volleyball National Championship; and</narrative>
  <narrative> (2) recognizes the achievements of the players, coaches, students, alumni, and staff who were instrumental in helping the University of California, Irvine, win the national title.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Ohio (Mr. Kucinich) and the gentleman from Delaware (Mr. Castle) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Ohio.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400227" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent for all Members to have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the resolution under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Ohio?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400227" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to congratulate the University of California, Irvine, for winning the NCAA Division I Men's Volleyball National Championship.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On May 5, 2007, the University of California, Irvine, won the 2007 NCAA Division I National Championship by defeating Indiana-Purdue University, Fort Wayne, known as IPFW in Columbus, Ohio. I want to congratulate the student athletes and coaches on an excellent season. We all take great pride in these athletes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400070" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, at this time I yield such time as he may consume to the bill's sponsor, Mr. Campbell of California.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412011" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I thank the gentleman from Delaware for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise today to congratulate the University of California, Irvine, men's volleyball team for winning the 2007 NCAA Division I Men's Volleyball National Championship, as was mentioned, on May 5, 2007. I am very proud of the Anteater volleyball team, who won the school's first men's volleyball national championship after finishing this 2006/2007 season with the most wins in the Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to especially honor the leadership of Coach John Speraw and the talent and effort of each athlete who performed all season long to win this championship.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am proud today to celebrate the accomplishments of this team that represents a tradition of excellence at the University of California, Irvine. But, you know, it is not a very long tradition of excellence, because the University of California, Irvine, was only established in 1965. But already in just over 40 years, the school has grown accustomed to receiving accolades in both academics and in sports as well. So I would like to also extend my congratulations to Chancellor Michael Drake, who  is continuing this, albeit short, but continuing tradition at UCI of excellence in both sports and in academic fields, particularly in the fields of science and technology.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I urge my colleagues to join me in recognizing this achievement and supporting <bill type="hr" number="511">H. Res. 511</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400070" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I also would like to congratulate the University of California-Irvine for its tremendous victory and dominance in the Division I Men's Volleyball National Championship. And I congratulate the gentleman from California for his sponsorship honoring this team, which did such an extraordinary job</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400227" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Ohio (Mr. Kucinich) that the House suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, <bill type="hr" number="511">H. Res. 511</bill>.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the resolution was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
