<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1179936136" ordinal="38" title="CARL SANDBURG HOME NATIONAL HISTORIC SITE BOUNDARY REVISION ACT OF 2007">
  <chair> Pursuant to House Resolution 429 and rule XVIII, the Chair declares the House in the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration of the bill, <bill type="h" number="1100">H.R. 1100</bill>.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> When the Committee of the Whole rose earlier today, a request for a recorded vote on amendment No. 3 printed in House Report 110-165 by the gentleman from Nevada (Mr. Heller) had been postponed.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400411" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, on rollcall No. 406, the Bishop of Utah amendment to <bill type="h" number="1100">H.R. 1100</bill>, amendment No. 1, I was mistakenly recorded as "no," intending to vote "aye."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 5-minute vote.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412222" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, on rollcall No. 407, the Heller of Nevada amendment, had I been present, I would have voted "no."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the committee amendment in the nature of a substitute.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400313" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>In its present form.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will report the motion to recommit.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> The gentleman from New Mexico is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400313" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, we are moving to recommit this bill in order to provide an amendment that would prohibit the Secretary of Interior from using eminent domain to acquire land, water, or interest in land or water under section 3 of the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, most of you, like me, received probably the hardest phone calls from both Democrats and Republicans alike when our Supreme Court made the Kelo decision which said that local entities could, in fact, use eminent domain to acquire property from private individuals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>This motion to recommit is extremely simple. We do not want the Park Service to use eminent domain to take over property.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I sat as the chairman of the National Park Subcommittee in the Resources Committee for all of the last year and part of the year before that, and I will tell you that the most disturbing things that happened in committee were that we heard testimony from people around the Appalachian Trail where the willing seller that is referenced in the bill, the underlying bill today, the willing seller legislation was in fact used to threaten, to intimidate, to cause people to become "willing sellers"  against their will.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Right now, I am working on the Continental Divide Trail, which goes north to south from the Mexico border to the Canadian border. Since 1978, it did not have one mile that had actually come from private landowners in New Mexico.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe in the park system and I believe in the trail system of the United States Government, but I do not believe that the government should or could be able to intimidate, to harass, to cause people to become willing sellers. And that is my fear in this legislation, that it does not go far enough and is not explicit enough.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have expressly worked to get all of the landowners through the Second District of New Mexico, including 22 miles on the Acoma Indian Reservation, where they did not want any Federal presence, no people coming across their land, and now they are excited about the prospect.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I support the concept of preservation, and I support the concept of our national parks, but I will fight to the last breath to protect the private property rights of the people in this country, because it is a constitutional right. The right to private property is the basis of our economic and, therefore, all other freedoms.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, Mr. Speaker, we simply say that in this bill "the willing seller" is not hard enough; that we want assurance that eminent domain will not be used to acquire land, water, or interests in land or water under section 3 of the bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in opposition to the motion to recommit.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, first of all, this legislation, <bill type="h" number="1100">H.R. 1100</bill>, went through full committee hearing, it went through subcommittee hearing, was referred to this floor by voice vote, and this whole discussion we have had on the bill today and the debate was under an open rule. So I fail to understand why we need a motion to recommit. I believe it is a red herring. It is a non-issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I remind Members that in the legislation itself under section 3, acquisition authority, let me quote: "The Secretary may acquire from willing sellers," willing sellers, "by donation, purchase with donated or appropriated funds, or exchange of land."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Willing sellers. The concept of willing seller means that you cannot use eminent domain. I think the legislation before us is good legislation. The motivation for its defeat is something that we have not been able to get to the root of that reason. But the legislation has merited support from the full committee, the subcommittee, and through the discussions today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would continue to urge that we defeat the motion to recommit and pass the underlying legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 1 minute to my colleague, the author of the legislation,  the gentleman from North Carolina (Mr. Shuler).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412225" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I just would like to say that in 1968, Stewart Udall, Secretary of Interior from 1961 to 1968, put forth this great historic site in Flat Rock, North Carolina. We continue to see a tremendous amount of bipartisan support in my community, an all-Republican county commission, might I add, along with both Republican Senators, Elizabeth Dole and Richard Burr, both with overwhelming support, with companion legislation in the Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We continue to find that we are playing politics here with the will of the people of my community. They have asked for this. The administration put forth in 2003 their management plan for this to adapt all 115 acres.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is a very good bill. I oppose this motion to recommit, and I ask all my colleagues to vote "yes" on final passage.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this motion is an attempt to kill the legislation. The use of the word "promptly" in the motion to recommit effectively kills the bill. The issue of this motion to recommit is redundant, not necessary, and I would urge its defeat and urge passage of the legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the previous question is ordered on the motion to recommit.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400313" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I demand a recorded vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 9 of rule XX, the Chair will reduce to 5 minutes the minimum time for any electronic vote on the question of passage.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412232" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on rollcall No. 408, had I been present, I would have voted "no."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400024" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on rollcall No. 408, I was unavoidably detained in a meeting of the Ways and Means Trade Subcommittee with the Chinese trade delegation. Had I been present, I would have voted "no."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the passage of the bill.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412225" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I demand a recorded vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 5-minute vote.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400115" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on rollcall No. 409 I was unavoidably detained during a hearing of the Committee on Rules. Had I been present, I would have voted "no."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
