<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1178640003" ordinal="47" title="THOMASINA E. JORDAN INDIAN TRIBES OF VIRGINIA FEDERAL RECOGNITION ACT OF 2007">
  <speaking speaker="400331" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, pursuant to House Resolution 377, I call up the bill (<bill type="h" number="1294">H.R. 1294</bill>) to extend Federal recognition to the Chickahominy Indian Tribe, the Chickahominy Indian Tribe-Eastern Division, the Upper Mattaponi Tribe, the Rappahannock Tribe, Inc., the Monacan Indian Nation, and the Nansemond Indian Tribe, and ask for its immediate consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to House Resolution 377, the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in the bill, modified by the amendments printed in House Report 110-130, is adopted and the bill, as amended, is considered read.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400331" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on <bill type="h" number="1294">H.R. 1294</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from West Virginia?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400331" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Mr. RAHALL asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400331" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, to my colleagues on both sides of the aisle I would observe that this is one of those rare moments in this body when history itself seems to hold its breath.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are here today 400 years after the first English settlers landed in what became Jamestown, Virginia, to finally acknowledge a government-to-government relationship with some of the Indian tribes who greeted those early settlers. Reflect upon that for a moment. The ancestors of the members of these Indian tribes were there 400 years ago at Jamestown and facilitated the very founding and early development of this Nation. Spanning the entire history of this Nation, they have been here, and they  have endured extreme adversity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These Indian tribes have taken part in ceremonies with the visiting Queen of England commemorating this 400th anniversary of the establishment of Jamestown, and they are a vital part of the official activities continuing this week.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I can think of no better time than this week for Congress to step up to its responsibility by using its constitutional authority to acknowledge these Indian tribes. Simply put, the pending legislation would extend Federal recognition to six Indian tribes located within the Commonwealth of Virginia.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is sponsored by our colleague Jim Moran of Virginia and enjoys bipartisan support, including Virginia Representatives Bobby Scott, Jo Ann Davis and Tom Davis. I, too, am a cosponsor of <bill type="h" number="1294">H.R. 1294</bill>, and I am pleased that the Natural Resources ranking republican member with us today, Mr. Don Young, is also a strong supporter.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Importantly, both former Virginia Governors George Allen and Mark Warner, as well as current Governor Tim Kaine, have endorsed the tribes' recognition and status as sovereign governments. The Virginia Council of Churches supports the measure as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The authority to recognize a government-to-government relationship with an Indian tribe is a very solemn one for the Congress. It is necessary in this case because the members of these six tribes have faced hundreds of years of discrimination, abuse, and outright attempts to extinguish their very existence and rob them of their heritage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>From 1912 to 1947, Dr. Walter Plecker, a white supremacist, set out to rid the Commonwealth of Virginia of any records that proved the existence of Indians or Indian tribes. He was instrumental in ensuring passage of the Racial Integrity Act in 1924, making it illegal for individuals to classify themselves or their newborn children as "Indian." But it went further than that, spending decades changing the race designation on birth certificates and other legal documents from "Indian" to "colored,"</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would note that this bill is named for Thomasina "Red Hawk Woman" Jordan, whose lifelong pursuit of advancing Native American rights encompassed ensuring the promise of education for all Indians and securing Federal recognition of Virginia Indian tribes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The pending measure was reported by the Natural Resources Committee by voice vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To address claims that the tribes are only interested in Federal recognition so that they may conduct gaming, all six tribes supported an outright gaming prohibition which was included in this bill. This gaming prohibition precludes the Virginia tribes from engaging in, licensing or regulating gambling pursuant to the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act on their lands.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In closing, I would like to pay special homage to the gentleman from Virginia (Mr. Moran) who has spent several years tirelessly working to achieve Federal recognition for Virginia's First Americans. He, Representative Bobby Scott and others I mentioned, Tom Davis and Jo Ann Davis, have been before our Committee on Natural Resources and testified on this issue, and I salute their superb leadership as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is because of this dedication to this issue that this legislation is before us today during this historic occasion marking the 400th anniversary of Jamestown. It is time to put this issue to rest and do the right thing by extending Federal recognition to these tribes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge all my colleagues to join me in supporting the pending measure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400440" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Mr. YOUNG of Alaska asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400440" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, as the gentleman from West Virginia said, I do support <bill type="h" number="1294">H.R. 1294</bill>. This bill and prior versions have been in the works over the last several Congresses. This bill is long overdue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have heard arguments saying that we should let the tribes undergo the Federal acknowledgment process at the Department of the Interior. This would be a reasonable argument except for the fact that the Department's process is not specifically authorized by Congress. The intentions behind the creation of the process in 1978 were honorable enough, and perhaps compelling tribes to use this process is appropriate in certain cases.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But it is a fact that the Department has not always abided by its own process in extending the recognition, or failing to extend recognition, to some legitimate tribes. It is a fact that the administrative process is bogged down  with hundreds of petitions, many of which are not filed by tribes that can demonstrate the history of the six Virginia tribes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the hearings held on this bill, the committee has heard convincing testimony describing the rich but sometimes sad history of the six Virginia tribes. I do not need to repeat the detailed history starting with Pocahontas and Captain John Smith. We have heard a lot of that recently.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What matters is whether or not the evidence presented to the Congress demonstrates a continuous existence of a distinct Indian community from the time of European contact to the present. And in this, the six group petitioners in <bill type="h" number="1294">H.R. 1294</bill> pass the test with flying colors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation enjoys broad support throughout the Commonwealth of Virginia. I would specifically point to the efforts of the gentlewoman from Virginia (Mrs. Jo Ann Davis) who has been an untiring advocate for recognizing the Rappahannock tribe, which is in her district. She is the sponsor of <bill type="h" number="106">H.R. 106</bill>, a bill to recognize this tribe. She is also cosponsoring the bill before us today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Her support, as well as the support of the elected officials of Virginia, is critical. Local knowledge and interaction with the tribes is a key consideration. We are obligated to weigh this very heavily in our deliberations over this bill. We have an obligation to defer to the judgment of the Members when bills affecting their constituents are at stake.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One of the few points of opposition to <bill type="h" number="1294">H.R. 1294</bill> concerns the issue of gaming. The bill contains a strict prohibition on any gaming in Virginia. I do not think it is fair to limit tribal sovereignty in this way. It is unfair to view recognition through the prism of Indian gaming.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, the committee made its decision to defer to some Members of the Virginia delegation on this issue, and I reluctantly supported an amendment to add the gaming measure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Therefore, I trust that <bill type="h" number="1294">H.R. 1294</bill> will pass the House with a strong majority today, and I urge my colleagues to give their Virginia tribes their due.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to also recognize Mr. Moran who has done an outstanding job on this issue and has been a great promoter. I always admire those, although not in his district, that have stepped forth and carried this torch on that side of the aisle, and I do compliment him on that effort.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400331" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I recognized the tremendous efforts of Mr. Moran of Virginia in my opening comments, and I know he spoke on the rule on this issue, but I now recognize him again, the gentleman from Virginia, Mr. Jim Moran, for 7 minutes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400283" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I thank very much my very good friend Chairman Rahall. He has shown a lot of courage and also caring and sensitivity to the situation that confronts these particular Indian tribes. I see my good friend Mr. Scott from Virginia, as well, who will speak to this and my good friend, the ranking minority member, Mr. Don Young; and I thank him for stepping up on this, too. I know that his words are deeply felt, and his support is deeply  appreciated.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also want to compliment the staff on both sides. They have done the research. They have provided the accurate information; and without that, there would be a lot of misimpressions that would be going around the floor that could defeat this bill; but the facts are on our side, and that is because particularly the very good, hardworking staff has made sure that the facts have become public.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me share some of those facts with you. The argument is going to be used that these tribes should go through the regular process at the BIA, and the argument will be made that this just opens it up to gambling and there is going to be another issue in terms of the corruption that is inherent within casino gambling and so on.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The fact is that it would be virtually impossible for these Virginia Indian tribes to provide the documentation that the Bureau of Indian Affairs requires. This is a unique situation that does not apply in other States because other States did not make it legal to go into courthouses, local courthouses, throughout the State and destroy the very documentation that is now necessary.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, of course, the Governor of Virginia and all the previous Governors, including Senator Allen who specifically recognized these Indian tribes when he was Governor, they have all acknowledged there is no question these Indian tribes exist. In fact, they have the oldest treaty that has been in existence in the United States, 1677, signed with King Charles II.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>But, of course, that was before there was an American government; and, as a result, ironically, we haven't specifically recognized these Indians, because they have the oldest treaty. But these were the Indians that enabled the Jamestown settlers to survive.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Here we are, the Queen is at the White House, and we are having all this pomp and circumstance, and the very Indians that enabled it to happen have not been recognized by our government and, in fact, have been treated to some of the worst injustices across this land. From 1912 to 1946, their documents were deliberately destroyed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1924, there was a Racial Integrity Act passed by a white supremacist, Dr. Walter Plecker. He was head of the Department of Vital Statistics, very politically powerful. And that, in effect, made it a crime to be identified as an Indian. You had to check a box "white" or "colored" throughout the State in the parlance of that time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My friend and colleague from Virginia knows what I mean, and he believes it, because he knows Virginia history. Many of our colleagues, though, might not believe that this could happen; and, yet, it did. It was a penalty of a year of imprisonment for identifying oneself as an American Indian. So they don't have the documentation. Bureau of Indian Affairs would say, yes, we would recognize you, there is no question you exist, but it won't be in your lifetime.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Well, 400 years. Isn't this time? Now, obviously, there has been a lot of intermarriage, but the fact is, there are records, and we can produce those records. But we don't have the time, and it doesn't seem to be fair to force these Indian tribes through a process that may fail only because of governmental action, a grossly unjust governmental action.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So gambling is not an issue. These Indian tribes, even though they should certainly be on a par with all other Indian tribes, have compromised, have accepted language that prohibits them from being able to gamble, even bingo. The State gets an enormous amount of money from lottery, but they can't participate. They have accepted that. This is a matter of pride for these Indians.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a matter of pride. These Native Americans want to be able to tell their children, and their grandchildren, and their grandchildren, in turn, their grandchildren, we were the ones that enabled the English settlement to survive. We have a proud tradition. We were recognized by the United States Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, hopefully, at some point, the other compromise we have made in terms of putting land into trust, that will be rectified, too, but that's not going to be immediately put into trust. We compromised with the communities; we have gone through all of the possible procedures that might raise some objection to this.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, Members may come to the floor who, I suspect, have not read the bill, with some objection. I don't think it's a matter of bias, but it certainly is a matter of concern that there has been abuse on the part of some lobbyists working with Indian tribes. We understand that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But, gosh, this is a unique situation. This is a matter of injustice that cries out to be rectified. This bill rectifies that injustice. Hopefully we can do it in time for the actual date of the English settlers landing at Jamestown. It's 400 years overdue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, I thank the chairman, the ranking member, and I thank the Speaker for the time. In advance, I thank my colleagues for doing the right thing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, if floor procedures were to permit, I would address the members of the six Virginia tribes seeking Federal recognition.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would say that I know their quest has been a long struggle to assert their identity and their rights.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Despite centuries of racial hostility and coercion by the Commonwealth of Virginia and others, they have refused to yield their most basic human right and have suffered and lost much.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But, throughout the centuries you have retained your dignity and supported your people.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When it appeared that no one else would, when little was available, when even the doors of the public school house were closed to your children, you have never yielded to those who said you didn't exist.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would say to the Virginia tribes that win or lose today, you have already won by refusing to yield and by remaining true and faithful to who you are.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would also say that it has been an honor for me to have helped carry this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While it is less than ideal, it moves you closer to the day our national government recognizes you exist.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, as Member of this chamber know, the crafting of congressional legislation is far from a perfect process. But, when it speaks, it speaks with the people's voice.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, I encourage my colleagues to speak and finally affirm that the Virginia tribes exist and deserve Federal recognition.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400440" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400331" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 2 minutes to the distinguished gentleman from Virginia (Mr. Scott), a cosponsor of this legislation, who helped us tremendously in reaching the point where we are today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400364" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="1294">H.R. 1294</bill>, the Thomasina E. Jordan Indian Tribes of Virginia Federal Recognition Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank my colleague from Virginia (Mr. Moran) for introducing the bill, and the gentleman from West Virginia and the gentleman from Alaska for their leadership and cooperation in bringing the bill to the floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This year marks the 400th anniversary of the founding of Jamestown, Virginia, the first permanent English settlement in North America. Jamestown is the cornerstone of our great republic, and its success relied heavily on the help of the indigenous people of Virginia. Virginia's Native Americans played a critical role in helping the first settlers of Jamestown survive the harsh conditions of the new world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After the Jamestown colony weathered the first couple of years in the new world, the colony expanded, and the English pushed further inland. The same Native Americans that helped those first settlers were coerced and pushed from their land without compensation. Treaties, many of which precede our own Constitution, were often made in an effort to compensate the Virginia Native Americans. But, unfortunately, as history has shown, those treaties were rarely honored or upheld.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Like many other Native Americans, Virginia Indian tribes were marginalized from society. They were deprived of their land, prevented from getting an education and denied a role in our society. Virginia's Native Americans were denied their very fundamental human rights and the very freedoms and liberties enshrined in our own Constitution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill on the House floor today will finally grant Federal recognition to the Chickahominy Tribe, the Eastern Chickahominy Tribe, the Upper Mattaponi Tribe, the Rappahannock Tribe, the Monacan Indian Nation, and the Nansemond Tribe. The bill will ensure the rightful status of Virginia's tribes in our Nation's history.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Federal recognition will also promote tribal economic development that will allow Virginia's tribes to become self-sufficient. Those same opportunities will allow Virginia's tribes to flourish culturally and economically, and will lead to a brighter future for a whole new generation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have waited too long to recognize Virginia's tribes. The time has come for Congress to act. I urge my colleagues to support the bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400440" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400331" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, in conclusion, I would observe that, before the eastern counties of Virginia seceded from the Union at the start of the Civil War, the legal western counties that are now West Virginia were part of the Commonwealth of Virginia, so we, too, owe these tribes our gratitude.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400095" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="1294">H.R. 1294</bill>, the Thomasina E. Jordan Indian Tribes of Virginia Federal Recognition Act. I would like to thank Representative Moran for his leadership, efforts and work, and also Chairman Rahall for bringing this measure to the floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Several of the Virginia tribes are located within my congressional district, and I am proud to be one of the primary cosponsors of this historically significant legislation. As a former member of the Virginia Council on Indians, it is important to me that the tribes who were here before the English landing at Jamestown in 1607, receive all the rights afforded other similarly situated Indian tribes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Often in the face of discrimination and persecution, the Virginia Indian community has strived for centuries to maintain their heritage and culture. Between 1912 and 1946 the Bureau of Vital Statistics in Virginia systematically erased all reference to Indians in public records. Additionally, Virginia's Racial Integrity Act of 1924 required all Indians to register as white or colored. These discriminatory actions and laws essentially erased hundreds of years of Virginia Indian dignity, heritage,  and genealogy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The members of these tribes have worked tirelessly and deserve greater autonomy and control to deal with tribal housing, health care and education. The six tribes were recognized by Virginia between 1983 and 1989. However, significant destruction of tribal records at the hands of the Commonwealth of Virginia have made prompt recognition and documentation through the Bureau of Indian Affairs' record intensive bureaucratic process impossible.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe it is appropriate that Congress take steps to federally recognize the Chickahominy, the Eastern Division Chickahominy, the Upper Mattaponi, the Rappahannock, the Monacan Indian Nation, and the Nansemond Indian Tribe.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is appropriate as the Nation commemorates the 400th Anniversary of the first permanent English settlement in the New World that Congress officially recognizes the tribes who were here before Captain John Smith set foot in America. I urge my colleagues to adopt this bill and extend much deserved recognition to these Virginia tribes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400154" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today regarding <bill type="h" number="1294">H.R. 1294</bill>, the Thomasina E. Jordan Indian Tribes of Virginia Federal Recognition Act of 2007. While I support granting these six Virginia tribes Federal recognition, I remain concerned about opening the door to casino-style gaming in the Commonwealth of Virginia.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Virginia tribes have always contended that they have no interest in pursuing gaming. And I was encouraged when the Resources Committee adopted an amendment to limit the tribes' ability to pursue gaming. However, in recent days I have begun to hear murmurs that the language is not as strong as we have been led to believe, and the tribes are considering challenging the gaming limitation. I have always believed the tribes when they have said they do not wish to pursue gambling, so I hope that  there is no truth to a challenge.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe it is the desire of this Congress that if challenged in court, this language would be upheld, just as similar language was upheld in Del Sur Pueblo v. The State of Texas, 69 Fed. App. 659. However, I urge the Senate to look closely at this bill to see if this language can be tightened and strengthened to further ensure that casino-style gambling doe not come to the Commonwealth. We must ensure that this bill, while well-intentioned, does not negatively affect Virginia.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Commonwealth of Virginia and the Nation should honor and recognize these tribes. However, we must continue to look for a way to grant them this recognition, without leaving our beautiful Commonwealth open to the ill-effects of gambling.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400098" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today to support this bill to correct a long standing historical inequity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1294">H.R. 1294</bill> would provide federal recognition to six American Indian tribes in the Commonwealth of Virginia. With this formal recognition our Government will extend to these tribes the respect, dignity and benefits afforded to 562 other American Indian tribes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Despite historical records documenting the existence of these tribes dating back to the 1600s and formal recognition by the Commonwealth in the 1980s, their efforts to receive Federal recognition have been ongoing for decades.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While documents normally required by the Bureau of Indian Affairs are missing or have been altered, this was not the fault or result of tribal action. In 1997, Virginia passed legislation to correct these historical records and in 1999 passed a resolution urging Congress to grant these tribes Federal recognition.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This inequity should stand no longer. The Chickahominy Indian Tribe, the Eastern Division of the Chickahominy Indian Tribe, the Upper Mattaponi Tribe, the Rappahannock Tribe Inc., the Monacan Indian Nation, and the Nansemond Indian Tribe deserve to be on equal footing with other tribes in the United States. They would benefit greatly from the ability to compete for educational programs, grants and other federal services.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this has gone on long enough. As we commemorate the 400th anniveary of  the founding of Jamestown and honor the history and courage that experience entailed, let us also honor these Native Americans who have persevered through a system of exclusion, by mandating Federal recognition.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400435" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I'm going to vote for this bill because I believe it represents a significant step forward in ensuring that the Commonwealth's interests are safeguarded when it comes to preventing casino-style gambling from coming to the state while providing full Federal recognition to these six Virginia Tribes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, I hope the Senate will take a very careful look at it before proceeding because I have already begun hearing rumors that attorneys are being consulted about ways to overturn the limitation on tribal gambling included in the legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe the tribes when they say they aren't interested in pursuing gambling. Nevertheless, I would be extremely disappointed if there is any merit to the chatter I am hearing already--even before the bill gets out of the House--about their interest in a court challenge of the bill's gambling limitation. I certainly hope that's not true, and that what I am hearing is simply rumor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also must admit that I am troubled by the fact the tribes have been paying a lobbyist at least $80,000 for the past several years to advance this legislation. I certainly hope that this bill isn't the first step down the slippery slope we've been down before relating to lobbying and tribal gambling.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In moving forward with approval of this legislation, I believe it is important to underscore Congress' basis for this gambling limitation. Under the bill, no Virginia Indian tribe or tribal member, if granted Federal recognition by <bill type="h" number="1294">H.R. 1294</bill>, would have any greater rights to gamble or conduct gambling operations under the laws of the Commonwealth of Virginia than any other citizen of Virginia. Further, it is the expectation of Congress that the language restricting gambling operations by Indian  tribes will be upheld if it is ever challenged in court, just as similar language was upheld in Ysleta Del Sur Pueblo v. the State of Texas, 69 Fed. App. 659. The Natural Resources Committee testimony demonstrates Congress' basis for including this limitation in the tribes' ability to engage in gambling.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In Narragansett Indian Tribe v. National Indian Gaming Commission, 332 U.S. App. D.C. 429, the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit applied the Supreme Court's rational basis test from Morton v. Mancari, 417 U.S. 535 (1947), to determine that the denial of gambling opportunities under the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act to the Narragansett Tribe under the Rhode Island Indian Claims Settlement Act did not violate the equal protection  standards of the Fifth Amendment. If the legislation before us today, <bill type="h" number="1294">H.R. 1294</bill>, is ever challenged in court, a court should similarly find a rational basis for this limitation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, my concern is not with the Federal recognition of Virginia's Indian tribes. It has always been with the explosive spread of gambling and the potential for casino gambling to come to Virginia. No bill should become law unless it protects the interests of the Commonwealth.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If casino gambling were to come to Virginia, it would open the door to the myriad of financial and socials ills associated with gambling. Virginia's tourism sector, its economy and its communities are some of the strongest in the country. Places such as the Shenandoah Valley, Williamsburg and Jamestown are national treasures which draw visitors from all over the world. Small businesses thrive in Virginia. The Commonwealth's reputation would be tarnished if it allowed casino-style gambling within  its borders.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As the author of legislation which created the National Gambling Impact Study Commission that released its 2-year study in 1999, I know firsthand about the devastating social and financial costs of gambling. Crime. Prostitution. Corruption. Suicide. Destroyed families. Child and spouse abuse. Bankruptcy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation, I believe, does shut the door on the opportunity for these tribes to acquire land and eventually establish tribal casinos. As I said, I know that the current tribal leadership has indicated that they do not want to pursue gambling--and I believe they are sincere. But what the leaders today say doesn't lock in the leaders of tomorrow. I have already started to worry that future leadership of the tribes will pursue establishing tribal casinos. I hope I am wrong.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412200" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="1294">H.R. 1294</bill>, the Tomasina E. Jordon Indian Tribes of Virginia Federal Recognition Act of 2006. This bill will confer long-delayed Federal recognition to the Chickahominy Indian Tribe, the Chickahominy Indian Tribe Eastern Division, the Upper Mattaponi Tribe, the Rappahannock Tribe, Inc., the Monacan Indian Nation, and Nansemond Indian Tribe.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The members of these tribes were thriving before the arrival of the first European settlers. They entered into treaties with the settlers, but as has happened all too often throughout Native American history, they lost their lands to the newcomers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In many cases, to correct the injustice, Congress recognized its obligation to these Native Americans and funded programs benefiting them, but without Federal recognition. This bill will finally begin to make amends to these proud tribes by granting Federal recognition.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill will permit members enrolled as tribal members to receive benefits applicable to Indians or nations, Indian tribes or bands of Indians without regard to the existence of a reservation and regardless of the location of the residence of any tribal member on or near any Indian reservation. This is only fair. The physical location of any member should not dictate whether he or she who may be otherwise entitled to and in need of assistance, should receive benefits entitled to the Tribe.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill also prohibits gaming on the tribal land. It permits the Secretary of the Interior to take any land into trust for the benefit of any member of the Tribe. The bill will finally grant the protections and benefits long denied the six Indian tribes for want of Federal recognition.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The experience of these tribes is similar to that of Native Hawaiians. To correct the injustices suffered by the indigenous people of Hawaii, my distinguished colleague from Hawaii, the Honorable Neil Abercrombie, and I have introduced <bill type="h" number="505">H.R. 505</bill>, which will lead to Federal recognition of Native Hawaiians.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We believe that the time has long passed when all indigenous people with similar histories of sovereignty lost and homelands taken are recognized and afforded the protections they deserve pursuant to Congress' plenary powers over Indian Commerce authorized by the Constitution of the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I strongly urge passage of this important legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400098" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today to support this bill to correct a long-standing historical inequity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1294">H.R. 1294</bill> would provide Federal recognition to six American Indian tribes in the Commonwealth of Virginia. With this formal recognition our Government will extend to these tribes the respect, dignity and benefits afforded to 562 other American Indian tribes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Despite historical records documenting the existence of these tribes dating back to the 1600s and formal recognition by the Commonwealth in the 1980s, their efforts to receive Federal recognition have been ongoing for decades.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While documents normally required by the Bureau of Indian Affairs are missing or have been altered, this was not the fault or result of tribal action. In 1997, Virginia passed legislation to correct these historical records and in 1999 passed a resolution urging Congress to grant these tribes Federal recognition.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This inequity should stand no longer. The Chickahominy Indian Tribe, the Eastern Division of the Chickahominy Indian Tribe, the Upper Mattaponi Tribe, the Rappahannock Tribe Inc., the Monacan Indian Nation, and the Nansemond Indian Tribe deserve to be on equal footing with other tribes in the United States. They would benefit greatly from the ability to compete for educational programs, grants and other Federal services.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this has gone on long enough. As we commemorate the 400th anniversary of the founding of Jamestown and honor the history and courage that experience entailed, let us also honor these Native Americans who have persevered through a system of exclusion, by mandating Federal recognition.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400331" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> All time for debate has expired.</chair>
</record>
