<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1185768000" ordinal="49" title="SHIRLEY A. CHISHOLM UNITED STATES-CARIBBEAN EDUCATIONAL EXCHANGE ACT OF 2007">
  <narrative>SHIRLEY A. CHISHOLM UNITED STATES-CARIBBEAN EDUCATIONAL EXCHANGE ACT OF 2007 -- (House of Representatives - July 30, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H8861]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400128" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="176">H.R. 176</bill>) to authorize assistance to the countries of the Caribbean to fund educational development and exchange programs, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="176">H.R. 176</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE AND TABLE OF CONTENTS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Short Title.--This Act may be cited as the "Shirley A. Chisholm United States-Caribbean Educational Exchange Act of 2007".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Table of Contents.--The table of contents for this Act is as follows:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..1..Short title and table of contents.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..2..Definitions.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..3..Findings and statement of purpose.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..4..Shirley A. Chisholm United States-Caribbean Educational Exchange Program.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..5..Program to provide educational development assistance for CARICOM countries.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..6..Administrative provisions.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..7..Reporting requirements.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..8..Authorization of appropriations.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. DEFINITIONS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; In this Act:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) ADMINISTRATOR.--Except as otherwise provided, the term "Administrator" means the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) APPROPRIATE CONGRESSIONAL COMMITTEES.--The term "appropriate congressional committees" means--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) CARICOM COUNTRY.--The term "CARICOM country"--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) means a member country of the Caribbean Community (CARICOM); but&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) does not include--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) a country having observer status in CARICOM; or&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) a country the government of which the Secretary of State has determined, for purposes of section 6(j) of the Export Administration Act of 1979 (as continued in effect pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act), section 40 of the Arms Export Control Act, section 620A of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, or any other provision of law, is a government that has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) SECRETARY.--Except as otherwise provided, the term "Secretary" means the Secretary of State.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) UNITED STATES COOPERATING AGENCY.--The term "United States cooperating agency" means--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) an accredited institution of higher education, including, to the maximum extent practicable, an historically Black college or university that is a part B institution (as such term is defined in section 322(2) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (20 U.S.C. 1061(2))) or an Hispanic-serving institution (as such term is defined in section 502(5) of such Act (20 U.S.C. 1101a(5)));&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) a higher education association;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) a nongovernmental organization incorporated in the United States; or&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (D) a consortium consisting of two or more such institutions, associations, or nongovernmental organizations.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 3. FINDINGS AND STATEMENT OF PURPOSE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Findings.--Congress finds the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) The United States and CARICOM countries have enjoyed long-standing friendly relations.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) As an important regional partner for trade and democratic values, the Caribbean region constitutes a "Third Border" of the United States.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) The decrease in tourism revenue in the aftermath of the tragic terrorist attacks on September 11, 2001, had an adverse affect on the Caribbean region.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) According to a 2005 World Bank Report on the Caribbean region, high rates of unemployment, particularly youth unemployment, have had severe implications on poverty and income distributions, as well as drug trafficking and addiction.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) The 2005 World Bank Report also concludes that better synchronization is needed between curricula in CARICOM countries and the skills needed in evolving national and regional job markets and economies.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (6) Caribbean leaders have highlighted the need for increased educational opportunities for Caribbean students in fields that will contribute to and support an increasingly competitive regional economy.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (7) Enhancing United States cultural and educational exchange programs in CARICOM countries will expand human resources, provide opportunities that promote economic growth, and improve regional security.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (8) Many Caribbean leaders studied at the undergraduate or graduate level in the United States before returning to their respective countries to contribute toward the strengthening of democracy, the economy, or the provision of social services.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (9) From 2003 through 2005, 217 Caribbean leaders participated in exchange programs with the United States that focused on good governance, combating drug trafficking, anti-corruption, and other regional issues of concern.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (10) The Department of State currently administers public outreach programs that include cultural, academic, and citizen-exchange initiatives in CARICOM countries through the public affairs sections at United States embassies with support from the Office of Public Diplomacy in the Bureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs.</narrative>
  <narrative> (11) The Caribbean Center for Excellence in Teacher Training (C-CETT), a Presidential Initiative funded by the United States Agency for International Development and implemented by the University of the West Indies, works to improve the quality of reading instruction by training classroom and student teachers in seven countries of the English-speaking Caribbean.  Belize, Jamaica, Grenada, St. Lucia, Guyana, St. Vincent and the Grenadines, and Trinidad and Tobago have participated in the C- &lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page:  H8862]&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/center&gt;</narrative>
  <narrative> (a) Funding From Private Sources and Partnerships With Other Appropriate Entities.--To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary of State and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development should implement the programs authorized under sections 4 and 5 of this Act through utilization of funding from private sources to maximize the impact of United States funds under this Act, and through partnerships with appropriate United States organizations, institutions,  and corporations.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Avoidance of Duplication.--The Secretary and the Administrator shall consult with the Secretary of Education to ensure that--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) activities under the programs authorized under sections 4 and 5 of this Act are not duplicative of other United States educational programs for CARICOM countries; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) United States cooperating agencies and partner institutions in CARICOM countries are accredited by national or regional accrediting bodies.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Reporting Under SEVIS.--To the extent necessary, the Secretary shall provide support to United States cooperating agencies that are participating in the program authorized under section 4 of this Act in order to fulfill the requirements for student data reporting under the Student and Exchange Visitor Information System (SEVIS).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 7. REPORTING REQUIREMENTS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Report Required.--Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act,  the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on plans to implement the programs authorized under sections 4 and 5 of this Act.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Matters To Be Included.--The report required by subsection (a) shall include--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) with respect to implementation of the program authorized under section 4--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) a plan for selecting participants in the program, including an estimate of the number of secondary school students, undergraduate students, graduate students, post-graduate students, and scholars from each country, by educational level, who will be selected as participants in the program for each fiscal year;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) a timeline for selecting United States cooperating agencies that will assist in implementing the program;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) a financial plan that--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) identifies budget plans for each educational level under the program; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) identifies plans or systems to ensure that the costs to public school, college, and university education under the program and the costs to private school, college, and university education under the program are reasonably allocated; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (D) a plan to provide outreach to and linkages with schools, colleges and universities, and nongovernmental organizations in both the United States and CARICOM countries for implementation of the program; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) a plan outlining implementation of the program authorized under section 5, identifying the initial countries in which the program will be implemented and a timeline for implementation.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Updates of Report.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) IN GENERAL.--The Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees updates of the report required by subsection (a) for each fiscal year for which amounts are appropriated pursuant to the authorization of appropriations under section 8 of this Act.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) MATTERS TO BE INCLUDED.--Such updates shall include the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) Information on United States cooperating agencies that are selected to assist in implementing the programs authorized under sections 4 and 5 of this Act.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) An analysis of the positive and negative impacts the program authorized under section 4 will have or is having on brain drain from the participating CARICOM countries.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) A description of efforts made by the Secretary of State, acting through the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, to implement the program authorized under section 5.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (D) A description of the programs established in each CARICOM country receiving assistance under the program authorized under section 5 that provides a detailed explanation of the extent to which the program and the assistance provided are contributing to the purpose of the program described in section 5(b) in the CARICOM country.</narrative>
  <narrative> (E) An evaluation of additional educational development goals in CARICOM countries, identifying those goals that could be maximized or achieved with United States assistance through the program authorized under section 5. In addition to standard or necessary areas of education review, the evaluation should give attention to factors affecting academic achievement, attrition, and graduation rates in CARICOM countries. The evaluation should suggest ways in which United States assistance can maximize  success factors and address factors contributing to poor achievement.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 8. AUTHORIZATION OF APPROPRIATIONS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; To carry out this Act, there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2008 through 2012. Amounts appropriated pursuant to the authorization of appropriations under this section are in addition to amounts otherwise available for such purposes.</narrative>
  <narrative>Amend the title so as to read: "A bill to authorize the establishment of educational exchange and development programs for member countries of the Caribbean Community (CARICOM).".</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from American Samoa (Mr. Faleomavaega) and the gentlewoman from Florida (Ms. Ros-Lehtinen) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from American Samoa.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400128" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from American Samoa?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400128" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in strong support of this resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would first like to thank my colleague, the distinguished gentlewoman from California (Ms. Lee), for introducing this important legislation and garnering the bipartisanship sponsors that it deserves. And certainly I want to thank the chairman of the Western Hemisphere Subcommittee, the gentleman from New York (Mr. Engel), for his tireless efforts in pushing forward this initiative.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, nearly four decades ago, history was made in the voting booths of New York City. A young lady by the name of Shirley Chisholm became the first African American woman elected to the U.S. House of Representatives in the history of our great land. With her election, Congresswoman Shirley Chisholm broke the ground for African Americans, to be sure. Congresswoman Chisholm was also the child of immigrants from the Caribbean area, and today she remains a great heroine for Caribbean Americans  throughout our Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>During her tenure in Congress, Congresswoman Chisholm was a staunch advocate for educational opportunity and access. She increased support for Historically Black Colleges and Universities and other institutions in the United States that serve minorities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is, therefore, entirely appropriate and fitting that the legislation before the House today is named after the late Congresswoman Shirley Chisholm from the great City of New York. This bill establishes a new and important educational exchange program between the United States and our friends in the Caribbean region.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This effort builds on a priority I have long promoted: fostering better educational and cultural ties between the United States and different regions of the world. Today's bill follows our recent historic passage of the Senator Paul Simon Study Abroad Foundation Act of 2007, a bill to vastly expand study abroad programs that overwhelmingly passed this House in a great example of bipartisan cooperation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The United States and nations of the Caribbean have long enjoyed friendly relations. As an important regional partner for trade and a bastion of democratic values, our friends in the Caribbean region have been called the "third border" of the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In talks with Members of Congress, Caribbean leaders have highlighted the need for educational opportunities for Caribbean students in fields that will allow them to contribute to an increasingly competitive regional economy. We aim to deliver on that request today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enhancing our cultural and educational exchange programs in the Caribbean will promote economic growth, improve regional security, and expand opportunities for the hardworking citizens of this region. This educational exchange program will enable secondary school, undergraduate, graduate, and post-graduate scholars from the Caribbean to attend schools, colleges, and universities in the United States. It will allow them to participate in activities designed to promote a greater understanding of  the values and culture of the United States. And it will grant them the option either to live in the United States with a host family, enriching them with community and town life here, or to live in an on-campus housing environment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the late Congresswoman Shirley Chisholm was a great American leader who has inspired generations of African Americans and Caribbean Americans. With passage of this legislation, we honor her memory and ensure that a new generation of Caribbeans can play an even more constructive role in the political and economic developments not only of this region but to continue our friendly relations with this region.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400344" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would like to recognize my good friend from California, Ms. BARBARA LEE, for her leadership in introducing this bill, which is intended to deepen our educational cooperation with our neighbors in the Caribbean.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="176">H.R. 176</bill> authorizes the creation of the Shirley A. Chisholm U.S.-Caribbean Educational Exchange Program to help provide U.S. educational opportunities to qualified students from the countries of the Caribbean community.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>It also authorizes State and USAID to expand existing primary and secondary school initiatives in the Caribbean to provide programs on teacher training methods, school management,  curriculum development, and increase community involvement in school activities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Increasing the quality of educational opportunities available to our good neighbors in the Caribbean serves the interests of our entire region, and deepens the goodwill that already exists between the people of our countries.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank Congresswoman Lee and Chairman Lantos for working with me at the committee level to incorporate language ensuring that state sponsors of terrorism do not receive the benefits provided under this bill. The committee also amended the text to authorize such sums as may be necessary rather than a sum certain for the new programs. This will help ensure that any new activities under the act will not disrupt those educational and exchange programs already being implemented  in the region by the State Department and USAID.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, I thank my colleagues for their cooperation in preparing this bill for floor consideration.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400128" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself 30 seconds just to offer my compliments to my dear friend, the senior ranking member of the House Foreign Affairs Committee, Ms. Ros-Lehtinen, for her support and leadership in bringing this legislation to the floor</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, it is my honor now to give 5 minutes to my good friend and colleague, the prime sponsor of this legislation, the gentlelady from California (Ms. Lee) for her statement.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="LEE" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, first let me just say today is a good day. I'm very delighted to be able to rise in support of <bill type="h" number="176">H.R. 176</bill>, the Shirley Chisholm U.S.-Caribbean Educational Exchange Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to thank Congressman Faleomavaega from the American Samoa, the distinguished chairman of the subcommittee on Asia, the Pacific and the Global Environment, for yielding to me, for managing this bill on the floor, and for your assistance and for your leadership.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Also, to our ranking member, Congresswoman Ileana Ros-Lehtinen, thank you so much for your diligence and hard work and understanding and clarity of what we wanted to do and making sure that this was done in a bipartisan way. We appreciate so much your leadership.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am very pleased, as I said, that the House will have an opportunity to discuss this bill today. I want to thank everyone who has helped with this very important piece of legislation. I would also like to thank my good friend, Congressman Eliot Engel, who is the Chair of the Western Hemisphere Subcommittee, and my colleague, the distinguished chairman of the Committee on Foreign Affairs, Congressman Tom Lantos.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Also, we couldn't have done with this without our staff, who have put in so many hours to ensure that this bill would have the most impact. Particularly, I would like to thank Jason Steinbaum of Mr. Engel's staff and Kristen Wells and Peter Quilter of Mr. Lantos' staff. And let me acknowledge Miguel Ayala from my office for his very, very excellent work on this bill, and Jamila Thompson, formerly of my staff, who really initially worked on this legislation as well as the designation  of June as Caribbean-American Heritage Month.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation is so important because our neighbors in the Caribbean, sometimes called the "Third Border," they're often neglected when we consider matters that affect our hemisphere. My bill creates an educational exchange program whereby students in the Caribbean, including secondary school, undergraduate, graduate, postgraduate students and scholars can come abroad to study at United States institutions of higher education. These important programs will not only encourage diplomacy between  our Nation and those in the Caribbean, but it will also prepare these students to return home to the Caribbean with the tools and the education they need to move their nations forward in the 21st century.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation also encourages academic partnerships with Historically Black Colleges and Universities and Hispanic-serving institutions, when possible, and will ensure parity between males and females in the program. Furthermore, both merit and financial need will be considered for those exchange programs which we are authorizing today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill also creates and provides educational development assistance for CARICOM nations. It will address the lack of access and the lack of quality education in some areas of the Caribbean by improving primary and secondary education through teacher training, strengthening curriculum, and improving administration and management of schools.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill is named after our former colleague, my dear friend, my mentor, the late Congresswoman Shirley Anita Chisholm, who I dearly loved and learned much from and who I deeply miss. She served in Congress from 1969 to 1983 and was of Caribbean descent. Her mother was from Barbados and her father was from Guyana. She represented the 12th District of New York, which to this day continues to have a significant Caribbean-American population.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congresswoman Chisholm would have been so proud to know that this program will address the very disparities in education that the leaders of the CARICOM nations raised during the conference last month here in Washington, D.C. They met with the President, the Secretary of State, Speaker Pelosi, and also with our colleagues on the House Ways and Means Committee, the House Committee on Foreign Affairs, and the Congressional Black Caucus. And during those meetings with the House Committee  on Foreign Affairs, many Members here in our own body heard about the lack of opportunities for students from the Caribbean to study in the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is clear to me that we need to do more to help our friends and neighbors in the Caribbean, and I hope this bill is just one step with regard to the many that we're looking at that will come forward to move us forward with closer ties to our regions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, I would like to thank everyone who helped me make this bill come to fruition. It has taken a while. It has taken a long time, actually. I am delighted that we, today, will be sending a very clear message to our friends in the Caribbean that we are truly supportive.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>You know, when you see other countries in the region providing scholarships for students from the Caribbean, such as Cuba, I think it is now up to the United States to step up to the plate and say we, too, can make sure that students from the Caribbean benefit from the wonderful educational opportunities present in the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thank you, again, Mr. Faleomavaega.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400128" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentlelady for a most eloquent statement.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400344" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I urge my colleagues to vote "aye" on this resolution, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400128" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 1 minute to the gentlelady from Texas (Ms. Jackson-Lee)</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400199" topic="">
    <paragraph>Let me thank the chairman of the subcommittee and the manager of the bill. And let me thank the Honorable Barbara Lee for her leadership and the ranking member for theirs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Very quickly, it is my pleasure to rise and support this legislation, having had the opportunity to be associated with the Honorable Shirley Chisholm in New York and to see her enormous and challenging leadership. But the crux of this bill is an answer in response to our friends in the Caribbean. Through CARICOM and the leaders and heads of State, they represent the third border of the United States. They provide additional security through their homeland security efforts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This opportunity for their skilled and talented young people to have an exchange program, to then go back to their own countries and provide the friendship, the alliance, and the security that we will need in the future is a key element of this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask my colleagues to support this legislation, and I congratulate all those responsible for it, and again, acknowledge the leadership of Shirley Chisholm</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in strong support of <bill type="h" number="176">H.R. 176</bill>, the Shirley A. Chisholm-U.S. Caribbean Educational Exchange Act of 2007 and urge my colleagues  to support its adoption. As an original cosponsor of this important bill, I want to congratulate my friend and colleague, the Honorable BARBARA LEE for her hard work in getting the bill to the floor today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, U.S.-Caribbean educational exchanges have been on the forefront of multilateral discussions in recent years. Many believe that education exchanges are an excellent means to developing and protecting democratic values. And while the U.S. has not particularly focused on educational advancement in the Caribbean, other nations have. Thousands of Caribbean students participate in exchange programs to distant parts of the globe, yet the U.S. has no specific exchange program for Caribbean  scholars.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation would establish in the State Department's Office of Public Diplomacy a U.S.-Caribbean educational exchange program for high school, undergraduate and graduate students, as well as scholars.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It would also enable the U.S. Agency for International Development to develop a regional strategy to expand existing early education initiatives. And the legislation would allow both State Department and USAID to use public-private partnerships to implement the program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The State Department has repeatedly advocated educational exchanges as one of the best means of public diplomacy. For decades, the Caribbean, our "Third Border," has been one of the U.S. staunchest allies with strong democratic traditions. We've seen how critical the adherence to these democratic ideals has been given how quickly the governments of the region were able to maintain order and rebuild in the wake of the recent devastating hurricane seasons. Furthermore, the leadership in these  affected countries was cultivated right here in the U.S.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In fact many of today's Caribbean leaders have received post-secondary education in the United States, and have used their different fields of training to strengthen Caribbean democracy and community involvement. From 2003-2005, 217 Caribbean leaders participated in U.S. exchange programs that centered on innovative ways to fight drug trafficking, anticorruption and good governance policies. We should continue these efforts and expand them to include the future leaders of the Caribbean.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As the only member in Congress whose district is in the English speaking Caribbean, I am well aware of the exciting possibilities that <bill type="h" number="176">H.R. 176</bill> holds.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, our Caribbean neighbors are among the most stable democracies in the world and some of our oldest friends. Too often we take them for granted though and don't give to them as much as we demand from them. While it will not solve all of the problems with our relationship of late, <bill type="h" number="176">H.R. 176</bill> will serve as a meaningful gesture of good faith and friendship going forward. I urge my colleagues to support passage of <bill type="h" number="176">H.R. 176</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400422" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I strongly support <bill type="h" number="176">H.R. 176</bill>; the Shirley A. Chisholm U.S.-Caribbean Educational Exchange Act. I am proud to be a cosponsor of this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Shirley A. Chisholm U.S.-Caribbean Educational Exchange Act creates an educational exchange program to enable students from the countries of the Caribbean Community to come to the U.S. and study at an American college or university. The bill requires program participants to return to a Caribbean country or work for the growth, progress and development of the Caribbean Community after they complete their studies. The bill also creates a program to improve primary and secondary education in  the Caribbean Community through teacher training, strengthening curriculum, and improving administration and management of schools.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many Caribbean leaders have received post-secondary education in the U.S. and have used their education to strengthen Caribbean democracy and benefit Caribbean people. For example, from 2003 through 2005, a total of 217 Caribbean leaders participated in U.S. exchange programs dealing with counter-narcotics, anticorruption and good governance policies. The Shirley A. Chisholm U.S.-Caribbean Educational Exchange Act would expand these efforts to include future Caribbean leaders.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is entirely appropriate that this legislation is named after our former colleague, Congresswoman Shirley Chisholm. Congresswoman Chisholm was of Caribbean heritage and was a strong advocate for quality education. She graduated from Brooklyn College in 1946, received a Masters in Elementary Education from the Teachers College at Columbia University in 1952, and went on to work as a teacher. In 1968, she became the first African-American woman elected to Congress, where she served with distinction  from 1969 to 1983. In 1972, Congresswoman Shirley Chisholm ran for president in the Democratic primaries. As a Member of Congress, Shirley Chisholm served on the influential Education and Labor Committee and rose to be its third-highest ranking member.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge all of my colleagues to honor Congresswoman Shirley Chisholm and support educational exchange opportunities for Caribbean students by voting in favor of the Shirley A. Chisholm U.S.-Caribbean Educational Exchange Act.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400204" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in strong support of the Shirley Chisholm U.S.-Caribbean Educational Exchange Act of 2007. I would like to thank Congresswoman Barbara Lee and her continued commitment to the Caribbean and education. This legislation helps bridge the educational gap in the Caribbean by creating an educational exchange program for Caribbean students to study in the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Caribbean Nations suffer from high poverty rates, high unemployment rates, and low literacy rates. These conditions have left most Caribbean students faced with the hard choice of education or work; and most are forced to choose work in order to provide for themselves and their families. Educational exchange programs allow Caribbean students to provide opportunities to learn necessary skills for leadership and career success, explore cultural issues, and promotes dialogue of community and/or  social relevance. Education is the building block that creates a sound foundation for success and develops strong democratic values. These exchange programs allow students to return to their native homes to contribute to the success of their nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill also creates new programs to improve primary and secondary education through teacher training. Teacher preparedness and education management is vital to any education system. Providing high quality teachers in critical subject areas is the most important components in building a strong educational structure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many Caribbean leaders have received education in the United States, and have used their education to strengthen Caribbean democracy and community involvement. This legislation will help to continue strengthen U.S.-Caribbean relations, I strongly urge my colleagues support in passage this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400122" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in strong support of <bill type="h" number="176">H.R. 176</bill>, the Shirley A. Chisholm United States-Caribbean Education Exchange Program. I would like to pay tribute to our colleague, BARBARA LEE, for introducing this excellent legislation and for the work of Chairman LANTOS in moving <bill type="h" number="176">H.R. 176</bill> forward.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Representative LEE and I have traveled to the Caribbean together, and we have seen through our site visits, including to St. George's University in Grenada and an education program at an orphanage in Haiti, the tremendous need for expanded educational cooperation between the United States and the Caribbean. In fact, Prime Minister Keith Mitchell of Grenada listed cooperation on education as among the most important issues for his country's citizens.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As such, <bill type="h" number="176">H.R. 176</bill> creates an educational exchange program between the United States and CARICOM countries, called the Shirley A. Chisholm United States-Caribbean Educational Exchange Program, and provides educational-related assistance for the nations in the CARICOM region. Education is an area in which the United States has a clear advantage--one which we should use to help our neighbors in the Caribbean.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As chair of the House Foreign Affairs Subcommittee on the Western Hemisphere, it has been a priority of mine to help promote good relations between the United States and CARICOM countries. Just last month, the Presidents and Prime Ministers of 14 Caribbean countries met with members of the House Committee on Foreign Affairs as part of the historic Conference on the Caribbean and discussed how we could expand relations. During our meeting, I told the Caribbean leaders that we would pass a U.S.-Caribbean  Education Exchange Act soon and hold a hearing on deportees. With today's passage of the Caribbean education legislation and last week's hearing, I am proud to say that we have lived up to our promises.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this bill is aptly named for Shirley Anita Chisholm, a former member of the United States House of Representatives from 1968 to 1983 who had family roots in the Caribbean nation of Barbados. I am glad that we honor her service with this important educational exchange program, and I urge my colleagues to support <bill type="h" number="176">H.R. 176</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400128" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from American Samoa (Mr. Faleomavaega) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="176">H.R. 176</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400313" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this motion will be postponed.</chair>
</record>
