<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1210176002" ordinal="53" title="PERSONAL EXPLANATION">
  <narrative>PERSONAL EXPLANATION -- (House of Representatives - May 07, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H3153]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400031" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, earlier today I travelled back to my district and was honored to participate in a ceremony dedicating a memorial to Lieutenant Michael P. Murphy, a Long Island native and constituent who was killed while serving in Afghanistan and posthumously awarded the Congressional Medal of Honor. Had I been here, I would have voted in the following manner:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rollcall vote No. 267, I would have voted "nay";</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rollcall vote No. 268, I would have voted "aye";</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rollcall vote No. 269, I would have voted "aye";</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rollcall vote No. 270, I would have voted "aye";</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rollcall vote No. 271, I would have voted "nay";</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rollcall vote No. 272, I would have voted "nay";</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rollcall vote No. 273, I would have voted "nay";</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rollcall vote No. 274, I would have voted "aye";</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rollcall vote No. 275, I would have voted "aye";</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rollcall vote No. 276, I would have voted "nay";</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rollcall vote No. 277, I would have voted "aye";</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rollcall vote No. 278, I would have voted "aye";</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rollcall vote No. 279, I would have voted "nay";</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rollcall vote No. 280, I would have voted "nay";</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rollcall vote No. 281, I would have voted "aye";</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rollcall vote No. 282, I would have voted "aye";</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rollcall vote No. 283, I would have voted "aye";</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rollcall vote No. 284, I would have voted "aye";</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rollcall vote No. 285, I would have voted "nay";</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rollcall vote No. 286, I would have voted "nay";</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rollcall vote No. 287, I would have voted "aye";</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rollcall vote No. 288, I would have voted "aye";</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rollcall vote No. 289, I would have voted "aye";</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rollcall vote No. 290, I would have voted "aye";</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rollcall vote No. 291, I would have voted "nay."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
