<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1179244824" ordinal="39" title="AUTHORIZING USE OF CAPITOL GROUNDS FOR DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA SPECIAL OLYMPICS LAW ENFORCEMENT TORCH RUN">
  <speaking speaker="400204" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and agree to the concurrent resolution (<bill type="hc" number="123">H. Con. Res. 123</bill>) authorizing the use of the Capitol Grounds for the District of Columbia Special Olympics Law Enforcement Torch Run.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the concurrent resolution.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from Texas (Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson) and the gentleman from Missouri (Mr. Graves) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400204" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days within which to revise and extend their remarks and to include extraneous material on House Concurrent Resolution 123.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from Texas?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400204" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, House Concurrent Resolution 123 authorizes the use of the Capitol Grounds for the District of Columbia Special Olympics Law Enforcement Torch Run.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Capitol Police, along with the D.C. Special Olympics, will participate in the torch run to be held on June 8, 2007. The D.C. Special Olympics will work closely with the Capitol Police and the Architect of the Capitol to make sure that the event is in full compliance with rules and regulations governing the use of the Capitol Grounds.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Law Enforcement Torch Run for the Special Olympics is run nationwide by law enforcement officials leading up to each State's or national Special Olympics summer games. Each year, nearly 50 local and Federal law enforcement agencies in Washington, D.C. participate to show their support of the D.C. Special Olympics. This torch relay event is a traditional part of the opening ceremonies for the Special Olympics. For the fifth year these opening ceremonies will take place at Catholic University  in the District of Columbia. This is a worthwhile event attended by thousands of Special Olympians, their families and friends, and I support the resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400158" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>House Concurrent Resolution 123 authorizes the use of the Capitol Grounds for the District of Columbia Special Olympics Law Enforcement Torch Run, which will be held June 8, 2007. This event is cosponsored by the U.S. Capitol Police.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Special Olympics is an international organization dedicated to enriching the lives of children and adults with disabilities through athletics. The U.S. Capitol Police will host the opening ceremonies for the torch run, which will take place on the west terrace of the Capitol. Once lit, the torch will be carried to Fort McNair. An estimated 2,000 law enforcement representatives from more than 60 local and Federal law enforcement agencies will participate in this year's event.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress has traditionally supported this worthy cause by authorizing the use of the Capitol Grounds. I encourage my colleagues to join the law enforcement community in supporting the Special Olympics and join me in supporting this resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in strong support of <bill type="hc" number="123">H. Con. Res. 123</bill>, which authorizes the use of the Capitol Grounds for the District of Columbia Special Olympics Law Enforcement Torch Run.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thanks to the tenacity to Eunice Kennedy Shriver and her family, thousands of Special Olympians see their self-confidence, self-esteem, and health increase by participating in the Special Olympics. These games highlight the athletic feats of mentally challenged children and young adults. Confidence and self-esteem are the building blocks for these Olympic Games. Better health, coordination, and lasting friendships are the results of participation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Law Enforcement Torch Run for the Special Olympics is run nationwide by law enforcement officers, leading up to each state's and the national Special Olympics Summer Games. Each year, nearly 50 local and Federal law enforcement agencies in Washington, DC, participate to show their support of the DC Special Olympics. This torch relay event is a traditional part of the opening ceremonies for the Special Olympics. Law enforcement officers, who are part of the extensive volunteer network that  supports the games, carry the Olympic torch across the Capitol Grounds through the District of Columbia to Catholic University. The Capitol Police, along with the DC Special Olympics, will participate in the torch run to be held on June 8, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Each year, approximately 2,500 Special Olympians of all ages compete in the DC Special Olympics in more than a dozen events. The event is supported by thousands of volunteers from the District and the region and is attended by thousands more family and friends of Special Olympians.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These games are a wonderful expression of inclusiveness and a confirmation of individual contribution. I enthusiastically support this resolution and the very worthwhile endeavor of the Special Olympics.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to join me in supporting <bill type="hc" number="123">H. Con. Res. 123</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400158" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400204" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I urge passage, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from Texas (Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson) that the House suspend the rules and agree to the concurrent resolution, <bill type="hc" number="123">H. Con. Res. 123</bill>.</chair>
</record>
