<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1168362004" ordinal="13" title="THE KUCINICH PLAN FOR EXIT FROM IRAQ">
  <speaking speaker="400227" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, there is a compelling need for a new direction in Iraq, one that recognizes the plight of the people of Iraq, the false and illegal basis of the United States' war against Iraq, the realities on the ground which make a military resolution of the conflict unrealistic, and the urgent responsibility of the United States to use the process of diplomacy and international law to achieve stability in Iraq.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, I am presenting to Congress what is called the Kucinich Plan for Exit from Iraq. These are some of the elements:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>1. The U.S. announces it will end the occupation, close military bases and withdraw.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>2. The U.S. announces it will use existing funds to bring the troops and necessary equipment home.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>3. Order a simultaneous return of all U.S. contractors to the U.S. and turn over all contracting work to the Iraqi government.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>4. Convene a regional conference for the purpose of developing a security and stabilization force for Iraq.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>5. Prepare an international security and peacekeeping force to move in, replacing U.S. troops who then return home.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>6. Develop and fund a process of national reconciliation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>7. Reconstruction and jobs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>8. Reparations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>9. Political sovereignty.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>10. Dealing with the Iraq economy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>11. Economic sovereignty for Iraq.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>12. A process of international truth and reconciliation between the people of the United States and the people of Iraq.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is time for a new direction, and the Kucinich plan offers that direction.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
