<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1181059208" ordinal="21" title="SUPPORTING THE GOALS AND IDEALS OF AMERICAN EAGLE DAY">
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution (<bill type="hr" number="341">H. Res. 341</bill>) supporting the goals and ideals of "American Eagle Day", and celebrating the recovery and restoration of the American bald eagle, the national symbol of the United States.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the resolution.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from the Virgin Islands (Mrs. Christensen) and the gentleman from Utah (Mr. Cannon) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from the Virgin Islands?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, House Resolution 341 celebrates the recovery of the American bald eagle, the symbol of our country displayed on American currency and government agency seals, including that of the United States Congress. The bald eagle's recovery is a huge success story for the Endangered Species Act and the conservation laws which preceded it. In 1963, there were 417 pairs of bald eagles in the lower 48 States. Today, there are an estimated 9,789 breeding pairs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Later this month, the Secretary of the Interior is expected to remove the bald eagle from the list of threatened species. Several Indian tribes, who consider the eagle extremely important to their culture and even sacred, have raised concerns that the eagle will lose all protections upon delisting. However, the Migratory Bird Treaty Act and the Bald and Golden Eagle Protection Act will continue to protect the bald eagle.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I commend Representative David Davis for introducing this resolution which encourages organizations and government agencies working on the conservation of endangered species to collaborate on education information for use in our schools. The resolution also asks the American people to observe American Eagle Day with appropriate ceremonies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This resolution merits our support.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise in support of House Resolution 341 which endorses the goals and ideals of American Eagle Day.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Two hundred and twenty-five years ago, the Second Continental Congress decided to use the image of the American bald eagle on the Great Seal of the United States. Since that time, the image of this majestic bird has graced American art, our culture, currency and stamps. It has been the subject of more than 2,500 books, making the bald eagle the most extensively studied bird in North America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While there were nearly 500,000 on this continent prior to European settlement, this species was particularly devastated by various chemical compounds that caused widespread reproductive failure. In response, the Congress enacted the Bald and Golden Eagle Protection Act and the bird was listed on our Endangered Species Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>From its all-time low of 417 nesting pairs in the continental United States in 1963, extraordinary conservation efforts have saved the bald eagle, and we have witnessed a significant population increase. Today, there are 9,789 breeding pairs, not including the more than 30,000 bald eagles living in Alaska.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By any objective standard, recovery of the bald eagle has been remarkable, but sadly, it is one of only a handful of species that have been recovered under the Endangered Species Act. While it is likely that the Secretary of the Interior will soon make a decision to remove the bald eagle from the Federal list of threatened and endangered species, there is no question that the bald eagle will continue to inspire millions of Americans because it symbolizes the fundamental values of this country  of courage, freedom and patriotic spirit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under the terms of House Resolution 341, the people of the United States are encouraged to observe American Eagle Day on June 20 and to provide educational information on the value of conserving our Nation's wildlife resources.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge an "aye" vote and want to compliment the author of this resolution, freshman Congressman David Davis of Tennessee, for his effective leadership in proposing this celebration of American Eagle Day.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield so such time as he may consume to the gentleman from Tennessee (Mr. David Davis), who is the author of the bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412235" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would like to thank my colleagues on the House Resources Committee for bringing this legislation that I've introduced, along with my fellow Tennessee Members, Jimmy Duncan and John Tanner, to the floor of the House today supporting the goals and ideals of American Eagle Day.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Almost 225 years ago, on June 20, 1782, the Second Continental Congress designated the bald eagle as the national symbol of the United States. Since that time, the bald eagle has become a fixture on the seals and marks of the Federal Government and on our stamps, currency and coinage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And while the bald eagle has always been such a popular fixture in the hearts and minds of so many Americans, it is difficult to believe that we were very close to forever losing the symbol of our great country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1963, the number of nesting pairs of eagles in the 48 contiguous States had dwindled to a figure of just over 400. As the habitat for the bald eagle solely exists in North America, these figures were extremely alarming and led to the bald eagle being listed as an endangered species for the first time in 1967.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, I'm pleased to note that, as a result of the Federal protection laws and through the diligent efforts of so many private conservationists, the bald eagle has made an incredible recovery.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>In 1995, the bald eagle was removed from the endangered list to the threatened list, and it could very soon be moved permanently off of these lists as soon as Federal guidelines can be finalized that will forever protect the birds and their habitats.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have been extremely interested in this issue, not only because of the importance of this as a matter of national concern but also because of my firsthand experience in dealing with a group located in the heart of the First Congressional District of Tennessee that has been working for the last 22 years to save the bald eagle.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The American Eagle Foundation is located in Pigeon Ford, Tennessee, at the base of the Great Smoky Mountains National Park. This nonprofit group has worked to establish recovery programs to protect the eagle and actively cares for many nonreleasable birds to ensure they live healthy lives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, they operate the largest bald eagle breeding facility in the world, and they have released hundreds of eaglets into the wild with the support of local, State and Federal officials.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Through the efforts of the American Eagle Foundation and the grassroots efforts of children nationwide, I am pleased to offer this legislation for this consideration. Spaced conveniently between Flag Day on June 14 and Independence Day on July 4, July 20 will give Americans another day in which they can celebrate their patriotism by honoring the unique symbol of our heritage and folklore.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I again thank my colleagues for bringing this legislation to the floor of the House and encourage all of my colleagues on the House to join me in supporting this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today to join my colleagues in recognizing American Eagle Day to honor the birds that have symbolized our country's freedom and democracy for centuries. <bill type="hr" number="341">H. Res. 341</bill> encourages all Americans to acknowledge American Eagle Day on June 20, 2007, which marks the 225th anniversary of the bald eagle's designation as our national symbol.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bald eagle habitats in Tennessee have been important in the recovery and restoration of this majestic species. I want to particularly thank the American Eagle Foundation and its president Al Cecere for their hard work to protect our American bald eagles. I have had the honor of visiting in my office with Al and Challenger, the world-famous American bald eagle that appears at high-profile events like the Super Bowl to represent the freedoms we enjoy in this great country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I hope you and our colleagues will join me in supporting <bill type="hr" number="341">H. Res. 341</bill> to celebrate June 20 as American Eagle Day.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from the Virgin Islands (Mrs. Christensen) that the House suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, <bill type="hr" number="341">H. Res. 341</bill>.</chair>
</record>
