<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1190736002" ordinal="37" title="IRAN COUNTER-PROLIFERATION ACT OF 2007">
  <narrative>IRAN COUNTER-PROLIFERATION ACT OF 2007 -- (House of Representatives - September 25, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H10764]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400231" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill>) to enhance United States diplomatic efforts with respect to Iran by imposing additional economic sanctions against Iran, and for other purposes, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE AND TABLE OF CONTENTS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Short Title.--This Act may be cited as the "Iran Counter-Proliferation Act of 2007".</narrative>
  <narrative> (b) Table of Contents.--The table of contents for this Act is as follows:&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <narrative>Sec..1..Short title and table of contents.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..2..United States policy toward Iran.</narrative>
  <narrative>Sec..101..Support for international diplomatic efforts.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..102..Peaceful efforts by the United States.</narrative>
  <narrative>Sec..201..Application to subsidiaries.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..202..Additional import sanctions against Iran.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..203..Additional export sanctions against Iran.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..204..Temporary increase in fee for certain consular services.</narrative>
  <narrative>Sec..301..Multilateral regime.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..302..Mandatory sanctions.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..303..Authority to impose sanctions on principal executive officers.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..304..United States efforts to prevent investment.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..305..Clarification and expansion of definitions.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..306..Removal of waiver authority.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..307..Clarification of authority.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..308..Applicability of certain amendments.</narrative>
  <narrative>Sec..401..Additions to terrorism and other lists.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..402..Increased capacity for efforts to combat unlawful or terrorist financing.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..403..Exchange programs with the people of Iran.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..404..Reducing contributions to the World Bank.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..405..Restrictions on nuclear cooperation with countries assisting the nuclear program of Iran.</narrative>
  <narrative>Sec..501..Termination.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. UNITED STATES POLICY TOWARD IRAN.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Findings.--Congress finds the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) The prospect of the Islamic Republic of Iran achieving nuclear arms represents a grave threat to the United States and its allies in the Middle East, Europe, and globally.</narrative>
  <narrative> (2) The nature of this threat is manifold, ranging from the vastly enhanced political influence extremist Iran would wield in its region, including the ability to intimidate its neighbors, to, at its most nightmarish, the prospect that Iran would attack its neighbors and others with nuclear arms. This concern is illustrated by the statement of Hashemi Rafsanjani, former president of Iran and currently a prominent member of two of Iran's most important decisionmaking bodies, of December 14, 2001,  when he said that it "is not irrational to contemplate" the use of nuclear weapons.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) The theological nature of the Iranian regime creates a special urgency in addressing Iran's efforts to acquire nuclear weapons.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) Iranian regime leaders have persistently denied Israel's right to exist. Current President Mahmoud Ahmadinejad has called for Israel to be "wiped off the map" and the Government of Iran has displayed inflammatory symbols that express similar intent.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) The nature of the Iranian threat makes it critical that the United States and its allies do everything possible--diplomatically, politically, and economically--to prevent Iran from acquiring nuclear-arms capability and persuade the Iranian regime to halt its quest for nuclear arms.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Sense of Congress.--It is the sense of the Congress that--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) Iranian President Ahmadinejad's persistent denials of the Holocaust and his repeated assertions that Israel should be "wiped off the map" may constitute a violation of the Convention on the Prevention and Punishment of the Crime of Genocide and should be brought before an appropriate international tribunal for the purpose of declaring Iran in breach of the Genocide Convention;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) the United States should increase use of its important role in the international financial sector to isolate Iran;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) Iran should be barred from entering the World Trade Organization (WTO) until all issues related to its nuclear program are resolved;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) all future free trade agreements entered into by the United States should be conditioned on the requirement that the parties to such agreements pledge not to invest and not to allow companies based in its territory or controlled by its citizens to invest in Iran's energy sector or otherwise to make significant investment in Iran;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) United Nations Security Council Resolutions 1737 (December 23, 2006) and 1747 (March 24, 2007), which were passed unanimously and mandate an immediate and unconditional suspension of Iran's nuclear enrichment program, represent a critical gain in the worldwide campaign to prevent Iran's acquisition of nuclear arms and should be fully respected by all nations;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (6) the United Nations Security Council should take further measures beyond Resolutions 1737 and 1747 to tighten sanctions on Iran, including preventing new investment in Iran's energy sector, as long as Iran fails to comply with the international community's demand to halt its nuclear enrichment campaign;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (7) the United States should encourage foreign governments to direct state-owned entities to cease all investment in Iran's energy sector and all exports of refined petroleum products to Iran and to persuade, and, where possible, require private entities based in their territories to cease all investment in Iran's energy sector and all exports of refined petroleum products to Iran;</narrative>
  <narrative> (8) moderate Arab states have a vital and perhaps existential interest in preventing Iran from acquiring nuclear arms, and therefore such states, particularly those with large oil deposits, should use their economic leverage to dissuade other nations, including the Russian Federation and the People's Republic of China, from assisting Iran's nuclear program directly or indirectly and to persuade other nations, including Russia and China, to be more forthcoming in supporting United Nations Security  Council efforts to halt Iran's nuclear program;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (9) the United States should take all possible measures to discourage and, if possible, prevent foreign banks from providing export credits to foreign entities seeking to invest in the Iranian energy sector;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (10) the United States should oppose any further activity by the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development with respect to Iran, or the adoption of a new Country Assistance Strategy for Iran, including by seeking the cooperation of other countries;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (11) the United States should extend its program of discouraging foreign banks from accepting Iranian state banks as clients;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (12) the United States should prohibit all Iranian state banks from using the United States banking system;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (13) State and local government pension plans should divest themselves of all non-United States companies investing more than $20,000,000 in Iran's energy sector;</narrative>
  <narrative> (14) the United States should designate the Iranian Islamic Revolutionary Guards Corps, which purveys terrorism throughout the Middle East and plays an important role in the Iranian economy, as a foreign terrorist organization under section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act, place the Iranian Islamic Revolutionary Guards Corps on the list of specially designated global terrorists, and place the Iranian Islamic Revolutionary Guards Corps on the list of weapons of mass destruction proliferators  and their supporters;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (15) United States concerns regarding Iran are strictly the result of actions of the Government of Iran; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (16) the American people have feelings of friendship for the Iranian people, regret that developments of recent decades have created impediments to that friendship, and hold the Iranian people, their culture, and their ancient and rich history in the highest esteem.</narrative>
  <narrative>SEC. 101. SUPPORT FOR INTERNATIONAL DIPLOMATIC EFFORTS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; It is the sense of the Congress that--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) the United States should use diplomatic and economic means to resolve the Iranian nuclear problem; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) the United States should continue to support efforts in the International Atomic Energy Agency and the United Nations Security Council to bring about an end to Iran's uranium enrichment program and its nuclear weapons program; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3)(A) United Nations Security Council Resolution 1737 was a useful first step toward pressing Iran to end its nuclear weapons program; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) in light of Iran's continued defiance of the international community, the United Nations Security Council should adopt additional measures against Iran, including measures to prohibit investments in Iran's energy sector.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 102. PEACEFUL EFFORTS BY THE UNITED STATES.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Nothing in this Act shall be construed as authorizing the use of force or the use of the United States Armed Forces against Iran.</narrative>
  <narrative> (a) In General.--Except as provided in subsection (b), in any case in which an entity engages in an act outside the United States which, if committed in the United States or by a United States person, would violate Executive Order No. 12959 of May 6, 1995, Executive Order No. 13059 of August 19, 1997, or any other prohibition on transactions with respect to Iran that is imposed under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.) and if that entity was created  or availed of for the purpose of engaging in such an act, the parent company of that entity shall be subject to the penalties for such violation to the same extent as if the parent company had engaged in that act.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Exception.--Subsection (a) shall not apply to any act carried out under a contract or other obligation of any entity if--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) the contract or obligation existed on May 22, 2007, unless such contract or obligation is extended in time in any manner or expanded to cover additional activities beyond the terms of the contract or other obligation as it existed on May 22, 2007; or&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) the parent company acquired that entity not knowing, and not having reason to know, that such contract or other obligation existed, unless such contract or other obligation is extended in time in any manner or expanded to cover additional activities beyond the terms of such contract or other obligation as it existed at the time of such acquisition.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Construction.--Nothing in this section shall be construed as prohibiting the issuance of regulations, orders, directives, or licenses under the Executive orders described in subsection (a) or as being inconsistent with the authorities under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (d) Definitions.--In this section--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) the term "entity" means a partnership, association, trust, joint venture, corporation, or other organization;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) an entity is a "parent company" of another entity if it controls, directly or indirectly, that other entity and is a United States person; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) the term "United States person" means any United States citizen, any alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States, any entity organized under the laws of the United States, or any person in the United States.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 202. ADDITIONAL IMPORT SANCTIONS AGAINST IRAN.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Effective 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) goods of Iranian origin that are otherwise authorized to be imported under section 560.534 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on March 5, 2007, may not be imported into the United States under such section; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) activities otherwise authorized by section 560.535 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on March 5, 2007, are no longer authorized under such section.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 203. ADDITIONAL EXPORT SANCTIONS AGAINST IRAN.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Effective on the date of the enactment of this Act--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) licenses to export or reexport goods, services, or technology relating to civil aviation that are otherwise authorized by section 560.528 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on March 5, 2007, may not be issued, and any such license issued before such date of enactment is no longer valid; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) goods, services, or technology described in paragraph (1) may not be exported or reexported.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 204. TEMPORARY INCREASE IN FEE FOR CERTAIN CONSULAR SERVICES.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Increase in Fee.--Notwithstanding any other provision of law, not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall increase by $1.00 the fee or surcharge assessed under section 140(a) of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1994 and 1995 (Public Law 103-236; 8 U.S.C. 1351 note) for processing machine readable nonimmigrant visas and machine readable combined border crossing identification cards and nonimmigrant visas.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Deposit of Amounts.--Fees collected under the authority of subsection (a) shall be deposited in the Treasury.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Duration of Increase.--The fee increase authorized under subsection (a) shall terminate on the date that is one year after the date on which such fee is first collected.</narrative>
  <narrative>SEC. 301. MULTILATERAL REGIME.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Section 4(b) of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (50 U.S.C. 1701 note) is amended to read as follows:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(b) Reports to Congress.--Not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of the Iran Counter-Proliferation Act of 2007 and every six months thereafter, the President shall transmit to the appropriate congressional committees a report regarding specific diplomatic efforts undertaken pursuant to subsection (a), the results of those efforts, and a description of proposed diplomatic efforts pursuant to such subsection. Each report shall include--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(1) a list of the countries that have agreed to undertake measures to further the objectives of section 3 with respect to Iran;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(2) a description of those measures, including--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(A) government actions with respect to public or private entities (or their subsidiaries) located in their territories, that are engaged in Iran;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(B) any decisions by the governments of these countries to rescind or continue the provision of credits, guarantees, or other governmental assistance to these entities; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(C) actions taken in international fora to further the objectives of section 3;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(3) a list of the countries that have not agreed to undertake measures to further the objectives of section 3 with respect to Iran, and the reasons therefor; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(4) a description of any memorandums of understanding, political understandings, or international agreements to which the United States has acceded which affect implementation of this section or section 5(a).".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 302. MANDATORY SANCTIONS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Section 5(a) of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (50 U.S.C. 1701 note) is amended by striking "2 or more of the sanctions described in paragraphs (1) through (6) of section 6" and inserting "the sanction described in paragraph (5) of section 6 and, in addition, one or more of the sanctions described in paragraphs (1), (2), (3), (4), and (6) of such section".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 303. AUTHORITY TO IMPOSE SANCTIONS ON PRINCIPAL EXECUTIVE OFFICERS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Section 5 of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (50 U.S.C. 1701 note) is amended by adding at the end the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(g) Authority to Impose Sanctions on Principal Executive Officers.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(1) SANCTIONS UNDER SECTION 6.--In addition to the sanctions imposed under subsection (a), the President may impose any of the sanctions under section 6 on the principal executive officer or officers of any sanctioned person, or on persons performing similar functions as such officer or officers. The President shall include on the list published under subsection (d) the name of any person on whom sanctions are imposed under this paragraph.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(2) ADDITIONAL SANCTIONS.--In addition to the sanctions imposed under paragraph (1), the President may block the property of any person described in paragraph (1), and prohibit transactions in such property, to the same extent as the property of a foreign person determined to have committed acts of terrorism for purposes of Executive Order 13224 of September 23, 2001 (50 U.S.C. 1701 note).".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 304. UNITED STATES EFFORTS TO PREVENT INVESTMENT.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Section 5 of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 is amended by adding the following new subsection at the end:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(h) United States Efforts to Address Planned Investment.--</narrative>
  <narrative> "(1) REPORTS ON INVESTMENT ACTIVITY.--Not later than January 30, 2008, and every 6 months thereafter, the President shall transmit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report on investment and pre-investment activity, by any person or entity, that could contribute to the enhancement of Iran's ability to develop petroleum resources in Iran. For each such activity, the President shall provide a description  of the activity, any information regarding when actual investment may commence, and what steps the United States has taken to respond to such activity.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(2) DEFINITION.--In this subsection--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(A) the term `investment' includes the extension by a financial institution of credit or other financing to a person for that person's investment; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(B) the term `pre-investment activity' means any activity indicating an intent to make an investment, including a memorandum of understanding among parties indicating such an intent."&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 305. CLARIFICATION AND EXPANSION OF DEFINITIONS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Person.--Section 14(13)(B) of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (50 U.S.C. 1701 note) is amended to read as follows:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(B)(i) a corporation, business association, partnership, society, trust, financial institution, insurer, underwriter, guarantor, and any other business organization;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(ii) any foreign subsidiary of any entity described in clause (i); and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(iii) any government entity operating as a business enterprise, such as an export credit agency; and".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Development and Investment.--Section 14 of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (50 U.S.C. 1701 note) is amended-- &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in paragraph (4), by inserting "tanker or" after "transportation by"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) in paragraph (9)--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) by inserting after subparagraph (C) the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(D) The sale of an oil tanker or liquefied natural gas tanker."; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) in the second sentence, by inserting ", other than a sale described in subparagraph (D)" after "goods, service, or technology".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 306. REMOVAL OF WAIVER AUTHORITY.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Six-Month Waiver Authority.--Section 4 of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (50 U.S.C. 1701 note) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in subsection (d)(1), by striking "except those with respect to which the President has exercised the waiver authority of subsection (c)";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) by striking subsection (c); and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) by redesignating subsections (d), (e), and (f) as subsections (c), (d), and (e), respectively.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) General Waiver Authority.--Section 9 of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (50 U.S.C. 1701 note) is amended by striking subsection (c).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 307. CLARIFICATION OF AUTHORITY.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Section 6(6) of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (50 U.S.C. 1701 note) is amended by inserting "the authorities under" after "in accordance with".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 308. APPLICABILITY OF CERTAIN AMENDMENTS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; The amendments made by sections 302, 305, and 306 shall apply with respect to acts done on or after August 3, 2007.</narrative>
  <narrative>SEC. 401. ADDITIONS TO TERRORISM AND OTHER LISTS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Determinations and Report.--Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) determine whether the Iranian Islamic Revolutionary Guards Corps (in this section referred to as "IRGC") should be--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) designated as a foreign terrorist organization under section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1189);&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) placed on the list of specially designated global terrorists; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) placed on the list of weapons of mass destruction proliferators and their supporters; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) report the determinations under paragraph (1) to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, including, if the President determines that such Corps should not be so designated or placed on either such list, the justification for the President's determination.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Extension of Authority.--The President may block all property and interests in property of the following persons, to the same extent as property and interests in property of a foreign person determined to have committed acts of terrorism for purposes of Executive Order 13224 of September 21, 2001 (50 U.S.C. 1701 note) may be blocked:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) Persons who assist or provide financial, material, or technological support for, or financial or other services to or in support of, the IRGC or entities owned or effectively controlled by the IRGC.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) Persons otherwise associated with the IRGC or entities referred to in paragraph (1).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Definitions.--In this section--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) the term "specially designated global terrorist" means any person included on the Annex to Executive Order 13224, of September 23, 2001, and any other person identified under section 1 of that Executive order whose property and interests in property are blocked by that section; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) the term "weapons of mass destruction proliferators and their supporters" means any person included on the Annex to Executive Order 13382, of June 28, 2005, and any other person identified under section 1 of that Executive order whose property and interests in property are blocked by that section.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 402. INCREASED CAPACITY FOR EFFORTS TO COMBAT UNLAWFUL OR TERRORIST FINANCING.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Findings.--The work of the Office of Terrorism and Financial Intelligence of the Department of Treasury, which includes the Office of Foreign Assets Control and the Financial Crimes Enforcement Center, is critical to ensuring that the international financial system is not used for purposes of supporting terrorism and developing weapons of mass destruction.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Authorization.--There is authorized for the Secretary of the Treasury $59,466,000 for fiscal year 2008 and such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2009 and 2010 for the Office of Terrorism and Financial Intelligence.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Authorization Amendment.--Section 310(d)(1) of title 31, United States Code, is amended by striking "such sums as may be necessary for fiscal years 2002, 2003, 2004, and 2005" and inserting "$85,844,000 for fiscal year 2008 and such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2009 and 2010".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 403. EXCHANGE PROGRAMS WITH THE PEOPLE OF IRAN.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Sense of Congress.--It is the sense of the Congress that the United States should seek to enhance its friendship with the people of Iran, particularly by identifying young people of Iran to come to the United States under United States exchange programs.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Exchange Programs Authorized.--The President is authorized to carry out exchange programs with the people of Iran, particularly the young people of Iran. Such programs shall be carried out to the extent practicable in a manner consistent with the eligibility for assistance requirements specified in section 302(b) of the Iran Freedom Support Act (Public Law 109-293).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Authorization.--Of the amounts available to the Department of State for "Educational and Cultural Exchanges" to carry out the Mutual Educational and Cultural Exchange Act of 1961, there is authorized to be appropriated to the President to carry out this section the sum of $10,000,000 for fiscal year 2008.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 404. REDUCING CONTRIBUTIONS TO THE WORLD BANK.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; The President of the United States shall reduce the total amount otherwise payable on behalf of the United States to the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development for each fiscal year by the percentage represented by--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) the total of the amounts provided by the Bank to entities in Iran, or for projects and activities in Iran, in the then-preceding fiscal year; divided by&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) the total of the amounts provided by the Bank to all entities, or for all projects and activities, in the then-preceding fiscal year.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 405. RESTRICTIONS ON NUCLEAR COOPERATION WITH COUNTRIES ASSISTING THE NUCLEAR PROGRAM OF IRAN.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) In General.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) RESTRICTION.--Notwithstanding any other provision of law or any international agreement--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) no agreement for cooperation between the United States and the government of any country that is assisting the nuclear program of Iran or transferring advanced conventional weapons or missiles to Iran may be submitted to the President or to Congress pursuant to section 123 of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (42 U.S.C. 2153),&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) no such agreement may enter into force with such country,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) no license may be issued for export directly or indirectly to such country of any nuclear material, facilities, components, or other goods, services, or technology that would be subject to such agreement, and</narrative>
  <narrative> (D) no approval may be given for the transfer or retransfer directly or indirectly to such country of any nuclear material, facilities, components, or other goods, services, or technology that would be subject to such agreement,&lt;p&gt; until the President makes the determination and report under paragraph (2).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) DETERMINATION AND REPORT.--The determination and report referred to in paragraph (1) are a determination and report by the President, submitted to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, that--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) Iran has ceased its efforts to design, develop, or acquire a nuclear explosive device or related materials or technology; or&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) the government of the country that is assisting the nuclear program of Iran or transferring advanced conventional weapons or missiles to Iran--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) has suspended all nuclear assistance to Iran and all transfers of advanced conventional weapons and missiles to Iran; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) is committed to maintaining that suspension until Iran has implemented measures that would permit the President to make the determination described in subparagraph (A).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Construction.--The restrictions in subsection (a)--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) shall apply in addition to all other applicable procedures, requirements, and restrictions contained in the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 and other laws; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) shall not be construed as affecting the validity of agreements for cooperation that are in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Definitions.--In this section:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) AGREEMENT FOR COOPERATION.--The term "agreement for cooperation" has the meaning given that term in section 11 b. of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (42 U.S.C. 2014(b)).</narrative>
  <narrative> (2) ASSISTING THE NUCLEAR PROGRAM OF IRAN.--The term "assisting the nuclear program of Iran" means the intentional transfer to Iran by a government, or by a person subject to the jurisdiction of a government with the knowledge and acquiescence of that government, of goods, services, or technology listed on the Nuclear Suppliers Group Guidelines for the Export of Nuclear Material, Equipment and Technology (published by the International Atomic Energy Agency as Information Circular INFCIRC/254/Rev.  3/Part 1, and subsequent revisions), or the Nuclear Suppliers Group Guidelines for Transfers of Nuclear-Related Dual-Use Equipment, Material, and Related Technology (published by the International Atomic Energy Agency as Information Circular INFCIR/254/Rev. 3/Part 2, and subsequent revisions).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) COUNTRY THAT IS ASSISTING THE NUCLEAR PROGRAM OF IRAN OR TRANSFERRING ADVANCED CONVENTIONAL WEAPONS OR MISSILES TO IRAN.--The term "country that is assisting the nuclear program of Iran or transferring advanced conventional weapons or missiles to Iran" means--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) the Russian Federation; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) any other country determined by the President to be assisting the nuclear program of Iran or transferring advanced conventional weapons or missiles to Iran.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) TRANSFERRING ADVANCED CONVENTIONAL WEAPONS OR MISSILES TO IRAN.--The term "transferring advanced conventional weapons or missiles to Iran" means the intentional transfer to Iran by a government, or  by a person subject to the jurisdiction of a government with the knowledge and acquiescence of that government, of goods, services, or technology listed on--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) the Wassenaar Arrangement list of Dual Use Goods and Technologies and Munitions list of July 12, 1996, and subsequent revisions; or&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) the Missile Technology Control Regime Equipment and Technology Annex of June 11, 1996, and subsequent revisions.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (d) Effective Date.--The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply to expense paid or incurred on or after January 1, 2007.</narrative>
  <narrative>SEC. 501. TERMINATION.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Termination.--The restrictions provided in sections 203, 404, and 405 shall cease to be effective with respect to Iran on the date on which the President determines and certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that Iran--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) has ceased its efforts to design, develop, manufacture, or acquire--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) a nuclear explosive device or related materials and technology;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) chemical and biological weapons; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) ballistic missiles and ballistic missile launch technology;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) has been removed from the list of countries the governments of which have been determined, for purposes of section 6(j) of the Export Administration Act of 1979 (50 U.S.C. 2405(j)), section 620A of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, section 40 of the Arms Export Control Act, or any other provision of law, to have repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) poses no significant threat to United States national security, interests, or allies.</narrative>
  <narrative> (b) Definition.--In subsection (a), the term "appropriate congressional committees" means the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from California (Mr. Lantos) and the gentlewoman from Florida (Ms. Ros-Lehtinen) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from California.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400231" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and to include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from California?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400231" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in strong support of this resolution. Mr. Speaker, Iranian President Mahmoud Ahmadinejad will address the United Nations General Assembly in just a couple of hours, the latest step in his campaign to remove all obstacles to Tehran's headlong pursuit of nuclear weapons. We, in turn, must resolve to use every available peaceful means, economic, political, and diplomatic, to put a stop to that deadly, dangerous pursuit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Peaceful persuasion in this instance will require a lot of leverage. Strong international sanctions must be imposed against the regime in Tehran, biting sanctions that will bring about a change in policy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ideally, Mr. Speaker, such measures would be undertaken through the United Nations. But if China and Russia continue to block effective U.N. sanctions against Iran, the United States must move ahead in the company of as many other like-minded nations as possible. And if multilateral sanctions are not in the offing, the United States needs to be prepared to tighten and to fully enforce our own sanctions without any exceptions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Current law imposes sanctions in the U.S. market on any foreign company that invests $20 million or more in the Iranian energy sector. But the law lets the executive branch, at its sole discretion, waive those sanctions. And for years, Mr. Speaker, administrations of both parties have done so without fail.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since 1999, giant companies such as Royal Dutch Shell, France's Total, Italy's ENI, and Inpex of Japan have invested over $100 billion, over $100 billion, in the Iranian energy industry, and the United States has done nothing to stop them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If we wish to impose serious and biting sanctions on Iran, effective measures that will change the behavior of the regime in Tehran, it is clear what we must do. We must take away the power from the administration to waive sanctions we pass.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Two days ago on 60 Minutes, the President of Iran had this to say about the issue of nuclear weapons: "We don't need a nuclear bomb ..... In political relations right now, the nuclear bomb is of no use. If it was useful, it would have prevented the downfall of the Soviet Union."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I wish that we could take Ahmadinejad at his word, but we obviously cannot. This is the same man who yesterday said, "Our people are the freest in the world" and "there are no homosexuals in Iran." We are all aware of the many other absurd and irrational statements that have emanated from Tehran since this man took power.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But there is one arena in which I agree with Ahmadinejad: when he says his country has the same right as every other country to use civilian nuclear power. Every country has that right. But if they all decide to get there by mastering the full nuclear fuel cycle, then the door will be wide open to an unprecedented global proliferation of nuclear weapons.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is why earlier the House passed my legislation to authorize the creation of an International Nuclear Fuel Bank under the auspices of the International Atomic Energy Agency. Every country, including Iran, can draw from that bank the nuclear fuel necessary for the production of civilian nuclear energy under strict IAEA safeguards, but no nation will be able to divert nuclear materials for military purposes. The International Atomic Energy Agency supports my approach, as do all five permanent  members of the U.N. Security Council, including our own administration.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One would think that the decision makers in Tehran would look upon this idea of an International Nuclear Fuel Bank as an elegant way to get Iran out of a difficult, unproductive, and singularly isolated situation. I hope that they will take this road and they will use this opportunity to move away from their current isolation in the international community.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And I hope as well that the administration will see its way clear to opening up serious and continuing dialogue with Iran. When I hear it said that it is somehow wrong to talk with Iran, I think back to the days when the Soviet Union had thousands of nuclear-tipped missiles aimed at the United States. Surely, the Soviets then were a great deal more dangerous to us than the Iranian leadership is today, and yet we talked with them daily. We maintained a very active diplomacy vis-a-vis the Soviet  Union. We were engaged in trade, travel, and cultural exchanges of many types.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I am not alone in hoping that relations with Iran can and will be improved. But as long as irrationality prevails in Tehran, we must be prepared to employ all peaceful means at our disposal to ensure that the regime renounces its pursuit of nuclear weapons.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Iran today faces a choice between a very big carrot and a very sharp stick. It is my hope that they will take the carrot, but today we are putting the stick in place.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400344" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, today is a day of contrast. Today as we stand here in this hallowed Chamber of democracy discussing the threat that Iran poses to the United States and, indeed, to global security, to its own people as well, Iran's leader will later be spewing his venomous rhetoric before the United Nations General Assembly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last year, the leader of the Iranian regime called for Israel to be wiped off the map and for a new wave of Palestinian attacks to destroy the Jewish state. He further stated that anyone who recognizes Israel will burn in the fire of the fury of Islamic nations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is not the first time that the Iranian leadership has called for the destruction of Israel. On December 14, 2001, former Iranian leader Rafsanjani threatened Israel with nuclear attack, saying that the use of even one nuclear bomb inside Israel would destroy that country while it would do little harm to the Islamic world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Given the Iranian regime's history of acting on its declarations, we should be under no illusions regarding its intentions. And its intentions are to get a nuclear weapon. In fact, they are even taking out advertisements about it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me show you this very revealing ad that appeared in the May issue of the Economist. As they say, "a picture is worth a thousand words." Even as the International Atomic Energy Agency reported that "gaps remain in the agency's knowledge with respect to the scope and content of Iran's centrifuge program ..... including the role of the military in Iran's nuclear program ....." and voiced concern regarding "undeclared nuclear material and activities in Iran," and even as additional sanctions  were being considered against Iran by the United Nations Security Council, this request for proposals for two new large nuclear plants appeared in a major western magazine. And let me point out that the ad clearly identifies the name of the bank, a European bank. For the record, it is Austria Bank Creditansalt, with the account number clearly evident in the advertisement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, for over 5 years, Iran has been manipulating the international community, buying time to expand and to hide its nuclear program, and it is making rapid progress. The International Atomic Energy Agency report of August 30 of this year stated that Iran is running almost 2,000 centrifuges with as many more being tested or under construction, indicating that it has already overcome many of the roadblocks to manufacturing nuclear fuel, including weapons-grade material.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The estimate of the International Atomic Energy Agency, however, may be too conservative. Iranian leader Ahmadinejad put the number of centrifuges at 3,000 and said that the program was making great strides. His comments underscored his regime's intense focus on its nuclear weapons program and should increase our focus and our sense of urgency.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>When thinking of the consequences of an Iranian nuclear bomb, we must always remember that Iran is the number one state sponsor of terrorism, supplying weapons, funding, training and sanctuary to terrorist groups such as Hezbollah and Hamas that have murdered countless civilians and threatens our allies in the region and elsewhere; that Iran continues to supply Shiite Islamic groups in Iraq with money, training and weapons that fuel sectarian violence; that Iran is responsible for the deaths  of U.S. troops by providing the resources and the materials used for improvised explosive devices, or IEDs, and other much more powerful weapons; that Iran is also supplying the Taliban with weapons to use against our troops serving in Afghanistan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My daughter-in-law is proudly wearing our Nation's uniform right now in Afghanistan, and Iran's work is a danger to her and all of our sons and daughters serving overseas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, Tehran's pursuit of these destructive policies has one weakness, namely, its dependence on the revenue derived from energy exports. For that reason, the U.S. has targeted Iran's energy sector, attempting to starve it of its foreign investment. U.S. law prohibits American firms from investing in Iran, but foreign entities continue to do so. To address that problem, my distinguished colleague, my good friend from California, the chairman of our committee, Mr. Lantos, and I introduced  the Iran Freedom Support Act, which was enacted into law in September of last year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation under consideration today, however, <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill>, builds upon that foundation, reiterates the application of the Iran Sanctions Act, ISA, to parent companies of foreign subsidiaries that engage in activities that ISA would prohibit for U.S. entities. Like its predecessors, the Iraq Freedom Support Act and <bill type="h" number="957">H.R. 957</bill>, this bill before us, <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill>, expands the application of the Iran Sanctions Act to any financial institution, insurer, underwriter, guarantor, or other business organization  including any foreign subsidiary of the foregoing. Mr. Speaker, this bill enlarges the scope of the ISA sanctions to include the sale of oil or liquefied natural gas tankers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, the bill before us states the sense of Congress that the United States should prevent foreign banks from providing export credits to foreign entities seeking to invest in Iran's energy sector. And in line with the Iran Freedom Support Act, which urged the President to instruct the U.S. ambassador to the U.N. to push for United Nations Security Council sanctions against Iran, this bill before us commends the U.N. Security Council for its previous action and urges additional action.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill> also restricts U.S. nuclear cooperation with any country that helps Iran's nuclear program or transfers advanced conventional weapons or missiles to Iran. This puts countries seeking to maintain good relations with the U.S. on notice that we will not allow ourselves to be used as indirect purveyors of nuclear assistance to Iran.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, let me emphasize, Mr. Speaker, that this bill speaks directly to the people of Iran. The regime in Tehran continues its brutal crackdown on human rights advocates, on religious and ethnic minorities, on opponents in the universities and the press, and on dissidents in general. And to address their plight, the bill before us expresses the unwavering support of the American people for the tens of millions of Iranians suffering under a brutal medieval regime.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We must always remember that we share a common enemy, the regime in Tehran, and a common goal, which is freedom.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, thank you for this time. But I mostly want to thank the chairman of our committee, Mr. Lantos, for his leadership on this issue, and I strongly urge my colleagues to support its adoption.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And with that, Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400231" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I am very pleased to yield 3 minutes to the distinguished chairman of the Middle East Subcommittee of the Foreign Affairs Committee, Mr. Ackerman of New York.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400003" topic="">
    <paragraph>Thank you, Mr. Chairman, for yielding me the time, as well as for your tireless efforts in support of the legislation that we are considering today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is no more imperative threat facing the world today than checking Iran's nuclear aspirations. Sometimes, in the midst of urgent debate over the right tactics to use to stop the mullahs' mad march towards the bomb, we lose sight of the big strategic picture. By focusing on the particular costs of each sanction, the monstrous reality of a world in which Iran possesses nuclear weapons can slip into the background. This loss of perspective is a terrible mistake.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Critics of <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill>, both here and abroad, see only the cost and the irritants of American sanctions. Their concerns focus on economic liberty and their own bottom line, on their national sovereignty, but not their national security.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Protests are heard regarding our insensitivity to the Iranian regime and the likelihood of sanctions hurting the Iranian people. The critics are, unfortunately, missing the point. In a vacuum, sanctions always seem harsh unless you consider the nonpeaceful alternative.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To fully and fairly judge the proposals in a sanctions measure such as <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill>, we have to consider what a future without it might look like. If you don't want to see the complete collapse of the nuclear nonproliferation regime and the rapid nuclearization of the entire Middle East, then you're for the bill. If you don't want to see Iranian proxies, such as Hamas and Hezbollah, taking over the Palestinian Authority and the Government of Lebanon, then you're for the bill. If you don't want to  see Iran accelerating its supply of arms and training to terrorists around the world, then you're for the bill. If you don't want the supply and the price of oil to be set in Tehran, then you're for the bill. If you don't want to even imagine a nuclear device exploding somewhere,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The official title is the Iran Counter-Proliferation Act. The proper title should be the Stop the Iranian Bomb by Every Peaceful Means Possible Act. This is the alternative.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are running out of time. Nuclear weapons in the hands of Iran's mullahs are not inevitable; but to prevent such an international security catastrophe,  we need every tool at our disposal now while there is still time. The longer we wait, the greater the danger and difficulty of the challenge we face. Now is the time to apply the absolute maximum diplomatic, political and economic pressure that we can muster.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill> will crank up the pressure and help us avoid having to choose between military action and an Iranian atomic bomb. I urge all Members to support this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400344" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, at this time, I would like to yield 6 minutes to Mr. Pence, the ranking member on the Subcommittee on the Middle East and South Asia of our Committee on Foreign Affairs.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Mr. PENCE asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400315" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentlelady for yielding. I also thank the ranking member and the distinguished chairman of this committee for their extraordinary and visionary work in bringing <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill> to the floor of this Congress to enhance United States diplomatic efforts with respect to Iran by imposing additional economic sanctions against Iran.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As the ranking member and my other senior colleagues have described, this legislation would continue an expanding effort to confront Iran's rhetoric and reality in a manner both diplomatic and economic. And the reasons to do so are legion. Iran, for instance, denies the Holocaust and hosted a Holocaust-denying conference which aired on Arab television across the region.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>President Ahmadinejad, as I will describe in a moment, has repeatedly advocated "wiping Israel off the map." Their headlong and reckless pursuit of a nuclear weapons program ominously would enable them to do that in a matter of minutes when combined with their missile technology.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Iran supplies and trains insurgents fighting U.S. forces and Iraqi forces in Iraq, as General Petraeus and Ambassador Crocker and the physical evidence and the incarceration of Iranian intelligence personnel now in Baghdad attest. Iran supports Hezbollah, Hamas, and other terrorist organizations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But I want to speak specifically, Mr. Speaker, to yesterday and today's events involving the Iranian President, Mahmoud Ahmadinejad, who arrived yesterday for a forum in Columbia University and an address at the United Nations today. Let me be clear: If my colleagues have no other reason to support <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill>, we can look to the rhetoric and the statements in the past 48 hours of President Ahmadinejad. He is a destabilizing force leading a threatening country and gave evidence of that repeatedly  in statements on American television, Columbia University, and I expect at the U.N. today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ahmadinejad veers regularly between the deadly and the bizarre. He is perhaps best known for the menacing statements about advocating the elimination of the State of Israel. But at last year's address to the U.N. General Assembly, President Ahmadinejad told an Iranian cleric that he had felt the hand of God entrancing world leaders as he addressed that body. All of these various threats and outrages are delivered with a trademark eery grin, which would be easy to dismiss as the rantings of a  madman were he not vested with the power of a head of state. Yet his musings are as clear and as threatening as those musings written in a prison cell in the 1930s entitled "Mein Kampf."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a man who is on a misguided mission; he is a dangerous and deluded leader. We ignore his intents at our peril. While his speech at Columbia University yesterday was described as a rambling speech by the New York Times that meandered from science to religion to the creation of human beings, it was his claim that he was a "peaceful" man, that Iran possessed, as he made some reference to, a thriving Jewish community, and his claim that Iran was a country where no homosexuals lived. For  me, I cannot decide which of those statements was more Orwellian or more offensive to reality or to western respect for individual liberty. But they do give us a window into the mindset of a leader.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And, Mr. Speaker, I believe no terrorist despot deserves an Ivy League forum, and have said so. On "60 Minutes" Sunday night, Ahmadinejad refused to address what we all know to be true: his forces and weaponry, as I said before, are directly implicated in the deaths of American forces in Iraq, and that would have been reason enough to deny him a podium.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, we are occasionally told, and maybe some will hesitate to support this legislation today because Ahmadinejad is not in charge, that some believe a relatively moderate group of clerics are the real power in Iran. But in a military parade just Saturday, the Supreme Leader Ayatollah Khamenei, allegedly a moderate in some versions, had a banner displayed alongside him that read: "The Iranian Nation is ready to bring any oppressive power to its knees." Clearly, this threatening posture is deep-seated;  it is not focused on one man.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But I think as we argue today for <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill> to bring additional economic sanctions against Iran, we should look at the man who is the leader of the country. <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill>, sponsored by our distinguished chairman and ranking minority member, does the reasonable step of imposing additional economic sanctions against Iran.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But let me say I believe it is imperative that we must continue to use every tool in our power to pressure and isolate this dangerous and threatening regime. And the people of the United States of America, the U.N. Security Council, our neighbors and allies in the region also need to be prepared to keep all options on the table as we confront this regime. It is my hope <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill>, with its diplomatic and economic initiative, will prevail and bring Iran back from the nuclear brink, and that would  be my prayer. But we must remain committed to the notion that this nation and this leader in Iran must not be permitted to come into possession of a usable nuclear weapon.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400231" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I am pleased to yield 3 minutes to the distinguished chairman of the Subcommittee on Terrorism, Nonproliferation and Trade of the Foreign Affairs Committee, Mr. Sherman of California.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400371" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I thank the chairman for yielding, and I thank him for this outstanding piece of legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Yesterday, at Columbia University, Mahmoud Ahmadinejad made two points that were newsworthy. First, there are no gay people in Iran. Second, there is no nuclear weapons program in Iran. These two points are equally true.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To focus on Iran's nuclear program, we do not need military action. I want to emphasize that this bill does not authorize, it does not justify, it does not urge military action in any way. In fact, it gives us an alternative, and that is economic and diplomatic pressure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, we owe a special debt of gratitude to the mullahs who are running Iran, because their mismanagement, corruption and oppression has made their government vulnerable, vulnerable even in an $80-a-barrel world. Today, Iran faces a slow decline in its oil fields. Without further investment, they won't be exporting oil in 10 years. Today, as I speak, they are rationing gasoline in Tehran.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We need to be able to use our considerable broadcasting resources to send a message into Iran for the people and elites of that country: that you face diplomatic and economic isolation if you don't abandon your nuclear program. The problem is that none of us can lie that well in Farsi. We have not imposed economic isolation on Iran. But with this bill, we can begin.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have acquiesced in World Bank loans to the Government of Iran. With this bill, we stop putting money into the unit of the World Bank that is making loans to Iran. We ought to look at other things we can do to make sure that there are no further World Bank loans to Iran.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Currently, we import from Iran--not oil, but only the stuff we don't need, and they can't sell anywhere else. This bill ends imports from Iran.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With regard to oil companies, again, we owe a special debt of gratitude to those mullahs whose outrageous business practices and threats of expropriation have made oil companies reluctant to invest in Iran. But now we have got to make them more reluctant to invest in Iran. This bill turns to foreign subsidiaries of U.S. oil companies and bans their investment in Iran.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With regard to foreign-based oil companies, it sends a clear message: Don't do business with Iran if you expect to do business-as-usual in the United States. We have had that kind of sanction against foreign-based oil companies for quite some time under what was then called the Iran-Libya Sanctions Act (ILSA). We applied that act against Libya, and it worked. It is now time to apply that act with regard to oil companies investing in Iran. This bill moves us a long way in that direction.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400344" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I am proud to yield 3 minutes to Mr. Shays of the National Security and Foreign Affairs Subcommittee of the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400370" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I thank the gentlewoman for yielding to me.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill>, the Iran Counter-Proliferation Act, what I call the bipartisan Lantos-Ros-Lehtinen Resolution. We need to prohibit nuclear cooperation between the U.S. and countries who are aiding Iran's nuclear program, and we need to strengthen our current sanctions against Iran.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, we cannot talk about Iran in a vacuum. We need to pass this resolution and put other pressure on this government. We also need to make sure that we do not leave Iraq and the Middle East to this country. Iran is pursuing nuclear capabilities and is one of the world's most egregious exporters of terrorism, funding Hamas, Hezbollah and Iraqi insurgents. We are needing to confront Iran because they are funding the Iraqi insurgents, therefore killing Iraqis who are on our side. They are literally  killing our American troops. The seriousness of these facts was made clear when Iran's president threatened to wipe Israel off the map. That is his intent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, in April 2006, Ayatollah Khamenei told another one of the world's worst human rights abusers, Sudan, that Iran would gladly transfer nuclear technology to it. Khamenei stated, "The Islamic Republic of Iran is prepared to transfer the experience, knowledge and technology of its scientists." That is a quote. I am hopeful the ongoing discussions between the Iranians and the United Nations to craft a permanent nuclear agreement will be successful. But I am not holding my breath.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is critical that our Government utilize the tools at our disposal, including economic and diplomatic sanctions and the appropriate distribution of foreign aid to those groups who oppose the current regime to deter the threat Iran poses to global security. It is also appropriate and essential for us to impose pressure on the other nations of the world who prop up the Iranian Government and the extremists at the helm by their investing heavily in that nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bottom line is, in spite of its assurances to the contrary, Iran remains committed to a nuclear weapons program. The United States must be unequivocal in its rejection of these ambitions. We need to realize that if you don't want war with Iran, then we need to make sanctions work.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I thank the gentlewoman for yielding.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400231" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I am pleased to yield 1 minute to my good friend from Texas (Mr. Edwards) for a colloquy.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400118" topic="">
    <paragraph>I first want to commend Chairman Lantos for his strong leadership in this legislation. I support it very strongly and think it's good for our Nation and the security of the world. I would like to express that I have heard some concerns raised about whether section 405 unintentionally might create any roadblocks to the Nunn-Lugar program where the United States and Russia work together to prohibit nuclear materials from getting into the hands of terrorists. Obviously, no  one here, no one in Russia, no one in this country would want to make it more difficult to protect our Nation from theft of nuclear material from Russia.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I just hope that as we move toward the final version of this legislation and discuss this with the Senate, I hope we can ensure it would not in any way unintentionally undermine our ability to evaluate physical protection systems at sites that receive U.S. nuclear exports and to just ensure that in no way do we unintentionally create some roadblocks for the continuation of the Nunn-Lugar program.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400231" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, will the gentleman yield?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400118" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield to the gentleman from California.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman's time has expired.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400231" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I want to thank my friend from Texas for raising this issue. The Nunn-Lugar program is one of the most valuable international pieces of legislation since the end of the Second World War. It has gone a long ways in preventing nuclear materials falling into dangerous hands. It is imperative that the Russian Federation work together with the international community to thwart Iran's nuclear ambitions. I very much look forward to working with my friend from Texas to ensure that that goal  and the nonproliferation goals are fully met in this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400118" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for his leadership and his comments.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400344" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 2 minutes to the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Kirk), the cochair of the Congressional Iran Working Group.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400222" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the history of the 20th century tells us that genocidal dictators say what they will do and then do what they said. Hitler told us in his writings that he would murder Jews. And he did. Stalin said that he would liquidate the Kulaks, Russia's small farmers. And he did. Pol Pot said he would eliminate the middle class and intellectuals. And he did. Now the President of Iran said he will wipe Israel off the face of the Earth. And he will.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, we Americans promised in 1945, never again. Ahmadinejad says that one Jewish holocaust is not enough, that he would wish to commit a second genocide, and he would deny that that would happen because he already denies that the holocaust happened.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, our options with regard to Iran are poor. Option one is to leave this to the United Nations alone. But that appears to lead to the Iranians having the bomb. Option two is to let Israel's armed forces remove the threat. But that mission is dangerous and uncertain.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thanks to Chairman Lantos and Ranking Member Ros-Lehtinen, we in Congress are developing a better and third option. Sanctions against Iran can work. This bill strengthens such sanctions. We can do more. We should bankrupt Bank Melli, a funder of terror. And we should quarantine gasoline sales to Iran. These measures could cripple Iran. Like the Yugoslav dictatorship, we can bring effective pressure to bear to achieve our objectives without military action.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The new President of France sees the growing danger and says the international community and Europe should act. The new French President is right. This bill takes us in the direction of a safer world and one in cooperation with our allies.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400231" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I am pleased to yield 2 minutes to the distinguished Chair of the Western Hemisphere Subcommittee of the Foreign Affairs Committee, Mr. Engel of New York.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400122" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I thank our distinguished chairman for yielding to me. I rise in strong support of this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, yesterday, I was in New York City, my hometown, where I spoke at a demonstration in front of the United Nations protesting Ahmadinejad's speaking at that world body. I also then went to Columbia University where I also participated in a protest outside of Columbia University.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I want to be able to tell my children and my grandchildren that I did something when evil raised its ugly head. Perhaps if there had been more of this in the 1930s, Adolph Hitler might not have come to power. He said what he was going to do, as the gentleman from Illinois just said, and he carried it out. When Mr. Ahmadinejad says he wants to wipe Israel off the face of the Earth and do all kinds of other countless, horrific things, he means it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill squeezes the Iranian regime where it counts the most, in the pockets, economically. No one could have  foreseen that the Soviet Union could have rotted from within. But the Iranian regime is rotting from within. They are now importing oil. There's an energy crunch in Iran. This is the way to topple that regime. I think that they are the biggest threat right now to the world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The United Nations discredits itself. We will soon have a resolution condemning their so-called Human Rights Commission, which does nothing but attack Israel. We need to stand up and say that we were able to act when it counted. This is one of the most important things that the Congress can do by slapping sanctions on Iran.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have the Syria Accountability Act which I introduced with the distinguished ranking member. We are going to have another bill. Syria and Iran, who represent threats to the region, need to be hit in the pocketbook, economically, in order for their regimes to collapse or for them to change their behavior.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this bill does that. That is why everyone should support it today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400344" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400231" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I am pleased to yield 1 3/4  minutes to the distinguished member of the Intelligence Committee, the gentlewoman from California (Ms. Harman).</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400166" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, California is poised to join several other States in requiring its huge pension funds to disinvest in Iran. The decision is bipartisan. I commend my State's Democratic legislature and Republican Governor for this bold move.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill> too, is a bold bipartisan move, and I urge its passage. It tightens enforcement of U.S. sanctions, which are working; it conditions future nuclear cooperation with Russia on that country's ceasing its nuclear ties with Iran; and it designates Iran's Revolutionary Guards, who have long carried out terrorist acts in Iraq and the region, as a terror organization.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, Los Angeles, California, is home to over 800,000 Iranian Americans. In fact, it's called sometimes the "Tehrangeles." I understand that, because we have such a large population. Our fight, however, is not with the "Tehrangelenos," and it surely is not with the Iranian people either; but our fight, and we must continue it, is against the threats and the actions of the extreme regime in Iran who threaten our Democratic ally Israel and who threaten the entire world with the prospect  of a nuclear bomb.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Coercive sanctions are working. <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill> will add new tools to those sanctions. This is the right way for this country to speak out and the right way for this country to achieve results.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400176" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill>, as amended to strengthen its goals and effect.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Iranian regime supports terrorism. Iran's President has called for Israel to be, and I quote, "wiped off the map." Iranian special forces are fighting a "proxy war" against U.S. troops in Iraq and are training Iraqi Shiite extremists. Iran's uranium enrichment continues to fly in the face of several United Nations resolutions, and the International Atomic Energy Agency, IAEA, reports that Iran could develop nuclear weapons in as few as 3 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A multilateral strategy will most effectively block Iran's dangerous ambitions. The U.N., in particular, must adopt additional, stronger measures to stop this hostile regime dead in its tracks. I am also very encouraged by the recent statements of French President Sarkozy calling on France and the rest of Europe to adopt "international" and "multilateral" economic sanctions against Iran, in coordination with U.S. efforts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As I have said on this floor before, I question the effectiveness of unilateral sanctions because they often disturb the very multilateralism that we currently see taking shape against Iran. Careful drafting, however, can alleviate the disruption, and the Ways &amp; Means Committee strengthened <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill> by inserting provisions that will preserve this growing international coalition.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>More specifically, <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill> maintains the President's discretion under current law not to impose import restrictions, if refraining would best serve the foreign policy purpose. To that end, Section 307 of this bill clarifies that the full "authorities" of IEEPA are implicated in Section 6(6) of the Iran Sanctions Act, not just the authority to impose import restrictions. A parallel rule of construction is included in Section 201.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, my Committee was careful to clarify in Section 202 that the bill's import restrictions apply only to the current regulation, so the President retains needed flexibility. Finally, Section 406 of the bill as introduced and reported was stripped and replaced with a new funding source.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For these reasons, I urge support of <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill>, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400231" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I submit a series of letters from other committees that have jurisdiction over parts of this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>COMMITTEE ON WAYS AND MEANS,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington, DC, September 24, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR MR. CHAIRMAN: I am writing regarding <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill>--"to enhance United States diplomatic efforts with respect to Iran by imposing economic sanctions against Iran, and for other purposes"--which was reported by the House Foreign Affairs Committee on August 2, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As you know, the Committee on Ways &amp; Means has jurisdiction over import matters. Accordingly, certain provisions of <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill> fall under the Committee's jurisdiction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There have been some productive conversations between the staffs of our committees, during which we have proposed some changes to <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill> that I believe I help clarify the intent and scope of the measure. My understanding is that there is an agreement with regard to these changes. Modifications were made to section 202, relating to additional import sanctions against Iran, and section 406, relating to certain tax incentives, was removed. In addition, provisions were included in section 201  and a new section 307 was added to <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill> to clarify that other provisions of the Act did not affect the President's authority under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act, particularly as such authority relates to measures restricting imports.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To expedite this legislation for floor consideration, the Committee will forgo action on this bill and will not oppose its consideration on the suspension calendar. This is done with the understanding that it does not in any way prejudice the Committee or its jurisdictional prerogatives on this, or similar legislation, in the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would appreciate your response to this letter, confirming our understanding with respect to <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill>, and would ask that a copy of our exchange of letters on this matter be included in the record.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Charles B. Rangel,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>&lt;pre&gt;--&lt;/pre&gt;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN AFFAIRS,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington, DC, September 24, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR MR. CHAIRMAN: Thank you for your letter regarding <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill>, the Iran Counter-Proliferation Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I appreciate your willingness to work cooperatively on this legislation and the mutually agreed upon text that is being presented to the House. I recognize that the bill contains provisions that fall within the jurisdiction of the Committee on Ways and Means. I agree that the inaction of your Committee with respect to the bill does not in any way prejudice the Committee on Ways and Means or its jurisdictional prerogatives on this or similar legislation in the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I will ensure that our exchange of letters be included in the Congressional Record.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Cordially,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Tom Lantos,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>&lt;pre&gt;--&lt;/pre&gt;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>COMMITTEE ON FINANCIAL SERVICES,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington, DC, September 21, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR MR. CHAIRMAN: I am writing concerning <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill>, the Iran Counter-Proliferation Act of 2007. This bill was introduced on March 8, 2007, and was referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition, to this Committee, among others. The bill has been reported by the Committee on Foreign Affairs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is an agreement with regard to this bill, and so in order to expedite floor consideration, I agree to forego further consideration by the Committee on Financial Services. I do so with the understanding that this decision will not prejudice this Committee with respect to its jurisdictional prerogatives on this or similar legislation. I request your support for the appointment of conferees from this Committee should this bill be the subject of a House-Senate conference.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Please place this letter in the Congressional Record when this bill is considered by the House. I look forward to the bill's consideration and hope that it will command the broadest possible support.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Barney Frank,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>&lt;pre&gt;--&lt;/pre&gt;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington, DC, September 6, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dear Chairman Lantos: In recognition of the desire to expedite consideration of <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill>, the "Iran Counter-Proliferation Act of  2007," the Committee on the Judiciary agrees to waive formal consideration of the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Section 401 of the bill, which requires the President to determine whether the Islamic Revolutionary Guards Corps in Iran should be listed as a foreign terrorist organization under section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act, falls within the rule X jurisdiction of the Committee on the Judiciary.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Committee takes this action with the understanding that by foregoing consideration of <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill> at this time, the Committee on the Judiciary does not waive any jurisdiction over subject matter contained in this or similar legislation. The Committee also reserves the right to seek appointment of an appropriate number of conferees to any House-Senate conference involving this legislation, and requests your support if such a request is made.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would appreciate your including this letter in your Committee's report for <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill>, or in the Congressional Record during consideration of the bill on the House floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thank you for your attention to this matter.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>John Conyers, Jr.,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>&lt;pre&gt;--&lt;/pre&gt;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN AFFAIRS,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington, DC, September 6, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR MR. CHAIRMAN: Thank you for your letter regarding <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill>, the Iran Counter-Proliferation Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I appreciate your willingness to work cooperatively on this legislation. I recognize that the bill contains provisions that fall within the jurisdiction of the Committee on the Judiciary. I acknowledge that the Committee will not seek a sequential referral of the bill and agree that the inaction of your Committee with respect to the bill does not waive any jurisdiction of the Judiciary Committee over subject matter contained in this bill or similar legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Further, as to any House-Senate conference on the bill, I understand that your committee reserves the right to seek the appointment of conferees for consideration of portions of the bill that are within the Committee's jurisdiction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I will ensure that our exchange of letters are included in the Congressional Record during the consideration of House debate on <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill>, and I look forward to working with you on this important legislation. If you wish to discuss this matter further, please contact me or have your staff contact my staff.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Cordially,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Tom Lantos,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>&lt;pre&gt;--&lt;/pre&gt;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>House of Representatives, Committee on Oversight and Government Reform,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington, DC, September 7, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR CHAIRMAN LANTOS: I am writing to confirm our mutual understanding with respect to the consideration of <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill>, the Iran Counter-Proliferation Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As you know, on August 2, 2007, the Committee on Foreign Affairs reported <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill> to the House. The Committee on Oversight and Government Reform (Oversight Committee) appreciates your effort to consult regarding those provisions of <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill> that fall within the Oversight Committee's jurisdiction, including matters related to the federal workforce and contracting.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the interest of expediting consideration of <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill>, the Oversight Committee will not separately consider this legislation. The Oversight Committee does so, however, with the understanding that this does not prejudice the Oversight Committee's jurisdictional interests and prerogatives regarding this bill or similar legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I respectfully request your support for the appointment of outside conferees from the Oversight Committee should <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill> or a similar Senate bill be considered in conference with the Senate. I also request that you include our exchange of letters in the Congressional Record during consideration of this legislation on the House floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thank you for your attention to these matters.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Henry A. Waxman,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>&lt;pre&gt;--&lt;/pre&gt;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN AFFAIRS,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington, DC, September 7, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR MR. CHAIRMAN: Thank you for your letter regarding <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill>, the Iran Counter-Proliferation Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I appreciate your willingness to work cooperatively on this legislation. I recognize that the bill contains provisions that fall within the jurisdiction of the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform. I acknowledge that the Committee will not seek a sequential referral of the bill and agree that the inaction of your Committee with respect to the bill does not prejudice the Oversight Committee's jurisdictional interests and prerogatives regarding this bill or similar legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Further, as to any House-Senate conference on the bill, I understand that your committee reserves the right to seek the appointment of conferees for consideration of portions of the bill that are within the Committee's jurisdiction, and I agree to support a request by the Committee with respect to serving as conferees on the bill (or similar legislation).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I will ensure that our exchange of letters are included in the Congressional Record during the consideration of House debate on <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill>, and I look forward to working with you on this important legislation. If you wish to discuss this matter further, please contact me or have your staff contact my staff.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Cordially,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Tom Lantos,</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400033" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I share my colleagues' concern about the possibility of a nuclear armed Iran, so it is with regret that I must vote against this bill. Similarly to other bills that purported to sanction Iran and which I voted against, this legislation doesn't provide additional tools for diplomacy. Rather it limits the President's flexibility to use sanctions as a tool to deal with the Iranian challenge. However, by focusing the sanctions within it on third-parties such as Russia  and Australia, this bill would make it more difficult to maintain the united international diplomatic front that is critical to resolving the Iranian situation peacefully.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We need to craft a new framework for relations with Iran; one that advances our interests and values through engagement and support for the Iranian people. I believe it is more important than ever for forceful U.S. diplomatic re-engagement to support peace, democracy, and a more secure regional dynamic. We must also undertake the difficult, yet critical, task of engaging directly and honestly with Iran, despite its often destructive and destabilizing role. The lack of a serious diplomatic relationship  strengthens those who seek chaos and isolation, while leaving the U.S. with fewer levers of influence and more blind spots than we can afford.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Faced with the prospect of nuclear war with the Soviet Union, President John F. Kennedy said, "Let us never negotiate out of fear. But let us never fear to negotiate." For the United States and our friends in the Middle East, the prospect of continued terror, violence, and instability is too dire to do otherwise.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400009" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill>, the Iran Counter-Proliferation Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With this bill, the United States will have the tools to persuade Iran's Government to abandon its pursuit of nuclear weapons.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are sending a strong message to the world. We will not tolerate violations of the Genocide Convention. This bill calls for Iranian President Mahmoud Ahmadinejad to be brought before the International Court of Justice for his repeated calls for the destruction of Israel.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We will continue to use diplomatic methods to stand tough and protect our allies abroad. This bill ends all Iranian imports to the United States and restricts U.S. exports to Iran to strictly food and medicine.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also believe economic pressure is an effective deterrence. This bill prevents U.S. subsidiaries of foreign oil companies that are sanctioned for investing in Iran's oil sector from receiving U.S. tax benefits for oil and gas exploration.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Iran will not violate rules and go unnoticed. This bill also encourages the administration to prohibit all Iranian state-owned banks from using the U.S. banking system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400184" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today as a cosponsor and strong supporter of the Iran Counter-Proliferation Act of 2007, <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill>. It is appropriate that we are debating this bill today while Iran's President Mahmoud Ahmadinejad addresses the United Nations General Assembly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The current regime in Iran poses troubling security challenges to the community nations and our allies in the Middle East. The hateful and threatening comments made by the President of Iran against Israel cannot be tolerated. Further, the provocative actions taken by Iran to further their nuclear weapons program are not acceptable. A nuclear Iran would destabilize the region and threaten the United States and our allies. Iran must alter its dangerous course, and the United States needs to be  fully involved to help bring this about.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My commitment to ending Iran's nuclear weapons program is one of the reasons I was an early cosponsor of the Iran Counter Proliferation Act of 2007. <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill> is important legislation that would prevent nuclear cooperation between the United States and any country that provides nuclear assistance to Iran as well as support diplomatic and economic means to resolve the Iranian nuclear problem. It would also expand bilateral sanctions against Iran by severely limiting the export of U.S. items to  Iran and by prohibiting all imports. Additionally, <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill> calls for enhanced UN Security Council efforts in response to Iran's continued defiance of the  international community. Finally, it is important to note that the bill specifically states that the administration cannot interpret anything in the legislation as a congressional authorization of a military strike on Iran.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Earlier this year, the House passed the Iran Sanctions Enabling Act of 2007, <bill type="h" number="2347">H.R. 2347</bill>. This legislation which I also supported would authorize State and local governments to divest from, and prevent investment in, companies with financial ties to Iran's energy sector, or that sell arms to the Government of Iran, and financial institutions that extend credit to the Government of Iran.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill> is logical next step to ensure that the United States does everything in our power to prevent Iran from becoming a nuclear state and further destabilizing the Middle East. I urge my colleagues to support this vital legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400311" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in strongest opposition to this curiously-timed legislation which continues to beat the drums for war against Iran. It is interesting that this legislation was not scheduled for a vote this week, but appeared on the schedule at the last minute after a controversial speech by Iran's President at Columbia University.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The House has obviously learned nothing at all from the Iraq debacle. In 2002, Congress voted to abrogate its Constitutional obligation to declare war and instead transfer that authority to the President. Many of my colleagues have expressed regrets over their decision to transfer this authority to the President, yet this legislation is Iraq all over again. Some have plausibly claimed that the move in this legislation to designate the Iranian military as a foreign terrorist organization is an  attempt to signal to the President that he already has authority under previous resolutions to initiate force against Iran. We should recall that language specifically requiring the President to return to Congress before initiating any strike on Iran was removed from legislation by House leadership this year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In expanding sanctions against Iran and against foreign businesses and countries that do business with Iran, we are hurting the American economy and moving the country closer to war. After all, sanctions are a form of warfare against a nation; and, if anyone has forgotten Cuba, sanctions never achieve the stated goals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation authorizes millions more dollars to identify and support young Iranians to come to the United States. Does anyone believe that we are assisting political opposition to the current Iranian regime by singling Iranians out for U.S. support? How would Americans react if the Chinese government were funding U.S. students to come to China to learn how to overthrow the U.S. government? This move is a counterproductive waste of U.S. taxpayer dollars.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The march to war with Iraq was preceded with numerous bills similar to <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill>. No one should be fooled: supporters of this legislation are aiming the same outcome for Iran. I strongly urge a "no" vote on this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400344" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I again thank the chairman, Mr. Lantos.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no further requests for time, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400231" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from California (Mr. Lantos) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400231" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX, this 15-minute vote on the motion to suspend the rules on <bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill> will be followed by 5-minute votes on motions to suspend the rules postponed yesterday in the following order:</chair>
  <chair><bill type="hr" number="584">H. Res. 584</bill>, by the yeas and nays;</chair>
  <chair><bill type="hc" number="210">H. Con. Res. 210</bill>, by the yeas and nays;</chair>
  <chair><bill type="hr" number="663">H. Res. 663</bill>, by the yeas and nays.</chair>
  <chair>The vote was taken by electronic device, and there were--yeas 397, nays 16, not voting 19, as follows:</chair>
  <chair>[Roll No. 895]</chair>
  <chair>Ackerman</chair>
  <chair>Aderholt</chair>
  <chair>Akin</chair>
  <chair>Alexander</chair>
  <chair>Allen</chair>
  <chair>Altmire</chair>
  <chair>Andrews</chair>
  <chair>Arcuri</chair>
  <chair>Baca</chair>
  <chair>Bachmann</chair>
  <chair>Bachus</chair>
  <chair>Baird</chair>
  <chair>Baker</chair>
  <chair>Barrett (SC)</chair>
  <chair>Barrow</chair>
  <chair>Barton (TX)</chair>
  <chair>Bean</chair>
  <chair>Becerra</chair>
  <chair>Berkley</chair>
  <chair>Berman</chair>
  <chair>Biggert</chair>
  <chair>Bilbray</chair>
  <chair>Bilirakis</chair>
  <chair>Bishop (NY)</chair>
  <chair>Bishop (UT)</chair>
  <chair>Blackburn</chair>
  <chair>Blunt</chair>
  <chair>Boehner</chair>
  <chair>Bonner</chair>
  <chair>Bono</chair>
  <chair>Boozman</chair>
  <chair>Boren</chair>
  <chair>Boswell</chair>
  <chair>Boucher</chair>
  <chair>Boustany</chair>
  <chair>Boyd (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Boyda (KS)</chair>
  <chair>Brady (PA)</chair>
  <chair>Brady (TX)</chair>
  <chair>Braley (IA)</chair>
  <chair>Broun (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Brown (SC)</chair>
  <chair>Brown, Corrine</chair>
  <chair>Brown-Waite, Ginny</chair>
  <chair>Buchanan</chair>
  <chair>Burgess</chair>
  <chair>Burton (IN)</chair>
  <chair>Butterfield</chair>
  <chair>Buyer</chair>
  <chair>Calvert</chair>
  <chair>Camp (MI)</chair>
  <chair>Campbell (CA)</chair>
  <chair>Cannon</chair>
  <chair>Cantor</chair>
  <chair>Capito</chair>
  <chair>Capps</chair>
  <chair>Capuano</chair>
  <chair>Cardoza</chair>
  <chair>Carnahan</chair>
  <chair>Carney</chair>
  <chair>Carter</chair>
  <chair>Castle</chair>
  <chair>Castor</chair>
  <chair>Chabot</chair>
  <chair>Chandler</chair>
  <chair>Clarke</chair>
  <chair>Clay</chair>
  <chair>Cleaver</chair>
  <chair>Clyburn</chair>
  <chair>Coble</chair>
  <chair>Cohen</chair>
  <chair>Cole (OK)</chair>
  <chair>Conaway</chair>
  <chair>Cooper</chair>
  <chair>Costa</chair>
  <chair>Costello</chair>
  <chair>Courtney</chair>
  <chair>Cramer</chair>
  <chair>Crenshaw</chair>
  <chair>Crowley</chair>
  <chair>Cuellar</chair>
  <chair>Culberson</chair>
  <chair>Cummings</chair>
  <chair>Davis (AL)</chair>
  <chair>Davis (CA)</chair>
  <chair>Davis (KY)</chair>
  <chair>Davis, David</chair>
  <chair>Davis, Lincoln</chair>
  <chair>Davis, Tom</chair>
  <chair>Deal (GA)</chair>
  <chair>DeFazio</chair>
  <chair>DeGette</chair>
  <chair>DeLauro</chair>
  <chair>Dent</chair>
  <chair>Diaz-Balart, L.</chair>
  <chair>Diaz-Balart, M.</chair>
  <chair>Dicks</chair>
  <chair>Dingell</chair>
  <chair>Doggett</chair>
  <chair>Donnelly</chair>
  <chair>Doolittle</chair>
  <chair>Doyle</chair>
  <chair>Drake</chair>
  <chair>Dreier</chair>
  <chair>Duncan</chair>
  <chair>Edwards</chair>
  <chair>Ehlers</chair>
  <chair>Ellsworth</chair>
  <chair>Emanuel</chair>
  <chair>Emerson</chair>
  <chair>Engel</chair>
  <chair>English (PA)</chair>
  <chair>Eshoo</chair>
  <chair>Etheridge</chair>
  <chair>Everett</chair>
  <chair>Fallin</chair>
  <chair>Farr</chair>
  <chair>Fattah</chair>
  <chair>Feeney</chair>
  <chair>Ferguson</chair>
  <chair>Filner</chair>
  <chair>Forbes</chair>
  <chair>Fortenberry</chair>
  <chair>Fossella</chair>
  <chair>Foxx</chair>
  <chair>Frank (MA)</chair>
  <chair>Franks (AZ)</chair>
  <chair>Frelinghuysen</chair>
  <chair>Gallegly</chair>
  <chair>Garrett (NJ)</chair>
  <chair>Gerlach</chair>
  <chair>Giffords</chair>
  <chair>Gillibrand</chair>
  <chair>Gingrey</chair>
  <chair>Gohmert</chair>
  <chair>Gonzalez</chair>
  <chair>Goode</chair>
  <chair>Goodlatte</chair>
  <chair>Gordon</chair>
  <chair>Granger</chair>
  <chair>Graves</chair>
  <chair>Green, Al</chair>
  <chair>Green, Gene</chair>
  <chair>Grijalva</chair>
  <chair>Gutierrez</chair>
  <chair>Hall (NY)</chair>
  <chair>Hall (TX)</chair>
  <chair>Hare</chair>
  <chair>Harman</chair>
  <chair>Hastert</chair>
  <chair>Hastings (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Hastings (WA)</chair>
  <chair>Hayes</chair>
  <chair>Heller</chair>
  <chair>Hensarling</chair>
  <chair>Herseth Sandlin</chair>
  <chair>Higgins</chair>
  <chair>Hill</chair>
  <chair>Hinojosa</chair>
  <chair>Hirono</chair>
  <chair>Hobson</chair>
  <chair>Hodes</chair>
  <chair>Hoekstra</chair>
  <chair>Holden</chair>
  <chair>Holt</chair>
  <chair>Honda</chair>
  <chair>Hooley</chair>
  <chair>Hoyer</chair>
  <chair>Hulshof</chair>
  <chair>Hunter</chair>
  <chair>Inglis (SC)</chair>
  <chair>Inslee</chair>
  <chair>Israel</chair>
  <chair>Issa</chair>
  <chair>Jackson (IL)</chair>
  <chair>Jackson-Lee (TX)</chair>
  <chair>Jefferson</chair>
  <chair>Johnson (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Johnson, Sam</chair>
  <chair>Jones (NC)</chair>
  <chair>Jones (OH)</chair>
  <chair>Jordan</chair>
  <chair>Kagen</chair>
  <chair>Kanjorski</chair>
  <chair>Kaptur</chair>
  <chair>Keller</chair>
  <chair>Kennedy</chair>
  <chair>Kildee</chair>
  <chair>Kilpatrick</chair>
  <chair>Kind</chair>
  <chair>King (IA)</chair>
  <chair>King (NY)</chair>
  <chair>Kingston</chair>
  <chair>Kirk</chair>
  <chair>Klein (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Kline (MN)</chair>
  <chair>Knollenberg</chair>
  <chair>Kuhl (NY)</chair>
  <chair>LaHood</chair>
  <chair>Lamborn</chair>
  <chair>Langevin</chair>
  <chair>Lantos</chair>
  <chair>Larsen (WA)</chair>
  <chair>Larson (CT)</chair>
  <chair>Latham</chair>
  <chair>LaTourette</chair>
  <chair>Levin</chair>
  <chair>Lewis (CA)</chair>
  <chair>Lewis (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Lewis (KY)</chair>
  <chair>Linder</chair>
  <chair>Lipinski</chair>
  <chair>LoBiondo</chair>
  <chair>Loebsack</chair>
  <chair>Lofgren, Zoe</chair>
  <chair>Lowey</chair>
  <chair>Lucas</chair>
  <chair>Lungren, Daniel E.</chair>
  <chair>Lynch</chair>
  <chair>Mack</chair>
  <chair>Mahoney (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Maloney (NY)</chair>
  <chair>Manzullo</chair>
  <chair>Marchant</chair>
  <chair>Markey</chair>
  <chair>Marshall</chair>
  <chair>Matheson</chair>
  <chair>Matsui</chair>
  <chair>McCarthy (CA)</chair>
  <chair>McCarthy (NY)</chair>
  <chair>McCaul (TX)</chair>
  <chair>McCollum (MN)</chair>
  <chair>McCotter</chair>
  <chair>McCrery</chair>
  <chair>McGovern</chair>
  <chair>McHenry</chair>
  <chair>McHugh</chair>
  <chair>McIntyre</chair>
  <chair>McKeon</chair>
  <chair>McMorris Rodgers</chair>
  <chair>McNerney</chair>
  <chair>McNulty</chair>
  <chair>Meek (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Meeks (NY)</chair>
  <chair>Melancon</chair>
  <chair>Mica</chair>
  <chair>Michaud</chair>
  <chair>Miller (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Miller (MI)</chair>
  <chair>Miller (NC)</chair>
  <chair>Miller, Gary</chair>
  <chair>Mitchell</chair>
  <chair>Mollohan</chair>
  <chair>Moore (KS)</chair>
  <chair>Moran (KS)</chair>
  <chair>Moran (VA)</chair>
  <chair>Murphy (CT)</chair>
  <chair>Murphy, Patrick</chair>
  <chair>Murphy, Tim</chair>
  <chair>Murtha</chair>
  <chair>Musgrave</chair>
  <chair>Myrick</chair>
  <chair>Nadler</chair>
  <chair>Napolitano</chair>
  <chair>Neal (MA)</chair>
  <chair>Neugebauer</chair>
  <chair>Nunes</chair>
  <chair>Oberstar</chair>
  <chair>Obey</chair>
  <chair>Ortiz</chair>
  <chair>Pallone</chair>
  <chair>Pascrell</chair>
  <chair>Pastor</chair>
  <chair>Payne</chair>
  <chair>Pearce</chair>
  <chair>Pence</chair>
  <chair>Perlmutter</chair>
  <chair>Peterson (MN)</chair>
  <chair>Peterson (PA)</chair>
  <chair>Petri</chair>
  <chair>Pickering</chair>
  <chair>Pitts</chair>
  <chair>Pomeroy</chair>
  <chair>Porter</chair>
  <chair>Price (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Price (NC)</chair>
  <chair>Pryce (OH)</chair>
  <chair>Putnam</chair>
  <chair>Radanovich</chair>
  <chair>Rahall</chair>
  <chair>Ramstad</chair>
  <chair>Rangel</chair>
  <chair>Regula</chair>
  <chair>Rehberg</chair>
  <chair>Reichert</chair>
  <chair>Renzi</chair>
  <chair>Reyes</chair>
  <chair>Reynolds</chair>
  <chair>Richardson</chair>
  <chair>Rodriguez</chair>
  <chair>Rogers (AL)</chair>
  <chair>Rogers (KY)</chair>
  <chair>Rogers (MI)</chair>
  <chair>Rohrabacher</chair>
  <chair>Ros-Lehtinen</chair>
  <chair>Roskam</chair>
  <chair>Rothman</chair>
  <chair>Roybal-Allard</chair>
  <chair>Royce</chair>
  <chair>Ruppersberger</chair>
  <chair>Rush</chair>
  <chair>Ryan (OH)</chair>
  <chair>Ryan (WI)</chair>
  <chair>Salazar</chair>
  <chair>Sali</chair>
  <chair>S&#xE1;nchez, Linda T.</chair>
  <chair>Sanchez, Loretta</chair>
  <chair>Sarbanes</chair>
  <chair>Saxton</chair>
  <chair>Schakowsky</chair>
  <chair>Schiff</chair>
  <chair>Schwartz</chair>
  <chair>Scott (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Scott (VA)</chair>
  <chair>Sensenbrenner</chair>
  <chair>Serrano</chair>
  <chair>Sessions</chair>
  <chair>Sestak</chair>
  <chair>Shadegg</chair>
  <chair>Shays</chair>
  <chair>Shea-Porter</chair>
  <chair>Sherman</chair>
  <chair>Shimkus</chair>
  <chair>Shuler</chair>
  <chair>Shuster</chair>
  <chair>Simpson</chair>
  <chair>Sires</chair>
  <chair>Skelton</chair>
  <chair>Slaughter</chair>
  <chair>Smith (NE)</chair>
  <chair>Smith (NJ)</chair>
  <chair>Smith (TX)</chair>
  <chair>Smith (WA)</chair>
  <chair>Solis</chair>
  <chair>Souder</chair>
  <chair>Space</chair>
  <chair>Spratt</chair>
  <chair>Stearns</chair>
  <chair>Stupak</chair>
  <chair>Sullivan</chair>
  <chair>Sutton</chair>
  <chair>Tancredo</chair>
  <chair>Tanner</chair>
  <chair>Tauscher</chair>
  <chair>Taylor</chair>
  <chair>Terry</chair>
  <chair>Thompson (CA)</chair>
  <chair>Thompson (MS)</chair>
  <chair>Thornberry</chair>
  <chair>Tiberi</chair>
  <chair>Tierney</chair>
  <chair>Towns</chair>
  <chair>Turner</chair>
  <chair>Udall (CO)</chair>
  <chair>Udall (NM)</chair>
  <chair>Upton</chair>
  <chair>Van Hollen</chair>
  <chair>Vel&#xE1;zquez</chair>
  <chair>Visclosky</chair>
  <chair>Walberg</chair>
  <chair>Walden (OR)</chair>
  <chair>Walsh (NY)</chair>
  <chair>Walz (MN)</chair>
  <chair>Wamp</chair>
  <chair>Wasserman Schultz</chair>
  <chair>Waters</chair>
  <chair>Watson</chair>
  <chair>Watt</chair>
  <chair>Waxman</chair>
  <chair>Weiner</chair>
  <chair>Welch (VT)</chair>
  <chair>Weldon (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Weller</chair>
  <chair>Westmoreland</chair>
  <chair>Wexler</chair>
  <chair>Whitfield</chair>
  <chair>Wicker</chair>
  <chair>Wilson (NM)</chair>
  <chair>Wilson (OH)</chair>
  <chair>Wilson (SC)</chair>
  <chair>Wolf</chair>
  <chair>Woolsey</chair>
  <chair>Wu</chair>
  <chair>Wynn</chair>
  <chair>Yarmuth</chair>
  <chair>Young (AK)</chair>
  <chair>Young (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Abercrombie</chair>
  <chair>Baldwin</chair>
  <chair>Bartlett (MD)</chair>
  <chair>Blumenauer</chair>
  <chair>Conyers</chair>
  <chair>Ellison</chair>
  <chair>Flake</chair>
  <chair>Gilchrest</chair>
  <chair>Hinchey</chair>
  <chair>Lee</chair>
  <chair>McDermott</chair>
  <chair>Miller, George</chair>
  <chair>Moore (WI)</chair>
  <chair>Olver</chair>
  <chair>Paul</chair>
  <chair>Stark</chair>
  <chair>Berry</chair>
  <chair>Bishop (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Carson</chair>
  <chair>Cubin</chair>
  <chair>Davis (IL)</chair>
  <chair>Davis, Jo Ann</chair>
  <chair>Delahunt</chair>
  <chair>Herger</chair>
  <chair>Jindal</chair>
  <chair>Johnson (IL)</chair>
  <chair>Johnson, E. B.</chair>
  <chair>Kucinich</chair>
  <chair>Lampson</chair>
  <chair>Platts</chair>
  <chair>Poe</chair>
  <chair>Ross</chair>
  <chair>Schmidt</chair>
  <chair>Snyder</chair>
  <chair>Tiahrt</chair>
  <chair/>
  <chair>Messrs. BLUMENAUER, GEORGE MILLER of California, GILCHREST, BARTLETT of Maryland, CONYERS, HINCHEY, Ms. LEE and Ms. BALDWIN changed their vote from "yea" to "nay."</chair>
  <chair>Mr. NEAL of Massachusetts and Ms. LORETTA SANCHEZ of California changed their vote from "nay" to "yea."</chair>
  <chair>So (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the bill, as amended, was passed.</chair>
  <chair>The result of the vote was announced as above recorded.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
  <chair>Stated if:</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400321" topic="NOT VOTING--19">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on rollcall No. 895 (<bill type="h" number="1400">H.R. 1400</bill>), I missed the vote due to extenuating circumstances. Had I been present, I would have voted "yea."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412010" topic="NOT VOTING--19">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on rollcall No. 895, I was late returning from Walter Reed Army Medical Center and missed the vote. Had I been present, I would have voted "yea."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
