<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1178121609" ordinal="34" title="IMPROVING HEAD START ACT OF 2007">
  <chair> Pursuant to House Resolution 348 and rule XVIII, the Chair declares the House in the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for the consideration of the bill, <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the bill is considered read the first time.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman and Members of the House, today we take up the Head Start Improvement Act of 2007. This is a bipartisan piece of legislation, as it was last year when it was brought to the House floor. And in that vein, I certainly want to begin by thanking the staff on both sides of the aisle that have worked very hard to bring this legislation in this form with the cooperation of the members of both sides of the committee, the majority and the minority. I begin by thanking Mr. Lloyd Horwich, who  is working for Mr. Kildee; Stephanie Milburn, with Mr. McKeon; Sarah Rittling, working with Mr. Castle; and Molly Carter and Ruth Friedman of the majority staff. This staff knows this program backwards and forwards. They have worked long and hard with the Head Start community, with the States, with Governors, with local communities, to make sure that, in fact,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Head Start has been the premiere early education program in this country for more than 40 years. It has served more than 20 million children and families in that time. It is a highly successful research-based, comprehensive childhood development and early education program for low-income children from birth to 5 and for their families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Both Head Start and Early Head Start help our country's most disadvantaged children become better prepared to succeed in school and in life by addressing the needs of the whole child and providing services such as  health and nutrition in addition to the educational curriculum. Its design has always been based in science, and the bill before us builds on the strong foundation again by turning to the best science to renew and improve the Head Start program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Head Start remains a cornerstone of this country's effort to close the achievement gap, to combat poverty, and to provide all its citizens with the opportunity to thrive.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today more than 12 million children in America live in poverty, 20 percent of them under the age of 6. Children who grow up in poverty are more likely to struggle in school, face physical and mental health problems, and see fewer economic opportunities throughout their life.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill before us is central to achieving the goals of No Child Left behind because the achievement gap that appears later on in elementary school begins before these children reach kindergarten. Head Start is one of the most evaluated Federal programs, and research concludes that Head Start works. Recent findings from the congressionally-mandated Impact Study found that after less than one school year, Head Start narrowed the achievement gap by 45 percent in prereading and 28 percent in prewriting.  The study also found that Head Start helped to improve some of the important parenting practices, including helping to increase the frequency with which parents read to and with their children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Another large-scale study on Head Start found that children made significant gains during the Head Start year, and made even greater gains over the kindergarten year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>By the end of kindergarten, Head Start graduates were essentially in the national norms in early reading and writing, narrowed by the achievement gap in vocabulary and general knowledge and early math.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am encouraged that the research concludes that Head Start is doing what we expect and demand that it should do to help prepare children to succeed in school. However, this research shows that there are many new ways to improve Head Start, and I believe we accomplish that in the bill before us. The bill before us will help more children arrive at kindergarten ready to succeed by improving the program quality and expanding access to more children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill includes many improvements to build on the latest research in brain and child development. The bill also recognizes that key to the first-class Head Start programs is teachers. This is absolutely imperative, and this bill works hard to make sure that we continue to provide for improvement and professional development of the teachers in the Head Start program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We increase the teacher qualifications by directing the majority of new funds for program improvement activities, including significant new funds to increase teacher salaries; requiring that all programs use research-based practices to support children's preliteracy and vocabulary skills; requiring a full time staff to develop career ladders and professional development plans; directing the Health and Human Services agency to implement an observational assessment tool that will evaluate classroom  quality and provide immediate feedback for programs on their strengths and weaknesses; improving the professional development and training and technical assistance systems so that they are better grounded in science and more responsive to local training needs; and requiring the Secretary to reevaluate and update current early learning standards and assessments using the best science available.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The point is this: This is a major revamping of the Head Start program, with an emphasis on quality, with an emphasis on outcomes, with an emphasis on the assessments and how these programs are doing so that we can provide the continuous improvement of these programs, and we can provide continuous high-quality programs to the children who are in need of these programs. It's only then that we can be assured that Head Start will continue to earn its reputation as the premier early childhood education  and development program in this Nation. It is only then that we can say to the taxpayers that this continues to be a very wise investment of the dollars in the children of this Nation in providing them access to the kinds of programs that are necessary if they are going to be able to take advantage of the educational opportunities in K-12, if they are going to be able to close the gap between themselves and middle-income kids, if they are going to be able to go to school with those skills.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe that this legislation does that. This legislation builds on what was tried and worked on in the last session of Congress under the leadership of Mr. Castle, Mr. McKeon, Mr. Boehner, myself and Mr. Kildee. This is a continuation of that process, and that's why it received the overwhelming bipartisan support when it was reported from the committee. I hope that my colleagues will lend it the same kind of support at the end of this debate and the amendment  process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With that, Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, let me start by commending my friends, Chairman Miller, Chairman Kildee and Mr. Castle, for their hard work on this good bill, which I am so pleased we were able to pass with an overwhelming bipartisan majority in committee 2 months ago.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While the resources to fund Head Start are significant, more work is needed to achieve the ultimate program goal on closing the readiness gap between Head Start children and their more advantaged peers as they enter kindergarten.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Some studies indicate that children enrolled in Head Start do make some progress, but at the same time we need to understand that we still have some work ahead of us in closing the readiness gap. With this in mind, the bill before us today will strengthen Head Start's academic standards by emphasizing cognitive development and the results of scientifically based research in topics critical to children's school readiness.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The measure also aims to improve teacher quality by ensuring a greater number of Head Start teachers have degrees and are adequately trained in early childhood development, particularly in teaching the fundamentals. That's great news for those children who will be participating in the Head Start program years down the road.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have also been disappointed that in recent years we have heard many stories that have marred Head Start's good name. In various communities we found that financial abuse within Head Start centers is far too commonplace. In fact, a March 2005 report from the Government Accountability Office warned that the financial control system in the Head Start program is flawed in failing to prevent multi-million-dollar financial abuses that cheat poor children, taxpayers and law-abiding Head Start operators.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the 109th Congress, Republicans led the House in passing a Head Start reauthorization bill that addressed these weaknesses in the Head Start financial control system. I believe the bill before us moves in that direction as well. It will require Head Start operators to meet a range of financial disclosure requirements as a condition of receiving and keeping their Federal Head Start grants. Furthermore, under this bill, grantees would have to be overseen by a local governance board that provides  direction and actively oversees program activities. These are positive steps to ensure abuses are minimized, and that taxpayers' funds and the children those funds are meant to serve are protected.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, while this bill does represent overall progress for Head Start, I would be remiss if I did not note that there are some significant flaws in it, flaws that I hope we can correct before this measure is sent to the President. For example, under this measure the majority has decided to expand Head Start eligibility to those who the program was not designed to serve. Ultimately I believe this policy change may have the impact of leaving many children who live in poverty underserved  by Head Start programs. This runs contrary to what we all believe to be the mission of this program and will do nothing to strengthen Head Start services; if anything, it will weaken them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am also disappointed that the House will not have an opportunity  today to vote on an amendment offered yesterday at the Rules Committee by Mr. Fortu&#xF1;o, to protect the civil liberties of faith-based providers by clarifying that these institutions are not required to relinquish their Civil Rights Act hiring protections when they participate in the Federal Head Start program. These protections are already the law of the land with regard  to various Federal programs, including those impacting welfare reform and Community Service Block Grants. In fact, President Clinton himself signed such language into the law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Fortu&#xF1;o amendment also would have ensured religious organizations would not be forced to remove art, icons, Scripture or other symbols in order to receive Federal Head Start grants. Barring these providers from fully participating in Head Start is not only a disservice to the faith-based providers, but also to the children who depend on the Head Start program and the taxpayers who should know that Federal dollars are granted to the best available service providers, faith-based or otherwise.  Instead, the majority thrust upon us an amendment that praises the work of faith-based organizations, but does not protect their civil rights. It's literally all talk and no action. Indeed, the only people protected by this amendment are certain members of the majority party seeking political cover. Faith-based providers are left to fend for themselves.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, in spite of these flaws, which I hope we can correct in time, the Improving Head Start Act remains a solid reauthorization measure. Head Start is a good program that is capable of achieving even greater results, and the bill before us will help us get there.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>I yield 4 minutes now to the gentleman from Michigan (Mr. Kildee), subcommittee chair and responsible for bringing this bill to the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400216" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, in March, the Education and Labor Committee overwhelming passed by a vote of 42-1 <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>, which was my privilege to introduce with both Democrats and Republicans as cosponsors. I hope at the close of today's debate the full House will do similarly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Head Start has served our most vulnerable children and families well for 42 years; and more recently, early Head Start has done the same for infants and toddlers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Head Start works, and this bill will make it work even better. This bill increases Head Start's authorization by $461 million to benefit as many as 10,000 more children, and increases funding for Indian and migrant and seasonal Head Start programs. It sets aside 60 percent of new funds for activities such as teacher salaries, professional development and extended program hours. It suspends the flawed national reporting system. It improves teacher qualifications. It increases access to Early Head  Start. It improves training and technical assistance to help programs identify their strengths and weaknesses. And it strengthens the quality of Head Start boards and maintains strong parental involvement through shared governance of Head Start programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would note that we are expecting a motion to recommit that would allow faith-based programs to discriminate in hiring based on religion using Federal funds. Before supporting this bill by 42-1, the committee considered and rejected such a policy. Faith-based programs can and do participate in Head Start and have done so for many years, and I support that strongly. However, this motion is wrong, and I encourage my colleagues to oppose it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In closing, I want to thank Chairman Miller for his outstanding work through the years on this program and for his specific work this year. This is a very good bill. I want to thank Ranking Members McKeon and Castle, it was really a pleasure to work with them, and all the members of the committee for their hard work on this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to thank the staff, especially Ruth Friedman, Chairman Miller's senior policy adviser; Susan Ross and James Bergeron with Ranking Member McKeon; and Jessica Gross with Ranking Member Castle; and Lloyd Horwich of my staff.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I look forward to passage of this bill today and to working through the conference committee to see that this bill becomes law.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 5 minutes at this time to the senior Republican on the subcommittee. I am proud of all the work that he has done to bring this bill to the floor last Congress and this Congress, the gentleman from Delaware (Mr. Castle).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400070" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I thank the distinguished ranking member of the subcommittee for his kind words and for yielding. I also obviously thank Mr. Miller and Mr. Kildee for their work on this, and Ms. Woolsey, who has worked on it before with me. And I am pleased to be able to be here.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I support the legislation before us today which will reauthorize the Head Start program. And like almost every other Member of this body, I believe strongly in the benefits of this program. I trust that <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>, the Improving Head Start Act, will improve Head Start by emphasizing that every child, regardless of their economic status, should have the best chance possible to succeed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1965, Head Start was created to give economically disadvantaged children access to the same educational, health, nutritional, social and other services that were enjoyed by their more affluent peers. The goal of the program was, as it remains today, to provide children a solid foundation that will prepare them for success in school and later in life.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As the centerpiece of the Federal Government's efforts to support quality early childhood education for our Nation's most disadvantaged youth, Head Start has served nearly 20 million low-income children and their families. Currently Head Start serves over 900,000 children every day and has over 1,600 grantees across the United States. In my home State of Delaware, Head Start programs serve over 2,000 children, with over 800 additional 3- and 4-year-olds receiving assistance through State government  funding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We all can agree on the need for Head Start and its successes. We must also recognize that Head Start can produce even greater results for children. Students who attend Head Start programs do start school more prepared than those with similar backgrounds who do not attend Head Start. However, Head Start students continue to enter kindergarten well below national norms of school readiness. By moving to close the school readiness gap, this bill will improve results for almost a million Head Start  students across the Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Toward the goal of closing the readiness gap, the Improving Head Start Act strengthens Head Start's academic focus while maintaining its comprehensive nature that is imperative to its success. The bill improves the academic focus of the program by establishing new quality standards that ensure enrolled children develop and demonstrate language skills; prereading knowledge, including an interest in and appreciation of books, reading and writing; premathematics knowledge, such as recognition of  numbers and counting; cognitive abilities related to academic achievement; and social development important for environments constructive for child development, early learning and school success.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Research consistently demonstrates a link between the learning potential of children and the level of education and training of classroom teachers. For that reason, we improve the quality of teachers in Head Start classrooms by requiring that in time 50 percent of all Head Start teachers nationwide must have a baccalaureate degree.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>As I am sure some of my colleagues know, this bill does not include a proposed State demonstration project, which was incorporated into the legislation the House passed in 2003. I believe strongly, however, in the policy goals of increased coordination and integration that were and continue to be at the heart of efforts to remove barriers and prevent collaboration between Head Start and successful State and local early childhood initiatives. I believe the proposal to be offered by Tom Price  of Georgia would foster integration among quality early childhood programs, and plan on supporting Mr. Price's amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>About 40 States, including Delaware, have established some form of early  childhood education, because States recognize that these services can make a real difference in preparing children for a successful future. Various local initiatives have also been launched, and today, disadvantaged children and families have access to programs and services from a wide range of sources.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Some of these programs rival or exceed the quality of Head Start, while others fall short. Head Start is no longer the only option for early childhood education, and we must ensure that all children are receiving the same quality education. In this new era, Head Start should be working toward integrating service with other school readiness programs not competing against them. Where we previously would have allowed no more than eight States to improve Head Start coordination with State and local  efforts, this bill will ensure programs in all 50 States are able to increase collaboration.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are encouraging Head Start grantees to align their academics with State-developed K-12 academic content standards, as well as to have a more active partnership with local school districts that serve the same communities. This will help to facilitate a smooth transition to kindergarten for their students.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, we are asking early childhood providers in the State, including Head Start, preschool and child care, to come together to identify ways to integrate school readiness initiatives across the State.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As I have said, I believe strongly in the Head Start program, particularly because of how the program helps children later in their lives. Despite these stories, we have also heard many stories of programs in which funds were being diverted away from this purpose.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 2005, the GAO released a report that warned the financial control system in the Federal Head Start early childhood program is flawed and failing to prevent multimillion-dollar financial abuses that cheat poor children, taxpayers and law-abiding Head Start operators. The GAO made some helpful recommendations on how we can strengthen the oversight structure to prevent abuses and protect good grantees. They recommended that increased competition in the program could help weed out poorly performing  grantees and ensure high-quality services are available to children and families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In response to the GAO's recommendations of how to eliminate financial mismanagement, we are increasing the competitive nature of the current program. The competition requirements in the Improving Head Start Act will help to alleviate these problems, but, more importantly, will drive program improvement across the board. Program improvements will ultimately help thousands of children nationwide, which should always be our goal.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As I said at the outset, Head Start is an important and very popular program. The importance of early childhood education services cannot be overstated. I believe strongly that the reforms sought in <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill> will go a long way to institute needed reforms in an already successful program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support the legislation, and I thank all those who worked on this, including the staff, and I look forward to the passage of the legislation today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield for the purpose of making a unanimous consent request to the gentleman from Texas (Mr. Gene Green).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Mr. GENE GREEN of Texas asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400160" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise today to express my support for the Head Start Reauthorization Bill that was sent to this Chamber.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Head Start is one of the best programs we offer our youngest students.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since its creation in 1965, it has proven to be our most valuable school readiness program in the history of this country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Especially, now that we know more about the importance of early-childhood education.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Time after time, we have seen reports that prove students who attend Head Start perform better than those who don't.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It has also proven to help close the achievement gap between students of differing socioeconomic status.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Republican amendment to this bill would repeal existing civil rights protections that ensure programs cannot use federal funds to discriminate in their hiring practices.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Head Start teachers should be chosen because they are qualified and effective teachers who will help children succeed and thrive.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Discrimination should not be supported with public funds.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>National religious organizations, civil rights groups, national labor organizations, and the education groups all oppose any roll back of civil rights protections.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is such a critical program, and it's important that this body reauthorize this program in a manner that shows bipartisan support for educating our children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thousands of children in my district benefit from Head Start and it's essential that we reauthorize this program with a bipartisan plan that will help this program serve more children effectively.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 1 1/2  minutes to the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Davis).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I want to begin by thanking Chairman Miller, Ranking Member McKeon, Chairman Kildee and Ranking Member Castle, as well as both the majority and minority staff for their hard work and for including so many issues near and dear to my heart in this bill. Some of those are recruiting minority male teachers; emphasizing children's social, emotional well-being; recognizing the expanding role of grandparents and kinship caregivers  in children's lives; keep parent councils as equals to the governing boards; incorporating the best practices from the field of home visitation into the Early Head Start programs; and encouraging the development of on-line graduate training. All of these are key issues to me and to the people of Chicago. I know that you have toiled long and hard to integrate Member concerns, and you have my appreciation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, I am very pleased that this bipartisan bill preserves the anti-discrimination history of Head Start advocated so ardently by the Head Start and religious communities. Federal funds are not meant to support discrimination of any type, and I applaud the Members of both sides for maintaining this fundamental commitment to justice and fairness in this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, I must mention a concern from Chicago Head Start programs. I know that the Chairs and ranking members have worked hard to address the problems surrounding low-income families in high cost of living areas such as Chicago from losing access to this critical child development program. I ask that the issue of income eligibility continue to be discussed so that the children of working poor families can be included.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400070" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield such time as he may consume to the wonderful Representative from Michigan (Mr. Ehlers).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400119" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise to briefly address a topic which I have not heard discussed here, although I have heard it discussed numerous times within the committee itself. I am very unhappy with the resulting bill that came out this year. The issue I wish to discuss is Head Start programs operated by faith-based institutions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What has happened in this bill is that we basically have reversed the Civil Rights Act, which provides that faith-based institutions may discriminate in hiring by hiring people of the same faith as the institution. If it is a church, for example, they can hire people who are members of their church or denominationm without violating civil rights laws. That is specifically legal under the Civil Rights Act. This bill prevents an institution from doing that; if they wish to operate a Head Start  program, then they are not allowed to hire on that basis. So this bill is actually a reversal of the Civil Rights Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, why is this important? Why do churches need to do that? A perfect example was given last year during the debate on this bill in committee, when Representative Tom Osborne, better known as Coach Osborne, related an example in his district where a small church which had a small staff decided to operate a program similar to the Head Start program. They wanted to hire someone who could serve on their staff half-time and also operate the  educational  program during the other half of their time. But they needed someone of their faith to do the church work. But this bill would prohibit that person to also teach in the school, but they were hired on a religious basis.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is so much misunderstanding on this issue, and it really puzzles me, because I have very good friends over on the other side of the aisle whom I know have a deep religious faith. But why they are so anti-religious on this subject, I do not understand. They seem to believe that they have to prevent anyone with a religious belief from operating within a program of this sort.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have to keep reminding everyone, this is not a case of churches trying to proselytize by having someone of their own faith running the program and teaching the kids that faith. That is not it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The point is simply that faith-based institutions, by virtue of their faith, are determined to help people in the community who need help. It doesn't matter whether it is a Head Start program, whether it is a food program, as we operate in my church back home, or many other programs. They are doing it as an expression of their faith.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, is this wrong? Do we have to say, I am sorry, you can't run this program because you are a member of this church and you might express your faith? That is not what they are trying to do. So why do we have to go to great lengths in this particular bill to stop people from doing that, to prevent churches and other faith-based institutions from operating a Head Start program, unless they hire people from outside their church? That, to me, is grossly unfair. Frankly, I think it violates the  Constitution, and I am strongly opposed to that practice.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Other than that, I think it is a wonderful bill and I would like to support this bill, but I am terribly disturbed by this anti-religious altitude that I have seen manifested here. I hope we can change this in this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 1 minute to the gentleman from Texas (Mr. Hinojosa).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Mr. HINOJOSA asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400179" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>I thank Chairman Miller for extending time to me.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in strong support of <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>, the Improving Head Start Act. This legislation is long overdue. I would like to commend Chairman Miller and Ranking Member McKeon and Subcommittee Chairman Kildee and Ranking Member Castle for working together to craft bipartisan legislation that will significantly improve the Head Start Program, especially for Hispanic and migrant farm worker families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is my hope that this spirit of bipartisanship will carry the legislation all the way to the President's desk for his signature. I strongly urge a "yes" vote on <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in strong support of <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>, the Improving Head Start Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation is long overdue. I would like to commend Chairman Miller and Ranking Member McKeon and Subcommittee Chairman Kildee and Ranking Member Castle for working together to craft bipartisan legislation that will significantly improve the Head Start program--especially for Hispanic and migrant farm worker families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is my hope that this spirit of bipartisanship will carry the legislation all the way to the President's desk for his signature.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is also my hope that this body will reject any attempts to allow discrimination to infect the Heat Start program--whether the discrimination is based on religion or on the language that is spoken at home.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill before us today strengthens "Head Start" for Hispanics and families whose primary language is not English.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Here are just a few of the highlights: The bill increases the base funding for Migrant and Seasonal Head Start to a minimum of 5 percent of the overall Head Start funding, which means that more farm worker children will be in preschool instead of in the fields; the bill sets standards for communications with limited English proficient (LEP) parents so that language is not a barrier to Head Start access.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It instructs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to conduct a study of how Head Start programs serve LEP populations. It enhances Head Start transitions for LEP children to kindergarten.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It provides technical assistance resources for improving the quality of Head Start services for LEP populations, particularly in communities that have</paragraph>
    <paragraph>experienced a rapid and large increase in Head Start eligible LEP children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It improves ensures that LEP children have access to linguistically and culturally appropriate instructional services that support proficiency in the English language and gains in other domains important for school readiness, including pre-literacy and numeracy skills.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It addresses the shortage of qualified teachers with expertise in serving LEP children by establishing a teacher career ladder demonstration program at Hispanic-serving Institutions and tribally-controlled Colleges and Universitites.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Tehese are significant improvements to the Head Start Program. Again, I would like to thank the chair and ranking member for working with us to include them in the bill before us today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I strongly urge a "yes" vote on <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400070" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 1 1/2  minutes to the gentlewoman from California (Ms. Woolsey), a member of the committee.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400436" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, we must ensure that no matter where a child comes from or what his or her background is, that child has an equal opportunity to succeed in school and in life. That begins with quality early childhood education, and that is why we need to and must reauthorize Head Start.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill will allow 10,000 more children to benefit from the Head Start program. But many, many more children are eligible for Head Start, and those children will continue to be left behind. A real investment in our children would ensure that every single child who is eligible has access to this very successful program. Without full funding, some children continue to start elementary school far behind their peers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Some Members, as my friend on the other side of the aisle talked about, would like to allow Head Start programs to discriminate by using taxpayer dollars to hire staff based upon their religion, which is against everything I believe that the Head Start program stands for. When we already have a shortage of qualified Head Start teachers, we must not allow qualified teachers to be turned away simply because of their religion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, children are 25 percent of our population. They are 100 percent of our future. We must support and expand Head Start for the best possible beginning of their lives.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400070" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>I yield 1 1/2  minutes to the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Hare), a member of the committee.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412204" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise today in strong support of <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>, the Improving Head Start Act. As a member of the Education and Labor Committee, I had the privilege of working on this bipartisan bill, which I believe will help more children arrive at kindergarten ready to succeed. Not only does this bill improve teacher quality, expand access and strengthen school readiness, it also addresses the unique challenges faced by rural Head Start programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Much of my district is rural. Therefore, I worked with several of my colleagues to ensure Head Start providers receive the support and flexibility required to serve America's rural communities. Specifically, we provided the assistance needed to improve transportation services in rural areas, the recruitment and retention of qualified instructors for rural programs and outreach to rural families. Later today, I will offer an amendment with my colleagues, Congressmen SPACE, WELCH  and ALTMIRE that will further expand this assistance to rural Head Start.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Head Start is the country's premier early education childhood development and education program, serving more than 900,000 of our Nation's most needy families annually. Children who attend Head Start make gains in vocabulary, early writing and social behavior and enter school better prepared than lower income children who do not attend Head Start.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is critical that all eligible families know about Head Start and that Congress allocates the necessary resources Head Start providers need in order to continue and expand these successful programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge all my colleagues to stand up for rural and low income children by voting "yes" on <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400070" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 4 minutes to the gentleman from Utah (Mr. Bishop).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400029" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I thank the gentleman from Delaware for giving me this opportunity to discuss the concept of Head Start, which is a significant program that does a great deal of good for kids who are in dire need of this kind of service.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If indeed the decisions that we made in life were always of a vast contrast, differences were black versus white, night versus day, even the simple ones of right versus wrong, our life would be easy and our choices would be easy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But, unfortunately, life is not like that. The decisions and choices we get to make are always going to be a shade of gray. We are given oftentimes two goods, and we have to decide which is the better choice. How we make those decisions identifies us as individuals; but it also defines what we are as a society.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This particular debate today is dealing with one of those basic choices between two goods. We have one of the big differences with this particular reauthorization of Head Start versus the reauthorization of Head Start that we passed last year, both of them good bills, is the concept of faith-based institutions within these two bodies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One of the things that bothered me also as a speech teacher is as we are talking about this issue, sometimes we are talking different angles, kind of like ships passing in the night, without discussing the same definition of terms.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One side will say that faith-based institutions should not be used because of the hiring practices. If this institution decides to hire within their own religious group, a program that is legal both legislatively as well as judicially, then they should not be used in the concept of Head Start, or used as a program for Head Start. It has nothing to do with proselytizing, it has to do with whether they should be used at all. The other side simply says value is what is best for kids. Those are two  goods. Neither one is necessarily bad. The issue is: Which is more important to us?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am going to make the argument to you that if we really want to define our society, what we have to do is to say our highest value for this education program is what is best for kids. If, indeed, a faith-based institution is the best program to help kids break the cycle of poverty, understand the importance of education to try to lead a better life and improve their lives and their family's at the same time, then that has to be our highest value. That must be our highest value.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What we have to do is avoid the biases that we have on any other issue. The question is what best helps kids. Once again, if a faith-based institution is the best way of helping a kid, do it. For heaven's sake, do it. Do not hold kids hostage to our own social dogma. It may not be a bad social dogma, but the question is, where is our priority? What are our values?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With these kids who desperately need this help, this assistance, the most important thing is to give them that help so they can move forward and they can break the poverty cycle, and they can move on with their lives and help themselves and their families at the same time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If that is not our goal, if that is not our purpose, if we are really not talking about how to help kids best, then we are fooling ourselves and making poor choices and kind of demeaning the entire debate and discussion of what the Federal Government will do in the area of education.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Once again, Mr. Chairman, we will have a chance to discuss these issues again in some other format, but I would urge my colleagues to remember we have to make a choice somehow, and our choice should be in the best interest of kids, and everything else, everything else, has to be secondary to that goal.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 2 minutes to the gentleman from Virginia (Mr. Scott).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400364" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, we have just heard the suggestion that some programs might be better if only the program sponsors could discriminate in employment. We hadn't heard those arguments for over 40 years before this administration came in.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let's talk about when you say "protect civil liberties," what liberties you are protecting? If you are protecting somebody's right to tell somebody they can't get a job because of their religion, if you can discriminate against someone because of their religion, racial discrimination laws essentially cannot be enforced. So who are you protecting? You are protecting the one trying to discriminate; the victim of discrimination loses all protection.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The children of families of unpopular religions will ask their parents why they couldn't get a job in the Head Start program, and they will have to be told they are not hiring people of our religion. Just what kind of Head Start is that?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Proponents are saying we lose opportunities. We have plenty of opportunities in Head Start. All we have to do is fund it more, and there will be plenty of opportunities for Head Start programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There has also been a suggestion you may have to take icons off the wall. If icons have to be taken down, it is because of a violation of the establishment clause of the Constitution. Let me tell you, passing a motion to recommit will not solve a violation of the establishment clause.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Forty years ago race and religious discrimination was found to be so reprehensible that we made it illegal even with your private funds. Now we have a plea to protect the people trying to discriminate and not the victims of discrimination. We need to leave the law the way it has been for the last 40 years. We can keep the antidiscrimination laws and those programs. Any program that can get funded with this faith-based initiative amendment could be funded anyway if you just comply with the antidiscrimination  laws that have been in effect for the last 40 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We ought not to have to tell our children why certain parents can't get a job in a program because we are failing to protect the civil rights of the victim of discrimination because all of a sudden we are interested in the civil rights of the person trying to discriminate.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400070" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 1 1/2  minutes to the gentleman from Kentucky (Mr. Yarmuth).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412211" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, as we pass the reins of our Nation to future generations, we must acknowledge that America's continued prosperity in the global economy will not be ensured unless we equip our children, the leaders of tomorrow, with the tools they need to succeed down the road.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To achieve this, we must cultivate not just the most privileged students, not only our brightest students, but also the students who grew up with disadvantages. Indeed, we must nurture the potential of all our children because it is in the best interest of our country to maximize the contributions and success of every American.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I recently visited a Head Start program at Indian Trail Elementary in my district in Louisville. The veritable beehive of activity there spoke louder than 40 years of studies on Head Start progress, but they said the same thing: The thoroughly engaged children were actively building a solid foundation for their futures, and they were loving the pursuit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Like their predecessors, the 1,800 Head Start students in Louisville and the 1 million nationwide are making tremendous gains in family literacy, vocabulary, early writing, letter recognition, and social behavior, skills that will pay huge dividends in their future pursuits.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have an opportunity today to extend and improve this program which is so vital to the preparation of today's youth, who in turn are critical to America's future. It is our moral responsibility and I believe our honor and privilege to reauthorize Head Start, and I urge my colleagues to join me in doing so.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400070" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 1 1/2  minutes to the gentleman from Massachusetts (Mr. Tierney).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400407" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I thank the gentleman from California for yielding me this time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are told over and over again in committee hearings from experts and scholars of all natures that we could close 50 percent of the achievement gap  that we see in our country if we have effective preschool, prekindergarten programs. Head Start is just that kind of a program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We see over and over again the evidence showing us it has a positive economic and social impact across this Nation, particularly in its comprehensive nature, the fact that it deals with education, deals with health issues and social implications.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Commonwealth of Massachusetts, my State, 80 percent of 3-year-olds are still not enrolled in prekindergarten or Head Start programs. We need to be expanding this program for all of the good things it does because we need to take advantage of that opportunity to close that gap.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One of the ways that we are going to do that is to attract quality teachers. I am glad to see in this bill that Mr. Sestak has filed an amendment to provide up to $10,000 in loan forgiveness for college graduates who commit to teach in the Head Start field. We have raised the standard of the teachers that we want, requiring them to meet a certain grade. That means we are going to have to pay people in order to go into this profession because it is still going to cost them considerably  to get that degree. If we are going to do that, we have to step forward. I think Mr. Sestak's idea, which we have been talking about in the higher education reauthorization bill for some time, is one way of doing that. Loan forgiveness for early education teachers over a period of years will allow us to have that program meet the pinnacle that we need it to reach.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For this and many other reasons, I think this bill is a good bill and deserves our attention and our support. I ask my colleagues to join me in voting for it.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400070" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 4 minutes to the gentleman from Georgia (Mr. Price).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I thank the gentleman from Delaware for allowing me to come and chat on a little different topic, a topic that we tried to bring to the floor today on this bill, and a topic that I think would truly expand and protect children in the Head Start program, but a topic that wasn't allowed to be brought to the floor because an amendment wasn't allowed. I think this issue truly demonstrates where the priorities of the majority party are.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This issue that I attempted to bring to the floor would have resulted in significantly greater safety for the children who are transported in Head Start programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1992, Mr. Chairman, Congress required the issuance of regulations that related to rear-door emergency exits and safety restraints on Head Start transportation. That was in 1992. Since the final rule for these new regulations was published, the effective date has been delayed three times.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last week, buried deep in <bill type="h" number="1591">H.R. 1591</bill>, the emergency supplemental for Iraq, was language that delays these transportation safety requirements for Head Start programs once again. The fine print reveals that the rear emergency exit requirements are delayed for another year, and a seat belt safety requirement is delayed until another study is done.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Well, Congress required these regulations to ensure the safe operation of vehicles by Head Start agencies; and currently, the leading cause of death for children ages 3 to 7 is motor vehicle, traffic crashes. The reason why these transportation requirements were put forth is that the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration does not approve of the use of vans or cars or vehicles of other types for the purpose of providing planned transportation services. School buses are the safest form  of transportation because they include many special features. Further delaying these requirements means authorizing that Head Start grantees can transport children using vehicles that are not designed specifically for the purpose of the safe transportation of children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My amendment, which wasn't allowed, would have ended this delay and make the regulations for emergency rear-door exits and seat belts on vehicles used to transport children effective immediately.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, as you know, on the first day of this Congress, children were paraded in front of the American people, and the new majority claimed that the House would come to order for the children. Well, today, if it is truly about the children, then the majority would have allowed this amendment to be entertained. Any further delays endangers lives of children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I suggest, Mr. Chairman, that the hypocrisy of this process is telling, and that if we truly are interested in making certain that our greatest resource, our children, the future of our Nation, are protected, then we would have allowed this amendment, and I am distressed it wasn't allowed. I encourage through the process the majority party make certain that we address this as this bill moves forward.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 1 1/2  minutes to the gentleman from New York (Mr. Bishop).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400031" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I thank the chairman for yielding me this time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise today in strong support of <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>, the Improving Head Start Act. I represent the majority of Suffolk County where 20 Head Start and three Early Head Start centers have been serving the community since 1966. In fact, my wife's first job out of college was as a Head Start teacher in one of those centers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Parents, teachers and many of our colleagues can all agree that Head Start is one of our Nation's most prominent and successful early education programs. This bill continues to build on Head Start's successes by ensuring that kids are prepared for school, by improving teacher and classroom quality, strengthening the focus on school readiness, increasing accountability and boosting coordination.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Research finds that children who attend Head Start enter school better prepared than low-income children who do not attend the program, and that children who attend Head Start make significant gains.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If we are serious about achieving the goals set forth by No Child Left Behind, then passing Head Start reauthorization is a down payment on achieving those goals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>During the markup of this bill, I was proud to offer an amendment that would allow Head Start programs to use up to 10 percent of their quality improvement funds for transportation costs. This amendment was in response to concerns brought to me by my constituents that many have thought programs were being forced to choose between providing transportation to children or sacrificing the quality of their program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With my amendment and so many other worthwhile improvements to Head Start, I strongly encourage my colleagues to support this balanced reauthorization for the benefit of our children and future generations of America.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, we have no further speakers, and we reserve the balance of our time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 1 1/2  minutes to the gentlewoman from Texas (Ms. Jackson-Lee).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Ms. JACKSON-LEE of Texas asked and was given permission to revise and extend her remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400199" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I thank the chairman of the full committee for his leadership and all the members of the committee and Mr. Kildee for his leadership as well on some of these very important issues. We have worked together. I thank the ranking member for their long-standing understanding that we must collaborate when it comes to teaching our children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise to support <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill> and had the pleasure of visiting a Head Start facility in my community. What was the greatest joy was to be able to see the parents and children working together on this very special day, and I want to thank the committee for persevering against all odds, particularly the opposition of those who would say it is time to change drastically, to do a surgical reform on Head Start.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It has worked for some 30-plus years, and what has been done in this legislation is the right direction: enhanced professional development, providing more degreed teachers teaching, providing opportunity for the associate degrees, working with caretakers or assistants in the classroom, and really  teaching our children the "yes, I can" method.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise also to support the amendment of Congresswoman Eddie Bernice Johnson that will be offered that provides the opportunity for collaboration with historically black colleges.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What we need to be doing is investing more in Head Start by proving that it has been a success, improving classroom and teacher quality, raising the quality of teachers, and increasing funding for teacher and staff salaries.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But most importantly, anyone who has taken the opportunity to see the youngsters, the babies that are in this program, see their eyes open wide, see them understand the world and the colors and what is real and that they can be the greatness that they are, we know that <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill> is on the right path, and I encourage my colleagues to enthusiastically support the Improving Head Start Act of 2007. These are the babies not of yesterday, but today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph> Mr. Chairman, I rise in strong support of <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>, the Improving the Head Start Act of 2007. This bipartisan legislation would allow up to 10,000 more children from low-income families to have access to the world of opportunities offered by early developmental education. It also appropriates the funding required for a range of necessary improvements, ensuring we are offering our children comprehensive and regulated programs. I urge my colleagues to join me in expressing that a child's educational  and developmental opportunities should not be limited by his or her family's income.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Head Start creates opportunities for children who are born without any. This program provides comprehensive early education programs and support services for well over a million children across our Nation; children whose families would otherwise be unable to offer them these opportunities. The program's holistic approach to education provides a wide range of services in addition to basic education, including medical and dental screenings, nutritional services, parental involvement activities,  and mental health services. Poverty has proven devastating to child development and success, but Head Start has proven capable of providing the broad range of support that all children need to succeed in school, and indeed in life.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This program is particularly crucial to minority communities. Of the over 1 million children enrolled in Head Start programs, 65 percent belong to minority groups. In a world and a country where minority children may continue to face discrimination and limited opportunities, Head Start ensures that they are prepared to begin school when they reach the proper age. This program has proven successful in minimizing the "readiness gap" between program participants and their more affluent peers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In Harris County, TX, where my district is located, Head Start has been active since 1999. In this county alone, the program currently operates in 17 locations, and has served over 5,000 children since its inception. There are, at present, over 1,170 children enrolled in its wide array of programs. In Harris County, and across our Nation, Head Start programs help children grow mentally, socially, emotionally, and physically.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill contains many vital provisions. It authorizes an additional $450 million dollars for 2008, funds that would allow up to 10,000 more children access to Head Start programs. It increases funding for teacher and staff salaries, ensuring a quality workforce and providing for the hiring of additional qualified staff. <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill> re-evaluates and updates the current standards and assessments, suspending the badly flawed National Reporting System. The bill also boosts cooperation between Head  Start and state and local child care programs, as well as improving coordination with state health, mental health, and family services.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill also contains important provisions to improve accountability for these government-funded programs. It includes a new system of application review that assesses program quality, allowing the Secretary of Health and Human Services to more quickly strip funding from low-quality programs. These review systems ensure both that our Nation's children are receiving the best services we can offer them, and that taxpayer dollars are spent to maximum effect.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, as Chair of the Congressional Children's Caucus, I am dedicated to providing the best possible opportunities and support to our Nation's children. Head Start is an important aspect of ensuring our children's future. I strongly support <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>, and I encourage my colleagues to do the same.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield such time as he may consume to the gentleman from Delaware (Mr. Castle).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400070" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, just very briefly, we are about to pursue I think a dozen amendments here. All of us had a chance to work on this, had a chance to look at it. I think some of them are very good amendments. I think some are relatively neutral. I think some are maybe a little detrimental to the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I just hope that everybody will listen carefully to the amendments and will not end up being a party vote necessarily and we do what is in the best interests of these children that we have talked about so frequently in the last hour or so.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is real significance to some of these amendments. I think it is very, very important that we understand the context of them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would just like to also finally say at the end that, in my judgment, if you look at any aspect of Head Start that this underlying legislation basically improves the opportunity for young children who are within the parameters of the Head Start program, and I hope that all of us will be supportive of that.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 1 minute to the gentleman from Virginia (Mr. Scott).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400364" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, as we discuss this faith-based amendment, I think we need to seriously consider the long-term societal implications of that amendment, allowing discrimination in the Head Start program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our Nation just went through quite a conversation when Don Imus made his remarks, and I would hope that that was just talking. We are actually going to do something in considering whether or not a program can deny an employment opportunity solely because of religion, and if you happen to go to an all-black or all-white church, the decision made on religion will deny you based on race as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We should have this conversation here on the floor, considering what we are doing long-term, similar to the conversation we had when Don Imus embarrassed himself. We should not embarrass ourselves here on the floor of the House of Representatives. We need to maintain the civil rights protections for prospective employees that we have had for the last 40 years.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I thank my colleagues for a productive debate on the Improving Head Start Act. As many of us have noted throughout the day, Head Start is a good program that can be made even better, and that is why we are here. I hope everybody listened carefully to Mr. Castle as he talked about the importance of the upcoming amendments we are going to discuss because they can make the bill better.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This program serves nearly 1 million underprivileged children and eases the divide between the haves and the have-nots when it comes to preparing them for kindergarten, which will give them a good start for their life. The bipartisan support we have seen for the bill today should lend all of us confidence that the program will remain on a solid foundation for generations to come.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By reauthorizing Head Start, we are voting to build upon improvements that were made by the House Republicans in past Congresses by strengthening academic standards by emphasizing cognitive development using scientifically-based research; improving teacher quality by ensuring more Head Start teachers have bachelor degrees and are adequately trained in early childhood development; increasing financial disclosure requirements by Head Start operators as custodians of Federal Head Start grants; and  requiring local governance boards to actively oversee grantees.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These are common-sense reforms that I wholeheartedly support. That said, this bill remains flawed, and soon, we will turn to a number of amendments that highlight those flaws. One such amendment that we will not be able to discuss unfortunately is one offered to the Rules Committee by Mr. Fortu&#xF1;o yesterday. The Fortu&#xF1;o amendment is a principled one. It clearly protects the hiring privileges of faith-based providers and protects their civil rights to display religious symbols,  rights that are sheltered under the 1964 Civil Rights Act. Yet, we will not be able to debate and vote on it today, a major statement about the real priorities of this purportedly fair, open and honest Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nonetheless, Mr. Chairman, I still believe the Improving Head Start Act is a worthy piece of legislation, deserving  of the same bipartisan support it received from the Education and Labor Committee just 2 months ago.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Before I conclude, I would like to thank a number of current and former members of my staff who have made this bill possible. First, to Kate Houston, who no longer works on Capitol Hill, let alone on our committee staff. Years ago, Kate helped craft legislation that closely tracks the bill we are poised to pass today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Stephanie Milburn, who left our staff earlier this year to join Mr. Boehner's team, played an integral role in bringing this bill to where it is today, and I thank her as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, I thank Susan Ross and James Bergeron for their work in helping to bring this bill across the finish line.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have already mentioned thanks to Mr. Miller, Mr. Kildee, Mr. Castle, and I would like to thank their staff also for working with us so closely on this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The team effort that we have demonstrated on this issue, and our ability to work closely with our Democratic counterparts, yielded the product we are poised to vote on this afternoon.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield myself such time as I may consume and just to thank my colleagues who joined in the general debate and for their support for this legislation and, again, to thank the staffs on both sides of the aisle of both the subcommittee and the full committee without whose work and effort and knowledge this legislation would not be in the kind of shape it is today, with the support that it has from both Republicans and Democrats for the Head Start bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400262" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I represent a community that honors the memory and civil rights legacy of Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. every day, because King County has adopted Dr. King's portrait as our symbol, and Dr. King's commitment to civil rights as our commitment to all the people in King County, Washington.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, it is with a unique responsibility that I rise to strongly oppose this Republican attempt to turn back the lock on civil rights in this Nation, beginning with the Head Start program. The Minority Leader, the leader and spokesman for the Republican Party in the House, wants us to legislate employment discrimination within Head Start based on religion. The Minority Leader wants to turn his back on civil rights, and turn back the clock on the struggle for freedom that Dr. King and so many others  fought and died for.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Republican House leader apparently finds the First Amendment inconvenient for his taste. The First Amendment protects Americans from exactly the kind of foolish proposal before us today. Separation of Church and State is one of the fundamental principles within the First Amendment: "Congress shall make no law respecting an establishment of religion, or prohibiting the free exercise thereof ....."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We must not roll back civil rights in this Nation, not today, not tomorrow, and not ever, but that's what the I leader of the Republican party proposes. There is no reason to justify this attempt to roll back longstanding civil rights and religious liberty protections in a program that has benefited countless children over the years. In a nation like ours with so many religious traditions, built-in protections prohibiting religious discrimination in federally funded programs represents a fundamental  commitment towards a society that values the contributions of people of all faiths.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Religious organizations have had a long and proud history in Head Start programs, including in my own district of Seattle, where the YWCA is a Head Start provider. Civil rights protections have never been a bar to participation by these organizations. If these safeguards are repealed, thousands of dedicated Head Start teachers and parent volunteers could find themselves no longer welcome at some Head Start programs run by followers of other faiths.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Religious organizations are free to engage in faith-based hiring when they use their own funds to promote their institutional ministry, but not when they use Federal money to educate our Nation's children. It would be wrong to permit religious organizations to use Federal dollars to discriminate on the basis of religion in running Head Start programs that are intended to benefit disadvantaged children of all faiths.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On behalf of the people of Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr., County, in Washington State, I strongly oppose this amendment and urge my colleagues to vote "No."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>, the Improving Head Start Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, for the last two Congresses we have successfully fought back the attempts by the then Republican leadership to cut funding, and to drastically change Head Start in ways that would prevent them from providing the services that our communities have come to depend on them for.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Every week I meet with outstanding high school and college students who began their educational journey in Head Start. This bill provides additional funding so that more children would have the opportunities provided by this important program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill> also provides greater monitoring and accountability and increases funds for salaries and professional development.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As amended it also provides loan forgiveness for Head Start teachers as a means to attract and retain some of the best teachers for this very vulnerable group of children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One thing this bill does not do is allow centers run by religious organizations to discriminate in their hiring.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, this bill, together with <bill type="h" number="1867">H.R. 1867</bill> is an important step forward in realizing the "competitiveness agenda" that you have laid out for us in the 110th Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge the passage of both bills.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400384" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>, the Improving Head Start Act of 2007. Head Start is a program that has been crucial on the development and academic success of our children for more than 40 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since 1965, more than 24 million children have benefited from Head Start's comprehensive services and school readiness. Last year alone Head Start served about 900,000 children nationwide--over 98,000 children in my home State of California and nearly 6,500 children, more than 60 percent Latino, in the 32nd Congressional District of California, which I represent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to providing these comprehensive services, Head Start programs engage parents as partners in their children's education. Parents volunteer at their child's school site and many become Head Start teachers. Head Start has a proven track record of improving the lives of low-income children and families. It narrows the gap between disadvantaged children and all children in vocabulary and writing skills. It also leads to continued improvements in word knowledge, letter recognition, and  math and writing skills relative to other children during their kindergarten year. 83 percent of Head Start children are at the national norm by the time they reach kindergarten.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Studies also demonstrate that Head Start programs improve the well-being of the children and families they serve, providing health and dental services to children and families who might otherwise not have them. Head Start programs benefit parents as well. Head Start parents report increases in education attainment and employment during their time affiliation with Head Start. In California, 24 percent of Head Start employees are or were Head Start parents. In addition, 86 percent of Head Start  volunteers in California are current or former parents of the local Head Start program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Improving Head Start Act of 2007, <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>, not updates this program so all children could be put in the road for academic success. It makes significant improvements that will help strengthen educational outcomes for students, ensure better coordination with local school districts, improve teacher quality, and increase program eligibility. It would help improve Head Start's workforce quality by increasing funding for teacher and staff salaries and professional development. This includes  providing funds for training personnel in addressing the unique needs of migrant and seasonal working families, families of children with disabilities, limited english proficient families and homeless families. It will also expand access to up to 10,000 more children and will strengthen school readiness by re-evaluating and updating current standards and assessments based on best science.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill> also reserves 5 percent of the total Head Start appropriation for the Migrant and Seasonal Head Start program. This is important because the Migrant and Seasonal Head Start program serves some of the country's neediest working families and is designed to meet the unique challenges and opportunities faced by the children of farmworkers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At a time when America needs to be at the forefront of innovation and education, programs like Head Start are an investment in our future workforce and their success. I applaud the members of the Committee on Education and Labor for their work on the reauthorization of this important program. I urge my colleagues to vote in favor of <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill> and to oppose any proposal that would block this grant program or would allow government-funded religious discrimination in Head Start programs. Supporting  this bill is supporting our Nation's future.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400400" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>, the Improving Head Start Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bipartisan legislation will benefit nearly one million disadvantaged children nationwide  by expanding Head Start's focus on school readiness. Low-income children will be taught key early learning skills such as alphabet, number, color and shape recognition to help them succeed in their school years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill also opens poor-performing Head Start programs to greater public scrutiny and needful competition. Triennial program reviews by the Federal government and independent investigation by the Government Accountability Office have revealed that some Head Start programs operate with Federal tax dollars despite chronic financial mismanagement, health and safety concerns, and poor community involvement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill> would help remedy this situation by requiring Head Start programs to demonstrate active partnerships with local school districts to ensure smooth transitions for children into kindergarten. Poor-performing programs would be opened to competition every 5 years. Annual disclosures of financial information and greater participation of parents in the decisions of Head Start governing boards will also make a difference.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have personally seen the benefits of partnering local school districts with Head Start. Several years ago, a long-standing Head Start program serving 1,000 children in Douglas County, Nebraska was transferred to the control of the Omaha Public School District to end long-standing financial mismanagement and safety concerns for children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Omaha Public Schools went the extra mile by partnering with EduCare, an outstanding private preschool program that involves the entire family, emphasizes best practices, and focuses on early learning skills to help disadvantaged children succeed in school and life.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>EduCare was created by Susie Buffett and currently serves 239 children from Omaha families living below the poverty level. Families must either work, be in job training, or attending school to qualify. Enrollment is free, with costs covered by the Nebraska Department of Education, Omaha Public Schools, the Department of Health and Human Services and private sources.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>EduCare has a low child-to-adult ratio: three infants per adult, and six preschoolers per adult. Bachelor level staff members are trained in early childhood education, and the program contains strong academic components to help children succeed in school, including limited english proficiency children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Buffett has said: "We look at the whole entire family, not just the child." Parents are directed to community resources to improve home life, such as food shelters and Christmas toy drives. Single mothers are helped with transportation and job searches.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Prelimary evaluation data indicates that the EduCare program is making a significant difference in the lives of children. Upon</paragraph>
    <paragraph>entering the program, children's language, literacy and social emotional areas of development are assessed. Most children initially score in the borderline range of development. Annual assessment results have shown the majority of participating children gained more vocabulary words in the course of the school year than one would expect based on maturity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By the time they transitioned to kindergarten, EduCare's children were scoring very close to the national average. Standardized assessments of children's literacy and kindergarten readiness skills show similar results. Because research has shown children's vocabulary and pre-literacy skills to predict later school success, every Head Start program should help children reach such strong learning potential while addressing the short and long-term needs of the child's family. EduCare is an incredible  success story in the lives of low-income children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also want to draw the attention of my colleagues to a provision of this bill to protect Head Start for children of military families. The privatization of military housing created an artificial raise in a military family's income, making their children ineligible for Head Start. <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill> would disregard the Basic Housing Allowance from a family's income when determining Head Start eligibility. Servicemembers protecting our freedom need not worry about their children's continued access to Head  Start.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I hope we can go even further in the future to strengthen the academic emphasis in Head Start and give states and excellent programs such as EduCare a greater ability to improve the lives of low-income children and their families. <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill> makes good progress in this direction.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400387" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise today in strong support of the Improving Head Start Act of 2007 (<bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since 1965, Head Start has served millions of low-income families and helped children prepare for school. It is an essential program and one whose success has a major impact on children, their families, their community, and ultimately the future of our country. We owe it to our children to pass this bill and make improvements that strengthen and grow the Head Start program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Scientific research shows us that 80 percent of brain development occurs by age 3 and 90 percent by age 5. Studies also show that education achievement gaps between poor and minority students and affluent and non-minority students are already in place when children begin elementary school. These achievement gaps, once in place, tend to persist and are exceedingly difficult to remedy. Head Start and Early Head Start are effective in closing achievement gaps and foster both short and long-term  success in participating children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to preparing children for success in school, recent research clearly demonstrates that children enrolled in Early Head Start and their parents realize other very significant gains. Early Head Start children show better approaches to learning, demonstrate more appropriate language acquisition, and exhibit less aggressive behavior. Early Head Start parents create a stronger home environment with more parent-child reading and a greater repertoire of discipline strategies. Early Head  Start parents also show significant progress toward economic self-sufficiency. These impacts are significant and result in children with increased linguistic, cognitive, social and emotional competence. What better investment could we be making for our children?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unlike programs dreamed up by ideologues in the Bush Administration like "abstinence only education" and "marriage promotion," we know that Head Start works. Unfortunately, less than half of eligible children are enrolled in Head Start. Even worse, less than 5 percent of eligible infants and toddlers are enrolled in Early Head Start.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If we are serious about providing all children with an opportunity to succeed in school and in life, we must expand Head Start and particularly Early Head Start. This bill is a step in that direction. It will more than double the amount of money available to Early Head Start programs. The bill will also expand services to infants and toddlers that are so crucial to child development, but often difficult for parents to access. In addition, the Improving Head Start Act will increase eligibility  levels so that children from families making up to 130 percent of the Federal poverty level can participate. This change is especially important in areas of the country with high costs of living, including my district where the poverty threshold is well below what it actually costs a family to live.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill's expansion of Early Head Start and Head Start should be applauded. We cannot lose sight, however, that these programs only address the tip of the iceberg. This Congress must focus more of our attention on all children birth to age 5 and guarantee that all families have access to high quality comprehensive early care and education programs. This is an investment that our country must make if we are serious about giving all of our children a chance at the American dream.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Despite the strong bipartisan support for this legislation, the White House has indicated that the President does not support this legislation as written unless we insert a special interest provision for the religious right. The President and many Republicans want to allow religious organizations to discriminate in their hiring practices. Religious organizations have been Head Start providers since the program was established and have done quite well playing by the same rules that prohibit all  employers from discriminating. Pandering rhetoric and veiled threats from the White House will not improve the life of a single family.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In closing, I hope that all of my colleagues will see the importance of investing in our children and supporting families. I urge a "yes" vote on this legislation and a "no" vote on Republican attempts to turn this into a vehicle for religious discrimination.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400437" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in strong support of this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Head Start has proven its ability to improve the lives of disadvantaged children. Numerous studies have demonstrated that children who attend Head Start come to school more prepared than children who do not participate, and that these effects last over a period of years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have personal experience with the program--my wife, Michelle, was a Head Start teacher for 7 years in Oregon. In her classes, I saw the children of janitors and security guards.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Their parents worked in the sparkling towers of downtown Portland, but they themselves never got to visit downtown, except in their Head Start field trips.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Improving Head Start Act makes several needed changes to current law. It ends the use of the National Reporting System--a flawed testing system that has tested over 500,000 4-year-olds, despite strong opposition by child development experts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also improves current law by making clear that Head Start agencies must establish and maintain a formal structure of shared governance with parent policy councils. This will codify in law that parents have the ability to shape and share a role in the success of their local Head Start program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, the bill authorizes $7.35 billion in funding for the program in FY08--an increase of over $400 million from this year's level.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Oregon's Department of Education reports that, as of January 2007, 43.2 percent of eligible children cannot participate in the program due to lack of funding. Head Start is a highly successful program, and it ultimately costs all of us when those eligible cannot participate.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400356" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise today in strong support of the Head Start Program and I am encouraged by <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>, the Head Start Improvement Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am a Head Start kid. I have firsthand experience of the comprehensive education programs and opportunities that Head Start provides to low-income families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Head Start programs promote school readiness by assisting with the social and cognitive development of young children. Research consistently identifies the early years of a child's development as ever more crucial to the child's lifetime success.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many Head Start programs already try to incorporate new research into their strategies through education, health, nutrition, and social services. This bill ensures that local Head Start programs have the resources to undertake the best practices for furthering a child's development.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Head Start is about the family. As I received education and health services, my mother learned valuable lessons on how to become a more active and involved parent in America's public school system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am glad to see that this bill maintains the existing shared governance structure to help empower parents and allow programs to be responsive to local needs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What's more, this bill is good for Head Start teachers. This bill takes the necessary steps to ensure that Head Start teachers' salaries and professional development are in line with the responsibility that we assign to them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Head Start Improvement Act of 2007 is a good bill that will keep Head Start strong so it can remain the great program that it was for me, and continues to be for so many Americans.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400415" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise today to support the Improving Head Start Act, a bill that will strengthen our nation's premiere early childhood education program and expand its services to thousands more children across the country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Head Start has been improving lives and increasing opportunities for children and families for more than 40 years. With this important program, we teach our children that they can succeed, regardless of background or family income. We open doors to millions and prepare them for future success in school and careers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill provides much-needed amendments to Head Start that will improve workforce quality by increasing funding for staff salaries and professional development, and enhance coordination between early education and primary schools. It also strengthens standards and accountability to ensure that our children are getting the best quality care and education.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am also pleased that this House defeated a divisive and misguided motion that would, for the first time, legitimize publicly funded religious discrimination in the Head Start program. It would have given taxpayer money to Head Start centers and allow those centers to exclude taxpayers from jobs solely on the basis of their religious beliefs. It would be a green light for religious bigotry. Its passage would have been bad for education and bad for religion and I joined the National Head Start  Association, the Interfaith Alliance, and countless other secular and religious advocates of the Head Start Program in opposing it. I am glad that we have a clean bill to pass today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also urge my colleagues to not only vote for this bill, but to continue to advocate for Head Start by supporting full funding for the program. It is not enough to pass the legislation--we need to give our communities the resources they need to carry out our mandates.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank Chairman Miller, Chairman Kildee and the Committee on Education and Labor for their work on this important legislation, and urge its final passage today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412200" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise today in support of the Improving Head Start Act of 2007. Over and over again, rigorous evaluations have shown that Head Start and Early Head Start works. It improves the lives of our neediest children and families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am proud to be an original cosponsor of the bill at hand, as it makes several positive changes to the Head Start program. It authorizes $450 million new dollars to the program, which is enough to provide up to 10,000 new spots for children. It prioritizes program improvement by increasing funding for teacher and staff salaries and professional development. It suspends the National Reporting System, which is a flawed testing system that does not adequately assess this comprehensive system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Science has shown that providing a quality early education experience leads to healthy brain development that prepares children for success in school, as well as later in life. Access to high quality early education, as well as to wrap around, comprehensive services, really sets the foundation for children and their parents.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this strong, bipartisan bill. It will directly improve the lives of many, many children and families.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400251" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in strong support of <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>, the Improving Head Start Act of 2007. Since 1965, the Head Start early childhood education program has provided low-income children with comprehensive child development, educational, health, nutritional, and social activities to ensure that they are ready to enter kindergarten on an equal playing field with other children. <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill> will expand and improve the successful Head Start program, which research has shown  works in raising children's achievement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank Representatives KILDEE, CASTLE and Chairman MILLER for their outstanding leadership on this bipartisan bill, which would allow as many as 10,000 more children to access the benefits Head Start. It improves classroom and teacher quality, raising the qualifications of teachers and increasing funding for teacher and staff salaries and professional development. The bill also includes strong accountability measures to better ensure that Head Start funds are used  appropriately and efficiently and that underperforming programs are either replaced or quickly improved.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a former educator, I understand the importance of closing the school-readiness gap and ensuring that all children can start their education on an equal playing field. Today, we have the opportunity to pass a bill that will make great strides toward just that.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="LEE" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in strong support of the amendment offered to the Head Start reauthorization bill by my friend and colleague from Texas, Congresswoman EDDIE BERNICE JOHNSON.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment would encourage partnerships with Historically Black Colleges and Universities and Head Start.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment builds on the important step that the underlying bill takes. That is, <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill> will require that fifty percent of Head Start teachers have a Bachelor's degree in early childhood education by 2013.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment would create a partnership between the Secretary of HHS and HBCU's to meet the new degree requirements. It would require those who benefit from this partnership to teach at a Head Start program for a period of time equivalent to the time they received assistance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a significant amendment not only because it will provide students with qualified teachers in their classrooms, it will also set a good example for these students. In fact, evidence suggests that students who attend early childhood programs have a better chance of success later in life. In an article published in the Developmental Psychology journal of the American Psychological Association in 2005 showed that children in Early Head Start had better test scores, had better cognitive and  language development. These children also showed less aggressive behavior then non-early Head Start children, which goes towards improving the overall environment of our elementary and secondary schools.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this amendment and the underlying bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> All time for general debate has expired.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400204" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I offer an amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will designate the amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400204" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise to offer an amendment that will increase the number of highly qualified African American Head Start teachers. Let me hasten to thank the chairman of the committee and the ranking member.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This program has been successful. I am fortunate enough to have what has been labeled as the number one Head Start program in the country in my district, and what I am attempting to do in this amendment is to create partnerships between our Nation's historically black colleges and universities and Head Start.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It does not eliminate anyone else's participation, but we know that by 2013 every Head Start teacher has to have a degree, and it could be parents because one of the secrets to success in these programs is to have lots of involvement of the parents and volunteers in the community.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The partnerships will provide an opportunity for Head Start staff and parents of Head Start students to obtain degrees in early childhood education.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, why must it be in a historically black college? Mr. Chairman, that is important because 30 percent of the total number of children in Head Start are African American.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Only 6 percent of our Nation's 3 million teachers are African American and this is far too few, but also the historically black colleges and universities educate more African American teachers than all the other universities put together.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So we would like to make this collaboration so that it can reflect the diversity and the need and encouragement of both the parents and the teachers to work together. They can serve as role models, the teachers who know and understand the students that come from their own communities, and this will not only increase the number of qualified African American Head Start teachers, but it will increase the number of role models for millions of children who are at risk of educational failure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, today, only 6 percent of our Nation's 3 million teachers are African American. It is far too small, but this would offer a unique resource and support for those that are seeking a degree which is going to be necessary to maintain these jobs, and it also will offer I think a very positive role model situation in our Head Start program where appropriate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to move adoption of my amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in support of the gentlewoman's amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the gentleman from California is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I believe that the amendment will improve the underlying bill. Let me just give one example that can come from her amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Delaware State University is an example of a Head Start HBCU partnership that nurtures a continual goal of providing high quality educational experiences to Head Start participants by enhancing the competence of teachers and teachers' aids; improving parental confidence and life management skills to ensure that the work of Head Start is continued in the home; and improving the administrative, managerial and leadership skills of centers directly so the Head Start resources, including personnel,  are used as efficiently as possible.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>We think that her amendment will further this help, and we think it improves the bill. We would be happy to support the amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400204" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 1 minute to the gentleman from North Carolina (Mr. Butterfield).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400616" topic="">
    <paragraph>I come to the floor this afternoon to thank, first, the chairman of the committee, Mr. George Miller of California, for his tireless work in this area, and also the gentlelady from Texas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>. There is no question, Mr. Chairman, that America needs more minority teachers in Head Start classrooms. I represent the First Congressional District of North Carolina, which is the 15th poorest district in the Nation. I can tell you that Head Start is making a difference in my congressional district.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I encourage the continuation of the program. I urge the adoption of this resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400204" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 30 seconds to the gentleman from California (Mr. George Miller).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="">
    <paragraph>I rise in strong support of this amendment and urge its adoption. I thank the gentlewoman for offering it.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400208" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise today in support of the Eddie Bernice Johnson Amendment to <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>, the Improving Head Start Act of 2007. This amendment will encourage partnerships between Head Start and Historically Black Colleges and Universities. The Johnson Amendment will encourage African American students to focus on early childhood education and participate in Head Start. My home is Cleveland, Ohio, and it is one of the poorest cities in the nation, with half of the children  living below the poverty line. Head Start provides a vital service to my community, it allows the youngest and most helpless children to have a chance at the developing basic skills so they are not behind when they start attending school. I am so pleased that my colleague from Texas, EDDIE BERNICE JOHNSON has offered this amendment. It will encourage more</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400204" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the amendment offered by the gentlewoman from Texas (Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson).</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I offer an amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will designate the amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I appreciate the opportunity to offer this amendment. I would urge my colleagues to support it. This is an amendment of expansion and educational opportunities for our young children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1965, when Head Start was implemented, State-run early childhood development programs didn't exist. Since then, and most recently, and in the past 15 years, States have invested considerable resources into early childhood initiatives. This amendment seeks to provide an incredible opportunity for eight States to participate in a 5-year demonstration program and leverage their resources and experience to improve school readiness.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It would allow eight States to coordinate Head Start and early childhood State-run programs, thus improving coordination, preventing duplication and expanding the number of children that can be served by the early childhood services. To carry it out, safeguards would be put in place. States would have to ensure that participants receive services that are as good or better than those in the Head Start program, including health, nutrition, mental health services on top of the educational services.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enacting a demonstration program will result in expanding the number of children that can be served, which is not possible in Head Start or just a State-run program alone. This is an innovative program that would help more children in our Nation, and I urge my colleagues to adopt this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in opposition to this amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from California is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, Members of the House, we are here today to authorize the Head Start program. What this amendment would do would simply end Head Start in those eight States as we know it. There would be no requirement that those States would take the money that we have set aside, that we have worked hard to provide within the budget for the Head Start program and use it to implement a program that is anything like Head Start, because there would simply be no requirements  on that money to provide the kind of comprehensive programs that are now required under the Head Start program that have demonstrated the success that we just spent an hour with speakers from both sides of the aisle attesting to in their own districts or on</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Essentially that's the end of it in those eight States. Now, maybe one of those States will have a strong commitment to Head Start and all the rest of it. That's what Head Start is. That's what Head Start is. Why are we running this money through another filter system to recreate the Head Start program? We already require, and we went through a series of hearings about coordination with the States to make sure that Head Start coordinates with other State programs and State agencies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But we also know that because of what we have done with Head Start over the years, where we have provided reauthorization after reauthorization, the continuous improvement of the programs that are integral to the success of Head Start and to the success of the children, where we have used scientific-based educational and performance standards, where we have provided for accountability and oversight and evaluation of the program, where we have provided for the parent policy councils, all of these  things that have been integral to this program over this time to bring it to a point now where we can see that it demonstrates a marked impact on these young children in closing the achievement gap for these children and getting them ready and the skills that they will need for early reading, for early math, for early writing, that is what this program does.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are not many States that do any of that. They have a lot of early childhood programs. They have a lot of child care programs, they have a lot of it. But they don't have this comprehensive program. That's why this is considered the premier program in the Nation for the education and the development of these young children. That is why we should not support this block grant amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I daresay that we have watched over the last decades effort after effort be made to block grant programs. Generally, where they have been successful, they have been the first step to the budget cuts, to the loss of quality. That's what's involved here.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, when we structured this legislation, and in consideration of the budget and the increases in the money, we are putting 60 percent of the money into quality, into teacher and professional development, into salaries, because we recognize that we have to have that continuous update and that improvement of the Head Start program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Voting for this amendment is not to vote for Head Start; it's to vote for something, but it's not to vote for Head Start. It's, in fact, detrimental because that money, then, is out of the Head Start system to be used for whatever purposes. In fact, you can take this Federal money and then withdraw the local money. There is no requirement in this amendment that there be a maintenance of effort by a State to do this.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What have you really done? You have taken money for the Federal taxpayers that paid into this program that we have decided on a bipartisan basis should go for the Head Start program. You said, oh, you can give it to a State, and they can draw their money out the bottom. So we put the taxpayers' money in at the top, and the State takes the money out of the bottom.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is not going to improve quality. That is not going to improve access. Now, you can argue that maybe you can add a lot of children to a program, a program, not the Head Start program, because the Head Start program is expensive because we do it the way we should be doing, the way it has been scientifically analyzed and supported by the data.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>You can put a lot of kids in low-quality programs, but that is not what we  are trying to achieve. We are trying to achieve high quality so we get the results that Head Start gets and most other States don't get.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, may I inquire as to how much time remains.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from Georgia has 3 1/2  minutes remaining.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>The gentleman from California?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from California has 30 seconds remaining.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I appreciate the chairman's passion on this, but his testimony bears little resemblance to reality. I would urge him to read the amendment which states clearly on page 11, "Head Start services furnished in a State program under this section shall include all Head Start services."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 1 1/2  minutes to my good friend from Delaware (Mr. Castle).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400070" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I strongly support this amendment. I have a tremendous amount of respect for the chairman of the committee, Mr. Miller, but I disagree with him on his basic premise here.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I do believe that the Governors of this country, which I had the chance to be one, seems eons ago now, but a few years ago, have a tremendous and strong interest in the children of their States and in the education of those children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also believe that in the time since Head Start was created, that many of these Governors have put together prekindergarten, kindergarten, early childhood programs. I think they are ready to move forward with this. I think in many instances they have been competitive with, if not even ahead of, Head Start. We basically backed off from what the White House proposed originally, which is to give all 50 States the option to do this, to a pilot program of eight States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are requirements that those eight States match these funds, in fact, put in extra money in order to be able to enter into this program of dealing with the Head Start-type programs. The State demo would be limited to States with a demonstrated investment in early childhood education and established existing preschool system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>You can't just jump into this and take the money or whatever. You have to show you are ready for it, and that you are ready to do it, and you are ready to put the money into it. I believe strongly that those States should be afforded the opportunity. I actually think the competition with some of the Head Start providers would be positive in terms of developing the opportunity for young children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would hope that everybody would stop for a moment and take time for a moment to listen to this amendment and the arguments pro and con before votes are cast on it. I believe Mr. Price has demonstrated through Georgia, as well as other States, that this is something which could be beneficial to the children, which is really what this is all about, hopefully helping those children in poverty so that they could move ahead.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I hope everybody will support the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 15 seconds to the gentleman from Michigan (Mr. Kildee).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400216" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I would just say in reading the amendment that States should generally follow the standards. I served in a State legislature for 12 years in appropriations, and I know what license that word "generally" gives to a State legislature in a State government. Generally it does not keep these really good high standards that we have worked on for 42 years on in this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I would just say that is exactly the point. Yes, it offers all services, but it doesn't require the same high-quality service we have now. You can do all of these things, but you end up doing these things on the cheap because the demand is for slots. We have seen that tension here all the time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are no requirements here that you have anything comparable to the quality and the requirements in the Head Start program, and yet you are you are taking money out of the program to give it for these other purposes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge a "no" vote on this amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 1 minute to the gentleman from California (Mr. McKeon).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, before I came to Washington, I served in local government on the school board, on the city council. I have great respect for local leadership. I don't know what we're afraid of.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sometimes I get the feeling that people here in Washington feel that all wisdom resides within the Beltway. I just think that to give the opportunity to a maximum of eight States to try to expand and bring creativity to a program that's good, to make it better, I think is nothing but a good thing, and it's on the upside.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I commend the gentleman from Georgia (Mr. Price) for this amendment. I encourage all to support it.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, how much time remains?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from Georgia has 45 seconds remaining.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I appreciate the perspective of the other side, but I would suggest, respectfully, that that's an old argument. It's an old argument about a block grant. This is not a block grant. This is a demonstration program that would allow States to serve more children, not fewer children, more, more than is currently possible than just with Head Start or with State-run early childhood development programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Economies of scale, it works. Funding levels for Head Start and early childhood services would be protected. Demonstration program States will be able to eliminate overlap, eliminate duplication of services, and participants must have access to services that are as extensive or greater than those found in Head Start. That's what the amendment states.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to read the amendment. I appreciate the fact that they have had previous amendments in legislation before them, but I urge them to read this amendment. I think they will find the common-sense aspect of it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I appreciate the opportunity to offer it, and I urge my colleagues to adopt the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the amendment offered by the gentleman from Georgia (Mr. Price).</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I demand a recorded vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 6 of rule XVIII, further proceedings on the amendment offered by the gentleman from Georgia will be postponed.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412232" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I offer an amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will designate the amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412232" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Mr. SESTAK asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412232" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise to speak in support of this amendment, to encourage more individuals to become Head Start and Early Head Start teachers, and to provide a way for existing Head Start teachers to improve their skills and education.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment is just building upon the efforts of someone that I have grown to very much respect, Congressman Tierney, who has been working on this issue for years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Specifically, this amendment proposes loan forgiveness of up to $10,000 for Head Start and Early Head Start teachers upon completion of a bachelor's degree, who will commit to working in a Head Start or Early Head Start program for at least 3 consecutive years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Earlier this spring, I held my district's first education summit, bringing together over 300 educators, experts, and citizens. We discussed the need to provide and retain high quality Head Start teachers, who serve our country's most disadvantaged, low-income children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Head Start teachers are so critical at the time of a child's cognitive reasoning development, and this amendment recognizes this by ensuring that more than 55,000 Head Start teachers have the means of getting their bachelor's degree by forgiving their student loan burden.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As we call for increased qualifications in the Head Start workforce in <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>, with 50 percent Head Start teachers nationwide now to hold a bachelor's degree by 2013, we should also provide the means to help them reach this goal. This amendment offers one way of helping current Head Start teachers upgrade their qualifications, as well as to encourage future and current students to enter this important field of teaching.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The rising cost of higher education is a concern for many, and repaying student loans is often too burdensome for these teachers, particularly when one realizes that Head Start teachers' average annual salary is only approximately $24,000 a year, forcing teachers not to go on to receive advanced degrees, or else to leave the profession in order to repay their student loans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment will help to ensure that we are able to recruit and retain a high quality workforce for our Nation's Head Start programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge all my colleagues to support this critical amendment to help our children's future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in opposition to the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from California is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, while I support the intent of the amendment, which I think is good and which we included in last year's bill that we passed, the higher ed reauthorization bill, that I think is a better vehicle for this particular amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would encourage the Member to withdraw it and put this in the higher ed bill when we move later this year to reauthorize that. It fits better there.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We did a study, and we found that most of the education programs don't come under the Department of Education, they come under 39 other bureaucracies throughout this town. And it would be, I think, moving to try to have things more organized. It fits better under the Higher Ed Act, and I would encourage that the gentleman put it under that. Otherwise, I would oppose this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412232" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 1 minute to the gentleman from Connecticut (Mr. Courtney).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412193" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in support of Congressman Sestak's amendment which flushes out, I think, the direction that this bill is taking, which is to try and improve the quality of teachers by mandating bachelor's degrees and associate's degrees over a very short period of time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For a lot of the teachers in the Head Start program, though, this still begs the question, which is, how do you pay for it?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Higher education costs have gone up 40 percent over the last 6 years, and unfortunately the prior Congresses took no action to raise the size of Pell Grants. And we have obviously taken  some steps towards reducing the cost of interest rates under the Stafford Student Loan program, but for many teachers, the challenge of paying for higher education costs, in Connecticut the average salary for Head Start teachers is $24,000, and the Sestak amendment goes  right to the heart of trying to make this new requirement affordable. I believe it is totally germane and central to the intent of this Head Start reauthorization bill. This amendment belongs there, and I strongly urge the Members to support passage of the Sestak amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank Congressman SESTAK for offering this important amendment today. It would provide concrete assistance for early childhood educators in Connecticut and around the country to attain their bachelors degree. As you know, the Head Start bill before us increases teacher qualifications--half of teachers nationwide have a BA by 2013 and all new teachers have at least an associate's degree beginning in 2009.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment also provides a strong incentive for students to enter the field and for established early childhood educators to remain in the field. Loan forgiveness of up to $10,000 is contingent upon at least 3 years service in a Head Start facility. Too often, our best and brightest educators are forced out of the profession because the salaries cannot keep up with individual and family economic demands.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In Connecticut, where the median Head Start salary is approximately $24,000, going back to school to attain a higher degree to satisfy the new teacher qualification requirements would be an economic hardship.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While I am pleased to say that Connecticut met the national goal of having at least 50 percent or more of its teachers having an associate's degree in early childhood education by the year 2003, the financial burden to now attain a bachelor's degree will be high.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We all know that college costs are rising and the last thing we want to do is encourage more debt. That is why I am so supportive of this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The need for committed, enthusiastic, and qualified Head Start teachers is on the rise. In Connecticut, there are more than 25 Centers serving more than 8,000 children. Poverty levels in many parts of the state are rising. Children receive valuable educational enrichment in Head Start programs, ensuring that they are on the path to educational success in elementary school and beyond. We cannot afford to leave children unprepared and we cannot afford to lose our best and talented teachers either.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment provides the incentive to enter or remain in the early childhood education field and I urge my colleagues to support this amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412232" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 1 minute to the gentlewoman from California (Ms. Woolsey).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400436" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, we must ensure that every child who could benefit from Head Start is able to enroll in a Head Start center. One way to do that is to provide full funding; another is to provide that we have the facilities we need; and, one of the most important ways is to ensure that we have qualified teachers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The base bill increases the requests and requirements for teacher qualification, and it supports higher salaries and requires more college degrees. Therefore, including this amendment in the Head Start bill is absolutely appropriate, because this amendment helps Head Start teachers get the degrees that we are demanding that they have. And we do this by offering loan forgiveness to those teachers, teachers who teach in the Head Start programs. Loan forgiveness will help balance out low salaries,  and it will assist with teacher retention.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Head Start is about the best thing we can do for our children, because this successful program gives children from all backgrounds a level playing field when they enter elementary school.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412232" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 30 seconds to the gentleman from Michigan (Mr. Kildee).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400216" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It has been suggested that we put this in the Higher Education bill, but the Higher Education bill has been kind of stalled. And I always believe you put your cargo on the train that is moving, and this train is moving.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senate reported its version out of committee. I think we have a much better chance to get this done if we put it on this bill. This train is moving.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412232" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the amendment offered by the gentleman from Pennsylvania (Mr. Sestak).</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400145" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I demand a recorded vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 6 of rule XVIII, further proceedings on the amendment offered by the gentleman from Pennsylvania will be postponed.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412200" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I offer an amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will designate the amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412200" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise today to ask for my colleagues' support for this amendment, to improve Early Head Start.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The amendment revises the training and technical assistance system by ensuring that these services are provided by entities with specific expertise in infant and toddler development. It also directs at least 50 percent of training and technical assistance funds directly to the grantees. These are the people on the ground working with children who are best able to prioritize their training needs for the purpose of program improvement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In our hearing on the bill in the Committee on Education and Labor, we heard that Head Start providers are not getting the assistance they need under the current system. One program director said that it had been 10 months since she saw her technical assistance specialist.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The current system centralized control often results in the assistance specialist spending more time filling out forms for their supervisors than directly helping the program directors in the field. The bill we are debating today solves this problem for the Head Start program serving preschoolers by directing the responsibility for training and technical assistance responsibility into the State-based system that can better meet the needs of the local providers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Early Head Start directors experience similar problems, and, therefore, should get a similar solution. This amendment provides that solution and, furthermore, requires that these State-based technical assistance providers include individuals with infant and toddler expertise available to work with Early Head Start providers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rigorous evaluations show that the Early Head Start program has made a positive difference in the lives of participating children and their families. This bill expands the Early Head Start program, which currently serves only 3 percent of eligible infants and toddlers. And as Early Head Start expands, we must ensure that individual programs have the knowledge and skills to provide positive outcomes for participants. This amendment will do that, and I urge all of my colleagues to support it.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, will the gentlewoman yield?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412200" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield to the gentleman from California.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank her very much for introducing this amendment, and we rise in support of this amendment. We think it improves the legislation, and thank her for her consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412200" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise to claim the time in opposition to the amendment, even though I support the gentlelady's amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the gentleman from California is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in support of the gentlelady's amendment, which revises the training and technical assistance program for Early Head Start by ensuring that training and technical assistance are provided by entities with specific expertise in infant and toddler development. I believe that that makes a stronger bill, and I thank her for her amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412200" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the amendment offered by the gentlewoman from Hawaii (Ms. Hirono).</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400145" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I demand a recorded vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 6 of rule XVIII, further proceedings on the amendment offered by the gentlewoman from Hawaii will be postponed.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400273" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I offer an amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will designate the amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400273" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, first of all, I want to take a minute to compliment Mr. Miller and also Mr. McKeon. This is one of the most important bills that this Congress will take up in this session because it deals with, as Mr. Miller said, as I listened to his opening statement, with our disadvantaged youth. And, unfortunately, we have many in this country. But it gives those youth the opportunity for the future and the opportunity that we have all shared that are here  on this floor and many of us listening Members.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think the bill is a step in the right direction in requiring that at least 50 percent of all Head Start teachers nationwide have a bachelor's or advanced degree in childhood education or related field by September 30, 2013. My amendment is a simple amendment. It would move up that date 2 years, to 2011.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am not a newcomer to this debate. I could go back to 1993, when I came here, and give statements from the floor and back over the years. My degree is in education. I am usually here on transportation and enjoy my service on that committee. But as someone educated as an educator, nothing is more important than the quality of education and those professionals that we have.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Mica amendment moves up the date to have professionals in place to 2011. We can do that. We have done it before. We have actually required qualifications, and now we have more than a majority having an associate degree. So we have done this in the past. Currently, 38 percent of all of our Head Start teachers already meet this goal, so we are only talking about 12 percent in 4 years as opposed to 6 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>Does it really take 6 years to get an additional 12 percent of the teachers to be in our most important educational program with these qualifications?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, we've moved this program from what I called it 14 years ago, from a glorified babysitting program, to a program that is giving our students the opportunity for quality educational opportunity. And these young people, at this age, deserve the very best. They are coming from the very worst, the worst as far as disadvantage in our society, the worst as far as opportunity, as far as family setting, as far as their readiness for school.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Miller talked about making them ready for school. Well, do you want them ready with someone who is unqualified or someone with the best qualifications?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Better prepared, Mr. Miller talked about. We need the most skilled professionals to give them the preparation. And these are our toughest students, the very toughest students. Do you want someone with or without qualifications?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I posed a question, and probably the reason I got this amendment out here to the Rules Committee, which is mostly composed of Democrat Members listening, there are more Head Start programs in Democrat districts than there are in Republican districts, just by the sheer economics of it, the demographics. I said, what if I came with a proposal that said, in kindergarten I'm going to recommend that we only have 50 percent of the teachers having a bachelor's degree in Democrat districts; how would  you like that?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Well, this is what's happening here as you're mandating that we have a poorer quality of teachers with quality for another additional 2 years. So I think we can do better.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>You heard the $24,000 average pay. That's right. We're going to increase on average a half a billion dollars, from $6.9 billion to $7.4 billion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In my schools, in closing, there are choices. I won't name the counties, but I have seven teachers in one program with $23,000 average salary. I have nine administrators with salaries from $32,000 to $41,600; another county, 21 teachers, $20,100 average salary, eight administrators with salaries from 31- to $42,000. So it's not always how much we spend, it's how we spend it. And we need to spend it on quality education for these, our most disadvantaged students. So I urge you to consider and  pass my amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in opposition to the amendment offered by the gentleman from Florida.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from California is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield myself 2 minutes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman and Members of the House, I rise in opposition to this amendment, simply for the simple fact that we are trying to balance, in this legislation, the best we can do to increase the number of teachers with a B.A. degree in child education, child development and at the same time meet the other needs of the program. And to accelerate that effort on behalf of more teachers with an M.A. upsets that balance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It's not like, with all due respect to my friend on the other side, and he shares my concern for teacher quality, it's what I've spent my public life trying to do. The fact of the matter is this is a program that essentially has received less than the COLA, last year got a 1 percent cut. And the fact of the matter is we're trying to patch it back up, trying to bring it back to the level where it was around 2002, and recognizing that we want to increase the access to a number of children, so money  has to go for slots, money has to go for professional development, money has to go for quality, and money has to go for the salaries, and that's the balance that we have put in this program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The date that you have was the date that you had at the beginning of 2005 when we started considering this legislation. That legislation didn't get through. We're now 2 years later, so we moved it back 2 years so that the programs can balance, can rebuild the quality, can add additional slots for the million children who are now waiting, and that's the balance that we arrived at on both sides of the aisle.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>You could offer an amendment and say, well, there's a million children waiting. Let's put all the money into slots. Then you just reduce the quality and the availability to pay teachers to have them to stay.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So this isn't a game where you can just pick out one part of the program and say, let's put the money there, and that's the reason why we did what we did. And I don't think that this amendment is helpful in terms of our ability to hold on to current staff that have B.A.'s, and that's the staff we're trying to build, and then to attract additional ones to be able to put some money into that pay quality, and the additional slots. And I would hope that we would oppose this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 2 minutes to the gentleman from Michigan (Mr. Kildee).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400216" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I don't question the motives of Mr. Mica, but his amendment would jeopardize program quality by speeding up the deadline for the 50 percent of the Head Start teachers having their bachelor's degrees.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Budgets have really forced Head Start centers to make very difficult, sometime impossible decisions to reduce services or to serve fewer children. And I fear that the Mica amendment would exacerbate the hard choices which Head Start programs have faced over recent years because this Congress has not appropriated the kind of money we need.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill that came out of committee, by 42-1, establishes, I think, a rather reasonable and ambitious time line for 50 percent of our Head Start teachers to attain their bachelor's degrees. Under this time line, the bill ensures that Congress can provide the necessary funding to achieve this goal. We have to, as I think we have done in this bill which came out of committee, we have to balance the improvements in the program with the real resources. If we had unlimited resources, we could do all  these things. But I think the bill balances the improvements with the resources.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I urge a "no" vote on this amendment and yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the amendment offered by the gentleman from Florida (Mr. Mica).</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400273" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I demand a recorded vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 6 of rule XVIII, further proceedings on the amendment offered by the gentleman from Florida will be postponed.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400215" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I offer an amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will designate the amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400215" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I'd first like to thank my colleague, John Hall, for his work on this amendment. He was president of his local board of education and knows this issue inside and out from the local perspective. And his work on this has been absolutely instrumental in its preparation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also want to thank Chairman Miller and Chairman Kildee, without whom the work of those for whom this amendment is designed to help, the disability community, those children with disabilities, this amendment is designed to supplement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Frankly, Mr. Chairman, this amendment is really an attempt to just support what is already in this bill in the way of support of inclusive education. What this amendment seeks to do is use those dollars in this bill for teacher education and research, to support the notion that we ought to include children in the classrooms with disabilities  so that we can both better educate those teachers teaching those children with disabilities in how to teach both  children with disabilities in integrated classrooms, in inclusive classrooms, as well as learn from their experiences in doing so, both to the benefit of both children in those inclusive classrooms; and use evidence-based research that we know is constantly coming towards us in terms of how to identify children with autism, how to identify children with learning disabilities and use those new findings and be able to employ them to the benefit of these children's growth and their development.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, that is why we've introduced this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise to claim the time in opposition, even though I support the gentleman's amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the gentleman from California is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe that this is an improvement to the bill and will assist Head Start programs which are required to spend 10 percent of their funds on services to disabled students in improving the quality of their programs to serve young children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400215" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I'd yield 2 minutes to my good friend and colleague from New York, John Hall.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412222" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I won't need that much time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thank you to my colleague from Rhode Island and from the other side of the floor, who just spoke in favor of this amendment. I would like to take a moment to commend all who support this issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are 27 Head Start facilities in my district, and they provide critical services to families that want their children to have every opportunity to grow and succeed. I'm glad that the bill we are considering today will expand access to Head Start and help make sure that America's less well-off children can have a great chance of long-term success when they arrive in our schools.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The amendment will help to meet these goals by providing more support for inclusive education. This is the practice of teaching children with disabilities in the same classrooms as those without disabilities, and it has largely been shown to have a positive effect on the development of those children with disabilities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Head Start Act already requires that 10 percent of enrollment slots go to students with disabilities, and the actual number of enrollees is even higher, at about 13 or 14 percent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although these classrooms can provide increased educational benefits, they also present teachers and staff with increased demands. Teachers and staff have often been forced to try to handle greater responsibilities without the necessary resources. This amendment would help to bridge that gap by allowing training and technical assistance funds to be spent to enhance the ability of classroom staff to meet the needs of eligible children in inclusive classrooms.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Providing more resources for teacher training and support, this amendment would make great strides in improving the quality of the educational experience for all children in a class.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Another fundamental goal of the Head Start program is to make sure that all children have the best chance of success in school and in life. The second provision of this amendment will help to further serve those goals by working to make sure that the inclusive classroom environment benefits every student, including typically developing children. It would do so by allowing research and evaluation funding to be used in further studying the impact of inclusive classrooms on the educational experience  of children with or without disabilities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support it.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400215" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, let me just say, I offer this amendment in honor of my aunt, Eunice Kennedy Shriver, who started the Special Olympics, who has inspired me in this work; and my uncle, Sarge Shriver, who was the first and founding director of Head Start, both individuals who are inspirations to me and to millions in this country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the amendment offered by the gentleman from Rhode Island (Mr. Kennedy).</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400328" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I offer an amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will designate the amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400328" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield myself 3 1/2  minutes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise today to urge my colleagues to support a very important amendment to <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>, and I want to commend Mr. Kildee, Mr. Miller, Mr. McKeon, and the others who have worked so hard on this important bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Head Start is a tremendously important program in the early childhood education continuum, but it is also desperately in need of reforms.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As we all know, the purpose of Head Start is to help disadvantaged children be better prepared to enter school. But we are doing those children an enormous disservice and squandering taxpayer dollars if we do not hold the providers of Head Start services to a higher level of accountability. The existing language in 1429 allows for automatic 5-year renewal of applications, automatic renewal, if they simply meet minimum standards to the satisfaction of the review panel. Providers that don't meet  the standards must enter into open competition for acceptance of their applications. I would respectfully submit this does not go far enough.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For the sake of ensuring the programs are performing better than minimal or better than good enough and as a safeguard for the taxpayers who foot the bill, I believe we should require that all Head Start providers face open competition. Such competition will encourage a higher level of performance and serve as a check on unscrupulous practices.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I am very familiar, unfortunately, with what can happen when a provider is allowed to skate through without the discipline that comes from competition. In my own district, the Polk County Opportunity Council became a poster child for mismanagement and abuse since its dealings first became public in 2003, which actually had followed a probationary status just several years before. Years of investigation have revealed breath-taking examples of malfeasance and mendacity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There has been everything from sweetheart deals involving the purchase of office equipment to claims for nonexistent hurricane damages, essentially amounting to insurance fraud. At one point the PCOC even fabricated a false "certificate of compliance" from the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, which it tried to use to short-circuit other investigations of its misdealings. It took 3 years, 3 years, to defund that agency, and the entire appeals process along the way, and this only  applies to the Head Start program, the entire appeals process was paid for not by the agency,  not by the grantee, but by the taxpayers. The taxpayers paid the bill for them to appeal mismanaging the taxpayers' dollars. Competition, I believe, an open competition, would go a long way towards solving that problem.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The effect of these abuses not only squandered taxpayer dollars, but it diverted resources from some of the neediest and most deserving members of our community. That is an outrage. We must expect better and we must do better. We cannot allow these types of abuses to become the norm. We should not maintain a system that simply continues the status quo. Let's expect providers of Head Start programs to compete with other potential providers, which, unlike during the creation of Head Start, today  there are a number of State and local governments and private entities that can provide that service. Then we will truly be giving these needy children the head start they deserve.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support the amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400216" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise to oppose the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from Michigan is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400216" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, the Putnam amendment would jeopardize the seamless services that many high-quality Head Start programs with very deep roots in their communities provide to disadvantaged children. Because the quality of our Head Start programs is critical to ensuring that disadvantaged children receive the benefits of Head Start, this bill, which passed out with only one dissenting vote from committee, implements a new process to recompete underperforming programs. The amendment by Mr.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>They are reviewed by a panel of experts we put in place to look at them. They are reviewed and have to satisfy that review, but they do not then have to recompete.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Putnam amendment also eliminates the bill's provisions to ensure a fair and equitable process for recompeting underperforming Head Start programs. And we worked hard to get a fair and equitable process for that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By striking those provisions, which he does in his amendment, the Department of Health and Human Services is authorized to create its own system for recompetition.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We worked hard with the Head Start community to try to ensure that we would have a panel of experts that would assure that the unperforming programs were really improved or put out of the system but not have the high performing have to go through the recompetition process every 5 years, but be reviewed by the panel of experts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400328" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 30 seconds to the distinguished ranking member from California.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I think this is a good amendment that Mr. Putnam has put forth. I don't think we should fear competition. I think the idea that once a program is granted, it should have lifelong tenure, I think, is something we should avoid. I think competition and accountability is good. Once every 5 years, programs that are good should not fear competing to keep the program for another 5 years. I think it is always good to have somebody coming up behind you that is going to make you  do a little bit better.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400216" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400328" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, the amendment provides for competition among agencies that are given millions of dollars to manage programs for our neediest children. And unlike during the creation of the Head Start program, today across America there are thousands of potential providers. School boards are now in the early childhood business. United Way is now in the early childhood business. Local communities are now in the early childhood business, providing tremendous educational opportunities for  our neediest young people before they enter kindergarten.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We want them to enter kindergarten ready to learn, and we want to guarantee that the grantees that are managing these precious Head Start dollars are running an adequate, professional, thoughtful program and being good stewards of the people's money. By providing for recompetition every 5 years, we are guaranteeing, as my ranking member friend from California said, that they understand that it is not their birthright to continue that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my friends to support this amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the amendment offered by the gentleman from Florida (Mr. Putnam).</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I demand a recorded vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 6 of rule XVIII, further proceedings on the amendment offered by the gentleman from Florida will be postponed.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400324" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I offer an amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will designate the amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400324" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is an honor to be here to talk about something very critical, I think, to our families and communities across the country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If you recall, last year this body passed historic legislation providing for protection of our children in light of the abuse of our kids throughout schools across the country. We passed legislation to provide for 24 additional States to do background checks on teachers via FBI background and other means through law enforcement. Unfortunately, 24 States were not allowed to, for many different reasons, and that legislation provided for these background checks. Through my amendment that is being  proposed today, close to a million kids that are in the Head Start program will have the same tools available to them that we passed just last year to help kids in K-12.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is one tragic example. There is one grantee in this country that between 2001 and 2005 did not perform background checks on their employees. They finally did background checks. Out of 660 employees, close to 106 had criminal charges against them, including first degree murder, involuntary manslaughter, domestic abuse, assault, child abuse, DUI, and violent crimes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, my language ensures that Head Start programs will have all the databases containing criminal records available to them to make sure that our parents can feel that their most precious resource, their children, will be safe in the Head Start program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield such time as he may consume to Ranking Member McKeon.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And I have seen the work that he has done over the years in protecting children. I think that children are our most vital asset. And because of the risk out there of the kind of lawbreakers that he mentioned that we could eliminate by having a good, solid  background check, I think this is a tremendous amendment. I think it really strengthens the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for his work on behalf of children, and I urge support of the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400324" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400216" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise to speak in support of the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the gentleman from Michigan is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400216" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, we support the amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many of these are included in the regulations, but you would put it in the statute now and expand them, and I think you have done a very good job in your expansion of that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I commend you for your work on this. I commend you for your concern for children. It is very important. We certainly want to protect our children, and I think this is a very good amendment and we support it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400324" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the amendment offered by the gentleman from Nevada (Mr. Porter).</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400638" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I offer an amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will designate the amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400638" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to really thank Chairman Miller and Ranking Member McKeon for their leadership on this bill under consideration today. The Improving Head Start Act of 2007 is a very good bill, and I am pleased to be able to support it and be here today and speak on this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to inquire first, before I got into the text of this, if there are any others that wanted to speak on our side, having just gotten into the Chamber. If not, I will proceed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am presenting this amendment to <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill> based on recommendations I received from my district Head Start leaders to address the goal of maintaining quality in the Head Start program. My amendment would allow for Head Start grantees to negotiate a funded enrollment level with the HHS Secretary if funding for the program does not keep pace with inflation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over the past 3 years, Head Start and Early Head Start have experienced an estimated 8 percent real decline, adjusted for inflation, in Federal funding from fiscal year 2002 through fiscal year 2007. If this trend were to continue, the decline in funding would climb to 10 percent for Head Start programs. If President Bush's budget were to become law, the Head Start programs would suffer an 11 percent cut.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This decline in funding has required already efficient Head Start agencies across the country to tighten their belts even more. Sadly, local agencies are now forced to pass these cuts on to quality staff.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>By default, agencies are unable to compete for the best and brightest of early childhood educators, thus risking the quality of Head Start programs. Our local agencies are forced to make the worst in managerial choices. As Chairman Miller and others have pointed out, we must maintain and enhance both funding and quality.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In my congressional district, I am proud to say that the four primary organizations responsible for administering Head Start services have successfully revitalized the program in the city of St. Louis. From 2001 to 2003, the enrolled number of children grew from about 1,000 to a full enrollment of 3,000 children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, the compensation of St. Louis area Head Start staff has lagged behind the salaries of those in comparable positions. After consulting with some of the brightest business leaders in our area, our local agencies have taken extraordinary steps to conserve costs and maximize efficiencies. Even with these steps, agencies are unable to keep staff compensation in line with inflation increases both in wages and insurance costs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Programs in St. Louis and across the country are at a serious risk of losing quality staff due to this critical situation. In fact, many of you may have agencies within your districts that have experienced worse cuts across their service lines. They have turned to cutting key staff, reducing the number of weeks they operate in a year, and reducing the number of hours they operate in a day just in order to adjust for financial constraints. We must ensure that the historic quality and strength  of Head Start is not placed in jeopardy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many of us know the vast evidence demonstrating the profound difference Head Start makes both in the lives of children served and in our local communities. I know that has been talked about at great length here in presenting this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I just want to close and say, I think all of us would agree that Head Start programs should not have the right to request reduced enrollment levels unless they have taken all appropriate steps to achieve efficiency first. I want to clarify that my amendment gives HHS the discretion to determine whether or not individual agencies have explored all possible solutions prior to requesting reduced funded enrollment. The grantee must demonstrate that any reduction in enrollment is necessary to maintain  the quality of services.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I appreciate, again, all the efforts on this bill that have brought this forth in a bipartisan way, and appreciate the amendment being considered.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="">
    <paragraph>Will the gentleman yield?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400638" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield to the gentleman from California.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in support of the amendment. This is what agencies have to do when the funding isn't sufficient and they are trying to hold on to the number of children, the hours of availability of the program and the quality of the teachers that are there. In the past when we had the cut, I believe the agency, HHS, allowed some local programs to do this. I would hope that this will not be a necessity. We are adding an additional $400 million to this program. I hope that the Appropriations  Committee will be able to follow through.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The amendment is a good amendment. I hope we don't have to use it, but it's a good amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in opposition to the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from California is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, this amendment allows grantees to negotiate a reduced enrollment level with the Secretary of HHS if the amounts appropriated for Head Start do not exceed the prior year's appropriation or include an increase commensurate with  the cost-of-living allowance. In effect, this amendment allows grantees to cut services for children and kick children out of the Head Start program if Congress does not appropriate ever-higher  funding amounts for Head Start.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think all of us want to service as many children as we can, and we want to have as high an appropriation level as we can, but if we fail to appropriate higher numbers, I don't think we should take it out on the children. I ask my colleagues, is Head Start an early education program or a jobs program?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We believe the purpose of Head Start is to help our Nation's most vulnerable youngsters lay the foundation for a very successful academic future. This misguided amendment has the potential for denying these children Head Start services, and I therefore urge my colleagues to oppose the amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the amendment offered by the gentleman from Missouri (Mr. Carnahan).</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I demand a recorded vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 6 of rule XVIII, further proceedings on the amendment offered by the gentleman from Missouri will be postponed.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400657" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I offer an amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will designate the amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400657" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise today to encourage my colleagues to support my amendment to the Improving Head Start Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First of all, I would like to thank Chairman Miller, Ranking Member McKeon, Chairman Kildee and Ranking Member Castle for bringing this legislation to the floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ensuring that Head Start continues to serve our communities is important to all of us. This straightforward amendment builds upon the strong foundation of this year's reauthorization. The reauthorization requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to conduct a study of Head Start students with limited English proficiency.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Studies have proven that the easiest time to learn a new language is when a child is young. With this in mind, early childhood is an important time for students with limited English proficiency to improve their grasp of the English language. Students who are fluent in multiple languages are better positioned to perform well in school.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation requires studies of the progress limited English proficiency students make towards proficiency. The amendment that I offer simply asks that the assessment used to determine progress in the English language skill development be described.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The explanation of what is used is important for a couple of reasons. First, Head Start service providers will become more uniform in their instruction. If a description of assessment is not required, however, there may be a higher likelihood that it will become arbitrary.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second, educators learn from the practices of their colleagues. By having all Head Start providers describe the assessments they use, meaningful information will be gathered to help educators get ideas and make better informed decisions about their own practices. Enhancing consistency and sharing methods are meaningful ways we can help students with limited English proficiency make the progress that they need to make.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My amendment is supported by the National Council of La Raza, the National Education Association, the Texas Migrant Council and the Texas Head Start Association. I urge my colleagues to support my amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 1 minute to Chairman Miller, the gentleman from California.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman, and I rise in support of his amendment. I think his explanation is correct, that this will provide not only perhaps more uniformity in terms of the assessments, but also communications between programs as to which assessments are really working and which assessments are appropriate for this purpose. I think it is a good amendment, and I would hope that we would accept it. I thank the gentleman for offering it.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400657" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise to claim the time in opposition, even though I support the gentleman's amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the gentleman from California is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in support of the amendment. I think it makes the bill stronger. Examining the number of children who are limited in English proficiency and monitoring the progress of these children is important to their mastery of the English language and will help determine future successes for these students in meeting the same challenging State academic content and student academic achievement standards that all children are expected to meet.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I support the amendment, and I encourage our colleagues to support the amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400657" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, again, I want to thank Chairman Miller, Ranking Member McKeon, Chairman Kildee and Ranking Member Castle for their support. And again, I ask for their support on this amendment and on the reauthorization of the Head Start Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the amendment offered by the gentleman from Texas (Mr. Cuellar).</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412225" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I offer an amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will designate the amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412225" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I am proud to be a product of Head Start. As a young boy, I attended a Head Start program, and that helped make me the man that I am today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It's time for Congress to recognize that faith communities contribute to Head Start. That's why I am proud to introduce this amendment today, along with Congressman Ellsworth, Congressman Donnelly, Congressman Carney and Congressman Loebsack.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment thanks the community and faith-based organizations for the good work that they have done running the Head Start programs. It also confirms its right to continue running these programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in opposition to the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from California is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, let's be very clear at the outset about why this amendment is being considered today: It's all about political cover. It has nothing to do with protecting the civil rights of faith-based providers. If that is what we are out to do today, we would be considering Mr. Fortu&#xF1;o's amendment right now. Instead, the majority has brought up a hollow, politically motivated attempt to have it both ways. On one hand, this amendment cheers the work of faith-based providers and  recognizes their contributions to our Nation; but on the other hand, it leaves them completely unprotected when it comes to their right to preserve their identity while serving children in Head Start. Frankly, this is insulting to faith-based organizations as it is transparent. Let me elaborate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With respect to hiring authority, section 702(a) of title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, as amended in 1972, states, "This subchapter shall not apply to a religious corporation, association, educational institution or society with respect to the employment of individuals of a particular religion to perform work connected with the carrying on by such corporation, association, educational institution or society of its activities."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, does this amendment reaffirm the language from this statute? No, it does not.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Consistent with this language from the Civil Rights Act, former President Clinton signed four laws that explicitly allow religious organizations to retain their right to staff on a religious basis when they receive Federal funds. The 1996 welfare reform law, the Children's Health Act of 2000, the Community Services Block Grant Act of 1998, and the Community Renewal Tax Relief Act of 2000 each contain language that reflects the language offered to the Rules Committee yesterday by Mr. Fortu&#xF1;o.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, does this amendment reaffirm the language signed into law on four separate occasions by former President Clinton? No, it does not. The Fortu&#xF1;o amendment would codify a 2002 executive order protecting the right of a participating faith-based organization to display a cross or other religious symbols on its grounds. Mr. Chairman, does this amendment do the same? No, it does not.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment may have been written in such a way that may run counter to that executive order, potentially endangering rights faith-based providers already enjoy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In short, Mr. Chairman, in an attempt to play politics, this amendment is, at best, an attempt to provide political cover for Members who do not want to take a real vote on the issue; and at worst, a poorly drafted measure that may end up turning back the clock on the rights of faith-based providers to display religious symbols. Because of that, I urge my colleagues to oppose it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412225" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 2 minutes to the gentleman from Indiana (Mr. Donnelly).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412205" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, we don't need any political cover. We are proud to stand for this amendment. The only political games are those being played by others.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise in support of this amendment, recognizing the important role that faith and community-based organizations play in Head Start's continued success. Head Start has been instrumental in advancing the development of comprehensive skills in disadvantaged children during the crucial years before they enter elementary school. Since 1965, Head Start has been a resounding success; in no small part because of faith-based organizations, organizations I support fully.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since the beginning, community and faith-based organizations have been a part of this program and currently serve more than 90,000 children and their families. Faith-based organizations play a critical role because they are intimately familiar with the community in which they serve and are driven by a moral commitment to our youth.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment reaffirms Congress' strong support for their current and future involvement in Head Start, making clear that regardless of rumors to the contrary, they will remain eligible on the same basis as other organizations to participate in Head Start.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I urge all my colleagues to support this amendment and the passage of <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>. I am proud to support it and the faith-based organizations that will serve it.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412225" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 2 minutes to the gentleman from California (Mr. George Miller).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I thank the gentleman for yielding and for offering this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is interesting that the other side would now oppose this amendment, but all day long they have been citing us the executive order with the exact same language in it as the basis for the right of faith-based organizations to participate in this program, a right that they have exercised now for more than 40 years. What your amendment does is to take it from the regulations and put it into the statute to guarantee them that right in the law, not just in the executive order and in the regulations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In my own district, the First Baptist organization runs the Head Start program. They do a marvelous job. The reason they are kicking up the smokescreen around Mr. Shuler's amendment is that they want to protect themselves, because they are going to come here with an amendment that is going to try to give people the right to discriminate against people based upon their religion, the right to discriminate with Federal dollars on religion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What Mr. Shuler's amendment does is to make sure that we do not weaken  the ability of faith-based organizations to participate, as they have over their proud history. That is why the broadest array of religious organizations will oppose what is going to be offered in the motion to recommit, but strongly support, strongly support, the Shuler amendment to add this language to the statute to provide this protection and to provide this recognition  of the historical service and the ongoing service that these faith communities have provided to the children that are eligible for Head Start to provide that quality education year after year after year after year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is what this amendment does. We should welcome it. We should adopt it overwhelmingly in this House and get on with the debate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I thank the gentleman and his cosponsors for offering this amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412225" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield the balance of my time to the gentleman from Indiana (Mr. Ellsworth).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from Indiana is recognized for 45 seconds.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412206" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I am proud to be a sponsor of this amendment, and I urge my colleagues to support it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment honors faith-based and community-based organizations that provide essential health services and education to thousands of low-income children each and every day. This program is a perfect example of government and faith-based organizations partnering to provide every child an equal playing field in school and in life, and we must ensure these churches and schools receive the support they need.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment demonstrates our support to the thousands of families across Indiana who depend on Head Start programs run by faith-based and community organizations. These programs are dedicated to ensuring equal opportunities for Hoosier children, and I am proud to support them today on the House floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this amendment and to pass this important bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I would like to read an excerpt from the Family Research Council. "This bill should help ensure that faith-based organizations with proven records of serving the neediest among us will be allowed the freedom to hire the best staff they see fit, free of burdensome regulation."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, it does not. If we had been able to discuss the Fortu&#xF1;o amendment today, we would have been able to vote on ensuring what they are asking for here. Later on in the discussion, I will add these letters, along with several others I have in support of the Fortu&#xF1;o amendment and in opposition to this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, with that, I urge my colleagues to defeat this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. McKeon. Mr. Chairman, I submit the following letters for the RECORD:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>April 30, 2007,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR SPEAKER PELOSI AND MINORITY LEADER BOEHNER: The Coalition to Preserve Religious Freedom, a multi-faith a1liance of education, social-service, and religious freedom organizations, asks for your support to make federal social programs fully open to the participation of qualified faith-based organizations. We are concerned that some federal legislation does not adequately invite faith-based participation, while ensuring the religious liberty of beneficiaries. We are also concerned that  other federal legislation, such as the Workforce Investment Act and the Head Start Act, has language excluding faith-based organizations that desire to retain their freedom when hiring to take account of the religious convictions of potential employees.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We ask in particular for your support to make the Head Start program hospitable to faith-based organizations when <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>, the Improving Head Start Act, comes up for floor action.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the Education and Labor Committee's recent markup of the bill, Resident Commissioner Fortuno's amendment to clarify the eligibility of faith-based organizations to participate in Head Start unfortunately was defeated. The amendment would have added language making it explicit that faith-based organizations are eligible to take part on the same basis as secular organizations, without being required to minimize their religious character. Such language reflects the U.S. Supreme Court's turn in  First Amendment interpretation to the equal treatment or neutrality standard.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As part of the confirmation of the equal eligibility of faith-based providers, the amendment provided that religious organizations participating in Head Start would no longer be required to waive their freedom under the 1964 Civil Rights Act to take account of religion when making employment decisions. We understand that some members regard such an affirmation of the Civil Rights Act's standard as introducing pernicious religious job discrimination into the federal early childhood education program.  Yet the Civil Rights Act expressly provides that it is not to be regarded as discrimination when a religious organization considers religion when evaluating potential employees.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We believe that the Civil Rights Act got it right on this, just as we believe that political and environmental organizations must be free to assess job candidates on</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We respectfully request that you disavow the characterization made by some members of Congress that religious staffing by faith-based organizations is invidious "Job discrimination." "We request that you support the continuing effort in Congress to remove from federal programs language contradicting the Civil Rights Act's affirmation of the religious staffing freedom. We believe that programs such as Head Start and the Workforce Investment Act should be brought into line with the large majority  of federal programs that do not restrict religious staffing by faith-based organizations that desire to collaborate with the government to provide assistance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thank you.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Stanley W. Carlson-Thies,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On behalf of the Coalition to Preserve Religious Freedom and the undersigned organizations:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Organizations are listed for identification purposes only.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dr. Robert C. Andringa, President Emeritus, Council for Christian Colleges and Universities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Anne R. Apodaca, Executive Director, New Mexico Community FaithLinks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dr. Art Ayris, President, The Florida Bridge.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Greg Baylor, Director, Center for Law and Religious Freedom, Christian Legal Society.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Richard Cizik, Vice President for Governmental Affairs, National Association of Evangelicals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rabbi Abba Cohen, Director and Counsel, Washington Office, Agudath Israel of America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Paul Corts, President, Council for Christian Colleges and Universities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Lisa Cummins, Center for New Communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rimmer DeVries, Camano Island, Washington.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nathan Diament, Union of Orthodox Jewish Congregations of America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Barrett Duke, Ph.D., Vice President for Public Policy and Research, Southern Baptist Ethics &amp; Religious Liberty Commission.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mark L. Earley, President, Prison Fellowship Ministries.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rev. Bill Emery, Director, Virginia Roundtable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dr. Bernard Fryshman, President, Association of Advanced Rabbinical and Talmudic Schools, New York, New York.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Israel Gaither, National Commander, The Salvation Army, United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Walter Gilbert, CEO, Open Door Adoption Agency, Inc., Thomasville, GA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dennis Griffith, Executive Director, Teen Challenge of Southern California.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rev. John Hughes, Metro United Methodist Urban Ministries, San Diego, CA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Andrea Lafferty, Executive Director, Traditional Values Coalition.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Donna Long, President, The National Bridge Alliance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>John Long, President, The Georgia Bridge.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rev. Paul Lundberg, Atwater Baptist Church, Atwater, CA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dr. Larry Martin, President, Kentucky Compassion Bridge.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Freddie John Martin, Teltech Development Consulting Corporation, Silver Spring, Maryland.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Tom McClusky, Vice-President for Government Affairs, Family Research Council.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ellen McKinley, Child Development Education Alliance, Orange Park, FL.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Stephen Monsma, The Henry Institute for the Study of Christianity and Politics, Calvin College, Grand Rapids, MI.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rev. James Ortiz, Senior Pastor, President, My Friend's House, Assembly of God, Inc., Metro Impact Ministries. Inc., Whittier Area Evangelical Ministerial Alliance, Whittier, California.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rev. Carl Rehling, Diocesan Liaison for Justice and Peace, Episcopal Diocese of Maryland.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Shari Rendall, Director of Legislation and Policy, Concerned Women for America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Amy L. Sherman, Director, Sagamore Institute Center on Faith in Communities, Charlottesville, VA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dr. Ronald J. Sider, Evangelicals for Social Action, Wynnewood, PA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dr. James W. Skillen, Center for Public Justice.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Taylor Smith, Jr., Vice President of Executive Support, Association of Christian Schools International.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dr. Robert Vickers, President, Artful Askers, The Missouri Bridge.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>David Winter, Chancellor, Westmont College, Santa Barbara, CA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Karen M. Woods, Executive Director, Empowerment Resource Network.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Terrence Woodnorth, Endicott, NY.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Robert L. Woodson, Sr., Center for Neighborhood Enterprise.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dr. Carl Zylstra, President, Dordt College, Sioux Center, Iowa.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Association of Christian Schools International, Office of Government Affairs, </paragraph>
    <paragraph>Silver Springs, MD, April 23, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR SPEAKER PELOSI AND MINORITY LEADER BOEHNER:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Association of Christian Schools International (ACSI), which has member schools and preschools in every state, applauds the strong bipartisan vote by the U.S. House Education and Labor Committee that recently advanced the Improving Head Start Act (<bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>). We know that this measure aims to strengthen the Head Start early childhood education program's teacher and classroom quality, boost coordination between Head Start and state and local early childhood programs, and increase Head Start's  financial accountability. <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill> was introduced by a bipartisan group of Members, led by the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education's Chairman and Ranking Republican Member, Rep. Dale Kildee and Rep. Mike Castle. The undersigned commend these efforts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We do have a major concern which we hope will be corrected before <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill> is voted upon and sent over to the U. S. Senate. During consideration of the Improving Head Start Act, the panel's majority chose to turn back an amendment offered by Committee Member Luis Fortu&#xF1;o (PR) to protect the civil liberties of faith-based providers by clarifying that these institutions are not required to relinquish their Title VII Civil Rights Act-hiring protections when they participate in the federal  Head Start program. The existing and historic civil rights law explicitly protects the rights of religious organizations to take religion into account in their hiring practices, and former President Bill Clinton signed four laws explicitly allowing faith-based groups to staff on a religious basis</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Faith-based groups should not be forced to give up their religious uniqueness because they want to assist the poor and hurting of their community. The faith and values that motivate these Americans to serve others should not be held against them. ACSI, with its many early education members, would like to cooperate with Head Start at the local level, but cannot because of this inappropriate Federal religious discrimination. We are hopeful that the House will have an opportunity to consider this  important issue again when the Head Start bill comes to the House floor. The working-poor families who depend on Head Start services are counting on Congress to protect the Constitutional rights of both the secular and religious organizations that provide an "educational jump-start" for their children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We commend HE&amp;L Committee Member Luis Fortu&#xF1;o of Puerto Rico for his forthright stand that defends religious entities and their Constitutional right to be faithful to their religious beliefs, including the people they choose to hire. We are contacting many Members of both parties, asking them to protect and defend religious hiring rights of faith-based entities. And finally, ACSI and the two dozen groups or individuals who have signed this letter will do all that we can to protect potential  Head Start programs that could be led by multi-faith-based groups in needy areas, but cannot because of the chilling effect of the draconian structure of current law. This is not a right to be given to Christian schools only, but to people of other faiths who represent a diverse, multi-faith society. Note additional cosigners listed on page 2.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Respectfully yours,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Organizations may be listed for purposes of identification only.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Carl H. Esbeck, Legal Counsel to the Office of Governmental Affairs, National Association of Evangelicals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Stephen Lazarus, M. Phil., Senior Policy Associate, Center for Public Justice.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Tim McGhee, President, Mountaintop Group.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>William Murray, Chairman, Religious Freedom Coalition.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rev. Paul Weyrich, Chairman and CEO, Free Congress Foundation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Jim Backlin, Vice President for Legislative Affairs, Christian Coalition of America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Star Parker, Founder and President, Coalition on Urban Renewal &amp; Education.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Robert Heckman, Central City Partners.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Maurine Proctor, President, Family Leader Network.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Gary Bauer. President, American Values.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Tom McClusky, Vice President of Government Affairs, Family Research Council.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Donald E. Wildmon, Founder and Chairman, American Family Association.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ron Shuping, Executive Vice President, The Inspiration Networks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Pam Pryor, Vice President of Government Affairs, We Care America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Kevin "Seamus" Hasson, President, The Becket Fund for Religious Liberty.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Joseph Cella, President, Fidelis.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dr. Carl Herbster, President, AdvanceUSA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Stephen V. Monsma, Ph.D., Research Fellow, The Henry Institute for the Study of Christianity and Politics, Calvin College.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Robin Stephenson, M.A., Director, Early Education Services, Association of Christian Schools International.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ron Sider, President, Evangelicals for Social Action.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rev. Richard Cizik, M. Div., M.A., Vice President of Governmental Affairs, National Association of Evangelicals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>James Standish, J.D., M.B.A., Director of Legislative Affairs, Seventh-day Adventist Church.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Gregory S. Baylor, J.D., Director, Center for Law &amp; Religious Freedom, Christian Legal Society.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Salvation Army, USA Commander Israel Gaither, National Commander.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dear Madam Speaker Pelosi: The Association of Christian Schools International (ACSI) wishes it were able to commend Representatives Shuler (NC), Ellsworth (IN) and Loebsack (IA) for their amendment to <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill> regarding Head Start and the religious rights of faith-based groups. However, we cannot.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Shuler amendment does not actually do anything. It merely lauds the history of Head Start and its relationship with faith-based groups. Should the amendment be accepted by the Rules Committee, it will only function as a "fig leaf" to those who do not want to vote for the legitimate Religious Freedom amendment, like the Fortu&#xF1;o amendment. Any worthwhile amendment must protect religious freedom for faith-based groups' right to hire co-religionists; and protect their rights to show that  they are religious by what they have on their walls--such a Scripture. The Fortu&#xF1;o wording actually reinforces the rights religious groups obtained in Section VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964. Such staffing freedom was held to be constitutional by the United States Supreme Court (9-0) in Presiding Bishop v. Amos in 1987.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We urge the Rules Committee to allow the Fortu&#xF1;o amendment to be voted upon on the House floor in an up-or-down vote. This stand-alone amendment gives Congress the opportunity to vote for or against religious freedom. Faith-based organizations that exist to impact the lives of at-risk children--especially in the inner cities--need a truly religious freedom amendment to bring hope to otherwise hopeless families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Regrettably, the Shuler amendment would only be a way of continuing to deny truly faith-based groups from participating in Head Start with a clear conscience.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Respectfully yours,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rev. John C. Holmes, EdD,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the amendment offered by the gentleman from North Carolina (Mr. Shuler).</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="THE CENTER FOR PUBLIC JUSTICE.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I demand a recorded vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 6 of rule XVIII, further proceedings on the amendment offered by the gentleman from North Carolina will be postponed.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412229" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I offer an amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will designate the amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412229" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise today in support of the Space-Hare-Welch-Altmire amendment to <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I believe that Head Start is critical for our Nation's working families. We are a Nation founded on equality and opportunity for all. All of our Nation's children deserve the opportunity to participate in early childhood development programs regardless as to the financial standing of their families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Head Start programs in rural areas face many unique challenges in delivering services. The January 2007 report from the National Advisory Committee on Rural Health and Human Services confirms the unfortunate reality that rural Head Start programs are, in many ways, disadvantaged.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Simply put, in rural and geographically isolated areas the distance between Head Start providers and participants is a significant mountain to climb. Especially as gas prices continue to stretch both program and household budgets, the cost of transportation can be prohibitive. These distances can also impede Head Start programs from reaching out to families eligible to participate. It is certainly a tragedy when families can't enjoy the opportunities offered by Head Start programs because they  didn't know about them, not because they weren't there.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am particularly concerned about barriers to parental involvement. I believe that parental involvement fostered by Head Start programs is incredibly important. There is no responsibility of our society more sacred or profound than raising our children. Bringing parents together to share in this experience strengthens our communities, creating bonds that can bring them closer together.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In rural areas, parental involvement is again a challenge. The realities of less advantaged areas can keep parents away from these programs. This is simply a missed opportunity to build our communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe that <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill> offers significant improvements to rural Head Start programs, and I applaud the work of my colleagues on the Committee on Education and Labor for making assistance to these areas a priority.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In particular, I wish to thank my colleague from Illinois (Mr. Hare) for his amendment in committee that draws attention to the challenges of teacher retention and the recruitment of new participants in our Nation's rural areas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise to claim the time in opposition, though I am not opposed to the gentleman's amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the gentleman from California is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I think that this amendment makes it a stronger bill. Rural grantees are more likely to rely on home visits due to problems associated with staffing and transportation. Head Start in-home programs are required to make a minimum of 32 visits per year, or one per week. In addition, there must be a minimum of 16 group socialization activities per year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For this reason, I rise in support of this amendment to provide additional training and support to rural Head Start programs facing these challenges to ensure that all children can access the skills necessary to succeed in school.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support the amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412229" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 2 minutes to the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Hare).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412204" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I am honored to join Congressmen Space, Welch and Altmire in introducing this amendment to improve Head Start programs for rural communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Much of my congressional district is rural. Therefore, I am very sensitive to the unique challenges that Head Start centers and rural families face in providing or accessing Head Start programs. Some of these challenges include instructor shortages, access to Head Start programs and outreach to eligible families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a member of the Education and Labor Committee, I had the privilege of addressing these concerns during the markup of this bill. The amendment we present today expands those efforts by directing the Education Secretary to provide the technical assistance and training to remove barriers to professional development, parental involvement, home visits and health screening in rural areas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is my hope that with this commitment from the Secretary and with the addition of services geared towards the needs of rural families, more eligible children will enroll in and experience the benefits of the Head Start program. Rural communities consist of the low-income populations that Head Start was created to serve. Therefore, it is critical that we address the challenges these communities face in administering Head Start to ensure that those families have the access to the opportunities  they need and they so much deserve.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, I thank my colleagues for helping me on this issue, and I urge all Members to vote "yes" to improve the rural Head Start program by passing the Space-Hare-Welch-Altmire amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412229" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield 1 minute to the gentleman from Pennsylvania (Mr. Altmire).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412231" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I thank the gentleman from Ohio for his leadership on this issue, and I rise in strong support of this amendment. I am happy to lend my name to it, because this amendment simply says that rural communities which have distinct needs in Head Start programs will now have a level playing field with the changes that have been made under <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>, which I strongly support.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill builds on Head Start's proven success in a way that is going to benefit parents and teachers who are involved in the program. We want to ensure through this amendment that those successes carry forward into rural communities, specifically as it relates to professional development, parental involvement, home visits and health screenings.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I am pleased to lend my name to this. It is a great amendment, and I thank the gentleman from Ohio for his leadership.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412229" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield the balance of my time to the gentleman from California, Chairman Miller.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I thank the gentleman from Ohio for offering this amendment and for bringing this perspective to this legislation, along with Mr. Hare and Mr. Altmire and Mr. Welch, and for representing the rural communities and raising these issues during this debate and during the consideration of this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sometimes issues get overlooked in the rush to reauthorize the bill and to reauthorize it from a single perspective, so I appreciate this information that they have brought to us. I think the direction to the Secretary to review and to look at these barriers and to see what we can do to remove them so that we can assure both the participation of the children in the program and of their families and their parents as is designed by the law is important.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I urge the adoption of the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the amendment offered by the gentleman from Ohio (Mr. Space).</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Members are advised 2 minutes remain in this vote.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 5-minute vote.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400024" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, on rollcall No. 278, had I been present, I would have voted "aye."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400366" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, on rollcall No. 278, had I been present, I would have voted "aye."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 5-minute vote.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 5-minute vote.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400246" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, during rollcall vote No. 280 on <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>, I mistakenly recorded my vote as "aye" when I should have voted "no." I ask unanimous consent that my statement appear in the RECORD immediately following rollcall vote No. 280.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 5-minute vote.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 5-minute vote.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 5-minute vote.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRY">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have a parliamentary inquiry.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman will state his parliamentary inquiry.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRY">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, isn't it true that under the rules adopted by this House, the number of votes  allowed in the Committee of the Whole is different than the number of votes allowed when the House sits?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman is correct.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRY">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, further parliamentary inquiry.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman will state his inquiry.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRY">
    <paragraph>Isn't it further true, Mr. Speaker, that because of the rules, any re-vote in the House on an amendment that passed in the Committee of the Whole with full participation, the total votes cast would be different?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> That is correct.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400626" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRY">
    <paragraph>I thank the Speaker.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> If not, the question is on the amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>I am in its present form.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will report the motion to recommit.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from California?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, because of a flaw in the Federal Head Start law, faith-based institutions have been forced to relinquish their civil liberties if they choose to participate in the Federal early childhood program we are poised to reauthorize today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A sham of an amendment adopted earlier today applauded these organizations but did nothing to protect faith-based providers' civil rights. This motion to recommit does.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have had this debate many times before here on the House floor, and each time we have had this debate, opponents of faith-based groups' federally protected right to maintain their religious nature and character through those they hire have equated these civil liberties as "discrimination."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The 1964 Civil Rights Act makes clear that faith-based groups may serve their communities without being forced to give up the right to employ individuals who share the tenets and practices of their faith. Mr. Speaker, were the authors of the Civil Rights Act pro-discrimination? No.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The United States Supreme Court in 1987 unanimously reaffirmed the hiring rights for faith-based organizations. Was the Supreme Court pro-discrimination? No.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Former President Clinton signed four laws explicitly allowing faith-based groups to staff on a religious basis when they receive Federal funds. Was he pro-discrimination? No.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The motion to recommit we are considering today is offered in the same spirit as the 1964 Civil Rights Act, the 1987 Supreme Court decision, and President Clinton's signature on those four bills.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I commend the gentleman from Puerto Rico (Mr. Fortu&#xF1;o) for offering this as an amendment before the Rules Committee yesterday.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I now yield the balance of my time to Mr. Fortu&#xF1;o.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. FORTU&#xD1;O. Mr. Speaker, thank you for allowing me to speak today on the motion to recommit <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>, the Improving Head Start Act of 2007. I must commend Chairmen Miller and Kildee and Ranking Members McKeon and Castle for completing work on this important reauthorization.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This motion to recommit would ensure that, one, religious organizations that are participating in the Head Start program are allowed to take religion into account in their hiring practices; and, two, religious organizations that are participating in the Head Start program are not discriminated against on the basis of their religious character and are not required to alter their form of governance or remove religious art, icons, or scripture or other symbols if they decide to participate in the  Federal Head Start program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Faith-based organizations, such as churches, synagogues and other faith-based charities, are a central part of the fabric of communities across America. Many of these organizations provide assistance and services to the neediest members of society, offering a helping hand to the least fortunate among us. Faith-based organizations can make a vital contribution to Federal assistance programs and are critical to the survival of many communities and to the improvement of the lives of countless individuals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When faith-based groups hire employees on a religious basis, they are exercising their civil rights and liberties. The Civil Rights Act made clear when faith-based groups hire employees on a religious basis, it is an exercise of the group's civil liberties and does not constitute "discrimination" under Federal law. Faith-based providers who are willing to help provide early childhood education and other critical social services should not be denied this opportunity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Faith-based organizations cannot be expected to sustain their religious mission without the ability to employ individuals who share the tenets and practices of their faith because it is that faith that motivates them to serve their neighbors in trouble. Without the right to continue to hire on a religious basis, religious organizations, in order to avoid such dangers, are likely to simply withdraw from the  Federal social service efforts altogether, to  the loss of people in need everywhere.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Constitutional protections are included. The motion to recommit prohibits funds from being used for worship, instruction, or proselytization in keeping with constitutional requirements.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This motion to recommit does not permit religious organizations to refuse to assist individuals on the basis of religion, a religious belief, or refusal to participate in a religious practice. The nondiscrimination language of the current Head Start statute prevents discrimination in the provision of service on the basis of race, creed, color, national origin, sex, political affiliation, or beliefs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I claim time in opposition to the motion to recommit.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield to the gentleman from Texas (Mr. Edwards).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400118" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this motion should be called the "religious job discrimination act."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a person of faith who believes strongly in the good work of faith-based groups, I rise to passionately oppose this ill-advised motion, a motion also opposed by the Baptist Joint Committee, the American Jewish Committee, the Episcopal Church, and the NAACP.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our principle is simple but deeply profound. No American, not one, should ever have to pass another American's private religious test to qualify for a tax-funded Federal job. Not one American. Mr. Speaker, I shouldn't have to pass Mr. McKeon's test if I am applying for a Head Start job program, and he should not have to pass my religious test.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The fact is that no group in America, which would be possible under this motion, should be able to accept a $1 million Head Start tax-funded grant and then literally, with your tax dollars in mind, put up a sign that says no Jews nor Catholics need apply here for a federally funded job. To do so is morally wrong. To do so is constitutionally wrong. No American, no American, not one, should ever have to choose between being true to his or her private religious faith and having a federally funded,  tax-funded job.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This motion will harm the Head Start program. It will harm the work of faith-based groups. Vote "yes" for Head Start and "no" for this motion to recommit.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield to the gentleman from Missouri (Mr. Cleaver).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400639" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have been the pastor of the St. James United Methodist Church for 33 years. The bishop gives me the authority to bring pastors onto our staff, and I discriminate. I have five pastors. All of them are Methodists, and they are paid with Methodist dollars. Each one of them. They are paid out of the stewardship of the church, and I have the right to do that. But I don't have the right to accept Federal dollars and discriminate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Minorities have come to Washington over the years because this was the seat of power and it was believed that if you could get close to the seat of power, freedom would be more available. The same thing holds true with dollars. People go to work for the Federal Government, and if they see dollars going to a Head Start program, they believe automatically that there will be no discrimination. And we should not, we should not, turn it around now.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield to the gentleman from Virginia (Mr. Scott).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400364" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, a few weeks ago, Don Imus provoked a national discussion about race, but that was just talk. If we pass this motion, we will take action and turn the clock back before 1965.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment doesn't allow faith-based programs to get funded. The Shuler amendment that we passed reminds us that faith-based organizations can and do sponsor Head Start programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The fact is that any program that can be funded under this amendment could be funded anyway if they would agree not to discriminate in employment. It has nothing to do with symbols. It is absurd to suggest that this has anything to do with symbols. Whatever problem there is with symbols is a constitutional problem that cannot be solved with a motion to recommit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is all about discrimination. And if you can discriminate based on religion, it has racial implications. So since the 1960s, for 40 years, when you talk about civil liberties, you are talking about the victims of discrimination. We decided 40 years ago that it was so reprehensible to discriminate in employment that we made it illegal, even with your own private money. And today, as we talk about discrimination, we ought to think about the victims, not the right of the person to discriminate  against the victim.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The present law allows the church to use its own church money, as the gentleman from Missouri said, to hire whom they want. But with Federal money, just with the Federal money, you have not been able to discriminate. So for 40 years, all children in Head Start programs have learned that their parents are eligible to be hired by the Head Start program regardless of the race or religion of the program. They have known that for over 40 years. This amendment will determine what the next generation  of Head Start students will learn.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We need to defeat this amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I urge my colleagues to vote against this motion to recommit and not adopt a policy of employment discrimination based upon religion.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the previous question is ordered on the motion to recommit.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400267" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I demand a recorded vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 and clause 9 of rule XX, this 15-minute vote on the motion to recommit will be followed by 5-minutes votes on passing <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>, if ordered, and suspending the rules and adopting House Resolution 243.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400412" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I was unavoidably detained and unable to be present at the time of the vote on the motion to recommit <bill type="h" number="1429">H.R. 1429</bill>. Had I been present, I would have voted "no."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the passage of the bill.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400278" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 5-minute vote.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400376" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on rollcall No. 285 I was unavoidably detained. Had I been present, I would have voted "aye."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
