<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1193068802" ordinal="29" title="SANTA ANA RIVER WATER SUPPLY ENHANCEMENT ACT OF 2007">
  <narrative>SANTA ANA RIVER WATER SUPPLY ENHANCEMENT ACT OF 2007 -- (House of Representatives - October 22, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H11803]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="813">H.R. 813</bill>) to amend the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to participate in the Prado Basin Natural Treatment System Project, to authorize the Secretary to carry out a program to assist agencies in projects to construct regional brine lines in California, to authorize the Secretary to participate in the Lower Chino Dairy Area desalination demonstration  and reclamation project, and for other purposes, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="813">H.R. 813</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "Santa Ana River Water Supply Enhancement Act of 2007".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. PRADO BASIN NATURAL TREATMENT SYSTEM PROJECT.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) In General.--The Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act (Public Law 102-575, title XVI; 43 U.S.C. 390h et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;"SEC. 16__. PRADO BASIN NATURAL TREATMENT SYSTEM PROJECT.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(a) In General.--The Secretary, in cooperation with the Orange County Water District, shall participate in the planning, design, and construction of natural treatment systems and wetlands for the flows of the Santa Ana River, California, and its tributaries into the Prado Basin.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(b) Cost Sharing.--The Federal share of the cost of the project described in subsection (a) shall not exceed 25 percent of the total cost of the project.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(c) Limitation.--Funds provided by the Secretary shall not be used for the operation and maintenance of the project described in subsection (a).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(d) Authorization of Appropriations.--There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $20,000,000.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(e) Sunset of Authority.--This section shall have no effect after the date that is 10 years after the date of the enactment of this section.".</narrative>
  <narrative> (b) Conforming Amendment.--The table of sections in section 2 of Public Law 102-575 is further amended by inserting after the last item the following:&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <narrative>"16__. Prado Basin Natural Treatment System Project.".</narrative>
  <narrative>SEC. 3. REGIONAL BRINE LINES.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) In General.--The Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act (Public Law 102-575, title XVI; 43 U.S.C. 390h et seq.) is further amended by adding at the end the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;"SEC. 16__. REGIONAL BRINE LINES.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(a) Southern California.--The Secretary, under Federal reclamation laws and in cooperation with units of local government, may assist agencies in projects to construct regional brine lines to export the salinity imported from the Colorado River to the Pacific Ocean as identified in--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(1) the Salinity Management Study prepared by the Bureau of Reclamation and the Metropolitan Water District of Southern California; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(2) the Southern California Comprehensive Water Reclamation and Reuse Study prepared by the Bureau of Reclamation.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(b) Agreements and Regulations.--The Secretary may enter into such agreements and promulgate such regulations as are necessary to carry out this section.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(c) Cost Sharing.--The Federal share of the cost of a project to construct regional brine lines described in subsection (a) shall not exceed--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(1) 25 percent of the total cost of the project; or&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(2) $40,000,000.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(d) Limitation.--Funds provided by the Secretary shall not be used for operation or maintenance of any project described in subsection (a).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(e) Sunset of Authority.--This section shall have no effect after the date that is 10 years after the date of the enactment of this section.".</narrative>
  <narrative> (b) Conforming Amendment.--The table of sections in section 2 of Public Law 102-575 is further amended by inserting after the last item the following:&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <narrative>"16__. Regional brine lines.".</narrative>
  <narrative>SEC. 4. LOWER CHINO DAIRY AREA DESALINATION DEMONSTRATION AND RECLAMATION PROJECT.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) In General.--The Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act (Public Law 102-575, title XVI; 43 U.S.C. 390h et seq.) is further amended by adding at the end the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;"SEC. 16__. LOWER CHINO DAIRY AREA DESALINATION DEMONSTRATION AND RECLAMATION PROJECT.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(a) In General.--The Secretary, in cooperation with the Chino Basin Watermaster, the Inland Empire Utilities Agency, and the Santa Ana Watershed Project Authority and acting under the Federal reclamation laws, shall participate in the design, planning, and construction of the Lower Chino Dairy Area desalination demonstration and reclamation project.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(b) Cost Sharing.--The Federal share of the cost of the project described in subsection (a) shall not exceed--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(1) 25 percent of the total cost of the project; or&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(2) $50,000,000.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(c) Limitation.--Funds provided by the Secretary shall not be used for operation or maintenance of the project described in subsection (a).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(d) Authorization of Appropriations.--There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out this section.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(e) Sunset of Authority.--This section shall have no effect after the date that is 10 years after the date of the enactment of this section.".</narrative>
  <narrative> (b) Conforming Amendment.--The table of sections in section 2 of Public Law 102-575 is further amended by inserting after the last item the following:&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <narrative>"16__. Lower Chino dairy area desalination demonstration and reclamation project.".</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from Guam (Ms. Bordallo) and the gentleman from Texas (Mr. Gohmert) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentlewoman from Guam.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from Guam?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the purpose of <bill type="h" number="813">H.R. 813</bill>, as amended, is to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to participate in several important projects to improve water supplies in Southern California. In consultation with the minority, the legislation has been amended to eliminate the authorization and funding for a technology center. Similar legislation passed the House in the 109th Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, Mr. Speaker, we support this noncontroversial bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400651" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="813">H.R. 813</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="813">H.R. 813</bill> does enjoy bipartisan support from the Orange County, California delegation. This legislation seeks to reduce Southern California's dependence on imported water by helping localities build needed desalinization infrastructure in the region.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congressman GARY MILLER's bill could not be considered at a better time since millions of water consumers in Southern California may soon feel the brunt of water rationing due to a lawsuit and subsequent judicial decision reducing water deliveries to the region.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A number of our colleagues, on a bipartisan basis, sent a letter over a month ago requesting that the Democratic majority hold a hearing on the impacts of this decision. This Congress needs to recognize that people are a part of the water equation as well in this endangered species debate. We hope the majority will work with us on this important hearing and ways to avoid future water shut-offs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation may be too late to mitigate harmful lawsuits and judicial decisions, but it will help in the long term; and that is why we support the bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400277" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of <bill type="h" number="813">H.R. 813</bill>, the Santa Ana River Water Supply Enhancement Act of 2007, which will significantly increase Southern California's water supply.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Santa Ana River Water Supply Enhancement Act of 2007 authorizes federal funding for a number of important local water projects. When complete, these projects will increase Southern California's water supply by over 37 billion gallons per year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of dwindling supplies, increasing demands, and looming drought, Southern California communities continue to seek non-traditional methods to produce dependable water sources. I am pleased that the House has recognized the importance of addressing the chronic water shortages in Southern California by providing the funding resources necessary to help local water agencies improve water reliability and diversity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="813">H.R. 813</bill>, the Santa Ana River Water Supply Enhancement Act of 2007, will improve Southern California's water supply by developing wetlands in the Prado Basin, and expanding groundwater desalination in the Chino Basin, and constructing regional brine lines.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Specifically, <bill type="h" number="813">H.R. 813</bill> authorizes the federal government to spend $20 million to develop large-scale wetlands along the Santa Ana River in the Prado Basin, to purify the River before it replenishes Orange County's groundwater supplies. This expanded natural treatment system will provide an additional 24.5 billion gallons of water per year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, <bill type="h" number="813">H.R. 813</bill> authorizes $50 million in federal funding to expand groundwater desalination in the Chino Basin from the current 2.9 billion gallons per year to 13 billion gallons per year. This will provide a new fresh drinking water supply for Jurupa Community Services District, Santa Ana Mutual Water Company in Riverside County, and the cities of Norco, Chino, Chino Hills, and Ontario in San Bernardino County.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Also, the bill authorizes $40 million in federal funding to provide methods to safely and efficiently discard excess brine from nearby desalination plants by constructing a line that transports residual brine to the Pacific Ocean. This will ensure salt water does not contaminate fresh groundwater supplies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If we want to sustain America's economic growth and provide for a rapidly increasing population, we must ensure our communities have efficient and reliable access to water resources. By encouraging the use of innovative technologies through water recycling and desalination, this bill ensures that more drinking water will be available across Southern California.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I urge my colleagues to support this important bill. As it moves forward through the legislative process, I will continue to urge for its expeditious enactment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400651" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no further requests for time, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from Guam (Ms. Bordallo) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="813">H.R. 813</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the bill, as amended, was passed.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
