<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1194973204" ordinal="33" title="ENHANCING THE EFFECTIVE PROSECUTION OF CHILD PORNOGRAPHY ACT OF 2007">
  <narrative>ENHANCING THE EFFECTIVE PROSECUTION OF CHILD PORNOGRAPHY ACT OF 2007 -- (House of Representatives - November 13, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H13594]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400080" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="4136">H.R. 4136</bill>) to amend title 18 of the United States Code to clarify the scope of the child pornography laws and for other purposes, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="4136">H.R. 4136</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "Enhancing the Effective Prosecution of Child Pornography Act of 2007".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. MONEY LAUNDERING PREDICATE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Section 1956(c)(7)(D) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting "2252A (relating to child pornography) where the child pornography at issue involves minors, 2260 (production of certain child pornography for importation into the United States)," before "section 2280".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 3. POSSESSION OFFENSES INCLUDE INTENTIONAL VIEWING ON THE INTERNET.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Section 2252.--Section 2252 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(d) Definition.--As used in this section with respect to a visual depiction, the term `possess' includes accessing by computer with the intent to view.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Section 2252A.--Section 2252A of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</narrative>
  <narrative> "(g) Definition.--As used in this section with respect to child pornography, the term `possess' includes accessing by computer with intent to view.".&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Michigan (Mr. Conyers) and the gentleman from Virginia (Mr. Goodlatte) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Michigan.</chair>
  <chair/>
  <speaking speaker="400080" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members  have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Michigan?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400080" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, <bill type="h" number="4136">H.R. 4136</bill>, the Enhancing the Effective Prosecution of Child Pornography Act, addresses two gaps in the criminal statutes that punish those who trade in, profit from, and create the market for child pornography. First, the bill provides that those who launder proceeds from the business of child pornography may be charged with money laundering. This is obviously common sense, and a provision supported by the Department of Justice.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Then, it clarifies the definition of possession in the child pornography laws so that knowingly accessing child pornography on the Internet with intent to view it constitutes possession, even if the user does not download or otherwise save the images. Some defendants have claimed that they did not intend to possess the images, even when they clearly intended to view them, and some courts have said the reach of the statute is unclear in this regard. This measure removes any ambiguity from the  law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are grateful to CHRIS CARNEY, our colleague from Pennsylvania, who has authored this measure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400154" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="4136">H.R. 4136</bill>, the Enhancing the Effective Prosecution of Child Pornography Act of 2007. This bill adds child pornography offenses as money laundering predicates and clarifies existing law to prohibit knowingly accessing child pornography with the intent to view it. Child pornography is a multibillion-dollar worldwide industry. It is despicable in its scope, and it is vicious in its victimization of children. Money is what fuels this horrific crime.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The majority's proposal in <bill type="h" number="4136">H.R. 4136</bill> takes a limited step to prohibit money laundering offenses as part of a child pornography scheme. But much more is needed. Legislation proposed by our ranking member, LAMAR SMITH, and Mr. Chabot, a member of the Judiciary Committee, contains a host of proposals to increase penalties for child predators and pornographers and provides law enforcement tools for combating these heinous crimes in a virtual universe. Unfortunately, the majority chose  to ignore the improvements proposed by many Republican members.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, <bill type="h" number="4136">H.R. 4136</bill> does enact Representative MARILYN MUSGRAVE'S proposals in <bill type="h" number="3148">H.R. 3148</bill>, which was introduced on July 24, 2007, the Child Pornography Elimination Act. I commend Mrs. Musgrave for her legislative efforts. This closes a loophole in the law that child pornographers use to avoid possession of child pornography by not downloading the material. This provision will prohibit accessing such material with the intent to view it and will not require an offender to actually  download the material.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This provision is a good one, and we support it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400080" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, we are happy to get the support and concurrence of the gentleman from Virginia on this measure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield such time as he may consume to the gentleman from Pennsylvania (Mr. Carney), the author of the legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412234" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I am proud here today to stand with my colleagues to consider a number of child safety bills on the floor. I especially want to thank the House Judiciary Committee and particularly Chairman Conyers and his staff for their help.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a proud father of five, I know how important the safety and well-being of our children is for our Nation. That is why I have introduced the Enhancing the Effective Prosecution of Child Pornography Act of 2007. This legislation will allow the Department of Justice to more effectively prosecute people who produce child pornography or knowingly access child pornography repeatedly with the intent to view it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are trying to dry up the source of demand for child pornographers. This legislation addresses a component of the problem that has been difficult for prosecutors to combat, the repeat consumer. We need to stop child pornography at the source and we need to stifle the demand. This is not about playing "gotcha" games with anyone accidentally stumbling across a mistyped Web address. Rather, this is going after those who repeatedly seek out child pornography and those that continue to produce  it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>No one disagrees that we need to protect our children and we need to stop pornography at its source, especially child pornography. I want to encourage all my colleagues to support this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400154" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no additional speakers and urge my colleagues to support this legislation. I thank the chairman of the committee for his hard work on all of these series of bills and hope to have the opportunity to continue to work with him to perhaps make some perfecting improvements as we move forward.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400080" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no further requests for speakers, and I yield back the balance of my time and thank the floor manager for his excellent work on all these measures.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Michigan (Mr. Conyers) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="4136">H.R. 4136</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400080" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this motion will be postponed.</chair>
</record>
