<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1179936136" ordinal="41" title="TRAUMATIC BRAIN INJURY HEALTH ENHANCEMENT AND LONG-TERM SUPPORT ACT OF 2007">
  <speaking speaker="400133" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="2199">H.R. 2199</bill>) to amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide certain improvements in the treatment of individuals with traumatic brain injuries, and for other purposes, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from California (Mr. Filner) and the gentleman from Indiana (Mr. Buyer) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400133" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself 3 minutes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would point out this is one of the most important bills on the floor today or at any time. It's called the Traumatic Brain Injury Health Enhancement and Long-Term Support Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The wounded from wars in Afghanistan and Iraq are returning with multiple injuries due to the use of improvised explosive devices, or IEDs. This often results in servicemembers and veterans needing polytrauma care, and has caused an increase in veterans with brain injury, or TBI.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are going to have tens of thousands of these young men and women with these injuries. Among veterans and servicemembers that return from OEF and OIF and treated at Walter Reed for injuries of any type, approximately 65 percent have TBI or a comorbid, as they call it, diagnosis. Survivors of TBI experience physical, cognitive, emotional and community integration issues. Because of their injury, their capacity and initiative to seek appropriate care on their own is diminished.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are also faced with thousands of veterans returning from Iraq and Afghanistan with milder cases of brain injury. This milder case often is missed and goes untreated, and symptoms may often mirror that of PTSD. Indeed, according to the Defense and Veterans Brain Injury Center, in prior military conflicts, TBI was present in up to 14 to 20 percent of surviving casualties. The numbers for operations in OEF/OIF are predicted to go much, much higher.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We must ensure that the health care and services that meet the needs of returning servicemembers are available and accessible, while never forgetting the needs of veterans from previous conflicts. This bill provides for mandatory screening of veterans for traumatic brain injury. It requires the Secretary to establish a comprehensive program of long-term care, of postacute traumatic brain injury rehabilitation at four geographically disbursed polytrauma network sites. It provides for the establishment  of TBI transition offices at each Department polytrauma network site to coordinate health care and services to veterans who suffer from moderate to severe traumatic brain injuries. It requires the Secretary to establish a registry of those who served in Iraq who exhibit symptoms associated with TBI.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation establishes centers for TBI research, education and clinical activities, and requires the Secretary to establish a committee on the care of veterans with TBI. In addition to the provisions that address health care, research and treatment for veterans, this legislation also provides for veterans who reside in rural areas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, it is a very important bill. We will hear soon from Mr. Michaud, the chairman of our Health Subcommittee, who was the primary author of this, who has been a leader to make sure that we serve the veterans who come back with these incredible injuries, that they receive the proper care that they need.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400056" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me first take this opportunity to thank the chairman of the Subcommittee on Health, Mr. Michaud, as well as the subcommittee's ranking member, Mr. Miller, for their leadership in developing this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2199">H.R. 2199</bill>, as amended, the Traumatic Brain Injury Health Enhancement and Long-Term Support Act of 2007, seeks to improve the treatment of veterans suffering with traumatic brain injuries, often referred to as TBI, and the care for veterans who live in rural communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>However, I would comment that several of the provisions included in this legislation are similar to initiatives that already exist or are getting underway. For example, section 2 of the bill would require the VA to screen eligible veterans for symptoms of traumatic brain injury and create a TBI registry. These are also the recommendations of the President's task force on returning global war on terror heroes. In addition, in March 2007, Secretary Nicholson directed a number of changes to improve  the way the VA provides care to our newest combat veterans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These veterans initiatives include screening all OEF and OIF combat patients for TBI and for PTSD; providing each polytrauma patient with an advocate to assist them and their family; mandatory training for all VA health care personnel to recognize and care for patients with TBI; and establishing an outside panel of clinical experts to review the VA polytrauma system of care.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Additionally, the bill would provide five new centers for TBI research, education, and clinical activities. During the 108th Congress, we recognized the frequency and unique nature of the polytrauma/blast injuries resulting from the global war on terror. These injuries require an interdisciplinary program to handle the medical, psychological, rehabilitation, and prosthetic needs of the injured servicemember.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Public Law 108-422, the Veterans' Health Programs Improvement Act of 2004, directed VA to establish "an appropriate number of centers for research, education, and clinical activities to improve and coordinate rehabilitative services for veterans suffering from complex multitrauma from combat injuries, and to coordinate these services with the Department of Defense."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The centers required in Public Law 108-422 became the Polytrauma System of Care. There are four centers located in Richmond, VA; Tampa, FL; Minneapolis, MN; and Palo Alto, CA. The committee strongly recommends that the new TBI centers be colocated with the VA's polytrauma rehabilitation centers. In this way, we can capitalize on the experience and expertise available at the polytrauma centers and enhance the ability to understand and treat the entire spectrum of the TBI injury from mild to most  severe.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank Mr. Michaud for recognizing that we can actually get some benefits by the colocation of these services where TBI is already located. Because we take and concentrate such expertise, the colocation can only have benefits. And the gentleman worked with me, and I think because TBI have a number of comorbidities such as PTSD, depression, anxiety disorders, and while these issues may appear with TBI, they may also exhibit themselves separately from TBI, and I think that is  exactly what Mr. Michaud is trying to get to. So I want to thank the gentleman for his leadership and for bringing this bill to the committee, along with your staff, for their good work.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400133" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I recognize the chairman of our subcommittee who has taken such a great leadership role on these issues, the gentleman from Maine (Mr. Michaud) for 4 minutes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400274" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I thank the chairman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2199">H.R. 2199</bill> is a bipartisan effort to address the challenges presented by traumatic brain injury and to improve the quality of care for our rural veterans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>TBI is considered to be the signature wound of this war. TBI is complex and frequently overlooked or misdiagnosed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We also have very little understanding of the long-term consequences of TBI. We must make sure that the VA is doing all they can to provide for these wounded soldiers. This is only the beginning, we still have more work to do, but this is a good first step.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2199">H.R. 2199</bill> also includes two provisions to improve the quality of care provided  to our rural veterans. With so many veterans from Iraq and Afghanistan living in rural areas, and an already existing population of older veterans in these areas, we need to explore innovative ways to improve VA accessibility and quality of care, especially on mental health issues. You heard both from the chairman and ranking member as far as what this legislation does.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to recognize the hard work of a group of Members on both sides of the aisle who helped craft this legislation. This truly is bipartisan legislation. I do want to start with my good friend, Mr. Miller of Florida, who is the ranking member of the Health Care Subcommittee, who has been extremely helpful in getting this legislation introduced and moved through the full committee; also, Mr. Altmire of Pennsylvania, who has taken a real leadership role in traumatic brain  injury, and for his focus on TBI with his legislation, <bill type="h" number="1944">H.R. 1944</bill>, which is included in <bill type="h" number="2199">H.R. 2199</bill>; Mr. Walz of Minnesota, for his legislation to establish centers for TBI research, education, and clinical activities, which are now also included in <bill type="h" number="2199">H.R. 2199</bill>, who also served on the Veterans' Affairs Committee; and Mr. McNerney of California, his legislation was included in <bill type="h" number="2199">H.R. 2199</bill> to create the Committee on Care for Veterans with TBI; Mr. Donnelly, who sits on the Veterans' Affairs Committee, of Indiana,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So this truly has been a real bipartisan piece of legislation that took a lot of components of other bills that were through, that were introduced and we had hearings on, to be part of this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also would like to thank Ranking Member Buyer for his focus on this issue, and for his understanding of the importance of long-term research and the pursuit of the best practices for TBI care. He definitely has been very helpful with this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And, finally, I would like to thank and congratulate Chairman Filner for his strong bipartisan leadership on this bill and other veterans bills on the floor as well, and look forward to tackling other veterans issues as we move forward in the 110th Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support <bill type="h" number="2199">H.R. 2199</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400056" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would like to thank Mr. Michaud because he did his committee work. He did his committee work because we brought a bill to the floor. Yes, under suspension, Mr. Filner, but he did his committee work. He filed a report which allowed us to work with him. When you don't file a report, you deny the minority their opportunity to be heard.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I want to thank Mr. Michaud for working with us and for his leadership.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield such time as he may consume to the gentleman from Arkansas (Mr. Boozman).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400040" topic="">
    <paragraph>The only thing I would say is that, again, I am very much in support of the bill and I appreciate the leadership that was shown, as Mr. Buyer just said, in getting the bill forward. I think it is a great example of everybody working together which, again, our committee very often does demonstrate. So I am very much in support, and urge a "yes" vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400133" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 1 1/4  minutes to the chairwoman of our Economic Opportunity Subcommittee, the gentlelady from South Dakota, Stephanie Herseth Sandlin.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="SANDLIN, HERSETH" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in strong support of <bill type="h" number="2199">H.R. 2199</bill>, the Traumatic Brain Injury Health Enhancement and Long-Term Support Act. I would like to thank the chairman of the Veterans' Affairs Health Subcommittee, Mr. Michaud, for introducing this important bill, and to thank Chairman Filner and the ranking member for their support of this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Among other provisions, <bill type="h" number="2199">H.R. 2199</bill> requires screening of veterans for TBI, establishes a comprehensive program for long-term TBI rehabilitation to be located at the polytrauma centers, and creates TBI transition offices at each of the polytrauma network sites. In addition, the bill creates an advisory committee on rural veterans. These are important steps toward helping the young men and women who have suffered traumatic brain injury, and ensuring the needs of our rural veterans are addressed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Working closely with a National Guard soldier from South Dakota who suffered a traumatic brain injury while serving in Iraq, and having visited him and his family at the Minneapolis polytrauma center, I witnessed both the good and the bad of the VA's efforts to deal with these wounded servicemembers. While we have made remarkable strides in treating veterans with brain injuries, there is much room for improvement, especially when it comes to the long-term support of these servicemembers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe the Traumatic Brain Injury Health Enhancement and Long-Term Support Act will tremendously improve the services available to veterans suffering from TBI. I look forward to continuing working with my colleagues on the Veterans' Affairs Committee to address these and other issues related to treating veterans suffering from traumatic brain injury.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, I thank Representative Michaud for introducing and advancing this bill, and I ask my colleagues to support <bill type="h" number="2199">H.R. 2199</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400056" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400133" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, we have had many people contribute to this legislation, as Mr. Michaud said. I would like to recognize a great new Member from Indiana who has worked hard on this legislation, Mr. Donnelly, for 2 minutes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412205" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in strong support of <bill type="h" number="2199">H.R. 2199</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this bill will help us better care for America's wounded warriors suffering from traumatic brain injury, the signature wound of the Iraq and Afghanistan wars. This important legislation will require the VA to better screen veterans for symptoms of TBI, devise a long-term care strategy, and promote better understanding of TBI and how we can provide the best care possible.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also want to thank my good friend, Mr. Michaud, for including my bill, <bill type="h" number="2190">H.R. 2190</bill>, establishing an advisory committee on rural veterans, as a provision of this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, over 40 percent of returning Iraq and Afghanistan veterans are coming home to rural communities, and countless older veterans live in rural America, places like Pulaski County and Starke County, Indiana. The health care needs and services rural veterans require are very, very unique. These veterans often have increased barriers to obtaining the same quality of care as their urban and suburban counterparts. We must do better by them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is critical that the VA have direct input from rural veterans at the highest level of policymaking. The Advisory Committee on Rural Veterans will work with and advise the VA Secretary on how policies and programs affect them, and how services can be improved for rural veterans and their families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues in the House to pass this bill to improve care for our wounded warriors and America's rural veterans.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400056" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would also like to express my support for a provision in the bill that would require the VA to establish a TBI transition office at each of the polytrauma network sites. Not only is this vital for the DOD and the VA to provide for a seamless transition from active duty to veteran status, but it is also important for VA to aid in the coordination of veteran care between VA and other health care providers for services that could possibly not be provided by the VA. These  transition offices would help coordinate veterans care for services not offered by the VA, and have the authority to arrange care with public or private entities to establish long-term neurobehavioral rehabilitation and recovery programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also includes two rural health initiative provisions, one of which would establish a pilot program for vet centers in rural areas. <bill type="h" number="2199">H.R. 2199</bill>, as amended, included an amendment  offered by Mr. Lamborn of Colorado, the ranking member of the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs. This amendment will expand the role of the mobile vet center pilot program to include helping veterans in need of assistance in the filing  of benefits claims.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield such time as he may consume to the gentleman from Colorado (Mr. Lamborn).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in strong support of <bill type="h" number="2199">H.R. 2199</bill>, the Traumatic Brain Injury Health Enhancement and Long-Term Support Act of 2007. I thank Chairman Filner, Ranking Member Buyer, and Health Subcommittee Chairman Michaud, the sponsor of this legislation, for their leadership in bringing this excellent legislation to the floor. I especially want to thank the gentleman from Maine for working with me on a bipartisan basis to include my amendment in this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One of the provisions of <bill type="h" number="2199">H.R. 2199</bill>, as introduced, is a pilot program of mobile vet centers which would provide veterans with readjustment counseling and related mental health services. My amendment would require that these mobile vet centers have trained staff to provide veterans with benefits outreach and help them with their claims applications and questions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, much of the trouble associated with the claims processing system is related to a veteran's difficulties in filing a correct and complete claim. Veterans may have an incomplete understanding of the claims system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>That could easily lead to an imperfectly completed application. My amendment would help solve this problem by placing qualified VA employees in the mobile vet centers to educate the veteran and help him or her to correctly fill out their paperwork the first time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2199">H.R. 2199</bill> could have significant impact on reducing the growing backlog of compensation and pension claims. I ask my colleagues to support this legislation. It will help veterans with traumatic brain injury get the care they need. At the same time, it will help veterans seeking to apply for the benefits they have earned in service to their Nation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400133" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would like to yield 2 minutes to another hard-working new member from our committee, the gentleman from California (Mr. McNerney).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412189" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, traumatic brain injury is the signature injury of the war in Iraq.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me explain a little bit what happens to a veteran soldier with a traumatic brain injury. They remove part of your skull so that your brain can expand into that while it's swelling up. They give you blood thinners so that you don't have blood clots. They give you antibiotics, and they put on a vest that keeps your body temperature cold, again so that you don't swell up and cause more injury. So this is the kind of thing that these veterans, these soldiers are going through.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And we estimate that there's approximately 12,000 servicemembers with some degree of traumatic brain injury. That's why I was motivated, along with Mr. Boozman from Arkansas, to introduce the Caring for Veterans with Traumatic Brain Injury Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2199">H.R. 2199</bill> ensures that the VA will develop the infrastructure necessary to meet the needs of an increasing number of veterans diagnosed with TBI. Among other things, the bill requires the VA to screen all veterans for TBI. It creates a registry for veterans with TBI so that we don't lose track of them once they're diagnosed, and it also creates transition offices for patients with TBI who live in areas where the Veterans Administration isn't able to meet their needs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I'm thankful for the leadership of Mr. Michaud and Mr. Filner on this issue, and for the opportunity to speak in favor of 2199.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400056" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400133" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would like to yield 2 minutes to another hard-working new member of our committee, the highest-enlisted man ever to be elected to Congress, Command Sergeant Major Tim Walz from Minnesota.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412214" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of <bill type="h" number="2199">H.R. 2199</bill>. I want to thank my colleague from Maine for sponsoring this piece of legislation; also thank my colleague from Maine (Mr. Michaud), who's been a leader on this issue and veterans issues in general; grateful that he introduced this piece of legislation, and grateful that he allowed a piece of legislation that I had introduced establishing the five TBI centers around the country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I'd also like to thank the ranking member, the gentleman from Indiana, for his thoughtful guidance on the colocation of those facilities. I think it's absolutely the right thing to do. I think it concentrates our resources and our expertise. So I thank him for that addition to it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The colocation at the polytrauma centers is the right thing to do. The research that's being done there is world class. And I think an example of how we can enhance that comes from, and you just heard one of my colleagues speaking about this injury.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I visit the VA centers every Veterans Day for the last quite some time. And several years ago there was a young man from Michigan there, and he had suffered a traumatic brain injury. He had survived a shrapnel wound, but his brain had literally been turned inside of his head. And because of the great care he was receiving there, he was stabilized, and he was starting to rehabilitate. This bill will allow us to enhance his recovery, starting to reintegrate him back to the life that he knows and  that he should be able to live.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On this floor we're going to continue to debate the wars. We're going to continue to see the debates divide us on the war in Iraq. This Congress, and I thank the ranking member, and the chairman for allowing the care of our veterans to bring us back together. Regardless of how we feel on this war, this Congress and this committee is proving that the 110th Congress can and will advance crucial legislation like <bill type="h" number="2199">H.R. 2199</bill>. So I thank you both. I thank my colleagues.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400056" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I want to thank the gentleman who just spoke. As a retired sergeant major, we benefit by his expertise not only on the Veterans' Affairs Committee, but also in Congress. We have a lot of people here who have been enlisted, and we have had officers and generals and admirals, but when you get a sergeant major, they speak softly. And there's a reason the sergeant major speaks softly, because he doesn't have to speak loudly because they are so well respected. And so, Sergeant  Major, your contributions to the committee are recognized and appreciated.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400133" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, how much time do we have left?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from California has 6 1/2  minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400133" topic="">
    <paragraph>I would now recognize another great new Member from Pennsylvania (Mr. Altmire) for 2 minutes. He has taken the lead on dealing with traumatic brain injury.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412231" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, our brave service men and women are returning from Iraq and Afghanistan with TBI at an alarming rate. Sixty-five percent of the soldiers at Walter Reed today have been diagnosed with traumatic injury, and thousands of veterans have mild TBI, but have not been diagnosed. And I'm concerned that the VA has not been properly diagnosing and treating those veterans with traumatic brain injury.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As has been mentioned today, traumatic brain injury is the signature injury for the wars in Afghanistan and Iraq. This is why I introduced the Veterans Traumatic Brain Injury Treatment Act, which has been included in its entirety in this legislation we're debating today. My bill would improve the diagnosis and treatment of TBI for our Nation's veterans by requiring the VA to screen veterans for symptoms, develop and operate a comprehensive program of long-term care for postacute TBI rehabilitation,  establish TBI transition offices at all polytrauma network sites, and create and maintain a TBI health registry.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to improving the diagnosis and treatment of traumatic brain injury, this bill will improve the VA's research of TBI and ensure that the VA provides better care to veterans in rural communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank the subcommittee chairman, Mr. Michaud, and the full  committee chair, Mr. Filner, for their leadership on this issue, for including my legislation in its entirety in this bill, and I want to urge my colleagues to support this piece of legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400056" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I appreciate the gentleman's comments that he just made. Before you take off, this issue, and I appreciate your interest in it because this is one of our great challenges. We've got the best helmet that we put on our soldiers and marines in the field and even some of the Air Force personnel, Navy personnel. And it protects them against ballistics, and it's the best in the world. But when it comes to blasts and crash, what it does to the brain, we're now on the forefront,  and we are pushing the boundary of our knowledge.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And some of the world's experts now are not only at the polytrauma centers, but in particular, when these soldiers end up at Landstuhl, Germany, that's where they are. So they can immediately deal with these neurotraumas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And when the gentleman said that there could possibly be thousands, what we do know is that at the polytrauma centers, those who are actually being treated for traumatic brain injury, there's less than 400 cases.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But the gentleman is right with regard to individuals who may have had a concussion. Yet, how severe is the concussion?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And if the science is unknown, and we're trying to understand that. That's the purpose of Mr. Michaud's bill. And I appreciate the gentleman's interest, would love to continue to work with you in your interest.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I'd bring to your attention the Veterans Health Administration Directive 2007-013 released April 13, 2007, establishes the VA policy and procedure for screening and evaluation of possible TBI in OEF and OIF veterans. This directive states, "Not all patients who screen positive have TBI. It is possible to respond positively to all four sections due to the presence of other conditions such as PTSD, cervical cranial injury with headaches and inner ear injury, for example. Therefore, it's critical  that patients not be labeled with a diagnosis of TBI on the basis of a positive screening test. Patients need to be referred for further evaluation."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So we are in an area of science whereby the sand shifts directly under our feet, and I would look forward to working with the gentleman.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400133" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I'd like to yield 2 minutes to the fighting gentleman from New Jersey (Mr. Pascrell), who we like to call an honorary member of the Veterans' Committee since he fights so hard for veterans and is cochair of the Traumatic Brain Injury Caucus in the Congress.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400309" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in favor of <bill type="h" number="2199">H.R. 2199</bill>, the Traumatic Brain Injury Health Enhancement and Long-Term Support Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As cochair of the 8-year-old Congressional Brain Injury Task Force of over 110 members, I commend the committee under Chairman Filner's leadership. You've never, ever acted, through the Speaker, to do favors for veterans. You've always handled it in terms of your own responsibility. I salute you for that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For his ongoing endeavors to explore and thoughtfully legislate for the benefit of our Nation's many veterans suffering from TBI, I want to thank Jack Murtha, Congressman Murtha, for all his work over the last 5 years on this issue when it wasn't popular to talk about.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Veterans Administration has shown tremendous effort in addressing the needs of our returning vets, our returning troops on its own; however, I believe the large volume of returning TBI victims, the need for timely treatment and the immediate need for rehab, expertise and capacity require additional resources. Flexibility for the VA to form partnerships to ensure top-notch care for our service personnel is essential. 2199 is an excellent first step to ensuring our Nation's veterans the care  they need and deserve.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill establishes five new Veterans Administration research centers for TBI, which, without a doubt, produce new and exciting prevention and treatment techniques. A comprehensive TBI treatment program within the VA is long overdue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to commend the TBI screening program for veterans. We recommended it. Football teams throughout the United States screen students before they put on football equipment. I think that's important that we do that with our vets. I worked to establish it in the civilian realm. We should have it in the military.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On behalf of the task force, I look forward to working with the Veterans Committee on this and other TBI issues in the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to vote in favor of <bill type="h" number="2199">H.R. 2199</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400056" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At the May 9, 2007, full committee hearing on the results of the President's Task Force on Returning Global War on Terror Heroes, in response to my questioning about the actual number of TBI cases treated in VA as inpatients, Secretary Nicholson responded that VA has treated 369 veterans in its polytrauma centers so far for TBI.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Secretary Nicholson also commented that the VA has the capacity in their polytrauma centers, and that many of the patients in the polytrauma centers are active duty military.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I continue to reserve my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400133" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I'd like to yield 2 minutes to another great new Member fighting for veterans, Congressman Welch from Vermont.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412239" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I want to thank the Veterans' Affairs Committee, the openness of that committee, to let anyone with a good idea to help veterans to come in and have an opportunity to do that. Mr. Filner, Mr. Michaud, and, of course, Mr. Buyer and Mr. Miller, thank you.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rural Americans have always served the Nation's armed services, National Guard and Reserves in very great numbers. In fact, though only 19 percent of the Nation lives in rural America, 44 percent of the current U.S. military recruits come from rural areas, and nearly one-third of those who died in Iraq are from small towns and communities across the Nation, Vermont very much among them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And unfortunately, access to health care for many of our veterans in rural areas is limited by mileage, distance and just the difficulty of transportation. Especially true, the provision of mental health care in rural settings has historically been a challenge for all health care systems and providers, including the VA. And therefore, what we recognize in this legislation is that we need to help the VA develop innovative solutions to address the need for mental health services in remote areas,  TBI being the big injury that's been discussed by my colleagues.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation takes a significant step towards improving the mental health services available to geographically isolated veterans. It creates a pilot program where at least two mobile vet centers will provide readjustment counseling and mental health services to veterans in at least five Veterans Integrated Service Networks that have the highest concentration of rural veterans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>One of these covers New England and my home State of Vermont. These mobile vet centers will also provide information and outreach concerning veterans benefits and, when practicable, assistance with claims for benefits.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rural individuals and their families have strong bonds and ties to their communities. These mobile vet centers will allow veterans to stay in their communities and prevent endless hours of car rides for the care they receive.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge support and passage of this legislation and thank the committee for its indulgence.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400056" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I believe that it is conceivable that at some point one of these needed Traumatic Brain Injury Centers of Excellence could be located in the Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Center in Albuquerque, New Mexico, which could be named the Raymond G. "Jerry" Murphy Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Center, if Chairman Filner would clear either <bill type="h" number="474">H.R. 474</bill> or take up Senate bill 229 for consideration on the floor of which that Senate bill, Mr. Speaker, sits  at your desk.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400133" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, let me just conclude by saying like everything else about this war, the administration did not prepare either for the fighting, the aftermath, or the treatment of the  veterans coming back. We simply left thousands of our veterans without adequate resources to treat these brain injuries or PTSD or other issues that arise. No matter what denial that comes from the minority party, no matter what denial comes from the administration,  we have not prepared for adequate treatment of these veterans. We are passing legislation today to do that, and we will not deny that there will be thousands and thousands of brain-injured veterans. We should bring them home now and we should treat them well when they get back.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412229" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise again today in support of <bill type="h" number="2199">H.R. 2199</bill>, the Traumatic Brain Injury Health Enhancement and Long-Term Support Act. This bill offers a comprehensive legislative solution to confronting our servicemembers' increasing suffering from Traumatic Brain Injury.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our brave men and women who serve in Operation Iraqi Freedom and Operation Enduring Freedom are faced with daunting physical and mental challenges every day as they carry out their duties. Troops deployed in Iraq, specifically, encounter the widespread use of IEDs, which can cause Traumatic Brain Injury. Extended deployments put our troops at risk for longer periods of time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2199">H.R. 2199</bill> brings together solutions to begin addressing the needs of our wounded warriors who have been diagnosed with TBI. The bill requires the VA to establish five centers for TBI research, education, and clinical activities. It also instructs the VA to establish a TBI screening program that would provide critical information to Congress regarding the number of veterans screened, the prevalence of TBI symptoms, and recommendations for improving care. <bill type="h" number="2199">H.R. 2199</bill> dictates that the VA should create  a comprehensive program for the long-term care and rehabilitation for veterans who suffer from TBI. The bill also requires the VA to create a Traumatic Brain Injury Veterans Health Registry to generate a list of those who served in Iraq and/or Afghanistan, who have symptoms of TBI, and who apply for VA medical care or file a disability claim. The VA can then notify those on the registry of significant developments in research on health consequences of serving in Iraq and/or Afghanistan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Additionally, this bill authorizes funding for a pilot program of mobile VA centers for rural areas. These mobile VA centers would improve access to readjustment benefits as well as mental health services. The mobile centers would also assist veterans in making disability claims.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I represent a rural district comprised of small towns and villages. I know that my rural veterans' constituency desperately needs better access to VA services and care, and these mobile VA centers could be part of the solution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I strongly urge my colleagues to support this bill because it makes great strides in providing comprehensive care for our Nation's wounded warriors suffering from Traumatic Brain Injury.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412204" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in strong support of <bill type="h" number="2199">H.R. 2199</bill>, the Traumatic Brain Injury Health Enhancement and Long-Term Support Act. As a Member of the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, I had the privilege of working on this bipartisan bill, which I believe provides critical resources to our heroes with combat-related brain injuries. I commend Representative Altmire who initiated this effort and I thank VA Subcommittee Chairman Michaud, and VA Chairman Filner  for quickly bringing this bill to the floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Traumatic brain injury (TBI) is the most common wound suffered by troops returning from Iraq and Afghanistan; unfortunately it is often undetected until it is too late. The bill before us today ensures we preemptively screen all veterans for brain injury and that we have the facilities and research necessary to provide the best care possible.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Additionally, this bill addresses the needs of the 44 percent of service members who live in rural areas, like those in my district, by establishing an Advisory Committee on Rural Veterans. It also creates a pilot program for mobile counseling and mental health services.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I am proud we took up this bill in the Veterans' Affairs Committee because it is a strong investment in timely healthcare for our returning troops. I urge my colleagues to support our military heroes by voting for the Traumatic Brain Injury Health Enhancement and Long-Term Support Act.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400337" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of <bill type="h" number="2199">H.R. 2199</bill>, the Traumatic Brain Injury Health Enhancement and Long Term Support Act of 2007. As a Vietnam combat veteran, I have seen the long term effects that war-related wounds and illnesses can have on the lives of our returning soldiers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As Agent Orange sickness and Post Traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD) came to typify the Vietnam War, I believe that Traumatic Brain Injuries (TBI) have become a signature wound of the current conflicts in Iraq and Afghanistan. Advances in body armor and battlefield medicine have allowed our troops to survive head wounds that once would have been fatal. However, the number of identified traumatic brain injuries is alarming. Of the 23,000-plus troops who have been wounded in the wars in Iraq and  Afghanistan, two-thirds reportedly have been diagnosed with traumatic brain injuries. These numbers may even be higher since many cases are often undiagnosed and go untreated. Some reports suggest that 150,000 veterans of the war in Iraq have suffered a traumatic brain injury of some kind.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many of those affected by these devastating injuries are unable to perform the most basic cognitive functions and have great difficulties with the tasks of everyday life. These injured soldiers will require quality care and treatment for the rest of their lives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While it is our obligation to ensure that our military forces have all the necessary arms and equipment to safely carry out their missions, we are also responsible for making sure that our troops know that we will take care of them when they return home. Today we have an opportunity to demonstrate to our wounded veterans our appreciation for their sacrifices and our firm commitment to providing them with the means for living a full and rewarding life. I urge my colleagues to join me in supporting  this important bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400133" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from California (Mr. Filner) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="2199">H.R. 2199</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400133" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this question will be postponed.</chair>
</record>
