<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1173888004" ordinal="38" title="PROVIDING FOR CONSIDERATION OF H.R. 985, WHISTLEBLOWER PROTECTION ENHANCEMENT ACT OF 2007">
  <speaking speaker="400170" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, by direction of the Committee on Rules, I call up House Resolution 239 and ask for its immediate consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the resolution, as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> The gentleman from Florida (Mr. Hastings) is recognized for 1 hour.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400170" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, for purpose of debate only, I yield the customary 30 minutes to my good friend and colleague from Florida, Mr. Diaz-Balart. All time yielded during consideration of the rule is for debate only.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Mr. HASTINGS of Florida asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400170" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, House Resolution 239 provides for consideration of <bill type="h" number="985">H.R. 985</bill>, the Whistleblower Protection Enhancement Act of 2007 under a structured rule. The rule provides 1 hour and 20 minutes of general debate with 1 hour equally divided and controlled by the chairman and ranking minority member of the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform. The remaining 20 minutes will be equally divided and controlled by the chairman and ranking minority member of the Committee  on Homeland Security.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The rule waives all points of order against consideration of the bill except clauses 9 and 10 of rule XXI. The rule provides that the amendment in the nature of a substitute, consisting of the text of the bill, modified by the amendments, recommended by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and printed in the bill, shall be considered as adopted.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill, as amended, shall be considered as an original bill for the purpose of amendment and shall be considered as read. The rule waives all points of order against provisions in the bill, as amended.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, the rule makes in order five amendments, three Republican amendments and two Democratic, which are printed in the Rules Committee report accompanying the resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The amendments may be offered only in the order printed in the report, may be offered only by a Member designated in the report and shall be considered as read and shall be debatable for the time specified in the report equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>All points of order against amendments, except for clauses 9 and 10, are waived.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, the rule provides for one motion to recommit with or without instructions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, today is an important day for the more than 2.7 million Federal employees who show us, day in and day out, their commitment to improving our great country. It is an important day because the House, in bipartisan cooperation, is closing the loopholes which permitted retaliation against Federal employees who have reported unlawful fraud, corruption, incompetence and abuse of power.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today is an important day because the House is saying loud and clear that whistleblower protection is an essential component of government, of government accountability and of government fiscal responsibility.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Throughout our history, whistleblowers have played integral roles in improving our government and holding it accountable for its negligence. From Shawn Carpenter to Joseph Darby to Mark Felt, and everyone in between, whistleblowers have faced harsh penalties from those who would prefer that what they know is never shared with the public. They have, nevertheless, put their careers on the line, and in some instances even their lives, to do what they knew was the right thing to do. Their courage  is to be commended and their conviction embraced.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When history judges this current administration, I believe it will look down upon the drastic and despicable actions taken by this administration, which have stifled those seeking to speak truth to power. These actions are, indeed, some of the very reasons why this bill is so desperately needed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For example, in 2005, the Bush administration officials placed a gag on a senior NOAA official who was scheduled to give an interview arguing that global warming exists and has contributed to greater and stronger hurricane activity. Three weeks later, Hurricane Katrina made landfall, first in my State of Florida, and then in Louisiana and Mississippi and Alabama, killing hundreds and leaving hundreds of thousands homeless, jobless and ill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>How can we forget former CIA operative Valerie Plame? Her life, and the lives of others, were placed in jeopardy after the Vice President's chief of staff revealed her name to a reporter in retaliation for her husband, former Ambassador Joe Wilson, revealing that the administration lied about the existence of weapons of mass destruction in Iraq and where they were trying to retrieve uranium from Africa.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When the Bush administration hasn't been able to directly punish whistleblowers, it has simply tried to unilaterally change the law. Just this past September, after a senior Environmental Protection Agency scientist revealed that the administration had purposefully misled the public regarding the air safety at Ground Zero following the attacks of September 11, the Bush administration issued an executive order declaring that EPA employees are no longer covered by Federal whistleblower protections.  That is outrageous.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These three high-profile cases, and there are a great deal more, these three capture only a small snapshot of the problems in the current administration. More importantly, they highlight the need for extended protection across all agency lines to Federal whistleblowers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, for nearly the last decade, Federal whistleblowers have received nothing more than lip service. Let me make it very clear, I said for the last decade, that includes the previous administration and this one. Even when the House drafted legislation in 2002 establishing the Department of Homeland Security, it failed to  include whistleblower protections for DHS employees.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, I am proud that I was the author of the amendment which extended these protections and was the only Democratic amendment adopted by the House during consideration of the legislation. The protection of whistleblowers in recent years has unfortunately garnered only lip service. Today, the House is backing up these words with real action that protects our 2.7 million Federal workforce.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I close by noting that this bill is not perfect. That is why the Rules Committee has made five amendments in order, the majority of which, I might add, are going to be offered by our colleagues, the Republicans, on the other side.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Democrats are proud to continue our efforts to work in a bipartisan manner, and to provide the minority with many opportunities to improve already good legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks during debate on House Resolution 239.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Florida?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400170" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400107" topic="">
    <paragraph>I would like to thank my friend from Florida for the time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress has the constitutional duty to oversee the executive branch. In order to discharge our constitutional oversight responsibility, Congress depends on information obtained through agency reports and direct communication from Department heads. However, we also depend on information provided directly from employees within the agencies who are witnesses to the misuse of taxpayer dollars and alert Congress of the possible corruption or incompetence in management.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1989, Congress passed the Whistleblower Protection Act in an effort to strengthen statutory protections for Federal employees who assist in the elimination of fraud, waste, abuse, illegality or corruption.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="985">H.R. 985</bill> would modernize and expand this protection to Federal employees, with added whistleblower protection.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For example, the bill would extend protection to FBI agents, CIA agents, employees of the Defense Intelligence Agency, the National Geospatial Agency and the National Security Agency.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think it is important to have whistleblower protection for the intelligence community. I would like to point out, however, that Congress has already passed such legislation. In 1998, Congress passed the Intelligence Community Whistleblower Protection Act to encourage the reporting to Congress of wrongdoing within the intelligence agencies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In crafting the 1998 legislation, Congress sought to balance the need for information with national security requirements, giving intelligence community whistleblowers access to Congress but through the intelligence committees.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Yesterday, the Rules Committee denied the ranking member of the Intelligence Committee, Mr. Hoekstra, from offering an amendment striking section 10 of the bill. Section 10 conflicts with the provisions of the existing Intelligence Community Whistleblower Protection Act of 1998.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The amendment, I believe, should have been made in order. National security is obviously one of the most important issues that we deal with. Before we make changes to how Congress handles intelligence oversight, we should have a full and complete debate on that particular provision. We could have done that if the majority had made the Hoekstra amendment in order.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under the bill, defendants in whistleblower cases will now be able to make their cases to any Federal district court if the Merit Systems Protection Board does not take action within 180 days.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Part of this provision will allow claims to be processed on a more timely basis than they are now. However, there are possible problems with the provision.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>Yesterday, Oversight and Government Reform Committee Ranking Member Davis asked the Rules Committee that his amendment be made in order. His amendment sought to retain uniformity in the consideration of whistleblower cases in the Federal courts by keeping in place the current requirement that all whistleblower appeals go through the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit, rather than opening up appeals to all circuits.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Without the amendment, Federal employee whistleblowers could end up possessing a different set of rights and protections, depending on where they file their claim. However, unfortunately, the majority decided to close down the debate process on that issue, and refused to allow the House to debate that very important and meaningful amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe the majority should have made those amendments, the Hoekstra amendment and the Davis amendment, in order, along with other important amendments brought before the Rules Committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400170" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time, before yielding to my good friend and colleague on the Rules Committee, only to respond to my friend from Florida regarding an amendment that was not made in order of the ranking member of the Intelligence Committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I serve on that committee, and one amendment that was made in order contemplates everything that the ranking member of the Intelligence Committee might have provided in the amendment that he sought.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Quite frankly, I think Mr. Tierney's amendment, which we will have an opportunity to debate here on the floor, will give a full exploration of those matters having to do with whistleblower concerns in the intelligence community. So I commend that to my colleague and all here in this body.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I am very pleased to yield to a new Member, who is not so new now, to the Rules Committee, my good friend, Mr. Arcuri from New York. I yield to him 4 minutes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412224" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I thank my good friend and colleague from the Rules Committee, the gentleman from Florida, for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, accountability is a word often used but seldom implemented. For the last 12 years it is as if Congress forgot one of its principal responsibilities is to demand accountability from the administration and protect the American people from waste, fraud and abuse.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Whistleblower Protection Enhancement Act, which this rule provides consideration for, will provide additional transparency and accountability for the way the Federal Government spends tax dollars of the hardworking Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is no secret that the only way we can truly gather firsthand accounts of instances where waste, fraud and abuse occur is from the people on the inside, the Federal employees. Unfortunately, not all Federal employees are currently protected from being fired if they unmask corruption or other fraudulent activities going on inside the administration.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation goes right to the heart of the issue by extending much needed whistleblower protections to Federal Government employees working on national security, government contractor employees and transportation security employees, including baggage screeners at our airports. It only makes sense that Federal employees, especially those who have undergone extensive background investigations, obtained security clearances and handled classified information on a routine basis, be afforded the  same rights and whistleblower protections as all other Federal employees.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, this legislation takes some very important steps. It would abolish the U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit's exclusive jurisdiction for overhearing whistleblower appeals cases, taking away its Supreme Court-like jurisdiction and allowing the appropriate Federal appeals courts in the respective circuit where the incident took place to hear such cases.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For instance, if the instance of whistleblowing were to occur in New York, in my district, that is the Second Circuit. The initial decision rendered by the Second Circuit should be appealed in the Second Circuit. It should not be required to come to the Federal Circuit here.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The current appeals structures for hearing whistleblower cases not only places a hefty financial burden on individuals who would have to travel from across the country to D.C. just to have their appeal heard, it also provides a disservice to our Nation's legal system by overburdening one court.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a former district attorney, I know from experience that having the ability to draw on decisions from similar cases rendered from different courts around the country would greatly improve our legal system. It would benefit all parties involved, and further enhance our Nation's exceptional legal system. Further, by allowing other Federal circuit appellate courts to hear whistleblower appeal cases increases the opportunity for those cases to be heard by the United States Supreme Court.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, it is time to level the playing field for all Federal employees who have the courage to stand up for the American people.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues on both sides of the aisle to support this rule and the Whistleblower Protection Enhancement Act.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400107" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield such time as he may consume to the distinguished ranking member of the Rules Committee, Mr. Dreier.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Mr. DREIER asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400115" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise to begin by thanking my friend from Miami and my friend from Fort Lauderdale. We have got this Sun Belt linkage now here. The only thing in between it was somebody from upstate New York there. And I know he likes that better than Los Angeles, as he told me up in the Rules Committee just before we were going into our last break. But I am proud that there are three of us at least who come from the Sun Belt who are representing this debate on this rule.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I do rise to reluctantly oppose both the rule and the underlying legislation. The bill is very well-intentioned, and it is designed to clarify and expand the laws regarding those who try to expose waste, fraud and mismanagement in the Federal Government.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Whistleblowers, oftentimes, put their jobs at risk to expose wrongdoing in the workplace, and whistleblowers are absolutely crucial to our Nation's security, safety and success as well. I believe very much that their protection is an inherent right for all employees, and it needs to be maintained.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, the whistleblower protections enable Congress to fulfill our constitutional responsibility of overseeing the executive branch. It is imperative that we do that. We need to recognize that we are a separate and coequal branch of our Federal Government. We have a right to know the actions of the executive branch and to oversee the implementation of the laws that we create as Members of this body, and whistleblowers are a very crucial part of that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, Mr. Speaker, I do support the idea of expanding and modernizing whistleblower protection laws. But, unfortunately, I believe that this legislation ends up falling short of that very important goal to which I believe we all aspire.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill aims to extend whistleblower protections to Federal workers who specialize in national security issues. These workers include employees of the FBI, the CIA, the Defense Intelligence Agency, among others. Unfortunately, the bill raises significant national security concerns that have really led me to conclude that I can't support this bill in its present form.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Within its oversight obligations, Mr. Speaker, Congress is tasked with protecting highly classified intelligence programs. It is absolutely critical for us to ensure that any oversight is conducted by Members and staff with the appropriate experience and expertise.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, this bill, in its current form, compromises that duty and outlines new procedures that have the potential to expose highly classified national security programs and information.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, during the Rules Committee hearing yesterday, an amendment was offered by the ranking member of the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, Mr. Hoekstra. And I just heard my friend from Fort Lauderdale, who has served very ably as a member of the Intelligence Committee, as well as on the Rules Committee, say that there is another amendment designed to address this.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But, frankly, I believe very strongly that the amendment that was filed in a timely manner by the gentleman from Michigan (Mr. Hoekstra) was one that was not made in order, and I believe really best takes on this issue of dealing with a better way to ensure the security of this important, very important information.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, Mr. Speaker, 10 amendments were offered at the Rules Committee, and while I commend the majority for making five of those 10 amendments in order, I do believe that an open rule would have been more appropriate. Give the Members of this body the opportunity to offer amendments to important pieces of legislation like this, not just on noncontroversial bills, which is what we have seen the open rule procedure used for in the past.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At the very least, Mr. Speaker, I think we should have made all 10 of the amendments that were submitted to the Rules Committee in order so that we could have had a free flowing debate on these, and we would have had a chance for people like the ranking member of the committee of jurisdiction here, the Oversight and Government Reform Committee, Mr. Davis, who served very ably as the chairman of that committee before we saw last November's election make this change. This former chairman,  the now ranking member, sought to offer an amendment, and he also was denied a chance to offer that amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I do commend my California colleague, Mr. Waxman, the distinguished chairman of the committee, as well as Mr. Davis, for their hard work and expertise on this very critical issue. Unfortunately, I believe that the bill does, as I say, fall short of that goal. The goal really is an important one, as I said, to ensure that whistleblowers help us meet our constitutional responsibility for oversight of the executive branch.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But the national security concerns that have been raised I think are such that, in its present form, I am not going to be able to support this measure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, Mr. Speaker, I do urge my colleagues to vote against this rule. And as I said, I am troubled enough that the bill itself, in its current form, is not legislation that I can support.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400170" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I am very pleased to yield 3 minutes to my good friend and classmate, the gentlewoman from New York (Mrs. Maloney).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400251" topic="">
    <paragraph>I rise, Mr. Speaker, in strong support of the rule, <bill type="hr" number="239">H. Res. 239</bill>, and the underlying bill, <bill type="h" number="985">H.R. 985</bill>, the Whistleblower Protection Enhancement Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And I want to commend, not only the Rules Committee for coming forward with a fair rule, but also Chairman Waxman and Ranking Member Davis for moving this important bill out of the Government Reform and Oversight Committee on which I serve.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Whistleblower Protection Act has been weakened by court cases in recent years, and even the weak protections offered under the Whistleblower Protection Act do not apply to national security whistleblowers or contractors at those agencies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Oversight Committee repeatedly has heard from people who have had their security clearances revoked after blowing the whistle. In some cases they have been fired for pointing out lapses in security, for pointing out waste, fraud and abuse.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have been told that wrongdoers have been allowed to continue their actions, while the whistleblowers have been the ones that have been made to suffer. This is absolutely wrong.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the 109th Congress I was joined by my colleague, Diane Watson, in offering an amendment during the committee's consideration of the Federal Employee Protection of Disclosures Act, that would have extended whistleblower protections to employees in national security and in the intelligence community.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would argue, and I believe many of my colleagues would agree, that revealing lapses in the security of our  Nation is a national security priority above all. Whistleblowers in these categories should be protected.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And I am thrilled that, under Democratic leadership, this has been included in the bill, that these protections have been extended to employees of intelligence agencies, and to Federal contractors in intelligence agencies. This is an important step forward for the American public. This is an important step forward, I would argue, for the national security of our country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Whistleblowers are heroes and heroines. They should not be turned into villains and be harassed out of their jobs, denied their security clearance because they see a breach in security or a breach in accountability in our government.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I am thrilled with this Democratic bill, and I urge my colleagues to vote for the rule and also for the underlying bill. I urge all of my colleagues to support it. It had bipartisan support coming out of our committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400107" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I thank again my distinguished friend from Florida for his courtesy in yielding the time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, we will oppose the previous question. If the previous question is defeated, I will offer an amendment to the rule to make in order the amendment offered yesterday in the Rules Committee by the gentleman from Michigan, the ranking member of the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, Mr. Hoekstra.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Hoekstra amendment would safeguard our national intelligence and allow the Intelligence Committee to appropriately address whistleblower concerns through regular order. While the Tierney amendment which was made in order, as was pointed out by my good friend, attempts to address these concerns, it still allows the possible disemination, we believe, of highly sensitive information to individuals outside of the Intelligence Community and, therefore, may put our security at risk.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent to insert the text of the Hoekstra amendment and extraneous materials immediately prior to the vote on the previous question.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Florida?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400107" topic="">
    <paragraph>At this time, Mr. Speaker, I urge all Members to oppose the previous question, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400170" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the underlying legislation is desperately needed. Federal employees need to know that Congress is on their side. They need to know that their jobs will not be at risk if they choose to reveal fraud, abuse of power, neglect, or corruption in their workplace.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The extension of these whistleblower protections is absolutely critical to our national security and our government accountability. I am proud to support the underlying legislation and hope that my colleagues will do the same. This is a fair rule for a bill that is supported by Members from both sides of the aisle, including the chairman and ranking Republican of the Government Reform Committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge a "yes" vote on the previous question and on the rule, Mr. Speaker.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The material previously referred to by Mr. Lincoln Diaz-Balart of Florida is as follows:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Amendment to <bill type="hr" number="239">H. Res. 239</bill></paragraph>
    <paragraph>Offered by Rep. Lincoln Diaz-Balart of Florida</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At the end of the resolution, add the following:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>SEC. 3. Notwithstanding any other provision of this resolution, the amendment printed in section 4 shall be in order as though printed as the last amendment in the report of the Committee on Rules if offered by Representative Hoekstra of Michigan or a designee. That amendment shall be debatable for 30 minutes equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>SEC. 4. The amendment referred to in section 3 is as follows:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Strike section 10 of the bill and conform the table of contents accordingly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Redesignate sections 11 through 14 as sections 10 through 13, respectively, and conform the table of contents accordingly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In section 11(a)(2), as redesignated, strike "section 2303a (as inserted by section 10)" and insert "section 2303".</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In section 13, as redesignated, strike "section 12(a)(2)" and insert "section 11(a)(2)".</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(The information contained herein was provided by Democratic Minority on multiple occasions throughout the 109th Congress.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400170" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time, and I move the previous question on the resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on ordering the previous question.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400107" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 and clause 9 of rule XX, this 15-minute vote on ordering the previous question will be followed by 5-minute votes on adoption of <bill type="hr" number="239">H. Res. 239</bill>, if ordered, and approval of the Journal, if ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400107" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 5-minute vote.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400077" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I was unavoidably absent for rollcall vote 146 on <bill type="hr" number="239">H. Res. 239</bill>, the rule to provide for consideration of <bill type="h" number="985">H.R. 985</bill>. Had I been present, I would have voted "nay."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
