<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1173114004" ordinal="18" title="DESIGNATING THE JIM WEAVER LOOP TRAIL AT WALDO LAKE IN WILLAMETTE NATIONAL FOREST">
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="247">H.R. 247</bill>) to designate a Forest Service trail at Waldo Lake in the Willamette National Forest in the State of Oregon as a national recreation trail in honor  of Jim Weaver, a former Member of the House of Representatives.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) and the gentleman from Utah (Mr. Bishop) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members have 5 legislative days within which to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Arizona?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, <bill type="h" number="247">H.R. 247</bill> was introduced by my colleague on the Natural Resources Committee, the gentleman from Oregon, Representative PETER DEFAZIO. This legislation designates an existing Forest Service trail in the Willamette National Forest in Oregon as a national recreation trail in honor of Jim Weaver, a former Member of the House of Representatives. This trail will be designated as the Jim Weaver Loop Trail. It forms a 19.6-mile loop around Waldo Lake.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congressman Weaver served in this body from the 94th Congress through the 99th Congress and was a former subcommittee chairman of the Committee on Natural Resources. He was a strong advocate of conservation and public lands. The establishment of this trail around one of Oregon's largest and most beautiful lakes is a fitting tribute to our former colleague. Under this bill, an interpretive sign will be installed at the trail head to indicate the name of the trail and provide information on the  life and career of our former colleague, Congressman Weaver.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill before us today is identical to a measure that was reported favorably by the Natural Resources Committee last year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, we strongly support <bill type="h" number="247">H.R. 247</bill> and urge its adoption by the House today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400029" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="247">H.R. 247</bill> and yield myself 45 seconds.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the majority has adequately explained this bill. We have no objections. It is a good bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no additional speakers, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the gentleman from Oregon (Mr. DeFazio), the sponsor of <bill type="h" number="247">H.R. 247</bill>, is at the moment traveling back to Washington, but he has a statement that will be submitted into the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400100" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of <bill type="h" number="247">H.R. 247</bill>, a bill to rename Forest Service trail number 3590, which circumnavigates the world-renowned Waldo Lake, as the "Jim Weaver Loop Trail" in honor of former Congressman Jim Weaver. The legislation would also designate this 22 mile trail as a national recreational trail under the National Trails System Act. This legislation has special significance to me because Mr. Weaver was not only my predecessor as the representative of  Oregon's Fourth Congressional District, but he was also my boss--both here in Washington, D.C. and back home in the district--and is a friend. I am pleased that the legislation is cosponsored and supported by all of Oregon's five House members. In addition, it is supported by the Forest Service and a number of local interest groups.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Jim Weaver has been an Oregonian for nearly sixty years. He represented the southwest portion of the state in the U.S. House of Representatives from 1975 to 1987. During his time in Congress, Mr. Weaver made natural resource conservation one of his signature pursuits. He was a tireless advocate for outdoor recreation, and the protection of some of Oregon's most treasured natural features.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He was the leading force responsible for the inclusion of new wilderness areas north of Waldo Lake in the Oregon Wilderness Act of 1984, and worked tirelessly with then Senator Hatfield to ensure that these lands received protection.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The 10 square mile Waldo Lake is considered ultraoligotrophic, meaning it's ranked as one of the purest bodies of water on Earth, and is comparable to distilled water. According to the Forest Service's Water Quality Report, two of the main reasons for its purity are the low levels of sedimentation and lack of development in the area, two characteristics which should be credited to Mr. Weaver's efforts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Waldo Lake and the surrounding area, including the loop trail, is a popular recreation destination. Naming this trail for Mr. Weaver is a fitting tribute to the legacy of Congressman Weaver and his commitment to protecting Waldo Lake and the surrounding area.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation gives long-overdue recognition to Congressman Weaver and forever associates his name with an area that he loves and worked hard to protect. I want to thank Chairman RAHALL and his Staff Director, Jim Zoia, and Ranking Member YOUNG for their efforts in dicharging the bill for today's floor action. I look forward to the Senate taking up the bill expeditiously, and I urge its adoption.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="247">H.R. 247</bill>.</chair>
</record>
