<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1173286803" ordinal="9" title="JOINT MEETING OF THE HOUSE AND SENATE TO HEAR AN ADDRESS BY HIS MAJESTY KING ABDULLAH II IBN AL HUSSEIN, KING OF THE HASHEMITE KINGDOM OF JORDAN">
  <chair> The Chair appoints as members of the committee on the part of the House to escort His Majesty King Abdullah II into the Chamber:</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="" name="The Vice President" of="">
    <paragraph>The President of the Senate, at the direction of that body, appoints the following Senators as members of the committee on the part of the Senate to escort His Majesty King Abdullah II Ibn Al Hussein, King of the Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan, into the House Chamber:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senator from Nevada (Mr. Reid);</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senator from Illinois (Mr. Durbin);</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senator from Vermont (Mr. Leahy);</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senator from Massachusetts (Mr. Kerry);</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senator from Kentucky (Mr. McConnell);</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senator from Mississippi (Mr. Lott);</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senator from Arizona (Mr. Kyl); and</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senator from Texas (Mr. Cornyn).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Deputy Sergeant at Arms announced the Dean of the Diplomatic Corps, His Excellency Roble Olhaye, Ambassador of the Republic of Djibouti.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Dean of the Diplomatic Corps entered the Hall of the House of Representatives and took the seat reserved for him.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At 11 o'clock and 5 minutes a.m., the Deputy Sergeant at Arms announced His Majesty King Abdullah II Ibn Al Hussein, King of the Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The King of the Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan, escorted by the committee of Senators and Representatives, entered the Hall of the House of Representatives and stood at the Clerk's desk.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>[Applause, the Members rising.]</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> Members of Congress, I have the high privilege and the distinct honor of presenting to you His Majesty King Abdullah II Ibn Al Hussein, King of the Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan.</chair>
</record>
