<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1173801604" ordinal="38" title="NEAL SMITH FEDERAL BUILDING">
  <speaking speaker="400042" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="1045">H.R. 1045</bill>) to designate the Federal building located at 210 Walnut Street in Des Moines, Iowa, as the "Neal Smith Federal Building".</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Iowa (Mr. Boswell) and the gentleman from Missouri (Mr. Graves) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400042" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days within which to revise and extend their remarks and to include extraneous material on <bill type="h" number="1045">H.R. 1045</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Iowa?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400042" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, it is quite a privilege today for me to stand here and speak about someone who has been my mentor and that I have admired for many, many years of my life. Neal Smith, and in fact I should say his wife, Bea, have been exemplary in so many ways and have meant so much to the people of Iowa and in fact the people of this Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would recognize that Neal served with distinction and bravery in World War II. He was a bomber pilot and was highly decorated.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Those of you here in the Congress that served with Neal know that he was highly regarded, both in Washington and in his home State of Iowa. He was known for his skillful legislating and attention to his congressional district. Having served 36 years in Congress, Neal is the longest serving Iowan to serve in the House of Representatives. Naming the Federal building in Des Moines is an honor he deserves, and the time is correct.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As chairman of the Commerce, Justice, State appropriations subcommittee, Neal spent most of his time outside the spotlight tenaciously defending programs under his jurisdiction against budget assaults.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He was rooted in Depression-era Iowa. Neal was a man of liberal instincts, but he was considered fair and an honest broker as a subcommittee chairman and was known to keep debating until an agreement could be reached. He once said, "I don't try to get confrontational. I try to do whatever I need to do to pass the bill."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Outside of appropriations, Neal was a champion for tougher meat and poultry inspection laws and introduced and supported legislation that required food labels stating sodium content. Neal was also instrumental in creating the Commodity Futures Trading Commission to guard against grain trading abuses and in setting up strict Federal procedures for grain inspection.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Back in Iowa, other tributes have been given to his honor. We now have the Neal Smith National Wildlife Refuge, the Neal Smith Trail, and the Neal and Bea Smith Law School at Drake. It is now only fitting that the Federal building in Des Moines, a building I understand he helped get funded, be named the Neal Smith Federal Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, Mr. Chairman, I appreciate this moment and urge passage of this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400158" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I don't think I could really add much to Mr. Smith's accomplishments and what he has done, other than what Mr. Boswell has pointed out.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He did mention he was a bomber pilot, and I looked up his service record. He was awarded the Purple Heart, nine Battle Stars and the Air Medal with four oak leaf clusters for his service, which is obviously a sign of a very outstanding individual. This obviously marks a long and very distinguished career. Obviously, he was one of us, a Member of Congress from Iowa; and I wholeheartedly support this.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, could I inquire of the gentleman from Iowa what Mr. Smith flew during the war.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400042" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, if the gentleman would yield, I would just share this. That is a very good question, Mr. Graves. It would be either a B-17 or B-29. It was one of the bombers at least. I know that. Neal was the kind of person, as others know from here, he never spoke about it. You had to kind of dig it out to know about that. But he truly was an American hero as well as a very much respected hero in Iowa, and I suspect that a lot of his influence reached over into Missouri.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400158" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I do thank the gentleman from Iowa (Mr. Boswell) for the kind words that he said. Again, this gentleman was a pilot, and you can't get any better than that. I would wholeheartedly support this bill and urge my colleagues to do the same.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400042" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, in closing, I would say this is a very special day for us in Iowa to name this building in Neal's honor. We also would say publicly and presently that we respect Bea so very much. They went to law school together at Drake and served together all these many, many years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Regula from Ohio was a colleague of Neal's and they served together, and he was very happy and ready to help sponsor the bill and so on. I would appreciate, Mr. Graves, if you will pass on to him our appreciation for his contribution and his greetings to Neal and Bea.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would urge my colleagues to support and pass this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in strong support of <bill type="h" number="1045">H.R. 1045</bill>, a bill to designate the Federal building at 210 Walnut Street in Des Moines, IA, as the "Neal Smith Federal Building."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Neal Smith was born on March 23, 1920, in his grandparents' home near Hedrick, Keokuk County, IA. He served in the United States House of Representatives from 1959 until 1995, and has the distinction of being the longest serving Member of the House of Representatives from Iowa. Congressman Smith is a World War II veteran, having served in the United States Army Air Force as a bomber pilot. His plane was shot down during combat and he received a Purple Heart, nine Battle Stars, and the Air Medal  with four oak leaf clusters.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He received his undergraduate training at the University of Missouri and Syracuse University. In 1950, he received his law degree from Drake University.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Neal Smith is one of Iowa's most respected and distinguished elected officials. His interests while serving in Congress were varied,  but he especially focused on agriculture, small business, and the environment. He became a champion for those issue areas and authored legislation establishing the Commodity Futures Trading Commission, the Federal Meat, Poultry and Egg Inspection Acts, and Small Business Development Centers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congressman Smith also sponsored legislation to authorize construction of the Big Creek and Rathbun Dams. Further, he was instrumental in creating the Red Rock Watershed Conservation District and a National Wildlife Refuge that was named in his honor. In the 1980s, he was especially active in helping to jump start Iowa's stagnant economy. In 1996, Smith published his autobiography, Mr. Smith Goes to Washington: From Eisenhower to Clinton.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is most fitting and proper to honor the long, distinguished civic career of Congressman Neal Smith with this designation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to join me in supporting <bill type="h" number="1045">H.R. 1045</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400042" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Iowa (Mr. Boswell) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="1045">H.R. 1045</bill>.</chair>
</record>
