<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1194973204" ordinal="66" title="MR. AUGUSTUS HAWKINS">
  <narrative>MR. AUGUSTUS HAWKINS -- (House of Representatives - November 13, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H13829]</narrative>
  <chair> Under a previous order of the House, the gentlewoman from California (Ms. Watson) is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400423" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, we mourn the passing of a great Congressman whose public service was emulated by leaders present and past. Gus Hawkins has left us with a sterling legacy that was built on the politics of inclusion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While in office, he authored over 100 laws in the area of adult education, apprenticeship training, slum clearance, low-cost housing, workmen's compensation for domestics, disability insurance, pensions for senior citizens, and child care centers. He was also responsible for the Fair Employment Practice Act of 1959, the Manpower Development and Training Act of 1962, and the Fair Housing Act of 1963. More importantly, he authored the Elementary and Secondary School Act of 1965, which was an extensive  statute funding primary and secondary education.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a founding member of the Congressional Black Caucus, he chaired various committees and continued in his effort to enhance educational opportunities for children. He was instrumental in forming the National Council on Educating Black Children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Augustus Hawkins' philosophy of service and leadership to the State of California and the Nation is perhaps best said in his own words, and I quote, "The leadership belongs not to the loudest, not to those who beat the drums or blow the trumpets, but to those who day in and day out in all seasons work for the practical realization of a better world, those who have the stamina to persist and to remain dedicated. To those belong the leadership."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
