<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1196787602" ordinal="23" title="NORTH BAY WATER REUSE PROGRAM ACT OF 2007">
  <narrative>NORTH BAY WATER REUSE PROGRAM ACT OF 2007 -- (House of Representatives - December 04, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H14095]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400290" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="236">H.R. 236</bill>) to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to create a Bureau of Reclamation partnership with the North Bay Water Reuse Authority and other regional partners to achieve objectives relating to water supply, water quality, and environmental restoration, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="236">H.R. 236</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "North Bay Water Reuse Program Act of 2007".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. PROJECT AUTHORIZATION.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) In General.--The Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act (Public Law 102-575, title XVI; 43 U.S.C. 390h et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;"SEC. 16__. NORTH BAY WATER REUSE PROGRAM.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(a) Definitions.--In this section:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(1) ELIGIBLE ENTITY.--The term `eligible entity' means a member agency of the North Bay Water Reuse Authority of the State located in the North San Pablo Bay watershed in--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(A) Marin County;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(B) Napa County;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(C) Solano County; or&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(D) Sonoma County.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(2) WATER RECLAMATION AND REUSE PROJECT.--The term `water reclamation and reuse project' means a project carried out by the Secretary and an eligible entity in the North San Pablo Bay watershed relating to--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(A) water quality improvement;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(B) wastewater treatment;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(C) water reclamation and reuse;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(D) groundwater recharge and protection;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(E) surface water augmentation; or&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(F) other related improvements. &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(3) STATE.--The term `State' means the State of California.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(b) North Bay Water Reuse Program.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(1) IN GENERAL.--Contingent upon a finding of feasibility, the Secretary, acting through a cooperative agreement with the State or a subdivision of the State, is authorized to enter into cooperative agreements with eligible entities for the planning, design, and construction of water reclamation and reuse facilities and recycled water conveyance and distribution systems.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(2) COORDINATION WITH OTHER FEDERAL AGENCIES.--In carrying out this section, the Secretary and the eligible entity shall, to the maximum extent practicable, use the design work and environmental evaluations initiated by--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(A) non-Federal entities; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(B) the Corps of Engineers in the San Pablo Bay Watershed of the State.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(3) PHASED PROJECT.--A cooperative agreement described in paragraph (1) shall require that the North Bay Water Reuse Program carried out under this section shall consist of 2 phases as follows:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(A) FIRST PHASE.--During the first phase, the Secretary and an eligible entity shall complete the planning, design, and construction of the main treatment and main conveyance systems.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(B) SECOND PHASE.--During the second phase, the Secretary and an eligible entity shall complete the planning, design, and construction of the sub-regional distribution systems.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(4) COST SHARING.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(A) FEDERAL SHARE.--The Federal share of the cost of the first phase of the project authorized by this section shall not exceed 25 percent of the total cost of the first phase of the project.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(B) FORM OF NON-FEDERAL SHARE.--The non-Federal share may be in the form of any in-kind services that the Secretary determines would contribute substantially toward the completion of the water reclamation and reuse project, including--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(i) reasonable costs incurred by the eligible entity relating to the planning, design, and construction of the water reclamation and reuse project; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(ii) the acquisition costs of land acquired for the project that is--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(I) used for planning, design, and construction of the water reclamation and reuse project facilities; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(II) owned by an eligible entity and directly related to the project.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(C) LIMITATION.--The Secretary shall not provide funds for the operation and maintenance of the project authorized by this section.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(5) EFFECT.--Nothing in this section--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(A) affects or preempts--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(i) State water law; or&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(ii) an interstate compact relating to the allocation of water; or&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(B) confers on any non-Federal entity the ability to exercise any Federal right to--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(i) the water of a stream; or&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(ii) any groundwater resource.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(6) AUTHORIZATION OF APPROPRIATIONS.--There is authorized to be appropriated for the Federal share of the total cost of the first phase of the project authorized by this section $25,000,000, to remain available until expended.".</narrative>
  <narrative> (b) Conforming Amendment.--The table of sections in section 2 of Public Law 102-575 is amended by inserting after the last item relating to title XVI the following:&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from California (Mrs. Napolitano) and the gentlewoman from Washington (Mrs. McMorris Rodgers) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentlewoman from California.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400290" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from California?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400290" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation, introduced by our colleague from California, Representative MIKE THOMPSON, authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to provide limited financial assistance for planning, design, and construction of the North Bay Water Reuse Program in Northern California. This is an innovative regional water recycling project that will allow North Bay Water Reuse Authority and many of the other regional partners to improve water supplies and water quality and to implement environmental  restoration work.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Similar legislation was introduced by Congressman Thompson in the 109th Congress, and I certainly want to thank Representative Thompson for his hard work on this important legislation, and my co-chair, Mrs. McMorris Rodgers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this measure receives strong bipartisan support, and we strongly support this noncontroversial bill. I urge my colleagues to support <bill type="h" number="236">H.R. 236</bill>, as amended.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mrs." name="RODGERS, McMORRIS" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, Chairwoman GRACE NAPOLITANO has done a great job of describing this bill. We have no objection and applaud the effort of those that have been involved in passing it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no additional speakers, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400290" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no requests for time, so I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from California (Mrs. Napolitano) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="236">H.R. 236</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400627" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this motion will be postponed.</chair>
</record>
