<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1190649602" ordinal="24" title="WOODROW WILSON PRESIDENTIAL LIBRARY AUTHORIZATION ACT">
  <narrative>WOODROW WILSON PRESIDENTIAL LIBRARY AUTHORIZATION ACT -- (House of Representatives - September 24, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H10716]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="1664">H.R. 1664</bill>) to authorize grants for contributions toward the establishment of the Woodrow Wilson Presidential Library.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="1664">H.R. 1664</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. GRANTS FOR ESTABLISHMENT OF THE WOODROW WILSON PRESIDENTIAL LIBRARY.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Grants Authorized.--Subject to subsections (b), (c), and (d), the Archivist of the National Archives and Records Administration may make grants to contribute funds for the establishment in Staunton, Virginia, of a library to preserve and make available materials related to the life of President Woodrow Wilson and to provide interpretive and educational services that communicate the meaning of the life of Woodrow Wilson.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Limitation.--A grant may be made under subsection (a) only from funds appropriated to the Archivist specifically for that purpose.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Conditions on Grants.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) MATCHING REQUIREMENT.--A grant under subsection (a) may not be made until such time as the entity selected to receive the grant certifies to the Archivist that funds have been raised from non-Federal sources for use to establish the library in an amount equal to at least double the amount of the grant.</narrative>
  <narrative> (2) RELATION TO OTHER WOODROW WILSON SITES AND MUSEUMS.--The Archivist shall further condition a grant under subsection (a) on the agreement of the grant recipient to operate the resulting library in cooperation with other Federal and non-Federal historic sites, parks, and museums that represent significant locations or events in the life of Woodrow Wilson. Cooperative efforts to promote and interpret the life of Woodrow Wilson may include the use of cooperative agreements, cross references,  cross promotion, and shared exhibits.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (d) Prohibition of Contribution of Operating Funds.--Grant amounts may not be used for the maintenance or operation of the library.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (e) Non-Federal Operation.--The Archivist shall have no involvement in the actual operation of the library, except at the request of the non-Federal entity responsible for the operation of the library.</narrative>
  <narrative> (f) Authority Through Fiscal Year 2011.--The Archivist may not use the authority provided under subsection (a) after September 30, 2011.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Davis) and the gentlewoman from Illinois (Mrs. Biggert) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Illinois.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days in which to revise and extend their remarks.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Illinois?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I might consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, as a member of the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, I am pleased to join my colleague in the consideration of <bill type="h" number="1664">H.R. 1664</bill>, a bill to authorize grants for contributions toward the establishment of the Woodrow Wilson Presidential Library. <bill type="h" number="1664">H.R. 1664</bill> was introduced by Representative Bob Goodlatte on March 23, 2007. This legislation was reported from the Oversight Committee on July 19, 2007, by voice vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, as a statesman, scholar and President, Woodrow Wilson faced an economic crisis and a world war while serving the country as Commander in Chief. Historians believe that World War I and President Wilson's leadership radically altered the role of diplomacy as a tool of foreign policy, a policy that established a new path for America's role in promoting democracies throughout the world. His vision helped shape the powers and responsibilities of the executive branch in times of war.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1664">H.R. 1664</bill>, the Woodrow Wilson Presidential Library Authorization Act, will allow the National Archives to provide grants for the establishment of a Presidential library to provide educational services to honor the life of former President Woodrow Wilson.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I commend my colleague, Representative Bob Goodlatte, for introducing this legislation, and urge swift passage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400027" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield such time as he may consume to the distinguished gentleman from Virginia (Mr. Goodlatte), the sponsor of this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400154" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would like to thank the gentleman from Illinois and the gentlewoman from Illinois for their assistance with this legislation, as well as Mr. Waxman, the chairman of the Government Reform Committee, and my colleague from Virginia, Congressman Tom Davis, all of whom have been a great help in moving this legislation forward.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="1664">H.R. 1664</bill>, the Woodrow Wilson Presidential Library Authorization Act, which will authorize grants from the National Archives for the establishment of a Presidential library to provide educational and interpretive service to honor the life of Woodrow Wilson.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a statesman, scholar and President, Woodrow Wilson faced economic crisis, democratic decay and a world war. Presidential historians agree that World War I and President Wilson's leadership radically altered the role of diplomacy as a tool of foreign policy, a policy that established a new path for America's role in promoting democracies throughout the world. So, too, did Wilson's high-minded ideals craft a legacy that shaped the powers and responsibilities of the executive branch in times  of war.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, as a professor and president of Princeton University, Wilson created a more selective and accountable system for higher education. By instituting curriculum reform, Wilson revolutionized the roles of teachers and students and quickly made Princeton one of the most renowned universities in the world. Due to Wilson's legacy at Princeton, I am pleased to have the support of current Princeton President Shirley Tilghman as we establish this library.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1664">H.R. 1664</bill> gives the National Archives the authority to make pass-through grants for the establishment of the Presidential library in Stanton, Virginia, Woodrow Wilson's birthplace, and does not create a new program. In addition, to ensure that this is a public-private partnership, this legislation mandates that no grant shall be available for the establishment of this library until a private entity has raised at least twice the amount to be allocated by the Archives. Quite frankly, more Federal  public-private programs should operate in this manner.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, and to ensure that the Woodrow Wilson Presidential Library is not part of the Presidential Library System, this legislation states that the Federal Government shall have no role or responsibility for the operation of the library.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am also pleased to have the support of several other presidential sites throughout the Commonwealth of Virginia, known as the birthplace of Presidents, including Monticello, Poplar Forest, Montpelier, Ash Lawn, and Mount Vernon.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, in order to increase the awareness and understanding of the life, principles and accomplishments of the 28th President of the United States, I ask that you join me in supporting this legislation. I want to thank House leadership for scheduling this bill today. The cosponsors include the entire Virginia delegation. I am also grateful to the staff of the Government Reform Committee and the Office of Legislative Counsel for their assistance in crafting this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a reminder to my colleagues, this legislation is identical to a bill the House passed by a voice vote in the 109th Congress but was not considered in the Senate. At this time, I urge my colleagues to support this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I continue to reserve.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400027" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, during President Franklin D. Roosevelt's second term of office, he decided there should be a way to preserve and maintain official records and artifacts from his Presidency and the Presidency of future generations. Until his Presidency, many historic documents had been damaged, ruined or unaccounted for over the years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>President Roosevelt realized the need for preserving these valuable pieces of history and sought a way to make them available to the public.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are currently 12 Presidential libraries, including the Nixon Presidential Materials. Each is funded through private donations, and upon  completion of the library is turned over to the National Archives. These libraries are essentially museums and centers for learning about these Presidents and their terms in office. <bill type="h" number="1664">H.R. 1664</bill> authorizes funding for the establishment of a Woodrow Wilson Presidential Library in his birthplace of Staunton, Virginia.  It also states the National Archives and Records Administration will provide a matching grant towards the establishment of the library. The library will coordinate its efforts with other Woodrow Wilson museums to share exhibits and educational services.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Presidency of Woodrow Wilson is known for many achievements, among them are establishing the Federal Trade Commission and the Federal Reserve. He served his second term during World War I and worked with European nations on peace negotiations, including the Treaty of Versailles and the creation of the League of Nations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is critical we preserve the Presidential papers, historical records, and other artifacts of Woodrow Wilson's Presidency as we do with the previous 11 Presidents. These libraries offer citizens the opportunity to learn, study and appreciate an important period of American history. I urge my colleagues to support the passage. I applaud the gentleman from Virginia (Mr. Goodlatte) for introducing this bill and urge passage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, if my history serves me right, President Woodrow Wilson did not hold an elected public office prior to becoming President of the United States of America, which I think is indeed a feat in and of itself. So I want to commend the gentleman from Virginia for his introduction of this legislation, and urge its support.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Davis) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="1664">H.R. 1664</bill>.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the bill was passed.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
