<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1185422400" ordinal="29" title="PROVIDING FOR FURTHER CONSIDERATION OF H.R. 3093, COMMERCE, JUSTICE, SCIENCE, AND RELATED AGENCIES APPROPRIATIONS ACT, 2008">
  <narrative>PROVIDING FOR FURTHER CONSIDERATION OF <bill type="h" number="3093">H.R. 3093</bill>, COMMERCE, JUSTICE, SCIENCE, AND RELATED AGENCIES APPROPRIATIONS ACT, 2008 -- (House of Representatives - July 26, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H8639]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400281" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that, during further consideration of <bill type="h" number="3093">H.R. 3093</bill> in the Committee of the Whole pursuant to House Resolution 562, notwithstanding clause 11 of rule XVIII, no further amendment to the bill may be offered except:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Pro forma amendments offered at any point in the reading by the chairman or ranking minority member of the Committee on Appropriations or their designees for the purpose of debate;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Price of Georgia regarding funding for the Executive Office of Immigration Review;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Campbell of California reducing funds in the bill by 0.05 percent, which shall be debatable for 30 minutes;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Capuano regarding funding for young witness assistance;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Conaway regarding use of reductions made through amendment for deficit reduction;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Garrett of New Jersey limiting funds for attendance at international conferences;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Inslee regarding Federal law enforcement on tribal land;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Ms. Jackson-Lee of Texas regarding the early release of prisoners;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Ms. Jackson-Lee of Texas regarding transit workers' access to interoperable communications;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Ms. Jackson-Lee of Texas regarding the safety of the International Space Station;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Jordan of Ohio reducing funds in the bill by 3 percent, which shall be debatable for 30 minutes;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Mack or Mr. Flake limiting funds for certain FBI letters unless certain reporting requirements are met;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. McHenry limiting funds to award a grant or contract on the basis of race, ethnicity or sex;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mrs. Musgrave reducing funds in the bill by 0.5 percent, which shall be debatable for 30 minutes;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Obey regarding earmarks;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Price of Georgia reducing funds in the bill, which shall be debatable for 30 minutes;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Ms. Linda T. S&#xE1;nchez of California regarding the State Criminal Alien Assistance Program;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Tancredo or Mr. Hunter limiting funds for the Security and Prosperity Partnership;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Upton, Ms. Harman, Mr. Lipinski, or Mr. Inglis of South Carolina regarding use of Energy Star certified light bulbs;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Weldon of Florida limiting Community Oriented Policing funds for State and local governments acting in contravention of section 642 of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. Weldon of Florida or Mr. King of Iowa limiting State Criminal Alien Assistance Funds for State and local governments acting in contravention of section 642 of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. King of Iowa limiting State Criminal Alien Assistance Funds for State and local governments unless certain reporting requirements are met;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. King of Iowa regarding a study of aliens in prison;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. King of Iowa limiting funds to employ workers described in section 274A of the Immigration and Nationality Act;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment by Mr. King of Iowa limiting funds for the Institute for Scientific Research, the West Virginia High Tech Consortium Foundation, the Vandalia Heritage Foundation, the MountainMade Foundation; or the Canaan Valley Institute; and</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An amendment or amendments by Mr. Mollohan regarding funding levels.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Each such amendment may be offered only by the Member named in this request or a designee, shall be considered as read, shall not be subject to amendment except that the chairman and ranking minority member of the Committee on Appropriations and the Subcommittee on Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies each may offer one pro forma amendment for the purpose of debate; and shall not be subject to a demand for division of the question in the House or in the Committee of the Whole.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Except as otherwise specified, each amendment shall be debatable for 10 minutes, equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent. An amendment shall be considered to fit the description stated in this request if it addresses in whole or in part the object described.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from West Virginia?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
</record>
