<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1182182403" ordinal="34" title="SBA VETERANS' PROGRAMS ACT OF 2007">
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from New York (Ms. Vel&#xE1;zquez) and the gentleman from Tennessee (Mr. David Davis) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412209" topic="TITLE III--EXPANDING VETERANS BUSINESS OUTREACH CENTERS">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentlewoman from New York for yielding, and I thank the gentleman from Florida for introducing this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise today to voice my strong support for the SBA's Veterans' Programs Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The SBA's Veterans' Business Outreach Initiative was established to facilitate business ownership among disabled veterans by providing one-stop assistance and counseling. Today's legislation will expand the success of this initiative.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As an exemplary public/private partnership, Veterans' Business Outreach Centers represent the comprehensive, cooperative and effective support that our Nation can and should provide our country's veterans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This program provides greater opportunity to returning servicemembers and encourages economic development in communities across the country. Our troops fight for our country abroad, and we have a responsibility to provide for their future at home. Their sacrifice warrants our support. And they deserve every opportunity to succeed in business after their dedicated service to our country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill provides veterans with the community and government support necessary to ensure their success, and I support its passage.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412235" topic="TITLE III--EXPANDING VETERANS BUSINESS OUTREACH CENTERS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ms. VEL&#xC1;ZQUEZ. Mr. Speaker, veterans have not only been critical to the defense of our Nation, but with the increasing number of service men and women engaging in entrepreneurship, they have also been invaluable in helping our economy grow. These men and women have dedicated their lives to preserving our freedom. It is crucial that we show our appreciation for their service. The SBA Veterans' Programs Act of 2007 does just that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I strongly urge my colleagues to vote for <bill type="h" number="2366">H.R. 2366</bill>, the SBA Veterans' Program Act of 2007. I urge its adoption.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400429" topic="TITLE III--EXPANDING VETERANS BUSINESS OUTREACH CENTERS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="2366">H.R. 2366</bill>, the SBA Veterans' Programs Act of 2007. This legislation will assist our soldiers when then return home with opportunities and information about starting a small business.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>More than a million and a half (1,502,125) men and women have answered the call to serve their country since 2001. They interrupted their careers, put their families economic security at risk, and face big personal challenges upon returning home.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I recently visited Iraq and Afghanistan. That trip gave me an even greater appreciation for the significant sacrifices our soldiers must make and must cope with for the rest of their lives. If our soldiers faced mortal danger every day abroad, let us help them have economic security when they return home.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It isn't just the veteran who makes the sacrifice, their families do as well: their parents, their spouses, their children, girlfriends and boyfriends and siblings. They give up so much in defense of our country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is our job, as Members of Congress, to make sure that our Nation lives up to its commitment to our veterans. It is a simple pact we have made with our troops--and one we are obligated to fulfill: after they have sacrificed to serve our country on the battlefield, we must do all we can to serve them here at home. The cost of any war must include caring for the warrior.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation helps our veterans get started with business opportunities in their communities. It does so by providing grants, information services, and personal assistance to help veterans evaluate business opportunities; increasing the number of veteran business outreach centers around the country, and encouraging further assistance to women veterans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Countless soldiers are returning from their tours of duty with new confidence and skills developed during their time in the military. This SBA program will help to ensure that those new abilities are put to good use when they return to civilian life.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill is the right thing to do for those who have given so much and it will directly impact Vermont and every State around the country. 97 percent of all Vermont firms are small businesses. My office has been involved in helping the Vermont Small Business Development Centers (SBDC) run business readiness classes for veterans. The Vermont SBDC is the primary small business assistance resource sought out by small business clients, lenders, government agencies and other economic development  partners. The Vermont SBDC is the keystone in a statewide business assistance infrastructure tying together all appropriate resources and serving as a "one-stop" gateway and clearing house to serve small businesses' needs. Drawing on collaborative relationships among service providers, Vermont SBDC leverages economic development resources of all kinds for advancement of small businesses, growing the local economy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Roughly 6 percent of deployed soldiers have small businesses depending on them. Veterans face a number of unique challenges, from increasing lengths and number of deployments overseas, to translating their military experience into business ventures. Yet, there is a lack of substantive programs to help these businesses survive through deployment, and to assist veterans returning home. This program is designed to meet current, real-time needs of people on active duty in business who now need to  leave for protracted periods, or for those who have just come back and really "need" to do something new with their lives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge all of my colleagues to support <bill type="h" number="2366">H.R. 2366</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="TITLE III--EXPANDING VETERANS BUSINESS OUTREACH CENTERS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of <bill type="h" number="2366">H.R. 2366</bill>, the Small Business Administration Veterans' Programs Act of 2007. I commend my colleague from Florida (Mr. Buchanan) for introducing this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill would authorize the Small Business Administration (SBA) to award grants to Small Business Development Centers (SBDCs) for the establishment of programs that would improve outreach to veterans and veterans service organizations. Specifically, this bill would authorize SBDCs to use such grant funds to create a marketing campaign to promote awareness of the services made available to veterans through that SBDC, and to target the campaign toward veterans, disabled veterans, military units,  federal agencies, and veterans service organizations. The bill would also authorize SBDCs to utilize grant funds to develop and expand technology-assisted counseling and distance learning services designed to help veterans and members of the United States Armed Forces overcome barriers to entrepreneurship.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill would further require that Veterans Business Outreach Centers (VBOCs) participate in the U.S. Department of Labor Technical Assistance Program (TAP). The Technical Assistance Program is offered in 173 locations throughout the United States and 53 locations internationally. <bill type="h" number="2366">H.R. 2366</bill> would authorize VBOCs to provide grants to eligible entities located in TAP locations to make presentations on the opportunities available from the SBA for recently separated veterans. According to this  bill such presentations must include, at a minimum, the entrepreneurial and business training resources available from the SBA. This bill would increase the number of authorized VBOCs by two in each of fiscal years 2008 and 2009.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Additionally, <bill type="h" number="2366">H.R. 2366</bill> would direct the SBA to establish a Women Veterans Business Training Resource Program. This program would compile information on resources available to women veterans for business training, including resources for vocational and technical education, the development of general business skills, and business assistance programs. <bill type="h" number="2366">H.R. 2366</bill> would direct that the SBA disseminate such information through VBOCs and women business centers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Support for this legislation will help Congress fulfill its commitment to ensuring that our veterans and servicemembers receive the support they need upon separation from service. I support this legislation on behalf of all veterans and servicemembers, in particular those veterans and servicemembers from Guam. I urge my colleagues to support <bill type="h" number="2366">H.R. 2366</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ms. VEL&#xC1;ZQUEZ. Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from New York (Ms. Vel&#xE1;zquez) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="2366">H.R. 2366</bill>.</chair>
</record>
