<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1193328001" ordinal="30" title="PROTECTING CHILDREN">
  <narrative>PROTECTING CHILDREN -- (House of Representatives - October 25, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H12093]</narrative>
  <chair> Under a previous order of the House, the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Franks) is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400141" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, most of my adult life has been related to children's issues. Before I came to Congress, I had the privilege of serving in the Arizona House of Representatives as chairman of the Subcommittee on Child Protection and Family Preservation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Later, I was director of the Arizona Governor's Office for Children, which had oversight of all of the State's programs for children in Arizona.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I was also chairman of both the Arizona State Children's Cabinet and the Interagency Study Committee on Children and AIDS.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And for another 4 1/2  years, Mr. Speaker, I had the privilege of being the executive director of the Arizona Family Research Institute.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I later wrote the Arizona scholarship tax credit legislation, a version of which has now gone through five States and serves to scholarship more than 100,000 low-income children who go to a school of their parents' choice.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also wrote Arizona's child obscenity and pornography bill, which became a national precedent and protects children from the insidious harm of both adult and child pornography.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the reason I say those things is that there is one critical component of protecting innocent children I have learned over and over again; and that is if you desire to protect children, you must protect the family. Because either families, or government bureaucrats, will ultimately make the decisions about nearly all aspects of our children's lives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The proposed SCHIP legislation funds and empowers government bureaucracies and not families. It is a quintessential example of a misguided and overreaching program that is an entitlement program and affixes itself to a funding mechanism that is a declining revenue source. Not only does it place this generation of children into a Hillary-care, government-run health care system, but it also places the burden of cost on the next generation of children, Mr. Speaker, and those many times who will  be forced to pay for it will be those making less money than those benefiting from the program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, Americans care desperately about their children. And, unfortunately, in this SCHIP debate, liberal Democrats are exploiting America's love for children for temporary political gain. The majority has cast this entire debate in terms of Republicans being against children and Democrats being for them. For a Republican like myself who has spent their entire life dedicated to children's issues, it is an equation that I have to reject in the strongest possible terms. And it is especially  difficult for me, Mr. Speaker, in light of the fact that the same party who says they advocate for poor children leaves the very poorest children of all out of the equation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is the Democrat Party, Mr. Speaker, that has for decades fought for an abortion-on-demand policy that has allowed thousands of unborn children to be killed in America every day.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At the beginning of this Congress, newly elected Democrat Speaker  Nancy Pelosi said, "We are here for the children." And she called the House to order for "all of America's children."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But she didn't mean all of them, Mr. Speaker. In fact, most Democrat Members of this body, including Speaker Pelosi, voted against, in the last Congress, allowing unborn children to even receive anesthetic when undergoing abortion procedures so torturous that they would be a felony if performed on an animal.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, behind me this picture is a little baby who deserves to be protected like every other child in this country, and yet before the sun sets in America today, 4,000 unborn children will be killed through abortion on demand, and, Mr. Speaker, their mothers will never be the same.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Democrat Speaker and the majority of this Congress have to somehow understand that there are better ways to help mothers than killing their children for them. And they must also realize that they can never have credibility as advocates for children while they still support an abortion-on-demand policy that has killed nearly 50 million innocent children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, it is time for Members of this body to come together and to truly do the right thing for all of America's children, even those yet unborn.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
