<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1210176002" ordinal="23" title="CALENDAR WEDNESDAY">
  <narrative>CALENDAR WEDNESDAY -- (House of Representatives - May 07, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H3114]</narrative>
  <chair> Today is the day of Calendar Wednesday. The Clerk will call the roll of committees.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk called the committees.</narrative>
  <narrative>Mr. SESSIONS (during the call). Mr. Speaker, I have a point of parliamentary inquiry.</narrative>
  <chair> The gentleman will state his inquiry.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400367" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRY">
    <paragraph>I understand that this procedure that we are going through is known as Calendar Wednesday.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Is it correct that any bill reported by a committee and placed on the Union or House Calendar could have been called up by the chairman as the committee name was read?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Clause 2(b) of rule XIII is sufficient authority for the chairman of the committee to call up from the Calendar a non-privileged bill on Calendar Wednesday.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400367" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRY">
    <paragraph>Further point of parliamentary inquiry, Mr. Speaker.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman will state his inquiry.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400367" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRY">
    <paragraph>Does the jurisdiction of the Energy and Commerce Committee, as provided under clause 1 of rule X of the rules of the House of Representatives, include exploration, production, storage, supply, marketing, pricing and regulation of energy resources, including all fossil fuels, which includes legislation to lower the price of gasoline which has increased to over $3.60 a gallon under Speaker Pelosi's watch?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Chair believes that the gentleman correctly stated the rule up to the point where he embarked on commentary.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400367" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRY">
    <paragraph>I have a further point of parliamentary inquiry, Mr. Speaker.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman will state his inquiry.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400367" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRY">
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="3236">H.R. 3236</bill>, introduced by Congressman Boucher of Virginia, to promote energy efficiency improvements in buildings and appliances was reported by the Energy and Commerce Committee on August 3, 2007, and placed on the Union Calendar.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Would it be possible for Mr. Dingell, the chairman of the Energy and Commerce Committee, to call up this bill under his committee's jurisdiction to help the Speaker to implement her secret plan to reduce gas prices by diverting less of America's energy supply to buildings and appliances, or for any other membership of the Democrat majority to help their leadership to call up the bill?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Chair will respond to the Member's parliamentary inquiry but not his political commentary and repeat that clause 2(b) of rule XIII is sufficient authority for the chairman of the committee to call up from the Calendar a non-privileged bill on Calendar Wednesday.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400367" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRY">
    <paragraph>Further point of parliamentary inquiry, Mr. Speaker.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman may state his inquiry.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400367" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRY">
    <paragraph>Is it in order for any Member of the majority to call up <bill type="h" number="3239">H.R. 3239</bill>, also introduced by Mr. Boucher of Virginia and also available on the Union Calendar, to promote advancing plug-in hybrid vehicles and vehicle components through loan guarantees and grants, and if this would help the Speaker to implement her secret plan by reducing the demand for gasoline and bringing down the prices that have skyrocketed under this Democrat leadership?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Only the chairman or another member of the committee acting by its express direction may call up a bill.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400367" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRY">
    <paragraph>Final point of parliamentary inquiry, Mr. Speaker.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman may state his inquiry.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400367" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRY">
    <paragraph>Under the rules of Calendar Wednesday, is it in order for any Member of this body, including Speaker Pelosi, to call up <bill type="hr" number="1135">H. Res. 1135</bill>, legislation drafted by Congressman DEAN HELLER of Nevada, which would call on Speaker Pelosi to reveal her secret commonsense plan to bring down gas prices since it's obviously not contained in the "no energy" energy bill passed by the Congress last December?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> No. To be considered under the Calendar Wednesday rule, a bill must be on the Calendar, be non-privileged, and be called up either by the committee  chairman or by another member of the committee having specific authorization of the committee to call it up.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400367" topic="PARLIAMENTARY INQUIRY">
    <paragraph>So in other words, Mr. Speaker, what you're saying is that the committee chairman and the Speaker have the ability to call up any bill that has been reported out.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> No, but that is not a parliamentary inquiry.</chair>
</record>
