<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1216051202" ordinal="42" title="HONORING THURGOOD MARSHALL ON THE 100TH ANNIVERSARY OF HIS BIRTH">
  <narrative>HONORING THURGOOD MARSHALL ON THE 100TH ANNIVERSARY OF HIS BIRTH -- (House of Representatives - July 14, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H6449]</narrative>
  <narrative>(Ms. JACKSON-LEE of Texas asked and was given permission to address the House for 1 minute and to revise and extend her remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400199" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today, as I indicated earlier in the afternoon, <bill type="hc" number="381">H. Con. Res. 381</bill> was being debated and that is the honoring and recognizing the dedication and achievements of Thurgood Marshall on the 100th anniversary of his birth. Let me thank Congressman Payne for his legislative initiative, the House Judiciary Committee Chairman JOHN CONYERS and Ranking Member Mr. LAMAR SMITH.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I stand here today as a living example of the legacy and the leadership of Justice Thurgood Marshall. Who would have thought as he broke the color line in Brown versus Topeka Board of Education that he would have opened the doors of opportunity for those from the East to the West and from the North to the South?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Most people don't know that America during the 1950s and earlier than that continued to be a segregated America. It did not matter where you lived. Thurgood Marshall had the courage to take this case to the United States Supreme Court. And the Warren court had the courage and rightness of mind to be able to establish an equal education for all.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I applaud Thurgood Marshall who was appointed to the Court of Appeals by President John F. Kennedy and ultimately the first African American to sit on the United States Supreme Court. He was one who understood justice. He was one who recognized the equality of all people. He was one who recognized that America is better when it reflects and appreciates its diversity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thank you, Justice Marshall, for the freedom and the opportunity you have given even to me.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
