<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1205164802" ordinal="34" title="PERMITTING THE USE OF THE ROTUNDA OF THE CAPITOL FOR A CEREMONY AS PART OF THE COMMEMORATION OF THE DAYS OF REMEMBRANCE OF VICTIMS OF THE HOLOCAUST">
  <narrative>PERMITTING THE USE OF THE ROTUNDA OF THE CAPITOL FOR A CEREMONY AS PART OF THE COMMEMORATION OF THE DAYS OF REMEMBRANCE OF VICTIMS OF THE HOLOCAUST -- (House of Representatives - March 10, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H1432]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400245" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I ask unanimous consent to discharge the Committee on House Administration from further consideration of House Concurrent Resolution 306, and ask for its immediate consideration in the House.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the concurrent resolution.</narrative>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from California?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400119" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I reserve the right to object, but I will not object.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, this is a very important resolution. It's something we do every year, and I can't imagine any more appropriate use of the rotunda of the Capitol than to recognize and commemorate the days of the Holocaust and the victims of the Holocaust. It's something that we do every year, something we should do every year and perhaps more frequently. And it is extremely important for us to recognize this as we confront genocide in other parts of the world, to recognize the genocide that started  all genocides and started the discussions about the horrible nature of genocide. So I'm very strongly in favor of this.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I withdraw my reservation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from California?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <chair>The text of the concurrent resolution is as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="hc" number="306">H. Con. Res. 306</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair> Resolved by the House of Representatives (the Senate concurring),&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. USE OF ROTUNDA FOR HOLOCAUST DAYS OF REMEMBRANCE CEREMONY.</chair>
  <chair> The Rotunda of the Capitol is authorized to be used on May 1, 2008, for a ceremony as part of the commemoration of the days of remembrance of victims of the Holocaust. Physical preparations for the ceremony shall be carried out in accordance with such conditions as the Architect of the Capitol may prescribe.&lt;p&gt;</chair>
  <chair>The concurrent resolution was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
