<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1223049602" ordinal="20" title="CHILD SAFE VIEWING ACT OF 2007">
  <narrative>CHILD SAFE VIEWING ACT OF 2007 -- (House of Representatives - October 03, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H10807]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400101" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Energy and Commerce be discharged from further consideration of the Senate bill (<bill type="s" number="602">S. 602</bill>) to develop the next generation of parental control technology, and ask for its immediate consideration in the House.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the Senate bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from Colorado?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <chair>The text of the Senate bill is as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="s" number="602">S. 602</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "Child Safe Viewing Act of 2007".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. FINDINGS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Congress finds the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) Video programming has a direct impact on a child's perception of safe and reasonable behavior.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) Children may imitate actions they witness on video programming, including language, drug use, and sexual conduct.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) Studies suggest that the strong appeal of video programming erodes the ability of parents to develop responsible attitudes and behavior in their children.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) The average American child watches 4 hours of television each day.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) 99.9 percent of all consumer complaints logged by the Federal Communications Commission in the first quarter of 2006 regarding radio and television broadcasting were because of obscenity, indecency, and profanity.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (6) There is a compelling government interest in empowering parents to limit their children's exposure to harmful television content.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (7) Section 1 of the Communications Act of 1934 requires the Federal Communications Commission to promote the safety of life and property through the use of wire and radio communications.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (8) In the Telecommunications Act of 1996, Congress authorized Parental Choice in Television Programming and the V-Chip. Congress further directed action on alternative blocking technology as new video technology advanced.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 3. EXAMINATION OF ADVANCED BLOCKING TECHNOLOGIES AND EXISTING PARENTAL EMPOWERMENT TOOLS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Inquiry Required.--Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Federal Communications Commission shall initiate a notice of inquiry to consider measures to examine--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) the existence and availability of advanced blocking technologies that are compatible with various communications devices or platforms;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) methods of encouraging the development, deployment, and use of such technology by parents that do not affect the packaging or pricing of a content provider's offering; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) the existence, availability, and use of parental empowerment tools and initiatives already in the market.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Content of Proceeding.--In conducting the inquiry required under subsection (a), the Commission shall consider advanced blocking technologies that--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) may be appropriate across a wide variety of distribution platforms, including wired, wireless, and Internet platforms;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) may be appropriate across a wide variety of devices capable of transmitting or receiving video or audio programming, including television sets, DVD players, VCRs, cable  set top boxes, satellite receivers, and wireless devices;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) can filter language based upon information in closed captioning;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) operate independently of ratings pre-assigned by the creator of such video or audio programming; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) may be effective in enhancing the ability of a parent to protect his or her child from indecent or objectionable programming, as determined by such parent.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Reporting.--Not later than 270 days after the enactment of this Act, the Commission shall issue a report to Congress detailing any findings resulting from the inquiry required under subsection (a).</chair>
  <chair> (d) Definition.--In this section, the term "advanced blocking technologies" means technologies that can improve or enhance the ability of a parent to protect his or her child from any indecent or objectionable video or audio programming, as determined by such parent, that is transmitted through the use of wire, wireless, or radio communication.&lt;p&gt;</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>Amendment offered by Ms. DeGette:</narrative>
  <narrative>Strike section 2.</narrative>
  <narrative>Redesignate section 3 as section 2.</narrative>
  <narrative>The amendment was agreed to.</narrative>
  <narrative>The bill was ordered to be engrossed and read a third time, was read the third time, and passed, and a motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</narrative>
</record>
