<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1194973204" ordinal="26" title="SAFEGUARDING AMERICA'S FAMILIES BY ENHANCING AND REORGANIZING NEW AND EFFICIENT TECHNOLOGIES ACT OF 2007">
  <narrative>SAFEGUARDING AMERICA'S FAMILIES BY ENHANCING AND REORGANIZING NEW AND EFFICIENT TECHNOLOGIES ACT OF 2007 -- (House of Representatives - November 13, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H13561]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400616" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="3461">H.R. 3461</bill>) to establish a public awareness campaign regarding Internet safety, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="3461">H.R. 3461</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "Safeguarding America's Families by Enhancing and Reorganizing New and Efficient Technologies Act of 2007".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. INTERNET SAFETY.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; For purposes of this Act, the issue of Internet safety includes issues regarding use of the Internet in a manner that promotes safe online activity, including safe transactions involved in online commerce, and protects against threats to financial information and privacy, threats from cyber-crime, and threats to juveniles, including cyber-predators and material that is inappropriate for minors.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 3. PUBLIC AWARENESS CAMPAIGN.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; The Federal Trade Commission shall carry out a nationwide program to increase public awareness and provide education regarding Internet safety, for families, businesses, organizations, and other users, that utilizes existing resources and efforts of the Federal Government, State and local governments, nonprofit organizations, private technology and financial companies, Internet service providers, World Wide Web-based resources, and other appropriate entities, that includes--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) identifying, promoting, and encouraging best practices for Internet safety;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) establishing and carrying out a national outreach and education campaign regarding Internet safety utilizing various media and Internet-based resources;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) facilitating access to, and the exchange of, information regarding Internet safety to promote up-to-date knowledge regarding current issues; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) facilitating access to Internet safety education and public awareness efforts the Commission considers appropriate to States, units of local government, schools, police departments, nonprofit organizations, and such other entities.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 4. ANNUAL REPORTS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; The Commission shall submit a report to Congress not later than March 31 of each year that describes the activities carried out under section 3 by the Commission during the preceding calendar year.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 5. ONLINE SAFETY AND TECHNOLOGY WORKING GROUP.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Establishment.--Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information shall establish an Online Safety and Technology working group comprised of representatives of relevant sectors of the business community, public interest groups, and other appropriate groups and Federal agencies to review and evaluate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) the status of industry efforts to promote online safety through educational efforts, parental control technology, blocking and filtering software, age-appropriate labels for content or other technologies or initiatives designed to promote a safe online environment for children;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) the status of industry efforts to promote online safety among providers of electronic communications services and remote computing services by reporting apparent child pornography under section 13032 of title 42, United States Code;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) the practices of electronic communications service providers and remote computing service providers related to record retention in connection with crimes against children; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) the development of technologies to help parents shield their children from inappropriate material on the Internet.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Report.--Not later than 1 year after the working group established under subsection (a) is first convened, it shall submit a report to the Assistant Secretary and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives that--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) describes in detail its findings, including any information related to the effectiveness of such strategies and technologies and any information about the prevalence within industry of educational campaigns, parental control technologies, blocking and filtering software, labeling, or other technologies to assist parents; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) includes recommendations as to what types of incentives could be used or developed to increase the effectiveness and implementation of such strategies and technologies.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 6. DEFINITIONS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; For purposes of this Act, the following definitions shall apply:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) COMMISSION.--The term "Commission" means the Federal Trade Commission.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) INTERNET.--The term "Internet" means collectively the myriad of computer and telecommunications facilities, including equipment and operating software, which comprise the interconnected world-wide network of networks that employ the Transmission Control Protocol/Internet Protocol, or any predecessor or successor protocols to such protocol, to communicate information of all kinds by wire or radio.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 7. AUTHORIZATION OF APPROPRIATIONS.</narrative>
  <narrative> For carrying out the public awareness campaign under section 3, there is authorized to be appropriated to the Commission $5,000,000 for fiscal year 2008, which shall remain available until until September 30, 2009.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from North Carolina (Mr. Butterfield) and the gentleman from Michigan (Mr. Upton) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from North Carolina.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400616" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, <bill type="h" number="3461">H.R. 3461</bill>, the Safeguarding America's Families by Enhancing and Reorganizing New and Efficient Technologies Act of 2007, or the SAFER NET Act as we refer to it, was introduced by Congresswoman MELISSA BEAN from Illinois. The bill, Mr. Speaker, has 41 cosponsors, and it was reported out of the Energy and Commerce Committee with unanimous, bipartisan support just 2 weeks ago, I believe it was, on October 30. As a member of the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection,  I want to thank the gentlelady for her ongoing and tireless efforts to protect children from the lurking dangers on the Internet.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Earlier this year, the distinguished gentlewoman (Ms. Bean) introduced <bill type="hr" number="455">H. Res. 455</bill>, which was a resolution supporting the goals of National Internet Safety Month, which passed the House on June 12. As such, the bill on the floor today is a quality legislative extension of her previous work on Internet safety.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="3461">H.R. 3461</bill>, the SAFER NET Act, directs the Federal Trade Commission to carry out a nationwide public awareness campaign about Internet safety and directs the Commission to annually report to Congress on its activity to promote Internet safety. The bill, as amended, authorizes $5 million for 1 year to carry out this public awareness campaign.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Currently, Mr. Speaker, the Federal Trade Commission is engaged in numerous activities to promote awareness and on-line safety habits. The Commission has established a toll-free number which serves as a help line where consumers can file their complaints. Moreover, the FTC has set up a very special Web site, www.OnGuardOnline.gov, that is all one word, to provide tips to consumers in protecting themselves and their children from Internet fraud.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Lastly, the Federal Trade Commission is engaged in a public awareness campaign to promote Internet safety through a child friendly mascot named Dewie the Turtle, much the same way that Smokey the Bear successfully promoted the prevention of forest fires many years ago. The office responsible for managing these initiatives is the Division of Consumer and Business Education. And Congresswoman Bean's bill will aid the FTC in its laudable efforts to protect children from inappropriate content  and from the predators that would do them harm.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the Internet is one of the most significant technological developments in the history of humankind, and my friend, Mr. Markey, who spoke just moments before me, made that point in a profound way. The way people obtain information and communicate with each other has been completely revolutionized in a manner unthinkable just 20 years ago. However, with this great revolution comes a price. Our children are now more vulnerable to the despicable creatures that would prey on  them by exploiting the powers of the Internet. It is, therefore, imperative that we in Congress do everything we can to fulfill our duties to promote healthy and safe environments for our children. The SAFER NET Act is a quality step in the right direction. I urge my colleagues to vote "yes" on this legislation and pass the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I retain the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400414" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to again thank Chairman Dingell and Mr. Barton, the ranking member of the committee. I remember 2 weeks ago when we moved this through our committee, it was a very important piece of legislation. Ms. Bean is the author of this. I know Mary Bono on our side helped immensely in getting it through the subcommittee. We all rise in support of <bill type="h" number="3461">H.R. 3461</bill>, Safeguarding America's Families by Enhancing and Reorganizing New and Efficient Technologies Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill directs the FTC, the Federal Trade Commission, to carry out a nationwide public awareness campaign about Internet safety, provides a 1-year authorization of $5 million to carry out that campaign, and directs the FTC to report annually to the Congress on its activities to promote Internet safety. I look forward to those reports as the ranking member of the Telecommunications and Internet Subcommittee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The FTC has been very active in the area, and its current computer security education campaign is built around an innovative multimedia Web site, www.OnguardOnline.gov, with special tips and features for children, teens and their parents. <bill type="h" number="3461">H.R. 3461</bill> expands these underway. Moreover, the Internet defines Internet safety to include threats to juveniles, including cyber predators and material that is inappropriate for minors, criminal activity beyond the FTC's authority and scope. And to fulfill  that directive, the FTC would then partner with the FBI and the U.S. Postal Service and with prominent nongovernmental organizations such as the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I visit a school almost every week, actually more than once a week, and often when I speak to an elementary school, I will ask those third or fourth graders, "How many of you have seen something inappropriate on the Internet?" It didn't used to be. It used to be that my question was, "How many of you have a computer at home?" Now practically everyone has a computer at home. But now when I ask that question, "Have you seen something inappropriate?" every hand goes up, including  mine.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I hosted an event in our district two Mondays ago on Internet safety in our intermediate school district in Berrien County, was attended by hundreds of people. We had votes that night so I couldn't be there. But it is a concern. Parents have to know what is going on. And that is why this new Web site, OnGuardOnline.gov is very important so that the word can get out, because the Internet is a double-edged sword. Yes, it helps our lives in so many different ways, but we have to look  out for the nightmare that could come into that home from someone who we would not want in as a decent parent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So this is good legislation. It is going to have a positive impact. There is a reason that it passed by unanimous vote among Republicans and Democrats. I hope that the Senate can move along quickly. We will be willing to give them a kick if they don't do that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I don't have any other speakers requesting time, and I yield back my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400616" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I don't have any further speakers on this side. I am ready to close this out and to yield back my time. Before doing so, I again want to thank Ms. Bean for this legislation and thank Mr. Upton for his advocacy and his passion for this issue. These legislators work very hard to bring this issue to the forefront, and they have done a magnificent job in doing this today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400631" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in strong support of my bill, <bill type="h" number="3461">H.R. 3461</bill>, The Safeguarding America's Families by Enhancing and Reorganizing New and Efficient Technologies Act or SAFER NET. I want to thank Chairman DINGELL and Chairman RUSH for their help in bringing this bill to the floor today. I also to thank Congressman BARON HILL, the lead cosponsor of this bill, and Congresswoman MARY BONO for her contributions to this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Internet is a wonderful resource for our children. Over 90 percent of school age children use the Internet on a regular basis. They use it to expand their knowledge beyond what they can learn in the classroom and use it to stay connected with their friends when not at school.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Internet has increased productivity and opened new opportunities to our children, but while doing so, it has created new threats. These threats whether it be unwanted online solicitations, Internet scams, or cyber-bullying are dangerous and real.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In order for our children to be protected from the dangers of the Internet, we must work together to raise awareness and educate them about Internet safety. As noted in a study conducted by the National Assessment Center:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>41 percent of middle and high school students do not share with their parents what they do on the Internet.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>61 percent of students admit to using the Internet unsafely or inappropriately.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And of most concern, 20 percent of middle school and high school students have met face-to-face with someone they first met online.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In recent studies conducted by the Department of Justice in conjunction with the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children, one in seven children between the ages of 10 and 17 received a sexual solicitation online.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And one in 25 or one per classroom receives an aggressive sexual solicitation when a predator calls them on the phone, sends them gifts, or requests a meeting.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Informing parents is just as important to keep our kids safe online. Unfortunately, approximately half of parents surveyed admit that they do not properly monitor their children's Internet activity and do not use filter, blocking, or monitoring software on their home computers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Parents need to be engaged and ask their children what they are doing online. Unfortunately, nearly half of parents surveyed do not believe that they are able to properly monitor their children's actions online.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a parent, you wouldn't let your son or daughter play with a friend without knowing who was in charge and where they would be playing. The same should be the case with the Internet. The Internet is a large virtual playground and just like on the playground at the park, kids need to be supervised.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Fortunately, our schools, non-profits, local, state, and federal governments, and concerned corporate citizens have been actively engaging children on Internet safety. Programs vary but all emphasize the importance of protecting personal information, keeping parents informed of Internet actions, and being careful who you talk to online.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although these resources are great, not enough kids and parents are aware of them. Internet safety is an issue of national importance that deserves a national response.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is why passing The SAFER NET Act today is so important.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The SAFER NET Act would authorize $5 million for the Federal Trade Commission to conduct a national public awareness campaign to promote Internet Safety.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, the bill will direct the Federal Trade Commission to build on the efforts of its Onguard Online website so it can better serve as a virtual clearinghouse of Internet safety information.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally the SAFER NET Act would establish a working group through the National Telecommunications and Information Administration (NTIA) to review and evaluate industry efforts to promote online safety and protect children from inappropriate material online.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In closing, I want to thank the staff on the Energy &amp; Commerce Committee, J.D. Grom on my staff, and Nathan Fenstermacher who previously served in my office and helped draft the original SAFER NET Act last Congress for their assistance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support <bill type="h" number="3461">H.R. 3461</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400616" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from North Carolina (Mr. Butterfield) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="3461">H.R. 3461</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400616" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this motion will be postponed.</chair>
</record>
