<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1190649602" ordinal="22" title="HUDSON-FULTON-CHAMPLAIN QUADRICENTENNIAL COMMEMORATION ACT OF 2007">
  <narrative>HUDSON-FULTON-CHAMPLAIN QUADRICENTENNIAL COMMEMORATION ACT OF 2007 -- (House of Representatives - September 24, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H10709]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="1520">H.R. 1520</bill>) to establish the Champlain Quadricentennial Commemoration Commission, the Hudson-Fulton 400th Commemoration Commission, and for other purposes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="1520">H.R. 1520</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE; TABLE OF CONTENTS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Short Title.--This Act may be cited as the "Hudson-Fulton-Champlain Quadricentennial Commemoration Act of 2007".</narrative>
  <narrative> (b) Table of Contents.--The table of contents for this Act is as follows:&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <narrative>Sec. 1..Short title; table of contents.</narrative>
  <narrative>Sec..101..Findings and purpose.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..102..Coordination.</narrative>
  <narrative>Sec..201..Definitions.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..202..Champlain Quadricentennial Commemoration Commission.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..203..Audit of Commission.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..204..Authorization of appropriations.</narrative>
  <narrative>Sec..301..Definitions.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..302..Hudson-Fulton 400th Commemoration Commission.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..303..Audit of Commission.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..304..Authorization of appropriations.</narrative>
  <narrative>SEC. 101. FINDINGS AND PURPOSE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Findings.--The Congress finds the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) The first European exploration of the Hudson River and Lake Champlain and the introduction of steam navigation to maritime commerce were events of major historical importance, both in the United States and internationally.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) In 1609, Englishman Henry Hudson, acting in the service of the Dutch East India Company, was the first European to sail up the river later named for him in the vessel HALF MOON. Also in 1609, French explorer Samuel de Champlain was the first European to see the lake later named for him, as well as the shores of Northern New York and Vermont.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) These voyages were two of the most significant passages in the European exploration and discovery of America, and included two of the earliest contacts in the New World between Native Americans and Europeans.</narrative>
  <narrative> (4) These explorations led to the establishment of Fort Orange, a Dutch (and later English) settlement of what is now the capital city of the State of New York, as well as the establishment of French trading posts, military posts, and settlements as far south as Lake George. From these early establishments came trade, commerce, cultural, and religious impact deep into the Mohawk Valley and as far west as Lake Erie. These settlements influenced the Nation's history, culture, law, commerce, and  traditions of liberty that extend to the present day, and that are constantly reflected in the position of the United States as the leader of the nations of the free world.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) In 1807, Robert Fulton navigated the Hudson River from the city of New York to Albany in the steamboat CLERMONT, successfully inaugurating steam navigation on a commercial basis. This event is one of the most important events in the history of navigation. It revolutionized waterborne commerce on the great rivers of the United States, transformed naval warfare, and fostered international relations through transoceanic travel and trade.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (6) In 1909, the Congress authorized a Champlain Tercentennial Commission and supported its activities. The Congress recognized the 350th anniversary by establishing a similar commission to coordinate Federal participation in the 1959 celebration of Hudson's and Champlain's discoveries.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (7) The National Park Service owns and operates significant resources in New York related to the early history of the Nation and the Hudson River Valley.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (8) In 2000, Canada's Province of Quebec established a Quebec 400 Commission with a budget in excess of $1,000,000, of which commemoration of the 1609 Champlain voyage into the Lake Champlain region is a part.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (9) In 2002, the State of New York established a Hudson-Fulton-Champlain Commission.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (10) In 2003, the State of Vermont established a Lake Champlain Quadricentennial Commission.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Purpose.--The purpose of this Act is to establish the Champlain Quadricentennial Commemoration Commission and the Hudson-Fulton 400th Commemoration Commission, to--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) ensure a suitable national observance of the Henry Hudson, Robert Fulton, and Samuel de Champlain 2009 commemorations through cooperation with and assistance to the programs and activities of New York, Vermont, and the commemorative commissions formed by these States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) assist in ensuring that Hudson-Fulton-Champlain 2009 observances provide an excellent visitor experience and beneficial interaction between visitors and the natural and cultural resources of the New York and Vermont sites;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) assist in ensuring that Hudson-Fulton-Champlain 2009 observances are inclusive and appropriately recognize the diverse Hudson River and Lake Champlain Valley communities that developed over four centuries;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) facilitate international involvement, including the involvement of the commemorative commission formed by Canada, in the Hudson-Fulton-Champlain 2009 observances;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) support and facilitate marketing efforts for a commemorative coin, a commemorative stamp, and related activities for the Hudson-Fulton-Champlain 2009 observances;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (6) assist in the appropriate development of heritage tourism and economic benefits to the United States; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (7) support and facilitate the related efforts of the Lake Champlain Basin Program in the coordination of efforts to commemorate the voyage of Samuel de Champlain.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 102. COORDINATION.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; The two commissions established under this Act shall ensure coordination of their activities to achieve seamless and successful commemorations, and ensure consistency with the plans and programs of the commemorative commissions established by the States of New York and Vermont.</narrative>
  <narrative>SEC. 201. DEFINITIONS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; In this title:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) COMMEMORATION.--The term "commemoration" means the commemoration of the 400th anniversary of Samuel de Champlain's voyage.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) COMMISSION.--The term "Commission" means the Champlain Quadricentennial Commemoration Commission established by section 202(a).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) LAKE CHAMPLAIN BASIN PROGRAM.--The term "Lake Champlain Basin Program" means the partnership with Federal agencies established by the States of New York and Vermont under section 120 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (33 U.S.C. 1270) to implement the Lake Champlain management plan entitled "Opportunities for Action".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) SECRETARY.--The term "Secretary" means the Secretary of the Interior.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) STATES.--The term "States"--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) means the States of New York and Vermont; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) includes agencies and other entities of each such State.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 202. CHAMPLAIN QUADRICENTENNIAL COMMEMORATION COMMISSION.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) In General.--The Secretary shall establish a commission to be known as the "Champlain Quadricentennial Commemoration Commission".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Membership.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) IN GENERAL.--The Commission shall be composed of 11 members, of whom--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) 2 members shall be employees of the National Park Service, of whom--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) one shall be the Director of the National Park Service (or a designee of the Director); and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) one shall be an employee of the National Park Service having experience relevant to the commemoration, who shall be appointed by the Secretary;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) 4 members shall be appointed by the Secretary from among individuals who, on the date of the enactment of this Act, are serving as members of the State of New York's Hudson-Fulton-Champlain Quadricentennial Commission and are residents of the Champlain Valley;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) 4 members shall be appointed by the Secretary from among individuals who, on the date of the enactment of this Act, are serving as members of the State of Vermont's Lake Champlain Quadricentennial Commission and are residents of Vermont; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (D) one member shall be appointed by the Secretary from among individuals who have an interest in, demonstrated their support for, and demonstrated expertise appropriate to, the commemoration, and are knowledgeable of the Champlain Valley.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) TERM; VACANCIES.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) TERM.--Each member of the Commission shall be appointed for the life of the Commission. &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) VACANCIES.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) IN GENERAL.--A vacancy on the Commission shall be filled in the same manner in which the original appointment was made.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) PARTIAL TERM.--A member appointed to fill a vacancy on the Commission shall serve for the remainder of the term for which the predecessor of the member was appointed.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) MEETINGS.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) IN GENERAL.--The Commission shall meet--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) at least twice each year; or&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) at the call of the chairperson or the majority of the members of the Commission.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) INITIAL MEETING.--Not later than 30 days after the date on which all members of the Commission have been appointed, the Commission shall hold the initial meeting of the Commission.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) CHAIRPERSON AND VICE CHAIRPERSON.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) IN GENERAL.--The Commission shall elect the chairperson and the vice chairperson of the Commission on an annual basis.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) VICE CHAIRPERSON.--The vice chairperson shall serve as the chairperson in the absence of the chairperson.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) QUORUM.--A majority of voting members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum, but a lesser number may hold meetings.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (6) VOTING.--The Commission shall act only on an affirmative vote of a majority of the voting members of the Commission.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Duties.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) IN GENERAL.--The Commission shall--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) plan, develop, and execute programs and activities appropriate to commemorate the 400th anniversary of the voyage of Samuel de Champlain, the first European to discover and explore Lake Champlain;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) facilitate Champlain-related activities throughout the United States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) coordinate its activities with State commemoration commissions and appropriate Federal Government entities, including the Departments of Agriculture, Defense, State, and Transportation, the Lake Champlain Basin Program, the National Endowment for the Humanities and the National Endowment for the Arts, and the Smithsonian Institution;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (D) encourage civic, patriotic, historical, educational, artistic, religious, economic, and other organizations throughout the United States to organize and participate in anniversary activities to expand the understanding and appreciation of the significance of the voyage of Samuel de Champlain;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (E) provide technical assistance to States, localities, and nonprofit organizations to further the commemoration;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (F) coordinate and facilitate for the public scholarly research on, publication about, and interpretation of, the voyage of Samuel de Champlain;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (G) ensure that the Champlain 2009 anniversary provides a lasting legacy and long-term public benefit by assisting in the development of appropriate programs and facilities;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (H) assist in ensuring that the observances of the voyage of Samuel de Champlain are inclusive and appropriately recognize the experiences and heritage of all people present when Samuel de Champlain arrived in the Champlain Valley; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (I) consult and coordinate with the Lake Champlain Basin Program and other relevant organizations in the planning and development of programs and activities for the commemoration of the voyage of Samuel de Champlain.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) STRATEGIC PLAN AND ANNUAL PERFORMANCE PLANS.--The Commission shall prepare a strategic plan in accordance with section 306 of title 5, United States Code, and annual performance plans in accordance with section 1115 of title 31, United States Code, for the activities of the Commission carried out under this Act.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) REPORTS.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) ANNUAL REPORT.--The Commission shall submit to the Congress an annual report that contains a list of each gift, bequest, or devise with a value of more than $250, together with the identity of the donor of each such gift, bequest, or devise.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) FINAL REPORT.--Not later than September 30, 2010, the Commission shall submit to the Secretary a final report that contains--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) a summary of the activities of the Commission;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) a final accounting of funds received and expended by the Commission; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (iii) the findings and recommendations of the Commission.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (d) Powers of the Commission.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) IN GENERAL.--The Commission may--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) solicit, accept, use, and dispose of gifts, bequests, or devises of money or other real or personal property for the purpose of aiding or facilitating the work of the Commission;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) appoint such advisory committees as the Commission determines to be necessary to carry out this Act;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) authorize any member or employee of the Commission to take any action that the Commission is authorized to take by this Act;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (D) subject to the availability of appropriations, procure supplies, services, and property, and make or enter into contracts, leases, or other legal agreements, to carry out this Act, except that any contracts, leases, or other legal agreements made or entered into by the Commission directly or with administrative assistance from the Lake Champlain Basin Program shall not extend beyond the date of the termination of the Commission;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (E) use the United States mails in the same manner and under the same conditions as other Federal agencies;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (F) subject to approval by the Commission and the availability of appropriations, make grants in amounts not to exceed $20,000 to communities, nonprofit organizations, and commemorative commissions formed by the States to develop programs to assist in the commemoration;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (G) subject to the availability of appropriations, make grants in amounts not to exceed $20,000 to research and scholarly organizations to research, publish, or distribute information relating to the early history of the voyage of Champlain; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (H) provide technical assistance to the States, localities, and nonprofit organizations to develop programs and facilities to further the commemoration.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) COORDINATION AND CONSULTATION WITH LAKE CHAMPLAIN BASIN PROGRAM.--The Commission shall coordinate and consult with the Lake Champlain Basin Program in providing grants and technical assistance under subparagraphs (F), (G), and (H) of paragraph (1) for the conduct of activities relating to the commemoration of the voyage of Samuel de Champlain.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (e) Commission Personnel Matters.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) COMPENSATION OF MEMBERS OF THE COMMISSION.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) IN GENERAL.--Except as provided in subparagraph (B), a member of the Commission shall serve without compensation.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) FEDERAL EMPLOYEES.--A member of the Commission who is an officer or employee of the Federal Government shall serve without compensation in addition to the compensation received for the services of the member as an officer or employee of the Federal Government.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) TRAVEL EXPENSES.--A member of the Commission shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for an employee of an agency under subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5, United States Code, while away from the home or regular place of business of the member in the performance of the duties of the Commission.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) STAFF.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) IN GENERAL.--The chairperson of the Commission may, without regard to the civil service laws (including regulations), appoint and terminate an executive director and such other additional personnel as are necessary to enable the Commission to perform the duties of the Commission.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) CONFIRMATION OF EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR.--The employment of an executive director shall be subject to confirmation by the Commission.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) COMPENSATION.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) IN GENERAL.--Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the chairperson of the Commission may fix the compensation of the executive director and other personnel without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5, United States Code, relating to classification of positions and General Schedule pay rates.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) MAXIMUM RATE OF PAY.--The rate of pay for the executive director and other personnel shall not exceed the rate payable for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of title 5, United States Code.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) DETAIL OF GOVERNMENT AND LAKE CHAMPLAIN BASIN PROGRAM EMPLOYEES.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) FEDERAL EMPLOYEES.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) IN GENERAL.--At the request of the Commission, the head of any Federal agency may detail, on a reimbursable or nonreimbursable basis, any of the personnel of the agency to the Commission to assist the Commission in carrying out the duties of the Commission under this Act.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) CIVIL SERVICE STATUS.--The detail of an employee under clause (i) shall be without interruption or loss of civil service status or privilege.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) STATE EMPLOYEES.--The Commission may--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) accept the services of personnel detailed from States (including subdivisions of States); and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) reimburse States for services of detailed personnel.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) LAKE CHAMPLAIN BASIN PROGRAM EMPLOYEES.--The Commission may--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) accept the services of personnel from the Lake Champlain Basin Program; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) reimburse the Lake Champlain Basin Program for services of detailed personnel.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) VOLUNTEER AND UNCOMPENSATED SERVICES.--Notwithstanding section 1342 of title 31, United States Code, the Commission may accept and use voluntary and uncompensated services as the Commission determines necessary.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (6) SUPPORT SERVICES.--The Director of the National Park Service shall provide to the Commission, on a reimbursable basis, such administrative support services as the Commission may request.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (f) Procurement of Temporary and Intermittent Services.--Subject to the availability of appropriations, the chairperson of the Commission may procure temporary and intermittent services in accordance with section 3109(b) of title 5, United States Code, at rates for individuals that do not exceed the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay prescribed for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of that title.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (g) FACA Nonapplicability.--Section 14(b) of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) shall not apply to the Commission. &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (h) No Effect on Authority.--Nothing in this section supersedes the authority of the States or the National Park Service concerning the commemoration.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) Termination.--The Commission shall terminate on December 31, 2010, and shall transfer all documents and materials of the Commission to the National Archives or other appropriate Federal entity.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 203. AUDIT OF COMMISSION.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; The Inspector General of the Department of the Interior shall perform an annual audit of the Commission, shall make the results of the audit available to the public, and shall transmit such results to the Committee on Government Reform of the House of Representatives.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 204. AUTHORIZATION OF APPROPRIATIONS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; There is authorized to be appropriated $500,000 for each of fiscal years 2007 through 2011 to carry out this title, of which--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) 45 percent shall be for New York activities relating to the Samuel de Champlain commemoration;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) 45 percent shall be for Vermont activities relating to the Samuel de Champlain commemoration; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) 10 percent shall be for distribution by the Commission in accordance with this Act for activities relating to the commemoration.</narrative>
  <narrative>SEC. 301. DEFINITIONS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; In this title:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) COMMEMORATION.--The term "commemoration" means the commemoration of--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) the 200th anniversary of Robert Fulton's voyage in the CLERMONT; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) the 400th anniversary of Henry Hudson's voyage in the HALF MOON.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) COMMISSION.--The term "Commission" means the Hudson-Fulton 400th Commemoration Commission established by section 302(a).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) GOVERNOR.--The term "Governor" means the Governor of the State of New York.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) SECRETARY.--The term "Secretary" means the Secretary of the Interior.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) STATE.--The term "State"--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) means the State of New York; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) includes agencies and entities of each such State.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 302. HUDSON-FULTON 400TH COMMEMORATION COMMISSION.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) In General.--The Secretary shall establish a commission to be known as the "Hudson-Fulton 400th Commemoration Commission".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Membership.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) IN GENERAL.--The Commission shall be composed of 16 members, of whom--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) 1 member shall be appointed by the Secretary, after consideration of the recommendation of the Governor;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) 6 members shall be appointed by the Secretary, after consideration of the recommendations from the Members of the House of Representatives whose districts encompass the Hudson River Valley;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) 2 members shall be appointed by the Secretary, after consideration of the recommendations from the Members of the Senate from New York;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (D) 2 members shall be employees of the National Park Service, of whom--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) one shall be the Director of the National Park Service (or a designee of the Director); and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) one shall be an employee of the National Park Service having experience relevant to the commemoration, who shall be appointed by the Secretary;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (E) 2 members shall be appointed by the Secretary from among individuals who have an interest in, demonstrated their support for, and demonstrated expertise appropriate to, the commemoration, of whom--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) one shall be knowledgeable of the Hudson River Valley National Heritage Area; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) one shall be knowledgeable of New York City as it relates to the commemoration;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (F) one member shall be the chairperson of any commemorative commission formed by New York, or the designee of the chairperson; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (G) two members shall be appointed by the Secretary, after consideration of the recommendation of the mayor of the City of New York and after consultation with Members of the House of Representatives whose districts encompass the City of New York.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) TERM; VACANCIES.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) TERM.--Each member of the Commission shall be appointed for the life of the Commission.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) VACANCIES.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) IN GENERAL.--A vacancy on the Commission shall be filled in the same manner in which the original appointment was made.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) PARTIAL TERM.--A member appointed to fill a vacancy on the Commission shall serve for the remainder of the term for which the predecessor of the member was appointed.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) MEETINGS.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) IN GENERAL.--The Commission shall meet--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) at least twice each year; or&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) at the call of the chairperson or the majority of the members of the Commission.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) INITIAL MEETING.--Not later than 30 days after the date on which all members of the Commission have been appointed, the Commission shall hold the initial meeting of the Commission.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) CHAIRPERSON AND VICE CHAIRPERSON.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) IN GENERAL.--The Commission shall elect the chairperson and the vice chairperson of the Commission on an annual basis.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) VICE CHAIRPERSON.--The vice chairperson shall serve as the chairperson in the absence of the chairperson.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) QUORUM.--A majority of voting members shall constitute a quorum, but a lesser number may hold meetings.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (6) VOTING.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) IN GENERAL.--The Commission shall act only on an affirmative vote of a majority of the voting members of the Commission.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) NONVOTING MEMBER.--The individual appointed under subparagraph (D)(ii) of paragraph (1) shall be a nonvoting member, and shall serve only in an advisory capacity.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Duties.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) IN GENERAL.--The Commission shall--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) plan, develop, and execute programs and activities appropriate to commemorate the 400th anniversary of the voyage of Henry Hudson, the first European to sail up the Hudson River, and the 200th anniversary of the voyage of Robert Fulton, the first person to use steam navigation on a commercial basis;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) facilitate Hudson-Fulton-related activities throughout the United States;</narrative>
  <narrative> (C) coordinate its activities with the State commemoration commission and appropriate Federal Government agencies, including the Departments of Agriculture, Defense, State, and Transportation, the National Park Service with respect to the Hudson River Valley National Heritage Area, and the American Heritage Rivers Initiative Interagency Committee established by Executive Order 13061, dated September 11, 1997, the National Endowment for the Humanities and the National Endowment for the Arts,  and the Smithsonian Institution;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (D) encourage civic, patriotic, historical, educational, artistic, religious, economic, and other organizations throughout the United States to organize and participate in anniversary activities to expand the understanding and appreciation of the significance of the voyages of Henry Hudson and Robert Fulton;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (E) provide technical assistance to States, localities, and nonprofit organizations to further the commemoration;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (F) coordinate and facilitate for the public scholarly research on, publication about, and interpretation of, the voyages of Henry Hudson and Robert Fulton;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (G) ensure that the Hudson-Fulton 2009 commemorations provide a lasting legacy and long-term public benefit by assisting in the development of appropriate programs and facilities; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (H) assist in ensuring that the observances of the voyage of Henry Hudson are inclusive and appropriately recognize the experiences and heritage of all people present when Henry Hudson sailed the Hudson River.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) STRATEGIC PLAN AND ANNUAL PERFORMANCE PLANS.--The Commission shall prepare a strategic plan in accordance with section 306 of title 5, United States Code, and annual performance plans in accordance with section 1115 of title 31, United States Code, for the activities of the Commission carried out under this Act.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) REPORTS.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) ANNUAL REPORT.--The Commission shall submit to the Congress an annual report that contains a list of each gift, bequest, or devise with a value of more than $250, together with the identity of the donor of each such gift, bequest, or devise.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) FINAL REPORT.--Not later than September 30, 2010, the Commission shall submit to the Secretary a final report that contains--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) a summary of the activities of the Commission;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) a final accounting of funds received and expended by the Commission; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (iii) the findings and recommendations of the Commission.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (d) Powers of the Commission.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) IN GENERAL.--The Commission may--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) solicit, accept, use, and dispose of gifts, bequests, or devises of money or other real or personal property for the purpose of aiding or facilitating the work of the Commission;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) appoint such advisory committees as the Commission determines to be necessary to carry out this Act;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) authorize any member or employee of the Commission to take any action that the Commission is authorized to take by this Act;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (D) subject to the availability of appropriations, procure supplies, services, and property, and make or enter into contracts, leases, or other legal agreements, to carry out this Act except that any contracts, leases, or other legal agreements made or entered into by the Commission shall not extend beyond the date of the termination of the Commission;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (E) use the United States mails in the same manner and under the same conditions as other Federal agencies;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (F) subject to approval by the Commission and the availability of appropriations, make grants in amounts not to exceed $20,000 to communities, nonprofit organizations, and commemorative commissions formed by the State to develop programs to assist in the commemoration;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (G) subject to the availability of appropriations, make grants in amounts not to exceed  $20,000 to research and scholarly organizations to research, publish, or distribute information relating to the early history of the voyages of Hudson and Fulton; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (H) provide technical assistance to the State, localities, and nonprofit organizations to develop programs and facilities to further the commemoration.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (e) Commission Personnel Matters.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) COMPENSATION OF MEMBERS OF THE COMMISSION.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) IN GENERAL.--Except as provided in subparagraph (B), a member of the Commission shall serve without compensation.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) FEDERAL EMPLOYEES.--A member of the Commission who is an officer or employee of the Federal Government shall serve without compensation in addition to the compensation received for the services of the member as an officer or employee of the Federal Government.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) TRAVEL EXPENSES.--A member of the Commission shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for an employee of an agency under subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5, United States Code, while away from the home or regular place of business of the member in the performance of the duties of the Commission.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) STAFF.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) IN GENERAL.--The chairperson of the Commission may, without regard to the civil service laws (including regulations), appoint and terminate an executive director and such other additional personnel as are necessary to enable the Commission to perform the duties of the Commission.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) CONFIRMATION OF EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR.--The employment of an executive director shall be subject to confirmation by the Commission.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) COMPENSATION.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) IN GENERAL.--Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the chairperson of the Commission may fix the compensation of the executive director and other personnel without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5, United States Code, relating to classification of positions and General Schedule pay rates.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) MAXIMUM RATE OF PAY.--The rate of pay for the executive director and other personnel shall not exceed the rate payable for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of title 5, United States Code.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) DETAIL OF GOVERNMENT EMPLOYEES.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) FEDERAL EMPLOYEES.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) IN GENERAL.--At the request of the Commission, the head of any Federal agency may detail, on a reimbursable or nonreimbursable basis, any of the personnel of the agency to the Commission to assist the Commission in carrying out the duties of the Commission under this Act.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) CIVIL SERVICE STATUS.--The detail of an employee under clause (i) shall be without interruption or loss of civil service status or privilege.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) STATE EMPLOYEES.--The Commission may--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) accept the services of personnel detailed from the State (including subdivisions of the State); and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) reimburse the State for services of detailed personnel.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) VOLUNTEER AND UNCOMPENSATED SERVICES.--Notwithstanding section 1342 of title 31, United States Code, the Commission may accept and use voluntary and uncompensated services as the Commission determines necessary.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (6) SUPPORT SERVICES.--The Director of the National Park Service shall provide to the Commission, on a reimbursable basis, such administrative support services as the Commission may request.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (f) Procurement of Temporary and Intermittent Services.--Subject to the availability of appropriations, the chairperson of the Commission may procure temporary and intermittent services in accordance with section 3109(b) of title 5, United States Code, at rates for individuals that do not exceed the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay prescribed for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of that title.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (g) FACA Nonapplicability.--Section 14(b) of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) shall not apply to the Commission.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (h) No Effect on Authority.--Nothing in this section supersedes the authority of the States or the National Park Service concerning the commemoration.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) Termination.--The Commission shall terminate on December 31, 2010, and shall transfer all documents and materials of the Commission to the National Archives or other appropriate Federal entity.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 303. AUDIT OF COMMISSION.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; The Inspector General of the Department of the Interior shall perform an annual audit of the Commission, shall make the results of the audit available to the public, and shall transmit such results to the Committee on Government Reform of the House of Representatives.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 304. AUTHORIZATION OF APPROPRIATIONS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; There is authorized to be appropriated $500,000 for each of fiscal years 2007 through 2011 to carry out this title, of which--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) 80 percent shall be for Hudson Valley activities relating to the commemoration;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) 10 percent shall be for New York City activities relating to the commemoration; and</narrative>
  <narrative> (3) 10 percent shall be for distribution by the Commission in accordance with this Act for activities relating to the commemoration.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Davis) and the gentlewoman from Illinois (Mrs. Biggert) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Illinois.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days in which to revise and extend their remarks.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Illinois?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, as a Member of the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, I am pleased to join my colleague in the consideration of <bill type="h" number="1520">H.R. 1520</bill>, a bill to establish the Champlain Quadricentennial Commemoration Commission and the Hudson-Fulton 400th Commemoration Commission. <bill type="h" number="1520">H.R. 1520</bill> was introduced by Representative Maurice Hinchey on March 14, 2007. This legislation was reported from the Oversight and Government Reform Committee on July 19, 2007, by voice vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, Henry Hudson was hired by the Dutch East India company to try to find the Northwest Passage. On this trip in a ship called the Half Moon, Mr. Hudson sailed to Nova Scotia and then sailed south. In 1609, he found what is now called the Hudson River. Also in 1609, a French explorer, Samuel de Champlain, was exploring Lake Champlain, as well as the shore of northern New York and Vermont.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These voyages were two of the most significant passages in the European exploration and discovery of America. They led to the establishment of a Dutch settlement of what is now the capital city of the State of New York. Also, it led to the establishment of French trading posts, military posts and settlements as far south as Lake George. These settlements had a great influence on our Nation's history, culture, law, and commerce.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1807, Robert Fulton navigated the Hudson River from the city of New York to Albany in a steamboat which successfully began the use of steam navigation on a commercial basis. It revolutionized waterborne commerce on the great rivers of the United States and fostered international relations through transoceanic travel and trade.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Hudson-Fulton-Champlain Quadricentennial Commemoration Act of 2007 establishes two commissions that would ensure a national observance of the Henry Hudson, Robert Fulton, and Samuel de Champlain 2009 commemorations through cooperation with the assistance to the programs and activities of New York, Vermont, and the commemorative commissions formed by these States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I commend my colleague, Representative Maurice Hinchey, for introducing this legislation, and I urge its swift passage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400027" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, <bill type="h" number="1520">H.R. 1520</bill> establishes two important and historically based commissions. One commission recognizes the explorations of Henry Hudson and Robert Fulton in New York and Vermont, and the other recognizes Samuel de Champlain's discoveries in the same region. The overall goal of the Hudson-Fulton 400th Commemoration Commission is to plan, develop, and perform activities to commemorate the 400th anniversary of Henry Hudson's voyage on the New York river named in his honor and the 200th anniversary  of Robert Fulton's voyage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1609, Englishman Henry Hudson, under the direction of the Dutch East India Company, was named the first European to sail up the river later to be named for him and his significant exploration. In 1807, Robert Fulton's breakthrough use of commercial steam navigation revolutionized water-based commerce, naval warfare, and international relations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It was these important expeditions which brought about the earliest encounters of Native Americans and Europeans. These voyages introduced new methods of commerce and trade and also introduced new religious beliefs,  cultural exchange, and traditions which extend into the present day. Together, these two historic events will be celebrated through the creation of the Hudson-Fulton 400th Commemoration Commission. The same year of Hudson's exploration,  Francis Samuel de Champlain became the first European to discover the New York lake later to be named in his honor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Champlain Quadricentennial Commemoration Commission will coordinate its festivities and celebrations with the Hudson-Fulton Commission. These commissions promote continued education and observations of historic events such as these which have helped to make our country what it is today. They influence the culture, heritage, and way of life for all early citizens of America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support the passage of <bill type="h" number="1520">H.R. 1520</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400264" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in strong support of <bill type="h" number="1520">H.R. 1520</bill>, the Hudson-Fulton-Champlain Quadricentennial Commemoration Act of 2007. I am proud to be an original cosponsor of this legislation, which I have been working with the Gentleman from New York, Mr. Hinchey, since 2003 to enact. In fact, the House previously passed our bill, <bill type="h" number="2528">H.R. 2528</bill>, by voice vote during the 108th Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill, <bill type="h" number="1520">H.R. 1520</bill>, before the House today would authorize $500,000 annually from fiscal year 2007 through fiscal year 2011 for the Champlain Quadricentennial Commemoration Commission, to plan and execute programs and activities to commemorate the 400th anniversary of Samuel de Champlain's voyage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Likewise, <bill type="h" number="1520">H.R. 1520</bill> would also authorize $500,000 annually from fiscal year 2007 through fiscal year 2011 for a second commission, the Hudson-Fulton 400th Commemoration Commission, to plan and execute programs and activities to commemorate the 400th anniversary of Henry Hudson's voyage, as well as the 200th anniversary of Robert Fulton's invention of the steamboat.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Samuel de Champlain, the "Father of New France," explored a great deal New York's 23rd Congressional District. In fact, he discovered Lake Champlain in 1609 and traveled extensively on the St. Lawrence River. Thus, my constituents in Northern New York, particularly those in Clinton County, have a keen interest in <bill type="h" number="1520">H.R. 1520</bill>, particularly its potential to enhance tourism.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thus, I greatly appreciate the work the Gentleman from New York, Mr. Hinchey, the Gentleman from California, Mr. Waxman, and the Gentleman from Virginia, Mr. Davis, have done to bring <bill type="h" number="1520">H.R. 1520</bill> to the House floor and I urge my colleagues to vote for it today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412222" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today to express my strong support for the Hudson-Fulton-Champlain Quadricentennial Commemoration Act of 2007, which will simultaneously pay homage to the history of New York's Hudson Valley while helping to build a vibrant future for the region.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to thank my colleague, Representative Hinchey, for his leadership in drafting and introducing this important piece of legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the Hudson Valley has been a cradle of prosperity and a driver of growth and exploration in America since long before there was a United States of America. The character of the region, and the history of the nation, was strongly shaped by two separate voyages that occurred almost 400 years ago.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In July of 1609, the French explorer Samuel de Champlain, having already founded the settlement of Quebec, arrived with a group of Native Americans at what would eventually be known as Lake Champlain. This expedition would lay the groundwork for the settlement of the Champlain valley by French colonists in the "New World".</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The next month, Henry Hudson would begin the voyage aboard that Half Moon that would bring him into New York under the Dutch flag. His efforts to find a sea route to Asia on behalf of the Dutch East India Company travels would eventually take him up what is now the Hudson River almost to Albany. Hudson was to be the first European explorer to navigate and note the full length of the Hudson River, and along the way he noted the region's inherent beauty and engaged in trade with Native Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By laying the groundwork for settlement and commerce in the region, these voyages would help establish a corridor for trade that helped to drive the prosperity of the "New World" and continues to be an economic engine of America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Two centuries after those fateful journeys, the region was once again home to a breakthrough that would transform commerce and transportation throughout the continent. On August 17, 1807 Robert Fulton successfully sailed his steamboat from New York City to Albany in the first long-distance trip of such a vessel. This 32-hour long trip opened the gateway to a new means of trade and transportation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Hudson-Fulton-Champlain Quadricentennial Commemoration Act of 2007 will make sure that these events, and their contribution to the greatness of our nation, will be appropriately honored. By establishing the Champlain Quadricentennial Commemoration Commission the Hudson-Fulton 400th Commemoration Commission to plan and execute commemorative activities in the region, the bill honors the storied past of the Hudson Valley, will bring increased prosperity to the region, and perhaps open the door  to the Corridor's next great adventure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Davis) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="1520">H.R. 1520</bill>.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the bill was passed.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
