<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1185768000" ordinal="39" title="HONORING THE 2007 NBA CHAMPION SAN ANTONIO SPURS">
  <narrative>HONORING THE 2007 NBA CHAMPION SAN ANTONIO SPURS -- (House of Representatives - July 30, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H8840]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform be discharged from further consideration of the resolution (<bill type="hr" number="490">H. Res. 490</bill>) honoring the 2007 NBA Champion San Antonio Spurs, and ask for its immediate consideration in the House.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the resolution.</narrative>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Illinois?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the resolution, as follows</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="hr" number="490">H. Res. 490</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas on June 14, 2007, the San Antonio Spurs won the 2007 National Basketball Association (NBA) Championship with a victory over the Cleveland Cavaliers;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Spurs' win results in their fourth NBA Championship in the last 9 years;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Spurs, after sweeping the Cavaliers to decisively win the Finals 4-0, are widely recognized as a modern-day basketball dynasty;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas San Antonio's four-game sweep was only the eighth sweep since the finals began in 1947;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Spurs' .727 winning percentage is the highest in finals history;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas under the leadership and instruction of Coach Gregg Popovich, the Spurs' Tony Parker, Tim Duncan, Manu Ginobili, Robert Horry, Bruce Bowen, Michael Finley, Fabricio Oberto, Francisco Elson, Jacque Vaughn, and Brent Barry played together as a team with determination and resolve to bring the NBA trophy back home to the Alamo City;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Tony Parker was named the Finals Most Valuable Player after using his speed and quickness to average 24.5 points and an amazing 57 percent from the field during the Finals, becoming the first European-born player to be honored as MVP;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Tim Duncan and Bruce Bowen anchored the Spurs with stifling defense throughout the NBA Finals;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Manu Ginobili used his pinpoint three-point shooting and strong drives to the basket to lead the Spurs to victory in Game 4 with 27 points;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Coach Gregg Popovich is recognized as one of the greatest coaches of all time after winning his fourth NBA Championship; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas San Antonio has the best fans in the league and the Alamo City is the perfect setting for a championship celebration: Now, therefore, be it</narrative>
  <narrative> Resolved, &lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; That the House of Representatives congratulates the San Antonio Spurs and Coach Gregg Popovich for winning the 2007 National Basketball Association Championship.&lt;ul&gt;</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on June 14, 2007, the San Antonio Spurs won the 2007 National Basketball Association (NBA) Championship with a victory over the Cleveland Cavaliers. This was the Spurs fourth NBA Championship in the last 9 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I join all my colleagues in congratulating the San Antonio Spurs and Coach Gregg Popovich for winning the 2007 National Basketball Association Championship.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The resolution was agreed to.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
