<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1209657603" ordinal="36" title="ON THE RETIREMENT OF MARK O'SULLIVAN">
  <narrative>ON THE RETIREMENT OF MARK O'SULLIVAN -- (House of Representatives - May 01, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H2992]</narrative>
  <narrative>(Mr. HOYER asked and was given permission to address the House for 1 minute.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400189" topic="">
    <paragraph>Ladies and gentlemen of the House, many of you have heard me, and Mr. Dreier as well, over the years speak to how extraordinarily advantaged we are in the House of Representatives, and the American people are, by the quality and commitment of the staff that serves this institution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It doesn't serve Republicans or Democrats, but it serves the purposes of assuring that this institution runs in a way that gets the business of the American people done in a way that's productive and positive for them and for our country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Regretfully, I am going to observe the retirement of one of those people. Happily, I can extol his virtues. I've known him for a very long period of time. I've seen his work, conscientious, able, and a very positive impact on this institution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mark O'Sullivan, who is sitting just to my left on the second-level rostrum, has been with us 31 years in the House, and he commutes from Baltimore every day. I don't know whose district he is in, maybe Mr. Cummings' or Mr. Ruppersberger's. I'm not sure whose district he is in, but I'm sure they are happy that he is living there, although he's totally bipartisan, I'm sure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He has done an outstanding job. I have always found him to be in even humor, even in the toughest of times. Even in the times when the body sometimes gets more loud and uproarious than at other times, he maintains an even demeanor. And, as I say, the competency and the talent and the commitment and the character he has brought to his job has advantaged our country and the House of Representatives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mark, we thank you. Congratulations to you. We wish you the very best, and we look forward to seeing you back here in the near future and repeating it.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
