<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1184558400" ordinal="21" title="DR. KARL E. CARSON POST OFFICE BUILDING">
  <narrative>DR. KARL E. CARSON POST OFFICE BUILDING -- (House of Representatives - July 16, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H7797]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="2570">H.R. 2570</bill>) to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 301 Boardwalk Drive in Fort Collins, Colorado, as the "Dr. Karl E. Carson Post Office Building".</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="2570">H.R. 2570</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. DR. KARL E. CARSON POST OFFICE BUILDING.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Designation.--The facility of the United States Postal Service located at 301 Boardwalk Drive in Fort Collins, Colorado, shall be known and designated as the "Dr. Karl E. Carson Post Office Building".</narrative>
  <narrative> (b) References.--Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the facility referred to in subsection (a) shall be deemed to be a reference to the "Dr. Karl E. Carson Post Office Building".&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Davis) and the gentleman from Utah (Mr. Cannon) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Illinois.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days in which to revise and extend their remarks.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Illinois?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, as a member of the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, I am pleased to join my colleague in the consideration of <bill type="h" number="2570">H.R. 2570</bill>, which names a postal facility in Fort Collins, Colorado, after Dr. Karl E. Carson. <bill type="h" number="2570">H.R. 2570</bill>, which was introduced by Representative Marilyn Musgrave on June 5, 2007, was reported from the Oversight Committee on June 12, 2007, by a voice vote. This measure has the support of the entire Colorado congressional delegation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dr. Karl E. Carson served in the U.S. Navy Reserve during World War II. He was a communications officer on the USS Strive, a minesweeper. Following his military service, he attended the University of Nebraska and received his doctor of dental surgery degree in 1951. Dr. Carson started his dental practice in 1954. His practice thrived and continued until his retirement in 1994.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1991, the Colorado Dental Association gave him its Distinguished Service Award. Dr. Carson was a member of the Fort Carson City Council from 1975 until 1973. He held the city's top post, mayor, for 5 years, from 1968 to 1973.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I commend my colleague, Representative Marilyn Musgrave, for introducing this legislation and urge the swift passage of this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, Dr. Karl Carson, a father, musician and public servant, led an honorable life of community service. Over the years the tremendous contributions he made to the City of Fort Collins, Colorado, certainly merit the naming of a post office in his honor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dr. Karl Carson was born in 1915 in Wichita, Kansas. He was raised on a dairy farm and milked cows each day before leaving for school. While in high school, he met his wife Wilma Schull, with whom he had five children. Dr. Carson demonstrated a deep devotion to his family as a loving husband, father and grandfather.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He attended Fort Collins State University in Kansas on a music scholarship and paid for his education by singing at weddings and other social occasions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After graduating, he served honorably in the U.S. Navy Reserve during World War II as a communications officer aboard the USS Strive. This service marked the beginning of a lifetime of serving his community and country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After the conclusion of his military service, Dr. Carson received a doctorate degree in dental surgery from the University of Nebraska. In 1954, he moved to Fort Collins, Colorado, with his family and established his own dental practice. Dr. Carson enjoyed a successful 43-year long dental career. He was recognized for his excellence in dentistry by the Colorado Dental Association in 1991 with a Distinguished Service Award.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1965, Dr. Carson began his noteworthy career of public service as a member of the Fort Collins City Council. He was subsequently elected by the City Council to be mayor in 1968.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>During his mayoral term, he initiated a program called Designing Tomorrow Today, which was the catalyst for building the downtown library, city hall and the Lincoln Center. Dr. Carson also regarded his support of adding fluoride to Fort Collins water supply as one of his greatest achievements.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dr. Carson will be remembered for his legendary record of community service. Beyond serving as the director of downtown Fort Collins development, the Colorado League of Cities and President of the Colorado Municipal League, he was a member of the Kiwanis Club for over 60 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Regarded by many of the fathers of Fort Collins, Dr. Karl Carson undoubtedly left his mark on the Colorado community. Let us recognize his legacy of community service and devotion to family by naming this post office in his honor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I urge the passage of <bill type="h" number="2570">H.R. 2570</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield such time as she may consume to the gentlewoman from Colorado (Mrs. Musgrave).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400287" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I rise today to speak on behalf of <bill type="h" number="2570">H.R. 2570</bill>, to designate the post office building at 301 Boardwalk Drive in Fort Collins, Colorado, as the Dr. Karl E. Carson Post Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I am pleased to have the opportunity to honor a man who has given so much to the Fort Collins community. He was quoted in 2005 saying that he lived life by a simple pledge: "I hope when I leave this place, I contributed to making it a better place."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>His legacy in Fort Collins was indeed a life of community service and devotion to his family. Dr. Carson passed away in February of this year, and I think it would be safe to say that Fort Collins was a better place because of Dr. Carson's service to this community.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Karl was born on September 27, 1915, in Wichita, Kansas, to Daniel and Clara Helfrick Carson. He was raised on the family dairy farm, and every day before he went to school he milked cows and bottled milk. In high school, he met his lifelong sweetheart, Wilma Schull, and they married on August 23, 1936. To this union, five children were born: Allen, James, Daniel, Thomas and LuAnn. The Carsons also had eight grandchildren and four great grandchildren.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Karl Carson attended Fort Hays State University in Kansas on a music scholarship, and he paid his way through college by singing at weddings and parties.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>He served in the United States Navy Reserve during World War II. He was a communication officer on the USS Strive, a mine sweeper.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Following his military service, Mr. Carson attended the University of Nebraska and received his Doctor of Dental Surgery degree in 1951. The Carson family moved to Fort Collins where Dr. Carson started his dental practice in  1954. His practice thrived and continued until retirement in 1994. Amazingly, for 30 of those 43 years he practiced dentistry with his son, Tom. In 1991, the Colorado Dental Association gave him its Distinguished Service Award.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dr. Carson was a member of the Fort Collins City Council from 1965 to 1973. He held the city's top post, mayor, for five terms, from 1968 to 1973 at a time when the city council elected the mayor. And he considered his support of adding fluoride to the Fort Collins water supply one of his greatest achievements. During his tenure, he started a program called Designing Tomorrow Today, which led to the construction of the Lincoln Center, city hall, and the downtown library.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dr. Carson's community service is legendary. He was the director of downtown Fort Collins development, President of the Colorado Municipal League and the Colorado League of Cities. He was also a member of Kiwanis since 1938. Continuing his love of music and youth, he lent his expertise to participants in the Kiwanis annual Stars of Tomorrow Talent Show.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, Dr. Karl Carson indeed fulfilled his legacy of leaving Fort Collins and this world a better place. The citizens of Fort Collins, Colorado, will never forget him. He was a man of love and commitment to his family and community. Upon hearing of his death in February of this year, the current mayor of Fort Collins, Doug Hutchinson, called Dr. Carson a "City Father."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to join me in recognizing Dr. Karl Carson for his many contributions to the Fort Collins community by supporting this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I urge passage of this legislation, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Davis) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="2570">H.R. 2570</bill>.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the bill was passed.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
