<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1193241604" ordinal="43" title="STATUS REPORT ON CURRENT SPENDING LEVELS OF ON-BUDGET SPENDING AND REVENUES FOR FY 2007 AND FY 2008 AND THE 5-YEAR PERIOD FY 2007 THROUGH FY 2008">
  <narrative>STATUS REPORT ON CURRENT SPENDING LEVELS OF ON-BUDGET SPENDING AND REVENUES FOR FY 2007 AND FY 2008 AND THE 5-YEAR PERIOD FY 2007 THROUGH FY 2008 -- (House of Representatives - October 24, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H11991]</narrative>
  <chair> Under a previous order of the House, the gentleman from South Carolina (Mr. Spratt) is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400386" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am transmitting a status report on the current levels of on-budget spending and revenues for fiscal years 2007 and 2008 and for the 5-year period of fiscal years 2008 through 2012. This report is necessary to facilitate the application of sections 302 and 311 of the Congressional Budget Act and sections 204, 206 and 207 of <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>, the Concurrent Resolution on the Budget for Fiscal Year 2008.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The term "current level" refers to the amounts of spending and revenues estimated for each fiscal year based on laws enacted or awaiting the President's signature.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The first table in the report compares the current levels of total budget authority, outlays, and revenues with the aggregate levels set by <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>. This comparison is needed to enforce section 311(a) of the Budget Act, which creates a point of order against measures that would breach the budget resolution's aggregate levels.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The second table compares the current levels of discretionary appropriations for fiscal years 2007 and 2008 with the "section 302(b)" suballocations of discretionary budget authority and outlays among Appropriations subcommittees. The comparison is needed to enforce section 302(f) of the Budget Act because the point of order under that section applies to measures that would breach the applicable section 302(b) suballocation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The third table compares the current levels of budget authority and outlays for each authorizing committee with the "section 302(a)" allocations made under <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill> for fiscal years 2007 and 2008 and fiscal years 2008 through 2012. This comparison is needed to enforce section 302(f) of the Budget Act, which creates a point of order against measures that would breach the section 302(a) allocation of new budget authority for the committee that reported the measure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The fourth table gives the current level for fiscal years 2009 and 2010 for accounts identified for advance appropriations under section 206 of <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>. This list is needed to enforce section 206 of the budget resolution, which creates a point of order against appropriation bills that contain advance appropriations that: (i) are not identified in the statement of managers; or (ii) would cause the aggregate amount of such appropriations to exceed the level specified in the resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For purposes of section 311 of the Congressional Budget Act, appropriations bills will generally be scored without regard to levels in the continuing resolution that expire on November 16, 2007. The continuing resolution provides $923,554 million in budget authority on an annualized basis. Thus enactment of measures that provide new budget authority for FY 2008 in excess of $928,523 million (if not already included in the current level estimate) would cause FY 2008 budget authority to exceed  the appropriate level set by <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For purposes of section 311 of the Congressional Budget Act, appropriations bills will generally be scored without regard to levels in the continuing resolution that expire on November 16, 2007. The continuing resolution results in $585,600 million in outlays on an  annualized basis. Thus enactment of measures providing new outlays for FY 2008 in excess of $587,273 million if not already included in the current level estimate) would cause FY 2008 outlays  to exceed the appropriate level set by <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enactment of measures resulting in revenue reduction for FY 2008 in excess of $34,577 million (if not already included in the current estimate) would cause FY 2008 revenue to fall below the appropriate level set by <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enactment of measures resulting in revenue reduction for the period of fiscal years 2008 through 2012 in excess of $176,017 million (if not already included in the current level estimate) would cause revenues to fall below the appropriate levels set by <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>&lt;pre&gt;--&lt;/pre&gt;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>CONGRESSIONAL BUDGET OFFICE,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>U.S. CONGRESS,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington, DC, October 24, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR MR. CHAIRMAN: The enclosed report shows the effects of Congressional action on the fiscal year 2007 budget and is current through October 1, 2007. This report is submitted under section 308(b) and in aid of section 311 of the Congressional Budget Act, as amended.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The estimates of budget authority, outlays, and revenues are consistent with the technical and economic assumptions of <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>, the Concurrent Resolution on the Budget for Fiscal Year 2008, as approved by the Senate and the House of Representatives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Pursuant to section 204(b) of <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>, provisions designated as emergency requirements are exempt from enforcement of the budget resolution. As a result, the enclosed current level report excludes these amounts (see footnote 1 of the report).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since my last letter to you, dated September 6, 2007, the Congress has cleared and the President has signed the College Cost Reduction and Access Act (Public Law 110-84), which affects budget authority and outlays for fiscal year 2007. (That act also affects spending in subsequent years.)</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Robert A. Sunshine</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enclosure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>U.S. CONGRESS,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>CONGRESSIONAL BUDGET OFFICE,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington, DC, October 24, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR MR. CHAIRMAN: The enclosed report shows the effects of Congressional action on the fiscal year 2008 budget and is current through October 19, 2007. This report is submitted under section 308(b) and in aid of section 311 of the Congressional Budget Act, as amended.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The estimates of budget authority, outlays, and revenues are consistent with the technical and economic assumptions of <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>, the Concurrent Resolution on the Budget for Fiscal Year 2008, as approved by the Senate and the House of Representatives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Pursuant to section 204(b) of <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>, provisions designated as emergency requirements are exempt from enforcement of the budget resolution. As a result, the enclosed current level report excludes these amounts (see footnote 1 of the report).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since my last letter to you, dated September 6, 2007, the Congress has cleared and the President has signed the following acts that affect budget authority, outlays, or revenues for fiscal year 2008: College Cost Reduction and Access Act (Public Law 110-84); Food and Drug Administration Amendments Act of 2007 (Public Law 110-85); an act to extend the trade adjustment assistance program under the Trade Act of 1974 for 3 months (Public Law 110-89); TMA, Abstinence Education, and QI Programs Extension  Act of 2007 (Public Law 110-90); and an act making continuing appropriations for the fiscal year 2008, and for other purposes (Public Law 110-92).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, the Congress has cleared the Water Resources Development Act of 2007 (<bill type="h" number="1495">H.R. 1495</bill>) for the President's signature.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Robert A. Sunshine</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enclosure.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
