<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1193068802" ordinal="23" title="DOUGLAS COUNTY, WASHINGTON, PUD CONVEYANCE ACT">
  <narrative>DOUGLAS COUNTY, WASHINGTON, PUD CONVEYANCE ACT -- (House of Representatives - October 22, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H11789]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="523">H.R. 523</bill>) to require the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain public land located wholly or partially within the boundaries of the Wells Hydroelectric Project of Public Utility District No. 1 of Douglas County, Washington, to the utility district, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="523">H.R. 523</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "Douglas County, Washington, PUD Conveyance Act".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. DEFINITIONS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; In this Act:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) PUBLIC LAND.--The term "public land" means the approximately 622 acres of Federal land managed by the Bureau of Land Management and identified for conveyance on the map prepared by the Bureau of Land Management entitled "Douglas County Public Utility District Proposal" and dated March 2, 2006.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) SECRETARY.--The term "Secretary" means the Secretary of the Interior.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) PUD.--The term "PUD" means the Public Utility District No. 1 of Douglas County, Washington.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) WELLS HYDROELECTRIC PROJECT.--The term "Wells Hydroelectric Project" means Federal Energy Regulatory Commission Project No. 2149.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 3. CONVEYANCE OF PUBLIC LAND, WELLS HYDROELECTRIC PROJECT, PUBLIC UTILITY DISTRICT NO. 1 OF DOUGLAS COUNTY, WASHINGTON.</narrative>
  <narrative> (a) Conveyance Required.--Notwithstanding the land use planning requirements of sections 202 and 203 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (43 U.S.C. 1712, 1713), and notwithstanding section 24 of the Federal Power Act (16 U.S.C. 818) and Federal Power Order for Project 2149, and subject to valid existing rights, if not later than 45 days after the date of completion of the appraisal required under subsection (b), the Public Utility District No. 1 of Douglas County,  Washington, submits to the Secretary of the Interior an offer to acquire the public land for the appraised value, the Secretary shall convey, not later than 30 days after the date of the offer, to the PUD all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the public land.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Appraisal.--Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall complete an appraisal of the public land. The appraisal shall be conducted in accordance with the "Uniform Appraisal Standards for Federal Land Acquisitions" and the "Uniform Standards of Professional Appraisal Practice".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Payment.--Not later than 30 days after the date on which the public land is conveyed under this section, the PUD shall pay to the Secretary an amount equal to the appraised value of the public land as determined under subsection (b).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (d) Map and Legal Descriptions.--As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall finalize legal descriptions of the public land to be conveyed under this section. The Secretary may correct any minor errors in the map referred to in section 2 or in the legal descriptions. The map and legal descriptions shall be on file and available for public inspection in appropriate offices of the Bureau of Land Management.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (e) Costs of Conveyance.--As a condition of conveyance, any costs related to the conveyance under this section shall be paid by the PUD.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (f) Disposition of Proceeds.--The Secretary shall deposit the proceeds from the sale in the Federal Land Disposal Account established by section 206 of the Federal Land Transaction Facilitation Act (43 U.S.C. 2305) to be expended to improve access to public lands administered by the Bureau of Land Management in the State of Washington.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 4. SEGREGATION OF LANDS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Withdrawal.--Except as provided in section 3(a), effective immediately upon enactment of this Act, and subject to valid existing rights, the public land is withdrawn from--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) all forms of entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws, and all amendments thereto;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) location, entry, and patenting under the mining laws, and all amendments thereto; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws, and all amendments thereto.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Duration.--This section expires two years after the date of enactment of this Act or on the date of the completion of the conveyance under section 3, whichever is earlier.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 5. RETAINED AUTHORITY.</narrative>
  <narrative> The Secretary shall retain the authority to place conditions on the license to insure adequate protection and utilization of the public land granted to the Secretary in section 4(e) of the Federal Power Act (16 U.S.C. 797(e)) until the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission has issued a new license for the Wells Hydroelectric Project, to replace the original license expiring May 31, 2012, consistent with section 15 of the Federal Power Act (16 U.S.C. 808).&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) and the gentleman from Texas (Mr. Gohmert) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Arizona.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Arizona?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the Wells Hydroelectric Project, operated by the Public Utility District in Douglas County, provides electricity to approximately 17,000 customers in Washington State. The central feature of the project is a dam on the Columbia River.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The utility district is in the early stages of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission's relicensing process. The project's current license was granted in 1962 and will expire in May 2012. An application for relicensing must be submitted by 2010.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="523">H.R. 523</bill> directs the Secretary of the Interior to sell 662 acres of BLM land within the project boundary to the utility district and requires the district to pay the appraised fair market value of the land.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Importantly, the legislation requires that, even after the conveyance takes place, the Secretary of the Interior will retain authority under the Federal Power Act to place conditions on the utility district's new license, if necessary, to protect the natural resources of the area.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, we have worked closely with the sponsor and our minority colleagues on the Natural Resources Committee to improve this legislation. We thank them for that and appreciate it very much.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400651" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="523">H.R. 523</bill> and yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, I would like to thank Committee Chairman Rahall and Subcommittee Chairman Grijalva for scheduling and for pushing this important legislation. This straightforward bill allows for the conveyance of a few small pieces of public land to the Douglas Public Utility District for fair market value and then dedicates the sales proceeds to improving public access to existing Bureau of Land Management lands in Washington State. This conveyance from one public agency to another  will better facilitate the use of this land.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congressman Doc Hastings is also to be commended for his work. He has worked and pushed, and it's great to see this all coming to fruition. Congressman Hastings is traveling from his district at this time and cannot be here.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400171" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I strongly support <bill type="h" number="523">H.R. 523</bill>, legislation I introduced to convey certain Bureau of Land Management land to the Douglas County Public Utility District in Washington state. The Douglas County PUD operates the Wells Hydropower Project on the Columbia River, in North Central Washington. The PUD manages the Wells Hydroelectric Dam and the associated reservoir for multiple purposes, including power generation, fish and wildlife protection, and recreation. Almost  all of the land encompassing the project area is owned by the PUD, with the exception of several small BLM holdings.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Passing this legislation enables the PUD to manage the project in a far more efficient manner. It also allows the BLM to concentrate its limited resources elsewhere, in areas where there are large contiguous blocks of BLM land. It is clear that we can achieve a better and more efficient management of our resources with this land conveyance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, since the Douglas PUD is a public agency under Washington state law, this conveyance simply moves land from the control of one public agency to the control of another agency. It is also important to note that the Douglas PUD has a stellar reputation as a steward of the environment. They worked diligently with federal and state agencies, tribal governments, and environmental groups to develop a model Habitat Conservation Plan for salmon and steelhead. The PUD also protects other forms  of wildlife and provides public access wherever possible.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As my colleagues may recall, similar legislation passed the House last year under suspension. There is one important addition to the legislation this year. <bill type="h" number="523">H.R. 523</bill> calls for the proceeds of this land sale to be used to improve public access to existing BLM lands in Washington state. I am pleased that I was able to reach a consensus with members of the Natural Resources Committee to ensure that the proceeds from this sale will stay in the state where the land conveyance occurred--my home state  of Washington. I am also pleased to note that these funds will go towards increasing the ability of our constituents to access their public lands.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is my intention to see that these funds go towards projects like the Juniper Dunes Wilderness Area in Washington state. Due to its close proximity to the Tri-Cities, Juniper Dunes is a highly popular recreation area for serious hikers as well as families who are looking for an interesting place to explore with their children. Despite its popularity, it is extremely difficult for the public to visit Juniper Dunes. The Dunes are currently surrounded by private lands. Therefore, in order to visit  the public area, one has to cross private property. <bill type="h" number="523">H.R. 523</bill> gives the BLM the financial resources and the flexibility they need to improve access to Juniper Dunes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, I am pleased that I was able to work with the Resources Committee to include language clarifying that the BLM will retain authority under the Federal Power Act for the current FERC relicensing of the Wells project. This authority will remain with the BLM until a new license is in place, which is expected in 2012.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank my colleagues on the Natural Resources Committee, specifically Chairman Rahall, Ranking Member Young and Subcommittee Chairman Grijalva and Subcommittee Ranking Member Bishop and their staffs for all their hard work on this legislation. <bill type="h" number="523">H.R. 523</bill> will benefit the Douglas County PUD, the BLM as well as improve vitally needed public access throughout Washington state. I urge my colleagues to support this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400651" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="523">H.R. 523</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this motion will be postponed.</chair>
</record>
