<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1211385602" ordinal="9" title="COUNTY PAYMENTS: HOOD RIVER COUNTY, OREGON">
  <narrative>COUNTY PAYMENTS: HOOD RIVER COUNTY, OREGON -- (House of Representatives - May 21, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H4326]</narrative>
  <narrative>(Mr. WALDEN of Oregon asked and was given permission to address the House for 1 minute and to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400419" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, by refusing to renew the county payments program, Congress has broken its promise to rural, timbered America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I've told you in the past about Harney County, a county that has 78 percent of its land mass, the size of New Jersey, all Federally controlled, 70 percent of its road budget affected by this law that has not been reauthorized.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me tell you today about Hood River County, where Congress' failure to act to renew the county timber payments program has forced this county to develop multiple county budgets because we don't know what's going to happen in my home county. One thing is for sure, though, the county annually uses up to $130,000 of Federal forest payments to fund search and rescue operations in the Mount Hood National Forest and Mount Hood itself. You see, Hood River County is responsible for most of the search  and rescue operations on that great mountain, and now those costs will be borne by the county because the Federal Government is shirking its responsibility.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That could change. We could pass <bill type="h" number="3058">H.R. 3058</bill>, a bill to reauthorize county timber payments. It has been on the Union Calendar for 127 days, held hostage by this leadership. The Democratic leadership refuses to bring it up for a vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Make good on the Federal promise. Let us vote on <bill type="h" number="3058">H.R. 3058</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
