<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1185768000" ordinal="57" title="UNDERGROUND RAILROAD EDUCATIONAL AND CULTURAL PROGRAM AUTHORIZATION ACT OF 2007">
  <narrative>UNDERGROUND RAILROAD EDUCATIONAL AND CULTURAL PROGRAM AUTHORIZATION ACT OF 2007 -- (House of Representatives - July 30, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H8882]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400227" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="2707">H.R. 2707</bill>) to reauthorize the Underground Railroad Educational and Cultural Program, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="2707">H.R. 2707</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. UNDERGROUND RAILROAD EDUCATIONAL AND CULTURAL PROGRAM.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Program Established.--The Secretary of Education, in consultation and cooperation with the Secretary of the Interior, is authorized to make grants to one or more nonprofit educational organizations that are established to research, display, interpret, and collect artifacts relating to the history of the Underground Railroad.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Grant Agreement.--Each nonprofit educational organization awarded a grant under this section shall enter into an agreement with the Secretary of Education. Each such agreement shall require the organization--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) to establish a facility to house, display, and interpret the artifacts related to the history of the Underground Railroad, and to make the interpretive efforts available to institutions of higher education that award a baccalaureate or graduate degree;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) to demonstrate substantial private support for the facility through the implementation of a public-private partnership between a State or local public entity and a private entity for the support of the facility, which private entity shall provide matching funds for the support of the facility in an amount equal to 4 times the amount of the contribution of the State or local public entity, except that not more than 20 percent of the matching funds may be provided by the Federal Government;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) to create an endowment to fund any and all shortfalls in the costs of the on-going operations of the facility;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) to establish a network of satellite centers throughout the United States to help disseminate information regarding the Underground Railroad throughout the United States, if such satellite centers raise 80 percent of the funds required to establish the satellite centers from non-Federal public and private sources;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) to establish the capability to electronically link the facility with other local and regional facilities that have collections and programs which interpret the history of the Underground Railroad; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (6) to submit, for each fiscal year for which the organization receives funding under this section, a report to the Secretary of Education that contains--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) a description of the programs and activities supported by the funding;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) the audited financial statement of the organization for the preceding fiscal year;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) a plan for the programs and activities to be supported by the funding as the Secretary may require; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (D) an evaluation of the programs and activities supported by the funding as the Secretary may require.</narrative>
  <narrative> (c) Authorization of Appropriations.--There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $3,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2008 through 2012.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Ohio (Mr. Kucinich) and the gentleman from Delaware (Mr. Castle) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Ohio.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400227" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Ohio?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400227" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in strong support of this important legislation that will reauthorize a competitive grant program administered by the Department of Education to research, display, interpret and collect artifacts relating to the history of the Underground Railroad.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>During one of the darkest eras of American history, a group of courageous Americans, both black and white as well as free and enslaved, bound together to form what would be known as the Underground Railroad. For example, the Father of our Nation, George Washington, complained in 1786 about how one of his runaway slaves was helped by a society of Quakers formed for such purposes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Underground Railroad was a decentralized network of people who helped fugitive slaves escape to the North. The railroad consisted of many individuals who knew only of the local efforts to aid fugitives, and none of the overall operation. Amazingly, the railroad effectively moved hundreds of slaves northward each year. According to one estimate, the South lost 100,000 slaves between 1810 and 1850.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This racially integrated movement to bring about social change has familiar heroes, such as Harriet Tubman, John Rankin and Susan B. Anthony; but there are thousands more who risked their lives to help others escape the clutches of slavery as they fled to the North.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For the slave, escaping to the North was anything but easy. The first step was to escape from the slaveholder. For many slaves, this meant taking great risks while relying on his or her own resources. The fugitives would move at night and travel between 10 and 20 miles to the next station, where they would rest and eat, hiding in barns and other out-of-the-way places. The journey was difficult, but the determination to gain freedom was immense.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Underground Railroad Educational and Cultural Program Act of 2007 would provide competitive grants to nonprofit organizations around the United States to shed light on one of the most important and courageous social movements in our history, while preserving and interpreting artifacts found from this critical era.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Moreover, this important legislation would ensure a strong public/private partnership exists to supplement and leverage Federal resources along with funds collected at the State and local levels. Since 1999, over $15 million has been appropriated to seven different institutions. For example, in my home State of Ohio, the National Underground Railroad Freedom Center has delivered highly interactive learning experiences for over 130,000 school children from around the country. This is an important  effort to educate citizens across the country and around the world about the Underground Railroad movement in America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400070" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="2707">H.R. 2707</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to thank my colleague, Mr. Kucinich, for introducing this bill to ensure that those organizations that work so hard to share the history of the Underground Railroad are able to continue their good works.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Underground Railroad Educational and Cultural Program was created in the 1998 reauthorization of the Higher Education Act to provide grants to nonprofit organizations that provide education about and research into the Underground Railroad. In addition, grants could be used for organizations to collect, display or interpret artifacts relating to the history of the Underground Railroad. For example, the National Underground Railroad Freedom Center, located in Cincinnati, Ohio, houses eight  permanent exhibits and hosts any number of temporary exhibits, including displays, musical programs, and group discussion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Other grantees under this program host tours that try and recreate the journey taken by anyone brave enough to utilize the Underground Railroad and exhibits the detail of the development of the Underground Railroad.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I supported the reauthorization of this program when Republicans brought a complete reauthorization of the Higher Education Act to the House floor last Congress. I had hoped to support this program again in the context of a complete reauthorization of the Higher Education Act again this year. Even though this program is receiving the attention of the Congress now, I hope we can complete the HEA reauthorization bill when we return from the August recess.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe strongly in promoting programs and partnerships to commemorate this time in history and educating the public about the historical significance of the Underground Railroad. The Underground Railroad was very active in the State of Delaware, I might also add. We have many of our own tributes to that in my small State.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this bill</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412010" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I rise today in strong support of H.R 2707, the Underground Railroad Education and Culture Act of 2007. I thank my colleague from Ohio, Mr. KUCINICH as well as Education and Labor Chairman GEORGE MILLER for bringing this important bill to the floor today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, this important bill will provide federal support to programs around the country that educate Americans about the courageous actions undertaken by ordinary people during one of the darkest eras in our history. During times of slavery, these courageous Americans, both Black and White as well as free and under slavery, bound together to form what would be known as the Underground Railroad. This racially integrated movement to bring about social change has familiar heroes such as Harriet  Tubman, John Rankin and Susan B. Anthony, but there are thousands more who risked their lives to help others escape the clutches of slavery as they fled to the North.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The National Underground Railroad Freedom Center, located in my Congressional District in Cincinnati, Ohio has successfully competed for grants under this program to connect the lessons of the past to the struggles for freedom in the current day through an informative educational curricula.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Should the Congress authorize and appropriate funds for this important grant program, educational centers such as the Freedom Center in my District as well as other sites around the country would be eligible to apply for competitive grants to shed light on one of the most important and courageous social movements in our history while preserving and interpreting artifacts found from this critical era.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Moreover, this important legislation would ensure a strong public-private partnership exists to supplement and leverage federal resources along with funds collected at the state and local level.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I want to again thank my colleague from Ohio, Mr. KUCINICH for his leadership in bringing this important bill to the floor. I ask my colleagues to support <bill type="h" number="2707">H.R. 2707</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400333" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker. I rise today in support of <bill type="h" number="2707">H.R. 2707</bill>, Mr. KUCINICH's resolution to reauthorize the Underground Railroad Educational and Cultural Program. I praise the initiative contained in this resolution to point out the historical, cultural, and educational legacy behind the Underground Railroad. It is through that network of tunnels and secret hiding places that many African Americans escaped slavery. As a symbol of freedom, the Underground Railroad deserves greater recognition  and appreciation, regrettably of its artifacts and secrets remain hidden and lost.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have long believed in and fought for more and better education of African American history. Well, an important part of that history is contained in the struggle for freedom that characterized the slave experience. Some would have us believe that slaves passively accepted their captivity in the plantations in the South. The truth is there was an active resistance to slavery; which included periodic uprisings and constant efforts to escape. The full role and extent of the Underground Railroad  has yet to be discovered and remains unknown. The legislation authorizes the Secretary of Education to sponsor studies and make grants for programs that promote knowledge of the Underground Railroad.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With the resources and technology available today, we owe it to the history of African Americans and the history of the United States to study, preserve, and make available to all the hidden secrets of the Underground Railroad. Secret routes and safe houses still remain unknown. Secrets that may remain buried in our backyards.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The establishment of this facility would allow significant missing pieces in African American history to be properly studied and commemorated.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Through the passage of this legislation, the work of the National Park Service and its study of the phenomenon known as the Underground Railroad will be continued. Established by Congress in 1990, the National Park Service has made major progress in learning more about the secret routes and the processes used in escorting these fugitive slaves to freedom. The story is far from well enough known, and the study far from complete. Let us as members of the 110th Congress exhibit the same respect  and appreciation of the Underground Railroad as was shown in 1990.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Please join me in support of <bill type="h" number="2707">H.R. 2707</bill>, as we move further in understanding the whole story and celebrating the legacy of the Underground Railroad.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400070" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400227" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Ohio (Mr. Kucinich) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="2707">H.R. 2707</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the bill, as amended, was passed.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
