<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1181145609" ordinal="44" title="SECURELY PROTECT YOURSELF AGAINST CYBER TRESPASS ACT">
  <speaking speaker="400350" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="964">H.R. 964</bill>) to protect users of the Internet from unknowing transmission of their personally identifiable information through spyware programs, and for other purposes, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Rush) and the gentleman from Florida (Mr. Stearns) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400350" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and to include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Illinois?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400350" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, today the House takes up <bill type="h" number="964">H.R. 964</bill>, the Securely Protect Yourself Against Cyber Trespass Act, or SPY Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill is not unfamiliar to the House of Representatives. Twice this body has passed the SPY Act with overwhelming margins, and it is my hope that today will be the third time. <bill type="h" number="964">H.R. 964</bill> aggressively tackles the problem of "spyware," the insidious software that consumers unwittingly download onto their computers, only to have their personal private information extracted for commercial or fraudulent purposes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the past two Congresses, Mrs. Bono and Mr. Towns introduced the bipartisan SPY Act, and both times the bill enjoyed overwhelming support. This year, Mr. Towns and Mrs. Bono have once again teamed up to introduce the SPY Act as <bill type="h" number="964">H.R. 964</bill>. And on March 15, the Consumer Protection Subcommittee held another legislative hearing on the bill. On May 10, 2007, the Energy and Commerce Committee unanimously reported <bill type="h" number="964">H.R. 964</bill>, the SPY Act, as amended.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="964">H.R. 964</bill> provides a broad regulatory framework that empowers consumers with knowledge and the ability to control what software is installed, and is not installed, on their personal computers. This bill prohibits unfair or deceptive acts and practices related to spyware and creates an "opt in" regime whereby entity cannot execute any program that collects a person's personal information without, first, giving explicit notice to the consumer and second, receiving his or her consent. <bill type="h" number="964">H.R. 964</bill>  provides that the FTC will enforce the SPY Act and will have the authority to impose significant civil penalties. During both the full committee and the subcommittee markups of <bill type="h" number="964">H.R. 964</bill>, I introduced manager's amendments tweaking provisions of the bill, and they were the work product of deliberative bipartisan cooperation. This bill has been thoroughly honed to be effective without being overbearing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the SPY Act is a quality piece of legislation that all Members of the House should enthusiastically support. The full Committee on Energy and Commerce and the subcommittee that I am privileged to chair, the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection, have a long history of bipartisan cooperation, and this bill is an extension of that longstanding tradition.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to vote "yes" on the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400388" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume. Mr. Speaker, I am pleased again, I have been here a number of times, to consider <bill type="h" number="964">H.R. 964</bill>, the SPY Act, a bill which is important to fight Internet privacy. In the past and as we speak on the floor today, this has bipartisan support with bipartisan leadership. It has been offered by my colleague from California, MARY BONO, and my colleague from New York, ED TOWNS. Both of them have worked dutifully to try to pass  this bill. And, unfortunately, the last time we passed it overwhelmingly in the House, it did not get through the Senate; so we are back at it again.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also want to thank the new chairman of the committee that I chaired last year, Mr. Rush, for his commitment to maintaining a bipartisan process in this, and that is why we are here on the floor today. If it hadn't been for the leadership of these individuals combined with what I think is a Federal Trade Commission commitment and the stakeholders in the community in this process, we would not have had a workable legislative solution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I think today that we have to realize that even at the last 11th hour we might have some people who don't totally agree, but I think the bill is a strong bill. It takes a firm and, I think, a fair on balance approach in balancing the need to address bad actors and the need to protect the functions of legitimate business tools.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Both at the committee level and on the floor, we have voted on this spyware before, as I mentioned, three times. Three times we have gone through the process of holding hearings, receiving testimony from many witnesses, listening to the horrors of spyware and how it can be a tool of identity thieves, and we know how identity theft is prevalent today, conducting negotiations, and we have asked for ways to improve the bill. So we have seen support across the board in industry for this bill. We  asked what is the best way to improve this bill. So I think we have worked hard on this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And, my colleagues, I think it is time we move this to the Senate, and if there are any further problems with this bill, we certainly can handle these problems in the conference between the House and the Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, you should realize that there are some in the business community who have raised a 11th hour concern about a specific provision that was added at the full committee markup. Not in our subcommittee, Mr. Speaker, but in our full committee. I have been through seven hearings on the question of privacy on the question of opt in and opt out. I am well aware of the feelings of Members dealing with opt in and opt out, depending upon how you view this process. So I share some of the concerns of  the business community in their 11th hour attempt to bring this to our attention. But the responsibility of continuing to move this process forward, I think, is important. That is why I have decided to vote "yes" today to support this bill. And, hopefully,</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>And we all in Congress here know that sometimes the enemy of the good is the perfect.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So we can solve this issue, I think, to satisfy all interested parties. It is a strong piece of legislation; and I cannot think of a reason why our Senate colleagues should not act on it, also.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, in closing, the SPY Act is a solid consumer protection bill that returns control of personal computers and private information to where it belongs, and that is to the consumer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to vote "yes" on <bill type="h" number="964">H.R. 964</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With that, Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400350" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I am pleased to yield 5 minutes to the gentleman from New York, my colleague, my friend (Mr. Towns).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400409" topic="">
    <paragraph>Thank you very much for yielding time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="964">H.R. 964</bill>, the SPY Act, which would greatly improve the privacy of consumers' online computer use. The time has come for this bill to pass.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A lot of hard work has been put into this legislation. First and foremost, I  would like to commend Congresswoman Mary Bono, the Republican sponsor of the bill. Of course, without her hard work, insight and persistence on this issue, we would not be where we are today. I have been proud to work with her on this bill, and I salute her for all of her efforts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Of course, we have been down this road a few times now with several hearings; and, of course, we passed it before. But this time I think that people realize how important this legislation is, and I do feel that it should go all the way.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also want to commend Chairman Dingell and Ranking Member Barton for their strong commitment to this issue and leadership in getting our bill to the floor. I would like to thank my very good friend, the subcommittee chairman, Chairman Rush of Chicago, Illinois, Ranking Member Stearns, who has been a friend for many, many years as well, for their hard work on this legislation. They have stayed with it and gone through the process over and over again because  they recognize how important this legislation is to our country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, I would like to acknowledge all of the staff for their hard work, especially Consuela Washington and David Cavicke for their hard work and, of course, their suggestions and ideas and recommendations. I would like to just take this opportunity to thank them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is no question that spyware is a serious problem. Spyware software, which is downloaded without a computer owner's knowledge, invades one's privacy by recording and transmitting personal information, monitoring the Web site someone visits, or even stealing documents from an individual's computer. Other programs hijack a computer by changing home pages or forcing a person to click through multiple screens until a spyware program is downloaded.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In fact, problems related to spyware have become so widespread that I cannot run into someone who hasn't been negatively affected by it. This is a big change from when we first began this effort a few years ago. There were only a few people complaining, but now we have a lot of people complaining. Now we know the seriousness of the problem and that we need Federal legislation to safeguard privacy, as well as to ensure the long-term integrity of e-commerce.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today's legislation provides consumers with new tools to protect themselves from unwanted, harmful software. Under the bill, consumers would have to receive a clear and concise warning about the spyware program. Second, consumers would have to provide their affirmative consent before the program could operate on their computer. Finally, Mr. Speaker, consumers must have the option to easily disable any harmful spyware programs to their computer. While some consumers may want to share their information  to receive free games other discount offers, all consumers have the right to make that choice.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, Mr. Speaker, and this time I really mean finally, any time we legislate on highly technical matters there is always a danger of stifling innovation and making the use of legitimate software too burdensome. It is a very difficult tightrope to walk. But I think we have done an excellent job in walking that tightrope.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill addresses many of the concerns raised, while at the same time retaining a meaningful notice and consent regime to protect consumer privacy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Through much hard work, we have carefully crafted a strong bipartisan consumer protection bill, and I would urge my colleagues to support this. This is a quality piece of legislation, and I hope that we are able to move it through both Houses very quickly and that the President would sign it into law.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400388" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 5 minutes to the author of the bill, the gentlelady from California (Mrs. Bono).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400039" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in strong support of <bill type="h" number="964">H.R. 964</bill>, the Securely Protect Yourself Against Cyber Trespass Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When the gentleman from New York and I first introduced the spyware bill in 2003, few people knew what spyware was or how problematic it could be to American citizens; and since that time the online threat of spyware remains. According to a recent Consumer Report survey, spyware and viruses cost American computer users nearly $8 billion over a 2-year period.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Historically, spyware legislation in this House has received strong bipartisan support. Our initial bill in the 108th Congress passed 399-1; and in the 109th Congress, our spyware bill again received overwhelming bipartisan support, garnering over 60 cosponsors and passing the House 393-4.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this Congress, <bill type="h" number="964">H.R. 964</bill>, the Securely Protect Yourself Against Cyber Trespass Act, or SPY Act, has again garnered wide bipartisan support with 41 cosponsors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of the Internet's role in interstate commerce, the need for Federal spyware legislation is clear. We cannot expect online companies to function efficiently when they are faced with a patchwork of State anti-spyware statutes. There needs to be legal uniformity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Additionally, I remain a strong proponent of anti-spyware legislation because I believe consumers should have the final say about what plants itself on their computer, not a third party with potentially conflicting interests. The SPY Act accomplishes this by prohibiting commonly known, unfair or deceptive acts relating to spyware.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="964">H.R. 964</bill> also prohibits the collection of personal information from a computer without notice and consent before the first execution of any information collection program. The bill also requires that the user is able to easily remove or disable the spyware.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also understand there are instances where spyware can be useful. <bill type="h" number="964">H.R. 964</bill> exempts action taken by law enforcement and national security pursuant to warrant, court order or other lawful process, or actions taken in good faith with the user's consent. <bill type="h" number="964">H.R. 964</bill> also protects the developers of anti-spyware software from the threat of serious lawsuits.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Simply stated, this bill works to restore privacy on the home computer, which has become the control center for our business transactions as well as as our personal interactions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, my colleague from New York and I began this effort in 2003; and I thank the gentleman, ED TOWNS, for all of his efforts and for being such a terrific partner in this process. Again, since that time, this effort has received the bipartisan support of the House. It is my hope that the 110th Congress will continue to act in a bipartisan way that passes this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask for the support of my colleagues and hope that once again we can take back our computers so the consumer owns their computer, not a third party. Let's pass the SPY Act, <bill type="h" number="984">H.R. 984</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400350" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400388" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400350" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, as was indicated earlier, this is the third time that this bill has been before this body. It was passed overwhelmingly two times in prior Congresses. We really believe that the third time should be the charm. This bill should pass out of this House with the same kind of margins that it passed out of two previous Congresses, and I would urge my colleagues to vote for this bill once again.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill needs to become law. This bill protects the American consumer. This bill protects the American economy. This is a good bill. It needs to become law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>None of the practices outlawed by section 2 of the bill are "legitimate." As for section 3's consumer notice, consent, identification, and easy disabling requirements, legitimate business practices are exempted by the exceptions in section 3(b)(2) and the limitations in section 5 of the SPY Act. The committee added new rule-making authority to exempt a broad class of entities operating Internet Web sites that collect information if the FTC finds that their notice to consumers is adequate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, we have corrected the bill, made minor tweaking improvements on the bill, and I urge my colleagues to support this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400360" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in strong support of <bill type="h" number="964">H.R. 964</bill>, the Securely Protect Yourself Against Cyber Trespass Act--the SPY Act. It is a strong consumer protection bill, of which I am an original cosponsor, that will help us in the fight against identity theft.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With today's vote, the House will have passed the SPY Act three times. Let's hope that the third time's a charm--and that today's passage means this bill will finally get signed into law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The SPY Act is important because it protects consumers from spyware, the unwanted and sneaky software that is so powerful that it can steal information from, monitor and control others' computers--without the computer's owner even knowing the software has been installed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The SPY Act would put the control of computers back in the hands of consumers--where it belongs. It prohibits indefensible uses of the software, like phishing and logging every keystroke entered, and requires that consumers be notified and opt-in before software is installed on their computers. Furthermore, the SPY Act gives the Federal Trade Commission the additional power it needs to pursue deceptive uses of the software.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe that this bill will go a long way toward protecting consumers from having their valuable and personal information stolen by purveyors of spyware. I am glad that I was part of the bipartisan process that brought this bill to the floor today. I urge my colleagues to support its passage. Thank you.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400154" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in opposition to <bill type="h" number="964">H.R. 964</bill>, the SPY Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The continued growth of the Internet has brought tremendous enhancements to our quality of life--from advances in the delivery of health care, to the ability of consumers to instantaneously conduct transactions online. Increasingly, consumers want a fast connection to the Internet and want the delivery of online services to be seamless and online service providers have invested significant resources to develop software to make their services as safe, reliable and fast as possible.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, as Congress considers legislation to combat spyware, I believe that four overarching principles should guide our efforts. First, we must punish the bad actors, while protecting legitimate online companies. Second, we must not over-regulate, but rather encourage innovative new services and the growth of the Internet. Third, we must not stifle the tree market interactions between consumers and service providers. Fourth, we must target the behavior, not the technology. It is my hope that  any legislation Congress enacts to combat spyware will adhere to these core principles.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On May 23, 2005, the House of Representatives passed legislation, similar to <bill type="h" number="964">H.R. 964</bill>, which sought to solve the spyware problem by targeting the technology, instead of the criminal behavior behind the technology. However, many developments have occurred during the intervening two years which have convinced me that this regulatory approach to combating spyware is even more unwise than previously thought.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For example, just last month, the House Energy and Commerce Committee adopted an amendment to <bill type="h" number="964">H.R. 964</bill> that would have had enormous consequences for the Internet and online innovation. This amendment would have, in part, regulated Internet "cookies" for the first time under the bill. Internet cookies are used by most websites to enhance consumers' experiences with the Internet and to make the Internet more seamless and navigable with fewer stoplights. To make every online company that uses  cookies comply with the notice and consent regime under the bill would have significantly interfered with consumers' Internet experiences. By forcing consumers to click through even more pre-scripted alert messages, this change would have, ironically, exacerbated the likelihood that consumers would become</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Apparently, the Democratic Leadership saw the error in the regulation of cookies and stripped the bill of this language just before the bill came to the Floor today. However, this mistake by the committee highlights the difficulties with trying to impose one-size-fits-all regulations to solve problems involving ever-evolving technologies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, Chairman Majoras of the Federal Trade Commission testified in October of 2005 that a notice-and-choice approach was not recommended for combating spyware for many reasons. He noted the fact that consumers will be overwhelmed by the notices they will receive when using the Internet and will most likely ignore the notices and click through them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Furthermore, in the past few years there have been major developments in technological solutions to help consumers combat spyware. Consumer packages are becoming more and more effective in screening out unwanted spyware from their computers and are offered by many Internet service providers, as well as independent software providers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, a broad cross-section of legitimate online businesses and trade associations has expressed opposition to the regulatory approach of <bill type="h" number="964">H.R. 964</bill>. On June 5, 2007, a coalition of over 30 trade associations and companies, including the U.S. Chamber of Commerce, the National Retail Federation, the Financial Services Roundtable, and numerous technology-based entities, sent a letter to all Members of the House of Representatives detailing their concerns with <bill type="h" number="964">H.R. 964</bill>. This letter specifically  expresses opposition to regulating Internet cookies, as well as opposition to including web sites (where consumers willingly submit information online) within in the scope of the legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The better approach to combating spyware would be to target the criminal behavior of those who actually use spyware, and to continue our policy of letting innovative online companies interact with consumers to develop the exciting new online services that consumers have come to enjoy and expect from the Internet.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have introduced legislation, along with my colleague Zoe Lofgren of California, to combat spyware by going after the criminals using spyware, rather than trying to regulate all software regardless of whether it is harmful or helpful. This legislation, <bill type="h" number="1525">H.R. 1525</bill>, was passed by the House and now awaits further action in the Senate. I urge my colleagues to support this targeted approach.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400018" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the bill we are considering today--the Towns-Bono SPY Act--is an important piece of legislation to me. We've been working on this bill for 4 years now, before many of us ever heard the term "spyware." I applaud the bipartisan sponsors for their unwavering commitment to pass this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The surreptitious installation of spyware on your computer without your knowledge and without your consent is a little like sneaking into your home and planting a bug: it is an invasion of your privacy and it is clearly wrong. This bill prohibits all the nefarious conduct that is used to harm consumers. The legislation provides the FTC a strong mandate to go after bad actors and their destructive behavior.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are many important and legitimate business functions of the Internet, and I have no problem with businesses trying to compete and sell their goods and services. And I recognize advertising is a part of commerce. But I feel strongly that there is a line that should not be crossed regarding the sharing of my personal information without first obtaining my consent. Consumers have the right to know if they are being profiled, if their personal information is going to be shared, and with whom  it might be shared. My computer and my personal information are my property. This legislation will ensure I have control over both.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill strikes a fair balance between the need to protect the functions of legitimate business tools and punishing bad actors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In closing, I want to thank Chairman RUSH, Chairman DINGELL, and Ranking Member STEARNS for moving the bill through the Committee. I commend MARY BONO and ED TOWNS for their tireless efforts to address this insidious activity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge all of my colleagues to vote for this important piece of legislation and hope that our Senate colleagues will do the same.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400350" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Rush) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="964">H.R. 964</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400627" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this question will be postponed.</chair>
</record>
