<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1174320004" ordinal="22" title="MARINE MAMMAL RESCUE ASSISTANCE AMENDMENTS OF 2007">
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="1006">H.R. 1006</bill>) to amend the provisions of law relating to the John H. Prescott Marine Mammal Rescue Assistance Grant Program, and for other purposes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) and the gentleman from Utah (Mr. Bishop) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Arizona?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I commend the ranking Republican on the Committee on Natural Resources, Congressman Don Young, for introducing <bill type="h" number="1006">H.R. 1006</bill>, the Marine Mammal Rescue Assistance Amendments of 2007. The bill would extend through fiscal year 2010 the authorization of appropriations for the John H. Prescott Marine Mammal Rescue Assistance Grant Fund and the Marine Mammal Unusual Mortality Event Fund.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1006">H.R. 1006</bill> would direct the relevant Secretary to collect and update procedures for rescuing and rehabilitating marine mammals entangled in fishing gear, rope, line, net or other material. The bill also authorizes the Secretary to enter into agreements for marine mammal stranding events requiring emergency assistance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the 109th Congress, the House passed a similar provision in <bill type="h" number="4075">H.R. 4075</bill>, by voice vote, on July 17, 2006. We support this bill and commend Congressman Don Young for his leadership on this issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400029" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I rise in strong support of <bill type="h" number="1006">H.R. 1006</bill>, the Marine Mammal Rescue Assistance Act amendments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation, introduced by the distinguished Ranking Republican on the Natural Resources Committee, Don Young, and the ranking Republican on the Fisheries, Wildlife and Oceans Subcommittee, Henry Brown, will extend the John H. Prescott Marine Mammal Rescue Assistance Grant Program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Prescott Grant program was first authorized in 2000 to assist the National Marine Fisheries Service with recovery and rehabilitation of stranded marine mammals. The Prescott Grant program has been very successful in supporting facilities around the Nation which volunteer space and staff time to rehabilitate these sea creatures and return many of them to the wild.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The National Marine Fisheries Service has received $4 million in appropriations each year for the Prescott Marine Mammal Rescue Assistance Grants. In 2006, the Service issued 42 grants to facilities in coastal States. While the Prescott Grant program has been successful in these areas, there are still areas of the country that do not have appropriate coverage; the Alaska region and the Southeast region are two examples.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation will increase funding for the Department of Commerce to address this lack of coverage and will also increase the number of grants that can be issued each year. The legislation will also cap administrative costs and roll over any unused funds into the grant program. The administration will have the authority to enter into cooperative agreements with trained personnel to allow for removal of floating debris from marine mammals to prevent the stranding and/or the death of those  animals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation also authorizes emergency assistance funding. In addition, it will reauthorize funding for the Marine Mammal Unusual Mortality Event Fund, which allows the agency to respond to mass stranding events and reimburse facilities that have assisted in the response activity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is an important conservation bill. I urge an "aye" vote on <bill type="h" number="1006">H.R. 1006</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield back the balance of our time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="1006">H.R. 1006</bill>.</chair>
</record>
