<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1168966803" ordinal="24" title="COMMENDING THE UNIVERSITY OF FLORIDA GATORS FOR THEIR 2006 BOWL CHAMPIONSHIP SERIES VICTORY">
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="SCHULTZ, WASSERMAN" of="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="hr" number="39">H. Res. 39</bill>, the Wasserman Schultz-Stearns resolution commending the University of Florida Fighting Gators for their victory in the 2006 Bowl Championship Series and for winning the national college football title.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, after a hard-fought football season, the Florida Gators proved victorious on January 8 with a dazzling 41-14 triumph over the Ohio State University Buckeyes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While many critics expressed doubt about the Gators' chances for victory, Florida's Congressional Delegation and all of the students, alumni and friends in the Gator Nation stood by the Orange and Blue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Led by senior quarterback Chris Leak, the MVP of the game, and Florida's impenetrable defense, Florida Gators dominated the game when the stakes were the highest.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This season, as Florida's football program celebrated its 100th anniversary, the University of Florida made history by winning national titles in both men's basketball and football in the same season.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congressman Stearns and I would like to extend special congratulations to Florida's head coach, Urban Meyer, who trained this football team to be the best in the country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Florida players, coaches, faculty, students and alumni all pulled together with hard work and dedication to help the team win. All of the student athletes are shining stars for the University, and deserve our highest praise.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Gator Nation's academic reputation is stellar, our sports teams are number one, and our fans are like none other.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, it is great to be a Florida Gator.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
</record>
