<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1186086470" ordinal="24" title="PROVIDING FOR FURTHER CONSIDERATION OF H.R. 3161, AGRICULTURE, RURAL DEVELOPMENT, FOOD AND DRUG ADMINISTRATION, AND RELATED AGENCIES APPROPRIATIONS ACT, 2008">
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DREIER" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself 2 minutes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I want to apologize to the House for calling for the motion to adjourn, and I do so because in 15 minutes a memorial service is going to be held for our former colleague, Guy VanderJagt, over in the Ways and Means Committee room.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And I will say that Guy VanderJagt is someone who served longer in the minority than any Member on the other side of the aisle.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But no one understood about the rights of the minority better than Guy VanderJagt; and I will tell you, Mr. Speaker, those rights are outlined very clearly in the opening of Jefferson's Manual.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, we have been excoriated over the past hour for having used what have been called dilatory tactics 2 days ago before we passed the SCHIP bill. The fact of the matter is that is now ancient history. We have been struggling to ensure that we continue with the debate on this very important bill under an open amendment process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am going to urge my colleagues to defeat the previous question so that we will have the opportunity to table this measure and go back to an open amendment process. Why? Because this rule represents the trifecta of bad process. It has shut down the amendment process, it has restricted the period of time for debate, and it has rewritten the bill through self-execution in this rule. And I am going to urge my colleagues to defeat the previous question so that we can go back to what was promised  on the opening day, and that is an open process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With that, Mr. Speaker, I yield the balance of my time to the distinguished minority leader, the gentleman from Ohio (Mr. Boehner).</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="BOEHNER" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker and my colleagues, this is disappointing, disappointing that the House has had to resort to a martial law to further stifle the voices of those of us in the minority who represent nearly half the American people.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have had a debate on this rule. I have listened to the debate. I even participated in part of the debate and listened to my colleagues in the majority complain about the fact that we spent 3 or 4 hours the other day trying to debate a measure that we were not going to have much time to debate on because we didn't have a committee process, it was going to be brought to the House under a closed rule. And my colleagues pulled the bill and have been whining now for days that we spent 3 or 4 hours  doing dilatory tactics.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, some of you were here in 1998 when the Ag appropriations bill was on the floor of the House, and that bill was held up for 9 hours by the then minority over the fact that there was an amendment that a Member wanted to have heard on the Foreign Operations bill. It just so happened it was the distinguished gentlewoman from California (Ms. Pelosi) who wanted an abortion amendment on the Foreign Operations bill and wasn't sure she was going to be able to get her amendment; and, as a  result, she and some of her colleagues held up the bill with dilatory tactics for 9 hours.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, who were those Members who held that bill for 9 hours on this floor?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It was the gentlewoman from Connecticut (Ms. DeLauro), it was the gentleman from Wisconsin (Mr. Obey), it was the gentlewoman from New York (Ms. Slaughter), and it was who is now the distinguished Speaker of the House, Ms. Pelosi.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nine hours of dilatory tactics over 3 days. So what did the Republican majority do? They went to the Rules Committee, and they got a rule. And do you know what they did in the rule? They told all Members any amendment that is filed will be made in order under the rule, and we came back to the floor and we spent 9 hours debating every amendment that Members wanted to offer, and we completed the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, if you want to bring a rule out here, at least allow us to be heard, at least allow us to participate, at least allow the 202 of us on this side of the aisle to represent the millions of American people that have sent us here to do their work.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>All I have asked and all my colleagues have asked all year is for fairness. All we want is fairness. I know how you wanted to be treated when you were in the minority. I say to my colleagues on the both sides of the aisle we have both been in a minority. We both know what it is like to not have many tools at your disposal. I, when I was chairing the Education and Workforce Committee, made sure that all of our members were treated fairly and treated honestly; and I think my work with the gentleman  from California (Mr. George Miller) demonstrates that, while we had differences, we had a very fair process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I understand that over the last 12 years some of my predecessors may have handled, may have handled, this floor in a less than delicate way. Over the last several years, my colleagues in the majority now complained that we  ought to have a more fair and open process here. I agreed with many of you, and you know it. And all I am asking for on behalf of the Republican Members, the minority Members here, is to be treated fairly and honestly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The rule that we have before us that shuts us down is unfair, it's unwise, it's undemocratic, and it does not deserve the support of any Member in this House.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DREIER" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I urge a "no" vote on the previous question and on the rule.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="McGOVERN" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I agree with the distinguished minority leader that this is disappointing. As a member of the Rules Committee, I regret this rule and I don't like it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But what I like less are efforts to obstruct and stop the people's business. There is a difference between legislating and obstructionism. And I would say to the distinguished minority leader that fairness is a two-way street and what happened in this House on Tuesday, in my opinion, was pathetic.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What is at stake here is a bill to feed hungry people, is a bill to help rural America, is a bill to provide for better food security, and a bill to help our economy. This is serious business, and this is what we were sent here to deal with.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What happened on Tuesday, as I said, was pathetic. It stalled consideration of the Agriculture appropriations bill. It dismantled an agreement that worked well during consideration of the last 10 appropriations bills.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And let me say to my friends on the other side of the aisle, where I come from in Massachusetts, a deal is a deal. Your word is everything. So, please, when you break your word, don't act shocked when there is a reaction from this side of the aisle.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I will close by saying to my colleagues that it is important for us to move beyond this. It is important for us to work together. It is important for us to be more civil. I will concede to my friends on the other side of the aisle that my side of the aisle can do better, but you need to concede that your side can do better as well. And that is the way we restore the trust that, unfortunately, has been lost.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge a "yes" on the previous question and on the rule.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. LEWIS of California, this is a sad day in the history of the Appropriations Committee and the House of Representatives. Meaningful, legitimate debate is being stifled and the voice of the Republican minority is being silenced. Sadly, this is the day that will be remembered as the day that the Democrat majority imposed martial law on the People's House.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My colleagues know that I have the highest level of respect for the chairman of the Appropriations Committee, Mr. Obey. Together, we worked as partners during the 109th Congress, passing Appropriations bills through our committee and through the House. Our committee, and indeed, the House, is at its very best when we work together across patty lines and rise above purely partisan politics.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>During the last Congress, I was privileged to serve as chairman of the House Appropriations Committee and Mr. Obey was our distinguished ranking member.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>During my tenure as chairman, the House considered 22 regular order appropriations bills. In each and every instance, I worked closely with my leadership and Chairman Dreier in seeking a rule that allowed for a maximum level of open debate, including amendments, on the House floor. Every one--every one--of those 22 annual spending bills was considered under an open rule.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We allowed and even encouraged dissenting voices to be heard on these bills. The result was often vigorous and lively debate on the House floor. But that's precisely why our constituents send us to Washington.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I was disappointed that Mr. Obey's first bills as chairman--the fiscal year 2007 continuing resolution and the emergency supplemental--were both considered under a closed rule. Mr. Obey, under direction from his leadership, is now heading down the same road yet gain.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Democrat leadership, with absolutely no consultation with the minority, has adopted a closed rule for the consideration of the Agriculture Appropriations bill. As a result, scores of legitimate policy amendments offered by the minority have not been made in order.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a dangerous and perilous precedent that sets precisely the wrong tone as we attempt to complete work on our annual spending bills. A closed rule leaves the minority little choice but to walk away from the tradition of comity that has marked our longstaning work on this committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I find it interesting that we had only spent 3-4 hours debating this bill before the Democrat majority decided to pull the plug. I find it troubling that the decision was made by the Democrat leadership to impose a martial law, closed rule on the Ag bill in their rush to begin their month-long August vacation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation is simply too important to have it rushed through the House with no debate and no opportunity for the body to consider amendments. An open rule is the only proper way for the House to consider this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I certainly hope that this lock-down martial law rule on the Ag Appropriations bill isn't a preview of what the House can expect tomorrow as we consider the DoD Appropriations bill, legislation that comprises roughly one-half of all discretionary spending.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Democratic leadership, which promised the most open and transparent legislative process in history, is now showing its true colors. It has failed to fulfill its commitment to the Members of this body by not affording all Members an opportunity to openly amend and debate this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my I colleagues to oppose this rule and adopt a rule that will allow free and open debate on this and other pending spending bills.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="MCGOVERN" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time, and I move the previous question on the resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The question is on ordering the previous question.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DREIER" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 9 of rule XX, the Chair will reduce to 5 minutes the minimum time for electronic voting, if ordered, on the question of adoption of the resolution.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="DREIER" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 5-minute vote.</chair>
</record>
