<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1178553612" ordinal="24" title="ALASKA WATER RESOURCES ACT OF 2007">
  <speaking speaker="400290" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="1114">H.R. 1114</bill>) to require the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Reclamation and the United States Geological Survey, to conduct a study on groundwater resources in the State of Alaska, and for other purposes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from California (Mrs. Napolitano) and the gentleman from Colorado (Mr. Lamborn) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400290" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from California?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400290" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of 1114, as introduced by the ranking member of the Natural Resources Committee, the Honorable Representative Don Young, is to require the Secretary of the Interior, through the Bureau of Reclamation and the United States Geological Survey, to conduct a study on groundwater resources in the State of Alaska.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>The assessment and evaluation of current water resources is essential to understanding the needs of that community and its environment. <bill type="h" number="1114">H.R. 1114</bill> would require the Bureau of Reclamation and the USGS to do exactly that, to study the water supplies, the water treatment, and the water distribution needs of Alaska. The bill requires the Secretary of Interior to report the findings of this study to Congress no later than 2 years after enactment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A study of this magnitude, Mr. Speaker, is vital to the proper management of our most precious natural resource. I do greatly appreciate the hard work of Representative Young on this legislation and urge my colleagues to join me in supporting <bill type="h" number="1114">H.R. 1114</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This important legislation introduced by the distinguished ranking member of the House Natural Resources Committee, Don Young, will help Alaskans through water infrastructure study and development, and improved flood control management.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield such time as he may consume to the author of the bill and the ranking Republican of the Natural Resources Committee, Mr. Young of Alaska.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Mr. YOUNG of Alaska asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400440" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, let me thank the chairman of the committee, Mrs. Napolitano from California, for bringing this bill up with Mr. Rahall.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill seeks to expand Alaska's water supply system and reduce flood threats. My State's combined water bodies comprise one-third of all the fresh water in the United States, but communities are struggling to provide drinking water due to the outdated water distribution system and lack of information on groundwater resources. For this reason, this bill will include a survey of potential water supplies in the City of Anchorage, the Matanuska-Susitna Borough, the City of Fairbanks and Fairbanks  Northstar Borough.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also improves streamflow information to improve flood forecasting, resource extraction and fire management. Streamflow information in the form of USGS streamgaging stations is insufficient in Alaska compared to other States. In fact, Alaska has only 100 streamgage stations, which is less than 10 percent of the information available in many other States. This bill will help alleviate that situation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, I want to thank Mr. Rahall and Mrs. Napolitano of California for bringing this bill, and I urge passage of this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, may I say that I am so happy today we are talking about water, water in California, water in Alaska, water in Nebraska. Water is going to be our next big crisis that we are going to be faced with in this Nation, it is energy now, and we must do something. We have to learn how to use water better, how to impound water, and how to deliver water so we have that which supports our life, and that is water.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400290" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I couldn't agree more with Congressman Young about the importance of water for our country, and I would hope that we can work in a bipartisan manner to continue to look at other areas that will be in dire need of help, Federal help, to be able to determine what needs to be done to help them address their water concerns, and I thank the gentleman.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from California (Mrs. Napolitano) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="1114">H.R. 1114</bill>.</chair>
</record>
