<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1211299202" ordinal="15" title="CONGRATULATING NORTHERN KENTUCKY UNIVERSITY'S WOMEN'S BASKETBALL TEAM">
  <narrative>CONGRATULATING NORTHERN KENTUCKY UNIVERSITY'S WOMEN'S BASKETBALL TEAM -- (House of Representatives - May 20, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H4158]</narrative>
  <narrative>(Mr. DAVIS of Kentucky asked and was given permission to address the House for 1 minute and to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400633" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today to join my colleagues in the House in congratulating the Northern Kentucky University women's basketball team for winning the NCAA Division II National Championship on March 29, 2008. Yesterday, the House of Representatives passed <bill type="hr" number="1147">H. Res. 1147</bill>, which congratulates the team and the coaches on their impressive victory.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>During the championship game, the Norse overcame a nine-point deficit with less than 6 minutes left in the game to beat the University of South Dakota, 63-58. Senior Angela Healy had 14 points and 13 rebounds in the game. In recognition of her performance, Ms. Healy was voted the Elite Eight's Most Outstanding Player.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This win marked the second time in the last decade that the Norse women have won an NCAA national championship in women's basketball. NKU is now the only collegiate women's program in the Commonwealth of Kentucky to win two national titles in any sport.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Norse team consisted of 11 outstanding women who are not only championship-caliber players, but by all accounts students and leaders who are a credit to their community as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Coach Nancy Winstel should be applauded for her excellent leadership and dedication to Northern Kentucky University.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I want to congratulate the team, the coaching staff, and the entire Northern Kentucky University community for a great season, and to thank my colleagues for their support of this resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
