<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1174320004" ordinal="21" title="ARTHUR V. WATKINS DAM ENLARGEMENT ACT">
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="839">H.R. 839</bill>) to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to study the feasibility of enlarging the Arthur V. Watkins Dam Weber Basin Project, Utah, to provide additional water for the Weber Basin Project to fulfill the purposes for which that project was authorized.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) and the gentleman from Utah (Mr. Bishop) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Arizona?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="839">H.R. 839</bill>, introduced by our colleague, Representative ROB BISHOP of Utah, would authorize the Secretary of the Interior to study the feasibility of enlarging the Arthur V. Watkins Dam. The dam is one of the main features of the Bureau of Reclamation's Weber Basin Project located along the shore of the Great Salt Lake near Ogden, Utah.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>Recent drought and a growing population in Utah have highlighted water supply needs in the area. The feasibility study authorized by this legislation will help local water agencies and the Bureau of Reclamation to decide whether we should consider raising the dam to improve water storage capacity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the 109th Congress, the Subcommittee on Water and Power held hearings on similar legislation. That legislation was subsequently reported by the committee and passed by the House.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have no objection to this legislation and urge its passage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400029" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="839">H.R. 839</bill>. The Bureau of Reclamation's Weber Basin Project, which is located in northern Utah only a short distance from the historic Brigham City, stores and delivers water from the Weber River into its tributaries.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Arthur V. Watkins Dam, which is part of the Weber Basin Project, is part of an off-stream reservoir on the northeastern edge of the Great Salt Lake. It is formed by a roughly rectangular perimeter dam that is about 14.5 miles long. Water from the Weber River near its outlet to the Great Salt Lake is diverted into the reservoir by the Willard Canal and pumped from the reservoir by that same canal for multiple purposes. In addition to providing water supply, the reservoir is a popular recreation  facility.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Recent drought and a growing population of Utah have highlighted the need for additional water storage. As a result, the Weber Basin Water Conservancy District, a water user which manages the Arthur V. Watkins Dam and Reservoir, desires the Bureau of Reclamation's assistance in determining the feasibility of adding water storage capacity to the reservoir.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="839">H.R. 839</bill> authorizes such assistance. This bill passed in the 109th Congress by voice vote. I again ask for your support.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield back the balance of our time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="839">H.R. 839</bill>.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this question will be postponed.</chair>
</record>
