<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1185249600" ordinal="43" title="HONORING CAPTAIN CLYDE CAMPBELL">
  <narrative>HONORING CAPTAIN CLYDE CAMPBELL -- (House of Representatives - July 24, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H8391]</narrative>
  <chair> Under a previous order of the House, the gentleman from Texas (Mr. Gohmert) is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400651" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, on Thursday evening, July 26, Gregg County, my home district, First District of Texas, will gather for a day of remembrance in honor of our great servicemembers who were held as prisoners of war or were missing in action.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>July 26 is a special day because it would be the 63rd birthday of U.S. Air Force captain Clyde Campbell, that is the man around whom this occasion is centered.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I, unfortunately, will be unable to attend since I will be here in Washington. Unfortunately, Captain Campbell will also be unable to make it on his own birthday celebration because he or his remains have not been brought home from Laos.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Clyde Campbell was born in Eagle Lake, Texas, in 1944, and graduated from Longview High School in 1962. After graduating from Texas A&amp;M University, he answered the call to service and joined the United States Air Force. An ambitious and talented young pilot, Captain Campbell was stationed at Nakhon Phanom Royal Thai Airport Base in Thailand, ready to sacrifice his all for the Nation that he loved so dearly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In March 1969, he took off in his Douglas A1 Skyraider on a bombing pass, but Captain Campbell's plane was shot down and crashed in Laos.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is now 2007, almost 40 years later. Although his crash site has been identified, Captain Campbell's remains are in a land that is not his home.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Campbell family has spent nearly four decades requesting help to have this patriot returned. But so far, that help has not come. I am ashamed that the Federal Government has not used anywhere near the devotion to giving his family closure as the devotion Captain Campbell provided this Nation in her time of need.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This family deserves better. Captain Campbell deserves better, and I, as are many others around here, am determined to see that his remains are removed from Laos and given a proper burial here in the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He and those who gave their last full measure of devotion for this country, as well as their beloved family members who have waited so long, deserve action, and they deserve results.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Captain Campbell and the Campbell family deserve our deepest gratitude for their sacrifice. May God bless them and comfort them, and may God and the Campbell family forgive this Federal Government for its 30 years of inadequate service to them.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
