<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1173114004" ordinal="19" title="AUTHORIZING NATIONAL PARK SERVICE STUDY REGARDING THE SOLDIERS' MEMORIAL MILITARY MUSEUM">
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="1047">H.R. 1047</bill>) to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a study to determine the suitability and feasibility of designating the Soldiers' Memorial Military Museum located in St. Louis, Missouri, as a unit of the National Park System.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) and the gentleman from Utah (Mr. Bishop) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members have 5 legislative days within which to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Arizona?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, <bill type="h" number="1047">H.R. 1047</bill>, introduced by my colleague from Missouri, Representative Clay, directs the Secretary of the Interior to carry out a study to determine the suitability and feasibility of designating the Soldiers' Memorial Military Museum located in St. Louis, Missouri, as a unit of the National Park System.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Construction of the memorial and military museum began in 1935. The site was dedicated by President Franklin Roosevelt in 1936. On Memorial Day, 1938, the building officially opened to the public. The Soldiers' Memorial Building is a stately structure which, in addition to serving as a memorial to those who lost their lives in the service of their country, also contains exhibit rooms that house a collection of military items. The building has been found eligible for listing in the National Register  of Historic Places. It is operated by the City of St. Louis and made available to the public free of charge.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to commend my colleague from Missouri, Representative Clay, for his efforts to preserve this memorial and museum, which was built to honor those who gave their lives to this country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the House approved identical legislation in the 109th Congress. We strongly support <bill type="h" number="1047">H.R. 1047</bill> and urge its adoption by the House today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400029" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the majority has adequately explained <bill type="h" number="1047">H.R. 1047</bill>, but I wish to note that while this legislation passed in the House in the 109th Congress, it is not supported by the administration because the memorial is not distinguished beyond that of many war memorials, and it is not known whether it meets the criteria of national significance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield such time as he may consume to the gentleman from Missouri (Mr. Clay).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400074" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I first want to thank my friend and colleague from Arizona for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the American people are unanimous in supporting the courageous men and women serving in our Armed Forces. In recent days, we were appalled to learn that our veterans are not receiving high-quality health care. We have been sickened by some of the stories and images of the patients at Walter Reed Hospital who have been neglected and left untreated. And we are beginning to understand that this is a nationwide crisis. We are all somewhat ashamed that we have failed to provide to those  who have given the most to keep our Nation free and secure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With these recent events in mind, I want to address the legislation before us today. <bill type="h" number="1047">H.R. 1047</bill> is a bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a study to determine the suitability and feasibility of designating the Soldiers' Memorial Military Museum in the city of St. Louis as a unit of the National Park System.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This memorial is a shining landmark to those brave men and women who gave their lives in World War I. Today, as much as any time in our history, the American people feel a very special connection to our military forces, and the citizens of our Nation have a real need to visit shrines that honor our wartime heroes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The St. Louis Soldiers' Memorial is a valuable shrine where citizens can participate in the tradition of honoring our Nation's veterans. Initiated by the residents of St. Louis in the 1920s, after many years of fundraising, the land was acquired and the monument was constructed. On October 14, 1936, St. Louis Soldiers' Memorial Military Museum was officially dedicated by President Roosevelt. And St. Louis Soldiers' Memorial Military Museum also has a unique place in our Nation's history as it  is the only structure in St. Louis that is known to have been dedicated by a sitting U.S. President.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Soldiers' Monument is a national treasure, and it is recognized as an architectural masterpiece. Designed by one of the 20th century's foremost art deco sculptors, Mr. Walter Hancock, the entrance to the memorial is flanked by four limestone sculptures which symbolize the most important virtues in a soldier's life: courage, loyalty, sacrifice and vision. The ceiling of the monument is decorated with mosaic tiles in the shape of large gold stars that are dedicated to our Nation's Gold Star  Mothers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, the St. Louis Soldiers' Memorial is an important cultural resource and gathering place. It attracts about 48,000 visitors a year, and provides the setting for more than 20 ceremonies annually, including change-of-command and retirement ceremonies, and many other patriotic events hosted by veterans groups. It is also the center of an annual Veterans Day parade which is the largest of its kind in the Midwest, drawing participants from several States and hosting more than 100 marching units.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In recent years, the city of St. Louis has relied upon the support and contributions of active military personnel and veterans to enable it to maintain this cherished monument. We all want to honor the veterans and citizens of our Nation. We should have Federal monuments to help us all remember those family members and friends who have given their lives for us in combat.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is the right time for the Federal Government to consider acquiring the St. Louis Soldiers' Memorial Military Museum in its inventory of national monuments. I believe that a study of the monument will show it is a historically important structure with a national significance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1047">H.R. 1047</bill> is strongly supported by veterans groups and other civic organizations. I hope the Members of this body will endorse this important effort to create a Federal monument to honor our Nation's veterans. I urge my colleagues to support this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400029" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="1047">H.R. 1047</bill>.</chair>
</record>
