<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1193068802" ordinal="28" title="CENTRAL OKLAHOMA MASTER CONSERVANCY DISTRICT FEASIBILITY STUDY">
  <narrative>CENTRAL OKLAHOMA MASTER CONSERVANCY DISTRICT FEASIBILITY STUDY -- (House of Representatives - October 22, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H11802]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="1337">H.R. 1337</bill>) to provide for a feasibility study of alternatives to augment the water supplies of the Central Oklahoma Master Conservancy District and cities served by the District, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="1337">H.R. 1337</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. CENTRAL OKLAHOMA MASTER CONSERVATORY DISTRICT FEASIBILITY STUDY.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Findings.--Congress finds that--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) Thunderbird Lake, located on Little River in central Oklahoma, was constructed in 1965 by the Bureau of Reclamation for flood control, water supply, recreation, and fish and wildlife purposes;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) the available yield of Thunderbird Lake is allocated to the Central Oklahoma Master Conservatory District, which supplies municipal and industrial water supplies to the cities of Norman, Midwest City, and Del City, Oklahoma; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) studies conducted by the Bureau during fiscal year 2003 indicate that the District will require additional water supplies to meet the future needs of the District, including through--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) the drilling of additional wells;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) the implementation of a seasonal pool plan at Thunderbird Lake;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) the construction of terminal storage to hold wet-weather yield from Thunderbird Lake;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (D) a reallocation of water storage; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (E) the importation of surplus water from sources outside the basin of Thunderbird Lake.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Study.--Beginning no later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commissioner of the Bureau of Reclamation shall conduct a feasibility study of alternatives to augment the water supplies of the Central Oklahoma Master Conservatory District and cities served by the District, including recommendations of the Commissioner, if any.</narrative>
  <narrative> (c) Authorization of Appropriations.--There is authorized to be appropriated to the  Commissioner of the Bureau of Reclamation $900,000 to conduct the study under subsection (b).&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from Guam (Ms. Bordallo) and the gentleman from Texas (Mr. Gohmert) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentlewoman from Guam.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from Guam?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of <bill type="h" number="1337">H.R. 1337</bill>, introduced by our colleague, Congressman Tom Cole of Oklahoma, is to direct the Commissioner of the Bureau of Reclamation to conduct a feasibility study on alternatives to augment the water supplies of the Central Oklahoma Master Conservancy District and cities served by that district.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation was previously considered by the House, and we have no objection to this noncontroversial bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400651" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="1337">H.R. 1337</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1337">H.R. 1337</bill>, authored by Congressman Tom Cole, authorizes a feasibility study to assist Norman, Oklahoma, and the surrounding area to meet long-term water supplies through the expansion of a Federal water project.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Like many areas throughout the West, these Oklahoma communities are faced with growing water supply challenges. This thoughtful bill provides limited Federal assistance to expand a Federal reservoir, but preserves local rights and jurisdiction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although some of us have concerns that there are people who play football in the Norman, Oklahoma, area and they have been overly aggressive as of late with some of our Texas teams, we are hopeful that by providing this help that it will cool down some of that overaggressiveness.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would urge my colleagues to support the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I thank my colleague from Texas (Mr. Gohmert) for his support on this noncontroversial bill, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from Guam (Ms. Bordallo) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="1337">H.R. 1337</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the bill, as amended, was passed.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
