<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1178553612" ordinal="20" title="CHEYENNE RIVER SIOUX TRIBE EQUITABLE COMPENSATION AMENDMENTS ACT OF 2007">
  <speaking speaker="400290" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="487">H.R. 487</bill>) to amend the Cheyenne River Sioux Tribe Equitable Compensation Act to provide compensation to members of the Cheyenne River Sioux Tribe for damage resulting from the  Oahe Dam and Reservoir Project, and for other purposes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from California (Mrs. Napolitano) and the gentleman from Colorado (Mr. Lamborn) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400290" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from California?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400290" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to commend my colleague from South Dakota, Representative Herseth Sandlin, for her very dedicated hard work and her persistence on this piece of legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="487">H.R. 487</bill> makes several technical corrections to address inequities that surfaced after the enactment of the original Cheyenne River Sioux Tribe Equitable Compensation Act of 2000. In short, this legislation provides for accelerated compensation for tribal members and landowners impacted by the construction of the Oahe Dam in 1962. It also satisfies a request from the administration to amend the underlying structure of the compensation fund.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="487">H.R. 487</bill> will assist the tribe in addressing this loss and help to ensure a positive future for the Cheyenne River Sioux.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield such time as she may consume to the gentlewoman from South Dakota (Ms. Herseth Sandlin), the bill's sponsor, to further describe the legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="SANDLIN, HERSETH" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I want to thank Chairwoman Napolitano for her support of this important legislation to my constituents and for her leadership on the subcommittee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise today in strong support of <bill type="h" number="487">H.R. 487</bill>, the Cheyenne River Sioux Tribe Equitable Compensation Amendments Act of 2007. This legislation is the result of a collaborative effort between the Cheyenne River Sioux Tribe, the South Dakota congressional delegation, the House Natural Resources Committee and the Department of the Treasury. I am very pleased to stand before my colleagues in the House today and urge final passage of this important bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The need for this legislation began more than 50 years ago with the construction of a series of dams and reservoir projects along the upper Missouri River basin. One of those projects, the Oahe Dam and Reservoir, caused flooding on over 100,000 acres of the Cheyenne River Indian Reservation in north central South Dakota. The loss of these lands was particularly devastating to the tribe and included some of their most important cropland, wildlife habitat and spiritually significant places.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Though the tribe did receive some initial compensation for this loss, the amount was woefully inadequate and did not reflect the magnitude of the loss imposed on the tribe. In 2000, Congress recognized this injustice when it passed legislation to provide additional compensation for the Cheyenne River Sioux Tribe and created a trust fund for additional tribal development. Unfortunately, the 2000 legislation was incomplete and flawed, requiring a number of amendments to the underlying law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to several technical changes advocated by the Department of the Treasury, <bill type="h" number="487">H.R. 487</bill> will allow for the immediate capitalization of the trust fund and also give the tribe the authority to redirect a limited amount of the fund towards private tribal landowners. Many of the 100,000-plus acres that were inundated due to the dam were actually privately owned by tribal members. Now tribal elders, these individuals have been waiting decades for fair compensation and will finally have that  opportunity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Not only will <bill type="h" number="487">H.R. 487</bill> capitalize the fund to allow immediate implementation of the tribe's poverty reduction program, it will help to right a historic wrong and ultimately saves the Federal Government approximately $9 million.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The merits of this legislation are clear, both through its history and the spirit of bipartisan collaboration that brought it to the floor today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to join me in supporting <bill type="h" number="487">H.R. 487</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="412191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself as much time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This well-intended legislation improves current law by directly compensating landowners whose tribal lands were flooded by the construction of the Federal Oahe Dam in South Dakota. It also releases Federal funding to the Cheyenne River Sioux who were affected by the dam and, in doing so, reduces Federal taxpayer expenditures throughout the life of the program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the last Congress, this bill had major issues, but all parties worked in good faith to resolve their disagreements. It now enjoys broad support.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have no objection to this legislation and urge its adoption.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400290" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, we have no objection to this noncontroversial bill. I would like to thank my colleague on the other side and also, especially, the sponsor of the bill, Ms.  Herseth Sandlin, for her very hard work and strong leadership.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from California (Mrs. Napolitano) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="487">H.R. 487</bill>.</chair>
</record>
