<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1194282001" ordinal="21" title="RECOGNIZING THE CLOSE RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN THE UNITED STATES AND THE REPUBLIC OF SAN MARINO">
  <narrative>RECOGNIZING THE CLOSE RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN THE UNITED STATES AND THE REPUBLIC OF SAN MARINO -- (House of Representatives - November 05, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H12468]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400122" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and agree to the concurrent resolution (<bill type="hc" number="236">H. Con. Res. 236</bill>) recognizing the close relationship between the United States and the Republic of San Marino, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the concurrent resolution.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the concurrent resolution is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="hc" number="236">H. Con. Res. 236</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas the Republic of San Marino is the oldest republic in the world;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Republic of San Marino was founded by those fleeing the religious persecution of the Roman Empire, and has adhered to the principles of tolerance and individual liberty throughout its history;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the United States and the Republic of San Marino have long held close ties based on common interests and common values;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the special bond between the Republic of San Marino and the United States was first expressed nearly a century and a half ago in an exchange of letters between President Abraham Lincoln and the Captains Regent of San Marino;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas President Lincoln expressed in his letter his deep respect for the Republic of San Marino as "one of the most honored in all of history" and took encouragement from its example that a "government founded on republican principles is capable of being so administered as to be secure and enduring";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Republic of San Marino has been a steadfast ally of the United States in many international organizations, such as the United Nations and the International Monetary Fund;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Republic of San Marino has been a close collaborator on a number of key economic issues, such as the protection of intellectual property;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Republic of San Marino has been a close collaborator in the fight against terrorism, including efforts to combat international terrorist financing;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas through its chairmanship of the Committee of Ministers of the Council of Europe, the Republic of San Marino has worked to promote inter-religious and inter-cultural dialogue;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas earlier this year, the United States and the Republic of San Marino upgraded their diplomatic relations to ambassador-level, and exchanged the first bilateral Ambassadors in our history;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Paolo Rondelli, the first Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the Republic of San Marino to the United States, presented his credentials to President Bush at a ceremony at the White House on July 25, 2007; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Honorable Ronald P. Spogli presented credentials to the Captains Regent (co-Heads of State) in a ceremony in San Marino's Palazzo Publico on March 8, 2007: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved by the House of Representatives (the Senate concurring), That Congress--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) recognizes the close relationship between the United States and the Republic of San Marino;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) expresses its deep gratitude to the Republic of San Marino for its close collaboration and support in issues of critical importance to our economic and national security interests; and</narrative>
  <narrative> (3) commemorates the first bilateral exchange of Ambassadors in the history of our long relationship.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from New York (Mr. Engel) and the gentleman from Arkansas (Mr. Boozman) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from New York.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400122" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the resolution under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from New York?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400122" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in strong support of this resolution and yield myself as much time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to thank my good friend and colleague, the gentleman from California (Mr. Dreier), for introducing this resolution that recognizes a small but important friend of the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is often said, Mr. Speaker, that good things come in small packages, and in the case of San Marino, this is certainly true. San Marino is the third smallest country in Europe, only Vatican City and Monaco being smaller.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>San Marino, which is home to 29,000 inhabitants in a territory one-third the size of the District of Columbia, attracts several million visitors a year. The tourist industry makes up over 50 percent of the country's GDP.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>San Marino is said to be the oldest republic in the world. It was founded in 301 A.D. by Marinus of Rab, a Christian fleeing from religious persecution by the Roman Emperor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Its constitution, which dates back to 1600, is the world's oldest written constitution, and remains in effect to this day.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>San Marino has been an active player at the international level, including the United Nations, International Monetary Fund, and Council of Europe. Through these bodies, San Marino has sought to promote interreligious and intercultural dialogue, as well as the protection of intellectual property.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>San Marino has also cultivated a close friendship with the United States based on our shared values and interests. This relationship was first expressed when President Abraham Lincoln exchanged letters with the Captains Regent of San Marino.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nearly 150 years after these letters were sent, the United States and San Marino upgraded their bilateral relations to include the first ever exchange of ambassadors. President Bush welcomed San Marino's new Ambassador, Paulo Rondelli, during a White House ceremony on July 25. U.S. Ambassador Ronald Spogli presented his credentials to the Captains Regent in San Marino's Palazzo Publico on March 8. I welcome this development in our bilateral relations, and look forward to ever closer cooperation  with our European ally.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to join me in supporting this resolution which recognizes the close relationship between our two countries, expresses gratitude to San Marino for its friendship and support, and commemorates the first ever exchange of ambassadors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400040" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, let's take a moment to recognize an ally whose relationship with the United States certainly exceeds its size. Completely surrounded by Italy, the European microstate of San Marino has the smallest population of all the members of the Council of Europe. Yet, San Marino has made a strong ally of the United States, most notably within a number of international institutions, including the United Nations and the International Monetary Fund. In fact, the U.S. and San Marino have collaborated  closely on several key issues such as combating international terrorist financing and protecting intellectual property rights.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Moreover, San Marino has been a leader in promoting interreligious and intercultural dialogue within the European Union. The value of our relationship was marked earlier this year by the first exchange of ambassadors between the U.S. and San Marino.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I, therefore, ask my colleagues to join me in supporting Ranking Member Dreier's <bill type="hc" number="236">H. Con. Res. 236</bill>, recognizing our close relationship with the Republic of San Marino.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400122" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400040" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield to the author of this resolution, the gentleman from California (Mr. Dreier) such time as he may consume.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Mr. DREIER asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400115" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I want to thank my colleagues, the gentleman from New York (Mr. Engel) and the gentleman from Arkansas (Mr. Boozman), for their very thoughtful remarks on this resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also want to join in expressing my appreciation to my fellow Californian, the distinguished Chair of the Committee on Foreign Affairs, Mr. Lantos and, of course, the ranking Republican, Ms. Ros-Lehtinen.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>I think both of the sets of remarks offered underscore something that is extraordinarily important, and that is that we thank and express our appreciation to our allies, no matter how  large or how small their populations, in dealing with the challenges that we face internationally.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But I will say I have a particular interest in the world's oldest republic because I am privileged to represent its namesake, the City of San Marino, California.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I had the privilege, Mr. Speaker, of leading the first bipartisan delegation to what, as my friend from New York correctly said, is the oldest republic on the face of the Earth, and we took this delegation back in 2004 to the Republic of San Marino. I had the opportunity to present to the Captains Regent, as was said, the co-heads of their state, of their government, a proclamation passed by the San Marino City Council expressing its greetings and appreciation for the friendship that they share.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>San Marino, California, was named at its founding for the republic on the Adriatic Sea and displays in its seal Mount Titano, where the republic was first established. Today, like its namesake, San Marino, California, is known for its beauty. It is home to the Huntington Library and Gardens, one of Southern California's great treasures. But the relationship with the Republic of San Marino reaches far beyond beauty. It's my hope that this resolution will help to make us all more aware of the great  bond the United States shares with this small, but very important, country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Republic of San Marino, as was said, was founded over 17 centuries ago by those who were fleeing the religious persecution of the Roman Empire. They founded a community based on liberty and tolerance 1,300 years before the Pilgrims would land on Plymouth Rock on a similar endeavor. Since those early days of the republic, San Marino has continued its strong tradition of democracy and freedom.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our close bond, based on a shared commitment to these principles, was first, as my friend from New York said, recorded in history through an exchange of letters between President Lincoln and the Captains Regent. President Lincoln expressed in that letter his deep respect for the Republic of San Marino, saying, "as one of the most honored in all of world history."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, he took encouragement from its example that any "government founded on republican principles is capable of being so administered as to be secure and enduring." Those are the words of President Lincoln. Now, as our Nation faced a great crisis, Lincoln looked to the example of San Marino, which had endured for so long while standing with its small "r" republican foundation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As the United States has faced new crises in the 20th and 21st centuries, it has again relied upon San Marino for its steadfast support within international institutions such as the United Nations. San Marino has been a close collaborator on a number of critical issues like combating international terrorist financing. This year we have honored their friendship and support, as was said, by elevating our relationship to the ambassadorial level.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My good friend and fellow Californian Ron Spogli, as the first U.S. Ambassador to the Republic of San Marino, presented his credentials to the Captains Regent in a ceremony in San Marino's Palazzo Publico on March 8 of 2007. And as my friend from New York said, the exchange was completed when on July 25 of this year, Paolo Rondelli, the first Ambassador of the Republic of San Marino to the United States, presented his credentials to President Bush at the White House.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, today we honor this exchange of ambassadors, and we honor the close relationship between our Nation and the world's oldest republic and the fundamental values that bind us.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And, again, I thank my colleagues for their support of this resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400040" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I urge adoption of Congressman Dreier's resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no further requests for time, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400122" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no further requests for time, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from New York (Mr. Engel) that the House suspend the rules and agree to the concurrent resolution, <bill type="hc" number="236">H. Con. Res. 236</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400040" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this motion will be postponed.</chair>
</record>
