<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1211212804" ordinal="14" title="CORAL REEF ECOSYSTEMS">
  <narrative>CORAL REEF ECOSYSTEMS -- (House of Representatives - May 19, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H4066]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and agree to the concurrent resolution (<bill type="hc" number="300">H. Con. Res. 300</bill>) recognizing the necessity for the United States to maintain its significant leadership role in improving the health and promoting the resiliency of coral reef ecosystems, and for other purposes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the concurrent resolution.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the concurrent resolution is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="hc" number="300">H. Con. Res. 300</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas coral reef ecosystems are among the world's most biologically diverse and productive marine habitats, and are often described as the tropical rain forest of the oceans;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas healthy coral reef ecosystems provide the basis for subsistence, commercial fisheries, and coastal and marine tourism and are of vital economic importance to coastal States and territories of the United States including Florida, Hawaii, Georgia, Texas, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas healthy coral reef ecosystems function as natural, regenerating coastal barriers, protecting shorelines and coastal areas from high waves, storm surges, and accompanying losses of human life and property;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the coral reef research community has long established that coral reefs are subject to a wide range of natural and anthropogenic threats, including climate change;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the health of coral reef ecosystems is at serious risk due to a variety of human activities, both local and global;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas protecting and conserving coral reef ecosystems is an urgent issue, but they may be preserved if we act now;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas changing climate is potentially one of the most significant long-term influences on the structure and function of coral reef ecosystems, including the devastating effects of ocean acidification and rising ocean temperatures;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas a wide variety of destructive fishing practices, including the use of cyanide, other poisons, surfactants, and explosives, are contributing to the global decline of coral reef ecosystems;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the United States has taken measures to protect national coral reef resources through the designation and management of several marine protected areas located in both the Pacific and Caribbean, through building local management capacity, and by supporting effective management and sound research to preserve, sustain, and restore valuable coral reef ecosystems;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas our Nation's coral reef ecosystems provide benefit and opportunity to all, and conservation of these important resources requires the coordinated efforts of the many Federal agencies and State, territory, and commonwealth partners that comprise the U.S. Coral Reef Task Force and our many nongovernmental, international, and academic partners;</narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas the United States, acting through its agencies, has established itself as a global leader in coral reef ecosystem stewardship by launching and remaining an active and engaged participant in the International Coral Reef Initiative, and by maintaining professional networks for the purposes of sharing knowledge and information on coral reef ecosystems, furnishing near real-time data collected at coral reef sites, providing a repository for historical data relating to coral reefs, and making  substantial contributions to the general body of coral reef knowledge; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas 2008 has been declared the "International Year of the Reef" by the coral reef research community and over 40 national and international coral reef research, conservation, and academic organizations: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved by the House of Representatives (the Senate concurring), That the Congress recognizes the necessity for the United States to maintain its significant leadership role in improving the health and promoting the resiliency of coral reef ecosystems, by--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) strengthening awareness about ecological, economic, social, and cultural values of coral reefs and associated ecosystems;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) improving understanding of the critical threats to coral reefs and generating both practical and innovative solutions to reduce those threats; and</narrative>
  <narrative> (3) initiating the prompt development and implementation of effective management strategies for the conservation and sustainable use of those ecosystems.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from Guam (Ms. Bordallo) and the gentleman from California (Mr. Issa) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentlewoman from Guam.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the resolution under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from Guam?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>House Concurrent Resolution 300 recognizes the necessity for the United States to maintain its significant leadership role in improving the health and promoting resiliency of coral reef ecosystems.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Coral reef ecosystems are not only economically important to commercial fisheries and marine tourism of many places, including my own district of Guam, but they also act as natural protective coastal barriers during storm surges and high waves.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 2008, the International Year of the Reef, the United States can help facilitate coordinated conservation efforts and maintain its leadership by working to strengthen awareness of the values of the coral reef ecosystems. This resolution, Mr. Speaker, encourages continued United States leadership in that regard, and I urge my colleagues to support it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400196" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise in support of this resolution. House Concurrent Resolution 300 does make an important point to the American people and to the world that the United States has been a leader in the preservation and restoration of our coral reefs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Like the gentlewoman from Guam, I have a long coastline and recognize that without the often-called "rain forest of the ocean," the world would not eat, our coastlines would be eroded, and, without a doubt, life as we know it would not prevail.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, Mr. Speaker, I do ask strong support in favor of this resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400128" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in strong support of <bill type="hc" number="300">H. Con. Res. 300</bill>, recognizing the urgency for the U.S. to maintain its leadership role in protecting and promoting the resiliency of our coral reef ecosystems.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, I want to commend the chief sponsors, Ms. Bordallo of Guam and Ms. Ros-Lehtinen of Florida, for their initiative in introducing this important resolution. I also want to acknowledge the support and leadership of Chairman Nick Rahall and Ranking Member Don Young of Alaska of the Committee on Natural Resources.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a member of the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, and Oceans, I want to personally commend my good friend, Chairwoman Bordallo, for her tireless work on the many issues affecting our oceans. This resolution in particular is an example of the efforts by the Congress in promoting U.S. leadership and participation in preserving our natural resources. Given that 2008 has been designated the "International Year of the Reef," it is only appropriate that we must reinforce U.S. commitments  to the international efforts to protect critical coral reef habitats.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, according to a recent U.N. report on oceans, 60 percent of the world's coral reefs will die-off by 2030. This is due to the changes in the climate because of global warming from the harm chemicals and human activity has placed on our environment. It is our responsibility to enhance international efforts to protect and restore our coastal marine resources. We have taken many steps to achieve these efforts by establishing the U.S. Coral Reef Task Force in 1998 that has done so much  through enhancing research and monitoring, implementing action strategies, and formulating and enforcing national policy on protecting and preserving all of our coastal reefs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last year, I introduced <bill type="h" number="1205">H.R. 1205</bill>, the Coral Reef Conservation Act of 2000, that was unanimously passed by the House in October 2007. This legislation will codify the U.S. Coral Reef Task Force and will advance existing programs that address this core issue. However, there has been no further action on the Senate side. I am hopeful that this important legislation will be passed by the end of the year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, I urge my colleagues to pass <bill type="hc" number="300">H. Con. Res. 300</bill>. I thank my colleagues for supporting this important bipartisan resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400196" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I again urge Members to support the resolution, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from Guam (Ms. Bordallo) that the House suspend the rules and agree to the concurrent resolution, <bill type="hc" number="300">H. Con. Res. 300</bill>.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400196" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I object to the vote on the ground that a quorum is not present and make the point of order that a quorum is not present.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this motion will be postponed.</chair>
  <chair>The point of no quorum is considered withdrawn.</chair>
</record>
