<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1213804802" ordinal="26" title="COMMEMORATING THE SERVICE OF SUPERINTENDENT SANDRA BARRY TO THE ANAHEIM CITY SCHOOL DISTRICT">
  <narrative>COMMEMORATING THE SERVICE OF SUPERINTENDENT SANDRA BARRY TO THE ANAHEIM CITY SCHOOL DISTRICT -- (House of Representatives - June 18, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H5488]</narrative>
  <narrative>(Ms. LORETTA SANCHEZ of California asked and was given permission to address the House for 1 minute and to revise and extend her remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400356" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, today I would like to honor the service of Anaheim City School District Superintendent Sandra Barry and to wish her luck in her upcoming retirement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Throughout her 11 years with the school district, including the last 8 as superintendent, Mrs. Barry has done an excellent job leading the Anaheim City School District, which is the largest elementary school district in Orange County and one of the largest in the State of California.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I applaud Superintendent Barry's commitment to the entire Anaheim community. Mrs. Barry has given her time and energy to many causes, including being on the board of directors for the Tiger Woods Foundation, the Anaheim Chamber of Commerce, the YMCA and the Police Chief Community Advisory Board. Her dedication to the community and the future of our Anaheim children is clear through her many achievements.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I sincerely thank superintendent Barry for her leadership, her commitment and her dedication to brightening the academic future of every Anaheim elementary student. She will be missed, but her lasting influence, and especially with respect to all the educators in the district, will go on for a long time in Anaheim.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I wish my good friend the best in her retirement, and I thank her for making the Anaheim City School District a great place to learn.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
