<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1207756802" ordinal="26" title="CONGRESSWOMAN JO ANN S. DAVIS POST OFFICE">
  <narrative>CONGRESSWOMAN JO ANN S. DAVIS POST OFFICE -- (House of Representatives - April 09, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H2081]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400074" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="5489">H.R. 5489</bill>) to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 6892 Main Street in Gloucester, Virginia, as the "Congresswoman Jo Ann S. Davis Post Office".</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="5489">H.R. 5489</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. CONGRESSWOMAN JO ANN S. DAVIS POST OFFICE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Designation.--The facility of the United States Postal Service located at 6892 Main Street in Gloucester, Virginia, shall be known and designated as the "Congresswoman Jo Ann S. Davis Post Office".</narrative>
  <narrative> (b) References.--Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the facility referred to in subsection (a) shall be deemed to be a reference to the "Congresswoman Jo Ann S. Davis Post Office".&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Missouri (Mr. Clay) and the gentleman from Texas (Mr. Marchant) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Missouri.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400074" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days in which to revise and extend their remarks.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Missouri?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400074" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, as a member of the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, I am pleased to join my colleagues in the consideration of <bill type="h" number="5489">H.R. 5489</bill>, which seeks to honor the life of Congresswoman Jo Ann Davis, and the example she has set for all of us; as an American stateswoman, legislator, and most importantly, as our friend, by naming a U.S. post office in her name.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congresswoman Davis represented Virginia's first Congressional District from 2001 until her untimely death in 2007. She was the second woman ever to be elected to Congress from Virginia.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A woman of faith and strong conviction, Congresswoman Davis lived admirably and with down-to-earth humility, which is why her presence here in the House is sure to be missed for quite some time to come.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill before us, <bill type="h" number="5489">H.R. 5489</bill>, was introduced by Representative Robert Wittman of Virginia on February 26, 2008 and was considered by and reported from the Oversight Committee on March 13, 2008 by voice vote. The measure has the support of over 20 Members of Congress, and provides our body a collective opportunity to acknowledge one of our very own for her dedication and congressional action to improve the lives of others, whether in her congressional district, her beloved home State  of Virginia, or throughout our great country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Jo Ann Davis was born in Rowan County, North Carolina on June 29, 1950. At the age of 9, her parents moved to the Virginia peninsula. Despite her humble beginnings, Congresswoman Davis set her sights high and the expectations for herself even higher. In 1968 she graduated from Kecoughtan High School in Hampton, Virginia and then went on to attend Hampton Roads Business College. After graduating she became an executive secretary at a real estate company in Newport News until she obtained her real  estate license in 1984 and soon thereafter, founded Jo Ann Davis Realty.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Her whole life she exceeded expectations, so it should come as no surprise when she ran for Congress in 1999 and won by receiving 58 percent of the vote in her Southern Virginia District.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Representative Davis' congressional record is a testimony to her fight for employees' rights and fairness in the workplace. Her first piece of legislation raised the life insurance benefit paid to survivors of military members killed on duty, and she also pushed for improving dental and vision benefits for government employees, and argued in favor of a more evenhanded system for compensating Federal law enforcement officers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our country owes her our sincere appreciation for her efforts in making public service, which is the lifeblood of our Nation, a more equitable and beneficial system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In September 2005, our dear friend Congresswoman Davis was diagnosed with breast cancer and for years underwent the necessary treatments. Although she was planning to seek re-election in 2008, Congresswoman Davis unfortunately succumbed to the cancer on October 6, 2007 in her home in Gloucester, Virginia.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>She is survived by her husband, Chuck Davis, a battalion chief of the Hampton Fire Department, two sons, and a granddaughter.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, let's join together this day to express our thanks and to pay our respects for the sacrifices and battles Congresswoman Jo Ann Davis fought in the name of liberty and justice and pass <bill type="h" number="5489">H.R. 5489</bill> which would designate the Main Street post office in her hometown of Gloucester, Virginia, as the "Congresswoman Jo Ann S. Davis Post Office." I urge the swift passage of the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400656" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself as much time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, born in North Carolina but a Virginian since the age of 9, Jo Ann Davis set the standard for Republican women in Virginia. After graduating from high school in Hampton, Virginia, she attended Hampton Roads Business College and became a real estate agent. Prior to her election to the House of Representatives in November 2000, she served in the General Assembly of Virginia. Subsequently, she was the first Republican woman elected in her own right to the United States Congress from  the Commonwealth. Congresswoman Davis served honorably for four terms as the representative of the First Congressional District of Virginia.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>During her tenure, Congresswoman Davis served on the House Armed Services Committee and on the Foreign Affairs Committee. Congresswoman Davis was particularly proud of securing funding for the construction of the Navy's next-generation aircraft carrier, the CVN-21.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 2001, the House passed her first piece of legislation, <bill type="h" number="1015">H.R. 1015</bill>, the SGLI Adjustment Act which increased the  amount of life insurance paid to beneficiaries of the Armed Forces who died in the performance of duty between November 2000 and April 2001.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 2005, Congresswoman Davis was diagnosed with breast cancer. Tragically, in 2007, the cancer returned and her condition rapidly worsened. Congresswoman Davis died in October at the age of 57 leaving behind her husband, Chuck Davis, and two sons and a granddaughter.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congresswoman Davis was an inspiration to so many of our Members, as well as her constituents, as she battled breast cancer courageously for over 2 years. Her determination to continue serving the citizens of the First District of Virginia while undergoing treatment set a remarkable standard of perseverance for many of us.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe that the naming of the postal service located at 6892 Main Street in Gloucester, Virginia, after Congresswoman Davis is a fitting tribute to her years of public service.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400074" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no further speakers, and I will reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400656" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield as much time as he may consume to my distinguished colleague from the State of Virginia (Mr. Wittman).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412255" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today to urge my colleagues to support <bill type="h" number="5489">H.R. 5489</bill>, a bill to designate a United States Postal Service facility located at 6892 Main Street in Gloucester, Virginia, as the "Congresswoman Jo Ann S. Davis Post Office." I introduced this legislation to honor Jo Ann who dedicated her entire being to serving the First District of Virginia.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As you've heard, Jo Ann made history in 2000 when she became the first female Republican elected to the U.S. House of Representatives from the Commonwealth of Virginia. In Congress, she was a passionate advocate for better government, lower taxes, and a strong national defense. Jo Ann believed that God called her to service, and in her years of service to this Nation, Jo Ann's reliance on God never wavered.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Virginia's First District is home to one of our Nation's most treasured historical sites. In 1607, our Nation's first settlement was founded at Jamestown. Jo Ann often reminded others in Virginia and around the Nation that she actually represented America's First District where the beginnings of America were founded.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Indeed, the First District has a rich history, including a significant and important military community. And Jo Ann was a tireless advocate for our brave servicemembers. She constantly supported legislation that strengthened our armed services and improved benefits for our men and women in uniform. As cochair and founding member of the Ship Building Caucus, she worked tirelessly to ensure that Congress provided for our Navy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Jo Ann truly loved her family and had an unwavering faith in our Lord and Savior, Jesus Christ. She regularly attended the Members' weekly prayer breakfast, and she was also cochair of the 2007 National Prayer Breakfast, an event designed to bring leaders of the country and leaders from around the world together in recognition of our dedication to God.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Jo Ann was known as an extraordinarily caring and helpful person, and anyone who came across her was touched. She worked on both sides of the aisle and truly defined bipartisanship.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Jo Ann represented the people of the First District of Virginia with extraordinary distinction, and through her service, she set an example of courage in the face of adversity. She refused to allow a disease that afflicts many to affect her life or to take away from her work that she loved so dearly. She was dedicated to representing her constituents even while undergoing chemotherapy treatments. And I have to say that the day after one of those chemotherapy treatments, she was in the little  town of Kilmarnock in the northern neck of Virginia to celebrate their 75th anniversary. I had the privilege of being with Jo Ann that day, and it was a cold, windy spring day, and she was there without a coat on. And I thought, how brave for her to be there right after a chemotherapy session, to be out there celebrating with the folks of Kilmarnock.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And that just proved to me what a brave and humble soul Jo Ann was and how she really had in mind others above herself.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, because of Jo Ann Davis' diligence and devoted service to our country, the Commonwealth of Virginia, and the people of the First District, I am proud to sponsor this legislation, and I urge my colleagues to support <bill type="h" number="5489">H.R. 5489</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400074" topic="">
    <paragraph>I continue to reserve.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400656" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, at this time, I would like to yield as much time as she may use to the gentlewoman from Virginia (Mrs. Drake).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400658" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would certainly like to thank my colleagues for this resolution today in honor of my dear friend, Congresswoman Jo Ann Davis.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Jo Ann really was the American dream, and we have all heard a lot about her life since her very unfortunate and very early passing last fall. But she came from a very poor childhood and reached just, I think, the highest of success to serve in this body.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But she was a success because she cared for other people and she put them first. And that's what people saw in Jo Ann. They loved and trusted her. She was a woman of great faith, great courage, great honesty, great strength, and great integrity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Jo Ann was a very private person, and when she told me of her diagnosis with breast cancer, I was really quite surprised that she had made the decision that she would be very public with her illness for the purpose of helping other women. I think we all admire and thank her for doing that. But I watched as she went through her chemo, and I saw how she struggled to be here with each and every one of us.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, Mr. Speaker, I just want to thank my colleagues. I know if Jo Ann were here today she would say, oh, don't bother doing that. But we all need a memory of Jo Ann. I think this is a fitting way to do it. She loved America. She served her constituents, she was true to herself, and she was a gift to each and every one of us who knew her.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400074" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I continue to reserve.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400656" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 2 minutes to my distinguished colleague from the State of North Carolina (Mrs. Myrick).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400288" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I thank the gentleman for yielding and also for bringing this resolution forward as a small token of honor for Jo Ann Davis.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>All of us in this Chamber loved her because Jo Ann was Jo Ann. She was simply who she was. She made no bones about it. As the gentlewoman from Virginia said, she came from a humble background and achieved very good things in her life. She did care about other people, and I think having this post office named after her lets the people in her district, every time they go by it, because it's on a main road, every time they go in it they will remember Jo Ann.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>She was a breast cancer survivor, as was mentioned, and she and I had a special bond not only because of that but because of a lot of similarities in our lives, and we all miss her greatly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But the thing about Jo Ann was she was here for the right reasons. She was here to do public service, she was here to help her constituents, and she did that, even in trying times. She still came here and did her job. And she served her people well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thank you again for this resolution, and I hope everyone will support it.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400074" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I continue to reserve.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400656" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no more speakers at this time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400074" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I urge my colleagues to give this recognition to our former colleague, Representative Jo Ann Davis, and urge the passage of this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400098" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today to honor my former colleague and friend, Jo Ann Davis. Congresswoman Davis was a remarkable woman whose courage under challenging circumstances made so many of us proud to be her friend. She never gave up during her valiant two-year fight  against breast cancer and continued to serve the citizens of the 1st District of Virginia throughout her treatments until her untimely death on October 6, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Inasmuch as Congresswoman Davis' district had a large number of Federal employees, and because of her impressive knowledge and advocacy on behalf of all civil servants, I appointed her Chairman of the Subcommittee on Civil Service and Agency Organization when I was Chairman of the Committee on Government Reform. Her dedication and sense of teamwork while a Member of Congress were traits I could always count on--as could the entire Virginia Delegation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is with pleasure I support the passage of <bill type="h" number="5489">H.R. 5489</bill> and thank Mr. Wittman for taking this opportunity to dedicate the Postal Service located at 6892 Main Street in Gloucester, Virginia in honor of our esteemed former colleague, Congresswoman Jo Ann Davis.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400435" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="5489">H.R. 5489</bill>, to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 6892 Main Street in Gloucester, Virginia, as the "Congresswoman Jo Ann S. Davis Post Office."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to thank Congressman Rob Wittman for introducing this legislation to honor the memory of our colleague and friend.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congresswoman Davis was not only my House colleague, she was my Virginia colleague who represented the First District of Virginia--a district, which she proudly called "America's 1st District" because of our country's roots at Jamestown and the many significant events in history, which occurred there.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Her career in elected office spanned 10 short years--from her first election in 1997 to the Virginia House of Delegates to her four elected terms in the House beginning in 2000. But over that decade, she made her mark as a deeply caring and hard-working public servant who believed in commonsense, conservative ideals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>She was a person of honesty, integrity, and strong moral conviction in representing her district and living her life. She was a dedicated and tenacious fighter for her beliefs, and the importance of her faith was obvious in the way she cared for and treated others. And, above all else, she worked tirelessly to protect the interests of the men and women in uniform, their families, and veterans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I believe that this designation will serve as a constant reminder to the constituents of the First District of Jo Ann's service and leadership. I wholeheartedly urge my colleagues to join us in recognizing Jo Ann's memory by supporting this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400060" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, just a few months ago, we said farewell to a great woman and a great patriot, my colleague of several years, Jo Ann Davis. Jo Ann was a terrific friend, and the Commonwealth of Virginia suffered tremendously from her loss.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since my days of serving with her in the Virginia House of Delegates, Jo Ann fought for and embodied the core values of Virginia. She was an ardent advocate for veterans, national defense and a strong military. The naming of a Gloucester post office in honor of Jo Ann Davis is a wonderful tribute that will serve as a reminder of her love and service to Virginia's First District.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400074" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Missouri (Mr. Clay) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="5489">H.R. 5489</bill>.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412255" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this motion will be postponed.</chair>
</record>
