<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1173114004" ordinal="31" title="AMENDMENT PROCESS FOR CONSIDERATION OF H.R. 700, HEALTHY COMMUNITIES WATER SUPPLY ACT; H.R. 569, WATER QUALITY INVESTMENT ACT; AND H.R. 720, WATER QUALITY FINANCING ACT OF 2007">
  <speaking speaker="400170" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the Rules Committee intends to meet Tuesday, March 6, to report rules for floor consideration of <bill type="h" number="569">H.R. 569</bill>, the Water Quality Investment Act; and <bill type="h" number="700">H.R. 700</bill>, the Healthy Communities Water Supply Act. It is anticipated that the rules will require that amendments be preprinted in the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Congressional Record prior to their consideration.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Members who wish to offer an amendment must preprint their amendments in the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Congressional Record by the close of business Tuesday, March 6, to ensure that their amendments are printed prior to consideration of the bill on the House floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Amendments should be drafted to the text of <bill type="h" number="569">H.R. 569</bill> or <bill type="h" number="700">H.R. 700</bill> as reported by the Transportation and Infrastructure Committee. The bills are posted on the Rules Committee Web site. Amendments should be drafted by Legislative Counsel and also should be reviewed by the Office of the Parliamentarian to be sure that amendments comply with the rules of the House. Members are also strongly encouraged to submit their amendments to the Congressional Budget Office for analysis regarding possible PAYGO  violations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, Mr. Speaker, the Rules Committee intends to meet this week to report a rule that could limit the amendment process on <bill type="h" number="720">H.R. 720</bill>, the Water Quality Financing Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Members who wish to offer an amendment to this bill should submit 55 copies of the amendment and a brief description of the amendment to the Rules Committee in H-312 in the Capitol no later than 12 noon on Wednesday, March 7.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Amendments must be drafted to the bill as ordered reported on March 1 by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure. A copy of that bill will be posted on the Web site of the Rules Committee. Amendments should be drafted by Legislative Counsel and also should be reviewed by the Office of the Parliamentarian to be sure that amendments comply with the rules of the House. Members are also strongly encouraged to submit their amendments to the Congressional Budget Office for analysis regarding  possible PAYGO violations.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
