<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1178812804" ordinal="29" title="SMALL BUSINESS FAIRNESS IN CONTRACTING ACT">
  <chair> Pursuant to House Resolution 383 and rule XVIII, the Chair declares the House in the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for the further consideration of the bill, <bill type="h" number="1873">H.R. 1873</bill>.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> When the Committee of the Whole rose on Wednesday, May 9, 2007, amendment No. 8 printed in House Report 110-137 by the gentlewoman from Texas (Ms. Jackson-Lee) had been disposed of.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400207" topic="">
    <paragraph>I was unavoidably detained. Had I been present, I would have voted "aye."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 5-minute vote.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 5-minute vote.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="ANNOUNCEMENT BY THE ACTING CHAIRMAN">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise today in strong support of <bill type="h" number="1873">H.R. 1873</bill>, the Small Business Fairness in Contracting Act. I commend my good friend from New York (Ms. VEL&#xC1;ZQUEZ) the Chairwoman of the Committee on Small Business for her leadership on this important legislation, and our colleague from Iowa (Mr. Braley), the bill's sponsor, for his work in crafting this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation would amend the Small Business Act to, among other things, revise and add to Small Business Administration (SBA) requirements concerning contract bundling; increase the government-wide goal for participation by small businesses in federal procurement and service contracts; include overseas contracts in such goal; and require certain small businesses to annually recertify compliance with maximum small business size standards for eligibility for SBA-awarded contracts and subcontracts.  These changes will make needed improvements to the contracting activities of federal departments and agencies with respect to America's small businesses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation also contains provisions that would direct the SBA Administrator to develop and maintain a database to assist small businesses in marketing to large corporations that have not achieved their small business goals; contact registered small businesses regarding the likelihood of federal contracting opportunities; prescribe regulations governing SBA review of subcontracting plans; ensure that whenever a small business loses a protest over its size, a notification is placed adjacent  to the listing for that business in the Central Contractor Registry (CCR); and ensure a biannual review of the CCR to purge businesses no longer considered small businesses. The SBA Administrator, as a result of this legislation, will be more able to advocate on behalf of and support America's small businesses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The federal marketplace today is worth upwards of $380 billion. That is, the federal government is the world's largest buyer of goods and services. Unfortunately, year after year, many federal agencies fall short of meeting mandated small business contracting goals. As a result, the numbers of and overall dollar amounts for contracts awarded to small businesses by departments and agencies of the federal government are not keeping pace with the overall growth of the federal marketplace. This legislation  would go far toward addressing this disturbing trend.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Small businesses constitute nearly ninety percent of the businesses in my district. Supporting them is a top priority for me. Small businesses are the engine of America's economy, representing roughly ninety-nine percent of all employers, creating half of our gross domestic product, and creating up to eighty percent of the new jobs today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Of particular importance to me, my constituents, and Guam's business community is Department of Defense small business contracting performance. The Department of Defense controls approximately seventy percent of the federal government's contracting dollars. But it controls the vast majority of the federal marketplace in my district, Guam. The amount of contracts issued by the Department of Defense for work on Guam will increase significantly in the years ahead as a result of the planned increase  in the military presence on the island.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ensuring that small businesses are prepared to and can successfully compete for contracts awarded by the Department of Defense is of particular importance to me. This is why I was very concerned last year when the Committee on Small Business issued its Scorecard VII Report. This report detailed federal government performance toward meeting small business contracting goals and found that approximately $8 billion of Department of Defense contracting money reported as going to small businesses was,  in fact, provided to large businesses. I was further concerned to learn from that report the Department of Defense from 2004 to 2005 has reduced its small business contract actions by sixty-five percent, despite the department having experienced a thirteen percent increase in total volume of contracts during the same period of time. I am</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nothing in this bill would change the fact that America's small business owners and operators must remain the hardworking innovators that they are and that they always have been in order for them to remain competitive and successful in the modem economy. This is particularly the case on Guam. Guam's small businesses will have to compete with bigger and better resourced companies that have significant capacity and that want to do business on Guam in support of the planned military build-up. The  pace of business on Guam will increase significantly. Guam's small firms need to prepare today to be ready to succeed in a more competitive environment. To do this, I continue to encourage Guam's small business owners and operators to, among other things, identify what their business does well today; what it can do better tomorrow; and what it can do better than others over the course of the military build-up on Guam.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But this much is true: America's small businesses deserve fairer treatment in the federal marketplace than they currently receive. This is why I support <bill type="h" number="1873">H.R. 1873</bill>. It is a bipartisan measure that represents a vital step toward leveling the playing field for America's twenty-six million small businesses. In doing so, <bill type="h" number="1873">H.R. 1873</bill> will help improve America's economy. Moreover, this legislation is critical toward improving the accountability in government contracting to America's small businesses.  I urge my colleagues support for this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the committee amendment in the nature of a substitute, as amended.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400123" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>I am in its current form.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will report the motion to recommit.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> The gentleman from Pennsylvania is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400123" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the motion to commit is very simple and self-explanatory, but at the same time, it is also very timely. It comes at a time when there are legitimate and growing concerns about the pending change in tax policy in America and how it might affect the most dynamic sector of the American economy, and that is, after all, small business.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We know that literally 80 percent of the small businesses, 80 percent of the jobs that are created in the economy in America are created in small business, as has been defined under statute. We are anticipating that as this body moves forward and has passed a budget from the majority that implies the largest tax increase in American history, implies the phaseout of tax policies that have grown the economy since 2001, implies that in order to deal with the pending challenge of the AMT, that there  is going to be a massive increase in personal rates, particularly at the high end, that affects subchapter S small businesses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We think that it is very important now to require the SBA administrator, under this motion, to consider small businesses as economically disadvantaged if they demonstrate an adverse impact due to the expiration of this tax relief. After all, who in this body could possibly be against accounting for and recognizing through an SBA designation the impact on such a vital portion of our economy before haphazardly increasing taxes through what we anticipate is going to be the father of all tax increases.  This is, I think, a huge challenge for us, and it is a challenge which we should adjust this program to acknowledge.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am concerned that if we see a change in our tax policies on this scale, that it is going to have a huge impact on small businesses in districts like mine. For example, the potential change in tax policy could dramatically downsize the section 179 small business expensing provision. This allows small businesses to immediately expense critical capital investment, allowing them to remain competitive in the global economy, allowing them to put money back into the their hands, back into their production  line, back into the hands of small business, an immediate write-off that demonstrably creates jobs right here in America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Without the help of section 179, many of our small businesses are at an enormous competitive disadvantage. Section 179 was once described to me by an economist as one of the most progrowth features currently in the Tax Code. The notion that we would allow it to lapse to its previous level is particularly troubling and I think requires us to prepare the SBA for the impact that these tax policy changes could have.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>All this motion to recommit is seeking to do is to give small businesses a tool to enhance their success in the marketplace, despite the potential for being hammered by a Brobdingnagian set of tax increases required by the budget that we are going to be facing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By offering this motion to recommit, we feel that the underlying bill ought to also lay before Congress a way to determine whether or not the tax increases that will be proposed by this budget will move small business backwards and also provide for a tool, but in a very small way, to counteract that. Every Member of this body should join me in supporting this motion to recommit if they care about the future ability of small businesses in their districts to grow, to survive, to compete and add  new jobs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge the adoption of this motion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ms. VEL&#xC1;ZQUEZ. Mr. Speaker, I rise in opposition to this motion.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentlewoman from New York is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400123" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I demand a recorded vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 9 of rule XX, the Chair will reduce to 5 minutes the minimum time for any electronic vote on the question of the passage of the bill.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 5-minute vote.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400065" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, on rollcall No. 323, I inserted by vote card but was not recorded. My intention was to vote "yes." Had I been present, I would have voted "aye."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
