<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1173200403" ordinal="41" title="AUTHORIZING USE OF ROTUNDA FOR CEREMONY TO AWARD CONGRESSIONAL MEDAL OF HONOR TO THE TUSKEGEE AIRMEN">
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from California (Ms. Millender-McDonald) and the gentleman from California (Mr. McCarthy) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412190" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself as much time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of <bill type="sc" number="15">S. Con. Res. 15</bill>, which authorizes the use of the rotunda of the Capitol for the ceremony to award the Congressional Gold Medal to the Tuskegee Airmen.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to thank the distinguished chairman from New York (Mr. Rangel) for sponsoring the House version of this resolution. I would also like to thank my Chair of House Administration for her work as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>All of our men and women of the armed services deserve our praise and recognition for the contributions they have made in defense of our country. It is notable that in the case of the Tuskegee Airmen they were fighting not one but two battles. As they bravely flew and maintained combat aircraft in World War II, these men also fought against the notion that somehow the color of their skin would affect their ability to courageously protect our Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1941, the formation of the all African American squadron based in Tuskegee, Alabama, a group that would come to be known as the Tuskegee Airmen, was largely regarded as an experiment of the U.S. military to test the combat readiness of the all-black fighting squadron. Sadly, there were some at the time who expected or perhaps even hoped that the experiment would fail. Instead, the Tuskegee Airmen became one of the most highly regarded units of the war, fighting bravely with distinction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Among the honors bestowed upon them, they were awarded 150 Distinguished Flying Crosses, 744 Air Medals, 14 Bronze Stars, and 8 Purple Hearts. I proudly support authorization of the use of the Capitol rotunda where they will be recognized once more for their bravery and for blazing a trail, not only in the sky, but in the history as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ms. MILLENDER-McDONALD. Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield as much time as he may consume to the gentleman from the great State of California (Mr. Daniel E. Lungren).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400617" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of this resolution authorizing the use of the rotunda of the Capitol for the ceremony honoring the Tuskegee Airmen with the Congressional Gold Medal. I am pleased that <bill type="sc" number="15">S. Con. Res. 15</bill> is currently under consideration.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As we all know, the Tuskegee Airmen were young men who enlisted to become America's first black military airmen at a time where, sadly in this country, there were many people who argued that black men lacked the necessary skills or ability to be part of an effective military force. Well, the Tuskegee Airmen effectively dispelled that notion that in any way African Americans were second-class citizens.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, although the term "hero" is perhaps overused in today's discourse, there is no better description of the Tuskegee Airmen. Not only were they the first black airmen to perform as they did, but they put their lives on the line for all Americans, regardless of color.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For that, we are all eternally grateful and eternally in their debt; and it is not only appropriate, but fitting, for us to take this step today. As one in his younger years who had an opportunity to meet some of these Tuskegee Airmen, I can tell you that they carried themselves with a great deal of pride in the contribution they had made to this Nation, and any conversations I had with such airmen, that is what they stressed, their contribution to this Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So it is fitting that we take the time, as a thankful Nation, to give them this respect and honor them in this singular way with a Congressional Gold Medal and to have this done here at the center, at the heart of our democracy, the rotunda of the United States Capitol.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412190" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ms. MILLENDER-McDONALD. On March 29 of this year, this Nation will give to its Americans, rightfully, the Congressional Gold Medal that they deserve</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400199" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in strong support of <bill type="hc" number="78">H. Con. Res. 78</bill>, which authorizes the use of the Capitol Rotunda for a ceremony to award the Congressional Gold Medal to the Tuskegee Airmen. I strongly support the resolution because it is an appropriate and fitting tribute to one of the greatest groups of the Greatest Generation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On July 19, 1941, the American Air Force created an all black flight training program at the Tuskegee Institute in Alabama. The Tuskegee Airmen were not only unique in their military record, but they inspired revolutionary reform in the Armed Forces, paving the way for integration of the Armed Services in the U.S.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The first class of cadets began in July of 1941 with 13 men, all of whom had college degrees, some with PhDs and all had pilot's licenses. From all accounts, the training of the Tuskegee Airmen was an experiment established to prove that "coloreds" were incapable of operating expensive and complex combat aircraft. Stationed in the segregated South, the black cadets were denied rifles.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Tuskegee Airmen were credited with 261 aircraft destroyed, 148 aircraft damaged, 15,553 combat sorties and 1,578 missions over Italy and North Africa. They destroyed or damaged over 950 units of ground transportation and escorted more than 200 bombing missions. "We proved that the antidote to racism is excellence in performance," said retired LTC Herbert Carter, who started his military career as a pilot and maintenance officer with the Tuskegee Airmen's 99th Fighter Squadron. Clearly,  the experiment, as it was called, was an unqualified success.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Tuskegee Airmen were awarded 3 Presidential Unit Citations, 150 Distinguished Flying Crosses and Legions of Merit, along with The Red Star of Yugoslavia, 9 Purple Hearts, 14 Bronze Stars and more than 700 Air Medals and clusters. On February 28, 2006, the House passed <bill type="hc" number="1259">H. Con. Res. 1259</bill>, authorizing the award of a Congressional Gold Medal on behalf of the Tuskegee Airmen. The President signed the legislation and it became Public Law 109-213 on April 11, 2006. The concurrent resolution before  us authorizes the use of the Capitol Rotunda on March 29, 2007, for the award ceremony.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to thank Congressman RANGEL for his tenacity in seeing to it that the contributions of Tuskegee Airmen are fully recognized and acknowledged by the people of the United States. I urge my colleagues to join me in supporting the resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ms. MILLENDER-McDONALD. Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from California (Ms. Millender-McDonald) that the House suspend the rules and concur in the Senate concurrent resolution, <bill type="sc" number="15">S. Con. Res. 15</bill>.</chair>
</record>
