<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1184040000" ordinal="18" title="NEW MEXICO WATER PLANNING ASSISTANCE ACT">
  <narrative>NEW MEXICO WATER PLANNING ASSISTANCE ACT -- (House of Representatives - July 10, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H7445]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412212" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="1904">H.R. 1904</bill>) to provide assistance to the State of New Mexico for the development of comprehensive State water plans, and for other purposes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="1904">H.R. 1904</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "New Mexico Water Planning Assistance Act".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. DEFINITIONS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; In this Act:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) SECRETARY.--The term "Secretary" means the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Reclamation and the United States Geological Survey.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) STATE.--The term "State" means the State of New Mexico.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 3. COMPREHENSIVE WATER PLAN ASSISTANCE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) In General.--Upon the request of the Governor of the State and subject to subsections (b) through (f), the Secretary shall--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) provide to the State technical assistance and grants for the development of comprehensive State water plans;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) conduct water resources mapping in the State; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) conduct a comprehensive study of groundwater resources (including potable, brackish, and saline water resources) in the State to assess the quantity, quality, and interaction of groundwater and surface water resources.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Technical Assistance.--Technical assistance provided under subsection (a) may include--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) acquisition of hydrologic data, groundwater characterization, database development, and data distribution;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) expansion of climate, surface water, and groundwater monitoring networks;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) assessment of existing water resources, surface water storage, and groundwater storage potential;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) numerical analysis and modeling necessary to provide an integrated understanding of water resources and water management options;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) participation in State planning forums and planning groups;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (6) coordination of Federal water management planning efforts;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (7) technical review of data, models, planning scenarios, and water plans developed by the State; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (8) provision of scientific and technical specialists to support State and local activities.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Allocation.--In providing grants under subsection (a), the Secretary shall, subject to the availability of appropriations, allocate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) $5,000,000 to develop hydrologic models and acquire associated equipment for the New Mexico Rio Grande main stem sections and Rios Pueblo de Taos and Hondo, Rios Nambe, Pojoaque and Teseque, Rio Chama, and Lower Rio Grande tributaries;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) $1,500,000 to complete the hydrographic survey development of hydrologic models and acquire associated equipment for the San Juan River and tributaries;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) $1,000,000 to complete the hydrographic survey development of hydrologic models and acquire associated equipment for Southwest New Mexico, including the Animas Basin, the Gila River, and tributaries;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) $4,500,000 for statewide digital orthophotography mapping; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) such sums as are necessary to carry out additional projects consistent with subsection (b).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (d) Cost-Sharing Requirement.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) IN GENERAL.--The non-Federal share of the total cost of any activity carried out using a grant provided under subsection (a) shall be 50 percent.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) FORM OF NON-FEDERAL SHARE.--The non-Federal share under paragraph (1) may be in the form of any in-kind services that the Secretary determines would contribute substantially toward the conduct and completion of the activity assisted.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (e) Nonreimbursable Basis.--Any assistance or grants provided to the State under this Act shall be made on a non-reimbursable basis.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (f) Authorized Transfers.--On request of the State, the Secretary shall directly transfer to 1 or more Federal agencies any amounts made available to the State to carry out this Act.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 4. AUTHORIZATION OF APPROPRIATIONS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act $3,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2008 through 2012.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 5. SUNSET OF AUTHORITY.</narrative>
  <narrative> The authority of the Secretary to carry out any provisions of this Act shall terminate 10 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Maryland (Mr. Sarbanes) and the gentleman from Oklahoma (Mr. Cole) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Maryland.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412212" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Maryland?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412212" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of <bill type="h" number="1904">H.R. 1904</bill>, as introduced by our colleague from New Mexico (Mrs. Wilson), is to provide assistance to the State of New Mexico for the development of comprehensive State water plans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill directs the Secretary of the Interior to provide New Mexico with technical assistance and grants for the development of a comprehensive State water plan. This includes a survey and mapping of water resources in New Mexico, a study of groundwater quality and quantity, and a study on the relationships between groundwater and surface water in the State.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A key understanding of our most precious resource is required if we are to meet the water supply needs of our growing communities and our environment. <bill type="h" number="1904">H.R. 1904</bill> seeks just such an understanding from New Mexico.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to join me in supporting <bill type="h" number="1904">H.R. 1904</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400077" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="1904">H.R. 1904</bill> and yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1904">H.R. 1904</bill>, introduced by our colleague, HEATHER WILSON, directs the Secretary of the Interior to provide New Mexico with technical assistance and grants for the development of comprehensive State water plans and to assess the quality, quantity and interaction of groundwater and surface water resources in the State.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation recognizes that States have primacy over groundwater but provides limited Federal assistance to help the State carry out its efforts and help water consumers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412212" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Maryland (Mr. Sarbanes) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="1904">H.R. 1904</bill>.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the bill was passed.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
