<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1185163200" ordinal="30" title="RESOLUTION COMMENDING IDAHO ON WINNING THE BID TO HOST THE 2009 SPECIAL OLYMPICS WORLD WINTER GAMES">
  <narrative>RESOLUTION COMMENDING IDAHO ON WINNING THE BID TO HOST THE 2009 SPECIAL OLYMPICS WORLD WINTER GAMES -- (House of Representatives - July 23, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H8210]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400371" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution (<bill type="hr" number="380">H. Res. 380</bill>) commending Idaho on winning the bid to host the 2009 Special Olympics World Winter Games.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the resolution.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the resolution is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="hr" number="380">H. Res. 380</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas Special Olympics is an international nonprofit organization that promotes personal development through sports training and competition;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Special Olympics advances the understanding of intellectual disabilities through participation and fellowship in the Nation and around the World;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Special Olympics serves more than 2,500,000 individuals with intellectual disabilities around the globe;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Special Olympics offers more than 205 programs in over 165 countries; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Special Olympics offers 30 Olympic-type summer and winter sports to both children and adults with intellectual disabilities;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Boise, Idaho won the International bid to host the 2009 Special Olympics World Winter Games to be held during February 6-13, 2009;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas thousands of athletes are expected to compete in 7 winter sports in the 2009 Special Olympics World Winter Games; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the 2009 Special Olympics World Winter Games will be the largest multi-sport event ever held in the State of Idaho: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, &lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; That the House of Representatives--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) applauds the goals and principles of Special Olympics;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) salutes the athletes, coaches, family members, friends, and volunteers that make Special Olympics World Winter Games possible;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) congratulates the State of Idaho as the host for the 2009 Special Olympics World Winter Games; and</narrative>
  <narrative> (4) supports the 2009 Special Olympic World Winter Games and the goals of the Special Olympics to enrich the lives of people with intellectual disabilities through sports.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from California (Mr. Sherman) and the gentleman from Indiana (Mr. Pence) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from California.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400371" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in strong support of this resolution and yield myself as much time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1968, Eunice Kennedy Shriver, the world's great champion of people with intellectual disabilities, created the Special Olympics. For Mrs. Shriver, the founding of the Special Olympics was a capstone of her decades-long effort to improve the lives of people with intellectual disabilities. It is a testament to her dogged dedication that the Special Olympics thrives today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Eunice's idea was simple: give people with intellectual disabilities the same opportunities other young people have to develop their physical fitness, to create friendships, and to enjoy the thrill of competition.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, the Special Olympics offers year-round training in 30 summer and winter sports for both children and adults with intellectual disabilities. The Special Olympics serves more than 2.25 million intellectually disabled people through 200 programs in 160 countries.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to salute my colleague Mr. Sali from Idaho for introducing this legislation. Mr. Sali rightfully takes pride that his State has landed the honor of hosting the 2009 Special Olympics World Winter Games. Being named host of the 2009 winter games is a tremendous achievement for the great State of Idaho. There could be no better backdrop than the stark beauty of the State of Idaho and the Sawtooth Mountains.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Special Olympics has become an important global event. The 2009 games will include thousands of competitors from over 100 countries competing in seven different winter sports. It will be the largest multisport event in the history of the State of Idaho. Idaho will be a terrific host for an event that empowers these brave young men and women and builds their self-esteem.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this important resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400315" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Mr. PENCE asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400315" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I'd like to congratulate Idaho on its successful bid, as well, to host the 2009 Special Olympics World Winter Games and express strong support for <bill type="hr" number="380">H. Res. 380</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Special Olympics program has benefited countless people with disabilities nationwide and around the globe, raising awareness, fostering support for a great cause while enabling the participants to enhance their self-confidence and gain a sense of well-deserved personal accomplishment through sports and competition. It is, in every sense, a blessing to the participants.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The millions of volunteers, coaches and athletes involved with the Special Olympics do a great service for their community and their country and, of course, to those with intellectual disabilities. I would also say, though, having been involved and been in attendance at Special Olympics programs, I haven't met a volunteer yet, Mr. Speaker, who didn't think that they were richer as a result of their participation in this extraordinary program, to see the courage of those who compete and the extraordinary  sacrifice of the parents of those who bring them to such a wonderful opportunity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Through the dedication of these volunteers, the Special Olympics have continued to grow and impact the lives of more and more people around the world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The 2009 Winter Games in Idaho promise to be a great showcase for Special Olympics participants from around the world to compete at a high level and demonstrate that disabilities are no match for individuals who are driven to succeed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, I congratulate Idaho for being selected as the host of an event of such magnitude. I extend my best wishes to their new Governor and my friend, and I am fully confident that it will be a resounding success.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to render their full support for this resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400371" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400315" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I again express support for <bill type="hr" number="380">H. Res. 380</bill> and congratulate the State of Idaho for winning the opportunity to host the 2009 Special Olympics World Winter Games.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from California (Mr. Sherman) that the House suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, <bill type="hr" number="380">H. Res. 380</bill>.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the resolution was agreed to.</chair>
</record>
