<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1189440002" ordinal="25" title="SUPPORTING THE GOALS AND IDEALS OF PANCREATIC CANCER AWARENESS MONTH">
  <narrative>SUPPORTING THE GOALS AND IDEALS OF PANCREATIC CANCER AWARENESS MONTH -- (House of Representatives - September 10, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H10333]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution (<bill type="hr" number="257">H. Res. 257</bill>) supporting the goals and ideals of Pancreatic Cancer Awareness Month, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the resolution.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the resolution is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="hr" number="257">H. Res. 257</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas over 37,170 people will be diagnosed with pancreatic cancer this year in the United States; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas pancreatic cancer is the fourth most common cause of cancer death in the United States; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas 75 percent of pancreatic cancer patients die within the first year of their diagnosis, and only 5 percent survive more than 5 years, making pancreatic cancer the deadliest of any cancer; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas there has been no significant improvement in survival rates in the last 25 years, and pancreatic cancer research is still in the earliest scientific stages; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas there are no early detection methods and minimal treatment options for pancreatic cancer; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas when symptoms of pancreatic cancer generally present themselves, it is too late for an optimistic prognosis, and the average survival rate of those diagnosed with metastatic disease is only 3 to 6 months; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the incidence rate of pancreatic cancer is 40 to 50 percent higher in African Americans than in other ethnic groups; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Pancreatic Cancer Action Network (PanCAN) is a national patient advocacy organization that serves the pancreatic cancer community by focusing its efforts on public policy, research funding, patient services, and public awareness and education related to developing effective treatments and a cure for pancreatic cancer; and &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Pancreatic Cancer Action Network has requested that the Congress designate November as Pancreatic Cancer Awareness Month in order to educate communities across the Nation about pancreatic cancer and the need for research funding, early detection methods, effective treatments, and prevention programs: Now, therefore, be it</narrative>
  <narrative> Resolved, That the House of Representatives supports the goals and ideals of Pancreatic Cancer Awareness Month.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Davis) and the gentleman from Idaho (Mr. Sali) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Illinois.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days in which to revise and extend their remarks.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Illinois?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, as a member of the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, I am pleased to join my colleague in the consideration of <bill type="hr" number="257">H. Res. 257</bill>, a resolution supporting the goals and ideals of Pancreatic Cancer Awareness Month.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="hr" number="257">H. Res. 257</bill>, which has 77 cosponsors, was introduced by Representative TODD PLATTS on March 20, 2007. <bill type="hr" number="257">H. Res. 257</bill> was reported from the Oversight Committee on June 12, 2007, by voice vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, pancreatic cancer is the fourth most common cause of cancer death in the United States. It develops when cancerous cells form in the tissues of one's pancreas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Pancreatic cancer spreads rapidly and is seldom detected in its early stages, which is a major reason why it is one of the leading causes of cancer death. The American Cancer Society estimated that 37,000 people will be diagnosed this year with pancreatic cancer in the United States, and about 33,000 of them will die.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I support the goals and ideals of Pancreatic Cancer Awareness Month in order to educate people about pancreatic cancer and the need for research funding, early detection methods, effective treatments, and preventative programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, Mr. Speaker, I commend my colleague, Representative Platts, for introducing this legislation and urge its swift passage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412201" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Pancreatic cancer, the fourth most common cause of cancer death in the United States, is a devastating disease caused by excessive cellular growth in the pancreatic gland. Approximately 37,200 people will be diagnosed with pancreatic cancer this year alone. Sadly, the average life expectancy for those diagnosed is only 3 to 6 months.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Despite the lethal nature of pancreatic cancer, research remains in the earliest scientific stages, and there are currently no identifiable early warning signs. By the time the symptoms become evident, it is almost always too late for successful treatment. While research and scientific developments have led to lower mortality rates for other types of cancer, such as cancer of the breasts, lung, prostate, and colon, the mortality rate for pancreatic cancer continues unabated.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Pancreatic Cancer Action Network, PanCAN, is the only national patient advocacy organization that serves the pancreatic cancer community. It focuses its efforts on public policy, research funding, patient services, public awareness, and education related to the development of an effective treatment and ultimately a cure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>PanCAN will once again be promoting pancreatic awareness during the month of November to educate citizens about pancreatic cancer, the need for funding, early detection methods, effective treatment, and prevention programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In honor of the many victims of this horrific disease and the efforts of the Pancreatic Cancer Action Network, I ask that the Members of Congress join me in declaring support for the goals of Pancreatic Cancer Awareness Month.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no further requests for time, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, it is my pleasure to yield such time as he may consume to the distinguished gentleman from the State of Maryland, the Honorable ELIJAH CUMMINGS.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400090" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, today I rise in support of <bill type="hr" number="257">H. Res. 257</bill>, a resolution that recognizes the goals and ideals of the National Pancreatic Awareness Month, which is in November.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today's consideration of this legislation comes on the heels of a recent tragedy that shook the Nation and the world. Last week, Italian operatic icon Luciano Pavarotti died in his home in Modena, Italy, from pancreatic cancer. He was 71 years old.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Pavarotti's flawless, rich sound left audiences awe-struck, earning him the nickname of the "King of the High Cs." I count myself among the millions of fans who were moved by his powerful voice.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Like Enrico Caruso and Jenny Lind before him, Pavarotti's talent was recognized beyond the standard opera audience. He became a household name in the 1990s with his popular "Pavarotti and Friends" charity concerts, performing with rock stars like Elton John, Sting, and Bono.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The maestro's moving music and charismatic demeanor will be remembered for generations to come. As we celebrate the life and legacy of one of the greatest tenors the world has ever known, we must also reflect on the need to improve the diagnosis and treatment of the disease that tragically took his life, pancreatic cancer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is why I am a lead sponsor of <bill type="hr" number="257">H. Res. 257</bill>, which highlights the need for improved investment in pancreatic cancer research. Pavarotti might still be alive today if we had made a greater commitment to fighting this very tragic disease.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Pavarotti's story is like so many other individuals who suffer from pancreatic cancer. He was diagnosed in 2006 and underwent surgery in July of that year. Treatment failed, however, and he eventually succumbed to the disease.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Far too many Americans and people around the world find that a diagnosis of pancreatic cancer is a death sentence. Seventy-five percent of all patients with pancreatic cancer die within 12 months of diagnosis. Only 5 percent of pancreatic cancer patients survive more than 5 years, making it the deadliest of any cancer. Of the 37,170 Americans who are expected to be diagnosed in 2007, an estimated 33,000 will die this year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Pancreatic cancer is the fourth leading cause of cancer death in the United States and the third leading cause of cancer death among 40- to 59-year-old men. It is a disease that disproportionately affects minorities. The incidence rate of pancreatic cancer is 40 to 50 percent higher in the African American community than in any other ethnic group.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, our financial commitment to the disease has not matched its impact. Only 1 1/2  percent of the National Cancer Institute's $4.747 billion cancer research budget for 2006 went to pancreatic cancer. No significant improvement in survival rates has been made in the last 25 years, and pancreatic cancer research is still in the earliest scientific stages.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are no early detection methods and minimal treatment options for pancreatic cancer. Sadly, when symptoms of pancreatic cancer present themselves, it is usually too late for an optimistic prognosis; and the average survival rate of those diagnosed with metastasis disease is only 3 to 6 months.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is simply unacceptable. We can do better, and we owe it to our citizens and to the legacy of the great Pavarotti to do better.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For this reason, I have joined my colleague, Congressman TODD RUSSELL PLATTS of Pennsylvania, in introducing <bill type="hr" number="257">H. Res. 257</bill>. We are also joined by 83 of our colleagues who are cosponsors of the bill. I want to thank Congressman Platts for his leadership on this issue, subcommittee Chairman DANNY DAVIS, and full committee Chairman HENRY WAXMAN for bringing this legislation to the floor, and our friends on the other side.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge all of my colleagues to vote in favor of this resolution and to join efforts to increase Federal support for pancreatic cancer research.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>I want to thank the gentleman from Maryland (Mr. Cummings) for his remarks.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412233" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of House Resolution 257, supporting the goals and ideals of Pancreatic Cancer Awareness Month.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By increasing awareness, we look to shine a spotlight on a disease that has historically received little attention from the Federal government: pancreatic cancer. It is the fourth most deadly cancer for both men and women, but research on pancreatic cancer is decades behind other cancers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I was fortunate to have a group of my constituents from the 8th District of Pennsylvania teach me more about this devastating illness. They work with the Pancreatic Cancer Action Network and are fighting hard to raise awareness and improve patient services to beat this disease.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>They told me that this year more than 37,000 Americans will be diagnosed and almost as many will die from the disease. It is difficult to recognize and with no early screening test, symptoms are often mistaken for other ailments. Because of this lack of early detection, 75 percent of those diagnosed don't survive longer than a year and only 5 percent survive more than 5 years. Pancreatic cancer shows no signs of slowing--with diagnoses and deaths increasing every year. Men and African-Americans  are particularly at risk, but with no significant improvement in survival rates in the last 25 years, every American needs to be aware.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A number of treatments are in development. Patients can undergo chemotherapy, radiation, surgery, or experimental treatments such as chemotherapy drugs or vaccines. While doctors and scientists are working hard to find a cure, they need our help to fund their important research and assist in educating the public.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, with so many Americans diagnosed each year, we must act with urgency. We must increase awareness in our communities and across our country in order to intensify our focus to find a cure. Through educating the public about this quiet killer, we can increase early diagnosis and improve the prognoses and treatment of the disease. Mr. Speaker, it is time to face this disease head-on and fight back.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400321" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise to strongly support House Resolution 257. This resolution will to help increase awareness for pancreatic cancer, the deadliest of all cancers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, few Americans may understand that pancreatic cancer is a horrific killer. This year alone, over 37,000 people will be diagnosed with this disease. Sadly, 99% of those diagnosed will lose their lives due to a lack of early detection tools.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many Americans are not aware that pancreatic cancer has the highest mortality rate of all cancers; only 4 percent of patients will survive beyond 5 years after diagnosis. This is why it is a moral imperative for Congress to work to increase awareness of this deadly cancer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I became aware of the Pancreatic Cancer Action Network (known as "Pan CAN") through a constituent of mine, Bob Hammen, who lost his wife to this terrible disease. Pan CAN is the only national advocacy organization which provides support for pancreatic cancer patients and their families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In their efforts to raise awareness for pancreatic cancer, Pan CAN regards each November as Pancreatic Cancer Awareness Month. <bill type="hr" number="257">H. Res. 257</bill> supports Pan CAN's efforts to raise the awareness which is desperately needed to improve early detection methods and treatment for this disease.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, because all of our fellow citizens have family, friends, and neighbors who are regrettably vulnerable to this dreaded disease, I urge support from my distinguished colleagues for this resolution here today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of House Resolution 257, supporting the goals and ideals of Pancreatic Cancer Awareness Month. Pancreatic Cancer Awareness Month aims to help educate communities across our country about pancreatic cancer and the need for research funding, early detection methods, effective treatments, and prevention programs. These are important goals and ones that I support fully.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is appalling that only 5 percent of persons diagnosed with pancreatic cancer this year will reach the five year survival mark. The Pancreatic Cancer Action Network (PanCAN), founded in 1999, is dedicated to improving survival rates. The Network's sponsors innovative and highly acclaimed programs intended to meet the informational needs of the panereatic cancer community. The PanCAN founders, directors, staff, donors, affiliated health care professionals, partners and volunteers are to be commended  for their work and the successes they have achieved.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The instances of panceatic cancer in Americans--indeed instances of all cancers in Americans--must be reduced and survivability rates increased. I am committed to helping achieving those goals. But achieving them is not an easy task.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For instance, as the Chair of the Congressional Asian Pacific American Caucus' Health Task Force, I am acutely aware of the high rates of cancer infections present in the Asian and Pacific Islander American communities. I am also all too aware of the disparities that exist for and the challenges that must be overcome by individuals--especially women--from minority communities in order for them to gain access to screening and diagnostic services for all types of cancer. Moreover, I remain very  concerned about the scarcity of oncology services in rural or isolated areas in the United States, such as Guam.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am encouraged by the focus the Pancreatic Cancer Awareness Month brings on the need to and importance of educating communities across our country about pancreatic cancer and the need for research funding, early detection methods, effective treatments, and prevention programs. I urge the leaders of the Pancreatic Cancer Awareness Month and PanCAN to work to ensure that minority communities and individuals who reside in rural and insular areas across our country benefit from these outreach efforts.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no further requests for time, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by  the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Davis) that the House suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, <bill type="hr" number="257">H. Res. 257</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this motion will be postponed.</chair>
</record>
