<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1173114004" ordinal="17" title="LOWELL NATIONAL HISTORICAL PARK BOUNDARY ADJUSTMENT ACT">
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="299">H.R. 299</bill>) to adjust the boundary of Lowell National Historical Park, and for other purposes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) and the gentleman from Utah (Mr. Bishop) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Arizona?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, <bill type="h" number="299">H.R. 299</bill>, introduced by my colleague from Massachusetts (Mr. Meehan), provides for a minor boundary adjustment to the Lowell National Historic Park. Lowell National Historic Park was established in 1978 to commemorate the City of Lowell's prominent role in the American Industrial Revolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="299">H.R. 299</bill> would authorize the Secretary of the Interior to acquire five small tracts of land totaling less than 1 acre. These tracts are necessary to complete development of the canalway, a linear park and walkway along Lowell's 5.6-mile historic power canal system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These parcels provide the access points needed for the development, maintenance, and surveillance necessary to complete the historic canalway. While the total boundary adjustment is less than 1 acre, it would allow public access to at least 2 miles of this historic canalway.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to commend my colleague from Massachusetts (Mr. Meehan) for his efforts on behalf of Lowell National Historic Park. He has worked diligently to advance many partnership efforts such as this one, which would bring together Federal, State, and local resources to preserve and interpret the park.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, <bill type="h" number="299">H.R. 299</bill> is supported by the administration, the City of Lowell, and the Commonwealth of Massachusetts. Identical legislation was approved by the House last Congress, and we urge our colleagues to support this measure today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400029" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="299">H.R. 299</bill>, and I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the majority has adequately explained this bill, which passed the House in the 109th Congress and is supported by the administration. I urge adoption of this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400269" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I want to thank the Gentleman from West Virginia (Mr. RAHALL) and the Gentleman from Arizona (Mr. GRIJALVA) for bringing this important bill to the floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill passed the House unanimously last December, and the other body was unable to take it up before the 109th Congress ended. I am hopeful that, given more time, this bill will work its way through the Senate and be signed into law by the President.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mister speaker, my bill is simple but its impact cannot be overstated. This bill will authorize the Secretary of the Interior to acquire five small tracts of land totaling less than an acre and add them to the boundaries of the Lowell National Historical Park.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Adding these small tracts of land will allow the park to add more and safer access points, and allow the visiting public full access to the entire canal system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The park was created in 1978, a product of the late Paul Tsongas and his vision for Lowell, Massachusetts. Paul knew that Lowell, as the cradle of America's Industrial Revolution, was worthy of preservation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The park attracts three-quarters of a million visitors each year, and the ripple effect is significant.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since the park has come into existence, Lowell has been named a Distinctive Destination City by the National Trust for Historic Preservation and an All American City by the National Civic League.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill will keep the progress at the Park rolling, by allowing the last two miles of Lowell's historic canal way to be accessed by the public.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to thank Park Superintendent Michael Creasey, Assistant Superintendent Peter Aucella, and all the others that have worked on this project.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Their tireless efforts, and the effort of their staff, keep Lowell National Historical Park as one of the crown jewels of the national park system, and make the Mill City proud.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400029" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no additional speakers, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="299">H.R. 299</bill>.</chair>
</record>
