<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1206979203" ordinal="11" title="CAPTIVE WILDLIFE SAFETY TECHNICAL AMENDMENTS ACT OF 2008">
  <narrative>CAPTIVE WILDLIFE SAFETY TECHNICAL AMENDMENTS ACT OF 2008 -- (House of Representatives - March 31, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H1781]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400001" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="4933">H.R. 4933</bill>) to amend the Lacey Act Amendments of 1981 to protect captive wildlife and to make technical corrections, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="4933">H.R. 4933</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "Captive Wildlife Safety Technical Amendments Act of 2008".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. CAPTIVE WILDLIFE SAFETY AMENDMENTS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Prohibited Acts.--Section 3 of the Lacey Act Amendments of 1981 (16 U.S.C. 3372) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in subsection (a)(2)--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) in subparagraph (A), by inserting "or" after the semicolon;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) in subparagraph (B), by striking "; or" and inserting a semicolon; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) by striking subparagraph (C); and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) in subsection (e)--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) by redesignating paragraphs (2), (3), (4), and (5) as paragraphs (3), (4), (5), and (6) respectively; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) by striking "(e)" and all that follows through "Subsection (a)(2)(C)" in paragraph (1) and inserting the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(e) Captive Wildlife Offenses.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(1) IN GENERAL.--It is unlawful for any person--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(A) to import, export, transport, sell, receive, acquire, or purchase in interstate or foreign commerce any live animal of any prohibited wildlife species; or&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(B) to attempt to commit any act described in subparagraph (A).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(2) NONAPPLICABILITY.--This subsection";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) in paragraph (2) (as redesignated by subparagraph (A))--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) by striking "a" before "prohibited" and inserting "any";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) by striking "(3)" and inserting "(4)"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (iii) by striking "(2)" and inserting "(3)";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (D) in paragraph (3) (as redesignated by subparagraph (A))--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) in subparagraph (C)--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (I) in clauses (ii) and (iii), by striking "animals listed in section 2(g)" each place it appears and inserting "prohibited wildlife species"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (II) in clause (iv), by striking "animals" and inserting "prohibited wildlife species"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) in subparagraph (D)--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (I) by striking "the animal" the first place it appears and inserting "an animal of any prohibited wildlife species"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (II) by striking "the animal" the second place it appears and inserting "that animal";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (E) in paragraph (4) (as redesignated by subparagraph (A)), by striking "(2)" and inserting "(3)";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (F) in paragraph (6) (as redesignated by subparagraph (A))--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) by striking "subsection (a)(2)(C)" and inserting "this subsection"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) by striking "fiscal years 2004 through 2008" and inserting "fiscal years 2009 through 2013"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (G) by inserting after paragraph (6) (as redesignated by subparagraph (A)) the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(7) APPLICATION.--This subsection shall apply beginning on the effective date of regulations promulgated under this subsection.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Civil Penalties.--Section 4(a) of the Lacey Act Amendments of 1981 (16 U.S.C. 3373(a)) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in paragraph (1), by striking "subsections (b) and (d)" and inserting "subsections (b), (d), and (e)"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) in paragraph (1), by striking "section 3(d)" and inserting "subsection (d) or (e) of section 3".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Criminal Penalties.--Section 4(d) of the Lacey Act Amendments of 1981 (16 U.S.C. 3373(d)) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in paragraphs (1)(A) and (1)(B) and in the first sentence of paragraph (2), by striking "subsections (b) and (d)" each place it appears and inserting "subsections (b), (d), and (e)"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) in paragraph (3), by striking "section 3(d)" and inserting "subsection (d) or (e) of section 3".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (d) Correction of Prior Amendment.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) CORRECTION.--Section 102(c) of Public Law 100-653 (102 Stat. 3826) is amended by striking "section 3(b)" and inserting "subsection 3(b)". &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) EFFECTIVE DATE.--This subsection shall take effect upon enactment of Public Law 100-653.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 3. APPLICABILITY PROVISION AMENDMENT.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Section 3 of the Captive Wildlife Safety Act (117 Stat. 2871; Public Law 108-191) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in subsection (a), by striking "(a) In General.--Section 3" and inserting "Section 3"; and</narrative>
  <narrative> (2) by striking subsection (b).&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Hawaii (Mr. Abercrombie) and the gentleman from Utah (Mr. Bishop) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Hawaii.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400001" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Hawaii?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400001" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="4933">H.R. 4933</bill>, the Captive Wildlife Safety Technical Amendments Act of 2008, was introduced by my colleague from Guam (Ms. Bordallo). As Mr. Kennedy indicated, unfortunately, she cannot be here in person at the moment because she is on her way here from Guam, but hopefully will arrive before the end of the proceedings. Coming as I do, Madam Speaker, on a 5,000 mile one-way commute, I have a lot of empathy and sympathy for her journey. But the issue before us today is very, very  important both to her and to Members of the House and, by extension, the Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Captive Wildlife Safety Act, Public Law 108-191, amended the Lacey Act Amendments of 1981, and that made it unlawful for any person to import, export, transport, sell, receive, acquire, or purchase in interstate or foreign commerce any prohibited wildlife species.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After the law was enacted, the Fish and Wildlife Service and the Department of Justice identified technical drafting problems that made full implementation and enforcement impossible. <bill type="h" number="4933">H.R. 4933</bill> would make those technical changes to the law needed to allow the original intent of the legislation to be achieved.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, on a personal note, I might add that, under Chairman Pombo, I had the privilege of traveling with him to Africa for the CITES, Convention on International Treaty on Endangered Species, so we could see with our own eyes what the consequences are by not having legislation like this correctly in place. The wildlife species are totally dependent upon human beings as the stewards of this planet and, most certainly, as the stewards of their welfare and for the salvation of endangered  species, not just in our country, but overseas as well. Therefore, I ask Members on both sides to support passage of this noncontroversial bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>May I say also, Madam Speaker, what a privilege it is to be on the floor with Mr. Bishop of Utah. I have the honor of serving with him on the Resources Committee, and have always valued his insight and perspective.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400029" topic="">
    <paragraph>I appreciate those kind words, and I will try to be as introspective as I possibly can here.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Public Law 108-191 made it illegal to buy, sell, or trade certain large exotic cats in interstate or foreign commerce. These include cheetahs, cougars, jaguars, leopards, lions, tigers, and bears, oh my. The measure did not ban the private ownership of these cats, and specific exemptions were provided for qualified aquariums, circuses, sanctuaries, and zoos.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the 5 years that this law has been enacted, the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service has been unable to prosecute anyone because of drafting deficiencies; so, I would urge an "aye" vote on <bill type="h" number="4933">H.R. 4933</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400001" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Hawaii (Mr. Abercrombie) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="4933">H.R. 4933</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the bill, as amended, was passed.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
