<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1176912003" ordinal="42" title="RELIEF FOR ENTREPRENEURS: COORDINATION OF OBJECTIVES AND VALUES FOR EFFECTIVE RECOVERY ACT OF 2007">
  <chair> Pursuant to House Resolution 302 and rule XVIII, the Chair declares the House in the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for the consideration of the bill, <bill type="h" number="1361">H.R. 1361</bill>.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the bill is considered read the first time.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400071" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield myself such time as I might consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, Mr. Chairman, I rise in opposition to <bill type="h" number="1361">H.R. 1361</bill>, the RECOVER Act. While there are many important things that this bill does, there are two provisions in particular, I believe, that unfortunately undermine the good work that has been done by the chairwoman in drafting the legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to make clear, I think she has worked very hard. I think the staff has worked very hard to craft what they thought was a good bill, and I think it still has the potential. There are two amendments that we are going to offer subsequent to the general debate argument here, and if those amendments are adopted, I think they fix the bill sufficiently that we can support it because, as I indicated, I think there are many good things in this bill. But without those two provisions being passed,  we unfortunately have to oppose it in its current form.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These two provisions, as I indicated, unfortunately make it impossible for me to support it as drafted, and the manager's amendment offered by the chairwoman, while making one of the provisions less problematic, does not assuage our underlying concerns about the two provisions that I just mentioned.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think everyone can agree that all branches of government failed to respond adequately to the devastation that was Hurricane Katrina, and one of those agencies that did not measure up is the Small Business Administration unfortunately. This is not the conclusion of Democrats or Republicans, or Louisiana or Mississippi Members of Congress. It is a conclusion reached by the GAO, small business owners in the region and even the SBA itself.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While much of the focus on the response to Katrina has focused on the immediate aftermath and the failures of FEMA, the SBA plays a key role in the response to disasters by issuing loans to both homeowners and small businesses affected by the disaster. Thus, an inadequate response by the SBA undermines the recovery of communities devastated by natural disasters. It is vital that the SBA be prepared to handle future disasters, including some worst-case possible scenarios.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Administrator Preston understands this and has taken a number of steps to improve the SBA's readiness and made efforts to ensure that the inadequate response does not repeat itself. Through his efforts, he has reduced backlogs, streamlined loan processing,  improved customer service and identified points where the processing of disaster loans broke down. Administrator Preston also will ensure that the computer systems at the SBA will be improved; establish  a reserve corps; utilize non-SBA staff to process loans; establish a new disaster manual that will be finalized by June 1 for the start of the current hurricane season; and continually revise responses to disasters based on the experience of previous disasters.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One may ask why a bill is necessary if Administrator Preston is making these changes. Well, as we have seen, other administrators may not have the same priorities and may reduce preparedness in the future to address other needs of the SBA. Therefore, incorporating many of these changes in statute will ensure that the administrator and SBA personnel will have the appropriate resources and congressional direction to ensure the SBA will have an adequate response to a disaster in the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Title I of the bill makes important changes in the SBA's management structure to ensure that the agency is prepared not only for predictable disasters but also the unpredictable ones. Title I requires the administrator to, A, develop a comprehensive disaster response plan; B, conduct an annual disaster simulation exercise; C, maintain a disaster reserve corps; D, create plans to obtain additional office space needed for major disasters; E, coordinate disaster assistance programs with FEMA; and  create, from existing personnel, the position of an associate administrator for disaster assistance that has experience in both disaster planning and disaster response. These changes are all beneficial and will ensure that the SBA has the necessary tools and experience to respond to disasters.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These changes are supplemented by section 208, which provides enhanced lending authority to banks and other financial institutions that are preferred SBA lenders to process disaster loans in certain circumstances. Given the expertise of SBA preferred lenders, they should be able to supplement the SBA's capability to process disaster loans when necessary.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are other important changes in title II that also are beneficial, and I commend the chairwoman, Chairwoman Vel&#xE1;zquez, for including those in this legislation. By themselves, these provisions would have made an effective bipartisan bill that ensures the SBA has the current planning and future capacity to respond to a disaster, whether it is a local tornado or an incident of national significance such as Hurricane Katrina.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, the legislation has two critical provisions that, in my view, seriously undercut the otherwise excellent work of the committee in creating a structure that will ensure the SBA is prepared to respond irrespective of the scope of the disaster. The first provision would authorize, according to CBO estimates, $180 million in grants to small businesses that were denied SBA loans. The other provision would grant the administrator the authority to, in essence, create a grant program that  replaces grant funds that must be applied against existing disaster loans issued by the SBA. In other words, it allows a double compensation, a person to be compensated for the same damage twice. Given my concern about these two provisions, I will be offering amendments at the appropriate time to strike these two provisions, two amendments that we will be offering.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If these two provisions are removed, I think the House would then be able to pass a sound bill on an overwhelmingly bipartisan basis that dramatically improves the administrative structure by which the SBA responds to disasters in a fiscally responsible manner.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As I indicated before, if the two amendments are not passed, unfortunately I am going to have to oppose this particular piece of legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>Ms. VEL&#xC1;ZQUEZ. Mr. Chairman, I yield 2 minutes to the gentleman from North Carolina (Mr. Shuler).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412225" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentlewoman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, today I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="1361">H.R. 1361</bill>, the RECOVER Act. This bill is a strong step in the right direction to ensure that the problems small businesses face in the wake of Hurricane Katrina and Hurricane Rita will never repeat.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I know firsthand the difficulties that small businesses face after a natural disaster. It is vital for our community to know that the government stands with them in their hour of greatest need.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My district recently suffered disastrous weather, which wiped out nearly the entire crop of apples, strawberries and ornamental horticulture. I asked the people of the community to join together in prayer for the farmers and their families as they work through this crisis. Just like the small business owners of the gulf region and other areas affected by disaster, these farmers need the quick and effective response of their government in their time of greatest need.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I commend Chairwoman Vel&#xE1;zquez for her work on this legislation, and I urge my colleagues to support this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400071" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield such time as he might consume to the gentleman from Ohio (Mr. Jordan) who, as one of the newer members of the committee, has been very active and is really contributing much to the committee already.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412226" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for yielding, and I thank the chairwoman of the committee for her hard work and the entire committee on this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise to oppose the bill for many of the reasons that the ranking member has cited. I believe the bill shortsightedly tries to move a good organization, the U.S. Small Business Administration, further from its original mission of helping create, strengthen and maintain small businesses across our country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The SBA was created by the Small Business Act of 1953. Its mission was to stand up for small businesses, and its main focus, other than loan guarantees, was promoting small businesses for Federal contracts. Since then, the SBA has grown to become the largest backer of small businesses in America. It has made progress toward its goal of improving small business and the engine of our free market economy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Of late, though, the SBA has done more in fueling small business to coordinating disaster relief for businesses and homeowners. This is certainly a worthy goal, but again, one that strays from its fundamental mission. As the ranking member pointed out, this bill would require the SBA to provide loans it once denied as bad risks. It would also allow recipients to receive disaster relief.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Small businesses are successful in part because they are uniquely focused on their mission, and because they watch every single penny. This RECOVER Act will further blur the focus of SBA's mission while making it impossible for them, or us, to protect the integrity of tax dollars.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, I would urge my colleagues to support the amendments that the ranking member plans to offer. Those will, I think, improve the legislation and make it worthy of everyone's support in a broad, bipartisan manner.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ms. VEL&#xC1;ZQUEZ. Mr. Chairman, I yield 5 1/2  minutes to the gentleman from Louisiana (Mr. Jefferson) who represents and has been very active in the committee addressing the issues of the Small Business Administration Disaster Loan program.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400201" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise today as a proud cosponsor of <bill type="h" number="1361">H.R. 1361</bill>, the RECOVER Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank Chairwoman Vel&#xE1;zquez for her leadership in crafting this important piece of legislation and in bringing it to the floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The storm that hit the gulf coast nearly 2 years ago exposed major flaws in the disaster planning system across all agencies of the Federal Government. Perhaps most appalling is that these storms exposed the fact that so many agencies had no plan at all for disasters such as Hurricanes Katrina and Rita. The Small Business Administration was just one of many agencies caught behind the curve, and the RECOVER Act aims to ensure that this never happens again by providing commonsense remedies for  the many problems brought to light by the storms.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are all quite familiar with the problems of the SBA in the aftermath of Hurricanes Katrina and Rita. Six weeks after the storms, there had been about 54,000 disaster loan applications received from the region. Ninety-five  percent of these applications were denied, while only 1,050 loans were approved, and only 58 checks, totaling $533,400 or so, were sent out. During the 6-week period that followed Hurricane Charley in 2004, the SBA disbursed four  times the amount that was disbursed after Hurricanes Katrina and Rita.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Additionally, many people in the gulf coast region fell victim to long delays in the process of the applications, and their paperwork was lost because the SBA lacked a fully functioning disaster processing system, as well as the required staff. The SBA lacked adequate service and support for its information and telecommunications systems. Only one vendor in the region of the SBA's primary telecommunications hub could service the type of phone system that the SBA uses. The SBA also failed to completely  stress test the agency's sole loan processing system prior to its implementation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The RECOVER Act mandates that the SBA develop a comprehensive written plan in order to deal with catastrophic disasters of this magnitude, as well as test the capacity of the system at least once each year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Administrator Steve Preston came before the Small Business Committee and made the claim that the problems involved in the loan processing system have been solved through a team case management solution. Yet in talking with various small business owners and homeowners as well, and in closely examining the loan processing numbers, doubt is cast on this assertion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One such example is Donna Colosino of New Orleans, who came before the committee and demonstrated the serious flaws that exist that this bill aims to remedy. After the storms flooded her electrical equipment business under 12 feet of water, she applied for a disaster loan from the SBA and was approved for $250,000. After 15 months of resubmitting paperwork lost by the SBA, she finally received a disbursement of $10,000 in May of this year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under the current repayment structure, she would have to begin paying back her loan as if she had received the full $250,000, though she has only received $10,000 to date. This is just one more nonsensical policy of the SBA Disaster Loan program the RECOVER Act will change by altering the payment schedule so that repayment only begins on the money received.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Perhaps the most troubling aspect of the current program to me, as well as to many of my constituents back home, is the requirement that money received from the Road Home program must be used to repay any outstanding loans from the SBA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Assume your home has a pre-Katrina value of $150,000, and it was completely destroyed by the storm. You qualify for an SBA loan in the amount of $100,000. The Road Home grant comes through in the amount of $50,000, enough perhaps to cover your pre-Katrina value, but you must then take the $50,000 Road Home grant and use it, not to complete your home, but to pay down the SBA loan by $50,000. The result is, you end up with only $100,000 in your hands to rebuild, $50,000 short of what you need.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The truth is, replacement cost of a home now is much, much more, given the spikes in the cost of rebuilding with building materials and insurance far exceeding their pre-Katrina value. The requirement to pay down the SBA disaster loan to the extent of the Road Home grant will leave the homeowner with less than is needed to replace the lost home no matter the Road Home grant award.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This SBA requirement has also kept many people from closing on their Road Home awards as they wait for this body to resolve this situation. The RECOVER Act would address this serious problem by allowing the SBA administrator to provide grants to replace compensation that has already been taken by the SBA as a duplication of benefits, as well as going forward to assist those who have yet to receive the Road Home awards to fully recover.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The requirement in the bill to impose discretion in the SBA administrator not to treat a Road Home grant as an automatic double dip is safeguard enough to prevent true double dipping from occurring. Grants are authorized in the bill to selective businesses that have been in business 2 years, who are, in fact, true pioneers in going back, because there is no guarantee that they are going to have customers there to meet the demand is a reasonable addressing of the problem there.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The flaws of the SBA Disaster Loan program have been exposed by the 2005 storms, and it now falls to this body to remedy these flaws. We have long since moved past the rescue phase. We are now focused on recovery. Yet we cannot recover under the existing structure, as 77,000 small businesses were damaged, along with 275,000 homes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Operating under the idea of business as usual is not enough. It is only through the passage of this bill and careful oversight in the coming months that we can ensure the SBA fulfills its obligations, not only to the victims of the storms of 2005, but also to deal more responsibly and efficiently with future disasters.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to oppose any amendments that would weaken this bill and to vote on this bill for its final passage.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400071" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, we reserve the balance of our time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ms. VEL&#xC1;ZQUEZ. Mr. Chairman, I yield 2 minutes to the gentleman from New Hampshire (Mr. Hodes).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412220" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>I thank the chairman. I thank the gentlewoman for yielding her time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise today in support of <bill type="h" number="1361">H.R. 1361</bill>, the RECOVER Act. This bill provided a much-needed overhaul to the Small Business Administration and its disaster aid program. After a disaster, the SBA issues loans to help individuals and small businesses rebuild their lives, often shattered by storms and other natural disasters.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>After Hurricane Katrina, the average time for the SBA to process a loan, not including closing, was 74 days, far above the agency's goal of 21 days. This is absolutely unacceptable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As I speak here today, people all across my home State of New Hampshire are dealing with the aftermath of a recent powerful nor'easter. On April 15, 2007, New Hampshire experienced a severe storm that dropped almost 6 inches of water in a matter of hours. The State as a whole has experienced sustained power and communications outages, and there are currently over 100 local communities that are reporting significant damage to local infrastructure. Our Governor has declared a state of emergency.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>More than 60 percent of the businesses in New Hampshire are small businesses. This program is absolutely vital to my constituents now more than ever. We owe it to our small businesses nationwide to have access to critical relief services. I encourage my colleagues in the House to support this overhaul of SBA disaster aid, and reject proposed amendments.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400071" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ms. VEL&#xC1;ZQUEZ. Mr. Chairman, I yield to the gentlewoman from Texas (Ms. Jackson-Lee) for a unanimous consent request.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Ms. JACKSON-LEE of Texas asked and was given permission to revise and extend her remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400199" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise enthusiastically to support the Relief for Entrepreneurs: Coordination of Objectives and Values for Effective Recovery Act of 2007, to solve the frustration of those in my district who are fleeing Hurricane Katrina, and I thank the gentlewoman.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="1361">H.R. 1361</bill>, the Recovery Act of 2007, which amends the Small Business Act to direct the Small Business Administration (SBA) to develop, implement and maintain a comprehensive written disaster response plan and to maintain a disaster reserve corps; to establish an Associate Administrator for Disaster Assistance; to authorize SBA disaster loans for incidents of national significance; to direct the Administrator to carry out an immediate Disaster Assistance program;  to provide a revised disbursement process for SBA disaster loans; to provide enhanced lending authority for private lenders; to authorize SBA grants to small businesses located in disaster areas upon their certification that they will reestablish the business in the same area; and to require annual SBA reports on disaster assistance operations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I applaud Chairwoman Vel&#xE1;zquez for bringing this bill to the floor and in doing so acknowledging that we need to be better prepared to respond to the needs of disaster victims from the affected areas. In the aftermath of Hurricanes Katrina, Rita and Wilma, we all saw the devastating consequences that came from not having disaster preparedness plans in place.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After those devastating hurricanes, small businesses and in particular minority and disadvantaged businesses, in the affected areas were severely and negatively impacted because they did not receive financial support necessary to rebuild their businesses and participate in the rebuilding of the affected community.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Homeland Security Committee has learned that small businesses in particular are very important to economic recovery and stability in an affected region in the aftermath of a disaster-regardless of whether the disaster is natural or man-made. The Committee also has learned that it is good common sense to use the local business owners in the disaster recovery process because they are most connected, and knowledgeable about the local area and what the local community needs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is why I offered two amendments to <bill type="h" number="1361">H.R. 1361</bill> that would require the Small Business Administration (SBA) Administrator to include in its disaster recovery processes, pre-negotiated contracts and to encourage inclusion of local, minority, and disadvantaged businesses in the disaster recovery response process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My first amendment would have encouraged the SBA to include local businesses from the affected area in the recovery process and to have in place in advance pre-negotiated contracts with these local businesses. Hurricanes Katrina, Rita and have proven that failure to include small businesses in the recovery process was detrimental to speedy and efficient recovery for the affected areas and lead to astronomical costs for the affected areas as well as the entire country. These costs include money,  time and lives. These are costs that we cannot afford to pay in future disasters.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also offered an amendment that would encourage the inclusion of minority and disadvantaged businesses in the disaster recovery response plans. In the aftermath of Hurricanes Katrina, Rita and Wilma, small, minority, and disadvantaged businesses from the region were shut out of disaster-related contracts because goals and preferences were not in place. We must correct this very serious problem that is often representative of problems that the most vulnerable members of our society consistently  face.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, the federal contracting goal for small, minority and disadvantaged businesses is a 23% participation rate as set forth by the Small Business Administration. My amendment that I offered would have required the SBA to include in its comprehensive response plan, a contracting goal and work to meet that goal. If the SBA plans well, then this goal should be achievable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I understand that the bill also allows for mitigation loans and grants. We would hope that the SBA encourages similar inclusion measures with respect to minority and disadvantaged businesses in its loan and grant authorizations as those used in federal contracting in general.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since the late 1960s, it has been the policy of the federal government to assist small businesses owned by minorities and women to become fully competitive, viable business concerns. As a result, the Small Business Administration set forth government-wide goals to level the playing field for small and minority businesses seeking federal government contracts. My amendment to encourage the inclusion of minority and disadvantaged businesses in the disaster loan and grant process would have gone  a long way to meet these goals. If these businesses are disadvantaged before disasters occur, then those who are negatively impacted after disasters would presumably suffer exponentially and disproportionately. Therefore, it is especially crucial to encourage the inclusion of minority and disadvantaged businesses in the disaster mitigation loan and grant recovery process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have seen over and over again the incredible need to include local, minority and disadvantaged businesses in the recovery and rebuilding process. It is time to seriously address this extremely important need.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge the Committee to support <bill type="h" number="1361">H.R. 1361</bill> and to be ever-mindful of the need to include local, minority and disadvantaged businesses in disaster recovery response plans. Further, I vigorously oppose the Chabot amendment, which one in particular is particularly punitive against a business suffering from disaster by requesting a recipient of a grant to pay an SBA disaster loan back that they may have received.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ms. VEL&#xC1;ZQUEZ. Mr. Chairman, I yield 3 minutes to the gentleman from Indiana (Mr. Ellsworth).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Mr. ELLSWORTH asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412206" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I thank the gentlewoman for yielding me this time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Less than 2 years ago, a devastating tornado ripped through my community in Evansville, Indiana, and although 25 residents of those two counties lost their lives, our emergency services organizations were applauded for their response to that devastating tornado. There is only one reason that we handled that; it is because we had a disaster plan in place and because we practiced that plan and we worked that plan so that when it hit, we did our job.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A few months after that tornado, a much larger disaster, Hurricane Katrina, showed the horrors of these disasters on a more massive scale. In the days and weeks that followed, Hoosiers watched the citizens of New Orleans searching for food, clean water, and a safe place to sleep. With the local government underwater, people relied on the government in Washington to come to their aid. The failures of the Federal Government at that time are far too many to list right here. While we work to fulfill  our promises to the citizens recovering from this disaster, we must also prepare for the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>America has suffered massive disasters in the past; and, unfortunately, we are going to see them in the future. As our families prepare themselves for the possible scenarios, Congress must ensure that a failure that we saw before does not happen again.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The RECOVER Act, and I am proud to support this, is an important step in improving the government's response to large-scale disasters. And I am proud to support it, as I said.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The RECOVER Act requires the Small Business Administration to prepare for future disasters by developing a comprehensive disaster plan. The government would be required to conduct regular disaster simulations and update its disaster plan in response to new challenges as we see them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill also requires the SBA to start to implement a new disaster plan, a 1,000-person disaster reserve corps that will receive annual training for future disaster responses. These additional employees would be prepared to meet the challenges posed by sudden disasters.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If programs like these were in place before Hurricane Katrina, the government might have been able to invigorate the local economy and speed up the rebuilding effort. I can understand we can't change the past, but we can improve our response to disasters in the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The RECOVER Act will make those improvements and help the government fulfill its responsibility to protect the citizens in the aftermath of disasters. I am proud to lend my support to the RECOVER Act, and I urge my colleagues to join me in helping protect disaster victims.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400071" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, we will continue to reserve our time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ms. VEL&#xC1;ZQUEZ. Mr. Chairman, I yield 2 minutes to the gentlewoman from New York (Ms. Clarke).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412221" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, first, I want to commend Chairwoman Vel&#xE1;zquez for her leadership on this issue and for bringing this bill to the House floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="1361">H.R. 1361</bill>, a bill to improve the disaster relief program of the Small Business Administration and to provide relief for entrepreneurs. This bill addresses the problems with the SBA's disaster loan program, which was implemented to provide timely financial assistance in the form of low-interest loans and working capital for businesses devastated by disasters.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In New York City, after 9/11, small businesses that once prospered near the World Trade Center had difficulty recovering from that tragedy. Four years later, in the wake of Hurricane Katrina and Hurricane Rita, many applicants of SBA disaster assistance were frustrated with the agency's response or lack thereof.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many businesses found their loan applications were delayed in backlogs that took over a year to process without a well-informed, centralized point of contact within the agency.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For entrepreneurs struggling to get back on their feet, the old adage "time is money" is much more than a cliche. Economic distress can quickly digress into systemic unemployment for the thousands of employees and bring extreme hardship to America's families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I support the intent of this bill because it will ensure that the SBA performs comprehensive, risk-based, disaster planning on an annual basis and that the agency has mechanisms in place to maintain its disaster readiness over the long term.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This new bill will also enhance the SBA's disaster loan program by improving the manner in which disaster  loans are processed, approved and disbursed, and by providing the agency with the additional financial assistance tools that are intended to better fit the various needs of small businesses following a disaster.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I will cast an "aye" vote in support of an unamended <bill type="h" number="1361">H.R. 1361</bill>, and I encourage my colleagues to do the same.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The RECOVER Act of 2007 is a bill that will ensure that members of Congress are adequately informed about all aspects of SBA's disaster assistance and disaster planning programs so that they may provide the SBA with the support they need to fulfill their vital mission following a disaster.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400071" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, we will continue to reserve our time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ms. VEL&#xC1;ZQUEZ. Mr. Chairman, I yield 2 minutes to the gentleman from Iowa (Mr. Braley).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412208" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I thank the gentlewoman for yielding me this time, and for her extraordinary leadership on this important measure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise today as the voice for 350,000 Iowans who lost power during an ice storm in February, to express my strong support for <bill type="h" number="1361">H.R. 1361</bill>, the RECOVER Act. This bill will develop a disaster plan so that the Small Business Administration can adequately assist small businesses in emergencies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Just this February, Iowa was hit with a massive ice storm, one of the worst in its history, which caused millions of dollars worth of damage throughout the State and left hundreds of thousands of people without power.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Weather in Iowa, like in many parts of the country, can be unpredictable and dangerous, and this was no exception. I was personally affected by this ice storm when a 40-foot ice-coated branch struck my home in Waterloo. With the help of my neighbors and our chain saws, I was able to cope with some minor property damage and personal inconvenience; but my situation paled in comparison to the constituents I met while visiting emergency storm shelters in Iowa's First Congressional District. These  Iowans were there seeking refuge after they had been displaced from their homes and businesses as a result of the ice storm.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On March 15, the Small Business Committee held a markup of the RECOVER Act. I introduced an amendment that day to expand the scope of Federal disaster assistance available to small businesses. Currently, the SBA has to wait for the President to make a formal disaster declaration before giving disaster loans to small businesses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are exceptions, however. These include severe situations such as "floods, hurricanes, tornadoes, earthquakes, fires, explosions, volcanoes, windstorms, landslides or mudslides, tidal waves" and other civil disorders.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The amendment I proposed adds "ice storms and blizzards" to this list of exceptions. The language will benefit small business owners who are trying to get back on their feet following severe winter weather.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I was pleased that the amendment received overwhelming bipartisan support and was passed by the committee unanimously. I urge my colleagues to recognize the importance of assisting small businesses in reopening following a disaster and ask them to support the RECOVER Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400071" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, we will reserve the balance of our time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ms. VEL&#xC1;ZQUEZ. Mr. Chairman, I yield 5 minutes to the gentleman from Louisiana (Mr. Melancon). And I want to take this opportunity to thank him for his leadership in working with us on this comprehensive legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400635" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, first, I want to thank Chairman Vel&#xE1;zquez for the continued commitment to helping rebuild the gulf coast. Over a year and a half has passed since Hurricanes Katrina and Rita devastated south Louisiana and other Gulf Coast States. I am pleased my colleagues remain committed to seeing us fully recover and rebuild.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I come to the floor today to support <bill type="h" number="1361">H.R. 1361</bill>, the RECOVER Act. Recovering from the two hurricanes that devastated our State and the gulf coast in 2005 is the biggest and most important challenge Louisiana and the gulf coast have ever faced. Katrina was the biggest natural disaster ever in the United States, and Rita, which may have been dubbed the "forgotten storm," was the third worst disaster. First and third in our Nation's history, and they hit the same region within one month each.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After these storms hit, it became very clear that SBA was not prepared for a disaster of this caliber. SBA was understaffed, poorly trained, poorly managed and, overall, unprepared to respond effectively to the urgent need of disaster relief loans. The SBA's disastrous response effectively discouraged small business owners from applying for business or home loans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Also, inadequate and inaccurate communications from SBA's employees kept many customers from finishing applications. I have personally heard of several instances in which small business owners were frustrated to the point of giving up on the SBA and the hope of getting financial assistance. I remind my colleagues again that this was a critical time, when these people needed help more than ever.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1361">H.R. 1361</bill> addresses those serious shortfalls experienced in the aftermath of Katrina. The RECOVER Act will better prepare the SBA to handle and fund disasters by requiring, among other things, that the agency develop a comprehensive disaster response plan, improve employee training, streamline their information tracking systems and follow-up process, and more efficiently distribute disaster loans by partnering with the private local lenders. SBA's unwillingness to immediately and effectively  delegate responsibility to qualified private lenders created a critical choke point in loan disbursements following these hurricanes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1361">H.R. 1361</bill> includes a commonsense solution that will cure this problem and allow for large, maximum loan amounts and create a more streamlined application process by allowing private, local, SBA-approved bankers to administer these loans. These private lenders have the unique advantage of being on the ground and knowing the community and, more importantly, the people in the businesses within them. By allowing these private lenders to participate, it will greatly increase the speed and efficiency  in getting the funds in the hands of the small businesses after a disaster.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Another problem we faced after the storms was SBA's unwillingness or inability to provide maximum flexibility in the administration of these disaster loans. Instead of nurturing struggling businesses as they adapted to the new environment following Katrina and Rita, the SBA often strangled them with red tape and bureaucratic hurdles.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After the storm, some businesses along the gulf coast were denied sufficient loans because the SBA judged their application solely based on their prestorm capabilities, rather than on the new realities they were trying to adjust to or their ability to meet poststorm demands. The RECOVER Act will make the SBA a more flexible agency and will permit them to approve larger grants for businesses that become major sources of employment following disasters.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The RECOVER Act also addresses one of the most notorious problems that arose after the storms, the duplications of benefit provisions. Under current law, storm victims who took the initiative to apply for SBA loans are now being forced to repay their SBA loans with Road Home money. Hurricane victims in Louisiana and along the gulf coast need all the help they can get with rebuilding their homes and getting their lives back to normal. They don't need the Federal Government giving with one hand  and taking with the other.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rebuilding in the wake of Hurricanes Katrina and Rita has been the biggest challenge the people on the gulf coast have ever faced. In order to continue to recover and rebuild, recovery money must stay in the disaster regions, not sent back to Washington.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I understand the administration does not want people to double dip and must be effective stewards of taxpayers' money, but in this instance, victims of catastrophic disaster are essentially being punished for receiving these disaster loans before they get their recovery grants. Under this bill, borrowers will still have to repay their SBA loans; they will just be able to pay them over the extended time frame they originally agreed to when they got the loan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am a fiscal conservative, but this policy is absolutely ridiculous. It is dooming the recovery to failure, and it is time that we correct it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support the RECOVER Act today. With hurricane season approaching fast, this bill is critical to the survival of small businesses. Small businesses are the lifeblood of this country, and we must be ready to protect them from another, possible, future disaster.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400071" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, we will continue to reserve our time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ms. VEL&#xC1;ZQUEZ. Mr. Chairman, I have no further speakers. If the minority is ready to close, I am ready to close.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, prior to yielding back all our time, if I could just make a comment or two. I will yield myself as much time as I may consume. I will be very brief.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I just want to reiterate that there are things within this bill which I think are very good efforts in resolving some of the difficulties that we saw in Katrina.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First of all, the SBA's response time for loans and other things was unacceptable, and it is absolutely critical that it be improved upon. And I think there are some things in this bill that do just that. For example, better coordination between the SBA and FEMA; the requirement of a plan ahead of time, a disaster plan ahead of time that everybody knows about so you are not looking for a plan or trying to put one together after the disaster has already hit; it makes sense to do that ahead of  time. This calls for this.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It calls for a reserve corps of trained personnel, which I particularly like because you are talking about training people ahead of time, but not necessarily hiring them as new government employees that then one has to pay and pay compensation to over a long period of time. So I like the fact that we are talking about training a reserve corps ahead of time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think the idea of having simulation exercises called for ahead of time makes a lot of sense so that people are prepared.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As I indicated before, however, there are a couple of, in my view, fatal flaws to this particular piece of legislation, which we are going to address in a few moments here in a couple of amendments. And if they pass, then we would be very supportive of the whole act. If they don't, unfortunately, we would have to oppose the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ms. VEL&#xC1;ZQUEZ. Mr. Chairman, I yield myself the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, we are now barely over a month away from hurricane season. Many small businesses have been struggling for a year and half to recover after the gulf coast storms of 2005. Following the hurricanes, delays in disaster loans, overwhelming amounts of paperwork and a lengthy application process left many small business owners frustrated and discouraged. In fact, entrepreneurs avoided what is supposed to be their primary source of assistance, the SBA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our Nation's 25 million small businesses need to know that the next time a disaster happens they will not be left with nothing, but will have efficient and reliable assistance. They need to know that what happened after the gulf coast hurricanes will not ever happen again.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The RECOVER Act of 2007 will require that the SBA have a disaster plan in place, provides assistance to the neediest of entrepreneurs and helps in the redevelopment of the community. <bill type="h" number="1361">H.R. 1361</bill> will given entrepreneurs the relief and assistance they deserve after a disaster.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With 44 days left till hurricane season, we simply cannot afford not to act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At this point, I want to take a moment to thank the staff who worked on this legislation. From Mr. Chabot's staff, Kevin Fitzpatrick, Mike Smullen and Barry Pinellis; from the majority staff, Michael Day, Adam Minehardt and Andy Jiminez and Tim Slattery.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400185" topic="IN THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise today in support of <bill type="h" number="1361">H.R. 1361</bill>, the Relief for Entrepreneurs: Coordination of Objectives and Values for Effective Recovery (RECOVER) Act of 2007. This bill makes crucial improvements to the Small Business Administration's disaster relief programs. It will help provide greater access to, and more effective distribution of, loans and grants to those affected individuals in the aftermath of natural disasters.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One of the many lessons learned from Hurricanes Rita and Katrina is that the Federal Government must be better prepared to assist all the people of this Nation in times of greatest need. In legislating to improve disaster relief programs, Congress must keep in mind the multifaceted nature of any solution and strive to create equitable access for all affected communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While this bill takes great strides in making funds available to individuals affected by natural disasters, more must be done to ensure access for the segments of the population that may not be reached through standard means, including limited English proficient communities. Among the communities severely impacted by Hurricane Katrina were the Vietnamese American and Cambodian American shrimpers of the Gulf Coast. For many, their livelihoods were destroyed as their boats were left damaged and  not seaworthy. These losses were compounded by the inaccessibility of government aid as many of these shrimpers are limited English proficient and were unable to learn of government programs that could have helped them. Unfortunately, the Federal Government fell short of servicing the needs of this segment of the American population.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, it is the responsibility of the Federal Government to ensure equitable access to Federal disaster relief programs for all Americans. We do not know where the next disaster will strike, but we will be better prepared if we acknowledge that different communities have different needs; access to information in the appropriate language is vital. Congress must do its part. The RECOVER Act certainly adds necessary amendments to the Small Business Act, but I stress to my colleagues in the  House, we cannot stop there. To ensure equitable access to all affected individuals and communities, Congress and the Small Business Administration must take the extra steps to ensure that information, outreach, and loan and grant disbursement are made available</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ms. VEL&#xC1;ZQUEZ. Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> All time for general debate has expired.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400071" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I offer an amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will designate the amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400071" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment is really rather simple. It just strikes section 211 of the bill as amended by the manager's amendment. Even though the manager's amendment addresses the direct cost provision of the original section as  determined by the CBO score, section 211 still is fraught with one major problem. And that is that it allows double compensation for the same injury or destruction or problem that the person had.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As I understand section 211 in the manager's amendment, here is how that provision operates: For example, a homeowner applies for a physical disaster loan from the SBA for, say, $100,000. The homeowner then receives a grant from the State for $50,000 for the same destruction. Under existing law, the homeowner would have to immediately pay back $50,000 of the SBA loan because the SBA loan only covers amounts not otherwise compensated for through some other financial resource. Typically, that is  insurance, but it does not have to be. Section 211 does not change the requirement that the homeowner would have to pay down the $50,000 in the disaster loan. Instead, section 211 would then allow the homeowner to apply for a grant from the SBA to replace the same amount of money that they had just paid to the SBA to reduce their loan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now you are probably asking yourself why go through this convoluted process. Well, this is the only way for the majority to obtain a program that does not require direct spending, and therefore, it gets around the PAYGO problem. But even though this is an improvement over the bill as reported out of the committee because it has no direct spending and therefore is in compliance with PAYGO, it remains fundamentally flawed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The disaster loan program is just that: the Federal Government's program designed to provide redress to those homeowners and small businesses injured in a disaster. And it is important to note that the vast majority of loan recipients, both businesses and homeowners, receive loans at heavily subsidized interest rates of 3 or 4 percent interest. It is not a grant program and was never designed to be a grant program. The interest rate subsidy, a 30-year term, and the SBA's authority to suspend  payment on principal and interest constitute the compensation needed to rebuild many areas, from Chatsworth in California to Homestead in Florida.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, section 211 of <bill type="h" number="1361">H.R. 1361</bill> has the recipient of a disaster loan obtaining a grant from a source other than the SBA, using that money to pay off all or a portion of the SBA disaster loan, and then apply to the SBA for a grant to replace the grant money that the recipient of the disaster loan just paid the SBA. And, again, I know this sounds very convoluted. In essence, there is a determination that double compensation is needed because the rather robust compensation already included in the  Small Business Act and sufficient for other disasters is insufficient compensation. It is also important to note that, for victims of Hurricane Katrina, there are billions of other dollars that have been made available to assist these victims on an ad hoc basis, yet it is never enough. And this bill indicates that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now comes section 211 of <bill type="h" number="1361">H.R. 1361</bill> in a clear effort to ensure that victims of Hurricanes Katrina, Wilma and Rita receive double compensation. This raises two distinct questions. First, why do victims of these three hurricanes get special treatment of double compensation, and why should not other disaster victims get double compensation? Yes, Katrina was a tragedy, but so were Hurricane Andrew and Hurricane Charley and the attacks of September 11, for example. This seems incredibly arbitrary  to select only those three disasters for something as unusual as double compensation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second and far more important is the concept, as I indicated, of double compensation. It has been a longstanding tradition of American jurisprudence that a party shall not receive double compensation for the same injury. That concept is codified in the disaster loan provisions of the Small Business Act by prohibiting the SBA from issuing a loan for amounts already compensated for by insurance or other means. Thus under current law, a disaster loan applicant cannot get an insurance claim for $100,000  for a $100,000 loss and also get an SBA disaster loan for the same amount of money.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I ask that Members support this amendment. It is fiscally responsible and continues to recognize that individuals should not be granted double compensation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ms. VEL&#xC1;ZQUEZ. Mr. Chairman, I rise in opposition to the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentlewoman from New York is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400201" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I thank the gentlewoman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The flaw in Mr. Chabot's argument and in this amendment is that the present statute automatically assumes in every instance where one receives a grant and a loan that there is double dipping. That is just not true. In the case where there is double dipping that is true double dipping, this bill permits the administrator to make a decision about that and to prevent it. In a case where there has been an insurance award, one would assume the SBA would not make a disaster loan award if there  is sufficient insurance. Only in a case where the insurance isn't sufficient will we assume that the loan would be justified.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So fundamentally here what we are doing is taking away the automatic assumption that is built into this law that, every time you receive a payment of this or that nature, it is a double dip. We remove that notion from the statute and put in place a more reasonable and commonsensical one and one that gives the administrator flexibility where he determines whether or not a double dip may take place. If it doesn't, then he permits the victim of the storm to receive the award. If it is, then, of  course, he denies it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I think there is no danger here of double dipping in this bill. None of us agree to double dipping in this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ms. VEL&#xC1;ZQUEZ. Mr. Chairman, I yield the balance of my time to the gentleman from Louisiana (Mr. Baker).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400012" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I thank the gentlewoman for yielding time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I wish to express concern about the operative effects of the gentleman's amendment. For many outside the storm impact area, you would not have an understanding of how processes work. But if you were eligible under the Road Home program, that was the federally funded program to assist people to return to their homes, the maximum allowable money that you could receive regardless of your circumstance was $150,000. But under current rule, if you are eligible for $150,000 and you, for example, had  purchased Federal flood insurance in the amount of $150,000 and got paid $150,000 pursuant to the flood insurance premium, you would get nothing out of the Road Home program. Because of that inequitable application of benefits, this House has already voted to eliminate the duplication of benefits in the flood insurance area.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now what is being suggested by the underlying bill is we should do the same thing with regard to an SBA loan. The argument here is even more persuasive. The person may have entered into the SBA obligation far in advance of the onslaught of Katrina. It  might be several hundred thousand dollars of loans that were made available to this individual through the SBA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>Under the current rule, any assistance that might be offered to that homeowner who happened to have the SBA loan would all go back to repaying the SBA obligation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So get the picture. The Federal Government puts a stamp on the check, drops it in the mailbox and sends it to the house. But before it gets there, another Federal agent picks it up and hauls it over and deposits it at the SBA. Do you see where the hole is in this argument? No money at all gets to the affected individual.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So what the bill now provides is that without increasing the overall expenditure, the money made available to assist people via Katrina and Rita has been appropriated by the Congress. It is over, that is it. We are talking about available resources, not new dollars.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Secondly, once the money gets to the individual, the individual is still capped by the rules of the Road Home program, and that is, there shall be no enrichment above that $150,000 level. This is a reasonable proposal. It will enable people to recover appropriately from the disaster which is so overwhelming.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I suggest if any still have doubt whether this level of assistance is required and justifiable, walk the streets of New Orleans, as I did this past weekend. Sure, the business district and the French Quarter look terrific. The shops are empty, the restaurants aren't full and people are not coming back. But get out into the neighborhoods where the devastation still exists. We need this help, and we need it now.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400071" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield the balance of my time to the gentleman from Missouri (Mr. Akin).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from Missouri is recognized for 15 seconds.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400005" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, our concern, and this could have been clarified, but the majority party has chosen not to clarify it, our problem is the question about the fact that somebody could be compensated multiple times for the same damage. That just is plain old double dipping. That is something that could have been simplified with an amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I oppose the bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> All time for debate having expired, the question is on the amendment offered by the gentleman from Ohio (Mr. Chabot).</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400071" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I demand a recorded vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 6 of rule XVIII, further proceedings on the amendment offered by the gentleman from Ohio will be postponed.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400071" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I offer an amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will designate the amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400071" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, this amendment is very straightforward. It strikes section 210 of the bill. Section 210 authorizes the administrator to issue grants of up to $100,000 to small businesses located in areas affected by Hurricanes Katrina, Rita and Wilma, but only if the business was denied a disaster loan by the SBA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is really, in my view, the height of fiscal irresponsibility. The SBA's determination of whether to grant a disaster loan is based on its determination of reasonable assurance that you can repay your loan, which is a direct quote from the SBA's rules found in the Code of Federal Regulations. Thus, if the SBA has denied a business a disaster loan, it already has determined that it is unlikely, for whatever reason, to repay the loan. In other words, its capacity as a viable business is seriously  called into question.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Section 210 provides that despite this determination, the Federal Government should create a grant program of up to $100,000 to help small businesses whose survivability was highly improbable to survive in the first place.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, the SBA has indicated that they don't think this business is viable, that it is going to survive, and then we are going to turn around and give them up to $100,000. It is just not fiscally responsible.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To fully fund all of those eligible, CBO estimates that the costs could be up to $180 million. I want to repeat that: $180 million we are talking about here. This seems again fiscally irresponsible, to fund grants when the SBA already has determined that the businesses are not likely to survive.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It also remains unclear whether the grants will be sufficient to satisfy the needs of small businesses. How many will be able to survive on a grant of $100,000 if they could not repay a disaster loan of that amount? CBO did not answer that question, but I suspect very few of these businesses will survive.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although the provision is written to include all small businesses affected by Hurricanes Katrina, Rita and Wilma, there are limitations on which businesses can apply based on the amount of housing stock in a county or parish that is damaged. It is highly likely that only small businesses in Louisiana will qualify. Was this done to reduce costs? If so, why are only Louisiana businesses favored? Were not many small businesses throughout the region devastated by these hurricanes? It seems patently  unfair to single out certain businesses for a very generous grant program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I ask that Members support this amendment. To do otherwise, in my view, is just not a fiscally responsible stand to take. Again, every Member has to stand according to their own vote, and I am sure we will determine this based upon what they consider to be its merits.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ms. VEL&#xC1;ZQUEZ. Mr. Chairman, I rise in opposition to the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentlewoman from New York is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400071" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ms. VEL&#xC1;ZQUEZ. Mr. Chairman, I yield the balance of my time to the gentleman from Louisiana (Mr. Melancon).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400635" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I thank the chairwoman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, this bill has the potential to help thousands of small businesses and business owners still struggling to recover from these hurricanes that devastated the U.S. gulf coast.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise today in opposition to this amendment. After surviving Hurricanes Katrina and Rita, two of the  worst natural disasters in our country's history, the citizens of the gulf coast were then faced with a man-made disaster, one of the most disorganized, chaotic Federal responses that anyone has ever seen. Many of the Federal agencies that were created to help these people recover wound up making matters worse. One of these agencies was the SBA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After these storms, 81,000 businesses were economically impacted. Over 18,000 were completely or severely destroyed. Astonishingly, however, following these hurricanes, only 38 percent of small business disaster loans were approved. In hearings, the SBA admitted that after "typical" disasters, they approved 60 percent of these business loans. After Katrina and Rita, conversely, over 60 percent did not receive SBA assistance and were left with nowhere to turn for help.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One of the many reasons that the SBA failed the people of the gulf coast was because it did not have the proper tools nor the flexibility it needed to sufficiently and adequately address the demands caused by the extraordinary storms. These were unprecedented natural disasters and they called for unprecedented response. This was not a one-size-fits-all storm, as my colleagues on the other side of the aisle seem to perceive.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>In the resourceful, self-sufficient economy of south Louisiana and Mississippi, small businesses are the lifeblood of the local economy. Many of these mom-and-pop shops are homegrown and family-run businesses, such as those in the shrimping industry in south Louisiana and Mississippi that do not fit the traditional mold of current SBA loan qualifications. These are the businesses that are being denied assistance, yet these are the businesses that are the local economy's most critical assets.  I am a fiscal conservative, but this policy is ridiculous. It's dooming the recovery to failure, and it's time that we correct it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To these business owners, these grants are critical investment capital which will help them pay utilities, keep the lights on, rent to keep the doors open and new equipment expenses to continue to recover and grow despite the incredibly difficult business climate that continues to persist in this area. Without this grant program, these small businesses will remain too debt-burdened to take the next decisive step required to move from recovery to rebuilding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I strongly urge my colleagues to oppose this amendment today. Help these small businesses along the gulf coast get back on their feet and help America be the proud Nation that it should be.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the amendment offered by the gentleman from Ohio (Mr. Chabot).</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400071" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I demand a recorded vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 6 of rule XVIII, further proceedings on the amendment offered by the gentleman from Ohio will be postponed.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400634" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I have an amendment at the desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will designate the amendment.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Louisiana?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400634" topic="AMENDMENT, AS MODIFIED, OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>I want to thank the chairwoman, and I want to thank Ranking Member Chabot as well for their working together with me. I especially want to thank the committee for helping me with this legislation and for this underlying bill for all they are trying to do and all they are doing to help the small businesses in Louisiana recover from the 2005 hurricanes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As my colleagues from Louisiana have already pointed out, prior to Hurricanes Katrina and Rita, there were an estimated 347,436 small businesses in Louisiana. These businesses created jobs and income for countless families all across the State. More than 65,000 of the new jobs in Louisiana in the past decade were created by small businesses, and in 2004, over 97 percent of the 96,000 Louisiana firms were small businesses. The devastation caused by the 2005 hurricanes is unprecedented, with total  losses, both insured and uninsured, approaching $140 billion. According to the United States Chamber of Commerce, over 125,000 businesses were disrupted by Hurricanes Katrina and Rita in 2005. In Louisiana alone, over 81,000 small businesses were damaged or economically impacted, with 18,700 businesses catastrophically destroyed by the storms.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As one example, in St. Bernard Parish, one of the Louisiana parishes hardest hit by Hurricane Katrina, only 370 businesses have reopened, far below the total of 1,400 businesses in operation before Katrina. The Nation's small businesses are the backbone of our economy, and when they are devastated by storms like Katrina, Rita and Wilma, we need to do everything possible to help them rebuild and recover.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am offering an amendment today that builds upon a provision in the underlying bill by providing Hurricanes Katrina, Rita and Wilma disaster victims with the option of receiving a 4-year deferment period to pay back their disaster loans. Section 204 of the underlying bill extends the deferment period to future disaster victims. My  amendment simply applies this option to those severely affected by the 2005 hurricanes. These cash-strapped small businesses  are truly in need of repayment flexibility.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My amendment allows the SBA to refinance the existing Katrina, Rita and Wilma disaster loans under identical loans, but with the added option of deferment of up to 4 years after the date on which the initial disbursement was made. This is a revised version of my original amendment that complies with all the budgetary and PAYGO rules.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By allowing small businesses that received certain small business loans to defer their repayment on those loans, we are freeing up money for these businesses to use for other purposes, such as rebuilding, expanding or continuing to hire new employees. The importance of small business as the gulf coast continues to rebuild cannot be overstated. It is critical that we help small businesses get up and running again and provide the job opportunities people so desperately need in these impacted areas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I certainly urge my colleagues to support my amendment. Again, I want to thank the chairman and ranking member for their work on the underlying bill and their work with me on this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Does any Member seek time in opposition to the amendment?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400201" topic="AMENDMENT, AS MODIFIED, OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentlelady for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also would like to thank the gentleman from Louisiana (Mr. Jindal) for offering this amendment. If anyone has been to the gulf coast recently, particularly if anyone has been to New Orleans recently, you will see that there are still many businesses that are still shuttered from the storm that happened now going on close to 2 years, and they are not at all ready to begin repaying loan obligations. There are still many obstacles to their recovery. This rightly recognizes that the reality  is that these businesses will take a long time to get themselves back together.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is very important to understand one simple thing here. This is not just a call from the people of our State for humanitarian assistance in the wake of a natural disaster. The Corps has admitted that its negligence in constructing, maintaining and designing our levees is the major reason why our city drowned and why so many businesses were put out of business. And so there is a special responsibility, it seems to me, to make special rules to overcome these problems. I really appreciate this  solution that is being offered here because I think it helps to address this extraordinary devastation we have caused in great respect by the action, or lack of action, the negligence, of an agency of our Federal Government.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank you for the amendment. I really urge the Members to support it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ms. VEL&#xC1;ZQUEZ. Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the amendment offered by the gentleman from Louisiana (Mr. Jindal), as modified.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400411" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, on rollcall No. 222, the Chabot amendment No. 1 to <bill type="h" number="1361">H.R. 1361</bill>, I am not recorded. Had I been present, I would have voted "aye."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 5-minute vote.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400644" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>In its current form.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will report the motion to recommit.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> The gentleman is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400644" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, there is nothing complicated about this motion to recommit today. It simply says that anyone who has pleaded no contest or has been found guilty of a felony cannot receive Federal funding under this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would urge my colleagues on the other side of the aisle to especially listen to the explanation of this motion to recommit, because some of them voted for a similar motion to recommit just weeks ago on this House floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This motion to recommit is very simple. It says that Federal funding cannot under this provision of this bill go to anyone who has been found guilty of a felony or has pleaded no contest. If you vote against this motion to recommit, you are saying to your constituents back home that you don't care if these Federal funds go to convicted murderers, rapists, or kidnappers for that matter.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the new Speaker of the House pledged to have the most ethical Congress in our Nation's history. If you vote for this motion to recommit, you are sending a message that you are willing to reward good behavior by supporting ethical oversight of taxpayer funds.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me be clear, Mr. Speaker. The RECOVER Act is another massive Democrat spending spree. That is why I am opposed to it. The Congressional Budget Office states that the Democrats' bill will cost the Federal taxpayers $562 million over the next 6 years. It makes government bigger while creating new programs, positions and offices. It expands the role of government in people's lives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But I think we owe our taxpayers the common courtesy of saying these funds should not go to felons. And while I and many of my colleagues in the House are at odds with the Democrats' ideology of big government is good government, we all can agree that kidnappers should not receive Federal funds under this bill here today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And in this motion to recommit, we fix this error in the Democrats' drawing up of this bill; this omission that the Democrats have permitted to be in this bill here today before us.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues on both sides of the aisle to support this motion to recommit and reassure your constituents you actually care where their taxpayer dollars are going.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And for those Democrats who voted for a similar motion to recommit on the Gulf Coast Hurricane Housing Recovery Act of 2007 just a few weeks ago, for those on the other side of the aisle, the 55 Democrats who voted for the motion to recommit on the Gulf Coast Hurricane Housing Recovery Act of 2007, they will recognize the language of this motion to recommit. It is very similar. It says, felons cannot receive these Federal funds. Felons, such as murderers, rapists, kidnappers, those are the type  of people who would not be eligible for funds under this act, and I encourage those same 55 Democrats to cross the aisle and work in a bipartisan way to fix a Democrat mistake.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ms. VEL&#xC1;ZQUEZ. Mr. Speaker, I rise in opposition to the motion to recommit.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentlewoman from New York is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400189" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I thank the gentlewoman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As she has said, this is the law. This is another attempt, another opportunity not to substantively legislate because this is already the law. This is an effort to kill this bill indirectly and without telling the public that that is what you are doing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am asking all of our Members to vote "no" on this. This is simply a procedural motion to kill this bill. If they wanted to add a substantive amendment, they could have done it. This was a modified open rule. All they had to do was file and notice it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I ask all of my colleagues, we are not going to go down this road and play this political game. We want to substantively legislate. We are going to vote "no" on this motion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ms. VEL&#xC1;ZQUEZ. Mr. Speaker, I yield the balance of my time to the gentleman from Louisiana (Mr. Melancon).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400635" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, here we go again.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We had a similar motion to recommit, the gentleman is right, 2 or 3 weeks ago, and 50 people fell for it. They fell for it because it came to the floor just minutes before we had to vote, and it sounded like people such as myself would condone felons getting loans, when the law already prevents that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For God's sake, the people in the gulf coast of the United States have suffered enough. And now we want to take  away or at least put some procedures in this just to screw with them some more. Let's vote this bill straight up and down. Let's kill this motion to recommit. It is a fallacy. It is fake. It is there just to disrupt. The people of this country and the people of the gulf coast need your help. Support the bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the previous question is ordered on the motion to recommit.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400644" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I demand a recorded vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 and clause 9 of rule XX, this 15-minute vote on the motion to recommit will be followed by 5-minute votes on passage of <bill type="h" number="1361">H.R. 1361</bill>, if ordered, motion to suspend the rules and agree to <bill type="hr" number="293">H. Res. 293</bill>, and motion to suspend the rules and agree to <bill type="hr" number="300">H. Res. 300</bill>.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 5-minute vote.</chair>
</record>
