<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1197565202" ordinal="21" title="PROVIDING FOR CONSIDERATION OF H.J. RES. 69, FURTHER CONTINUING APPROPRIATIONS, FISCAL YEAR 2008">
  <narrative>PROVIDING FOR CONSIDERATION OF <bill type="hj" number="69">H.J. RES. 69</bill>, FURTHER CONTINUING APPROPRIATIONS, FISCAL YEAR 2008 -- (House of Representatives - December 13, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H15422]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400378" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, by direction of the Committee on Rules, I call up House Resolution 869 and ask for its immediate consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the resolution, as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="hr" number="869">H. Res. 869</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Resolved, That upon the adoption of this resolution it shall be in order to consider in the House the joint resolution (<bill type="hj" number="69">H.J. Res. 69</bill>) making further continuing appropriations for the fiscal year 2008, and for other purposes. All points of order against consideration of the joint resolution are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. The joint resolution shall be considered as read. All points of order against provisions of the joint resolution are waived. The previous  question shall be considered as ordered on the joint resolution to final passage without intervening motion except: (1) one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by the chairman and ranking minority member of the Committee on Appropriations; and (2) one motion to recommit.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Sec. 2.  During consideration of House Joint Resolution 69 pursuant to this resolution, notwithstanding the operation of the previous question, the Chair may postpone further consideration of the joint resolution to such time as may be designated by the Speaker.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Sec. 3.  The chairman of the Committee on Appropriations shall insert in the Congressional Record at any time during the remainder of the first session of the 110th Congress such material as he may deem explanatory of appropriations measures for the fiscal year 2008.</narrative>
  <narrative> Sec. 4.  House Resolution 839 and House Resolution 850 are laid upon the table.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> The gentlewoman from New York is recognized for 1 hour.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400378" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, for the purpose of debate only, I yield the customary 30 minutes to the gentleman from Florida (Mr. Diaz-Balart). All time yielded during the consideration of the rule is for debate only.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members be given 5 legislative days in which to revise and extend their remarks on House Resolution 869.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from Florida?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400378" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, <bill type="hr" number="869">H. Res. 869</bill> provides for the consideration of <bill type="hj" number="69">H.J. Res. 69</bill>, a simple, 1-week extension of the fiscal year 2008 continuing resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, every Congress has the constitutional responsibility to be good stewards of the money entrusted to it by the American people. It is one of our most important responsibilities. Voters do not expect us to abdicate that responsibility, or any other, for that matter.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am proud to say that we here in the House of Representatives have fulfilled our fiscal responsibility to the American people by passing all of our appropriations bills on time. We in the majority have been absolute in our promise to construct and pass spending bills with broad bipartisan support, and I am proud to say we have delivered on those promises.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Of the 12 fiscal year 2008 appropriations bills that have passed the House this year, we have garnered an average of 50 Republican votes, with one bill collecting as many as 187 votes from the minority. And in that spirit of working together, we have successfully pushed ahead our bold and new agenda and passed legislation that prioritizes veterans health care, education and energy independence.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, we all agree that it is unfortunate that we are forced to pass a continuing resolution. But, it is something that must be done to work out the remaining issues that we have. We all understand it is our prime duty to make sure that the government is running efficiently, from our children who need quality education to our veterans who need the benefits promised to them when they signed up to serve our country, and to our senior citizens who need access to health care and affordable  prescription drugs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many on the other side still fought tooth and nail, with some Members holding up the legislative process, in fighting these bipartisan appropriations bills, but we remained focused and strong and passed our bills on time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is important to note that continuing resolutions are extremely common, with a CR being enacted for every fiscal year since 1954. Additionally, Congress has averaged five continuing resolutions per year. And I would like to say to my friends on the other side of the aisle that over the last 10 years of Republican control, the House has considered 75 continuing resolutions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, this is an important resolution that will allow us to do the work necessary to fulfill our promises to the American people, and I urge its passage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400107" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, first, I would like to thank my friend, the distinguished chairwoman, Ms. Slaughter, for the time, and I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, here we are 74 days into the new fiscal year, and the new majority is requesting their third continuing resolution to fund the government because they failed to pass the necessary appropriations bills.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As of today, only one appropriations bill funding the Department of Defense has been signed into law. What is the status of the rest? Well, another one has made it to a conference committee, and the rest of the appropriations bills wait for the majority to decide what to do. They control both Houses of Congress, and yet they still have to decide what to do.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>They had a chance to bring their record to two appropriations bills signed into law. But instead, the majority decided to play politics with a bill that had extraordinary bipartisan support, the Veterans Affairs Appropriations Act, because the majority thought they could use it as a campaign ploy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The new majority promised that they would finish their appropriations work. About a year ago, my friend, the distinguished chairwoman, Ms. Slaughter, came to the floor and said things would be different under the leadership of the new majority. She said, and I quote, "The House will no longer avoid asking tough questions or fail to live up to its most basic duties."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Well, today we see that that has not been possible. Next week, the majority is expected to propose an omnibus appropriations bill for all the appropriations bills that haven't been finished. That bill will probably run into the thousands of pages and spend nearly half a trillion dollars. Members may not have enough time to read and digest that legislation before they are asked to vote on it. And unless the majority decides to move the omnibus appropriations bill through a conference committee,  that bill will fall squarely within one of the loopholes to the majority's earmark rule, and the rules of the House then would not require any disclosure of earmarks that will be contained in that massive omnibus appropriations bill. The majority should not be asking Members to vote on a bill that may include numerous earmarks that no one is going to be able to vet and that most won't even be able to see.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of this loophole in the earmark rule, I, along with Mr. Dreier, Mr. Hastings and Mr. Sessions, sent a letter to the distinguished chairman of the Appropriations Committee, Mr. Obey, asking him to "adhere not just to the letter of clause 9 of rule XXI, but to its spirit as well and provide the Rules Committee and the House with a list of earmarks contained in the omnibus appropriations bill prior to the consideration by the Rules Committee."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I sincerely hope that Chairman Obey will comply with our request. If he does, that would, to an extent, provide Members with a bit of comfort when the bill comes to the floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>COMMITTEE ON RULES,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington, DC, December 6, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR CHAIRMAN OBEY: Today the Committee on Rules reported a "martial law" rule to provide for the same day consideration of an omnibus appropriations vehicle. That measure also includes a provision giving you the option of inserting extraneous explanatory material in the Congressional Record for appropriations measures for the remainder of this session.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>During the markup of that measure, we offered an amendment to the rule to require that you provide the list of earmarks required by clause 9 of rule XXI for the omnibus appropriations measure. Unfortunately, that amendment to the rule was rejected along partisan lines.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, we know that you have made an effort during this Congress to provide transparency for earmarks contained in bills coming through your committee. However, because the omnibus appropriations bill will be considered as a Senate amendment to a House bill, it falls squarely within one of the loopholes of the earmark rule and the Rules of the House will not require any disclosure of earmarks that will be contained therein. As you were the presiding officer over the motion to concur in  the Senate amendment to <bill type="h" number="6">H.R. 6</bill>, the energy bill, you are well aware that no list of earmarks was provided for that measure because it fell within the same loophole.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We respectfully request that you adhere not just to the letter of clause 9 of rule XXI, but to its spirit as well and provide the Rules Committee and the House with a list of earmarks contained in the omnibus appropriations bill prior to consideration by the Rules Committee. That kind of disclosure will be in the best interest of the House, its Members, and the Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We appreciate your willingness to consider our request.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Respectfully,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>David Dreier,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Doc Hastings,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Lincoln Diaz-Balart,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Pete Sessions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, the new majority, again, has failed to live up to their promises to finish their work on time and many others, and the underlying third continuing resolution is just another example of their failure to lead.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400378" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I would ask my friend, Mr. Diaz-Balart, if he has any speakers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have no speakers, either, so if the gentleman would like to close, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400107" topic="">
    <paragraph>Again, I thank my friend.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I will be asking for a "no" vote on the previous question so that we can amend this rule and move toward passing the conference report on the bipartisan Military Construction and Veterans Affairs Appropriations Act that I made reference to a few minutes ago. The House passed the veterans and military funding bill on June 15 of this year by a vote of 409-2. The Senate followed suit and named conferees on September 6 of this year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, the majority leadership in the House has refused to move the Military Construction and Veterans Affairs Appropriations Act. They have even refused to name conferees. Instead, the majority plans to include the veterans funding in the massive omnibus appropriations legislation. But the status of the omnibus is still in doubt.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>Negotiations apparently are ongoing, but we all know there is one bill that has extraordinarily wide bipartisan support and that the President will quickly sign it into law, the Veterans Affairs appropriations bill. We already know that we are going to be here next week. We should pass the Veterans Affairs appropriation bill and provide the veterans the funding they deserve.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to help move this important legislation and oppose the previous question. Our veterans deserve better than partisan gamesmanship holding back their funding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I ask unanimous consent to insert the text of the amendment and extraneous materials immediately prior to the vote on the previous question.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Florida?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400107" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, at this time, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400378" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I urge a "yes" vote on the previous question and the rule.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The material previously referred to by Mr. Lincoln Diaz-Balart of Florida is as follows:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Amendment to <bill type="hr" number="869">H. Res. 869</bill> Offered by Mr. Lincoln Diaz-Balart of Florida</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At the end of the resolution, add the following:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sec. 5. The House disagrees to the Senate amendment to the bill, <bill type="h" number="2642">H.R. 2642</bill>, making appropriations for military construction, the Department of Veterans Affairs, and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2008, and for other purposes, and agrees to the conference requested by the Senate thereon. The Speaker shall appoint conferees immediately, but may declare a recess under clause 12(a) of rule I for the purpose of consulting the Minority Leader prior to such appointment.  The motion to instruct conferees otherwise in order pending the appointment of conferees instead shall be in order only at a time designated by the Speaker in the legislative schedule within two additional legislative days after adoption of this resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>&lt;pre&gt;--&lt;/pre&gt;</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(The information contained herein was provided by Democratic Minority on multiple occasions throughout the 109th Congress.)</narrative>
  <narrative>The Vote on the Previous Question: What It Really Means</narrative>
  <narrative>This vote; the vote on whether to order the previous question on a special rule, is not merely a procedural vote. A vote against ordering the previous question is a vote against the Democratic majority agenda and a vote to allow the opposition, at least for the moment, to offer an alternative plan. It is a vote about what the House should be debating.</narrative>
  <narrative>Mr. Clarence Cannon's Precedents of the House of Representatives, (VI, 308-311) describes the vote on the previous question on  the rule as "a motion to direct or control the consideration of the subject before the House being made by the Member in charge." To defeat the previous question is to give the opposition a chance to decide the subject before the House. Cannon cites the Speaker's ruling of January 13, 1920, to the effect that "the refusal  of the House to sustain the demand for the previous question passes the control of the resolution to the opposition" in order to offer an amendment. On March 15, 1909, a member of the majority party offered a rule resolution. The House defeated the previous question and a member of the opposition rose</narrative>
  <narrative>Because the vote today may look bad for the Democratic majority they will say "the vote on the previous question is simply a vote on whether to proceed to an immediate vote on adopting the resolution ..... [and] has no substantive legislative or policy implications whatsoever." But that is not what they have always said. Listen to the definition of the previous question used in the Floor Procedures Manual published by the Rules Committee in the 109th Congress, (page 56). Here's how the Rules  Committee described the rule using information from Congressional Quarterly's "American Congressional Dictionary": "If the previous question is defeated, control of debate shifts to the leading opposition member (usually the minority Floor Manager) who then manages an hour of debate and may offer a germane amendment to the pending business."</narrative>
  <narrative>Deschler's Procedure in the U.S. House of Representatives, the subchapter titled "Amending Special Rules" states: "a refusal to order the previous question on such a rule [a special rule reported from the Committee on Rules] opens the resolution to amendment and further debate." (Chapter 21, section 21.2) Section 21.3 continues: Upon rejection of the motion for the previous question on a resolution reported from the Committee on Rules, control shifts to the Member leading the opposition to  the previous question, who may offer a proper amendment or motion and who controls the time for debate thereon."</narrative>
  <narrative>Clearly, the vote on the previous question on a rule does have substantive policy implications. It is one of the only available tools for those who oppose the Democratic majority's agenda and allows those with alternative views the opportunity to offer an alternative plan.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400378" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield back the balance of my time, and I move the previous question on the resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on ordering the previous question.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and the Speaker pro tempore announced that the ayes appeared to have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400107" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 and clause 9 of rule XX, this 15-minute vote on ordering the previous question will be followed by 5-minute votes on adoption of <bill type="hr" number="869">H. Res. 869</bill>, if ordered; ordering the previous question on <bill type="hr" number="859">H. Res. 859</bill>; and adoption of <bill type="hr" number="859">H. Res. 859</bill>, if ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The vote was taken by electronic device, and there were--yeas 222, nays 184, not voting 25, as follows:</chair>
  <chair>[Roll No. 1156]</chair>
  <chair>Abercrombie</chair>
  <chair>Ackerman</chair>
  <chair>Allen</chair>
  <chair>Altmire</chair>
  <chair>Andrews</chair>
  <chair>Arcuri</chair>
  <chair>Baca</chair>
  <chair>Baird</chair>
  <chair>Baldwin</chair>
  <chair>Barrow</chair>
  <chair>Bean</chair>
  <chair>Becerra</chair>
  <chair>Berkley</chair>
  <chair>Berman</chair>
  <chair>Berry</chair>
  <chair>Bishop (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Bishop (NY)</chair>
  <chair>Blumenauer</chair>
  <chair>Boren</chair>
  <chair>Boswell</chair>
  <chair>Boucher</chair>
  <chair>Boyd (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Boyda (KS)</chair>
  <chair>Brady (PA)</chair>
  <chair>Braley (IA)</chair>
  <chair>Brown, Corrine</chair>
  <chair>Butterfield</chair>
  <chair>Capps</chair>
  <chair>Capuano</chair>
  <chair>Carnahan</chair>
  <chair>Carney</chair>
  <chair>Castor</chair>
  <chair>Clarke</chair>
  <chair>Clay</chair>
  <chair>Cleaver</chair>
  <chair>Clyburn</chair>
  <chair>Cohen</chair>
  <chair>Conyers</chair>
  <chair>Cooper</chair>
  <chair>Costa</chair>
  <chair>Costello</chair>
  <chair>Courtney</chair>
  <chair>Cramer</chair>
  <chair>Crowley</chair>
  <chair>Cuellar</chair>
  <chair>Cummings</chair>
  <chair>Davis (AL)</chair>
  <chair>Davis (CA)</chair>
  <chair>Davis (IL)</chair>
  <chair>Davis, Lincoln</chair>
  <chair>DeFazio</chair>
  <chair>DeGette</chair>
  <chair>Delahunt</chair>
  <chair>DeLauro</chair>
  <chair>Dicks</chair>
  <chair>Dingell</chair>
  <chair>Doggett</chair>
  <chair>Donnelly</chair>
  <chair>Doyle</chair>
  <chair>Edwards</chair>
  <chair>Ellsworth</chair>
  <chair>Emanuel</chair>
  <chair>Eshoo</chair>
  <chair>Etheridge</chair>
  <chair>Farr</chair>
  <chair>Fattah</chair>
  <chair>Filner</chair>
  <chair>Frank (MA)</chair>
  <chair>Giffords</chair>
  <chair>Gillibrand</chair>
  <chair>Gonzalez</chair>
  <chair>Gordon</chair>
  <chair>Green, Al</chair>
  <chair>Green, Gene</chair>
  <chair>Grijalva</chair>
  <chair>Gutierrez</chair>
  <chair>Hall (NY)</chair>
  <chair>Hare</chair>
  <chair>Harman</chair>
  <chair>Hastings (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Herseth Sandlin</chair>
  <chair>Higgins</chair>
  <chair>Hill</chair>
  <chair>Hinchey</chair>
  <chair>Hirono</chair>
  <chair>Hodes</chair>
  <chair>Holden</chair>
  <chair>Holt</chair>
  <chair>Honda</chair>
  <chair>Hoyer</chair>
  <chair>Inslee</chair>
  <chair>Israel</chair>
  <chair>Jackson (IL)</chair>
  <chair>Jackson-Lee (TX)</chair>
  <chair>Jefferson</chair>
  <chair>Johnson (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Johnson, E. B.</chair>
  <chair>Jones (OH)</chair>
  <chair>Kagen</chair>
  <chair>Kanjorski</chair>
  <chair>Kaptur</chair>
  <chair>Kennedy</chair>
  <chair>Kildee</chair>
  <chair>Kilpatrick</chair>
  <chair>Kind</chair>
  <chair>Klein (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Kucinich</chair>
  <chair>Lampson</chair>
  <chair>Langevin</chair>
  <chair>Lantos</chair>
  <chair>Larsen (WA)</chair>
  <chair>Larson (CT)</chair>
  <chair>Lee</chair>
  <chair>Levin</chair>
  <chair>Lewis (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Lipinski</chair>
  <chair>Loebsack</chair>
  <chair>Lofgren, Zoe</chair>
  <chair>Lowey</chair>
  <chair>Lynch</chair>
  <chair>Mahoney (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Maloney (NY)</chair>
  <chair>Markey</chair>
  <chair>Marshall</chair>
  <chair>Matheson</chair>
  <chair>Matsui</chair>
  <chair>McCarthy (NY)</chair>
  <chair>McCollum (MN)</chair>
  <chair>McDermott</chair>
  <chair>McGovern</chair>
  <chair>McIntyre</chair>
  <chair>McNerney</chair>
  <chair>McNulty</chair>
  <chair>Meek (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Meeks (NY)</chair>
  <chair>Melancon</chair>
  <chair>Michaud</chair>
  <chair>Miller (NC)</chair>
  <chair>Miller, George</chair>
  <chair>Mitchell</chair>
  <chair>Mollohan</chair>
  <chair>Moore (KS)</chair>
  <chair>Moore (WI)</chair>
  <chair>Moran (VA)</chair>
  <chair>Murphy (CT)</chair>
  <chair>Murphy, Patrick</chair>
  <chair>Murtha</chair>
  <chair>Nadler</chair>
  <chair>Napolitano</chair>
  <chair>Neal (MA)</chair>
  <chair>Oberstar</chair>
  <chair>Obey</chair>
  <chair>Olver</chair>
  <chair>Ortiz</chair>
  <chair>Pallone</chair>
  <chair>Pascrell</chair>
  <chair>Pastor</chair>
  <chair>Payne</chair>
  <chair>Perlmutter</chair>
  <chair>Peterson (MN)</chair>
  <chair>Pomeroy</chair>
  <chair>Price (NC)</chair>
  <chair>Rahall</chair>
  <chair>Rangel</chair>
  <chair>Reyes</chair>
  <chair>Richardson</chair>
  <chair>Ross</chair>
  <chair>Rothman</chair>
  <chair>Roybal-Allard</chair>
  <chair>Ruppersberger</chair>
  <chair>Rush</chair>
  <chair>Ryan (OH)</chair>
  <chair>Salazar</chair>
  <chair>S&#xE1;nchez, Linda T.</chair>
  <chair>Sanchez, Loretta</chair>
  <chair>Sarbanes</chair>
  <chair>Schakowsky</chair>
  <chair>Schiff</chair>
  <chair>Schwartz</chair>
  <chair>Scott (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Scott (VA)</chair>
  <chair>Serrano</chair>
  <chair>Sestak</chair>
  <chair>Shea-Porter</chair>
  <chair>Sherman</chair>
  <chair>Shuler</chair>
  <chair>Sires</chair>
  <chair>Skelton</chair>
  <chair>Slaughter</chair>
  <chair>Smith (WA)</chair>
  <chair>Snyder</chair>
  <chair>Solis</chair>
  <chair>Space</chair>
  <chair>Spratt</chair>
  <chair>Stark</chair>
  <chair>Stupak</chair>
  <chair>Sutton</chair>
  <chair>Tanner</chair>
  <chair>Tauscher</chair>
  <chair>Taylor</chair>
  <chair>Thompson (CA)</chair>
  <chair>Thompson (MS)</chair>
  <chair>Tierney</chair>
  <chair>Towns</chair>
  <chair>Tsongas</chair>
  <chair>Udall (CO)</chair>
  <chair>Udall (NM)</chair>
  <chair>Van Hollen</chair>
  <chair>Vel&#xE1;zquez</chair>
  <chair>Visclosky</chair>
  <chair>Walz (MN)</chair>
  <chair>Watson</chair>
  <chair>Watt</chair>
  <chair>Waxman</chair>
  <chair>Weiner</chair>
  <chair>Welch (VT)</chair>
  <chair>Wexler</chair>
  <chair>Wilson (OH)</chair>
  <chair>Woolsey</chair>
  <chair>Wu</chair>
  <chair>Wynn</chair>
  <chair>Yarmuth</chair>
  <chair>Aderholt</chair>
  <chair>Akin</chair>
  <chair>Alexander</chair>
  <chair>Bachmann</chair>
  <chair>Bachus</chair>
  <chair>Baker</chair>
  <chair>Barrett (SC)</chair>
  <chair>Bartlett (MD)</chair>
  <chair>Barton (TX)</chair>
  <chair>Biggert</chair>
  <chair>Bilbray</chair>
  <chair>Bilirakis</chair>
  <chair>Bishop (UT)</chair>
  <chair>Blackburn</chair>
  <chair>Blunt</chair>
  <chair>Boehner</chair>
  <chair>Bonner</chair>
  <chair>Boozman</chair>
  <chair>Boustany</chair>
  <chair>Brady (TX)</chair>
  <chair>Broun (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Brown (SC)</chair>
  <chair>Brown-Waite, Ginny</chair>
  <chair>Buchanan</chair>
  <chair>Burgess</chair>
  <chair>Burton (IN)</chair>
  <chair>Buyer</chair>
  <chair>Calvert</chair>
  <chair>Camp (MI)</chair>
  <chair>Campbell (CA)</chair>
  <chair>Cannon</chair>
  <chair>Cantor</chair>
  <chair>Capito</chair>
  <chair>Carter</chair>
  <chair>Castle</chair>
  <chair>Chabot</chair>
  <chair>Coble</chair>
  <chair>Cole (OK)</chair>
  <chair>Conaway</chair>
  <chair>Crenshaw</chair>
  <chair>Davis (KY)</chair>
  <chair>Davis, David</chair>
  <chair>Davis, Tom</chair>
  <chair>Deal (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Dent</chair>
  <chair>Diaz-Balart, L.</chair>
  <chair>Diaz-Balart, M.</chair>
  <chair>Doolittle</chair>
  <chair>Drake</chair>
  <chair>Dreier</chair>
  <chair>Duncan</chair>
  <chair>Ehlers</chair>
  <chair>Emerson</chair>
  <chair>English (PA)</chair>
  <chair>Everett</chair>
  <chair>Fallin</chair>
  <chair>Feeney</chair>
  <chair>Ferguson</chair>
  <chair>Flake</chair>
  <chair>Forbes</chair>
  <chair>Fortenberry</chair>
  <chair>Fossella</chair>
  <chair>Foxx</chair>
  <chair>Franks (AZ)</chair>
  <chair>Frelinghuysen</chair>
  <chair>Gallegly</chair>
  <chair>Garrett (NJ)</chair>
  <chair>Gerlach</chair>
  <chair>Gilchrest</chair>
  <chair>Gingrey</chair>
  <chair>Gohmert</chair>
  <chair>Goode</chair>
  <chair>Goodlatte</chair>
  <chair>Granger</chair>
  <chair>Graves</chair>
  <chair>Hall (TX)</chair>
  <chair>Hastings (WA)</chair>
  <chair>Hayes</chair>
  <chair>Hensarling</chair>
  <chair>Herger</chair>
  <chair>Hobson</chair>
  <chair>Hoekstra</chair>
  <chair>Hulshof</chair>
  <chair>Hunter</chair>
  <chair>Inglis (SC)</chair>
  <chair>Issa</chair>
  <chair>Johnson (IL)</chair>
  <chair>Johnson, Sam</chair>
  <chair>Jordan</chair>
  <chair>Keller</chair>
  <chair>King (IA)</chair>
  <chair>King (NY)</chair>
  <chair>Kingston</chair>
  <chair>Kirk</chair>
  <chair>Kline (MN)</chair>
  <chair>Knollenberg</chair>
  <chair>Kuhl (NY)</chair>
  <chair>LaHood</chair>
  <chair>Lamborn</chair>
  <chair>Latham</chair>
  <chair>LaTourette</chair>
  <chair>Lewis (CA)</chair>
  <chair>Linder</chair>
  <chair>LoBiondo</chair>
  <chair>Lucas</chair>
  <chair>Lungren, Daniel E.</chair>
  <chair>Manzullo</chair>
  <chair>Marchant</chair>
  <chair>McCarthy (CA)</chair>
  <chair>McCaul (TX)</chair>
  <chair>McCotter</chair>
  <chair>McCrery</chair>
  <chair>McHenry</chair>
  <chair>McHugh</chair>
  <chair>McKeon</chair>
  <chair>McMorris Rodgers</chair>
  <chair>Mica</chair>
  <chair>Miller (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Miller (MI)</chair>
  <chair>Moran (KS)</chair>
  <chair>Murphy, Tim</chair>
  <chair>Musgrave</chair>
  <chair>Myrick</chair>
  <chair>Neugebauer</chair>
  <chair>Nunes</chair>
  <chair>Pearce</chair>
  <chair>Pence</chair>
  <chair>Peterson (PA)</chair>
  <chair>Petri</chair>
  <chair>Pickering</chair>
  <chair>Pitts</chair>
  <chair>Platts</chair>
  <chair>Poe</chair>
  <chair>Porter</chair>
  <chair>Price (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Pryce (OH)</chair>
  <chair>Putnam</chair>
  <chair>Radanovich</chair>
  <chair>Ramstad</chair>
  <chair>Regula</chair>
  <chair>Rehberg</chair>
  <chair>Reichert</chair>
  <chair>Rogers (MI)</chair>
  <chair>Rohrabacher</chair>
  <chair>Ros-Lehtinen</chair>
  <chair>Roskam</chair>
  <chair>Royce</chair>
  <chair>Ryan (WI)</chair>
  <chair>Sali</chair>
  <chair>Saxton</chair>
  <chair>Schmidt</chair>
  <chair>Sensenbrenner</chair>
  <chair>Sessions</chair>
  <chair>Shadegg</chair>
  <chair>Shays</chair>
  <chair>Shimkus</chair>
  <chair>Shuster</chair>
  <chair>Simpson</chair>
  <chair>Smith (NE)</chair>
  <chair>Smith (NJ)</chair>
  <chair>Smith (TX)</chair>
  <chair>Souder</chair>
  <chair>Stearns</chair>
  <chair>Sullivan</chair>
  <chair>Tancredo</chair>
  <chair>Terry</chair>
  <chair>Thornberry</chair>
  <chair>Tiahrt</chair>
  <chair>Tiberi</chair>
  <chair>Turner</chair>
  <chair>Upton</chair>
  <chair>Walberg</chair>
  <chair>Walden (OR)</chair>
  <chair>Walsh (NY)</chair>
  <chair>Wamp</chair>
  <chair>Weldon (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Weller</chair>
  <chair>Westmoreland</chair>
  <chair>Whitfield (KY)</chair>
  <chair>Wicker</chair>
  <chair>Wilson (NM)</chair>
  <chair>Wilson (SC)</chair>
  <chair>Wolf</chair>
  <chair>Young (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Bono</chair>
  <chair>Cardoza</chair>
  <chair>Carson</chair>
  <chair>Chandler</chair>
  <chair>Cubin</chair>
  <chair>Culberson</chair>
  <chair>Ellison</chair>
  <chair>Engel</chair>
  <chair>Heller</chair>
  <chair>Hinojosa</chair>
  <chair>Hooley</chair>
  <chair>Jindal</chair>
  <chair>Jones (NC)</chair>
  <chair>Lewis (KY)</chair>
  <chair>Mack</chair>
  <chair>Miller, Gary</chair>
  <chair>Paul</chair>
  <chair>Renzi</chair>
  <chair>Reynolds</chair>
  <chair>Rodriguez</chair>
  <chair>Rogers (AL)</chair>
  <chair>Rogers (KY)</chair>
  <chair>Wasserman Schultz</chair>
  <chair>Waters</chair>
  <chair>Young (AK)</chair>
  <chair> Members are advised 2 minutes remain in this vote.</chair>
  <chair/>
  <chair>Mr. NEUGEBAUER changed his vote from "yea" to "nay."</chair>
  <chair>So the previous question was ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The result of the vote was announced as above recorded.</chair>
  <chair> The question is on the resolution.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
