<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1181059208" ordinal="19" title="EXPRESSING SENSE OF CONGRESS THAT NATIONAL MUSEUM OF WILDLIFE ART BE DESIGNATED AS &quot;NATIONAL MUSEUM OF WILDLIFE ART OF THE UNITED STATES&quot;">
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and agree to  the concurrent resolution (<bill type="hc" number="116">H. Con. Res. 116</bill>) expressing the sense of Congress that the National Museum of Wildlife Art, located in Jackson, Wyoming, shall be designated as the "National Museum of Wildlife Art of the United States".</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the concurrent resolution.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from the Virgin Islands (Mrs. Christensen) and the gentleman from Utah (Mr. Cannon) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the measure under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from the Virgin Islands?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>House Concurrent Resolution 116, introduced by the gentlewoman from Wyoming (Mrs. Cubin), expresses the sense of Congress that the National Museum of Wildlife Art located in Jackson, Wyoming, shall be designated as the National Museum of Wildlife Art of the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The National Museum of Wildlife Art is a private museum located on non-Federal land. The museum is housed at a facility that overlooks the 25,000 acre National Elk Refuge and is adjacent to Grand Teton National Park.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The National Museum of Wildlife Art was founded in 1987 with a private gift of a collection of art. Today, the museum features a collection of over 2,000 pieces of art portraying wildlife dating back to 2000 B.C.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, <bill type="hc" number="116">H. Con. Res. 116</bill> will help the National Museum of Wildlife Art receive greater public awareness. I commend Representative Cubin for her work on this matter. We support the concurrent resolution and urge its adoption by the House today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of House Concurrent Resolution 116, and yield myself as much time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>House Concurrent Resolution 116 has been adequately explained by the majority. The only thing I would add is I would like to commend Congresswoman Cubin for her work on this resolution to designate the National Museum of Wildlife Art of the United States in Jackson, Wyoming. This designation places the National Museum of Wildlife Art of the United States in a prestigious class of less than 20 museums to earn such a designation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge adoption of the resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from the Virgin Islands (Mrs. Christensen) that the House suspend the rules and agree to the concurrent resolution, <bill type="hc" number="116">H. Con. Res. 116</bill>.</chair>
</record>
