<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1185163200" ordinal="20" title="SANTA ROSA URBAN WATER REUSE PLAN ACT">
  <narrative>SANTA ROSA URBAN WATER REUSE PLAN ACT -- (House of Representatives - July 23, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H8195]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="716">H.R. 716</bill>) to amend the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to participate in the Santa Rosa Urban Water Reuse Plan, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="716">H.R. 716</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "Santa Rosa Urban Water Reuse Plan Act".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. PROJECT AUTHORIZATION.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) In General.--The Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act (Public Law 102-575, title XVI; 43 U.S.C. 390h et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;"SEC. 16__. CITY OF SANTA ROSA, CALIFORNIA, URBAN WATER REUSE PLAN.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(a) Authorization.--The Secretary, in cooperation with the City of Santa Rosa, California, is authorized to participate in the design, planning, and construction of projects to implement the plan titled `Santa Rosa Urban Water Reuse Plan'.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(b) Cost Share.--The Federal share of the costs of the projects authorized by this section shall not exceed 25 percent of the total cost. The Secretary shall credit the City of Santa Rosa with the value of all expenditures made before the date of the enactment of this section that are used toward completion of projects that are compatible with this section.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(c) Limitations.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(1) Federal funds shall not be used for the operation or maintenance of a project authorized by this section.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(2) Funds authorized by this legislation shall not be used for the development of new wetland areas.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(d) Authorization of Appropriations.--There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $20,000,000.".</narrative>
  <narrative> (b) Conforming Amendment.--The table of sections in section 2 of Public Law 102-575 is amended by inserting after the last item relating to title XVI the following:&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <narrative>"Sec..16__..City of Santa Rosa, California, Urban Water Reuse Plan.".</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) and the gentlewoman from Washington (Mrs. McMorris Rodgers) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Arizona.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members have 5 legislative days to revise and extend and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Arizona?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the purpose of <bill type="h" number="716">H.R. 716</bill>, as amended, is to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to participate in the design and construction of the Santa Rosa Urban Water Reuse Plan. The water recycling facilities authorized by this legislation will result in significant improvements in water quality and water supply reliability in the Santa Rosa area.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I commend the sponsor of this legislation, Ms. Woolsey, for her commitment in this important project.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to join me in supporting this important bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield such time as she may consume to the gentlewoman from California (Ms. Woolsey).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400436" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="716">H.R. 716</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I want to thank Chairman Rahall for his leadership in bringing <bill type="h" number="716">H.R. 716</bill>, the Santa Rosa Urban Water Reuse bill, to the floor. The Santa Rosa Urban Water Reuse bill is a huge step in the right direction for the City of Santa Rosa. It will help the city increase its reuse of wastewater as an alternative to releasing the water into the Russian River, where my district receives the great majority of our drinking water. The project is especially important in a region that remains  arid for 6 months of the year and where droughts pose a genuine threat to humans and endangered species.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under the reuse plan, the City of Santa Rosa will use recycled water for landscape irrigation, allowing the city to conserve valuable water for human consumption and for watershed preservation and enhancement. It is essential that we find new ways to reuse wastewater and prevent further discharge into nearby waterways. This project can help the City of Santa Rosa by making great strides in its water reuse program and give the city an opportunity to help endangered species, and at the same time  protect the Russian River from further discharge.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask for support of <bill type="h" number="1716">H.R. 1716</bill>, the Santa Rosa Urban Water Reuse bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mrs." name="RODGERS, McMORRIS" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The chairman and sponsor have adequately explained the bill. I applaud the amendment agreed to in committee that prohibits taxpayer dollars from being used to create unrelated wetlands in this project.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, given that the majority has not fully funded the title XVI program in the Energy and Water appropriations bill, I note that this bill makes the $328 million backlog problem worse.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="716">H.R. 716</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the bill, as amended, was passed.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
