<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1195059601" ordinal="61" title="TIME FOR PAKISTAN TO STOP BEING A DICTATORSHIP">
  <narrative>TIME FOR PAKISTAN TO STOP BEING A DICTATORSHIP -- (House of Representatives - November 14, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H13943]</narrative>
  <narrative>(Ms. ZOE LOFGREN of California asked and was given permission to address the House for 1 minute and to revise and extend her remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400245" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, Thirty years ago, I was in law school studying, among other things, the Constitution and deepening my passion for freedom under law. With me at Santa Clara Law School was Munir Malik. That small Jesuit institution instilled in me a sense of duty to stand for principle that led me to this House. That same sense of duty led Malik to leave behind a lucrative career as a CPA and lawyer to return to Pakistan. Last year, he was named president of Pakistan's  Supreme Court Bar Association. This May, he was the target of an assassination attempt. And, this month, he was arrested by our ally. Our ally? President Musharraf. His crime? Standing up for the rule of law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Musharraf is liberating al Qaeda members in the western territories while arresting judges and lawyers who believe in law. Pakistan is using our money to do it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It's time for Pakistan to tell us where Malik and the other lawyers are. Time for Pakistan to set them free. Time for Pakistan to stop being a dictatorship.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I include for the Record a letter from the faculty at Santa Clara Law  School asking for a return to the rule of law and the release of their former student.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Statement by Members of the Faculty of Santa Clara University School of Law on General Musharraf's Abrogation of Rule of Law</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are deeply concerned about the abrogation of the Rule of Law in Pakistan. General Musharraf, in a brazen attempt to perpetuate his own rule, has used his state apparatus to disband the highest courts of the country. Thousands of lawyers, journalists, judges, human rights activists have been jailed. in many cases families have no idea of the whereabouts of the detainees.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our own concern is particularly sparked by the arrest and detention of one of our graduates, Muneer Malik, the Immediate Past President of the Pakistani Supreme Court Bar Association. His fate is, of course, merely a small part of the overall tragedy taking place but as we know him to be a conscientious, industrious lawyer dedicated to the welfare of his country, and not in the least a threat to law and order; he symbolizes the injustice being practiced.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We, in fact, are not an organized political group. We have never before joined in a statement of this sort with each other. What brings us together in this plea is the fact that we are all professors of law who teach in the law school which graduated Mr. Malik and who share a respect for the rule of law. We deplore what has happened. We assume that many more people like him have been swept from public view. The Supreme and High Court judges have been locked in their own homes. Police have stormed  into bar-association gatherings and have manhandled lawyers, some of them women, some of them septuagenarian! TV stations have been blacked out and police vans are carting off telecommunication equipment from private TV stations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The U.S. must use all its influence and in no uncertain terms demand the restoration of the Supreme Court status quo ante Nov 2nd 2007. It must demand the immediate release of and accounting for all persons who have been jailed after the promulgation of the so-called emergency. It should be recalled that President Musharraf removed the Chief Justice once before, a short while ago, and that he was forced to rescind his order because of the pressure of world opinion. The embattled civil society  in Pakistan must realize that America stands for the rule of Law and the liberty of all peoples.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Signed by:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>George Alexander, Dean and Professor of Law Emeritus.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Patricia Cain, Inez Mabie Professor of Law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Colleen Chien, Assistant Professor of Law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rev. Paul Goda, S.J., Professor of Law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Allen Hammond, Phil and Bobbie San Filippo Professor of Law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ellen Kreitzberg Professor of Law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Philip Jimenez Professor of Law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Jean Love Elizabeth H. and John A. Sutro Professor of Law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Gary Neustadter Professor of Law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Michelle Oberman Professor of Law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Robert Peterson Professor of Law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mack Player Professor of Law and Director, Center for Global Law and Policy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Margaret Russell Professor of Law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Catherine Sandoval Assistant Professor of Law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Jiri Toman Professor of Law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Gerald Uelman Professor of Law and Director, California Commission for the Fair Administration of Justice.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Stephanie Wildman Professor of Law and Director, Center for Social Justice and Public Service.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nancy Wright Professor of Law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Eric Wright Professor of Law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>David Yosifon Assistant Professor of Law.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
