<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1170781203" ordinal="38" title="YAKIMA-TIETON IRRIGATION DISTRICT CONVEYANCE ACT OF 2007">
  <speaking speaker="400290" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="386">H.R. 386</bill>) to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain buildings and lands of the Yakima Project, Washington, to the Yakima-Tieton Irrigation District.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from California (Mrs. Napolitano) and the gentlewoman from Washington (Mrs. McMorris Rodgers) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400290" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from California?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400290" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, <bill type="h" number="386">H.R. 386</bill> would transfer title for approximately 9 acres of land and several buildings to the Yakima-Tieton Irrigation District. The terms of the transfer are included in a formal agreement between the Bureau of Reclamation and the irrigation district. Other parts of the reclamation project, including the Tieton diversion dam and associated canals, would not be affected.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the 109th Congress, the Subcommittee on Water and Power held a hearing on similar legislation. That bill was favorably reported by the committee and passed by this House. We have no objection to this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mrs." name="RODGERS, McMORRIS" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="386">H.R. 386</bill> and yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, <bill type="h" number="386">H.R. 386</bill>, sponsored by our colleague, the gentleman from Washington (Mr. Hastings), conveys 9 acres of federally owned land and administrative buildings to the Yakima-Tieton Irrigation District in Washington State. No project facilities, such as dams, diversion structures or canals, are included in this title transfer. The transfer has been in the works for almost a decade.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation, also introduced by the junior Senator from Washington State, will enhance more private ownership and decrease the Federal Government's liability. It is a win for the local community and a win for the American taxpayer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this important bipartisan legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400290" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mrs." name="RODGERS, McMORRIS" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield such time as he may consume to the gentleman from Washington (Mr. Hastings).</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400171" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I thank the gentlelady for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, <bill type="h" number="386">H.R. 386</bill> is a pretty straightforward bill. This legislation would authorize the transfer of about 9 acres of Federal property along with a few associated structures from the Bureau of Reclamation to the Yakima-Tieton Irrigation District in central Washington.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The irrigation district has fully repaid its obligations to the Federal Government related to these properties and now simply pays the bureau for their operation and maintenance. This conveyance would enable the irrigation district to make needed improvements, while allowing the bureau to focus its limited resources where they are more urgently needed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation is based on a formula agreement negotiated between the bureau and the Yakima-Tieton Irrigation District in 2004. I commend the irrigation district and the staff of the bureau for working together at the local level to resolve the concerns of the parties involved.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this same legislation passed unanimously during the previous Congress, but didn't get through during the final parts of the session. So I urge my colleagues to support this bill again today so that we may move it on to the other body.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank Chairman Rahall and Ranking Member Young of the Natural Resources Committee and their staff for their assistance in expediting this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mrs." name="RODGERS, McMORRIS" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no additional speakers, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400290" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from California (Mrs. Napolitano) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="386">H.R. 386</bill>.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400290" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this question will be postponed.</chair>
</record>
