<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1192550402" ordinal="38" title="PERSONAL EXPLANATION">
  <narrative>PERSONAL EXPLANATION -- (House of Representatives - October 16, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H11576]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400207" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, unfortunately today, October 16, 2007, I was unable to cast my votes on ordering the previous question on <bill type="hr" number="741">H. Res. 741</bill>, <bill type="hr" number="741">H. Res. 741</bill>; ordering the previous question on <bill type="hr" number="742">H. Res. 742</bill>, H. Res 742; and on suspending the rules and passing <bill type="h" number="3678">H.R. 3678</bill> and wish the record to reflect my intentions had I been able to vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Had I been present for rollcall No. 964 on ordering the previous question on <bill type="hr" number="741">H. Res. 741</bill>, providing for the consideration of <bill type="hr" number="734">H. Res. 734</bill>, expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding the withholding of information relating to corruption in Iraq, I would have voted "nay."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Had I been present for rollcall No. 965 on passing <bill type="hr" number="741">H. Res. 741</bill>, providing for the consideration of <bill type="hr" number="734">H. Res. 734</bill>, expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding the withholding of information relating to corruption in Iraq, I would have voted "nay."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Had I been present for rollcall No. 966 on ordering the previous question on <bill type="hr" number="742">H. Res. 742</bill>, providing for the consideration of <bill type="h" number="2102">H.R. 2102</bill>, the Free Flow of Information Act, I would have voted "nay."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Had I been present for rollcall No. 967 on passing <bill type="hr" number="742">H. Res. 742</bill>, providing for the consideration of <bill type="h" number="2102">H.R. 2102</bill>, the Free Flow of Information Act, I would have voted "nay."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Had I been present for rollcall No. 968 on suspending the rules and passing <bill type="h" number="3678">H.R. 3678</bill>, the Internet Tax Freedom Act Amendments Act of 2007, I would have voted "yea."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
