<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1182182403" ordinal="30" title="SBA ENTREPRENEURIAL DEVELOPMENT PROGRAMS ACT OF 2007">
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from New York (Ms. Vel&#xE1;zquez) and the gentleman from Tennessee (Mr. David Davis) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412235" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of the request to suspend the rules and pass <bill type="h" number="2359">H.R. 2359</bill>, the SBA Entrepreneurial Development Programs Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to thank Chairwoman Vel&#xE1;zquez for working in a cooperative and bipartisan manner to bring this bill to the floor. This bill makes modest yet necessary changes in the core entrepreneurial technical assistance programs of the SBA, the Small Business Development Center Program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Small business development centers, on a relatively modest appropriation, provide free training sessions which last at least 1 hour and free individual one-on-one counseling. The centers met a total of 700,000 individual business owners and prospective owners in fiscal year 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Changes are necessary to clarify the statutory mandate and ensure that small business development centers are appropriately responding to the new challenges facing America's entrepreneurs. These alterations are reflected in title I of the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Even though the program is more than 25 years old, there is no definition of the term "small business development center," which substantially adds to the confusion interpreting the statutory language. I would like to thank the chairwoman for including the definition in the term.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Another key change demonstrates the need to update the mission of the small business development centers as technology and business practices change. Broadband access is no longer a luxury for many, if not most, small businesses; yet the only reliable data on broadband access in America comes from providers that make the reports to the Federal Communications Commission.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congressman Fortenberry, the ranking member of the Committee's Subcommittee on Rural and Urban Entrepreneurship, had the idea that rather than relying on these providers, a more accurate picture might come from actually asking individuals whether they had access to broadband services. Mr. Fortenberry thought it would make sense to have the center survey their clients when they come in the door on the availability of broadband service. The survey might prove a valuable addition  to supplement the existing data from broadband providers. And without appropriate information on broadband access and penetration, it is impossible to develop policies that ensure small businesses will have affordable access to broadband.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Title II also includes a mechanism to increase the capacity of small business development centers to offer regulatory compliance assistance to small businesses disproportionately affected by erroneous regulatory burdens. It is an idea supported by the House in the previous four Congresses and by the National Federation of Independent Business. I would like to thank the chairwoman and Mr. Sestak for including this critical assistance to small business owners.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ultimately, <bill type="h" number="2359">H.R. 2359</bill> is designed to help small businesses get the advice and assistance they need to continue their ever-increasing importance in maintaining America's prime place in the global economy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ms. VEL&#xC1;ZQUEZ. Mr. Speaker, I recognize Mr. Sestak, the sponsor of the legislation, for as much time as he may consume.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412232" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would like to thank the distinguished chairwoman from New York for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today to urge my colleagues to support a piece of legislation to enhance two critical Small Business Administration entrepreneurial development programs, the Small Business Development Centers and the Service Corps for Retired Executives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Serving as the Representative in a district that has been historically driven economically by vibrant local small businesses, I greatly appreciate and support the entrepreneurial development assistance that the SBA provides.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We know that entrepreneurial development programs work. Businesses who receive SBA entrepreneurial assistance are twice as likely to succeed. And for every Federal dollar spent on entrepreneurial development, $7 are generated in increased tax revenue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But in the past 3 years, due to changes in our ever-changing globalizing economy, my district has lost 607 small businesses and one out of five manufacturing establishments. This is a trend that I am committed to reversing through fostering entrepreneurial development and creating the right set of conditions to help businesses flourish, stay and be attracted to my district, and I believe that supporting effective small business entrepreneurial development programs is a key part of that strategy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1980, Congress established the SBDC program to foster economic development by providing management, technical and research assistance to current and prospective small businesses. As you know, SBDCs provide services which include assisting small businesses with financial, marketing, production, organizational, engineering and technical problems and feasibility studies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>SBDCs serve Americans with a desire to start their own venture but who lack the technical expertise associated with starting and running a successful business, and in the past decades, SBDCs have provided assistance to millions of entrepreneurs across America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The SBDC program also represents the effective and efficient use of allocated Federal moneys through public/private collaboration. To that end, SBDCs are funded by matching moneys provided by State legislatures, foundations, State and local chambers of commerce, public and private universities, vocational and technical schools and community colleges. In fact, sponsors' contributions have been increasingly exceeding the minimum 50 percent matching share, signifying greater participation among  such groups and institutions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is why I feel especially fortunate to have several Small Business Development Sub-Centers located at local universities, such as Widener University and the University of Pennsylvania, which provide critical business resources and technical assistance to small businesses in and around my district.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to stress that the core SBDC program has been extremely effective, but there are certain operational improvements that can be implemented to increase the flexibility of SBDCs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To that end, changes proposed in this legislation will ensure the quality of grant recipients to host SBDCs; help SBDCs maintain their autonomy from undue SBA interference; protect the confidentiality of SBDC clients; ensure that taxpayer dollars are being spent as efficiently as possible by not using SBDC funds except for the sole purpose of business development; and allowing exemptions to the current cap on non-matching portability grants in the event of federally designated natural or human  caused disasters.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>In addition to these operational changes, it is important to strengthen the SBDC core program, which successfully navigates entrepreneurs in managing their business, by establishing specific grant programs that will allow SBDCs to tailor their services.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For instance, the Capital Access Initiative would establish grants to assist entrepreneurs in processing loan applications and obtaining private equity. An Innovation and Competitiveness Initiative would establish grants to allow SBDCs to become technology centers, to help market technologies and advanced projects to manufacturers. A disaster recovery program would establish grants to allow SBDCs to assist and coordinate the Federal response for small business disaster victims.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The older entrepreneurial assistance program will target older Americans  interested in transitioning to become business owners, while the Small Business Sustainability Initiative will promote the development and implementation of energy-efficient and clean energy improvements and technology. And an Affordable Health Care Initiative will help small business owners provide affordable health care insurance options to their employees, as the chairwoman mentioned.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As I also spoke about, a second program which this legislation will address is SCORE, which provides entrepreneurs with free counseling assistance by former executives. SCORE provides a valuable service to small businesses, and I believe it will be even stronger with a provision to actively recruit volunteer mentors who will then provide a greater reflection of the social and economic diversity of those who will utilize SBA services, such as women and underrepresented minorities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge all my colleagues to support this important bill, which will greatly enhance the business development resources available to America's small business owners and aspiring entrepreneurs.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412235" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would like to yield such time as he may consume to my good friend Mr. Latham.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400234" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I thank the gentleman from Tennessee for yielding me time, and I congratulate the committee and the chairman for bringing this piece of legislation forward.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of <bill type="h" number="2359">H.R. 2359</bill>, the Small Business Administration Entrepreneurial Development Programs Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am especially pleased that the Small Business Committee included legislation that I introduced earlier this Congress, <bill type="h" number="731">H.R. 731</bill>, the National Small Business Regulatory Assistance Act, into this broad legislative package. This National Small Business Regulatory Assistance Act utilizes one of SBA's most effective programs, the Small Business Development Center program. Generally the SBDCs support small businesses with financial, management, and marketing activities. My legislation, included in  section 207 of <bill type="h" number="2359">H.R. 2359</bill>, creates a pilot program through the SBDCs that will provide free confidential counseling on regulatory compliance and help small businesses gain access to regulatory information and resources.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The research done by the Small Business Administration demonstrates that small businesses with less than 20 employees pay more than $7,600 per employee to comply with Federal regulations each year, while large firms pay 45 percent less per employee. Adjusted for inflation, the annual cost of Federal regulations faced by America's small businesses in 2004 was over $875 billion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The fact of the matter is many small business owners have neither the time nor the expertise to sort through hundreds of pages of regulations in the Federal Register. Small business owners often learn of their failure to comply with Federal regulations or even that new Federal regulations have been imposed only after a penalty has been assessed. The current system denies small businesses access to regulatory compliance assistance and further weakens the opportunity for America's small businesses  to compete with larger firms both domestically and internationally.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Small Business Regulatory Assistance Act represents a win-win for America's small businesses. Not only will the SBDCs help small business owners understand what they must do to comply with Federal regulations but also how they may do so in a most cost-effective manner.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, I would like to thank the committee for including this legislation in the bill, and I urge my colleagues to support the overall bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ms. VEL&#xC1;ZQUEZ. Mr. Speaker, I yield myself the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today's entrepreneurs are facing countless challenges. SBA's entrepreneurial development programs must be modernized to provide small businesses with the ability to deal with the economic conditions of today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Sestak's legislation, the SBA Entreprenurial Development Programs Act of 2007, makes much-needed updates to the agency's programs so that they are better able to assist entrepreneurs and enable small firms to remain a driving force in our economy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2359">H.R. 2359</bill> has the support of the NFIB, who, in addition to supporting it, has made it one of their key votes for the 110th Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again I want to thank Mr. Sestak and also Mr. Chabot, the ranking minority member, for working in a bipartisan manner to move this legislation and other bills that will be moved today. I want to thank the staff that worked on this bill. From the majority staff, Michael Day, Adam Minehardt, Nicole Witenstein; from Representative Sestak's staff, Clarence Tong; and from the minority staff, Barry Pineles.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I strongly urge my colleagues to vote for <bill type="h" number="2359">H.R. 2359</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in strong support of <bill type="h" number="2359">H.R. 2359</bill>, the SBA Entrepreneurial Development Programs Act of 2007. I commend our colleague from Pennsylvania (Mr. Sestak) for sponsoring this legislation. I also commend our colleague from New York (Ms. Vel&#xE1;zquez), Chairwoman of the Committee on Small Business, and the members of the Committee on Small Business for their initiatives to strengthen America's small businesses and for bringing to the House chamber  today four important bills aimed at improving programs and services administered by the U.S. Small Business Administration.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2359">H.R. 2359</bill> would reauthorize certain entrepreneurial development programs and aid small businesses across our country in receiving enhanced assistance from Small Business Development Centers (SBDCs). <bill type="h" number="2359">H.R. 2359</bill> would also expand the services available through SBDCs to include assistance aimed to help businesses prepare for and respond to economic disruptions caused by natural and manmade disasters, regulatory burdens, and increased costs. By ensuring that the SBDC core programs remain robust and  authorizing new programs that are designed specifically to meet evolving needs of small business owners and operators, this bill will help SBDCs sustain a reputation as trusted and valued sources of technical assistance for our country's entrepreneurs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation would further make important changes to the Small Business Administration Service Corps of Retired Executives (SCORE) Program. These changes will help ensure that SBA clients from socially and economically disadvantaged backgrounds can benefit from advice, counseling and mentoring from executives from similar, disadvantaged backgrounds. This bill would require the SBA to increase its efforts to recruit such executives to participate in the SCORE Program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The SBDC and SCORE programs have been remarkably successful. This bill will help ensure that those excellent programs are as responsive as possible to the evolving needs of our country's small businesses. I urge my colleagues' support for this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412235" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no further requests for time, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from New York (Ms. Vel&#xE1;zquez) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="2359">H.R. 2359</bill>.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this question will be postponed.</chair>
</record>
