<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1170694805" ordinal="43" title="PAKISTAN REFUSING TO TAKE ACTION AGAINST TALIBAN">
  <chair> Under a previous order of the House, the gentleman from New Jersey (Mr. Pallone) is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400308" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I come to the floor this evening to once again call upon Pakistani President Musharraf to take action against Taliban fighters in the western region of his country. President Musharraf continues to deny that Taliban leaders are hiding in Pakistan and that the Taliban are regrouping there, despite numerous international press accounts describing otherwise.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>President Musharraf claims that securing the border between Pakistan and Afghanistan is not the sole responsibility of his country. He has admitted that border guards at the tactical level often, quote, turn a blind eye when insurgents cross the border into Pakistan. Yet he still shirks the responsibility his country must take in dealing with the situation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In Musa Qala, a town in southern Afghanistan where a peace deal last year was signed by NATO-led troops and local elders, government officials confirmed that Taliban forces had taken partial control of the town in the last few days. The Taliban's movement into Musa Qala completely disregards the peace agreement and goes against the wishes of the Afghani citizens living in the town.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A similar deal was developed last year in North Waziristan, a region in western Pakistan. As was the case in Musa Qala, Taliban fighters disregarded this deal and have taken partial control of the region. Yet President Musharraf continues to defend this peace deal, despite the fact that the Taliban seemed to have created a stronghold in the region where they can likely plan future offensives against U.S. forces and the citizens of Afghanistan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If the Pakistani President truly wishes to defend this peace deal, he must take the necessary steps towards eliminating Taliban forces, not only in North Waziristan, but throughout his country. President Musharraf has also scaled back plans to enforce and patrol the border between Afghanistan and Pakistan. If Musharraf actually wishes to eliminate Taliban forces in Pakistan, he must work to control this border in a safe and diplomatic manner.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, last week I came to the floor to highlight <bill type="h" number="1">H.R. 1</bill>, a bill that implements the recommendations of the bipartisan 9/11 Commission. This is part of our first 100 hours. Included in <bill type="h" number="1">H.R. 1</bill> is language that would end U.S. military assistance and armed sales licensing to Pakistan unless it is certified that the Islamabad government is, I quote, making all possible efforts to end Taliban activities on Pakistani soil.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is my hope that once this law is passed, the bill will finally force President Musharraf to crack down on Taliban training camps and leaders within his country. The Bush administration, however, has already signaled its opposition to this language in <bill type="h" number="1">H.R. 1</bill>. Last week, Deputy Assistant Secretary of State John Gastright assured Musharraf's government that the administration opposed any end to military assistance to Pakistan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe it is absolutely unacceptable for President Bush to oppose these actions against the Pakistani government. The language in <bill type="h" number="1">H.R. 1</bill> places appropriate pressure on President Musharraf to finally take suitable action against the Taliban forces currently plotting within his country's borders.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Bush administration claims that it deals with President Musharraf regardless of his actions, because it believes the Pakistani President is better than the Islamic extremist and anti-Western alternatives in Pakistan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, there are Democratic alternatives in Pakistan. According to a recent poll by the International Republican Institute, the second most popular leader in Pakistan is former Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto. Now, Mrs. Bhutto's party, the Pakistani People's Party, has joined with the Muslim League Party to form the Alliance for Restoration of Democracy and hopes to restore democratic government to Pakistan in the near future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, it is essential for the United States to increase pressure on President Musharraf to step up his commitment to eliminate Taliban fighters in training hubs in his country. A significant step towards applying this pressure came with the language in <bill type="h" number="1">H.R. 1</bill>, which we passed in the first 100 hours, ending military aid to Pakistan unless the Pakistani President takes steps towards this goal of routing out Taliban forces. It is imperative for President Bush to realize the importance of  the language in this bill and support the provisions outlined in <bill type="h" number="1">H.R. 1</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
