<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1170781203" ordinal="36" title="ALLOWING FOR RENEGOTIATION OF PAYMENT SCHEDULE OF CONTRACTS BETWEEN SECRETARY OF THE INTERIOR AND REDWOOD VALLEY COUNTY WATER DISTRICT">
  <speaking speaker="400290" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="235">H.R. 235</bill>) to allow for the renegotiation of the payment schedule of contracts between the Secretary of the Interior and the Redwood Valley County Water District, and for other purposes, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from California (Mrs. Napolitano) and the gentlewoman from Washington (Mrs. McMorris Rodgers) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400290" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from California?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400290" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise in very strong support of <bill type="h" number="235">H.R. 235</bill>, as amended. This legislation will allow the Redwood Valley County Water District in Northern California to renegotiate loans it received from the Federal Government for an unsuccessful water project. This action will clear the way for the Water District to initiate a new project that will develop a reliable supply of drinking water for that area. The District will rely only on private financing for the new project. No Federal money will be spent on this  new project.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, before the District can secure private financing for any project, it must renegotiate the existing loans to provide for their repayment subsequent to repayment of the new loan. Once the new project is built and delivering water, it will provide enough revenue to allow the District to repay both its private loan and the United States Government.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Specifically, this legislation allows the Redwood County Valley Water District to secure a private loan for a project to provide the region with a reliable water supply. It also requires the Water District to repay its current suspended loan to the Federal Government once the renewed water project is paid for.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In consultation with the minority, the legislation includes a minor amendment to clarify the requirement that the Secretary of the Interior must reschedule loan payments and that the payments must begin immediately upon satisfaction of the Water District's newer financial obligation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Similar legislation was passed by this House in the 109th Congress; and I congratulate my colleague, Congressman Mike Thompson, for all of his hard work on behalf of the Redwood Valley County Water District.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I do urge my colleagues to support passage of <bill type="h" number="235">H.R. 235</bill>, as amended.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mrs." name="RODGERS, McMORRIS" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in reluctant support of <bill type="h" number="235">H.R. 235</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There were many last-minute questions about this bill mainly because a hearing wasn't held on it. I hope this will not be the standard procedure for how the majority party brings legislation to the House floor. That is why I am pleased that the majority has made additional inquiries regarding this bill and has decided to offer an amendment to address some concerns. With this amendment, I will not oppose the legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I have no further requests for time, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="400290" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from California (Mrs. Napolitano) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="235">H.R. 235</bill>, as amended.</chair>
</record>
