<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1191340802" ordinal="67" title="YOUTH PRESIDENTIAL FORUM">
  <narrative>YOUTH PRESIDENTIAL FORUM -- (House of Representatives - October 02, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H11129]</narrative>
  <chair> Under a previous order of the House, the gentleman from Florida (Mr. Keller) is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400212" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, what are the most important issues facing today's high school and college students? Being able to afford college? Access to health care? The Iraq war? Who are their favorite Democratic candidates? Obama? Clinton? Edwards?  Who are their favorite Republican candidates? Giuliani? McCain? Romney?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Well, thanks to the first ever National Youth Presidential Forum on November 14, 2007, up to 10 million young people will have the opportunity to hear from the Presidential candidates from both parties and then cast their votes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As the Congressman from central Florida, I'm very proud that the Lou Frey Institute of Politics and Government at the University of Central Florida is playing a key role in putting together this unprecedented event.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>They've joined together with the EWN Foundation, The Presidential Classroom, and the United States Association of Former Members of Congress to sponsor a 3-hour forum online, which brings together Presidential candidates and America's young people for the first time in a unique Webcast.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is how it will work. Presidential classroom scholars will create questions which will then be sent to the Presidential candidates who can respond via videotape prior to the event or live the day of the event. Then, thanks to the event sponsors, the Webcast will be provided free to each of the participating high schools and colleges across the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>All of the students will then be able to vote for up to 36 hours after hearing from each of the candidates on the issues most important to them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to go to www.rocktheweb.org for more information on this great project. It provides a valuable civics lesson for our students and important feedback to our Presidential candidates on the key issues facing America's young people.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would encourage all of the Presidential candidates, high schools and colleges to participate in this worthwhile educational opportunity.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
