<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1195059601" ordinal="50" title="CONFERENCE REPORT ON H.R. 3074, TRANSPORTATION, HOUSING AND URBAN DEVELOPMENT, AND RELATED AGENCIES APPROPRIATIONS ACT, 2008">
  <narrative>CONFERENCE REPORT ON <bill type="h" number="3074">H.R. 3074</bill>, TRANSPORTATION, HOUSING AND URBAN DEVELOPMENT, AND RELATED AGENCIES APPROPRIATIONS ACT, 2008 -- (House of Representatives - November 14, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H13902]</narrative>
  <chair> The gentleman from Massachusetts has 1 minute remaining. The gentleman from Michigan has 18 minutes remaining.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Massachusetts.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400301" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400225" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400301" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, at this time I would like to enter into the Record two more letters, which I have in hand now, one from The United States Conference of Mayors, the National Association of Counties, the National Associations of Local Housing Finance Agencies, the Association for County Community and Economic Development, and the National Community Development Association in support of the conference report on <bill type="h" number="3074">H.R. 3074</bill>. And also, the second letter from the U.S. Chamber of Commerce  urging support of the conference report for <bill type="h" number="3074">H.R. 3074</bill>, signed by the executive director of the U.S. Chamber.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>November 14, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR CHAIRMAN OLVER: The undersigned organizations of local elected and appointed officials urge passage of the conference report on <bill type="h" number="3074">H.R. 3074</bill> that provides funding of transportation and housing programs at $105.6 billion. Housing and community development is a major challenge. Local government officials know that decent, safe, affordable housing is at the core of family stability and strong neighborhoods. Your bill will assist us in achieving affordable housing and community development  goals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="3074">H.R. 3074</bill> provides funding for the Community Development Block Grant (CDBG), HOME Investment Partnerships Program, Public Housing, Section 8, Homeless, and other housing and community development programs. As you know, more than 260 mayors signed a letter calling for increased funding for the CDBG program. HOME continues to be an effective affordable housing program having assisted the development and rehabilitation of nearly 900,000 affordable homes for very low and moderate-income families.  These are just two examples of effective programs. Virtually every housing and community development program in your bill can be cited as having an exemplary record.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We urge the House to pass the conference report to the bill, <bill type="h" number="3074">H.R. 3074</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The United States Conference of Mayors; National Association of Counties; National Associations of Local Housing Finance Agencies; National Association for County Community and Economic Development; and National Community Development Association.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>&lt;pre&gt;--&lt;/pre&gt;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>November 13, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The U.S. Chamber of Commerce, the world's largest business federation representing more than three million businesses and organizations of ever size, sector, and region, strongly urges you to support the conference report for <bill type="h" number="3074">H.R. 3074</bill>, the "Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2008." This bill provides the necessary funding to ensure that the U.S. transportation system is the safest and most efficient in the world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The business community depends on a safe and reliable transportation system to remain competitive and efficient. The nation's transportation system is the foundation of the nation's economy. If the investments necessary to maintain this foundation are not made, the U.S. economy win suffer. The inadequate surface transportation system costs the economy $63 billion annually in lost time and fuel.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="3074">H.R. 3074</bill> addresses the enormous demands of the nation's transportation infrastructure system by providing funding for the highway and transit programs authorized by Safe, Accountable, Flexible and Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (SAFETEA-LU), which President Bush signed into law two years ago as well as funding for the Federal Aviation Administration to improve the safety, performance and capacity of the nation's aviation system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While the Chamber strongly supports passage of <bill type="h" number="3074">H.R. 3074</bill>, it is important to note that the Chamber is disappointed that <bill type="h" number="3074">H.R. 3074</bill> under-funds public transportation by $81 million. These investments are vital to the safety of our system and the health of the nation's economy. It is imperative that commitments made under SAFETEA-LU be maintained as is required by law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For these reasons, the Chamber urges you to support the conference report for <bill type="h" number="3074">H.R. 3074</bill> and may consider using votes on, or in relation to, this issue in our annual How They Voted scorecard.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely,</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400423" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the conference report on <bill type="h" number="3074">H.R. 3074</bill> provides critical funding for construction of new roads, repairs, and overall improvements to our Nation's infrastructure. The legislation also provides needed funding for housing vouchers and new vouchers for veterans and disabled and low-income families.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400080" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, when it comes to passing a funding bill that has a positive economic impact on our Nation, none is more important than the fiscal year appropriation for the Departments of Transportation, Treasury, and Housing and Urban Development.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>America's transportation system is being stretched beyond its capacity. Both public and private usage of highways, transit, and aviation systems are increasing at rates far outpacing infrastructure investment. A decaying surface transportation system costs the U.S. economy $78 billion annually in lost time and fuel while congestion adds significant pollution to the air, and substandard roads claim thousands of lives every year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By investing $40 billion in the Nation's highway system for construction of new roads, repairs and improvements and $1 billion to address deficient bridges across America, <bill type="h" number="3074">H.R. 3074</bill> honors the commitments to capital investment in highway and public transportation infrastructure made by Congress in the Safe, Accountable, Flexible and Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (SAFETEA-LU) and will not increase the Federal budget deficit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill also addresses many of our Nation's pressing housing needs, at a time when we are facing a housing crisis that has directly impacted millions of American homeowners and millions more as the effects have rippled through the U.S. and world economy. National estimates indicate that as many as 2.5 million mortgages will reset to higher interest rates in the near future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The fiscal year 2008 appropriation for the Department of Housing and Urban Development also addresses the plight of homeless veterans. According to the National Coalition for Homeless Veterans, one out of every three homeless men who is sleeping in a doorway, alley or box in our cities and rural communities has put on a uniform and served this country. By providing $75 million in housing vouchers to homeless veterans, we are beginning to address this problem by providing safe, affordable, permanent  housing access to 7,500 of our homeless veterans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Another housing program strongly supported by my constituents that this bill funds is the Section 8 Project Based Vouchers. If passed the conference report will allocate $6.4 billion, $405 million above 2007 and $568 million above the President's request, to provide affordable housing to 1.3 million low- and very low-income families and individuals, two-thirds of whom are elderly or disabled.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When we pass this bill today and send it to the President, the House of Representatives will be addressing the important challenges of keeping our Nation's transportation system safe and strong, ensuring that every American has adequate shelter, and doing so in a way that strengthens the economy.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400412" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of this conference report for the Transportation, Housing and Urban Development Appropriations for 2008.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The funding provided in the conference report helps enhance our national transportation system at a critical time. Our transportation system is extended beyond its capacity. Public  and private use of highways, transit, and aviation systems are growing far beyond the current level of investment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am particularly pleased the agreement provides funds for a number of important projects not just in my own district but throughout Colorado. Our State faces a number of transportation challenges as a result of rapid expansion in the northwest Denver sububs and mountain and resort communities. Without the passage of this conference report, critical transportation and infrastructure needs for Colorado and the Nation will continue to be shortchanged.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am committed to continue working with the rest of the Colorado delegation, local communities, the Transportation Committee and the administration to secure essential Federal funding to get people and goods from one place to another with a focus on transit and other transportation alternatives, and improving current modes of Colorado's transportation network.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The report also includes a number of important provisions with national implications.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The United States and Colorado are facing a housing crisis that has caused dire impacts to millions of homeowners. Very often a home purchase represents the largest single investment that individuals and families will make in their lifetimes. Homeownership is a cornerstone of the American Dream, and Congress needs to treat it as a top priority. I am pleased the report provides additional funding for counseling assistance for at-risk homeowners. Funding in the bill will assist thousands of borrowers  with mortgage changes and restructuring to help them keep their homes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am also pleased the report makes changes to inequities in the retirement age of U.S. pilots. Like the Senate bill, the report raises the mandatory retirement age for pilots to 65, with certain exceptions. I supported similar provisions that passed the House in the reauthorization of the Federal Aviation Administration. We must take urgent action to ensure that more competent pilots are not lost.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker this legislation is far from perfect but by passing the conference report, Congress will maintain its commitment to a safe, efficient and competitive transportation system that will fuel job creation. I urge its passage today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the previous question is ordered on the conference report.</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <chair> Is the gentleman opposed to the conference report?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400239" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>In its present form, I am.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will report the motion to recommit.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>Mr. Lewis of California moves to recommit the conference report on the bill, <bill type="h" number="3074">H.R. 3074</bill>, to the committee of conference.</narrative>
  <chair> Without objection, the previous question is ordered on the motion to recommit.</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <chair> The question is on the motion to recommit.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and the Speaker pro tempore announced that the noes appeared to have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400239" topic="MOTION TO RECOMMIT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 9 of rule XX, the Chair will reduce to 5 minutes the minimum time for any electronic vote on the question of adoption of the conference report.</chair>
  <chair>The vote was taken by electronic device, and there were--yeas 182, nays 231, not voting 19, as follows:</chair>
  <chair>[Roll No. 1101]</chair>
  <chair>Aderholt</chair>
  <chair>Akin</chair>
  <chair>Alexander</chair>
  <chair>Bachmann</chair>
  <chair>Bachus</chair>
  <chair>Baker</chair>
  <chair>Barrett (SC)</chair>
  <chair>Bartlett (MD)</chair>
  <chair>Barton (TX)</chair>
  <chair>Biggert</chair>
  <chair>Bilbray</chair>
  <chair>Bilirakis</chair>
  <chair>Bishop (UT)</chair>
  <chair>Blackburn</chair>
  <chair>Blunt</chair>
  <chair>Boehner</chair>
  <chair>Bonner</chair>
  <chair>Boozman</chair>
  <chair>Boustany</chair>
  <chair>Brady (TX)</chair>
  <chair>Broun (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Brown (SC)</chair>
  <chair>Brown-Waite, Ginny</chair>
  <chair>Buchanan</chair>
  <chair>Burgess</chair>
  <chair>Burton (IN)</chair>
  <chair>Buyer</chair>
  <chair>Calvert</chair>
  <chair>Camp (MI)</chair>
  <chair>Campbell (CA)</chair>
  <chair>Cannon</chair>
  <chair>Cantor</chair>
  <chair>Capito</chair>
  <chair>Carter</chair>
  <chair>Castle</chair>
  <chair>Chabot</chair>
  <chair>Coble</chair>
  <chair>Cole (OK)</chair>
  <chair>Conaway</chair>
  <chair>Crenshaw</chair>
  <chair>Culberson</chair>
  <chair>Davis (KY)</chair>
  <chair>Davis, David</chair>
  <chair>Davis, Tom</chair>
  <chair>Deal (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Dent</chair>
  <chair>Diaz-Balart, L.</chair>
  <chair>Diaz-Balart, M.</chair>
  <chair>Doolittle</chair>
  <chair>Drake</chair>
  <chair>Dreier</chair>
  <chair>Duncan</chair>
  <chair>Ehlers</chair>
  <chair>Emerson</chair>
  <chair>English (PA)</chair>
  <chair>Everett</chair>
  <chair>Fallin</chair>
  <chair>Feeney</chair>
  <chair>Flake</chair>
  <chair>Forbes</chair>
  <chair>Fortenberry</chair>
  <chair>Fossella</chair>
  <chair>Foxx</chair>
  <chair>Franks (AZ)</chair>
  <chair>Frelinghuysen</chair>
  <chair>Gallegly</chair>
  <chair>Garrett (NJ)</chair>
  <chair>Gerlach</chair>
  <chair>Gilchrest</chair>
  <chair>Gingrey</chair>
  <chair>Gohmert</chair>
  <chair>Goode</chair>
  <chair>Goodlatte</chair>
  <chair>Granger</chair>
  <chair>Graves</chair>
  <chair>Hall (TX)</chair>
  <chair>Hastert</chair>
  <chair>Hastings (WA)</chair>
  <chair>Hayes</chair>
  <chair>Heller</chair>
  <chair>Hensarling</chair>
  <chair>Herger</chair>
  <chair>Hobson</chair>
  <chair>Hoekstra</chair>
  <chair>Hulshof</chair>
  <chair>Inglis (SC)</chair>
  <chair>Issa</chair>
  <chair>Johnson (IL)</chair>
  <chair>Johnson, Sam</chair>
  <chair>Jones (NC)</chair>
  <chair>Jordan</chair>
  <chair>King (IA)</chair>
  <chair>Kingston</chair>
  <chair>Kirk</chair>
  <chair>Kline (MN)</chair>
  <chair>Kuhl (NY)</chair>
  <chair>LaHood</chair>
  <chair>Lamborn</chair>
  <chair>Latham</chair>
  <chair>LaTourette</chair>
  <chair>Lewis (CA)</chair>
  <chair>Lewis (KY)</chair>
  <chair>Linder</chair>
  <chair>Lucas</chair>
  <chair>Lungren, Daniel E.</chair>
  <chair>Manzullo</chair>
  <chair>Marchant</chair>
  <chair>McCarthy (CA)</chair>
  <chair>McCaul (TX)</chair>
  <chair>McCotter</chair>
  <chair>McCrery</chair>
  <chair>McHenry</chair>
  <chair>McKeon</chair>
  <chair>McMorris Rodgers</chair>
  <chair>Mica</chair>
  <chair>Miller (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Miller (MI)</chair>
  <chair>Miller, Gary</chair>
  <chair>Moran (KS)</chair>
  <chair>Murphy, Tim</chair>
  <chair>Musgrave</chair>
  <chair>Myrick</chair>
  <chair>Neugebauer</chair>
  <chair>Nunes</chair>
  <chair>Pearce</chair>
  <chair>Pence</chair>
  <chair>Peterson (PA)</chair>
  <chair>Petri</chair>
  <chair>Pickering</chair>
  <chair>Pitts</chair>
  <chair>Platts</chair>
  <chair>Poe</chair>
  <chair>Price (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Pryce (OH)</chair>
  <chair>Putnam</chair>
  <chair>Radanovich</chair>
  <chair>Ramstad</chair>
  <chair>Regula</chair>
  <chair>Rehberg</chair>
  <chair>Renzi</chair>
  <chair>Reynolds</chair>
  <chair>Rogers (AL)</chair>
  <chair>Rogers (KY)</chair>
  <chair>Rogers (MI)</chair>
  <chair>Rohrabacher</chair>
  <chair>Ros-Lehtinen</chair>
  <chair>Roskam</chair>
  <chair>Royce</chair>
  <chair>Ryan (WI)</chair>
  <chair>Sali</chair>
  <chair>Saxton</chair>
  <chair>Schmidt</chair>
  <chair>Sensenbrenner</chair>
  <chair>Shadegg</chair>
  <chair>Shays</chair>
  <chair>Shimkus</chair>
  <chair>Shuster</chair>
  <chair>Simpson</chair>
  <chair>Smith (NE)</chair>
  <chair>Smith (TX)</chair>
  <chair>Souder</chair>
  <chair>Stearns</chair>
  <chair>Sullivan</chair>
  <chair>Tancredo</chair>
  <chair>Terry</chair>
  <chair>Thornberry</chair>
  <chair>Tiahrt</chair>
  <chair>Tiberi</chair>
  <chair>Turner</chair>
  <chair>Upton</chair>
  <chair>Walberg</chair>
  <chair>Walden (OR)</chair>
  <chair>Wamp</chair>
  <chair>Weldon (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Westmoreland</chair>
  <chair>Whitfield</chair>
  <chair>Wicker</chair>
  <chair>Wilson (NM)</chair>
  <chair>Wilson (SC)</chair>
  <chair>Wolf</chair>
  <chair>Young (AK)</chair>
  <chair>Young (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Abercrombie</chair>
  <chair>Ackerman</chair>
  <chair>Allen</chair>
  <chair>Altmire</chair>
  <chair>Andrews</chair>
  <chair>Arcuri</chair>
  <chair>Baca</chair>
  <chair>Baird</chair>
  <chair>Baldwin</chair>
  <chair>Barrow</chair>
  <chair>Bean</chair>
  <chair>Becerra</chair>
  <chair>Berkley</chair>
  <chair>Berman</chair>
  <chair>Berry</chair>
  <chair>Bishop (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Bishop (NY)</chair>
  <chair>Blumenauer</chair>
  <chair>Boren</chair>
  <chair>Boswell</chair>
  <chair>Boucher</chair>
  <chair>Boyd (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Boyda (KS)</chair>
  <chair>Brady (PA)</chair>
  <chair>Braley (IA)</chair>
  <chair>Brown, Corrine</chair>
  <chair>Butterfield</chair>
  <chair>Capps</chair>
  <chair>Capuano</chair>
  <chair>Cardoza</chair>
  <chair>Carnahan</chair>
  <chair>Carney</chair>
  <chair>Castor</chair>
  <chair>Chandler</chair>
  <chair>Clarke</chair>
  <chair>Clay</chair>
  <chair>Cleaver</chair>
  <chair>Clyburn</chair>
  <chair>Cohen</chair>
  <chair>Conyers</chair>
  <chair>Cooper</chair>
  <chair>Costa</chair>
  <chair>Costello</chair>
  <chair>Courtney</chair>
  <chair>Cramer</chair>
  <chair>Crowley</chair>
  <chair>Cuellar</chair>
  <chair>Cummings</chair>
  <chair>Davis (AL)</chair>
  <chair>Davis (CA)</chair>
  <chair>Davis (IL)</chair>
  <chair>Davis, Lincoln</chair>
  <chair>DeFazio</chair>
  <chair>DeGette</chair>
  <chair>Delahunt</chair>
  <chair>DeLauro</chair>
  <chair>Dicks</chair>
  <chair>Dingell</chair>
  <chair>Doggett</chair>
  <chair>Donnelly</chair>
  <chair>Edwards</chair>
  <chair>Ellison</chair>
  <chair>Ellsworth</chair>
  <chair>Emanuel</chair>
  <chair>Engel</chair>
  <chair>Eshoo</chair>
  <chair>Etheridge</chair>
  <chair>Farr</chair>
  <chair>Fattah</chair>
  <chair>Ferguson</chair>
  <chair>Filner</chair>
  <chair>Frank (MA)</chair>
  <chair>Giffords</chair>
  <chair>Gillibrand</chair>
  <chair>Gonzalez</chair>
  <chair>Gordon</chair>
  <chair>Green, Al</chair>
  <chair>Green, Gene</chair>
  <chair>Grijalva</chair>
  <chair>Hall (NY)</chair>
  <chair>Hare</chair>
  <chair>Harman</chair>
  <chair>Hastings (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Herseth Sandlin</chair>
  <chair>Higgins</chair>
  <chair>Hill</chair>
  <chair>Hinchey</chair>
  <chair>Hinojosa</chair>
  <chair>Hirono</chair>
  <chair>Hodes</chair>
  <chair>Holden</chair>
  <chair>Holt</chair>
  <chair>Honda</chair>
  <chair>Hooley</chair>
  <chair>Hoyer</chair>
  <chair>Inslee</chair>
  <chair>Israel</chair>
  <chair>Jackson (IL)</chair>
  <chair>Jefferson</chair>
  <chair>Johnson (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Johnson, E. B.</chair>
  <chair>Jones (OH)</chair>
  <chair>Kagen</chair>
  <chair>Kanjorski</chair>
  <chair>Kaptur</chair>
  <chair>Kennedy</chair>
  <chair>Kildee</chair>
  <chair>Kilpatrick</chair>
  <chair>Kind</chair>
  <chair>King (NY)</chair>
  <chair>Klein (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Knollenberg</chair>
  <chair>Kucinich</chair>
  <chair>Lampson</chair>
  <chair>Lantos</chair>
  <chair>Larsen (WA)</chair>
  <chair>Larson (CT)</chair>
  <chair>Lee</chair>
  <chair>Lewis (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Lipinski</chair>
  <chair>LoBiondo</chair>
  <chair>Loebsack</chair>
  <chair>Lofgren, Zoe</chair>
  <chair>Lowey</chair>
  <chair>Lynch</chair>
  <chair>Mahoney (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Maloney (NY)</chair>
  <chair>Markey</chair>
  <chair>Marshall</chair>
  <chair>Matheson</chair>
  <chair>Matsui</chair>
  <chair>McCarthy (NY)</chair>
  <chair>McCollum (MN)</chair>
  <chair>McDermott</chair>
  <chair>McGovern</chair>
  <chair>McHugh</chair>
  <chair>McIntyre</chair>
  <chair>McNerney</chair>
  <chair>McNulty</chair>
  <chair>Meek (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Meeks (NY)</chair>
  <chair>Melancon</chair>
  <chair>Michaud</chair>
  <chair>Miller, George</chair>
  <chair>Mitchell</chair>
  <chair>Mollohan</chair>
  <chair>Moore (KS)</chair>
  <chair>Moore (WI)</chair>
  <chair>Moran (VA)</chair>
  <chair>Murphy (CT)</chair>
  <chair>Murphy, Patrick</chair>
  <chair>Murtha</chair>
  <chair>Nadler</chair>
  <chair>Napolitano</chair>
  <chair>Neal (MA)</chair>
  <chair>Obey</chair>
  <chair>Olver</chair>
  <chair>Ortiz</chair>
  <chair>Pallone</chair>
  <chair>Pascrell</chair>
  <chair>Pastor</chair>
  <chair>Payne</chair>
  <chair>Perlmutter</chair>
  <chair>Peterson (MN)</chair>
  <chair>Pomeroy</chair>
  <chair>Porter</chair>
  <chair>Price (NC)</chair>
  <chair>Rahall</chair>
  <chair>Rangel</chair>
  <chair>Reichert</chair>
  <chair>Reyes</chair>
  <chair>Richardson</chair>
  <chair>Rodriguez</chair>
  <chair>Ross</chair>
  <chair>Rothman</chair>
  <chair>Roybal-Allard</chair>
  <chair>Rush</chair>
  <chair>Ryan (OH)</chair>
  <chair>Salazar</chair>
  <chair>S&#xE1;nchez, Linda T.</chair>
  <chair>Sanchez, Loretta</chair>
  <chair>Sarbanes</chair>
  <chair>Schakowsky</chair>
  <chair>Schiff</chair>
  <chair>Schwartz</chair>
  <chair>Scott (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Scott (VA)</chair>
  <chair>Serrano</chair>
  <chair>Sestak</chair>
  <chair>Shea-Porter</chair>
  <chair>Sherman</chair>
  <chair>Shuler</chair>
  <chair>Sires</chair>
  <chair>Skelton</chair>
  <chair>Slaughter</chair>
  <chair>Smith (NJ)</chair>
  <chair>Smith (WA)</chair>
  <chair>Snyder</chair>
  <chair>Solis</chair>
  <chair>Space</chair>
  <chair>Spratt</chair>
  <chair>Stark</chair>
  <chair>Stupak</chair>
  <chair>Sutton</chair>
  <chair>Tanner</chair>
  <chair>Tauscher</chair>
  <chair>Taylor</chair>
  <chair>Thompson (CA)</chair>
  <chair>Thompson (MS)</chair>
  <chair>Tierney</chair>
  <chair>Towns</chair>
  <chair>Tsongas</chair>
  <chair>Udall (CO)</chair>
  <chair>Udall (NM)</chair>
  <chair>Van Hollen</chair>
  <chair>Vel&#xE1;zquez</chair>
  <chair>Visclosky</chair>
  <chair>Walsh (NY)</chair>
  <chair>Walz (MN)</chair>
  <chair>Wasserman Schultz</chair>
  <chair>Waters</chair>
  <chair>Watt</chair>
  <chair>Waxman</chair>
  <chair>Weiner</chair>
  <chair>Welch (VT)</chair>
  <chair>Wexler</chair>
  <chair>Wilson (OH)</chair>
  <chair>Woolsey</chair>
  <chair>Wu</chair>
  <chair>Wynn</chair>
  <chair>Yarmuth</chair>
  <chair>Bono</chair>
  <chair>Carson</chair>
  <chair>Cubin</chair>
  <chair>Doyle</chair>
  <chair>Gutierrez</chair>
  <chair>Hunter</chair>
  <chair>Jackson-Lee (TX)</chair>
  <chair>Jindal</chair>
  <chair>Keller</chair>
  <chair>Langevin</chair>
  <chair>Levin</chair>
  <chair>Mack</chair>
  <chair>Miller (NC)</chair>
  <chair>Oberstar</chair>
  <chair>Paul</chair>
  <chair>Ruppersberger</chair>
  <chair>Sessions</chair>
  <chair>Watson</chair>
  <chair>Weller</chair>
  <chair> Members are advised there are less than 2 minutes remaining on this vote.</chair>
  <chair/>
  <chair>So the motion to recommit was rejected.</chair>
  <chair>The result of the vote was announced as above recorded.</chair>
  <chair>Stated against:</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400349" topic="NOT VOTING--19">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on rollcall No. 1101, I was unable to vote due to medical reasons. Had I been present, I would have voted "nay."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400199" topic="NOT VOTING--19">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on the previous motion to recommit vote, in light of the new extraordinary and difficult and strenuous voting time, I was unavoidably delayed in an Iraq briefing. If I was present, I would have voted "nay" on the motion to recommit on the Transportation-HUD appropriations bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400230" topic="NOT VOTING--19">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, during the previous vote on the motion to recommit, number 1101 on <bill type="h" number="3074">H.R. 3074</bill>, I was unavoidably detained and I missed that vote. I would like the record to show that I would have voted "nay."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the conference report.</chair>
  <chair>Pursuant to clause 10 of rule XX, the yeas and nays are ordered.</chair>
  <chair>This will be a 5-minute vote.</chair>
  <chair>The vote was taken by electronic device, and there were--yeas 270, nays 147, not voting 15, as follows:</chair>
  <chair>[Roll No. 1102]</chair>
  <chair>Abercrombie</chair>
  <chair>Ackerman</chair>
  <chair>Aderholt</chair>
  <chair>Allen</chair>
  <chair>Altmire</chair>
  <chair>Andrews</chair>
  <chair>Arcuri</chair>
  <chair>Baca</chair>
  <chair>Baird</chair>
  <chair>Baker</chair>
  <chair>Baldwin</chair>
  <chair>Barrow</chair>
  <chair>Bean</chair>
  <chair>Becerra</chair>
  <chair>Berkley</chair>
  <chair>Berman</chair>
  <chair>Berry</chair>
  <chair>Bishop (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Bishop (NY)</chair>
  <chair>Blumenauer</chair>
  <chair>Boren</chair>
  <chair>Boswell</chair>
  <chair>Boucher</chair>
  <chair>Boyd (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Boyda (KS)</chair>
  <chair>Brady (PA)</chair>
  <chair>Braley (IA)</chair>
  <chair>Brown, Corrine</chair>
  <chair>Butterfield</chair>
  <chair>Camp (MI)</chair>
  <chair>Capito</chair>
  <chair>Capps</chair>
  <chair>Capuano</chair>
  <chair>Cardoza</chair>
  <chair>Carnahan</chair>
  <chair>Carney</chair>
  <chair>Castle</chair>
  <chair>Castor</chair>
  <chair>Chandler</chair>
  <chair>Clarke</chair>
  <chair>Clay</chair>
  <chair>Cleaver</chair>
  <chair>Clyburn</chair>
  <chair>Cohen</chair>
  <chair>Conyers</chair>
  <chair>Cooper</chair>
  <chair>Costa</chair>
  <chair>Costello</chair>
  <chair>Courtney</chair>
  <chair>Cramer</chair>
  <chair>Crowley</chair>
  <chair>Cuellar</chair>
  <chair>Cummings</chair>
  <chair>Davis (AL)</chair>
  <chair>Davis (CA)</chair>
  <chair>Davis (IL)</chair>
  <chair>Davis, Lincoln</chair>
  <chair>Davis, Tom</chair>
  <chair>DeFazio</chair>
  <chair>DeGette</chair>
  <chair>Delahunt</chair>
  <chair>DeLauro</chair>
  <chair>Dent</chair>
  <chair>Dicks</chair>
  <chair>Dingell</chair>
  <chair>Doggett</chair>
  <chair>Donnelly</chair>
  <chair>Edwards</chair>
  <chair>Ehlers</chair>
  <chair>Ellison</chair>
  <chair>Ellsworth</chair>
  <chair>Emanuel</chair>
  <chair>Emerson</chair>
  <chair>Engel</chair>
  <chair>Eshoo</chair>
  <chair>Etheridge</chair>
  <chair>Everett</chair>
  <chair>Farr</chair>
  <chair>Fattah</chair>
  <chair>Ferguson</chair>
  <chair>Filner</chair>
  <chair>Fortenberry</chair>
  <chair>Frank (MA)</chair>
  <chair>Gerlach</chair>
  <chair>Giffords</chair>
  <chair>Gilchrest</chair>
  <chair>Gillibrand</chair>
  <chair>Gonzalez</chair>
  <chair>Goode</chair>
  <chair>Gordon</chair>
  <chair>Graves</chair>
  <chair>Green, Al</chair>
  <chair>Green, Gene</chair>
  <chair>Grijalva</chair>
  <chair>Hall (NY)</chair>
  <chair>Hare</chair>
  <chair>Harman</chair>
  <chair>Hastings (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Hayes</chair>
  <chair>Herseth Sandlin</chair>
  <chair>Higgins</chair>
  <chair>Hill</chair>
  <chair>Hinchey</chair>
  <chair>Hinojosa</chair>
  <chair>Hirono</chair>
  <chair>Hodes</chair>
  <chair>Holden</chair>
  <chair>Holt</chair>
  <chair>Honda</chair>
  <chair>Hooley</chair>
  <chair>Hoyer</chair>
  <chair>Inslee</chair>
  <chair>Israel</chair>
  <chair>Jackson (IL)</chair>
  <chair>Jackson-Lee (TX)</chair>
  <chair>Jefferson</chair>
  <chair>Johnson (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Johnson (IL)</chair>
  <chair>Johnson, E. B.</chair>
  <chair>Jones (NC)</chair>
  <chair>Jones (OH)</chair>
  <chair>Kagen</chair>
  <chair>Kanjorski</chair>
  <chair>Kaptur</chair>
  <chair>Kennedy</chair>
  <chair>Kildee</chair>
  <chair>Kilpatrick</chair>
  <chair>Kind</chair>
  <chair>King (NY)</chair>
  <chair>Kirk</chair>
  <chair>Klein (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Knollenberg</chair>
  <chair>Kucinich</chair>
  <chair>Kuhl (NY)</chair>
  <chair>LaHood</chair>
  <chair>Lampson</chair>
  <chair>Langevin</chair>
  <chair>Lantos</chair>
  <chair>Larsen (WA)</chair>
  <chair>Larson (CT)</chair>
  <chair>LaTourette</chair>
  <chair>Lee</chair>
  <chair>Lewis (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Lipinski</chair>
  <chair>LoBiondo</chair>
  <chair>Loebsack</chair>
  <chair>Lofgren, Zoe</chair>
  <chair>Lowey</chair>
  <chair>Lynch</chair>
  <chair>Mahoney (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Maloney (NY)</chair>
  <chair>Markey</chair>
  <chair>Marshall</chair>
  <chair>Matheson</chair>
  <chair>Matsui</chair>
  <chair>McCarthy (NY)</chair>
  <chair>McCollum (MN)</chair>
  <chair>McDermott</chair>
  <chair>McGovern</chair>
  <chair>McHugh</chair>
  <chair>McIntyre</chair>
  <chair>McNerney</chair>
  <chair>McNulty</chair>
  <chair>Meek (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Meeks (NY)</chair>
  <chair>Melancon</chair>
  <chair>Michaud</chair>
  <chair>Miller (MI)</chair>
  <chair>Miller (NC)</chair>
  <chair>Miller, George</chair>
  <chair>Mitchell</chair>
  <chair>Mollohan</chair>
  <chair>Moore (KS)</chair>
  <chair>Moore (WI)</chair>
  <chair>Moran (VA)</chair>
  <chair>Murphy (CT)</chair>
  <chair>Murphy, Patrick</chair>
  <chair>Murphy, Tim</chair>
  <chair>Murtha</chair>
  <chair>Nadler</chair>
  <chair>Napolitano</chair>
  <chair>Neal (MA)</chair>
  <chair>Obey</chair>
  <chair>Olver</chair>
  <chair>Ortiz</chair>
  <chair>Pallone</chair>
  <chair>Pascrell</chair>
  <chair>Pastor</chair>
  <chair>Payne</chair>
  <chair>Perlmutter</chair>
  <chair>Peterson (MN)</chair>
  <chair>Petri</chair>
  <chair>Pomeroy</chair>
  <chair>Porter</chair>
  <chair>Price (NC)</chair>
  <chair>Rahall</chair>
  <chair>Ramstad</chair>
  <chair>Rangel</chair>
  <chair>Regula</chair>
  <chair>Reichert</chair>
  <chair>Renzi</chair>
  <chair>Reyes</chair>
  <chair>Richardson</chair>
  <chair>Rodriguez</chair>
  <chair>Rogers (AL)</chair>
  <chair>Ross</chair>
  <chair>Rothman</chair>
  <chair>Roybal-Allard</chair>
  <chair>Rush</chair>
  <chair>Ryan (OH)</chair>
  <chair>Salazar</chair>
  <chair>S&#xE1;nchez, Linda T.</chair>
  <chair>Sanchez, Loretta</chair>
  <chair>Sarbanes</chair>
  <chair>Schakowsky</chair>
  <chair>Schiff</chair>
  <chair>Schwartz</chair>
  <chair>Scott (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Scott (VA)</chair>
  <chair>Serrano</chair>
  <chair>Sestak</chair>
  <chair>Shays</chair>
  <chair>Shea-Porter</chair>
  <chair>Sherman</chair>
  <chair>Shuler</chair>
  <chair>Shuster</chair>
  <chair>Sires</chair>
  <chair>Skelton</chair>
  <chair>Slaughter</chair>
  <chair>Smith (NE)</chair>
  <chair>Smith (NJ)</chair>
  <chair>Smith (WA)</chair>
  <chair>Snyder</chair>
  <chair>Solis</chair>
  <chair>Space</chair>
  <chair>Spratt</chair>
  <chair>Stark</chair>
  <chair>Stupak</chair>
  <chair>Sutton</chair>
  <chair>Tanner</chair>
  <chair>Tauscher</chair>
  <chair>Taylor</chair>
  <chair>Thompson (CA)</chair>
  <chair>Thompson (MS)</chair>
  <chair>Tierney</chair>
  <chair>Towns</chair>
  <chair>Tsongas</chair>
  <chair>Turner</chair>
  <chair>Udall (CO)</chair>
  <chair>Udall (NM)</chair>
  <chair>Upton</chair>
  <chair>Van Hollen</chair>
  <chair>Vel&#xE1;zquez</chair>
  <chair>Visclosky</chair>
  <chair>Walsh (NY)</chair>
  <chair>Walz (MN)</chair>
  <chair>Wasserman Schultz</chair>
  <chair>Waters</chair>
  <chair>Watt</chair>
  <chair>Waxman</chair>
  <chair>Weiner</chair>
  <chair>Welch (VT)</chair>
  <chair>Wexler</chair>
  <chair>Wilson (OH)</chair>
  <chair>Wolf</chair>
  <chair>Woolsey</chair>
  <chair>Wu</chair>
  <chair>Wynn</chair>
  <chair>Yarmuth</chair>
  <chair>Young (AK)</chair>
  <chair>Akin</chair>
  <chair>Alexander</chair>
  <chair>Bachmann</chair>
  <chair>Bachus</chair>
  <chair>Barrett (SC)</chair>
  <chair>Bartlett (MD)</chair>
  <chair>Barton (TX)</chair>
  <chair>Biggert</chair>
  <chair>Bilbray</chair>
  <chair>Bilirakis</chair>
  <chair>Blackburn</chair>
  <chair>Blunt</chair>
  <chair>Boehner</chair>
  <chair>Bonner</chair>
  <chair>Boozman</chair>
  <chair>Boustany</chair>
  <chair>Brady (TX)</chair>
  <chair>Broun (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Brown (SC)</chair>
  <chair>Brown-Waite, Ginny</chair>
  <chair>Buchanan</chair>
  <chair>Burgess</chair>
  <chair>Burton (IN)</chair>
  <chair>Buyer</chair>
  <chair>Calvert</chair>
  <chair>Campbell (CA)</chair>
  <chair>Cannon</chair>
  <chair>Cantor</chair>
  <chair>Carter</chair>
  <chair>Chabot</chair>
  <chair>Coble</chair>
  <chair>Cole (OK)</chair>
  <chair>Conaway</chair>
  <chair>Crenshaw</chair>
  <chair>Culberson</chair>
  <chair>Davis (KY)</chair>
  <chair>Davis, David</chair>
  <chair>Deal (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Diaz-Balart, L.</chair>
  <chair>Diaz-Balart, M.</chair>
  <chair>Doolittle</chair>
  <chair>Drake</chair>
  <chair>Dreier</chair>
  <chair>Duncan</chair>
  <chair>English (PA)</chair>
  <chair>Fallin</chair>
  <chair>Feeney</chair>
  <chair>Flake</chair>
  <chair>Forbes</chair>
  <chair>Fossella</chair>
  <chair>Foxx</chair>
  <chair>Franks (AZ)</chair>
  <chair>Frelinghuysen</chair>
  <chair>Gallegly</chair>
  <chair>Garrett (NJ)</chair>
  <chair>Gingrey</chair>
  <chair>Gohmert</chair>
  <chair>Goodlatte</chair>
  <chair>Granger</chair>
  <chair>Hall (TX)</chair>
  <chair>Hastert</chair>
  <chair>Hastings (WA)</chair>
  <chair>Heller</chair>
  <chair>Hensarling</chair>
  <chair>Herger</chair>
  <chair>Hobson</chair>
  <chair>Hoekstra</chair>
  <chair>Hulshof</chair>
  <chair>Hunter</chair>
  <chair>Inglis (SC)</chair>
  <chair>Issa</chair>
  <chair>Johnson, Sam</chair>
  <chair>Jordan</chair>
  <chair>Keller</chair>
  <chair>King (IA)</chair>
  <chair>Kingston</chair>
  <chair>Kline (MN)</chair>
  <chair>Lamborn</chair>
  <chair>Latham</chair>
  <chair>Lewis (CA)</chair>
  <chair>Lewis (KY)</chair>
  <chair>Linder</chair>
  <chair>Lucas</chair>
  <chair>Lungren, Daniel E.</chair>
  <chair>Manzullo</chair>
  <chair>Marchant</chair>
  <chair>McCarthy (CA)</chair>
  <chair>McCaul (TX)</chair>
  <chair>McCotter</chair>
  <chair>McCrery</chair>
  <chair>McHenry</chair>
  <chair>McKeon</chair>
  <chair>McMorris Rodgers</chair>
  <chair>Mica</chair>
  <chair>Miller (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Miller, Gary</chair>
  <chair>Moran (KS)</chair>
  <chair>Musgrave</chair>
  <chair>Myrick</chair>
  <chair>Neugebauer</chair>
  <chair>Nunes</chair>
  <chair>Pearce</chair>
  <chair>Pence</chair>
  <chair>Peterson (PA)</chair>
  <chair>Pickering</chair>
  <chair>Pitts</chair>
  <chair>Platts</chair>
  <chair>Poe</chair>
  <chair>Price (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Pryce (OH)</chair>
  <chair>Putnam</chair>
  <chair>Radanovich</chair>
  <chair>Rehberg</chair>
  <chair>Reynolds</chair>
  <chair>Rogers (KY)</chair>
  <chair>Rogers (MI)</chair>
  <chair>Rohrabacher</chair>
  <chair>Ros-Lehtinen</chair>
  <chair>Roskam</chair>
  <chair>Royce</chair>
  <chair>Ryan (WI)</chair>
  <chair>Sali</chair>
  <chair>Saxton</chair>
  <chair>Schmidt</chair>
  <chair>Sensenbrenner</chair>
  <chair>Shadegg</chair>
  <chair>Shimkus</chair>
  <chair>Simpson</chair>
  <chair>Smith (TX)</chair>
  <chair>Souder</chair>
  <chair>Stearns</chair>
  <chair>Sullivan</chair>
  <chair>Tancredo</chair>
  <chair>Terry</chair>
  <chair>Thornberry</chair>
  <chair>Tiahrt</chair>
  <chair>Tiberi</chair>
  <chair>Walberg</chair>
  <chair>Walden (OR)</chair>
  <chair>Wamp</chair>
  <chair>Weldon (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Westmoreland</chair>
  <chair>Whitfield</chair>
  <chair>Wicker</chair>
  <chair>Wilson (NM)</chair>
  <chair>Wilson (SC)</chair>
  <chair>Young (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Bishop (UT)</chair>
  <chair>Bono</chair>
  <chair>Carson</chair>
  <chair>Cubin</chair>
  <chair>Doyle</chair>
  <chair>Gutierrez</chair>
  <chair>Jindal</chair>
  <chair>Levin</chair>
  <chair>Mack</chair>
  <chair>Oberstar</chair>
  <chair>Paul</chair>
  <chair>Ruppersberger</chair>
  <chair>Sessions</chair>
  <chair>Watson</chair>
  <chair>Weller</chair>
  <chair>The Speaker pro tempore (during the vote). Members are advised they now have less than 2 minutes remaining in which to cast their vote.</chair>
  <chair/>
  <chair>Mr. TURNER changed his vote from "nay" to "yea."</chair>
  <chair>So the conference report was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The result of the vote was announced as above recorded.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
  <chair>Stated for:</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400349" topic="NOT VOTING--15">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on rollcall No. 1102, I was unable to vote due to medical reasons. Had I been present, I would have voted "yea."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400423" topic="NOT VOTING--15">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this afternoon I was unavoidably detained and could not cast my vote for <bill type="h" number="3074">H.R. 3074</bill>, on agreeing to the Conference Report for the Departments of Transportation, and Housing, and Urban Development and Related Agencies Appropriations for FY 2008.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Had I been able to cast my vote, I would have voted "yea" for <bill type="h" number="3074">H.R. 3074</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
