<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1178553612" ordinal="30" title="NATIONAL PHYSICAL EDUCATION AND SPORTS WEEK">
  <speaking speaker="412231" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution (<bill type="hr" number="371">H. Res. 371</bill>) in observance of National Physical Education and Sports Week.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the resolution.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Pennsylvania (Mr. Altmire) and the gentleman from Tennessee (Mr. David Davis) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412231" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I request 5 legislative days during which Members may insert material relevant to <bill type="hr" number="371">H. Res. 371</bill> into the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Pennsylvania?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412231" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this resolution designates May 1-7 as National Physical Education and Sports Week. This is the second year in which Congress has officially observed the first week of May for this purpose.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The benefits of physical activity are well documented. It reduces the risk of obesity, heart disease, high blood pressure, diabetes, back pain, and even certain types of cancer. It can increase one's self-esteem and body image and reduce anxiety. In youth, it develops motor skills, leads to healthier lifestyles, improves social awareness, and averts risky behaviors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Centers for Disease Control recommends 60 minutes of daily physical activity for children and teenagers, and 30 minutes of daily physical activity for adults. Moderate exercise, such as a brisk walk, when done regularly, has a significant health benefit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a Nation, we should be more active. One out of four children do not attend any physical education classes in school; 61 percent of children, ages 9 through 13, do not participate in any physical activity outside of school. Only 25 percent of children get a minimum of 20 minutes of vigorous physical activity per day.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, in comparison, 60 percent of adults are not regularly active, and 25 percent are not physically active at all. The lack of physical activity has many negative results. The percentage of overweight young people has more than tripled since 1980. It is 18 percent of that population today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Children are now being diagnosed with high blood pressure, high cholesterol and type 2 diabetes, all once thought to be age related. Two-thirds of adults are overweight or obese. Obesity-related diseases cost the economy more than $100 billion annually.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to recognize some exemplary programs that are currently promoting and encouraging physical activity. Four thousand Boys and Girls Clubs across this country provide more than 4.6 million kids with the opportunity to be physically active. YMCA provides services to over 20 million people, including the Silver Sneakers programs for seniors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This resolution acknowledges that physical activity and sports play a central role in creating a healthy lifestyle for children and adults. Schools should include physical education classes and other opportunities for physical opportunities as part of the school day, and this resolution says communities should be involved and support schools in the promotion of physical activities, nutrition education and healthy lifestyles.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412235" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise today in support of House Resolution 371 to recognize National Physical Education and Sports Week, which took place this year from May 1 to May 7, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ralph Waldo Emerson once wrote: "The first wealth is health." Today, these words could not hold more significance. In an increasingly technologically advanced society dominated by the Internet, cell phones, BlackBerrys, and, yes, electronic video game controls, the evidence is growing and is more convincing than ever. People of all ages who are generally inactive can improve their health and well-being by becoming active at a moderate intensity on a regular basis.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Regular physical activity substantially reduces the risk of a number of preventable diseases such as coronary heart disease, the Nation's leading cause of death; and decreases the risk of stroke, colon cancer, diabetes, and high blood pressure. It also helps to control weight, contributes to healthy bones, muscles and joints, reduces falls among elderly adults and is associated with fewer hospitalizations. Moreover, physical activity does not need to be strenuous to be beneficial. People of all  ages benefit from participating in regular moderate-intensity physical activity, such as 30 minutes of brisk walking five or more times a week.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These are facts we should impress upon our children to ensure they lead health-conscious lives. Yet according to the Surgeon General's "Call to Action to Prevent and Decrease Overweight and Obesity," only half of adolescents participate in regular physical activity, and one-fourth report no physical activity at all.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, we find that more than a third of young people in grades 9-12 do not regularly engage in physical activity. Additionally, daily participation in high school physical education classes dropped from 42 percent in 1991 to only 33 percent in 2005. Physical activity offers a broad range of benefits, including the prevention of obesity, improves self-confidence and the overall sense of well-being.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Physical education programs within school settings can set the stage for how children view physical fitness, activity levels, and future health. Physical education programs also include general health and safety information, as well as providing opportunities for students to learn how to cooperate with one another in a team setting. Equally important is the fact that physical education programs can teach students that physical activity can be fun.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With a broad range of games and activities, children are exposed to forms of exercise that incorporate teamwork, strategy, skill-building exercises, and other curricula such as math. Indeed, physical education plays an important role in the development of an individual, just as a classroom education does.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I join my colleague, Mr. Altmire, in calling for the communities to work with schools, along with key community stakeholders to craft and implement a local wellness plan as required in the Child Nutrition and WIC Reauthorization Act of 2004.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask my colleagues to support this resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412231" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman from Tennessee for his leadership on this issue and the other legislation that we talked about today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Pennsylvania (Mr. Altmire) that the House suspend the  rules and agree to the resolution, <bill type="hr" number="371">H. Res. 371</bill>.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412231" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this question will be postponed.</chair>
</record>
