<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1174320004" ordinal="20" title="CONVEYANCE OF LAND BY THE BUREAU OF LAND MANAGEMENT TO PARK CITY, UTAH">
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="838">H.R. 838</bill>) to provide for the conveyance of the Bureau of Land Management parcels known as the White Acre and Gambel Oak properties and related real property to Park City, Utah, and for other purposes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) and the gentleman from Utah (Mr. Bishop) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Arizona?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="838">H.R. 838</bill>, sponsored by the ranking member of the National Parks, Forests and Public Lands Subcommittee, Representative Rob Bishop, is intended to preserve existing open space in Park City, Utah. The bill would transfer two parcels of land owned by the Bureau of Land Management to Park City, with a deed restriction that the land be maintained as open space. Park City will pay fair-market value for the land.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Two other parcels in the area owned by the BLM are encumbered with unpatented mining claims. The bill directs that these parcels, which the BLM had previously identified for disposal, be sold at auction, subject to any valid existing rights, to resolve these outstanding issues. Park City is expected to bid for these properties at the auction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is our understanding that Park City has undertaken an aggressive campaign to maintain open space and that the citizens of Park City have proven their commitment by approving a local bond initiative to fund this project.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We applaud Park City's efforts and congratulate Representative Bishop for working hard to bring this legislation to the floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, identical legislation was approved by the House in the 109th Congress. We support passage of <bill type="h" number="838">H.R. 838</bill> and urge its adoption by the House today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400029" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="838">H.R. 838</bill> and yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="838">H.R. 838</bill> conveys to Park City about 110 acres of Bureau of Land Management land that was previously marked for disposal. This land would be used by Park City as recreational open space. The residents of Park City have placed a premium on preserving this space for the character of their resort town; and as the chairman accurately said, they have approved a $20 million bond to purchase this environmentally sensitive land. The conveyance of this is consistent with Park City's long-range plan to  protect its sensitive landscape.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Park City hosted many of the events of the 2002 Olympics, and visitors from around the world visit there to ski and  partake of the scenic vistas, which will be enhanced by this bill. As was stated, this bill, as passed by the 109th session of Congress and as considered today, enjoys the support of both Republicans and Democrats and does have a companion bill that has been introduced in the United States Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask for your support of this particular bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I actually have no additional speakers, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400162" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, we have no additional speakers, and we yield back the balance of our time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Grijalva) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="838">H.R. 838</bill>.</chair>
</record>
