<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1190822402" ordinal="21" title="PROVIDING FOR CONSIDERATION OF H.J. RES. 52, CONTINUING APPROPRIATIONS, FISCAL YEAR 2008">
  <narrative>PROVIDING FOR CONSIDERATION OF <bill type="hj" number="52">H.J. RES. 52</bill>, CONTINUING APPROPRIATIONS, FISCAL YEAR 2008 -- (House of Representatives - September 26, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H10910]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400378" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, by direction of the Committee on Rules, I call up House Resolution 677 and ask for its immediate consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the resolution, as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="hr" number="677">H. Res. 677</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative>Resolved, That upon the adoption of this resolution it shall be in order to consider in the House the joint resolution (<bill type="hj" number="52">H.J. Res. 52</bill>) making continuing appropriations for the fiscal year 2008, and for other purposes. All points of order against the joint resolution and against its consideration are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. The joint resolution shall be considered  as read. The previous question shall be considered  as ordered on the joint resolution to final passage without intervening motion except: (1) one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by the chairman and ranking minority member of the Committee on Appropriations; and (2) one motion to recommit.</narrative>
  <narrative>Sec. 2. During consideration of House Joint Resolution 52 pursuant to this resolution, notwithstanding the operation of the previous question, the Chair may postpone further consideration of the joint resolution to such time as may be designated by the Speaker.</narrative>
  <narrative>Sec. 3. House Resolution 659 is laid upon the table.</narrative>
  <chair> The gentlewoman from New York is recognized for 1 hour.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400378" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, for the purpose of debate only, I yield the customary 30 minutes to the gentleman from Washington (Mr. Hastings). All time yielded during consideration of the rule is for debate only.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield myself such time as I may consume and ask unanimous consent that all Members be given 5 legislative days in which to revise and extend their remarks on House Resolution 677.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from New York?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400378" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, <bill type="hr" number="677">H. Res. 677</bill> provides for consideration of <bill type="hj" number="52">H.J. Res. 52</bill>, making continuing appropriations for the fiscal year 2008, and for other purposes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The rule provides 1 hour of general debate controlled by the Committee on Appropriations. The rule waives all points of order against the joint resolution and against its consideration except for clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The rule also provides that the joint resolution shall be considered as read. The rule provides one motion to recommit with or without instructions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, every Congress has a constitutional responsibility to be good stewards of the money sent to us by the American people. And I am proud to say that we here in the House of Representatives have fulfilled our fiscal responsibility to the American people by passing all of our appropriations bills on time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We, in the new majority, have been absolute in our promise to construct and pass spending bills with broad bipartisan support, and I am proud to say that we have delivered on those promises.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Of the 12 fiscal year 2008 appropriations bills that passed the House this year, we have garnered an average of 50 Republican votes. In a spirit of working together, we have successfully pushed ahead our bold and new agenda and passed legislation that prioritize veterans, health care, education and energy independence.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, H. Res 677 provides for consideration of <bill type="hj" number="52">H.J. Res. 52</bill>, as I said before, for continuing appropriations for the year 2008.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, with that, I will reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400171" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I want to thank the gentlelady and chairman of the Rules Committee for yielding me the customary 30 minutes, and I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, in just 5 days, fiscal year 2007 will come to an end and a new fiscal year will begin. I am disappointed that this rule and the underlying continuing resolution are on the floor today. Not one, let me repeat that, not one spending bill has been sent to the President for his signature this year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress has a responsibility to fund the priorities of the government, and here we are, just days before the start of a new fiscal year, and not one of the 12 spending bills that must be signed into law have been signed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, Mr. Speaker, I will support the underlying continuing resolution because I recognize the government must continue to be funded. It is my strong hope, however, that within the next 6 weeks, 12 separate conference reports will come before the House of Representatives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I do not believe that omnibus bills are the best vehicles for spending billions and billions of taxpayer dollars, and I truly hope that that will not be what we end with on November 16.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With that, Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400378" topic="">
    <paragraph>I have no requests for time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400171" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself the balance of the time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this is a disappointing day for the American people. Here we are, nearly 9 months into this Congress controlled by the Democrat majority, and still the majority has failed to live up to their promises by denying every American taxpayer accountability when it comes to transparency of earmarks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Just yesterday, a challenge was made to an earmark slipped into a bill 299 pages long that had not been disclosed. The Democrat majority certified the bill was "earmark free," but then denied all accountability and scrutiny of this earmark.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is vital that the House act today to allow the House to debate openly and honestly the validity and accuracy of earmarks contained in all bills, such as the SCHIP bill yesterday, and not just on appropriation bills. Therefore, Mr. Speaker, I will be asking Members to oppose the previous question so that they may amend the rule to allow for immediate consideration of House Resolution 479, the Earmark Accountability bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By defeating the previous question, the House will be able to consider the continuing resolution today, but will also be able to address earmark enforceability in order to restore the credibility of this House.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By considering and approving House Resolution 479, we will send a strong message to the American taxpayers that this House will no longer turn its head the other way when it comes to transparency of earmarks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent to have the text of the amendment and extraneous material inserted into the Record prior to the vote on the previous question.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Washington?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400171" topic="">
    <paragraph>With that, I urge my colleagues to oppose the previous question, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400378" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I feel obliged to say simply for the record that there are no earmarks in this bill and that everybody knows it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The material previously referred to by Mr. Hastings of Washington is as follows:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Amendment to <bill type="hr" number="677">H. Res. 677</bill> Offered by Mr. Hastings of Washington</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At the end of the resolution, add the following:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>SEC. 4. That immediately upon the adoption of this resolution the House shall, without intervention of any point of order, consider the resolution (<bill type="hr" number="479">H. Res. 479</bill>) to amend the Rules of the House of Representatives to provide for enforcement of clause 9 of rule XXI of the Rules of the House of Representatives. The resolution shall be considered as read. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the resolution to final adoption without intervening motion or demand for division  of the question except: (1) one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by the chairman and ranking minority member of the Committee on Rules; and (2) one motion to recommit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>&lt;pre&gt;--&lt;/pre&gt;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Vote on the Previous Question: What It Really Means</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(The information contained herein was provided by Democratic Minority on multiple occasions throughout the 109th Congress.)</narrative>
  <narrative>This vote, the vote on whether to order the previous question on a special rule, is not merely a procedural vote. A vote against ordering the previous question is a vote against the Democratic majority agenda and a vote to allow the opposition, at least for the moment, to offer an alternative plan. It is a vote about what the House should be debating.</narrative>
  <narrative>Mr. Clarence Cannon's Precedents of the House of Representatives, (VI, 308-311) describes the vote on the previous question on the rule as "a motion to direct or control the consideration of the subject before the House being made by the Member in charge." To defeat the previous question is to give the opposition a chance to decide the subject before the House. Cannon cites the Speaker's ruling of January 13, 1920, to the effect that "the refusal of the House to sustain the demand for the  previous question passes the control of the resolution to the opposition" in order to offer an amendment. On March 15, 1909, a member of the majority party offered a rule resolution. The House defeated the previous question and a member of the opposition rose to a parliamentary inquiry, asking who was</narrative>
  <narrative>Because the vote today may look bad for the Democratic majority they will say "the vote on the previous question is simply a vote on whether to proceed to an immediate vote on adopting the resolution ..... [and] has no substantive legislative or policy implications whatsoever." But that is not what they have always said. Listen to the definition of the previous question used in the Floor Procedures Manual published by the Rules Committee in the 109th Congress, (page 56). Here's how the Rules  Committee described the rule using information form Congressional Quarterly's "American Congressional Dictionary": "If the previous question is defeated, control of debate shifts to the leading opposition member (usually the minority Floor Manager) who then manages an hour of debate and may offer a germane amendment to the pending business."</narrative>
  <narrative>Deschler's Procedure in the U.S. House of Representatives, the subchapter titled "Amending Special Rules" states: "a refusal to order the previous question on such a rule [a special rule reported from the Committee on Rules] opens the resolution to amendment and further debate." (Chapter 21, section 21.2) Section 21.3 continues: Upon rejection of the motion for the previous question on a resolution reported from the Committee on Rules, control shifts to the Member leading the opposition to  the previous question, who may offer a proper amendment or motion and who controls the time for debate thereon."</narrative>
  <narrative>Clearly, the vote on the previous question on a rule does have substantive policy implications. It is one of the only available tools for those who oppose the Democratic majority's agenda and allows those with alternative views the opportunity to offer an alternative plan.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400378" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time, and I move the previous question on the resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on ordering the previous question.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and the Speaker pro tempore announced that the ayes appeared to have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400171" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <narrative>Pursuant to clause 8 and clause 9 of rule XX, this 15-minute vote on ordering the previous question on House Resolution 677 will be followed by 5-minute votes on adoption of House Resolution 677, if ordered; ordering the previous question on House Resolution 678, by the yeas and nays; and adoption of House Resolution 678, if ordered.</narrative>
  <narrative>The vote was taken by electronic device, and there were--yeas 220, nays 192, not voting 20, as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>[Roll No. 908]</narrative>
  <narrative>Ackerman</narrative>
  <narrative>Allen</narrative>
  <narrative>Altmire</narrative>
  <narrative>Andrews</narrative>
  <narrative>Arcuri</narrative>
  <narrative>Baca</narrative>
  <narrative>Baird</narrative>
  <narrative>Baldwin</narrative>
  <narrative>Bean</narrative>
  <narrative>Becerra</narrative>
  <narrative>Berkley</narrative>
  <narrative>Berman</narrative>
  <narrative>Berry</narrative>
  <narrative>Bishop (GA)</narrative>
  <narrative>Bishop (NY)</narrative>
  <narrative>Blumenauer</narrative>
  <narrative>Boren</narrative>
  <narrative>Boswell</narrative>
  <narrative>Boucher</narrative>
  <narrative>Boyda (KS)</narrative>
  <narrative>Brady (PA)</narrative>
  <narrative>Braley (IA)</narrative>
  <narrative>Butterfield</narrative>
  <narrative>Capps</narrative>
  <narrative>Capuano</narrative>
  <narrative>Cardoza</narrative>
  <narrative>Carnahan</narrative>
  <narrative>Carney</narrative>
  <narrative>Castor</narrative>
  <narrative>Chandler</narrative>
  <narrative>Clarke</narrative>
  <narrative>Clay</narrative>
  <narrative>Cleaver</narrative>
  <narrative>Clyburn</narrative>
  <narrative>Cohen</narrative>
  <narrative>Conyers</narrative>
  <narrative>Cooper</narrative>
  <narrative>Costa</narrative>
  <narrative>Costello</narrative>
  <narrative>Courtney</narrative>
  <narrative>Cramer</narrative>
  <narrative>Crowley</narrative>
  <narrative>Cuellar</narrative>
  <narrative>Cummings</narrative>
  <narrative>Davis (AL)</narrative>
  <narrative>Davis (CA)</narrative>
  <narrative>Davis (IL)</narrative>
  <narrative>Davis, Lincoln</narrative>
  <narrative>DeFazio</narrative>
  <narrative>DeGette</narrative>
  <narrative>Delahunt</narrative>
  <narrative>DeLauro</narrative>
  <narrative>Dicks</narrative>
  <narrative>Dingell</narrative>
  <narrative>Doggett</narrative>
  <narrative>Donnelly</narrative>
  <narrative>Doyle</narrative>
  <narrative>Edwards</narrative>
  <narrative>Ellison</narrative>
  <narrative>Ellsworth</narrative>
  <narrative>Emanuel</narrative>
  <narrative>Eshoo</narrative>
  <narrative>Etheridge</narrative>
  <narrative>Farr</narrative>
  <narrative>Fattah</narrative>
  <narrative>Filner</narrative>
  <narrative>Frank (MA)</narrative>
  <narrative>Giffords</narrative>
  <narrative>Gillibrand</narrative>
  <narrative>Gonzalez</narrative>
  <narrative>Gordon</narrative>
  <narrative>Green, Al</narrative>
  <narrative>Green, Gene</narrative>
  <narrative>Grijalva</narrative>
  <narrative>Gutierrez</narrative>
  <narrative>Hall (NY)</narrative>
  <narrative>Hare</narrative>
  <narrative>Harman</narrative>
  <narrative>Hastings (FL)</narrative>
  <narrative>Herseth Sandlin</narrative>
  <narrative>Higgins</narrative>
  <narrative>Hill</narrative>
  <narrative>Hinchey</narrative>
  <narrative>Hirono</narrative>
  <narrative>Hodes</narrative>
  <narrative>Holden</narrative>
  <narrative>Holt</narrative>
  <narrative>Honda</narrative>
  <narrative>Hooley</narrative>
  <narrative>Hoyer</narrative>
  <narrative>Inslee</narrative>
  <narrative>Israel</narrative>
  <narrative>Jackson (IL)</narrative>
  <narrative>Jackson-Lee (TX)</narrative>
  <narrative>Jefferson</narrative>
  <narrative>Johnson (GA)</narrative>
  <narrative>Jones (OH)</narrative>
  <narrative>Kagen</narrative>
  <narrative>Kanjorski</narrative>
  <narrative>Kaptur</narrative>
  <narrative>Kennedy</narrative>
  <narrative>Kildee</narrative>
  <narrative>Kilpatrick</narrative>
  <narrative>Kind</narrative>
  <narrative>Klein (FL)</narrative>
  <narrative>Lampson</narrative>
  <narrative>Langevin</narrative>
  <narrative>Lantos</narrative>
  <narrative>Larsen (WA)</narrative>
  <narrative>Larson (CT)</narrative>
  <narrative>Lee</narrative>
  <narrative>Levin</narrative>
  <narrative>Lewis (GA)</narrative>
  <narrative>Lipinski</narrative>
  <narrative>Lofgren, Zoe</narrative>
  <narrative>Lowey</narrative>
  <narrative>Lynch</narrative>
  <narrative>Mahoney (FL)</narrative>
  <narrative>Maloney (NY)</narrative>
  <narrative>Markey</narrative>
  <narrative>Marshall</narrative>
  <narrative>Matheson</narrative>
  <narrative>Matsui</narrative>
  <narrative>McCarthy (NY)</narrative>
  <narrative>McCollum (MN)</narrative>
  <narrative>McDermott</narrative>
  <narrative>McGovern</narrative>
  <narrative>McIntyre</narrative>
  <narrative>McNerney</narrative>
  <narrative>McNulty</narrative>
  <narrative>Meek (FL)</narrative>
  <narrative>Melancon</narrative>
  <narrative>Michaud</narrative>
  <narrative>Miller (NC)</narrative>
  <narrative>Miller, George</narrative>
  <narrative>Mitchell</narrative>
  <narrative>Mollohan</narrative>
  <narrative>Moore (KS)</narrative>
  <narrative>Moore (WI)</narrative>
  <narrative>Moran (VA)</narrative>
  <narrative>Murphy (CT)</narrative>
  <narrative>Murphy, Patrick</narrative>
  <narrative>Murtha</narrative>
  <narrative>Nadler</narrative>
  <narrative>Napolitano</narrative>
  <narrative>Neal (MA)</narrative>
  <narrative>Oberstar</narrative>
  <narrative>Obey</narrative>
  <narrative>Olver</narrative>
  <narrative>Ortiz</narrative>
  <narrative>Pallone</narrative>
  <narrative>Pascrell</narrative>
  <narrative>Pastor</narrative>
  <narrative>Payne</narrative>
  <narrative>Perlmutter</narrative>
  <narrative>Peterson (MN)</narrative>
  <narrative>Pomeroy</narrative>
  <narrative>Price (NC)</narrative>
  <narrative>Rahall</narrative>
  <narrative>Rangel</narrative>
  <narrative>Reyes</narrative>
  <narrative>Richardson</narrative>
  <narrative>Rodriguez</narrative>
  <narrative>Ross</narrative>
  <narrative>Rothman</narrative>
  <narrative>Roybal-Allard</narrative>
  <narrative>Ruppersberger</narrative>
  <narrative>Rush</narrative>
  <narrative>Ryan (OH)</narrative>
  <narrative>Salazar</narrative>
  <narrative>S&#xE1;nchez, Linda T.</narrative>
  <narrative>Sanchez, Loretta</narrative>
  <narrative>Sarbanes</narrative>
  <narrative>Schakowsky</narrative>
  <narrative>Schiff</narrative>
  <narrative>Schwartz</narrative>
  <narrative>Scott (GA)</narrative>
  <narrative>Scott (VA)</narrative>
  <narrative>Serrano</narrative>
  <narrative>Sestak</narrative>
  <narrative>Shea-Porter</narrative>
  <narrative>Sherman</narrative>
  <narrative>Shuler</narrative>
  <narrative>Sires</narrative>
  <narrative>Skelton</narrative>
  <narrative>Slaughter</narrative>
  <narrative>Smith (WA)</narrative>
  <narrative>Snyder</narrative>
  <narrative>Solis</narrative>
  <narrative>Space</narrative>
  <narrative>Spratt</narrative>
  <narrative>Stark</narrative>
  <narrative>Stupak</narrative>
  <narrative>Sutton</narrative>
  <narrative>Tanner</narrative>
  <narrative>Tauscher</narrative>
  <narrative>Taylor</narrative>
  <narrative>Thompson (CA)</narrative>
  <narrative>Thompson (MS)</narrative>
  <narrative>Tierney</narrative>
  <narrative>Towns</narrative>
  <narrative>Udall (CO)</narrative>
  <narrative>Udall (NM)</narrative>
  <narrative>Van Hollen</narrative>
  <narrative>Vel&#xE1;zquez</narrative>
  <narrative>Visclosky</narrative>
  <narrative>Walz (MN)</narrative>
  <narrative>Wasserman Schultz</narrative>
  <narrative>Waters</narrative>
  <narrative>Watson</narrative>
  <narrative>Watt</narrative>
  <narrative>Waxman</narrative>
  <narrative>Weiner</narrative>
  <narrative>Welch (VT)</narrative>
  <narrative>Wexler</narrative>
  <narrative>Wilson (OH)</narrative>
  <narrative>Woolsey</narrative>
  <narrative>Wu</narrative>
  <narrative>Wynn</narrative>
  <narrative>Yarmuth</narrative>
  <narrative>Aderholt</narrative>
  <narrative>Akin</narrative>
  <narrative>Alexander</narrative>
  <narrative>Bachmann</narrative>
  <narrative>Bachus</narrative>
  <narrative>Baker</narrative>
  <narrative>Barrett (SC)</narrative>
  <narrative>Barrow</narrative>
  <narrative>Bartlett (MD)</narrative>
  <narrative>Barton (TX)</narrative>
  <narrative>Biggert</narrative>
  <narrative>Bilbray</narrative>
  <narrative>Bilirakis</narrative>
  <narrative>Bishop (UT)</narrative>
  <narrative>Blackburn</narrative>
  <narrative>Blunt</narrative>
  <narrative>Boehner</narrative>
  <narrative>Bonner</narrative>
  <narrative>Bono</narrative>
  <narrative>Boozman</narrative>
  <narrative>Boustany</narrative>
  <narrative>Brady (TX)</narrative>
  <narrative>Broun (GA)</narrative>
  <narrative>Brown (SC)</narrative>
  <narrative>Brown-Waite, Ginny</narrative>
  <narrative>Buchanan</narrative>
  <narrative>Burgess</narrative>
  <narrative>Burton (IN)</narrative>
  <narrative>Buyer</narrative>
  <narrative>Calvert</narrative>
  <narrative>Camp (MI)</narrative>
  <narrative>Campbell (CA)</narrative>
  <narrative>Cannon</narrative>
  <narrative>Cantor</narrative>
  <narrative>Capito</narrative>
  <narrative>Carter</narrative>
  <narrative>Castle</narrative>
  <narrative>Chabot</narrative>
  <narrative>Coble</narrative>
  <narrative>Cole (OK)</narrative>
  <narrative>Conaway</narrative>
  <narrative>Culberson</narrative>
  <narrative>Davis (KY)</narrative>
  <narrative>Davis, David</narrative>
  <narrative>Davis, Tom</narrative>
  <narrative>Deal (GA)</narrative>
  <narrative>Dent</narrative>
  <narrative>Diaz-Balart, L.</narrative>
  <narrative>Diaz-Balart, M.</narrative>
  <narrative>Doolittle</narrative>
  <narrative>Drake</narrative>
  <narrative>Dreier</narrative>
  <narrative>Duncan</narrative>
  <narrative>Ehlers</narrative>
  <narrative>Emerson</narrative>
  <narrative>English (PA)</narrative>
  <narrative>Everett</narrative>
  <narrative>Fallin</narrative>
  <narrative>Feeney</narrative>
  <narrative>Ferguson</narrative>
  <narrative>Flake</narrative>
  <narrative>Forbes</narrative>
  <narrative>Fortenberry</narrative>
  <narrative>Fossella</narrative>
  <narrative>Foxx</narrative>
  <narrative>Franks (AZ)</narrative>
  <narrative>Frelinghuysen</narrative>
  <narrative>Gallegly</narrative>
  <narrative>Garrett (NJ)</narrative>
  <narrative>Gerlach</narrative>
  <narrative>Gilchrest</narrative>
  <narrative>Gingrey</narrative>
  <narrative>Gohmert</narrative>
  <narrative>Goode</narrative>
  <narrative>Goodlatte</narrative>
  <narrative>Granger</narrative>
  <narrative>Graves</narrative>
  <narrative>Hall (TX)</narrative>
  <narrative>Hastert</narrative>
  <narrative>Hastings (WA)</narrative>
  <narrative>Hayes</narrative>
  <narrative>Heller</narrative>
  <narrative>Hensarling</narrative>
  <narrative>Hobson</narrative>
  <narrative>Hoekstra</narrative>
  <narrative>Hulshof</narrative>
  <narrative>Inglis (SC)</narrative>
  <narrative>Issa</narrative>
  <narrative>Johnson (IL)</narrative>
  <narrative>Johnson, Sam</narrative>
  <narrative>Jones (NC)</narrative>
  <narrative>Jordan</narrative>
  <narrative>Keller</narrative>
  <narrative>King (IA)</narrative>
  <narrative>King (NY)</narrative>
  <narrative>Kingston</narrative>
  <narrative>Kirk</narrative>
  <narrative>Kline (MN)</narrative>
  <narrative>Knollenberg</narrative>
  <narrative>Kucinich</narrative>
  <narrative>Kuhl (NY)</narrative>
  <narrative>LaHood</narrative>
  <narrative>Lamborn</narrative>
  <narrative>Latham</narrative>
  <narrative>LaTourette</narrative>
  <narrative>Lewis (CA)</narrative>
  <narrative>Lewis (KY)</narrative>
  <narrative>Linder</narrative>
  <narrative>LoBiondo</narrative>
  <narrative>Lucas</narrative>
  <narrative>Lungren, Daniel E.</narrative>
  <narrative>Mack</narrative>
  <narrative>Manzullo</narrative>
  <narrative>Marchant</narrative>
  <narrative>McCarthy (CA)</narrative>
  <narrative>McCaul (TX)</narrative>
  <narrative>McCotter</narrative>
  <narrative>McCrery</narrative>
  <narrative>McHenry</narrative>
  <narrative>McHugh</narrative>
  <narrative>McKeon</narrative>
  <narrative>McMorris Rodgers</narrative>
  <narrative>Mica</narrative>
  <narrative>Miller (FL)</narrative>
  <narrative>Miller (MI)</narrative>
  <narrative>Miller, Gary</narrative>
  <narrative>Moran (KS)</narrative>
  <narrative>Murphy, Tim</narrative>
  <narrative>Myrick</narrative>
  <narrative>Neugebauer</narrative>
  <narrative>Nunes</narrative>
  <narrative>Paul</narrative>
  <narrative>Pearce</narrative>
  <narrative>Pence</narrative>
  <narrative>Peterson (PA)</narrative>
  <narrative>Petri</narrative>
  <narrative>Pickering</narrative>
  <narrative>Pitts</narrative>
  <narrative>Platts</narrative>
  <narrative>Poe</narrative>
  <narrative>Porter</narrative>
  <narrative>Price (GA)</narrative>
  <narrative>Pryce (OH)</narrative>
  <narrative>Radanovich</narrative>
  <narrative>Ramstad</narrative>
  <narrative>Regula</narrative>
  <narrative>Rehberg</narrative>
  <narrative>Reichert</narrative>
  <narrative>Renzi</narrative>
  <narrative>Reynolds</narrative>
  <narrative>Rogers (AL)</narrative>
  <narrative>Rogers (KY)</narrative>
  <narrative>Rogers (MI)</narrative>
  <narrative>Rohrabacher</narrative>
  <narrative>Ros-Lehtinen</narrative>
  <narrative>Roskam</narrative>
  <narrative>Royce</narrative>
  <narrative>Ryan (WI)</narrative>
  <narrative>Sali</narrative>
  <narrative>Saxton</narrative>
  <narrative>Schmidt</narrative>
  <narrative>Sensenbrenner</narrative>
  <narrative>Sessions</narrative>
  <narrative>Shadegg</narrative>
  <narrative>Shays</narrative>
  <narrative>Shimkus</narrative>
  <narrative>Shuster</narrative>
  <narrative>Simpson</narrative>
  <narrative>Smith (NE)</narrative>
  <narrative>Smith (NJ)</narrative>
  <narrative>Stearns</narrative>
  <narrative>Sullivan</narrative>
  <narrative>Tancredo</narrative>
  <narrative>Terry</narrative>
  <narrative>Thornberry</narrative>
  <narrative>Tiahrt</narrative>
  <narrative>Tiberi</narrative>
  <narrative>Turner</narrative>
  <narrative>Upton</narrative>
  <narrative>Walberg</narrative>
  <narrative>Walden (OR)</narrative>
  <narrative>Walsh (NY)</narrative>
  <narrative>Wamp</narrative>
  <narrative>Weldon (FL)</narrative>
  <narrative>Weller</narrative>
  <narrative>Westmoreland</narrative>
  <narrative>Wicker</narrative>
  <narrative>Wilson (NM)</narrative>
  <narrative>Wilson (SC)</narrative>
  <narrative>Wolf</narrative>
  <narrative>Young (AK)</narrative>
  <narrative>Young (FL)</narrative>
  <narrative>Abercrombie</narrative>
  <narrative>Boyd (FL)</narrative>
  <narrative>Brown, Corrine</narrative>
  <narrative>Carson</narrative>
  <narrative>Crenshaw</narrative>
  <narrative>Cubin</narrative>
  <narrative>Davis, Jo Ann</narrative>
  <narrative>Engel</narrative>
  <narrative>Herger</narrative>
  <narrative>Hinojosa</narrative>
  <narrative>Hunter</narrative>
  <narrative>Jindal</narrative>
  <narrative>Johnson, E. B.</narrative>
  <narrative>Loebsack</narrative>
  <narrative>Meeks (NY)</narrative>
  <narrative>Musgrave</narrative>
  <narrative>Putnam</narrative>
  <narrative>Smith (TX)</narrative>
  <narrative>Souder</narrative>
  <narrative>Whitfield</narrative>
  <narrative/>
  <narrative>Ms. GINNY BROWN-WAITE of Florida and Messrs. LEWIS of Kentucky, BOOZMAN and TIM MURPHY of Pennsylvania changed their vote from "yea" to "nay."</narrative>
  <narrative>Mr. HILL changed his vote from "nay" to "yea."</narrative>
  <narrative>So the previous question was ordered.</narrative>
  <narrative>The result of the vote was announced as above recorded.</narrative>
  <chair> The question is on the resolution.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
