<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1186176989" ordinal="19" title="ISSUE IS WHETHER ILLEGAL IMMIGRANTS CAN GET BENEFITS">
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="McHENRY" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the issue before us is whether or not illegal immigrants can get government benefits, and the Democrat majority in this House has shown that they are willing to cheat in order to win a vote. Cheat in order to win a vote. And----</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mrs." name="TAUSCHER" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would like the gentleman's words taken down, please.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The gentleman will suspend.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will report the words.</narrative>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="McHENRY" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent to withdraw my words.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from North Carolina?</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="McHENRY" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, my point is that the actions of the Democrat majority on the House floor last night besmirches the character of this House, and it's because they support giving benefits to illegal aliens in this country, and it's about the issue of illegal immigration and whether or not illegals in this country can receive government benefits. They're willing to protect some of their freshmen vulnerable Democrats and make them toe the line.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But Mr. Speaker, when they lost the vote on the House floor, the Speaker came down and voted in this well in order to tie that vote, and when that wasn't good enough and when a vote switched and they lost, they lost that vote, they're willing to gavel it down in order to protect themselves from a tough vote demanding that illegals do not receive government benefits.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, Mr. Speaker, was it a cover-up? Was it a sham? Absolutely. And some, some believe the actions were cheating the facts.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
</record>
