<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1178640003" ordinal="56" title="COMMENDING PUBLIC SERVANTS FOR THEIR DEDICATION AND CONTINUED SERVICE TO THE NATION">
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution (<bill type="hr" number="307">H. Res. 307</bill>) expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that public servants should be commended for their dedication and continued service to the Nation during Public Service Recognition Week, May 7 through 13, 2007.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the resolution.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Davis) and the gentlewoman from North Carolina (Ms. Foxx) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days in which to revise and extend their remarks.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Illinois?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would yield myself such time as I might consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="hr" number="307">H. Res. 307</bill> commends public servants for their outstanding contributions to this great Nation during Public Service Recognition Week, May 7 through May 13, 2007. This resolution salutes their unyielding dedication and spirit of public service.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On Tuesday, April 17, 2007, I introduced this legislation in conjunction with Senator Akaka, who introduced <bill type="sr" number="150">S. Res. 150</bill> to honor and celebrate the commitment of the men and women who have dedicated their lives to serving the public.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over 18 million individuals in cities, counties and States in America and abroad serve our government and the American people. They perform essential services that the Nation relies upon every day. Federal employees from agencies like the National Institutes of Health, National Science Foundation, and the Food and Drug Administration are committed to promoting health, advances in research, regulating industries, and ensuring the well-being and safety of our citizens.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The men and women serving in the Armed Forces of the United States as well as the skilled trade and craft employees who support their efforts contribute greatly to the security of our country and to the world. We cannot thank our public servants enough for the work that they do for their fellow citizens day in and day out.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Governments at all levels simply cannot function properly without good employees who are committed to public service. We should be reminded of their contributions, not just in May, but when we are setting their pay and benefits, and by ensuring that they have the resources they need to do their jobs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last Wednesday, the Senate passed Senate Resolution 150, the companion bill to <bill type="hr" number="307">H. Res. 307</bill>, and I would urge my colleagues to do the same.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400643" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself as much time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am extremely proud to rise today in support of <bill type="hr" number="307">H. Res. 307</bill>, honoring the millions of dedicated public servants that serve our Nation. Our country simply could not function without its innovative, professional, highly trained public service employees. At all levels of government you will find hardworking staff making our country prosper and thrive through their contributions. The expertise and work ethic offered by these individuals sets an honorable example for future generations of employees.  From emergency responders to librarians, public servants span the spectrum of jobs that keep our country efficient and safe.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Beyond the tremendous work of civilian employees and uniformed service personnel, the members of our National Guard and Reserves are crucial to the welfare of all U.S. citizens. They provide vital strategic support for our Nation's military both at home and abroad. Their tremendous accomplishments with assisting States and countries overseas with natural disasters is to be praised.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Once again, I commend these employees for performing challenging and oftentimes thankless jobs with honor and dedication. I appreciate them for moving our country forward and maintaining our safety and security. For these reasons I am thrilled to express my support for a week of honoring these individuals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I want to commend the gentlelady for her comments, and I appreciate her support of this resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400435" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today to mark the 23rd annual Public Service Recognition Week. I am proud to be a co-chair of the Congressional Public Service Caucus, proud to have been a federal employee, and proud to represent in Congress a large number of my constituents who are federal employees. These employees are a national asset who work hard day after day with professionalism and dedication.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Federal employees are the backbone of our government. They can be found working to find cures for diseases at the National Institutes of Health, helping seniors with their Social Security benefits, representing our interests overseas in the State Department, serving as stewards of America's natural resources in the National Park Service, helping our country defend the homeland at the Department of Defense and at the Department of Homeland Security. These are but a few examples of the many areas  in which federal employees are serving our country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We must not forget those federal employees who are risking their lives in the war against  terrorism. The first combat death in Afghanistan in the wake of September 11 was CIA officer Johnny Micheal Spann, one of my constituents. And today, Federal employees can be found throughout the globe fighting the war against terrorism in many different ways.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The sacrifice and hard work of our federal employees, whether abroad or at home, should never be forgotten. Federal employees deserve fair pay--which is why I have been pleased to support pay parity for federal employees since I have been in Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>They deserve adequate health care--which is why I have supported legislation to make sure federal employees get quality health benefits.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And retired Federal employees must not be forgotten--which is why I have supported legislation to aid Federal employees who have retired from active service. Federal employees deserve to be honored during Public Service Recognition Week. But we must always remember the they are serving our country every day of the year.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Davis) that the House suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, <bill type="hr" number="307">H. Res. 307</bill>.</chair>
</record>
