<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1196787602" ordinal="54" title="2007 WORLD AIDS DAY">
  <narrative>2007 WORLD AIDS DAY -- (House of Representatives - December 04, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H14135]</narrative>
  <chair> Under a previous order of the House, the gentlewoman from the Virgin Islands (Mrs. Christensen) is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, as you heard, last Saturday was World AIDS Day, and I join my colleagues to remind us of its goals and ideals and to support the resolution that is going to be introduced by my colleague and good friend Congresswoman BARBARA LEE to have this Congress support those goals and ideals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We also call on our colleagues on both sides of the aisle and in both sides of the Capitol to honor this year's World AIDS Day theme, both in this Nation and abroad, to stop AIDS and keep the promise.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As you heard, Congresswoman Lee and I recently returned from South Africa, where we were inspired and motivated by the commitment of the people, young and old, to confront HIV and AIDS.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It was a distinct privilege for me to have been invited to give the keynote address at a World AIDS Day ceremony in Sekhukhune in the Greater Tabatse Region of South Africa. South Africa has the most AIDS cases of any country in the world. And while we were proud to know that it is also the country with the largest PEPFAR program, we and the rest of the world still need to do more.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>From all we saw, all of the programs we witnessed that were funded, either by PEPFAR or by private corporations such as Johnson and Johnson and Humana, in Limpopo, in Zola in Soweto, in Pretoria or as it will now be called, Tshwane or in Johannesburg, and from the revised reports we have seen coming from UNAIDS, we greeted World AIDS Day with a sense of hope for all the individuals, the families and the nations in our global community who have for far too long struggled with this pandemic.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And in my keynote I drew comparisons between the HIV and AIDS in sub-Saharan Africa, in the Caribbean whose prevalence rate is second to theirs, in the African American community in  the United States and in my own Virgin Islands, speaking to how people of African descent the world over are so disproportionately impacted by this virus.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But everywhere there are signs, early signs, of change and potentially promising trends, everywhere, including in the Virgin Islands and the rest of the Caribbean, everywhere except in the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The HIV epidemic is more than 25 years old; and despite all that we know and all of the resources we have, the CDC is finalizing a report which will be released early next year that I understand will show that the case rate here in the U.S. is possibly more than 50 percent higher than we previously thought. Given the lack of response from this administration to the requests of the CBC and our community partners, I'm sure that it will show that the highest increases are in people of racial and  ethic minority backgrounds.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, let me say that the theme for this in the past 2 years has been "Stop AIDS, Keep the Promise." The promise has not been fully kept anywhere, but nowhere has it fallen more short, has that promise been more empty than right here at home in this country of great resources and the most advanced medicines and technologies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There's another part to the theme, and that is leadership, which is needed more than ever. On our part we need to lead by directing more Federal resources to HIV prevention. Beyond that, our leadership must be open to proven methods of prevention instead of limiting the good we can do and the lives we can save because of ideology and narrow politics. And the prevention we provide needs to be not of the abstinence-only kind, which our government agencies have clearly demonstrated is not effective.  Lifting the ban on needle exchange alone would dramatically reduce the transmission of the disease, and developing low-cost barrier methods such as microbicides need to be given as much attention as funding the latest ARVS, but those too need to be made more affordable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And, Madam Speaker, we need a national plan. It is clear from the fact that we are losing ground while some of the poorest areas of the world are making strides that the leadership we provide must define global as in global epidemic, or global HIV/AIDS as including this country on par with all of the others. We need to restore the 19 percent of funding that has been cut from domestic AIDS in this administration and greatly increase HIV/AIDS funding across the board. We need to fund the Ryan White  CARE Act at the level it needs to be funded, more than $1 billion above the current level, to restore and re-fund the Minority Aids Initiative to build capacity in the communities that are hardest hit, and to eliminate ADAP waiting lists, where people who cannot get treatment wait to die.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We need to ensure that we expand access to information, testing services and treatment to ex-offenders who are at great risk for HIV and who after paying their debt return to their communities and families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And we need to dramatically increase PEPFAR funding while expanding it to include all Caribbean countries and making it more flexible so it can meet the unique needs of the countries that need it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The global report shows that when we apply the recommendations of social and scientific research and when we support and replicate programs that work, results are seen. It shows that empowering communities that are hard hit by HIV and AIDS by putting the resources, technical assistance and support in their indigenous community and faith-based organizations here and abroad produce great impact.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The most dramatic thing is that people are looking to us for leadership and we can provide it and we can start by supporting Congresswoman Lee's resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
