<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1184558400" ordinal="19" title="RECOGNIZING AND HONORING THE CATHEDRAL SQUARE CORPORATION ON ITS 30TH ANNIVERSARY">
  <narrative>RECOGNIZING AND HONORING THE CATHEDRAL SQUARE CORPORATION ON ITS 30TH ANNIVERSARY -- (House of Representatives - July 16, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H7795]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412220" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution (<bill type="hr" number="408">H. Res. 408</bill>) recognizing and honoring the Cathedral Square Corporation on its 30th anniversary.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the resolution.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the resolution is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="hr" number="408">H. Res. 408</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas in 1977 the Cathedral Church of St. Paul, the Cathedral of the Episcopal Diocese of Vermont, recognized the need to provide safe and affordable housing for its low-income seniors, organized the Cathedral Square Corporation, and began construction of a single project;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas since that small beginning Cathedral Square Corporation has grown into one of the largest and most innovative nonprofit housing developers in Vermont;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the work of Cathedral Square Corporation has been groundbreaking, both literally and figuratively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Cathedral Square Corporation has developed housing for persons with mental health challenges, and operates the housing in partnership with mental health agencies;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Cathedral Square Corporation has developed housing for younger adults with severe mobility impairments, and operates the housing in partnership with the Visiting Nurse Association;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Cathedral Square Corporation completed one of the first assisted living conversion projects in the country for very low-income seniors who otherwise would be in nursing homes;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Cathedral Square Corporation saved the historic Ruggles House, a property on the National Register of Historic Places, converting it to shared housing;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Cathedral Square Corporation developed an intergenerational community, serving the elderly, teenage parents, and parents returning to college;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Cathedral Square Corporation created Whitcomb Terrace, a housing development for persons of any age, income, or disability, which is a truly integrated, barrier-free community;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Cathedral Square Corporation recently completed construction of an innovative mixed-financing project, which is one of few such projects in the Nation and will be home to 63 senior households and 4 nonprofit organizations;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Cathedral Square Corporation currently manages housing for 837 seniors, 79 young adults with special needs, and 24 low-income children, and every property managed by the Corporation provides as many services as possible to enable independent living by the residents;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas not only has Cathedral Square Corporation made possible 40 affordable housing communities throughout Vermont, but the Board of Directors and staff of the Corporation are always looking to the future, anticipating the housing and service needs of those Vermonters who otherwise would have few housing options; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Cathedral Square Corporation does not just build housing, they provide homes: Now, therefore, be it</narrative>
  <narrative> Resolved, &lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; That the House of Representatives recognizes and honors the tremendous accomplishments and dedication of Cathedral Square Corporation, a Vermont nonprofit housing development organization, on the occasion of its 30th anniversary.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from New Hampshire (Mr. Hodes) and the gentleman from New Mexico (Mr. Pearce) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from New Hampshire.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412220" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days within which to revise and extend their remarks on this legislation and to insert extraneous material thereon.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from New Hampshire?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412220" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield myself so much time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise today in support of House Resolution 408. This resolution recognizes and honors the Cathedral Square Corporation on its 30th anniversary in September of this year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Cathedral Square Corporation is based in Burlington, Vermont, in the district of my esteemed colleague, PETER WELCH.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1977, the Cathedral Church of St. Paul, the Cathedral of the Episcopal Diocese of Vermont, recognized the need to provide safe and affordable housing for its low-income seniors. It organized the Cathedral Square Corporation and began construction of a single project. Since then, it has grown into one of the largest and most innovative nonprofit housing developers in Vermont.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Cathedral Square Corporation has developed much needed housing for persons with mental health challenges, younger adults with severe mobility impairments, and completed one of the first assisted living conversion projects in the country for very low-income seniors who otherwise would be in nursing homes. In addition, the Cathedral Square Corporation has worked with the community to save the historic Ruggles House, a property on the National Register of Historic Places, converting it to shared  housing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This extremely important organization has worked to develop an intergenerational community, serving the elderly, teenage parents, and parents returning to college.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In total, Madam Speaker, the Cathedral Square Corporation currently manages housing for 837 seniors, 79 young adults with special needs, and 24 low-income children. And every property managed by the corporation provides as many services as possible to enable independent living by the residents.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, not only has Cathedral Square Corporation made possible 40 affordable housing communities throughout Vermont, but the board of directors and staff of this corporation are always looking to the future, anticipating the housing and service needs of those Vermonters who otherwise would have few housing options.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Cathedral Square Corporation doesn't just build housing, they provide homes and help create community. They are an outstanding example to all housing groups, and I applaud their innovation and their diligent work and service to the community.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I congratulate the Cathedral Square Corporation. And this resolution congratulates them on 30 years of distinguished service.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, at this time I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400313" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I rise today in support of <bill type="hr" number="408">H. Res. 408</bill> to honor Cathedral Square Corporation in respect to their 30 years of dedicated service to providing quality, affordable housing for seniors and individuals with special needs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The United States must take care of its seniors and individual needs. I appreciate the work done by the Cathedral Square Corporation over the last 30 years to provide the most quality assistance to our seniors and special need individuals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank and congratulate the CSC on reaching their 30th anniversary. And I encourage my colleagues to support the resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412220" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for his concurrence in this resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I have no further requests for time, and I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from New Hampshire (Mr. Hodes) that the House suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, <bill type="hr" number="408">H. Res. 408</bill>.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the resolution was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
