<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1183046405" ordinal="33" title="FINANCIAL SERVICES AND GENERAL GOVERNMENT APPROPRIATIONS ACT, 2008">
  <chair> Pursuant to House Resolution 517 and rule XVIII, the Chair declares the House in the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for the further consideration of the bill, <bill type="h" number="2829">H.R. 2829</bill>.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> When the Committee of the Whole rose earlier today, a request for a recorded vote on amendment No. 32 by the gentleman from Virginia (Mr. Goode) had been postponed.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400388" topic="ADDITIONAL GENERAL PROVISIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a simple amendment that none of the funds made available in this act may be used by the Internal Revenue Service to implement a Spanish language version of the Where's my Refund? service.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, the English language has been one of the strongest, most durable ties that unites us all as Americans. Yet today our unity in the English language is undermined by policies that require government agencies to communicate in an increasing number of foreign languages. It is not just one, two, or three. In some of the cases, it is five, and six languages.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I rise today to offer an amendment to strike language in the underlying bill that would mandate even more government multilingualism. My amendment would prohibit the IRS from developing a Spanish language version of the agency's Where's my Refund? Web site, which is currently only offered in English.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So think about that. As it turns out now, if you want to get a refund, you go to the IRS Web site, and sure enough, you can find out how to do it. English is right there. You go through the procedure and understand it. But now in the bill, they want to put it into Spanish. So I am just saying let's continue with the status quo and keep it in English.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Taxpayers should not be required to pay the cost of translating information so that people can demand a tax refund in another language. This is our country and we want to promote English, and I am sure most people that want to get a refund, of all things, would like to learn English so they can get their refund. Generations of immigrants have made great sacrifices to learn English and assimilate into this great American "melting pot." This is what has allowed us to become the most successful  multiracial and multiethnic Nation in the world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Making exceptions now for another language I don't think is the right thing to do. It just assumes they are incapable of learning English like the previous generations. And many, many immigrants that came here learned English, and for all these years they have been able to determine what their refund was by going forward. So I think it is not a good idea to change this tradition. I realize that there are lots of people who don't agree with me, but I think we should have a vote on this to understand  it and have the will of the House.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, California Governor Arnold Schwarzenegger knows something about the importance of learning English. He emigrated to the United States from Austria knowing very little English. He has said he immersed himself in American culture and made an effort to only speak English once he came to the United States. So he is a good example.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We should be encouraging immigrants to learn English, not enabling them by providing more and more government services in various foreign languages. It could be one language here, another language here, and pretty soon taxpayers are forced to deal with many, many languages just to get their refund.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Additionally, what makes Spanish speakers in this country more deserving than perhaps people from South Korea or people from Japan or people from China? I mean, is there one particular reason we are singling out this one language? If it is true we need to have this and I don't think we do, then I certainly think we should solve the problem of looking at all the languages.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The policy of our government should be to conduct official business in English and uphold the longstanding credo of "E Pluribus Unum": out of many, one. My amendment, I believe, simply would further this goal, and I urge my colleagues to support this amendment and help preserve our national linguistic unity and strengthen our democracy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400366" topic="ADDITIONAL GENERAL PROVISIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I rise to claim the time in opposition to the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from New York is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400366" topic="ADDITIONAL GENERAL PROVISIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, this is the kind of amendment that shows up every so often. It plays to our patriotic feelings and to our feelings of wanting to be good Americans. So what you tell Americans is that if a language other than English is used anywhere in the country for any purpose, somehow, as the gentleman says, it attacks our democracy and threatens our democracy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are not saying that we want people to stay away from learning to speak English, and I think it is important to note that when people come into this country and what some folks go through to come into this country, that is a statement about how much they want to be in this country. Is it true that Mom and Dad may take a little longer to speak English? Absolutely. But the young man that comes in or the young woman that comes in at the age of 8, 9, 10, 12, whatever, I assure you that 10 months  after they are here, they are acting very American and a year or two later they are speaking English. That's a fact of life.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In fact, I know this for a fact as one who spoke Spanish before he spoke English. When Hispanics sit around the dinner table and the issue of language comes up, it has never been a plot against the English language. It is usually the lament by the grandmother that the grandchildren no longer speak Spanish. That is the reality of America. That is how it has been from day one. That is how it is always going to be.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, what is it that we provide here? We are saying that if you still have not reached that point where you feel comfortable enough in English to deal with government services, you can go to a Web site, listen to this, and say, Where is my tax refund? That in itself makes a statement. It says you are working in this country, that you are paying taxes in the country, that you have a refund coming, and you want to know where your refund is. So to make it easier for you to communicate and get that  service, the IRS has seen fit to put together that kind of a service.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, folks who deal with the IRS on a regular basis like the IRS National Taxpayers Advocate, in the annual report earlier this year, commended the IRS for the efforts to establish a Spanish-language version of Where's My Refund?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So if you don't like the fact that this service is provided, say that. That's fine. But don't make it sound like this is a threat to our democracy. This country is strong for what it is and who we are, not because we have a website that allows people, who speak Spanish and feel a little more comfortable as they transition into English, get this kind of information.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What is ironic is that we come to the House floor and make all these comments about government agencies offering Spanish as a language, but, Mr. Chairman, none of our colleagues from the other side ever get up and criticize their friends in corporate America who on a daily basis advertise in Spanish.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Do you know that there is an ESPN in Spanish, there is an ESPN Deportes in Spanish? There's a Fox, yes, a Fox News in Spanish. There's a Fox Sports, I said Fox, in Spanish. There's a People magazine in Spanish.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, is that government doing that or is that corporate America, who at times hangs out more with that side than this side, doing what they know is correct to sell their products? All these folks are saying is to give a service to the people, we will do it in Spanish too. Trust me, this does not threaten the democracy at all.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am, on a personal level, kind of a little shocked at my friend, the only man who ever passed a ball to me in a congressional basketball game because he knows of my lack of talent, and he knows he's my friend, but you would think he comes from another State. He comes from Florida.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I don't know how you are going to explain this back home. I am trying to help you here. Maybe you want to withdraw this amendment so you can save a lot of headaches back home.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400388" topic="ADDITIONAL GENERAL PROVISIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, may I inquire as to how much time I have remaining?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman has 1 1/2  minutes remaining.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400388" topic="ADDITIONAL GENERAL PROVISIONS">
    <paragraph>Let me just move to use the 1 1/2  minutes I have remaining and say to my sage colleague from New York that I certainly respect him. He's one of my favorite Members. We have lots of fun together. And I remember when he made those three pointers in the congressional basketball team how surprised, and pleasantly surprised, I was that he made them. So I'm respectful of that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But I ask him, shouldn't government treat everybody equally? I mean, here you're talking about setting aside a special program, Where is My Refund program, under the IRS for the Spanish language. But I call the gentleman's attention to New York City. There are Chinese, almost 400,000 Chinese; 300,000 Italians; there are almost 250,000 Russians, there's 152,000 Frenchmen, Polish is a language there. The French Creole is about 100,000. Korean is about 86,000, German is about 86,000. In fact, the  total number of people speaking foreign languages in his area, New York City, other than Spanish is 1.7 million people. So why shouldn't the government treat everybody equal is the question for you?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400366" topic="ADDITIONAL GENERAL PROVISIONS">
    <paragraph>May I inquire as to how much time I have left?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from New York has 30 seconds.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400366" topic="ADDITIONAL GENERAL PROVISIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I move to strike the last word and yield to the gentleman from Massachusetts.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400140" topic="ADDITIONAL GENERAL PROVISIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, we've just heard one of the least persuasive arguments that we have ever heard in this body. We hear them repeatedly. People who are opposed to doing something use the argument that we shouldn't do it, even though they're objecting to it on its own basic grounds because it doesn't go far enough. If, of course, it went far enough, they would be even more upset, Mr. Chairman.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The argument that if you cannot solve every problem for everybody, you should not try to improve the situation for large numbers of people is never what people really think. It is always advanced by people who don't want fully to defend the position they take. The objection is to accommodating the many millions of Americans for whom Spanish is the primary language.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have to say, I do not understand the impulse to make life harder for others when making it easier for them has no cost to us. I represent a large number of people who speak English. Nobody has ever said to me, you know what? My life is now more difficult because people who speak primarily Spanish can get a refund.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What is the impulse that drives us to object to making life easier for many of our hardworking fellow citizens in some principle when it comes at no cost to us?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And by the way, I have a large number of people for whom Portuguese is a primary language. I do not think they will tell me, when I go back to march in parades in that area, we're very upset because you supported allowing tens of millions of our Spanish-speaking friends this advantage and you didn't do everything for us. It is, of course, reasonable for a community to take into account large numbers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And so again, I am really troubled by this lashing out at our fellow citizens when it comes at no cost to the rest of us. You talk about benefit cost analysis. What is the cost, it's minimal, of letting people who work hard who have trouble with the English language?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And as the gentleman from New York has pointed out, overwhelmingly the younger people learn English. No one who has had any association with an immigrant community has any doubt about the accuracy of what he said. The young people learn English, they become the translators and interpreters for their parents and their grandparents.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are people who came to America out of love for this country and they work hard, and they are much more comfortable, particularly reading sort of technical information, in the language they grew up with than the new language. Their children and those who come after will speak English. Why do we want to make their lives harder? Why this objection to trying to ease the transition for these people?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I very much hope this amendment is defeated. I would hope we would say we are a better country than to begrudge people who have taken the difficult decision to immigrate to make their lives better, this very small accommodation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for yielding to me.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400366" topic="ADDITIONAL GENERAL PROVISIONS">
    <paragraph>Reclaiming my time, the gentleman from Massachusetts, my friend, makes the best point of all. If you can just imagine, and I think you do because Lou Dobbs and other people show you all the time, what some people go through to get to this country, not to mention others who enter here with documents. You don't go through all of that to decide later that you don't want to be part of this society and not speak English. That is a fallacy. That is not true. And I can tell you firsthand  it doesn't happen.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I can tell you that I go to community meetings now in my district where there is no need any longer to say a word in Spanish other than to sound cute at the beginning by saying, Hola. Como esta, Ustedes?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is not a problem. And I am trying to save you, once again, from all this wrath you're going to get back in  Florida for proposing this. So I still give you a chance to withdraw this. I hope everybody will vote against this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400334" topic="ADDITIONAL GENERAL PROVISIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I move to strike the last word.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from Ohio is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400334" topic="ADDITIONAL GENERAL PROVISIONS">
    <paragraph>I yield to the gentleman from Florida (Mr. Stearns).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400388" topic="ADDITIONAL GENERAL PROVISIONS">
    <paragraph>I thank my distinguished colleague from Ohio for his kindness.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We can wrap up this debate and I will just try to answer the gentleman from Massachusetts and the gentleman from New York here.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What can be more of an incentive to learn English? But the IRS program Where is My Refund? You would think if you are getting money back from the government, isn't that enough of an incentive to learn English? Maybe we should not have Spanish on the IRS Web site so we can get people to learn English. I mean, I would think giving them money back would be a great incentive. I would think you would be for this amendment because people who have to speak Spanish would have an incentive to learn English.  That's my first point.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second of all, the gentleman from Massachusetts says it's a minor cost. We don't know if this is a minor cost. But as we take his argument a little further, he says that I have no right to say there's another 1.7 million people in New York who speak other languages, and because the perfect is the enemy of good, we've got to give it to all these people, which is an argument that makes it confusing to people and say well, you have to vote against Stearn's amendment because we're not doing it for  all these people. There certainly would be a cost if we went ahead and did if for 1.7 million various languages in Italian, Russian, French, Polish, French Creole, Korean and German.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And I ask the gentleman from New York (Mr. Serrano), why is one language selected to do this at the expense of another 1.7 million? Which goes to my point. We shouldn't do it for only one, we need not do it for any of them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And so there is no reason to do the other languages here. They're getting money back. It would be very expensive if we did if for all the languages. And the cost here, we don't know what it's going to be. So I think the country is better off if we treat everybody equally.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The question you mention, Mr. Serrano, about CNN and other news organizations, these are private companies, they are not taxpayers funded. This is taxpayers funded. And I would think if a person is speaking French Creole in New York, he would like to have it in his language for the tax refund program, also.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, I mean, you really make a difficult argument if you're saying it's just for people who are Spanish and you're not recognizing all of them, which goes to the heart of my argument, which is, basically the United States Government should treat everybody equal. The language should be the English language, and particularly when you're talking about the Where is My Refund program with the IRS. Vote for the Stearns amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And with that, Mr. Chairman, may I inquire as to how much time I have left of my own and how much time I left of Mr. Regula? If that's possible to do that.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Mr. Regula has 2 minutes left, and the gentleman from Florida has 30 seconds.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400366" topic="ADDITIONAL GENERAL PROVISIONS">
    <paragraph>Will the gentleman yield?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400388" topic="ADDITIONAL GENERAL PROVISIONS">
    <paragraph>I would be glad to yield Mr. Regula's time if Mr. Regula will yield.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400334" topic="ADDITIONAL GENERAL PROVISIONS">
    <paragraph>Yes, I would be glad to yield to the gentleman.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400366" topic="ADDITIONAL GENERAL PROVISIONS">
    <paragraph>If you're willing to join me in a further amendment that says we should do 125 languages, I would be glad to join you because I believe in that. That's fine. That's because I don't know what you're really saying there.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400388" topic="ADDITIONAL GENERAL PROVISIONS">
    <paragraph>Are you saying 25 languages?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400366" topic="ADDITIONAL GENERAL PROVISIONS">
    <paragraph>125, that's what you said; we should do it for everybody. So that's 125 languages.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My other point, because I don't want to take up your time, is, it's interesting to note how the language changes. Now you're saying they're getting money back from the government, they should be happy to do that in English. Just a few minutes ago, for 3 days, for 3 weeks we heard how the government only holds the money from the taxpayer. So only this group is getting money back from the government, the rest of the Nation is just having the government hold their money.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from Florida is recognized for his final 30 seconds.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400388" topic="ADDITIONAL GENERAL PROVISIONS">
    <paragraph>I would just say, if you're speaking French Creole in your congressional district and you got a refund, you would certainly want that to be in our language, too.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think I've made the argument clear that with all these different languages, the government should not pick out any one and should just do it in the official language, which is English.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So with that, Mr. Chairman, thank you for your indulgence.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400334" topic="ADDITIONAL GENERAL PROVISIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from New York has 30 seconds.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400366" topic="ADDITIONAL GENERAL PROVISIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield to the gentleman from Massachusetts.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400140" topic="ADDITIONAL GENERAL PROVISIONS">
    <paragraph>I was struck when the gentleman of Florida said, why should we do this at the expense of other people? That's the crux of the disagreement between us. It doesn't come at the expense of other people. The fact that the largest single linguistic minority gets an ability to do this in their own language, which will, by the way, also probably increase tax collection, so it probably is an offset and it probably makes money for the Federal Government. But the gentleman's  phrasing "at the expense of," that's what troubles me. It does not come at my expense if we reach out to hardworking people who have trouble with English.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman's time has expired.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400388" topic="ADDITIONAL GENERAL PROVISIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I demand a recorded vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 6 of rule XVIII, further proceedings on the amendment offered by the gentleman from Florida will be postponed.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400366" topic="ADDITIONAL GENERAL PROVISIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I move to strike the last word.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400366" topic="ADDITIONAL GENERAL PROVISIONS">
    <paragraph>I yield to our majority leader, Mr. Hoyer.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400189" topic="ADDITIONAL GENERAL PROVISIONS">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, I would like to congratulate Mr. Serrano. This is his first bill that he has brought to the floor and handled, and he has done it very well. I want to thank him.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also want to congratulate my good friend, RALPH REGULA. I had the great honor of serving for 6 years under his chairmanship of the Labor Health Committee of which I had the honor of serving. He did an outstanding job, he's done a good job with this bell as well. I thank him for facilitating consideration of this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400239" topic="ADDITIONAL GENERAL PROVISIONS">
    <paragraph>Will the gentleman yield?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400189" topic="ADDITIONAL GENERAL PROVISIONS">
    <paragraph>I will yield to the gentleman.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400239" topic="ADDITIONAL GENERAL PROVISIONS">
    <paragraph>I simply want to say to the leader, I very much appreciate your taking the time to make those expressions. They've done a fabulous job on this bill, and it's an illustration of what can happen when we work so well together.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400189" topic="ADDITIONAL GENERAL PROVISIONS">
    <paragraph>Reclaiming my time, Mr. Chairman, at this time, however, I would like to mention a matter. I would have liked to ask for a unanimous consent. I will not ask for that unanimous consent because it has not been agreed to. And under our rules, I therefore am constrained to ask for the unanimous consent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senate passed yesterday, by unanimous consent, without objection, obviously, by definition, the Transition Medical Assistance and Abstinence Education Program. That program is a program which provides for transitional medical assistance for those who transit from welfare to work. It's a very important program. It, unfortunately, expires on June 30. We will not  be here on June 30. This could have been passed, and I would hope would have been passed  by unanimous consent. Unfortunately, that has not occurred, and therefore I will not be offering, as I said, such request.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would say, however, that it will be our intention to offer this as soon as we return the first week that we're back. We believe this is very important to pass. And as a result, we will move it as quickly as we can.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for yielding the time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400366" topic="ADDITIONAL GENERAL PROVISIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 6 of rule XVIII, proceedings will now resume on those amendments on which further proceedings were postponed, in the following order:</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> The Chair wishes to remind Members that the remainder of the votes, which are substantial in number, are going to be 2-minute votes. The Chair entreats Members to please stay in the Chamber. We intend to be strict with regard to the 2 minutes.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
  <narrative>The Clerk will redesignate the amendment.</narrative>
  <chair> A recorded vote has been demanded.</chair>
  <narrative>A recorded vote was ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> This will be a 2-minute vote.</chair>
</record>
