<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1178553612" ordinal="16" title="AUTHORIZING USE OF CAPITOL GROUNDS FOR NATIONAL PEACE OFFICERS' MEMORIAL SERVICE">
  <speaking speaker="400274" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and agree to the concurrent resolution (<bill type="hc" number="124">H. Con. Res. 124</bill>) authorizing the use of the Capitol Grounds for the National Peace Officers' Memorial Service.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the concurrent resolution.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Maine (Mr. Michaud) and the gentlewoman from West Virginia (Mrs. Capito) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400274" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on House Concurrent Resolution 124.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Maine?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400274" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, House Concurrent Resolution 124 authorizes the use of the Capitol grounds for the National Peace Officers' Memorial Service. Over 150 Federal, State, and local law enforcement officers killed in the line of duty in 2006 will be honored at this memorial service.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1962, President John F. Kennedy signed a proclamation which designated May 15 as Peace Officers' Memorial Day, and the week in which the date falls as Police Week.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The first official memorial service took place on May 15, 1982, at which 91 law enforcement officers were honored. Over the past 26 years, the memorial service has honored over 3,000 law enforcement officers from around our Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, the National Peace Officers' Memorial Service on Capitol Hill has become one in a series of well-attended events during Police Week. Activities on Capitol grounds conducted under House Concurrent Resolution 124 will be coordinated with the Office of Architect of the Capitol, will be free and open to the public. I support this resolution and urge its passage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400061" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>House Concurrent Resolution 124 authorizes the use of the Capitol grounds for the annual National Peace Officers' Memorial Service to be held Tuesday May 17, 2007. The Grand Lodge of the Fraternal Order of Police and its auxiliary annually sponsor this event honoring some of America's bravest men and women.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since the first recorded police death in 1792, there have been more than 17,900 law enforcement officers killed in the line of duty. The memorial service will honor the 145 Federal, State, and local law enforcement officers who made the ultimate sacrifice while protecting their communities in 2006, as well as all law enforcement officers who have died in the line of duty.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This will be the 26th time that this event has been held on the grounds of the Capitol. This memorial service is part of National Police Week, which was created by law in 1962 and runs this year from May 8 through May 15.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Police Week draws officers, their families and survivors of fallen officers from around the country and includes such events as the Blue Mass at St. Patrick's Catholic Church, the candlelight vigil at the National Law Enforcement Memorial, and a police unity tour featuring officers and historic vehicles.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The memorial service begins at noon on Tuesday. Following the ceremony on the Capitol Hill grounds, there will be a procession to the Law Enforcement Memorial and a wreath-laying ceremony.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I encourage my colleagues to attend this much deserved memorial service and honor those who protect our communities on the front lines.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I support the measure and encourage my colleagues to do the same.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400199" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of <bill type="hc" number="124">H. Con. Res. 124</bill>, which authorizes the use of the Capitol grounds for the National Peace Officers' Memorial Service.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Peace officers, the sworn, public-sector officers entrusted with law enforcement authority and the power of arrest, risk their lives daily to protect our nation. These individuals, who are responsible for safeguarding the rights and freedoms we enjoy as Americans, are true heroes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Peace Officers Memorial Day honors those who have made the ultimate sacrifice for the safety and security of their communities and our nation. Created by Public Law 87-726, signed by President Kennedy in 1962, this day gives us the opportunity to acknowledge and pay our respects to those who, through their courageous deeds, have fallen in the line of duty.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on Sunday, May 13, 2007, 382 names will be added to the National Law Enforcement Officers Memorial during the 19th Annual Candlelight Vigil. These 382 names include 145 officers who died in 2006, plus 237 from earlier years who had previously been lost to history. Of these 382 names, 55 represent Texas law officers who lost their lives in the line of duty, nine of them in 2006.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, one of the names of the fallen heroes to be added to the list is Officer Rodney J. Johnson of the Houston Police Department. Officer Johnson, a 12 year veteran of the Houston Police Department, was killed September 21, 2006, while taking a suspect in custody during a traffic stop. He leaves to honor his memory his beloved wife, Houston Police Department Officer Joslyn</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Johnson, and five teen-age children; three daughters and two sons, ages 14 to 19.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Officer Rodney Johnson was born in Houston and served in the U.S. Army as a military police officer until being honorably discharged in 1990. He then went to work as a corrections officer for the Texas Department of Criminal Justice and then as a jail attendant. He graduated from the Houston police academy in 1994.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a member of the department's Southeast Gang Task Force, Officer Rodney Johnson earned two Lifesaving Awards and one Medal of Valor from the state of Texas. In January 1998, Officer Rodney Johnson rescued a physically challenged driver trapped in rising floodwaters in January 1998 and later that year he rescued mentally challenged people trapped inside of a burning house.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Officer Rodney Johnson, who stood 6 feet 5 inches tall and weighed nearly 300 pounds, served on his union's board of directors. As Hans Marticiuc, the president of Officer Johnson's union stated, "he was big and he was intimidating-looking, but he was as gentle as a baby bear."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the number of officers killed in the line of duty last year declined nearly 8 percent from 2005, when there were 157 officer deaths. The 2006 figure was the lowest annual total since 1999, when 143 officers were lost.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although the number of officers killed in the line of duty has declined in recent years, the fact that one officer is killed every two-and-a-half days in our country is a sober reminder that protecting our communities and safeguarding our democracy come at a heavy price. Including this year's officers, there are now 17,917 names engraved on the Memorial, representing officers from all 50 states, the District of Columbia, U.S. territories, and federal law enforcement and military police agencies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This resolution permits the Grand Lodge of the Fraternal Order of Police and its auxiliary to sponsor a free public event, the 26th Annual National Peace Officers' Memorial Service, on the Capitol grounds on May 15, 2007. This service will honor the law enforcement officers killed in the line of duty during 2006 who have died in the line of duty, as well as the 800,000 officers who continue to serve in federal, state and local law enforcement agencies nationwide.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I urge my colleagues to join me in supporting this important resolution. I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400061" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400274" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Maine (Mr. Michaud) that the House suspend the rules and agree to the concurrent resolution, <bill type="hc" number="124">H. Con. Res. 124</bill>.</chair>
</record>
