<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1197997209" ordinal="73" title="JOY DIVINE: REMEMBERING THE LATE HON. JULIA CARSON">
  <narrative>JOY DIVINE: REMEMBERING THE LATE HON. JULIA CARSON -- (House of Representatives - December 18, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H16810]</narrative>
  <chair> Under a previous order of the House, the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Rush) is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400350" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, there have been many characterizations and descriptions of our departed colleague JULIA CARSON. But let me just tell you how I view JULIA CARSON. For me JULIA CARSON epitomized the Christian value of joy divine. Joy divine, the Bible calls it an unspeakable joy. It's the kind of joy that the Congress, the world can't give you and the world can't take it away. This joy is based on your faith. JULIA CARSON had, in my estimation, joy divine because  she understood the meaning of the Scripture when it states: "All things work together for good to those who love the Lord and those who are called according to His purpose."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What is His purpose, one might ask? Well, He makes it pretty clear in the Old Testament. He says: "What do I require of thee, o man, but to love mercy, do justly, and walk humbly with your God?"</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, JULIA CARSON had the joy divine. She epitomized it. She represented it. Because she knew that everything that we do, the things that we bind on Earth, we bind in heaven. And she was really not working for just her constituents, but she was, indeed, working for eternal life. And now she is at a better place in the heavens with her God.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And I can just, in my own imagination, imagine JULIA when she got to heaven how the angels erupted in applause because of the work that she had done while she lived here on Earth.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, JULIA CARSON did something that was almost impossible in the few years that she served in this great House. She made this great House even greater because of her commitment, her dedication, her resolve, her leadership, her insight, her compassion, those things that make one great.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I know that in heaven when she approached the throne of grace, when she approached the company of her Lord and Savior, I can hear the words spoken to her right now in the old way. I can hear her Lord and her master telling her: JULIA, servant, servant, well done. You did an extraordinary job under ordinary conditions. Servant, well done.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
