<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1173200403" ordinal="33" title="NATO FREEDOM CONSOLIDATION ACT OF 2007">
  <speaking speaker="400395" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the  bill (<bill type="h" number="987">H.R. 987</bill>) to endorse further enlargement of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) and to facilitate the timely admission of new members to NATO, and for other purposes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Tennessee (Mr. Tanner) and the gentlewoman from Florida (Ms. Ros-Lehtinen) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400395" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Tennessee?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400395" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I want to thank Chairman Lantos and my good friend, Representative Paul Gillmor from Ohio, for helping with this bill, and also the ranking member on the Foreign Affairs Committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>NATO is probably arguably one of the most important organizations now in this post-cold war period. NATO, our allies in Europe and Canada, have presently almost 17,000 troops on the ground in Kosovo and 35,000 in Afghanistan. The alliance is strong, and it is very important from the standpoint of being an international organization that can go anywhere and bring order to chaos and back it up with some military capability. That is unique and critical, in my judgment, in this post-Cold War world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>NATO itself symbolizes really the cooperative effort across the Atlantic to promote regional and area-wide stability and also to encourage fledgling democracies, particularly in Eastern Europe. This legislation before us recognizes the continuing efforts of Albania, Croatia, Georgia, Macedonia and Ukraine to become members of NATO and encourages them to continue on that path. It is a statement from the Congress that we believe that what they are doing is important, and we believe that they are  moving in the right direction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since 1989, 10 countries have joined NATO. We have seen Eastern European countries join NATO and make a remarkable contribution to the ongoing effort not only in Afghanistan and in the Balkans, but also as it relates to the furthering of democracy across some of those formerly Warsaw Pact countries. Every President has endorsed the efforts that are embodied in this bill in terms of the expansion of NATO, and this process is not yet complete.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400344" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I thank the gentleman for recognizing the great work that both Chairman Lantos as well as Congressman Gillmor of Ohio have done in paying attention to this issue of NATO.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I am so pleased to support this very timely legislation. This measure is a further step in helping to ensure that NATO, its member states and those aspiring to join this alliance are united in pursuit of European democracy and security.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since its formation in 1949, NATO's mission has been to safeguard the freedom, common heritage and civilization of its members by promoting stability and well-being in the North Atlantic area.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>The measure before us serves to express America's continued support for these important goals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The NATO Freedom Consolidation Act should help to nurture all those European states that may eventually join that alliance and give it a sense of common strategic peacekeeping goals, by encouraging them to prepare, assume and maintain the responsibilities of membership.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Specifically, the legislation calls for the timely admission of Albania, Croatia, Georgia, Macedonia, and Ukraine to NATO and authorizes security assistance for these countries in fiscal year 2008. The standards for joining NATO should not be lowered in any way and each country should be evaluated individually on the merits.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Albania, Croatia, and Macedonia have been making progress on reforms through their participation in the NATO Membership Action Plan since 2002.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Georgia and Ukraine have not yet been granted a Membership Action Plan, but these two nations are making strides in order to qualify for MAP.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The NATO Freedom Consolidation Act will provide important incentives and assistance to the countries to continue the implementation of democratic, defense and economic reforms. In these times, Madam Speaker, when we have important missions to accomplish overseas, I encourage my colleagues to vote in support of this measure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield such time as he may consume to Mr. Gillmor, who just returned from a NATO conference overseas.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400150" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I thank the gentlewoman for yielding and also for her support of this resolution. I am very pleased to join with my colleague, JOHN TANNER, in supporting this resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>NATO is our most successful military alliance, maybe the most successful military alliance in history. It won the Cold War, and it is also providing security now in many other areas of the world that are outside the exact geographical footprint of the NATO countries. For example, as Mr. Tanner pointed out, there are troops in the Balkans. There are NATO troops in Afghanistan where they are carrying the fight. Many of those NATO allies have had troops also in Iraq.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Very shortly after NATO was created in 1949, there was another group called the NATO Parliamentary Assembly to keep a close liaison between the North Atlantic Council, which is NATO, and the parliaments of those countries. Mr. Tanner and I have had the opportunity to represent the United States on that organization for I think a little over 10 years, and it has been a very valuable organization from the point of view of the United States. We have both had the opportunity at different  times to serve as vice president of it and as chairman of the Economic and Security Committee, and Mr. Tanner now leads our delegation to that group.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One of the things that I think is important about that when we go, as Republicans and Democrats, we seem to quit being Republicans and Democrats when we get outside of the United States. I would say when we meet with our European allies, the only way they know which party we belong to is when they ask us, because we speak with one voice.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But many of the nations on the other side of the Cold War east of the Iron Curtain are now members of NATO, and they are some of the strongest and most enthusiastic members. As recently as 2004, seven new countries were added, all of them Warsaw countries, bringing the NATO membership to 26: Bulgaria, Estonia, Latvia, Lithuania, Romania, Slovakia, and Slovenia.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to point out that NATO is not a club you just join. You have to earn membership in NATO. It is a military alliance. You have to meet the criteria, and you have to contribute your part to that military strength in order to be a member. As long as the new members meet those commitments, NATO will continue to be a strong alliance and one of the strongest forces for peace, stability, and democracy in the world.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400344" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400395" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, it is my pleasure to recognize a member of our delegation to the NATO PA; and by the way, Mr. Gillmor is a vice president of the NATO PA this term, and I am proud to serve with him, and now I would like to recognize a member of our delegation to the NATO Parliamentary Assembly, the gentlewoman from Missouri (Mrs. Emerson), and yield to her such time as she may consume.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400121" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="987">H.R. 987</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to tell a little story, if that is all right. Back in 1968 when I was 17 years old and a senior in high school, my high school actually organized a spring break Eastertime trip to the Soviet Union, to Czechoslovakia, to Poland, and to East Berlin. It was my first trip out of the country; it was my first trip on an airplane; and of all places to go, it was behind the Iron Curtain.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I knew a lot about NATO back then simply because we were studying it in my civics class, but I really didn't understand the importance of NATO until I went on that trip; and I didn't understand what it all meant until I went with my colleagues to my very first NATO Parliamentary Assembly meeting a few years ago.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When you went to visit countries behind the Iron Curtain back when communism was rampant, it was remarkable to go into these countries where you had no freedom, no expression of thought, no nothing. It was gray and it was dreary, and it was so sad. Even though we were able to spend, at least in Czechoslovakia, time with some students, you really understood the importance of protecting your civil rights and your freedom of speech. I really understood that for the first time because of course we  were all as kids afraid that we were being bugged in our hotel rooms and we were afraid to say anything because we thought we would get taken by the police.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Anyway, back to my first NATO meeting and we are sitting across the table from members of the Czech Republic, from Latvia, Lithuania, Estonia, countries that had always been under the iron thumb of communism and the Soviet Union, and with the fall of the Berlin Wall, of course, were able to come into their own once again. That is one of the most remarkable things about getting to known our fellow parliamentarians and understanding their great desire to join an alliance like NATO that has done  really an amazing job in protecting the North Atlantic region and our allies throughout that particular area.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I don't know that people really understand the importance of this treaty organization and how it has fostered security and cooperation for almost 60 years now.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I know, though, that the work of NATO is not complete because we have newly democratic countries such as Georgia and the Ukraine who have expressed strong interest in joining NATO, as well as other countries like Croatia and Macedonia who have actually opened constructive dialogues on their potential for NATO membership.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When you have lived or touched on what it is like to live in countries that had no freedoms or protections like NATO can offer, it is so important for us to look favorably upon their opportunity to join this important treaty organization.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is no doubt in my mind that NATO membership will be able to further our goal of extending democracy throughout the globe. Certainly <bill type="h" number="987">H.R. 987</bill> will help accomplish this goal, and I am very pleased that my colleague,  Mr. Tanner, has offered this bill; and I look forward to its passage.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400344" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time, and I thank Mr. Tanner for his leadership.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400395" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I want to thank Mrs. Emerson and Mr. Gillmor, and you, Ms. Ros-Lehtinen, for participating. This is an important bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Tennessee (Mr. Tanner) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="987">H.R. 987</bill>.</chair>
</record>
