<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1169053202" ordinal="36" title="CONGRATULATING THE GRAND VALLEY STATE UNIVERSITY LAKERS FOR WINNING THE 2006 NCAA DIVISION II FOOTBALL NATIONAL CHAMPIONSHIP">
  <speaking speaker="400364" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution (<bill type="hr" number="62">H. Res. 62</bill>) congratulating the Grand Valley State University Lakers for winning the 2006 NCAA Division II Football National Championship.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Virginia (Mr. Scott) and the gentleman from Michigan (Mr. Hoekstra) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400364" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days during which Members may insert material relevant to <bill type="hr" number="62">H. Res. 62</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Virginia?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400364" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I want to thank the gentleman from Michigan (Mr. Hoekstra) for introducing this resolution that salutes Grand Valley State for their recent victory over the Northwest Missouri State Bearcats in the NCAA Division II national football championship in December.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Grand Valley State was led by quarterback Cullen Finnerty, who completed 15 of 33 passes for 225 yards and rushed for 115 yards on 22 carries for 340 yards of total offense, becoming the first quarterback in the history of the NCAA Division II national football  championship to pass for more than 200 yards and rush for more than 100 yards.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The game also saw tremendous plays by Bill Brechin, who made two first quarter interceptions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would also point out that Northwest Missouri State University also played an excellent game, and I congratulate them for their effort.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Lakers are no strangers to this championship, having won in 2002, 2003 and 2005. It is also the second year that the Lakers have defeated the Bearcats in a championship game.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Much is due to the coaching of Chuck Martin, who was named Division II Coach of the Year for the second year. Clearly, the Lakers deserve to be recognized by the House for their outstanding accomplishments on the football field, and I urge my colleagues to support this resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400182" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to thank my colleague from Virginia for bringing forward this resolution today. I think it is a wonderful opportunity to educate the colleague from Virginia on the talents that we have in the State of Michigan, especially in western Michigan. I am excited to see how well versed he has become about the Grand Valley State University football team. As he indicated, we rise today to congratulate the student athletes on the Grand Valley State University Lakers 2006 football team.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On December 16, 2006, the Lakers football team won the NCAA Division II football national championship by defeating the Northwest Missouri State University Bearcats 17-14. The Grand Valley State University football program has now won championships in 2002, 2003, 2005 and 2006.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The victory capped another storybook season for Coach Chuck Martin. He has coached his team to a 23-3 record, including a 10-1 post-season record after assuming coaching responsibility after a successful stint as the Lakers' defensive coordinator.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Grand Valley State University seniors finished their 4-year run with the Lakers with a 52-4 record, making them the all-time winningest senior class in all of NCAA history.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>Grand Valley student athletes have displayed great strength, ability and resolve during the 2006 season. They have made the great State of Michigan proud once again.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I encourage all Members to support the passage of <bill type="hr" number="62">H. Res. 62</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I include for the RECORD the full roster of this national championship team and their coaching staff.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Chuck Martin--head coach.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Steve Brockelbank--assistant head coach/OL/rec. coordinator.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Matt Pawlowski--defensive coordinator/defensive backs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Todd Kolster--offensive coordinator/quarterbacks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Matt Mitchell--linebackers/strength &amp;amp; conditioning.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>William Pascol--running backs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Jim Schaak--kickers/tight/ends.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Matt Yoches--defensive line.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dan Fodrocy--graduate assistant.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Adam McClain--graduate assistant</paragraph>
    <paragraph>David Sartin--graduate assistant.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dan Price--video coordinator.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400119" topic="COACHES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today in support of <bill type="hr" number="62">H. Res. 62</bill>, a resolution congratulating the Grand Valley State University Lakers for winning the 2006 NCAA Division II Football National Championship.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Head Coach Chuck Martin and his team have helped to bring national reknown to GVSU's campuses in Allendale, Grand Rapids and throughout West Michigan with their excellence on the field. Over the past five years, the Lakers have won four National Championships in their division, a feat that has been duplicated at no other level of college football in the same time span.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The senior class of this team compiled a four-year record of 52-4, making them the winningest senior class of football players in NCAA history. Led by quarterback Cullin Finnerty, Eric Fowler and Mike McFadden--each of them named first-team Little All-America players by the Associated Press--the Lakers dominated their competition to an undefeated 15-0 season, culminating in a 17-14 championship victory over the Northwest Missouri State University Bearcats on December 16, 2006, in Florence, Alabama.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The game was witnessed by 7,000 fans in the stadium and by a worldwide audience including our soldiers in Iraq and elsewhere, who watched the game on the Armed Forces TV Network. One GVSU official, my former press secretary, Chris Barbee, reported hearing from two soldiers in Iraq congratulating the team on its victory.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Laker football team is emblematic of Grand Valley State University as a whole--a thriving, bustling university in West Michigan with more than 23,000 students and nearly 2,000 faculty and staff. The university, led by its new president Thomas J. Haas, is striving for excellence at all levels academic and athletic alike.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congratulations again to Grand Valley State University, Coach Martin and his staff, and all the players, support staff and fans who made this championship a reality.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400158" topic="COACHES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, today we will be considering <bill type="hr" number="62">H. Res. 62</bill>, a resolution congratulating the Grand Valley State University Lakers for winning the 2006 NCAA Division II Football National Championship. And although I will be supporting this resolution out of respect for my friend and colleague, Congressman PETER HOEKSTRA, I would like to take a moment to recognize the Northwest Missouri State University Bearcats.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is the second consecutive year Northwest Missouri State University has made a run for the championship. Unfortunately, the football Gods were not kind to them at the championship game this year. However, the Northwest Missouri State University Bearcats are an exceptional football team with great team spirit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph> Mr. Speaker, I proudly ask you to join me in recognizing the Northwest Missouri State University Bearcats football team for an outstanding 2006 season, and I look forward to cheering them on to the NCAA Division II Football Championship again next year.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400182" topic="COACHES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400364" topic="COACHES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Virginia (Mr. Scott) that the House suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, <bill type="hr" number="62">H. Res. 62</bill>.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds of those voting have responded in the affirmative.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400364" topic="COACHES">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this question will be postponed.</chair>
</record>
