<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1207756802" ordinal="42" title="MOTION TO GO TO CONFERENCE ON H.R. 2419, FOOD AND ENERGY SECURITY ACT OF 2007">
  <narrative>MOTION TO GO TO CONFERENCE ON <bill type="h" number="2419">H.R. 2419</bill>, FOOD AND ENERGY SECURITY ACT OF 2007 -- (House of Representatives - April 09, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H2119]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400183" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, by direction of the Committee on Agriculture, I move to take from the Speaker's table the bill (<bill type="h" number="2419">H.R. 2419</bill>) to provide for the continuation of agricultural programs through fiscal year 2012, and for other purposes, with a Senate amendment thereto, disagree to the Senate amendment, and agree to the conference asked by the Senate.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The motion was agreed to.</narrative>
  <narrative>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</narrative>
  <narrative>The Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>Mr. Goodlatte moves that the managers on the part of the House at the conference on the disagreeing votes on the two Houses on the Senate amendment to the bill <bill type="h" number="2419">H.R. 2419</bill> be instructed, within the scope of the conference, to--</narrative>
  <narrative>Disagree to any provision which will result in an increase in taxes.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 7 of rule XXII, the gentleman from Virginia (Mr. Goodlatte) and the gentleman from Pennsylvania (Mr. Holden) each will control 30 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Virginia.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400154" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I offer this motion to instruct conferees to make clear that tax increases do not belong in a farm bill. While there are still some funding issues that need to be worked out and many policy decisions to be negotiated, these instructions are very clear in stating that tax increases cannot be used to fund the remaining elements of the farm bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again I will read the actual language of the motion, which is that the managers on the part of the House at the conference on the disagreeing votes on the two Houses on the Senate amendment to the bill <bill type="h" number="2419">H.R. 2419</bill> be instructed within the scope of the conference to disagree to any provision which will result in an increase in taxes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These instructions are very clear in stating that tax increases cannot be used to fund the remaining elements of the farm bill. Farm bills have long enjoyed bipartisan support in this body, and it would be devastating to American agriculture to add a divisive element such as tax increases to this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This conference has been a long time coming, and we are ready to put together a reform-minded farm bill that addresses a variety of issues, including conservation, nutrition, energy, rural development, fruits and vegetables, and forestry, while maintaining a strong safety net for America's farmers and ranchers so that they can continue to meet the growing demand for their products in the global market.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>This motion is very important. I expect that there will be strong bipartisan support for this motion, and it's important because we have been down this road of attempting to pass a farm bill for quite some time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When the bill came out of the House Agriculture Committee last summer, many of the Members on this side of the aisle expected that the amount of money that was added outside of the committee's jurisdiction would not constitute tax increases. We are very disappointed to find that it did include tax increases, and that has definitely bogged down this process for the many, many, many months since.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have now had some very good discussions with members of other committees that are involved in making sure that we have the ability to move forward and to pay for measures that exceed the amount of money within the jurisdiction of the Agriculture Committee, and those do not include tax increases.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is, I think, an important statement to be made here and in the other body that we can complete this work without tax increases. We do not need to repeat the mistakes that were made earlier in that regard.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also think it's very clear that the President of the United States has been very strong in his statement that this bill would be vetoed if it included tax increases. While we continue to work with the administration on a number of other issues, we are making progress there as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, this would reaffirm, I think, the kind of bipartisan support that it takes to pass a farm bill and get it signed into law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this motion to instruct.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400183" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>I want to commend the ranking member of the committee for the hard work that he has done with the chairman of the committee, who is now in a meeting with leadership, as we are trying to iron out the final details of a long process where a lot of people, particularly Chairman Peterson and Ranking Member Goodlatte, have put a lot of time and effort to get to this spot in the process where we are. We are hoping that we can meet our deadline of next Friday to see that  we can have this conference report completed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The ranking member has correctly evaluated the process that we have gone through as we try to get to this process, and we are in agreement. We believe that we can pass this farm bill without any tax increases.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Before I yield back the balance of my time, Mr. Speaker, I yield 2 minutes to the gentleman from Wisconsin (Mr. Kind).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400218" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>I thank my friend from Pennsylvania for yielding me this time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, we need a farm bill, and we need it soon. Planting season is  starting throughout the country, but I would hope that at the end of the process we get a good farm bill rather than a bad farm bill, one that recognizes current market prices and the conditions that farmers are experiencing out there. It was a little more bold on reform, especially under those title I commodity programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The President has made it clear that he won't find a farm bill acceptable that does call for an increase in taxes in order to pay for it. I and others who have been a part of a reform effort, especially with the commodity subsidy programs, believe that we are capable of producing a farm bill that maintains an important safety net for family farmers, but also protects the important priorities that are also a part of the farm bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It's based on the philosophy of let's help family farmers when they need it, let's not when they don't. Clearly with commodity prices at or near record highs in the marketplace today, part of it driven by the biofuels portion in this country, a large part of it due to the increased global demand, many of us are suspecting that these prices are going to continue. That's been great for the rural economy, and it's been great for farm income.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But let us also take this opportunity then of starting to move forward on some commonsense reasonable reforms of these commodity programs, while still maintaining a safety net in the farm bill, but without jeopardizing the conservation title or nutrition or specialty crops, rural economic development programs and renewable fuel investment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would hope that my colleagues support this motion to instruct. I think it's the right thing to do. I think at the end of the day, if we are going to have a bipartisan bill that the President feels comfortable in doing, one of the goals that we have to strive for is a bill that does not call for an increase in taxes in light of record high market prices.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I commend the gentleman for offering this motion and encourage support on the vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400154" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would just say to the gentleman from Pennsylvania that I very much appreciate his kind words. We have worked in a very bipartisan fashion. The chairman of the committee has been very dedicated to working with us, and we very much appreciate that, as have the other members of the committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We now look forward to going to conference and have the opportunity to work together as we work with the other body to try to work out what are still many, many hurdles. A lot of the people have been excited that we are going to conference, and we need to make sure they understand that we are not done with this, but we do have some good ideas that we are going to be able to move forward with. I think that's very encouraging.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would also say to the gentleman from Wisconsin that I too share his desire for reform. This farm bill will contain a lot of reform, and it will result in substantial savings to the taxpayers of the country, because, in fact, that has already occurred.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The current farm bill, if it were to be perpetuated, which I do not support, but if it were to be perpetuated, would cost $58 billion less for the next 5 years than it cost for the last 5. So the fact of the matter is there is already substantial savings being achieved.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are, nonetheless, additional reforms that I and many others support as we move to conference with this legislation, and I think the outcome will be one that maintains the safety net for America's farmers and ranchers, but makes a number of very important reforms in a number of different areas and enhances those new areas that I know the gentleman has championed and others, like conservation, which I very much join him in supporting and making sure that the nutritional needs of many in this  country are met, and other purposes. We can do that without tax increases, and, as a result, I think this is a very appropriate motion to instruct to adopt today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400183" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>I would just like to thank the ranking member for his comments and also to say to my friend from Wisconsin, who served on the committee, that he understands that we are fortunate to serve on one of the most bipartisan committees in the Congress. We do not have Democrat and Republican disagreements on agriculture, but we do have regional ones.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe that the final product will reflect those regional differences and also will have a significant amount of reform that all of us are going to be able to go home and talk about that we did something positive in this farm bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the previous question is ordered on the motion to instruct.</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <chair> The question is on the motion to instruct.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and the Speaker pro tempore announced that the ayes appeared to have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400154" topic="MOTION TO INSTRUCT OFFERED BY MR.">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I object to the vote on the ground that a quorum is not present and make the point of order that a quorum is not present.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Evidently a quorum is not present.</chair>
  <chair>The Sergeant at Arms will notify absent Members.</chair>
  <chair>Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX, this 15-minute vote on the motion to instruct will be followed by 5-minute votes on motions to suspend the rules with respect to <bill type="h" number="5489">H.R. 5489</bill> and <bill type="h" number="5472">H.R. 5472</bill>.</chair>
  <chair>The vote was taken by electronic device, and there were--yeas 400, nays 11, not voting 19, as follows:</chair>
  <chair>[Roll No. 175]</chair>
  <chair>Ackerman</chair>
  <chair>Aderholt</chair>
  <chair>Akin</chair>
  <chair>Alexander</chair>
  <chair>Allen</chair>
  <chair>Altmire</chair>
  <chair>Andrews</chair>
  <chair>Arcuri</chair>
  <chair>Baca</chair>
  <chair>Bachmann</chair>
  <chair>Baird</chair>
  <chair>Baldwin</chair>
  <chair>Barrett (SC)</chair>
  <chair>Barrow</chair>
  <chair>Bartlett (MD)</chair>
  <chair>Barton (TX)</chair>
  <chair>Bean</chair>
  <chair>Becerra</chair>
  <chair>Berkley</chair>
  <chair>Berman</chair>
  <chair>Berry</chair>
  <chair>Biggert</chair>
  <chair>Bilbray</chair>
  <chair>Bilirakis</chair>
  <chair>Bishop (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Bishop (NY)</chair>
  <chair>Bishop (UT)</chair>
  <chair>Blackburn</chair>
  <chair>Blunt</chair>
  <chair>Boehner</chair>
  <chair>Bonner</chair>
  <chair>Bono Mack</chair>
  <chair>Boozman</chair>
  <chair>Boren</chair>
  <chair>Boswell</chair>
  <chair>Boucher</chair>
  <chair>Boustany</chair>
  <chair>Boyd (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Boyda (KS)</chair>
  <chair>Brady (PA)</chair>
  <chair>Brady (TX)</chair>
  <chair>Braley (IA)</chair>
  <chair>Broun (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Brown (SC)</chair>
  <chair>Brown, Corrine</chair>
  <chair>Brown-Waite, Ginny</chair>
  <chair>Buchanan</chair>
  <chair>Burgess</chair>
  <chair>Burton (IN)</chair>
  <chair>Butterfield</chair>
  <chair>Calvert</chair>
  <chair>Camp (MI)</chair>
  <chair>Campbell (CA)</chair>
  <chair>Cannon</chair>
  <chair>Cantor</chair>
  <chair>Capito</chair>
  <chair>Capps</chair>
  <chair>Cardoza</chair>
  <chair>Carnahan</chair>
  <chair>Carney</chair>
  <chair>Carson</chair>
  <chair>Carter</chair>
  <chair>Castle</chair>
  <chair>Castor</chair>
  <chair>Chabot</chair>
  <chair>Chandler</chair>
  <chair>Clarke</chair>
  <chair>Clay</chair>
  <chair>Cleaver</chair>
  <chair>Clyburn</chair>
  <chair>Coble</chair>
  <chair>Cohen</chair>
  <chair>Cole (OK)</chair>
  <chair>Conaway</chair>
  <chair>Conyers</chair>
  <chair>Cooper</chair>
  <chair>Costa</chair>
  <chair>Costello</chair>
  <chair>Courtney</chair>
  <chair>Cramer</chair>
  <chair>Crenshaw</chair>
  <chair>Crowley</chair>
  <chair>Cubin</chair>
  <chair>Cuellar</chair>
  <chair>Culberson</chair>
  <chair>Cummings</chair>
  <chair>Davis (AL)</chair>
  <chair>Davis (CA)</chair>
  <chair>Davis (IL)</chair>
  <chair>Davis (KY)</chair>
  <chair>Davis, David</chair>
  <chair>Davis, Lincoln</chair>
  <chair>Davis, Tom</chair>
  <chair>Deal (GA)</chair>
  <chair>DeGette</chair>
  <chair>Delahunt</chair>
  <chair>DeLauro</chair>
  <chair>Dent</chair>
  <chair>Diaz-Balart, L.</chair>
  <chair>Diaz-Balart, M.</chair>
  <chair>Dicks</chair>
  <chair>Dingell</chair>
  <chair>Doggett</chair>
  <chair>Donnelly</chair>
  <chair>Doolittle</chair>
  <chair>Doyle</chair>
  <chair>Drake</chair>
  <chair>Dreier</chair>
  <chair>Duncan</chair>
  <chair>Ehlers</chair>
  <chair>Ellsworth</chair>
  <chair>Emanuel</chair>
  <chair>Emerson</chair>
  <chair>Engel</chair>
  <chair>English (PA)</chair>
  <chair>Eshoo</chair>
  <chair>Etheridge</chair>
  <chair>Everett</chair>
  <chair>Fallin</chair>
  <chair>Farr</chair>
  <chair>Fattah</chair>
  <chair>Feeney</chair>
  <chair>Filner</chair>
  <chair>Flake</chair>
  <chair>Forbes</chair>
  <chair>Fortenberry</chair>
  <chair>Fossella</chair>
  <chair>Foster</chair>
  <chair>Foxx</chair>
  <chair>Franks (AZ)</chair>
  <chair>Frelinghuysen</chair>
  <chair>Gallegly</chair>
  <chair>Garrett (NJ)</chair>
  <chair>Gerlach</chair>
  <chair>Gilchrest</chair>
  <chair>Gillibrand</chair>
  <chair>Gingrey</chair>
  <chair>Gohmert</chair>
  <chair>Gonzalez</chair>
  <chair>Goode</chair>
  <chair>Goodlatte</chair>
  <chair>Gordon</chair>
  <chair>Graves</chair>
  <chair>Green, Al</chair>
  <chair>Green, Gene</chair>
  <chair>Grijalva</chair>
  <chair>Gutierrez</chair>
  <chair>Hall (NY)</chair>
  <chair>Hall (TX)</chair>
  <chair>Hare</chair>
  <chair>Harman</chair>
  <chair>Hastings (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Hastings (WA)</chair>
  <chair>Hayes</chair>
  <chair>Heller</chair>
  <chair>Hensarling</chair>
  <chair>Herger</chair>
  <chair>Herseth Sandlin</chair>
  <chair>Higgins</chair>
  <chair>Hill</chair>
  <chair>Hinchey</chair>
  <chair>Hinojosa</chair>
  <chair>Hirono</chair>
  <chair>Hobson</chair>
  <chair>Hodes</chair>
  <chair>Hoekstra</chair>
  <chair>Holden</chair>
  <chair>Holt</chair>
  <chair>Honda</chair>
  <chair>Hoyer</chair>
  <chair>Hulshof</chair>
  <chair>Hunter</chair>
  <chair>Inglis (SC)</chair>
  <chair>Inslee</chair>
  <chair>Israel</chair>
  <chair>Issa</chair>
  <chair>Jackson (IL)</chair>
  <chair>Jackson-Lee (TX)</chair>
  <chair>Jefferson</chair>
  <chair>Johnson (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Johnson (IL)</chair>
  <chair>Johnson, E. B.</chair>
  <chair>Johnson, Sam</chair>
  <chair>Jones (NC)</chair>
  <chair>Jones (OH)</chair>
  <chair>Jordan</chair>
  <chair>Kagen</chair>
  <chair>Kanjorski</chair>
  <chair>Kaptur</chair>
  <chair>Keller</chair>
  <chair>Kennedy</chair>
  <chair>Kildee</chair>
  <chair>Kilpatrick</chair>
  <chair>Kind</chair>
  <chair>King (IA)</chair>
  <chair>King (NY)</chair>
  <chair>Kingston</chair>
  <chair>Kirk</chair>
  <chair>Klein (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Kline (MN)</chair>
  <chair>Knollenberg</chair>
  <chair>Kucinich</chair>
  <chair>Kuhl (NY)</chair>
  <chair>LaHood</chair>
  <chair>Lamborn</chair>
  <chair>Lampson</chair>
  <chair>Langevin</chair>
  <chair>Larsen (WA)</chair>
  <chair>Latham</chair>
  <chair>LaTourette</chair>
  <chair>Latta</chair>
  <chair>Lee</chair>
  <chair>Levin</chair>
  <chair>Lewis (CA)</chair>
  <chair>Lewis (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Lewis (KY)</chair>
  <chair>Linder</chair>
  <chair>Lipinski</chair>
  <chair>LoBiondo</chair>
  <chair>Loebsack</chair>
  <chair>Lofgren, Zoe</chair>
  <chair>Lowey</chair>
  <chair>Lucas</chair>
  <chair>Lungren, Daniel E.</chair>
  <chair>Lynch</chair>
  <chair>Mack</chair>
  <chair>Mahoney (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Maloney (NY)</chair>
  <chair>Manzullo</chair>
  <chair>Marchant</chair>
  <chair>Markey</chair>
  <chair>Marshall</chair>
  <chair>Matheson</chair>
  <chair>Matsui</chair>
  <chair>McCarthy (CA)</chair>
  <chair>McCarthy (NY)</chair>
  <chair>McCaul (TX)</chair>
  <chair>McCollum (MN)</chair>
  <chair>McCotter</chair>
  <chair>McCrery</chair>
  <chair>McHenry</chair>
  <chair>McHugh</chair>
  <chair>McIntyre</chair>
  <chair>McKeon</chair>
  <chair>McMorris Rodgers</chair>
  <chair>McNerney</chair>
  <chair>McNulty</chair>
  <chair>Meek (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Meeks (NY)</chair>
  <chair>Melancon</chair>
  <chair>Mica</chair>
  <chair>Michaud</chair>
  <chair>Miller (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Miller (MI)</chair>
  <chair>Miller (NC)</chair>
  <chair>Miller, Gary</chair>
  <chair>Miller, George</chair>
  <chair>Mitchell</chair>
  <chair>Mollohan</chair>
  <chair>Moore (KS)</chair>
  <chair>Moore (WI)</chair>
  <chair>Moran (KS)</chair>
  <chair>Moran (VA)</chair>
  <chair>Murphy (CT)</chair>
  <chair>Murphy, Patrick</chair>
  <chair>Murphy, Tim</chair>
  <chair>Murtha</chair>
  <chair>Musgrave</chair>
  <chair>Nadler</chair>
  <chair>Napolitano</chair>
  <chair>Neal (MA)</chair>
  <chair>Neugebauer</chair>
  <chair>Nunes</chair>
  <chair>Oberstar</chair>
  <chair>Obey</chair>
  <chair>Ortiz</chair>
  <chair>Pallone</chair>
  <chair>Pascrell</chair>
  <chair>Pastor</chair>
  <chair>Paul</chair>
  <chair>Pearce</chair>
  <chair>Pence</chair>
  <chair>Perlmutter</chair>
  <chair>Peterson (MN)</chair>
  <chair>Petri</chair>
  <chair>Pickering</chair>
  <chair>Pitts</chair>
  <chair>Platts</chair>
  <chair>Poe</chair>
  <chair>Pomeroy</chair>
  <chair>Porter</chair>
  <chair>Price (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Price (NC)</chair>
  <chair>Pryce (OH)</chair>
  <chair>Putnam</chair>
  <chair>Radanovich</chair>
  <chair>Rahall</chair>
  <chair>Ramstad</chair>
  <chair>Regula</chair>
  <chair>Rehberg</chair>
  <chair>Reichert</chair>
  <chair>Renzi</chair>
  <chair>Reyes</chair>
  <chair>Reynolds</chair>
  <chair>Richardson</chair>
  <chair>Rodriguez</chair>
  <chair>Rogers (AL)</chair>
  <chair>Rogers (KY)</chair>
  <chair>Rogers (MI)</chair>
  <chair>Rohrabacher</chair>
  <chair>Ros-Lehtinen</chair>
  <chair>Roskam</chair>
  <chair>Ross</chair>
  <chair>Rothman</chair>
  <chair>Roybal-Allard</chair>
  <chair>Royce</chair>
  <chair>Ruppersberger</chair>
  <chair>Ryan (OH)</chair>
  <chair>Ryan (WI)</chair>
  <chair>Sali</chair>
  <chair>S&#xE1;nchez, Linda T.</chair>
  <chair>Sanchez, Loretta</chair>
  <chair>Sarbanes</chair>
  <chair>Saxton</chair>
  <chair>Schakowsky</chair>
  <chair>Schiff</chair>
  <chair>Schmidt</chair>
  <chair>Schwartz</chair>
  <chair>Scott (GA)</chair>
  <chair>Scott (VA)</chair>
  <chair>Sensenbrenner</chair>
  <chair>Serrano</chair>
  <chair>Sessions</chair>
  <chair>Sestak</chair>
  <chair>Shadegg</chair>
  <chair>Shea-Porter</chair>
  <chair>Sherman</chair>
  <chair>Shimkus</chair>
  <chair>Shuler</chair>
  <chair>Shuster</chair>
  <chair>Simpson</chair>
  <chair>Skelton</chair>
  <chair>Slaughter</chair>
  <chair>Smith (NE)</chair>
  <chair>Smith (NJ)</chair>
  <chair>Smith (TX)</chair>
  <chair>Smith (WA)</chair>
  <chair>Snyder</chair>
  <chair>Solis</chair>
  <chair>Souder</chair>
  <chair>Space</chair>
  <chair>Spratt</chair>
  <chair>Stupak</chair>
  <chair>Sullivan</chair>
  <chair>Sutton</chair>
  <chair>Tancredo</chair>
  <chair>Tanner</chair>
  <chair>Tauscher</chair>
  <chair>Taylor</chair>
  <chair>Terry</chair>
  <chair>Thompson (CA)</chair>
  <chair>Thompson (MS)</chair>
  <chair>Thornberry</chair>
  <chair>Tiahrt</chair>
  <chair>Tiberi</chair>
  <chair>Tierney</chair>
  <chair>Towns</chair>
  <chair>Tsongas</chair>
  <chair>Turner</chair>
  <chair>Udall (CO)</chair>
  <chair>Udall (NM)</chair>
  <chair>Upton</chair>
  <chair>Van Hollen</chair>
  <chair>Vel&#xE1;zquez</chair>
  <chair>Visclosky</chair>
  <chair>Walberg</chair>
  <chair>Walden (OR)</chair>
  <chair>Walsh (NY)</chair>
  <chair>Walz (MN)</chair>
  <chair>Wamp</chair>
  <chair>Wasserman Schultz</chair>
  <chair>Watson</chair>
  <chair>Watt</chair>
  <chair>Weiner</chair>
  <chair>Welch (VT)</chair>
  <chair>Weldon (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Weller</chair>
  <chair>Westmoreland</chair>
  <chair>Wexler</chair>
  <chair>Whitfield (KY)</chair>
  <chair>Wilson (NM)</chair>
  <chair>Wilson (OH)</chair>
  <chair>Wilson (SC)</chair>
  <chair>Wittman (VA)</chair>
  <chair>Wolf</chair>
  <chair>Wu</chair>
  <chair>Wynn</chair>
  <chair>Yarmuth</chair>
  <chair>Young (AK)</chair>
  <chair>Young (FL)</chair>
  <chair>Blumenauer</chair>
  <chair>Capuano</chair>
  <chair>DeFazio</chair>
  <chair>Ellison</chair>
  <chair>Frank (MA)</chair>
  <chair>McDermott</chair>
  <chair>McGovern</chair>
  <chair>Olver</chair>
  <chair>Payne</chair>
  <chair>Waters</chair>
  <chair>Woolsey</chair>
  <chair>Abercrombie</chair>
  <chair>Bachus</chair>
  <chair>Buyer</chair>
  <chair>Edwards</chair>
  <chair>Ferguson</chair>
  <chair>Giffords</chair>
  <chair>Granger</chair>
  <chair>Hooley</chair>
  <chair>Larson (CT)</chair>
  <chair>Myrick</chair>
  <chair>Peterson (PA)</chair>
  <chair>Rangel</chair>
  <chair>Rush</chair>
  <chair>Salazar</chair>
  <chair>Shays</chair>
  <chair>Sires</chair>
  <chair>Stark</chair>
  <chair>Stearns</chair>
  <chair>Waxman</chair>
  <chair/>
  <chair>Ms. WOOLSEY and Messrs. DeFAZIO and PAYNE changed their vote from "yea" to "nay."</chair>
  <chair>Messrs. NADLER and CLYBURN changed their vote from "nay" to "yea."</chair>
  <chair>So the motion to instruct was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The result of the vote was announced as above recorded.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
  <chair>Stated for:</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400388" topic="NOT VOTING--19">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on rollcall No. 175, I was unavoidably detained. Had I been present, I would have voted "yea."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
