<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1191945602" ordinal="17" title="CHARLES H. HENDRIX POST OFFICE BUILDING">
  <narrative>CHARLES H. HENDRIX POST OFFICE BUILDING -- (House of Representatives - October 09, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H11327]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="3518">H.R. 3518</bill>) to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 1430 South Highway 29 in Cantonment, Florida, as the "Charles H. Hendix Post Office Building," as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="3518">H.R. 3518</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled, &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. CHARLES H. HENDRIX POST OFFICE BUILDING.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Designation.--The facility of the United States Postal Service located at 1430 South Highway 29 in Cantonment, Florida, shall be known and designated as the "Charles H. Hendrix Post Office Building".</narrative>
  <narrative> (b) References.--Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the facility referred to in subsection (a) shall be deemed to be a reference to the "Charles H. Hendrix Post Office Building".&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Davis) and the gentleman from Virginia (Mr. Tom Davis) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Illinois.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days within which to revise and extend their remarks.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Illinois?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, as a member of the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, I am pleased to join my colleagues in the consideration of <bill type="h" number="3518">H.R. 3518</bill>, which names the postal facility in Cantonment, Florida, after Charles H. Hendrix.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="3518">H.R. 3518</bill>, which was introduced by Representative JEFF MILLER on September 10, 2007, was reported from the Oversight Committee on September 20, 2007, by a voice vote. This measure has the support of the entire Florida congressional delegation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, Mr. Charles Hendrix is the former Postmaster of the Cantonment Post Office and worked there for 37 years. He retired from the postal service in 1986. Mr. Hendrix was a charter member of the Molino Volunteer Fire Department where he served as fire chief and a member of the Cantonment Rotary Club since 1962. He was a prominent and respected resident of the Cantonment and Molino communities in Florida.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I commend my colleague, Representative Jeff Miller, for introducing this legislation, and I urge its swift passage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400098" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I rise to pay tribute to an outstanding public servant, community leader and family man. It is fitting that <bill type="h" number="3518">H.R. 3518</bill> requests the designation of the post office in Cantonment, Florida, as the Charles H. Hendrix Post Office. Mr. Hendrix retired from the postal service after 37 years of service. Starting his career as a mail carrier and ultimately serving as the post master of the Cantonment post office, he was the type of employee that exemplifies loyalty and dedication.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A life-long resident of Molino, Florida, Mr. Hendrix over the years served his community in many ways. He was a member of the Highland Baptist Church his entire life, where he served as Sunday School superintendent. He was church treasurer and chairman of the board of deacons at the time of his death. He was also a member of the Cantonment Rotary Club since 1962.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He served one year as president and was an active member of the club service committee. He was also a charter member of the Molino Volunteer Fire Department, where he served as fire chief, assistant fire chief, and later as secretary of the fire department's board of directors, once again showing his dedication and service to others in the community.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of Mr. Hendrix's service to the community, he is remembered with appreciation as a man of great integrity and willingness to help others. It is for these reasons that we name the Cantonment, Florida post office for Charles Harold Hendrix.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400093" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Illinois (Mr. Davis) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="3518">H.R. 3518</bill>, as amended.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the bill, as amended, was passed.</chair>
  <chair>The title was amended so as to read: "A Bill to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 1430 South Highway 29 in Cantonment, Florida, as the `Charles H. Hendrix Post Office Building' ".</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
