<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1207670402" ordinal="29" title="SAFETY OF SENIORS ACT OF 2007">
  <narrative>SAFETY OF SENIORS ACT OF 2007 -- (House of Representatives - April 08, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H2034]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400062" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the Senate bill (<bill type="s" number="845">S. 845</bill>) to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to expand and intensify programs with respect to research and related activities concerning elder falls.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the Senate bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the Senate bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="s" number="845">S. 845</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "Safety of Seniors Act of 2007".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. AMENDMENTS TO THE PUBLIC HEALTH SERVICE ACT.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Part J of title III of the Public Health Service Act (42 U.S.C. 280b et seq.) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) by redesignating section 393B (as added by section 1401 of Public Law 106-386) as section 393C and transferring such section so that it appears after section 393B (as added by section 1301 of Public Law 106-310); and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) by inserting after section 393C (as redesignated by paragraph (1)) the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;"SEC. 393D. PREVENTION OF FALLS AMONG OLDER ADULTS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(a) Public Education.--The Secretary may--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(1) oversee and support a national education campaign to be carried out by a nonprofit organization with experience in designing and implementing national injury prevention programs, that is directed principally to older adults, their families, and  health care providers, and that focuses on reducing falls among older adults and preventing repeat falls; and</narrative>
  <narrative> "(2) award grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements to qualified organizations, institutions, or consortia of qualified organizations and institutions, specializing, or demonstrating expertise, in falls or fall prevention, for the purpose of organizing State-level coalitions of appropriate State and local agencies, safety, health, senior citizen, and other organizations to design and carry out local education campaigns, focusing on reducing falls among older adults and preventing repeat  falls.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(b) Research.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(1) IN GENERAL.--The Secretary may--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(A) conduct and support research to--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(i) improve the identification of older adults who have a high risk of falling;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(ii) improve data collection and analysis to identify fall risk and protective factors;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(iii) design, implement, and evaluate the most effective fall prevention interventions;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(iv) improve strategies that are proven to be effective in reducing falls by tailoring these strategies to specific populations of older adults;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(v) conduct research in order to maximize the dissemination of proven, effective fall prevention interventions;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(vi) intensify proven interventions to prevent falls among older adults;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(vii) improve the diagnosis, treatment, and rehabilitation of elderly fall victims and older adults at high risk for falls; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(viii) assess the risk of falls occurring in various settings;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(B) conduct research concerning barriers to the adoption of proven interventions with respect to the prevention of falls among older adults;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(C) conduct research to develop, implement, and evaluate the most effective approaches to reducing falls among high-risk older adults living in communities and long-term care and assisted living facilities; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(D) evaluate the effectiveness of community programs designed to prevent falls among older adults.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(2) EDUCATIONAL SUPPORT.--The Secretary, either directly or through awarding grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements to qualified organizations, institutions, or consortia of qualified organizations and institutions, specializing, or demonstrating expertise, in falls or fall prevention, may provide professional education for physicians and allied health professionals, and aging service providers in fall prevention, evaluation, and management.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(c) Demonstration Projects.--The Secretary may carry out the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(1) Oversee and support demonstration and research projects to be carried out by qualified organizations, institutions, or consortia of qualified organizations and institutions, specializing, or demonstrating expertise, in falls or fall prevention, in the following areas:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(A) A multistate demonstration project assessing the utility of targeted fall risk screening and referral programs.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(B) Programs designed for community-dwelling older adults that utilize multicomponent fall intervention approaches, including physical activity, medication assessment and reduction when possible, vision enhancement, and home modification strategies.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(C) Programs that are targeted to new fall victims who are at a high risk for second falls and which are designed to maximize independence and quality of life for older adults, particularly those older adults with functional limitations.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(D) Private sector and public-private partnerships to develop technologies to prevent falls among older adults and prevent or reduce injuries if falls occur.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(2)(A) Award grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements to qualified organizations, institutions, or consortia of qualified organizations and institutions, specializing, or demonstrating expertise, in falls or fall prevention, to design, implement, and evaluate fall prevention programs using proven intervention strategies in residential and institutional settings.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(B) Award 1 or more grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements to 1 or more qualified organizations, institutions, or consortia of qualified organizations and institutions, specializing, or demonstrating expertise, in falls or fall prevention, in order to carry out a multistate demonstration project to implement and evaluate fall prevention programs using proven intervention strategies designed for single and multifamily residential settings with high concentrations of older adults, including--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(i) identifying high-risk populations;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(ii) evaluating residential facilities;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(iii) conducting screening to identify high-risk individuals;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(iv) providing fall assessment and risk reduction interventions and counseling;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(v) coordinating services with health care and social service providers; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(vi) coordinating post-fall treatment and rehabilitation.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(3) Award 1 or more grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements to qualified organizations, institutions, or consortia of qualified organizations and institutions, specializing, or demonstrating expertise, in falls or fall prevention, to conduct evaluations of the effectiveness of the demonstration projects described in this subsection.</narrative>
  <narrative> "(d) Priority.--In awarding grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements under this section, the Secretary may give priority to entities that explore the use of cost-sharing with respect to activities funded under the grant, contract, or agreement to ensure the institutional commitment of the recipients of such assistance to the projects funded under the grant, contract, or agreement. Such non-Federal cost sharing contributions may be provided directly or through donations from public  or private entities and may be in cash or in-kind, fairly evaluated, including plant, equipment, or services.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(e) Study of Effects of Falls on Health Care Costs.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(1) IN GENERAL.--The Secretary may conduct a review of the effects of falls on health care costs, the potential for reducing falls, and the most effective strategies for reducing health care costs associated with falls.</narrative>
  <narrative> "(2) REPORT.--If the Secretary conducts the review under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall, not later than 36 months after the date of enactment of the Safety of Seniors Act of 2007, submit to Congress a report describing the findings of the Secretary in conducting such review.".&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from California (Mrs. Capps) and the gentleman from Georgia (Mr. Deal) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentlewoman from California.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400062" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the Senate bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from California?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400062" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I rise in strong support of Senate bill 845, the Safety of Seniors Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Falls represent a serious health risk for millions of older Americans. In the United States, one of every three persons age 65 or older falls each year. Falls are the leading cause of injury deaths and the most common cause of injuries and hospital admissions for trauma in older adults.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senate bill 845 seeks to address the growing problem of falling and fall-related injuries among older adults. This legislation would direct the Department of Health and Human Services to oversee and support national and local education campaigns focused on reducing falls and preventing repeated falls among older adults. It is important to note that the House Committee on Energy and Commerce held a markup of the House companion legislation <bill type="h" number="3701">H.R. 3701</bill>, the Keeping Seniors Safe From Falls Act, which  was introduced by Health Subcommittee Chairman Frank Pallone. The committee amended <bill type="h" number="3701">H.R. 3701</bill> to ensure that it was identical to Senate bill 845, which has already passed the Senate by unanimous consent. So I want to commend my good friend Frank Pallone for his hard work and commitment on this important piece of legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support Senate bill 845.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400099" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, my wife and I had the opportunity to take care of my mother and her parents in their later years for a period of about 8 1/2  years prior to their passage some 1 1/2  years ago. We were always aware of the danger that was posed by falls, and certainly falls are one of the main causes of injuries and hospital admissions for senior adults.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="845">S. 845</bill>, the Safety of Seniors Act of 2008, tries to address this danger by focusing attention on preventing falls among senior citizens and conducting research to evaluate the cause of falls among our older adults. The legislation provides the Secretary with discretion to implement a national education campaign, and, also, it gives him authority to evaluate the effectiveness of community programs designed to prevent falls. It also gives the Secretary the ability to create demonstration projects  focused on evaluating and preventing falls in senior citizens.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge the adoption of this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400062" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I have no further requests for time, and I support the passage of Senate bill 845, which seeks to address the growing problem of falls and fall-related injuries among older adults.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400308" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, many of us have elder parents, relatives, neighbors or colleagues who have experienced an unnecessary fall. Recently, Nancy Reagan and Senator Robert Byrd have both suffered from falls that have caused them to be hospitalized.</paragraph>
    <paragraph> Falls among elderly Americans in fact are so commonplace that one in three Americans over the age of 65 each year experiences a debilitating fall. As a result, it is the leading cause of injury-related deaths for older Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph> The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, CDC, estimates that fall-related medical expenses cost Americans more than $20 billion annually. Projections are that those expenses will climb to more than $40 billion over the next 15 years, posing additional burdens on already strapped Medicare and Medicaid funding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph> Effective demonstration tests and comprehensive public information and education campaigns can help reduce and mitigate these avoidable and frequently disabling injuries.</paragraph>
    <paragraph> To that end, I introduced <bill type="h" number="3701">H.R. 3701</bill>, the "Keeping Seniors Safe from Falls Act of 2007" with my good friend Representative Ralph Hall, which is the House companion to <bill type="s" number="845">S. 845</bill>, the bill we are debating today. If enacted, this legislation would launch a comprehensive preventive care program and educational campaign to reduce the number and severity of falls to the elderly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph> In closing I want to acknowledge all the hard work that went into this bill, including the work of my colleagues both here in the House and the Senate, as well as the Falls Free Coalition working group, which has been advocating for this legislation for sometime.</paragraph>
    <paragraph> Madam Speaker, falls among the elderly are clearly an issue that affect and potentially imperil us all. This legislation offers a national approach to reducing these tragic events I urge my colleagues on both sides of the aisle to support this important bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400062" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from California (Mrs. Capps) that the House suspend the rules and pass the Senate bill, <bill type="s" number="845">S. 845</bill>.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the Senate bill was passed.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
