<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1194973204" ordinal="10" title="ACT COMMEMORATING THE LITE, OR LIFETIME INNOVATIONS OF THOMAS EDISON">
  <narrative>ACT COMMEMORATING THE LITE, OR LIFETIME INNOVATIONS OF THOMAS EDISON -- (House of Representatives - November 13, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H13525]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="2627">H.R. 2627</bill>) to establish the Thomas Edison National Historic Park in the State of New Jersey as the successor to the Edison National Historic Site.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the bill is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="2627">H.R. 2627</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "Act Commemorating the LITE, or Lifetime Innovations of Thomas Edison".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. FINDINGS AND PURPOSE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Findings.--Congress finds the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) The Edison National Historic Site, located in West Orange, New Jersey, is a vital part of America's national system of parks which preserves Thomas Alva Edison's research and development laboratories, library, papers, and artifacts, as well as his home.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) The Site is a national historic treasure and contains the world's largest collection of materials related to Thomas Edison, encompassing an estimated 5,000,000 pages of documents, over 400,000 artifacts, approximately 35,000 sound recordings, and 10,000 books from Edison's personal library.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) Thomas Edison is one of America's greatest inventors, whose inexhaustible energy and genius produced 1,093 patents in his lifetime, more than any other American, including patents for the incandescent light bulb, the motion picture camera, and the phonograph.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) In 1928, Thomas Edison was awarded the Congressional Gold Medal for the "development and application of inventions that have revolutionized civilization in the last century." &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) In 1998, Congress again honored Thomas Edison by directing the Secretary of the Treasury to mint a commemorative coin celebrating the 125th anniversary of Edison's invention of the light bulb, celebrated in 2004.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (6) The Edison National Historic Site is one of America's most endangered historic places. The National Park Service, in its General Management Plan and Development Concept Plan, identified the need for numerous actions to preserve, protect, restore, and enhance the Site and determined that sufficient government funds are not likely to be appropriated to complete these necessary actions in the foreseeable future.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (7) On November 6, 1997, the National Park Service signed an agreement with the Thomas Alva Edison Preservation Foundation (now the Edison Preservation Foundation), establishing a public-private partnership to jointly raise money to fund identified improvements at the Edison National Historic Site so as to leave the Site unimpaired for the enjoyment of future generations.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Purposes.--The purposes of this Act are--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) to recognize and pay tribute to Thomas Alva Edison and his innovations; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) to preserve, protect, restore, and enhance the Edison National Historic Site to ensure public use and enjoyment of the Site as an educational, scientific, and cultural center.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 3. THOMAS EDISON NATIONAL HISTORICAL PARK.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Establishment.--There is established the Thomas Edison National Historical Park as a unit of the National Park System (hereafter the "Historical Park").&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Boundaries.--The Historical Park shall be comprised of--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) all property owned by the United States in the Edison National Historic Site as well as all property authorized to be acquired by the Secretary of the Interior for inclusion in the Edison National Historic Site before the date of the enactment of this Act, as generally depicted on the map entitled the "Edison National Historic Site", numbered 20003B, and dated April 1977; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) all property authorized to be acquired for inclusion in the Historical Park by this Act or other law enacted after the date of the enactment of this Act.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Map.--The map of the Historical Park shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the National Park Service.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 4. ADMINISTRATION.</narrative>
  <narrative> (a) In General.--The Secretary shall administer the Historical Park in accordance with this Act and with the provisions of law generally applicable to units of the National Park System, including the Acts entitled "An Act to establish a National Park Service, and for other purposes," approved August 25, 1916 (39 Stat. 535; 16 U.S.C. 1 et seq.) and "An Act to provide for the preservation of historic American sites, buildings, objects, and antiquities of national significance, and  for other purposes," approved August 21, 1935 (16 U.S.C. 461 et seq.).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Acquisition of Property.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) REAL PROPERTY.--The Secretary may acquire land or interests in land within the boundaries of the Historical Park, from willing sellers only, by donation, purchase with donated or appropriated funds, or exchange.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) PERSONAL PROPERTY.--The Secretary may acquire personal property associated with, and appropriate for, interpretation of the Historical Park.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Cooperative Agreements.--The Secretary may consult and enter into cooperative agreements with interested entities and individuals to provide for the preservation, development, interpretation, and use of the Historical Park.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (d) Repeal of Superseded Law.--Public Law 87-628 (76 Stat. 428), regarding the establishment and administration of the Edison National Historic Site, is repealed.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (e) References.--Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the "Edison National Historic Site" shall be deemed to be a reference to the "Thomas Edison National Historical Park".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 5. AUTHORIZATION OF APPROPRIATIONS.</narrative>
  <narrative> There is authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this Act.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from Guam (Ms. Bordallo) and the gentleman from Utah (Mr. Bishop) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentlewoman from Guam.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members have 5 legislative days in which to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from Guam?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, Thomas Edison is a towering figure in American history, a man whose genius continues to impact our world more than 75 years after his death.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thanks to Mr. Edison's generosity, both his laboratory and his home in West Orange, New Jersey, are included within the National Park System and open to the public.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2627">H.R. 2627</bill> simply changes the name of this unit from the Edison National Historic Site to the Thomas Edison National Historic Park. The new name is more appropriate for a unit that includes multiple properties. Nearly identical legislation passed the House by a vote of 399-1 in February 2006, but, Mr. Speaker, it was never considered by the Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The sponsor of <bill type="h" number="2627">H.R. 2627</bill>, the Representative from New Jersey (Mr. Payne), is to be commended for his outstanding work on this legislation, along with other cosponsors from the New Jersey delegation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge all our colleagues to support <bill type="h" number="2627">H.R. 2627</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400029" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="2627">H.R. 2627</bill>, which designates the Edison National Historic Site as the Thomas Edison National Historic Park. Supporters of the park anticipate this redesignation will improve the visitation revenue to the Edison historic site.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like also to recognize the critical contributions to this legislation made by Congressman Scott Garrett. Last year, Mr. Garrett successfully moved this bill through the Resources Committee in the House. I urge my colleagues to support this effort, and hopefully it will go all the way through both Houses at this time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield to my colleague from New Jersey (Mr. Holt) for such time as he may consume.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400184" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of the Lifetime Innovations of Thomas Edison Act, originally sponsored by my colleague Mr. Payne from New Jersey, with others of us from New Jersey joining him. The legislation before us would reclassify the Edison home and laboratory as a National Historic Park.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First dedicated as the Edison National Historic site by the National Park Service in 1962, the site is badly in need of restoration. Dedicating this site as a National Historic Park and authorizing funding for the preservation of the Edison home and laboratory will preserve a national treasure. As you have heard from my colleague, the collection there, as well as the buildings themselves, are of great historical national importance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thomas Edison was one of America's most prominent inventors. From starting one of the first industrial laboratories, something that is often forgotten, to inventing the first incandescent light bulb, the motion picture, the phonograph, et cetera, Edison played an integral role in the technological advances that helped spur America's industrial revolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Edison held over 1,000 patents in the United States and other countries, was named by Life magazine as the man of the millennium, and awarded the Congressional Gold Medal by the Congress in 1928 for his development and application of inventions that have revolutionized civilization. Thomas Edison certainly deserves to be remembered and his collection deserves to be preserved.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The 13.5 acre site will make an outstanding national historic park. It will draw people from all across the country to see the important collection there, as well as the site of the first really major scientific industrial laboratory in the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Despite being designated a national historic site, it has fallen into disrepair, and in 1992 the National Trust for Historic Preservation listed this as one of the Nation's most endangered historic places. This redesignation is of great importance. Mr. Speaker, we are not only recognizing Thomas Edison's numerous contributions to American society, but we will, with this, be preserving the Edison National Historic Site as a leading educational, scientific, and cultural center.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank the gentlelady.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400312" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would like to ask my colleagues to join me today in recognizing one of New Jersey's own--Thomas Alva Edison. <bill type="h" number="2627">H.R. 2627</bill>, the Lifetime Innovations of Thomas Edison, LITE, Act, is a testament to Edison, whose impact is still being felt today. Congress, in 1928, honored Edison with the Congressional Gold Medal for the "development and application of inventions that have  revolutionized civilization in the last century." In 1997,  Life magazine named Edison "Man of the Millennium" in recognition of his inventions that have transformed modern society, including the incandescent light bulb, the motion picture camera, and the phonograph. The LITE Act will preserve the intellectual and physical</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Edison site is actually comprised of two separate sites--Edison's home of 45 years, known as Glenmont, and his laboratory complex. The Edison site houses over 5 million pages of documents, over 400,000 artifacts, approximately 35,000 sound recordings, and over 10,000 books from Edison's personal library. Like this priceless collection of documents and artifacts, Edison's laboratory complex and home are also historical treasures. With buildings dating back to 1887, the laboratory complex was  one of America's first research and development facilities, and is where Edison earned over half of his 1,093 patents. Moreover, Mr. Edison's gravesite is located on the grounds of his beloved Glenmont, a 29-room home built in 1880 that contains original furnishings and other family items.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2627">H.R. 2627</bill> is critical to efforts to protect the Thomas Edison National Historic Site. The Edison site has enormous historical significance for America and for the world, and is badly in need of restoration. The need for major infrastructure improvements at the Edison site has been documented as early as 1972. Additionally, the site was listed, in 1992, by the National Trust for Historic Preservation as one of the Nation's most "endangered historic places." The laboratory complex is currently  closed to the public because of an extensive restoration effort. It is estimated that the first phase of the restoration effort will be completed next year and that the laboratory complex will re-open to the public some time between June and September of 2008. Renovations at Glenmont have been completed and the site is open to the public and fully functioning.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When the Edison site was fully operational, approximately 95,000 people visited the site each year. It is estimated that the number of visitors will nearly triple when the first phase of the restoration project is completed next year. <bill type="h" number="2627">H.R. 2627</bill> would ensure this commitment by re-designating the Edison site as a "national historical park"--consistent with National Park Service guidelines--and authorizing appropriations for restoration work. These measures will preserve Thomas Edison's historical  legacy, enhance the educational experience of visitors to the site, and hopefully, encourage more private funding for restoration projects.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although private benefactors--most notably the Edison Preservation Foundation--have generously donated significant resources to restore the site, the Federal Government's long-term commitment to the site is critical to its longevity and educational mission. This legislation recognizes Thomas Edison's numerous contributions to American society and preserves the Edison National Historic Site as a leading educational, scientific and cultural center.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, this legislation is non-controversial. Similar legislation in the 109th Congress was supported by the National Park Service and approved by the House by a vote of 399-1. I respectfully urge my colleagues to support this important legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400029" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from Guam (Ms. Bordallo) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="2627">H.R. 2627</bill>.</chair>
  <chair>The question was taken; and (two-thirds being in the affirmative) the rules were suspended and the bill was passed.</chair>
  <chair>A motion to reconsider was laid on the table.</chair>
</record>
