<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1193932801" ordinal="35" title="HONORING THE LIFE OF MR. RHYS LEWIS">
  <narrative>HONORING THE LIFE OF MR. RHYS LEWIS -- (House of Representatives - November 01, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H12435]</narrative>
  <chair> Under a previous order of the House, the gentleman from Michigan (Mr. McCotter) is recognized for 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400260" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, today I rise to honor and mourn the extraordinary life of Rhys Lewis upon his passing at the age of 83.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Born on May 13, 1924, Rhys Lewis dedicated his life to serving others. As a United States Marine Corps sergeant  during World War II, Rhys served in the South Pacific and fought to defend the liberty of Americans and all humanity. His tour of duty included seeing combat on Iwo Jima, where he demonstrated his unfaltering honor and valor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Following his return home in 1947, Rhys married his beloved Ruth and continued his service to our Nation. An active church member, Rhys was ultimately elected to and entrusted with numerous positions of governmental and civic trust.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He served as a Republican precinct delegate, a Redford Township trustee, a Redford Civil Affairs chairman, the chairman of the Redford Republican Party, as a member of the Michigan Republican State Committee, and a 1980 Bush delegate to the national convention.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Regrettably, on October 27, 2007, Rhys Lewis passed from this earthly world to his eternal reward. He is survived by his wife, Ruth Lewis, his children, Arthur Lewis and Charlotte Wirth, his grandchildren, Kathryn Ostreko, David R. Wirth and Jeffrey Lewis, and his great grandchild, Jack Ostreko. A courageous and honorable man, Rhys will be sorely missed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, Rhys Lewis is remembered as a compassionate father, a dedicated husband, a leader, a soldier and a friend. Today, as we bid Rhys farewell, I ask my colleagues to join me in mourning his passing and honoring the unwavering patriotism and legendary service to our country and community of this fine American.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And I would be remiss if I did not add what I believe encapsulates the essence of the man. Early in my tenure as a Member of Congress, I was honored to be asked to participate in a ceremony where Rhys Lewis was honored for his commitment to our Nation and his service as a member of the Greatest Generation of World War II. We had to work with his wife, Ruth, because Rhys, an honorable man, was not a proud man. And so when we surprised him at the VFW that day with the medals that he had earned,  he was stunned. Part of him seemed to be surprised that people had remembered his service to our Nation in its crucible of liberty, and the other part of him was deeply, deeply concerned that he was being singled out for what he and so many other fine young Americans had done to preserve the freedoms we now hold.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That was the man that we honor today. That is the man whose example I believe we should ever cherish and ever emulate.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
