<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1178553612" ordinal="23" title="LOWER REPUBLICAN RIVER BASIN STUDY ACT">
  <speaking speaker="400290" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and pass the bill (<bill type="h" number="1025">H.R. 1025</bill>) to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a study to determine the feasibility of implementing a water supply and conservation project to improve water supply reliability, increase the capacity of water storage, and improve water management efficiency in the Republican River Basin between Harlan County Lake in Nebraska and Milford Lake in Kansas.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentlewoman from California (Mrs. Napolitano) and the gentleman from Colorado (Mr. Lamborn) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400290" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 days to revise and extend their remarks and include extraneous material on the bill under consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentlewoman from California?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400290" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of <bill type="h" number="1025">H.R. 1025</bill>, as introduced by our colleague from Kansas (Mr. Moran), is to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a feasibility study on the Republican River Basin between Harlan County Lake in Nebraska and Milford Lake in Kansas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1025">H.R. 1025</bill> is a cooperative agreement between Nebraska, Kansas, Colorado, and the Federal Government that calls for a feasibility study of water resources of that river basin. The goal is to find new solutions to provide water reliability, increase the capacity of the current water storage, which is so important, and improve water management efficiency. This study is imperative to the responsible management of our water supplies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to join me in supporting <bill type="h" number="1025">H.R. 1025</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1025">H.R. 1025</bill>, introduced by our colleagues Jerry Moran and Adrian Smith, implements the Republican River Compact Settlement as negotiated between the States of Colorado, Nebraska, and Kansas. This legislation serves as the first step to increase water storage and water use efficiency to benefit those served by the waters of the Republican River.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I commend Mr. Moran and Mr. Smith for their leadership on this important matter. I urge my colleagues to support this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield 3 minutes to the gentleman from Nebraska (Mr. Smith).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412217" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for yielding me time and bringing this bill forward today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, <bill type="h" number="1025">H.R. 1025</bill> would authorize one of the requirements of the Republican River Compact Settlement negotiated between the States of Nebraska, Kansas and Colorado and approved by the Supreme Court in 2003. It is not only necessary to ensure the States remain in compliance with this agreement, but to make certain the agriculture, industrial and domestic use of the water is carried out in the most efficient and effective manner possible.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Lower Republican River Basin Study will examine how to better utilize opportunities to increase water storage in the river basin. I am hopeful the results of this study will lead to an increase in water availability while we continue to encourage more efficient water use.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As many of you know, especially those from the Midwest, the current water shortage has made this a very critical issue for my congressional district. So if we can, through this study, allocate more water, allocate water more effectively, it will help farmers, ranchers, municipalities both in Nebraska and Kansas in the long term.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank Mr. Rahall, Mr. Young, and the Natural Resources Committee staff for bringing forth this bill. I appreciate the cooperation on both sides of the aisle. I urge Members of Congress to approve this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400284" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise in support of <bill type="h" number="1025">H.R. 1025</bill>, the Lower Republican River Basin Study Act. I would like to thank Chairman Rahall and the Resources Committee for helping to bring this legislation before the House today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The timing of this legislation is significant, not only for farmers in Kansas who have dealt with successive years of drought and decreased water supplies, but because the respective states have already appropriated funds for the current fiscal year to conduct the feasibility study authorized by this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1025">H.R. 1025</bill> is a product of the Republican River Compact Settlement. That settlement resulted from litigation filed by the State of Kansas against the States of Nebraska and Colorado in 1998 because required amounts of water were not reaching Kansas under the Republican River Compact terms. In 2003, the Republican River Compact Settlement brought that litigation to an end.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Settlement was signed not only by the party States, but also administration officials and was subsequently approved by the United States Supreme Court in 2003. As part of that Settlement, the Parties agreed to have the Secretary of the Interior conduct a study to determine the feasibility of implementing water supply and conservation projects in the Republican River Basin below Harlan Reservoir. In accordance with the Settlement Agreement, <bill type="h" number="1025">H.R. 1025</bill> provides that the cost of the study will  be shared between the Federal Government and the States of Kansas and Nebraska.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As of today, the States have done their part under the settlement agreement. In fact, my home State of Kansas has already appropriated funds for the current fiscal year. I also understand that Mr. Smith's State of Nebraska has done the same.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, all that remains is for the Federal Government to meet its obligation under the settlement agreement. The feasibility study is desperately needed to increase water availability and encourage more efficient water use and delivery systems.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Lower Republican Basin has a history of periodic droughts and water shortages. The upper third of the Kansas Bostwick Irrigation District, which lies above Lovewell Reservoir, received limited water allocations in 2003 and no water allocations in 2004 and 2005.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Producers in the lower two-thirds of the Kansas Bostwick Irrigation District have also experienced water shortages since 2003. Irrigators in this portion of the District have only received half of the base supply they were supposed to receive. The project facilities in the Lower Republican River Basin are over 50 years old. Changed hydrological conditions and aging facilities require better utilization of limited water supplies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, the feasibility study authorized by <bill type="h" number="1025">H.R. 1025</bill> is not only necessary to ensure the states remain in compliance with an interstate compact, but also to ensure the economic viability of the rural communities that rely on delivery of a consistent supply of water, and I urge Members to approve this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412191" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400290" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentlewoman from California (Mrs. Napolitano) that the House suspend the rules and pass the bill, <bill type="h" number="1025">H.R. 1025</bill>.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400290" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this question will be postponed.</chair>
</record>
