<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="h" when="1209571202" ordinal="37" title="SAFETEA-LU TECHNICAL CORRECTIONS ACT OF 2008">
  <narrative>SAFETEA-LU TECHNICAL CORRECTIONS ACT OF 2008 -- (House of Representatives - April 30, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: H2867]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I move to suspend the rules and concur in the Senate amendment to the bill (<bill type="h" number="1195">H.R. 1195</bill>) to amend the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users to make technical corrections, and for other purposes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The Clerk read the title of the bill.</narrative>
  <narrative>The text of the Senate amendment is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>Senate amendment:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="1195">H.R. 1195</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative>SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE; TABLE OF CONTENTS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Short Title.--This Act may be cited as the "SAFETEA-LU Technical Corrections Act of 2008".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Table of Contents.--The table of contents of this Act is as follows:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..1..Short title; table of contents.</narrative>
  <narrative>Sec..101..Surface transportation technical corrections.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..102..MAGLEV.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..103..Projects of national and regional significance and national corridor infrastructure improvement projects.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..104..Idling reduction facilities.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..105..Project authorizations.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..106..Nonmotorized transportation pilot program.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..107..Correction of Interstate and National Highway System designations.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..108..Budget justification; buy America.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..109..Transportation improvements.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..110..I-95/Contee Road interchange design.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..111..Highway research funding.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..112..Rescission.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..113..TEA-21 technical corrections.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..114..High priority corridor and innovative project technical corrections.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..115..Definition of repeat intoxicated driver law.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..116..Research technical correction.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..117..Buy America waiver notification and annual reports.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..118..Efficient use of existing highway capacity.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..119..Future interstate designation.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..120..Project flexibility.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..121..Effective date.</narrative>
  <narrative>Sec..201..Transit technical corrections.</narrative>
  <narrative>Sec..301..Technical amendments relating to motor carrier safety.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..302..Technical amendments relating to hazardous materials transportation.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..303..Highway safety.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..304..Correction of study requirement regarding on-scene motor vehicle collision causation.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..305..Motor carrier transportation registration.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..306..Applicability of Fair Labor Standards Act requirements and limitation on liability.</narrative>
  <narrative>Sec..401..Conveyance of GSA Fleet Management Center to Alaska Railroad Corporation.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..402..Conveyance of retained interest in St. Joseph Memorial Hall.</narrative>
  <narrative>Sec..501..De Soto County, Mississippi.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sec..502..Department of Justice review.</narrative>
  <narrative>SEC. 101. SURFACE TRANSPORTATION TECHNICAL CORRECTIONS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Correction of Internal References in Disadvantaged Business Enterprises.--Paragraphs (3)(A) and (5) of section 1101(b) of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (119 Stat. 1156) are amended by striking "paragraph (1)" each place it appears and inserting "paragraph (2)".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Correction of Distribution of Obligation Authority.--Section 1102(c)(5) of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (119 Stat. 1158) is amended by striking "among the States".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Correction of Federal Lands Highways.--Section 1119 of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (119 Stat. 1190) is amended by striking subsection (m) and inserting the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(m) Forest Highways.--Of the amounts made available for public lands highways under section 1101--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(1) not more than $20,000,000 for each fiscal year may be used for the maintenance of forest highways;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(2) not more than $1,000,000 for each fiscal year may be used for signage identifying public hunting and fishing access; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(3) not more than $10,000,000 for each fiscal year shall be used by the Secretary of Agriculture to pay the costs of facilitating the passage of aquatic species beneath forest roads (as defined in section 101(a) of title 23, United States Code), including the costs of constructing, maintaining, replacing, and removing culverts and bridges, as appropriate.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (d) Correction of Description of National Corridor Infrastructure Improvement Project.--Item number 1 of the table contained in section 1302(e) of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (119 Stat. 1205) is amended in the State column by inserting "LA," after "TX,".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (e) Correction of High Priority Designations.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) KENTUCKY HIGH PRIORITY CORRIDOR DESIGNATION.--Section 1105(c)(18)(E) of the Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act of 1991 (105 Stat. 2032; 112 Stat. 189; 115 Stat. 872) is amended by inserting before the period at the end the following: ", follow Interstate Route 24 to the Wendell H. Ford Western Kentucky Parkway, then utilize the existing Wendell H. Ford Western Kentucky Parkway and Edward T. Breathitt (Pennyrile) Parkway to Henderson".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) INTERSTATE ROUTE 376 HIGH PRIORITY DESIGNATION.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) IN GENERAL.--Section 1105(c)(79) of the Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act of 1991 (105 Stat. 2032; 119 Stat. 1213) is amended by striking "and on United States Route 422".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) CONFORMING AMENDMENT.--Section 1105(e)(5)(B)(i)(I) of the Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act of 1991 (105 Stat. 2033; 119 Stat. 1213) is amended by striking "and United States Route 422".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (f) Correction of Infrastructure Finance Section.--Section 1602(d)(1) of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (119 Stat. 1247) is amended by striking "through 189 as sections 601 through 609, respectively" and inserting "through 190 as sections 601 through 610, respectively".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (g) Correction of Project Federal Share.--Section 1964(a) of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (119 Stat. 1519) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) by striking "only for the States of Alaska, Montana, Nevada, North Dakota, Oregon, and South Dakota,"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) by striking "section 120(b)" and inserting "section 120".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (h) Transportation Systems Management and Operations Defined.--Section 101(a) of title 23, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(39) TRANSPORTATION SYSTEMS MANAGEMENT AND OPERATIONS.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(A) IN GENERAL.--The term `transportation systems management and operations' means an  integrated program to optimize the performance of existing infrastructure through the implementation of multimodal and intermodal, cross-jurisdictional systems, services, and projects designed to preserve capacity and improve security, safety, and reliability of the transportation system.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(B) INCLUSIONS.--The term `transportation systems management and operations' includes--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(i) regional operations collaboration and coordination activities between transportation and public safety agencies; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(ii) improvements to the transportation system, such as traffic detection and surveillance, arterial management, freeway management, demand management, work zone management, emergency management, electronic toll collection, automated enforcement, traffic incident management, roadway weather management, traveler information services, commercial vehicle operations, traffic control, freight management, and coordination of highway, rail, transit, bicycle, and pedestrian operations.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) Correction of Reference in Apportionment of Highway Safety Improvement Program Funds.--Effective October 1, 2007, section 104(b)(5)(A)(iii) of title 23, United States Code, is amended by striking "the Federal-aid system" each place it appears and inserting "Federal-aid highways".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (j) Correction of Amendment To Advance Construction.--Section 115 of title 23, United States Code, is amended by redesignating subsection (d) as subsection (c).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (k) Correction of High Priority Projects.--Section 117 of title 23, United States Code, is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) by redesignating subsections (d) through (h) as subsections (e) through (i), respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) by redesignating the second subsection (c) (relating to Federal share) as subsection (d);&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) in subsection (a)(2)(A) by inserting "(112 Stat. 257)" after "21st Century"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) in subsection (a)(2)(B)--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) by striking "subsection (b)" and inserting "subsection (c)"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) by striking "SAFETEA-LU" and inserting "Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (119 Stat. 1256)".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (l) Correction of Transfer of Unused Protective-Device Funds to Other Highway Safety Improvement Program Projects.--Section 130(e)(2) of title 23, United States Code, is amended by striking "purposes under this subsection" and inserting "highway safety improvement program purposes".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (m) Correction of Highway Bridge Program.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) IN GENERAL.--Section 144 of title 23, United States Code, is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) in the section heading by striking "&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;REPLACEMENT AND REHABILITATION";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) in subsections (b), (c)(1), and (e) by striking "Federal-aid system" each place it appears and inserting "Federal-aid highway";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) in subsections (c)(2) and (o) by striking "the Federal-aid system" each place it appears and inserting "Federal-aid highways";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (D) in the heading to paragraph (4) of subsection (d) by inserting "SYSTEMATIC" before "PREVENTIVE";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (E) in subsection (e) by striking "off-system bridges" each place it appears and inserting "bridges not on Federal-aid highways";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (F) by striking subsection (f);&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (G) by redesignating subsections (g) through (s) as subsections (f) through (r), respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (H) in paragraph (1)(A)(vi) of subsection (f) (as redesignated by subparagraph (G) of this paragraph) by inserting "and the removal of the Missisquoi Bay causeway" after "Bridge";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (I) in paragraph (2) of subsection (f) (as redesignated by subparagraph (G) of this paragraph) by striking the paragraph heading and inserting "BRIDGES NOT ON FEDERAL-AID HIGHWAYS";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (J) in subsection (m) (as redesignated by subparagraph (G) of this paragraph) by striking the subsection heading and inserting "Program for Bridges Not on Federal-Aid Highways"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (K) in subsection (n)(4)(B) (as redesignated by subparagraph (G) of this paragraph) by striking "State highway agency" and inserting "State transportation department".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) SPECIAL CONDITIONS.--Section 1114 of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (Public Law 109-59; 119 Stat. 1172) is amended by adding at the end the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(h) Special Conditions.--Any unobligated or unexpended funds remaining on completion of the project carried out under section 144(f)(1)(A)(vi) of title 23, United States Code, shall be made available to carry out the project described in section 144(f)(1)(A)(vii) of that title after the date on which the Vermont Agency of Transportation certifies to the Federal Highway Administration the final determination of the agency regarding the removal of the Missisquoi Bay causeway.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) CONFORMING AMENDMENTS.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) METROPOLITAN PLANNING.--Section 104(f)(1) of title 23, United States Code, is amended by striking "replacement and rehabilitation".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) EQUITY BONUS PROGRAM.--Subsections (a)(2)(C) and (b)(2)(C) of section 105 of such title are amended by striking "replacement and rehabilitation" each place it appears.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) ANALYSIS.--The analysis for chapter 1 of such title is amended in the item relating to section 144 by striking "replacement and rehabilitation".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (n) Metropolitan Transportation Planning.--Section 134 of title 23, United States Code, is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in subsection (f)(3)(C)(ii) by striking subclause (II) and inserting the following:</narrative>
  <narrative> "(II) FUNDING.--For fiscal year 2008 and each fiscal year thereafter, in addition to other funds made available to the metropolitan planning organization for the Lake Tahoe region under this title and chapter 53 of title 49, prior to any allocation under section 202 of this title and notwithstanding the allocation provisions of section 202, the Secretary shall set aside  1/2  of 1 percent of all funds authorized to be appropriated for such fiscal year to carry out section 204 and shall  make such funds available to the metropolitan planning organization for the Lake Tahoe region to carry out the transportation planning process, environmental reviews, preliminary engineering, and design to complete environmental documentation for transportation projects for the Lake Tahoe region under the Tahoe Regional Planning Compact as consented to in Public Law 96-551 (94 Stat. 3233) and this paragraph.";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) in subsection (j)(3)(D) by inserting "or the identified phase" after "the project" each place it appears; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) in subsection (k)(2) by striking "a metropolitan planning area serving".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (o) Correction of National Scenic Byways Program Coverage.--Section 162 of title 23, United States Code, is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in subsection (a)(3)(B) by striking "a National Scenic Byway under subparagraph (A)" and inserting "a National Scenic Byway, an All-American Road, or one of America's Byways under paragraph (1)"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) in subsection (c)(3) by striking "or All-American Road" each place it appears and inserting "All-American Road, or one of America's Byways".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (p) Correction of Reference in Toll Provision.--Section 166(b)(5)(C) of title 23, United States Code, is amended by striking "paragraph (3)" and inserting "paragraph (4)".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (q) Correction of Recreational Trails Program Apportionment Exceptions.--Section 206(d)(3)(A) of title 23, United States Code, is amended by striking "(B), (C), and (D)" and inserting "(B) and (C)".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (r) Correction of Infrastructure Finance.--Section 601(a)(3) of title 23, United States Code, is amended by inserting "bbb minus, BBB (low)," after "Baa3,".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (s) Correction of Miscellaneous Typographical Errors.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) Section 1401 of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (119 Stat. 1226) is amended by redesignating subsections (d) and (e) as subsections (c) and (d), respectively.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) Section 1404(e) of such Act (119 Stat. 1229) is amended by inserting "tribal," after "local,".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) Section 10211(b)(2) of such Act (119 Stat. 1937) is amended by striking "plan administer" and inserting "plan and administer".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) Section 10212(a) of such Act (119 Stat. 1937) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) by inserting "equity bonus," after "minimum guarantee,";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) by striking "freight intermodal connectors" and inserting "railway-highway crossings";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) by striking "high risk rural road,"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (D) by inserting after "highway safety improvement programs" the following: "(and separately the set aside for the high risk rural road program)".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 102. MAGLEV.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Funding.--Section 1101(a)(18) of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (119 Stat. 1155) is amended by striking "Act--" and all that follows through the end of the paragraph and inserting "Act, $45,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2008 and 2009.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Contract Authority.--Section 1307 of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (119 Stat. 1217) is amended by adding at the end the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(e) Contract Authority.--Funds authorized under section 1101(a)(18) shall be available for obligation in the same manner as if the funds were apportioned under chapter 1 of title 23, United States Code; except that the funds shall not be transferable and shall remain available until expended, and the Federal share of the cost of a project to be carried out with such funds shall be 80 percent.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Allocation.--Section 1307 of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (119 Stat. 1217) is amended by striking subsection (d) and inserting the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(d) Allocation.--Of the amounts made available to carry out this section for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall allocate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(1) 50 percent to the Nevada department of transportation who shall cooperate with the California-Nevada Super Speed Train Commission for the MAGLEV project between Las Vegas and Primm, Nevada, as a segment of the high-speed MAGLEV system between Las Vegas, Nevada, and Anaheim, California; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(2) 50 percent for existing MAGLEV projects located east of the Mississippi River using such criteria as the Secretary deems appropriate.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (d) Effective Date.--The amendments made by this section take effect on October 1, 2007.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 103. PROJECTS OF NATIONAL AND REGIONAL SIGNIFICANCE AND NATIONAL CORRIDOR INFRASTRUCTURE IMPROVEMENT PROJECTS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Project of National and Regional Significance.--The table contained in section 1301(m) of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity: A Legacy for Users (119 Stat. 1203) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in item number 4 by striking the project description and inserting "$7,400,000 for planning, design, and construction of a new American border plaza at the Blue Water Bridge in or near Port Huron; $12,600,000 for integrated highway realignment and grade separations at Port Huron to eliminate road blockages from NAFTA rail traffic";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) in item number 19 by striking the project description and inserting "For purposes of construction and other related transportation improvements associated with the rail yard relocation in the vicinity of Santa Teresa"; and &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) in item number 22 by striking the project description and inserting "Redesign and reconstruction of interchanges 298 and 299 of I-80 and accompanying improvements to any other public roads in the vicinity, Monroe County".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) National Corridor Infrastructure Improvement Project.--The table contained in section 1302(e) of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (119 Stat. 1205) is amended in item number 23 by striking the project description and inserting "Improvements to State Road 312, Hammond".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 104. IDLING REDUCTION FACILITIES.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Section 111(d) of title 23, United States Code, is repealed.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 105. PROJECT AUTHORIZATIONS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Project Modifications.--The table contained in section 1702 of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (119 Stat. 1256) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in item number 34 by striking the project description and inserting "Removal and Reconfiguration of Interstate ramps, I-40, Memphis";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) by striking item number 61;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) in item number 87 by striking the project description and inserting "M-291 highway outer road improvement project";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) in item number 128 by striking "$2,400,000" and inserting "$4,800,000";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) in item number 154 by striking "Virginia" and inserting "Eveleth";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (6) in item number 193 by striking the project description and inserting "Improvements to or access to Route 108 to enhance access to the business park near Rumford";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (7) in item number 240 by striking "$800,000" and inserting "$2,400,000";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (8) by striking item number 248;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (9) in item number 274 by striking the project description and inserting "Intersection improvements at Belleville and Ecorse Roads and approach roadways, and widen Belleville Road from Ecorse to Tyler, Van Buren Township, Michigan";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (10) in item number 277 by striking the project description and inserting "Construct connector road from Rushing Drive North to Grand Ave., Williamson County";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (11) in item number 395 by striking the project description and inserting "Plan and construct interchange at I-65, from existing SR-109 to I-65";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (12) in item number 463 by striking "Cookeville" and inserting "Putnam County";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (13) in item number 576 by striking the project description and inserting "Design, right-of-way acquisition, and construction of Nebraska Highway 35 between Norfolk and South Sioux City, including an interchange at Milepost 1 on I-129";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (14) in item number 595 by striking "Street Closure at" and inserting "Transportation improvement project near";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (15) in item number 649 by striking the project description and inserting "Construction and enhancement of the Fillmore Avenue Corridor, Buffalo";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (16) in item number 655 by inserting ", safety improvement construction," after "Environmental studies";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (17) in item number 676 by striking the project description and inserting "St. Croix River crossing project, Wisconsin State Highway 64, St. Croix County, Wisconsin, to Minnesota State Highway 36, Washington County";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (18) in item number 770 by striking the project description and inserting "Improve existing Horns Hill Road in North Newark, Ohio, from Waterworks Road to Licking Springs Road";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (19) in item number 777 by striking the project description and inserting "Akutan Airport access";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (20) in item number 829 by striking the project description and inserting "$400,000 to conduct New Bedford/Fairhaven Bridge modernization study; $1,000,000 to design and build New Bedford Business Park access road";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (21) in item number 881 by striking the project description and inserting "Pedestrian safety improvements near North Atlantic Boulevard, Monterey Park";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (22) in item number 923 by striking the project description and inserting "Improve safety of a horizontal curve on Clarksville St. 0.25 miles north of 275th Rd. in Grandview Township, Edgar County";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (23) in item number 947 by striking the project description and inserting "Third East/West River Crossing, St. Lucie River";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (24) in item numbers 959 and 3327 by striking "Northern Section," each place it appears;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (25) in item number 963 by striking the project description and inserting "For engineering, right-of-way acquisition, and reconstruction of 2 existing lanes on Manhattan Road from Baseline Road to Route 53";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (26) in item number 983 by striking the project description and inserting "Land acquisition for highway mitigation in Cecil, Kent, Queen Annes, and Worcester Counties";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (27) in item number 1039 by striking the project description and inserting "Widen State Route 98, including storm drain developments, from D. Navarro Avenue to State Route 111";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (28) in item number 1047 by striking the project description and inserting "Bridge and road work at Little Susitna River Access road in Matanuska-Susitna Borough";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (29) in item number 1124 by striking "bridge over Stillwater River, Orono" and inserting "routes";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (30) in item number 1206 by striking "Pleasantville" and inserting "Briarcliff Manor";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (31) in item number 1281 by striking the project description and inserting "Upgrade roads in Attala County District 4 (Roads 4211 and 4204), Kosciusko, Ward 2, and Ethel, Attala County";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (32) in item number 1487 by striking "$800,000" and inserting "$1,600,000";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (33) in item number 1575 by striking the project description and inserting "Highway and road signage, and traffic signal synchronization and upgrades, in Shippensburg Boro, Shippensburg Township, and surrounding municipalities";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (34) in item number 1661 by striking the project description and inserting "Sheldon West Extension in Matanuska-Susitna Borough";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (35) in item number 1810 by striking the project description and inserting "Design, engineering, ROW acquisition, construction, and construction engineering for the reconstruction of TH 95, from 12th Avenue to CSAH 13, including bridge and approaches, ramps, intersecting roadways, signals, turn lanes, and multiuse trail, North Branch";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (36) in item number 1852 by striking "Milepost 9.3" and inserting "Milepost 24.3";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (37) in item numbers 1926 and 2893 by striking the project descriptions and inserting "Grading, paving roads, and the transfer of rail-to-truck for the intermodal facility at Rickenbacker Airport, Columbus, Ohio";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (38) in item number 1933 by striking the project description and inserting "Enhance Byzantine Latino Quarter transit plazas at Normandie and Pico, and Hoover and Pico, Los Angeles, by improving streetscapes, including expanding concrete and paving";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (39) in item number 1975 by striking the project description and inserting "Point MacKenzie Access Road improvements in Matanuska-Susitna Borough";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (40) in item number 2015 by striking the project description and amount and inserting "Heidelberg Borough/Scott Township/Carnegie Borough for design, engineering, acquisition, and construction of streetscaping enhancements, paving, lighting and safety upgrades, and parking improvements" and "$2,000,000", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (41) in item number 2087 by striking the project description and inserting "Railroad crossing improvement on Illinois Route 82 in Geneseo";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (42) in item number 2211 by striking the project description and inserting "Construct road projects and transportation enhancements as part of or connected to RiverScape Phase III, Montgomery County, Ohio";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (43) in item number 2234 by striking the project description and amount and inserting "North Atherton Signal Coordination Project in Centre County" and "$400,000", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (44) in item number 2316 by striking the project description and inserting "Construct a new bridge at Indian Street, Martin County";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (45) in item number 2420 by striking the project description and inserting "Preconstruction and construction activities of U.S. 51 between the Assumption Bypass and Vandalia";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (46) in item number 2482 by striking "Country" and inserting "County";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (47) in item number 2663 by striking the project description and inserting "Rosemead Boulevard safety enhancement and beautification, Temple City";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (48) in item number 2671 by striking "from 2 to 5 lanes and improve alignment within rights-of-way in St. George" and inserting ", St. George";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (49) in item number 2743 by striking the project description and inserting "Improve safety of culvert replacement on 250th Rd. between 460th St. and Cty Hwy 20 in Grandview Township, Edgar County";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (50) by striking item number 2800;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (51) in item number 2826 by striking "State Street and Cajon Boulevard" and inserting "Palm Avenue";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (52) in item number 2931 by striking "Frazho Road" and inserting "Martin Road";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (53) in item number 3047 by inserting "and roadway improvements" after "safety project";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (54) in item number 3078 by striking the project description and inserting "U.S. 2/Sultan Basin Road improvements in Sultan";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (55) in item number 3174 by striking the project description and inserting "Improving Outer Harbor access through planning, design, construction, and relocations of Southtowns Connector-NY Route 5, Fuhrmann Boulevard, and a bridge connecting the Outer Harbor to downtown Buffalo at the Inner Harbor";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (56) in item number 3219 by striking "Forest" and inserting "Warren";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (57) in item number 3254 by striking the project description and inserting "Reconstruct PA Route 274/34 Corridor, Perry County";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (58) in item number 3260 by striking "Lake Shore Drive" and inserting "Lakeshore Drive and parking facility/entrance improvements serving the Museum of Science and Industry";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (59) in item number 3368 by striking the project description and inserting "Plan, design, and engineering, Ludlam Trail, Miami";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (60) in item number 3410 by striking the project description and inserting "Design, purchase land, and construct sound walls along the west side of I-65 from approximately 950 feet south of the Harding Place interchange south to Hogan Road";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (61) in item number 3537 by inserting "and the study of alternatives along the North South Corridor," after "Valley";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (62) in item number 3582 by striking the project description and inserting "Improving Outer Harbor access through planning, design, construction, and relocations of Southtowns Connector-NY Route 5, Fuhrmann Boulevard, and a bridge connecting the Outer Harbor to downtown Buffalo at the Inner Harbor";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (63) in item number 3604 by inserting "/Kane Creek Boulevard" after "500 West";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (64) in item number 3632 by striking the State, project description, and amount and inserting "FL", "Pine Island Road pedestrian overpass, city of Tamarac", and "$610,000", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (65) in item number 3634 by striking the matters in the State, project description, and amount columns and inserting "FL", "West Avenue Bridge, city of Miami Beach", and "$620,000", respectively; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (66) in item number 3673 by striking the project description and inserting "Improve marine dry-dock and facilities in Ketchikan";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (67) in item number 2942 by striking the project description and inserting "Redesigning the intersection of Business U.S. 322/High Street and Rosedale Avenue and constructing a new East Campus Drive between High Street (U.S. 322) and Matlock Street at West Chester University, West Chester, Pennsylvania";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (68) in item number 2781 by striking the project description and inserting "Highway and road signage, road construction, and other transportation improvement and enhancement projects on or near Highway 26, in Riverton and surrounding areas";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (69) in item number 2430 by striking "200 South Interchange" and inserting "400 South Interchange";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (70) by striking item number 20;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (71) in item number 424 by striking "$264,000" and inserting "$644,000";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (72) in item number 1210 by striking the project description and inserting "Town of New Windsor--Riley Road, Shore Drive, and area road improvements";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (73) by striking item numbers 68, 905, and 1742;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (74) in item number 1059 by striking "$240,000" and inserting "$420,000";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (75) in item number 2974 by striking "$120,000" and inserting "$220,000";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (76) by striking item numbers 841, 960, and 2030;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (77) in item number 1278 by striking "$740,000" and inserting "$989,600";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (78) in item number 207 by striking "$13,600,000" and inserting "$13,200,000";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (79) in item number 2656 by striking "$12,228,000" and inserting "$8,970,000";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (80) in item number 1983 by striking "$1,600,000" and inserting "$1,000,000";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (81) in item number 753 by striking "$2,700,000" and inserting "$3,200,000";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (82) in item number 64 by striking "$6,560,000" and inserting "$8,480,000";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (83) in item number 2338 by striking "$1,600,000" and inserting "$1,800,000";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (84) in item number 1533 by striking "$392,000" and inserting "$490,000";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (85) in item number 1354 by striking "$40,000" and inserting "$50,000";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (86) in item number 3106 by striking "$400,000" and inserting "$500,000";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (87) in item number 799 by striking "$1,600,000" and inserting "$2,000,000";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (88) in item number 159--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) by striking "Construct interchange for 146th St. and I-69" and inserting "Upgrade 146th St. to I-69 Access"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) by striking "$2,400,000" and inserting "$3,200,000";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (89) by striking item number 2936;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (90) in item number 3138 by striking the project description and inserting "Elimination of highway-railway crossing along the KO railroad from Salina to Osborne to increase safety and reduce congestion";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (91) in item number 2274 by striking "between Farmington and Merriman" and inserting "between Hines Drive and Inkster, Flamingo Street between Ann Arbor Trail and Joy Road, and the intersection of Warren Road and Newburgh Road";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (92) in item number 52 by striking the project description and inserting "Pontiac Trail between E. Liberty and McHattie Street";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (93) in item number 1544 by striking "connector";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (94) in item number 2573 by striking the project description and inserting "Rehabilitation of Sugar Hill Road in North Salem, NY";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (95) in item number 1450 by striking "III-VI" and inserting "III-VII";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (96) in item number 2637 by striking the project description and inserting "Construction, road and safety improvements in Geauga County, OH";</narrative>
  <narrative> (97) in item number 2342 by striking the project description and inserting "Streetscaping, bicycle trails, and related improvements to the I-90/SR-615 interchange and adjacent area and Heisley Road in Mentor, including acquisition of necessary right-of-way within the Newell Creek development to build future bicycle trails and bicycle staging areas that will connect into the existing bicycle trail system at I-90/SR-615, widening the Garfield Road Bridge over I-90 to provide connectivity to the  existing bicycle trail system between the I-90/SR-615 interchange and Lakeland Community College, and acquisition of additional land needed for the preservation of the Lake Metroparks Greenspace Corridor with the Newell Creek development adjacent to the I-90/SR-615 interchange";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (98) in item number 161 by striking the project description and inserting "Construct False Pass causeway and road to the terminus of the south arm breakwater project";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (99) in item number 2002 by striking the project description and inserting "Dowling Road extension/reconstruction west from Minnesota Drive to Old Seward Highway, Anchorage";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (100) in item number 2023 by striking the project description and inserting "Biking and pedestrian trail construction, Kentland";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (101) in item number 2035 by striking "Replace" and inserting "Repair";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (102) in item number 2511 by striking "Replace" and inserting "Rehabilitate";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (103) in item number 2981 by striking the project description and inserting "Roadway improvements on Highway 262 on the Navajo Nation in Aneth";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (104) in item number 2068 by inserting "and approaches" after "capacity";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (105) in item number 98 by striking the project description and inserting "Right-of-way acquisition and construction for the 77th Street reconstruction project, including the Lyndale Avenue Bridge over I-494, Richfield";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (106) in item number 1783 by striking the project description and inserting "Clark Road access improvements, Jacksonville";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (107) in item number 2711 by striking the project description and inserting "Main Street Road Improvements through Springfield, Jacksonville";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (108) in item number 3485 by striking the project description and inserting "Improve SR 105 (Hecksher Drive) from Drummond Point to August Road, including bridges across the Broward River and Dunns Creek, Jacksonville";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (109) in item number 3486 by striking the project description and inserting "Construct improvements to NE 19th Street/NE 19th Terrace from NE 3rd Avenue to NE 8th Avenue, Gainesville";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (110) in item number 3487 by striking the project description and inserting "Construct improvements to NE 25th Street from SR 26 (University Blvd.) to NE 8th Avenue, Gainesville";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (111) in item number 803 by striking "St. Clair County" and inserting "city of Madison";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (112) in item number 615 by striking the project description and inserting "Roadway improvements to Jackson Avenue between Jericho Turnpike and Teibrook Avenue";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (113) by striking item number 889;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (114) in item number 324 by striking the project description and inserting "Alger County, to reconstruct, pave, and realign a portion of H-58 from 2,600 feet south of Little Beaver Lake Road to 4,600 feet east of Hurricane River";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (115) in item number 301 by striking the project description and inserting "Improvements for St. Georges Avenue between East Baltimore Avenue on the southwest and Chandler Avenue on the northeast";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (116) in item number 1519 by inserting "at the intersection of Quincy/West Drinker/Electric Streets near the Dunmore School complex" after "roadway redesign";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (117) in item number 2604 by inserting "on Coolidge, Bridge (from Main to Monroe), Skytop (from Gedding to Skytop), Atwell (from Bear Creek Rd. to Pittston Township), Wood (to Bear Creek Rd.), Pine, Oak (from Penn Avenue to Lackawanna Avenue), McLean, Second, and Lolli Lane" after "roadway redesign";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (118) in item number 1157 by inserting "on Mill Street from Prince Street to Roberts Street, John Street from Roberts Street to end, Thomas Street from Roberts Street to end, Williams Street from Roberts Street to end, Charles Street from Roberts Street to end, Fair Street from Roberts Street to end, Newport Avenue from East Kirmar Avenue to end" after "roadway redesign";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (119) in item number 805 by inserting "on Oak Street from Stark Street to the township line at Mayock Street and on East Mountain Boulevard" after "roadway redesign";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (120) in item number 2704 by inserting "on West Cemetery Street and Frederick Courts" after "roadway redesign";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (121) in item number 4599 by striking the project description and inserting "Pedestrian paths, stairs, seating, landscaping, lighting, and other transportation enhancement activities along Riverside Boulevard and at Riverside Park South";</narrative>
  <narrative> (122) in item number 1363 by striking the project description and inserting "Design, engineering, right-of-way acquisition, and construction of streetscaping enhancements, paving, lighting, safety improvements, handicap access ramps, parking, and roadway redesign on Bilbow Street from Church Street to Pugh Street, on Pugh Street from Swallow Street to Main Street, Jones Lane from Main Street to Hoblak Street, Cherry Street from Green Street to Church Street, Main Street from Jackson Street  to end, Short Street from Cherry Street to Main Street, and Hillside Avenue in Edwardsville Borough, Luzerne County";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (123) in item number 883 by striking the project description and inserting "Design, engineering, right-of-way acquisition, and construction of streetscaping enhancements, paving, lighting, parking, roadway redesign, and safety improvements (including curbing, stop signs, crosswalks, and pedestrian sidewalks) at and around the 3-way intersection involving Susquehanna Avenue, Erie Street, and Second Street in West Pittston, Luzerne County";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (124) in item number 625 by striking the project description and inserting "Design, engineering, right-of-way acquisition, and construction of streetscaping enhancements, paving, lighting, safety improvements, parking, and roadway redesign on Sampson Street, Dunn Avenue, Powell Street, Josephine Street, Pittston Avenue, Railroad Street, McClure Avenue, and Baker Street in Old Forge Borough, Lackawanna County";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (125) in item number 372 by inserting ", replacement of the Nesbitt Street Bridge, and placement of a guard rail adjacent to St. Vladimir's Cemetery on Mountain Road (S.R. 1007)" after "roadway redesign";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (126) in item number 2308 by striking the project description and inserting "Design, engineering, right-of-way acquisition, and construction of streetscaping enhancements, paving, lighting, safety improvements, parking, and roadway redesign, including a project to establish emergency access to Catherino Drive from South Valley Avenue in Throop Borough, Lackawanna County";</narrative>
  <narrative> (127) in item number 967 by striking the project description and inserting "Design, engineering, right-of-way acquisition, and construction of streetscaping enhancements, paving, lighting, safety improvements, parking, roadway redesign, and catch basin restoration and replacement on Cherry Street, Willow Street, Eno Street, Flat Road, Krispin Street, Parrish Street, Carver Street, Church Street, Franklin Street, Carolina Street, East Main Street, and Rear Shawnee Avenue in Plymouth Borough,  Luzerne County";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (128) in item number 989 by inserting "on Old Ashley Road, Ashley Street, Phillips Street, First Street, Ferry Road, and Division Street" after "roadway redesign";</narrative>
  <narrative> (129) in item number 342 by striking the project description and inserting "Design, engineering, right-of-way acquisition, and construction of streetscaping enhancements, paving, lighting, safety improvements, parking, roadway redesign, and cross pipe and catch basin restoration and replacement on Northgate, Mandy Court, Vine Street, and 36th Street in Milnesville West, and on Hillside Drive (including the widening of the bridge on Hillside Drive), Club 40 Road, Sunburst and Venisa Drives,  and Stockton #7 Road in Hazle Township, Luzerne County";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (130) in item number 2332 by striking "Monroe County" and inserting "Carbon, Monroe, Pike, and Wayne Counties";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (131) in item number 4914 by striking the project description and inserting "Roadway improvements on I-90 loop in Mitchell along Haven Street from near Burr Street to near Ohlman Street";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (132) by striking item number 2723;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (133) in item number 61 by striking the matters in the State, project description, and amount columns and inserting "AL", "Grade crossing improvements along Wiregrass Central RR at Boll Weevil Bypass in Enterprise, AL", and "$250,000", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (134) in item number 314 by striking the project description and amount and inserting "Streetscape enhancements to the transit and pedestrian corridor, Fort Lauderdale, Downtown Development Authority" and "$610,000", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (135) in item number 1639 by striking the project description and inserting "Operational and highway safety improvements on Hwy 94 between the 20 mile marker post in Jamul and Hwy 188 in Tecate";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (136) in item number 2860 by striking the project description and inserting "Roadway improvements from Halchita to Mexican Hat on the Navajo Nation";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (137) in item number 2549 by striking "on Navy Pier";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (138) in item number 2804 by striking "on Navy Pier";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (139) in item number 1328 by striking the project description and inserting "Construct public access roadways and pedestrian safety improvements in and around Montclair State University in Clifton";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (140) in item number 2559 by striking the project description and inserting "Construct sound walls on Route 164 at and near the Maersk interchange";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (141) in item number 1849 by striking the project description and inserting "Highway, traffic-flow, pedestrian facility, and streetscape improvements, Pittsburgh";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (142) in item number 697 by striking the project description and inserting "Highway, traffic-flow, pedestrian facility, and streetscape improvements, Pittsburgh";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (143) in item number 3597 by striking the project description and inserting "Road Alignment from IL Route 159 to Sullivan Drive, Swansea";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (144) in item number 2352 by striking the project description and inserting "Streetscaping and transportation enhancements on 7th Street in Calexico, traffic signalization on Highway 78, construction of the Renewable Energy and Transportation Learning Center, improve and enlarge parking lot, and create bus stop, Brawley";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (145) in item number 3482 by striking the project description and inserting "Conduct a study to examine multi-modal improvements to the I-5 corridor between the Main Street Interchange and State Route 54";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (146) in item number 1275 by striking the project description and inserting "Scoping, permitting, engineering, construction management, and construction of Riverbank Park Bike Trail, Kearny";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (147) in item number 726 by striking the project description and inserting "Grade Separation at Vanowen and Clybourn, Burbank";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (148) in item number 1579 by striking the project description and inserting "San Gabriel Blvd. rehabilitation project, Mission Road to Broadway, San Gabriel";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (149) in item number 2690 by striking the project description and inserting "San Gabriel Blvd. rehabilitation project, Mission Road to Broadway, San Gabriel";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (150) in item number 2811 by striking the project description and inserting "San Gabriel Blvd. rehabilitation project, Mission Road to Broadway, San Gabriel";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (151) in item number 259 by striking the project description and inserting "Design and construction of the Clair Nelson Intermodal Center in Finland, Lake County";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (152) in item number 3456 by striking the project description and inserting "Completion of Phase II/Part I of a project on Elizabeth Avenue in Coleraine to west of Itasca County State Aid Highway 15 in Itasca County";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (153) in item number 2329 by striking the project description and inserting "Upgrade streets, undertake streetscaping, and implement traffic and pedestrian safety signalization improvements and highway-rail crossing safety improvements, Oak Lawn";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (154) in item number 766 by striking the project description and inserting "Design and construction of the walking path at Ellis Pond, Norwood";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (155) in item number 3474 by striking the project description and inserting "Yellow River Trail, Newton County";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (156) in item number 3291 by striking the amount and inserting "$200,000";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (157) in item number 3635 by striking the matters in the State, project description, and amount columns and inserting "GA", "Access Road in Montezuma", and "$200,000", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (158) in item number 716 by striking the project description and inserting "Conduct a project study report for new Highway 99 Interchange between SR 165 and Bradbury Road, and safety improvements/realignment of SR 165, serving Turlock/Hilmar region";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (159) in item number 1386 by striking the project description and amount and inserting "Pedestrian and bicycle facilities, and street lighting in Haddon Heights" and "$300,000", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (160) in item number 2720 by striking the project description and amount and inserting "Pedestrian and bicycle facilities and street lighting in Barrington and streetscape improvements to Clements Bridge Road from the circle at the White Horse Pike to NJ Turnpike overpass in Barrington" and "$700,000", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (161) in item number 2523 by striking the project description and inserting "Penobscot Riverfront Development for bicycle trails, amenities, traffic circulation improvements, and waterfront access or stabilization, Bangor and Brewer";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (162) in item number 545 by striking the project description and inserting "Planning, design, and construction of improvements to the highway systems connecting to Lewistown and Auburn downtowns";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (163) by striking item number 2168;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (164) by striking item number 170;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (165) in item number 2366 by striking the project description and inserting "Design, engineering, right-of-way acquisition, and paving of the parking lot at the Casey Plaza in Wilkes-Barre Township";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (166) in item number 826 by striking "and Interstate 81" and inserting "and exit 168 on Interstate 81 or the intersection of the connector road with Northampton St.";</narrative>
  <narrative> (167) in item number 2144 by striking the project description and inserting "Design, engineering, right-of-way acquisition and construction of streetscaping enhancements, paving, lighting, safety improvements, parking, and roadway redesign on Third Street from Pittston Avenue to Packer Street; Swift Street from Packer Street to Railroad Street; Clark Street from Main Street to South Street; School Street from Main Street to South Street; Plane Street from Grove Street to William Street; John  Street from 4 John Street to William Street; Grove Street from Plane Street to Duryea Borough line; Wood Street from Cherry Street to Hawthorne Street in Avoca Borough, Luzerne County";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (168) in item number 1765 by striking the project description and amount and inserting "Design, engineering, right-of-way acquisition, and construction of street improvements, streetscaping enhancements, paving, lighting, safety improvements, parking, roadway redesign in Pittston, including right-of-way acquisition, structure demolition, and intersection safety improvements in the vicinity of and including Main, William, and Parsonage Streets in Pittston" and "$1,600,000", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (169) in item number 2957 by striking the project description and amount and inserting "Design, engineering, land acquisition, right-of-way acquisition, and construction of a parking garage, streetscaping enhancements, paving, lighting, safety improvements, parking, and roadway redesign in the city of Wilkes-Barre" and "$2,800,000", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (170) in item number 3283 by striking the project description and amount and inserting "Pedestrian access improvements, including installation of infrastructure and equipment for security and surveillance purposes at subway stations in Astoria, New York" and "$1,300,000", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (171) in item number 3556 by striking the project description and amount and inserting "Design and rehabilitate staircases used as streets due to the steep grade of terrain in Bronx County" and "$1,100,000", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (172) by striking item number 203;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (173) by striking item number 552;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (174) by striking item number 590;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (175) by striking item number 759;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (176) by striking item number 879;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (177) by striking item number 1071;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (178) by striking item number 1382;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (179) by striking item number 1897;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (180) by striking item number 2553;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (181) in item number 3014 by striking the project description and amount and inserting "Design and Construct school safety projects in New York City" and "$2,500,000", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (182) in item number 2375 by striking the project description and amount and inserting "Subsurface environmental study to measure presence of methane and benzene gasses in vicinity of Greenpoint, Brooklyn, and the Kosciusko Bridge, resulting from the Newtown Creek oil spill" and "$100,000";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (183) in item number 221 by striking the project description and inserting "Study and Implement transportation improvements on Flatbush Ave. between Avenue U and the Marine Park Bridge in front of Gateway National Park in Kings County, New York";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (184) in item number 2732 striking the project description and inserting "Pedestrian safety improvements in the vicinity of LIRR stations";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (185) by striking item number 99;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (186) in item number 398 by striking the project description and inserting "Construct a new 2-lane road extending north from University Park Drive and improvements to University Park Drive";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (187) in item number 446 by striking the project description and inserting "Transportation improvements for development of the Williamsport-Pile Bay Road corridor";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (188) in item number 671 by striking "and Pedestrian Trail Expansion" and inserting ", including parking facilities and Pedestrian Trail Expansion";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (189) in item number 674 by striking the matters in the State, project description, and amount columns and inserting "AL", "Grade crossing improvements along Conecuh Valley  RR at Henderson Highway (CR-21) in Troy, AL", and "$300,000", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (190) in item number 739 by striking the matters in the State, project description, and amount columns and inserting "AL", "Grade crossing improvements along Luxapalila Valley RR in Lamar and Fayette Counties, AL (Crossings at CR-6, CR-20, SH-7, James Street, and College Drive)", and "$300,000", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (191) in item number 746 by striking "Planning and construction of a bicycle trail adjacent to the I-90 and SR 615 Interchange in" and inserting "Planning, construction, and extension of bicycle trails adjacent to the I-90 and SR 615 Interchange, along the Greenway Corridor and throughout";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (192) in item number 749 by striking the matters in the State, project description, and amount columns and inserting "PA", "UPMC Heliport in Bedford", and "$750,000", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (193) in item number 813 by striking the project description and inserting "Preliminary design and study of long-term roadway approach alternatives to TH 36/SH 64 St. Croix River Crossing Project";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (194) in item number 816 by striking "$800,000" and inserting "$880,000";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (195) in item number 852 by striking "Acquire Right-of-Way for Ludlam Trail, Miami, Florida" and inserting "Planning, design, and engineering, Ludlam Trail, Miami";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (196) in item number 994 by striking the matters in the State, project description, and amount columns and inserting "PA", "Construct 2 flyover ramps and S. Linden Street exit for access to industrial sites in the cities of McKeesport and Duquesne", and "$500,000", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (197) in item number 1015 by striking the project description and inserting "Mississippi River Crossing connecting I-94 and US 10 between US 160 and TH 101, MN";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (198) in item number 1101 by striking the project description and inserting "I-285 underpass/tunnel assessment and engineering and interchange improvements in Sandy Springs";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (199) in item number 1211 by striking the matters in the State, project description, and amount columns and inserting "PA", "Road improvements and upgrades related to the Pennsylvania State Baseball Stadium", and "$500,000", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (200) in item number 1345 by striking "to Stony Creek Park, 25 Mile Road in Shelby Township" and inserting "south to the city of Utica";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (201) in item number 1501 by striking the project description and inserting "Construction and right-of-way acquisition of TH 241, CSAH 35 and associated streets in the city of St. Michael";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (202) in item number 1525 by striking "north of CSX RR Bridge" and inserting "US Highway 90";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (203) in item number 1847 by striking the project description and inserting "Improve roads, sidewalks, and road drainage, City of Seward";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (204) in item number 2031 by striking the project description and inserting "Construct and improve Westside Parkway in Fulton County";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (205) in item number 2103 by striking "$2,000,000" and inserting "$3,000,000";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (206) in item number 2219 by striking "SR 91 in City of Twinsburg, OH" and inserting "Center Valley Parkway in Twinsburg, OH";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (207) in item number 2302 by inserting "and other road improvements to Safford Street" after "crossings";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (208) in item number 2560 by striking the project description and inserting "I-285 underpass/tunnel assessment and engineering and interchange improvements in Sandy Springs";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (209) in item number 2563 by striking the project description and amount and inserting "Construct hike and bike path as part of Bridgeview Bridge replacement in Macomb County" and "$486,400", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (210) in item number 2698 by striking the project description and inserting "Interchanges at I-95/Ellis Road and between Grant Road and Micco Road, Brevard County";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (211) in item number 3141 by striking "$2,800,000" and inserting "$1,800,000";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (212) by striking item number 3160;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (213) in item number 3353 by inserting "and construction" after "mitigation";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (214) in item number 996 by striking "$2,000,000" and inserting "$687,000";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (215) in item number 2166 by striking the project description and inserting "Design, right-of-way acquisition, and construction for I-35 and CSAH2 interchange and CSAH2 corridor to TH61 in Forest Lake";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (216) in item number 3251 by striking the project description and inserting "I-94 and Radio Drive Interchange and frontage road project, design, right-of-way acquisition, and construction, Woodbury";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (217) in item number 1488 by striking the project description and inserting "Construct a 4-lane highway between Maverick Junction and the Nebraska border";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (218) in item number 3240 by striking the project description and inserting "Railroad-highway crossings in Pierre";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (219) in item number 1738 by striking "Paving" and inserting "Planning, design, and construction";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (220) in item number 3672 by striking the project description and inserting "Pave remaining stretch of BIA Route 4 from the junction of the BIA Route 4 and N8031 in Pinon, AZ, to the Navajo and Hopi border";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (221) in item number 2424 by striking "Construction" and inserting "preconstruction (including survey and archeological clearances) and construction";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (222) in item number 1216 by striking the matters in the State, project description, and amount columns and inserting "PA", "For roadway construction improvements to Route 222 relocation, Lehigh County", and "$1,313,000", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (223) in item number 2956 by striking "$1,360,000" and inserting "$2,080,000";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (224) in item number 1256 by striking the matters in the State, project description, and amount columns and inserting "PA", "Construction of a bridge over Brandywine Creek as part of the Boot Road extension project, Downingtown Borough", and "$700,000", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (225) in item number 1291 by striking the matters in the State, project description, and amount columns and inserting "PA", "Enhance parking facilities in Chester Springs, Historic Yellow Springs", and "$20,000", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (226) in item number 1304 by striking the matters in the State, project description, and amount columns and inserting "PA", "Improve the intersection at SR 100/SR 4003 (Kernsville Road), Lehigh County", and "$250,000", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (227) in item number 1357 by striking the matters in the State, project description, and amount columns and inserting "PA", "Intersection signalization at SR 3020 (Newburg Road)/Country Club Road, Northampton County", and "$250,000", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (228) in item number 1395 by striking the matters in the State, project description, and amount columns and inserting "PA", "Improve the intersection at SR 100/SR 29, Lehigh County", and "$220,000", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (229) in item number 80 by striking "$4,544,000" and inserting "$4,731,200";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (230) in item number 2096 by striking "$4,800,000" and inserting "$5,217,600";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (231) in item number 1496 by striking the matters in the State, project description, and amount columns and inserting "PA", "Study future needs of East-West road infrastructure in Adams County", and "$115,200", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (232) in item number 2193 by striking the project description and inserting "710 Freeway Study to comprehensively evaluate the technical feasibility of a tunnel alternative to close the 710 Freeway gap, considering all practicable routes, in addition to any potential route previously considered, and with no funds to be used for preliminary engineering or environmental review except to the extent necessary to determine feasibility";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (233) in item number 2445 by striking the project description and inserting "$600,000 for road and pedestrian safety improvements on Main Street in the Village of Patchogue; $900,000 for road and pedestrian safety improvements on Montauk Highway, between NYS Route 112 and Suffolk County Road 101 in Suffolk County";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (234) in item number 346 by striking the project description and inserting "Hansen Dam Recreation Area access improvements, including hillside stabilization and parking lot rehabilitation along Osborne Street between Glenoaks Boulevard and Dronfield Avenue";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (235) by striking item number 449;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (236) in item number 3688 by striking "road" and inserting "trail";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (237) in item number 3695 by striking "in Soldotna" and inserting "in the Kenai River corridor";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (238) in item number 3699 by striking "to improve fish habitat";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (239) in item number 3700 by inserting "and ferry facilities" after "a ferry";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (240) in item number 3703 by inserting "or other roads" after "Cape Blossom Road";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (241) in item number 3704 by striking "Fairbanks" and inserting "Alaska Highway";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (242) in item number 3705 by striking "in Cook Inlet for the Westside development/Williamsport-Pile Bay Road" and inserting "for development of the Williamsport-Pile Bay Road corridor";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (243) in item number 3829 by striking the amount and inserting "$3,050,000";</narrative>
  <narrative> (244) by inserting after item number 3829 the following:&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <narrative> (245) in item number 4788 by striking the project description and inserting "Heidelberg Borough/Scott Township/Carnegie Borough for design, engineering, acquisition, and construction of streetscaping enhancements, paving, lighting and safety upgrades, and parking improvements";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (246) in item number 3861 by striking the project description and inserting "Creation of a greenway path along the Naugatuck River in Waterbury";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (247) in item number 3883 by striking the project description and inserting "Wilmington Riverfront Access and Street Grid Redesign";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (248) in item number 3892 by striking "$5,000,000" and inserting "$8,800,000";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (249) in item number 3894 by striking "$5,000,000" and inserting "$1,200,000";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (250) in item number 3909 by striking the project description and inserting "S.R. 281, the Avalon Boulevard Expansion Project from Interstate 10 to U.S. Highway 91";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (251) in item number 3911 by striking the project description and inserting "Construct a new bridge at Indian Street, Martin County";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (252) in item number 3916 by striking the project description and inserting "City of Hollywood for U.S. 1/Federal Highway, north of Young Circle";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (253) in item number 3937 by striking the project description and inserting "Kingsland bypass from CR 61 to I-95, Camden County";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (254) in item number 3945 by striking "CR 293 to CS 5231" and inserting "SR 371 to SR 400";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (255) in item number 3965 by striking "transportation projects" and inserting "and air quality projects";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (256) in item number 3986 by striking the project description and inserting "Extension of Sugarloaf Parkway, Gwinnett County"; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (257) in item number 3999 by striking "Bridges" and inserting "Bridge and Corridor";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (258) in item number 4003 by striking the project description and inserting "City of Council Bluffs and Pottawattamie County East Beltway Roadway and Connectors Project";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (259) in item number 4043 by striking "MP 9.3, Segment I, II, and III" and inserting "Milepost 24.3";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (260) in item number 4050 by striking the project description and inserting "Preconstruction and construction activities of U.S. 51 between the Assumption Bypass and Vandalia";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (261) in item number 4058 by striking the project description and inserting "For improvements to the road between Brighton and Bunker Hill in Macoupin County";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (262) in each of item numbers 4062 and 4084 by striking the project description and inserting "Preconstruction, construction, and related research and studies of I-290 Cap the Ike project in the village of Oak Park";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (263) in item number 4089 by inserting "and parking facility/entrance improvements serving the Museum of Science and Industry" after "Lakeshore Drive";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (264) in item number 4103 by inserting "and adjacent to the" before "Shawnee";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (265) in item number 4110 by striking the project description and inserting "For improvements to the road between Brighton and Bunker Hill in Macoupin County";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (266) in item number 4120 by striking the matters in the project description and amount columns and inserting "Upgrade 146th Street to Improve I-69 Access" and "$800,000", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (267) in item number 4125 by striking "$250,000" and inserting "$1,650,000";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (268) by striking item number 4170;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (269) by striking item number 4179;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (270) in item number 4185 by striking the project description and inserting "Replace the Clinton Street Bridge spanning St. Mary's River in downtown Fort Wayne";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (271) in item number 4299 by striking the project description and inserting "Improve U.S. 40, MD 715 interchange and other roadways in the vicinity of Aberdeen Proving Ground to support BRAC-related growth";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (272) in item number 4313 by striking "Maryland Avenue" and all that follows through "Rd. corridor" and inserting "intermodal access, streetscape, and pedestrian safety improvements";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (273) in item number 4315 by striking "stormwater mitigation project" and inserting "environmental preservation project";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (274) in item number 4318 by striking the project description and inserting "Planning, design, and construction of improvements to the highway systems connecting to Lewiston and Auburn downtowns";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (275) in item number 4323 by striking the project description and inserting "MaineDOT Acadia intermodal passenger and maintenance facility";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (276) in item number 4338 by striking the project description and inserting "Construct 1 or more grade-separated crossings of I-75, and make associated improvements to improve local and regional east-west mobility between Mileposts 279 and 282";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (277) in item number 4355 by striking the project description and inserting "Design, engineering, ROW acquisition, construction, and construction engineering for the reconstruction of TH 95, from 12th Avenue to CSAH 13, including bridge and approaches, ramps, intersecting roadways, signals, turn lanes, and multiuse trail, North Branch";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (278) in item number 4357 by striking the project description and inserting "Design, construct, ROW, and expand TH 241 and CSAH 35 and associated streets in the city of St. Michael";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (279) in item number 4360 by striking the project description and inserting "Planning, design, and construction for Twin Cities Bioscience Corridor in St. Paul";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (280) in item number 4362 by striking the project description and inserting "I-494/U.S. 169 interchange reconstruction including U.S. 169/Valley View Road interchange, Twin Cities Metropolitan Area";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (281) in item number 4365 by striking the project description and inserting "34th Street realignment and 34th Street and I-94 interchange, including retention and reconstruction of the SE Main Avenue/CSAH 52 interchange ramps at I-94, and other transportation improvements for the city of Moorhead, including the SE Main Avenue GSI and Moorhead Comprehensive Rail Safety Program";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (282) in item number 4369 by striking the project description and inserting "Construction of 8th Street North, Stearns C.R. 120 to TH 15 in St. Cloud";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (283) in item number 4371 by striking the project description and inserting "Construction and ROW of TH 241, CSAH 35 and associated streets in the city of St. Michael";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (284) in item number 4411 by striking "Southaven" and inserting "DeSoto County";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (285) in item number 4424 by striking the project description and inserting "U.S. 93 Evaro to Polson transportation improvement projects";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (286) in item number 4428 by striking the project description and inserting "US 76 improvements";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (287) in item number 4457 by striking the project description and inserting "Construct an interchange at an existing grade separation at SR 1602 (Old Stantonsburg Rd.) and U.S. 264 Bypass in Wilson County";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (288) in item number 4461 by striking the project description and inserting "Transportation and related improvements at Queens University of Charlotte, including the Queens Science Center and the Marion Diehl Center, Charlotte";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (289) in item number 4507 by striking the project description and inserting "Design, right-of-way acquisition, and construction of Highway 35 between Norfolk and South Sioux City, including an interchange at milepost 1 on U.S. I-129";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (290) in item number 4555 by inserting "Canal Street and" after "Reconstruction of";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (291) in item number 4565 by striking the project description and inserting "Railroad Construction and Acquisition, Ely and White Pine County";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (292) in item number 4588 by inserting "Private Parking and" before "Transportation";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (293) in item number 4596 by striking the project description and inserting "Centerway Bridge and Bike Trail Project, Corning";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (294) in item number 4610 by striking the project description and inserting "Preparation, demolition, disposal, and site restoration of Alert Facility on Access Road to Plattsburgh International Airport";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (295) in item number 4649 by striking the project description and inserting "Fairfield County, OH U.S. 33 and old U.S. 33 safety improvements and related construction, city of Lancaster and surrounding areas";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (296) in item number 4651 by striking "for the transfer of rail to truck for the intermodal" and inserting ", and construction of an intermodal freight";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (297) in item number 4691 by striking the project description and inserting "Transportation improvements to Idabel Industrial Park Rail Spur, Idabel";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (298) in item number 4722 by striking the project description and inserting "Highway, traffic, pedestrian, and riverfront improvements, Pittsburgh";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (299) in item number 4749 by striking "study" and inserting "improvements";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (300) in item number 4821 by striking "highway grade crossing project, Clearfield and Clinton Counties" and inserting "Project for highway grade crossings and other purposes relating to the Project in Cambria, Centre, Clearfield, Clinton, Indiana, and Jefferson Counties";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (301) in item number 4838 by striking "study" and inserting "improvements";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (302) in item number 4839 by striking "fuel-celled" and inserting "fueled";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (303) in item number 4866 by striking "$11,000,000" and inserting "$9,400,000";</narrative>
  <narrative> (304) by inserting after item number 4866 the following:&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <narrative> (305) in item number 4892 by striking the project description and inserting "Construct a 4-lane highway between maverick Junction and the Nebraska border";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (306) in item number 4916 by striking "$1,000,000" and inserting "$328,000";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (307) in item number 4924 by striking "$3,450,000" and inserting "$4,122,000";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (308) in item number 4960 by inserting "of which $50,000 shall be used for a street paving project, Calhoun" after "County";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (309) in item number 4974 by striking ", Sevier County";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (310) in item number 5008 by inserting "/Kane Creek Boulevard" after "500 West";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (311) in each of item numbers 5011 and 5033 by striking "200 South Interchange" and inserting "400 South Interchange";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (312) in item number 5021 by striking "Pine View Dam,";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (313) in item number 5026 by striking the project description and inserting "Roadway improvements on Washington Fields Road/300 East, Washington";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (314) in item number 5027 by inserting "and roadway improvements" after "safety project";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (315) in item number 5028 by inserting "and roadway improvements" after "lighting";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (316) in item number 5029 by inserting "and roadway improvements" after "lights";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (317) in number 5032 by striking the project description and inserting "Expand Redhills Parkway, St. George";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (318) in item number 5132 by striking the project description and inserting "St. Croix River crossing project, Wisconsin State Highway 64, St. Croix County, Wisconsin, to Minnesota State Highway 36, Washington County";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (319) in item number 5161 by striking the project description and inserting "Raleigh Street Extension Project in Martinsburg";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (320) in item number 1824 by striking the project description and inserting "U.S. Route 10 expansion in Wadena and Ottertail Counties";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (321) in item number 1194 by striking the project description and inserting "Roadway and pedestrian design and improvements for Pennsylvania Avenue, Brooklyn";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (322) in item number 2286 by striking the project description and inserting "Road improvements for Church Street between NY State Route 25A and Hilden Street in Kings Park";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (323) in item number 1724 by striking the project description and amount and inserting "For road resurfacing and upgrades to Old Nichols Road and road repairs in the Nissequogue River watershed in Smithtown" and "$1,500,000", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (324) in item number 3636 by striking the matters in the State, project description, and amount columns and inserting "NY", "Road repair and maintenance in the Town of Southampton", and "$500,000", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (325) in item number 3638 by striking the matters in the State, project description, and amount columns and inserting "NY", "Improve NY State Route 112 from Old Town Road to NY State Route 347", and "$6,000,000", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (326) in item number 3479 by striking the project description and inserting "Road improvements and utility relocations within the city of Jackson";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (327) in item number 141 by striking "construction of pedestrian and bicycle improvements" and inserting "transportation enhancement activities";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (328) in item number 1204 by striking "at SR 283";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (329) in item number 2896 by striking the project description and inserting "Improve streetscape and signage and pave roads in McMinn County, including $50,000 that may be used for paving local roads in the city of Calhoun";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (330) in item number 3017 by striking ", Pine View Dam";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (331) in item number 3188 insert after "Reconstruction" the following: "including U.S. 169/Valley View Road Interchange,";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (332) in item number 1772 by striking the project description and inserting "Reconstruction of Historic Eastern Parkway";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (333) in item number 2610 by striking the project description and inserting "Reconstruction of Times and Duffy Squares in New York City";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (334) in item number 2462--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) by striking "of the New Jersey Turnpike, Carteret" and inserting "and the Tremley Point Connector Road of the New Jersey Turnpike"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) by striking "$1,200,000" and inserting "$450,000";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (335) in item number 2871 by striking the amount and inserting "$2,430,000";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (336) in item number 3381 by striking the project description and inserting "Determine scope, design, engineering, and construction of Western Boulevard Extension from Northern Boulevard to Route 9 in Ocean County, New Jersey";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (337) in item number 2703 by striking the project description and inserting "Upgrading existing railroad crossings with installation of active signals and gates and to study the feasibility and necessity of rail grade separation";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (338) in item number 1004 by inserting "SR 71 near" after "turn lane on";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (339) in item number 2824 by striking the project description and inserting the following: "Sevier County, TN, SR 35 near SR 449 intersection";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (340) in item number 373 by striking the project description and inserting "Widening existing Highway 226, including a bypass of Cash and a new connection to Highway 49";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (341) in item number 1486, by striking the project description and inserting "Bridge reconstruction and road widening on Route 252 and Route 30 in Tredyffrin Township, PA, in conjunction with the Paoli Transportation Center Project";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (342) in item number 4541 by striking "of the New Jersey Turnpike, Carteret" and inserting "and the Tremley Point Connector Road of the New Jersey Turnpike";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (343) in item number 4006 by striking the project description and inserting "Improvement to Alice's Road/105th Street Corridor including bridge, interchange, roadway, right-of-way, and enhancements";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (344) in item number 2901 by striking the project description and inserting "Purchase of land and conservation easements within U.S. 24 study area in Lucas, Henry, and Fulton Counties, Ohio";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (345) in item number 2619 by striking the project description and inserting "Improve access to I-55 between Bayless Avenue and Loughborough Avenue, including bridge 230.06";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (346) in item number 1687 by striking the project description and inserting "Construct an interchange at I-675 and Warren Avenue near downtown Saginaw";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (347) by striking item number 206;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (348) by striking item number 821;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (349) by striking item number 906;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (350) by striking item number 1144;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (351) in item number 1693 by striking the project description and amount and inserting "Plan and implement truck route improvements in the Maspeth neighborhood of Queens County" and "$500,000", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (352) in item number 3039 by striking the project description and inserting "Pittsfield greenways construction to connect Pittsfield to the Ann Arbor greenway system, Pittsfield Township";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (353) in item number 2922 by striking the project description and amount and inserting "Detroit River International Wildlife Refuge for land acquisition adjacent to I-75 in Monroe County for wetland mitigation and habitat restoration, Fish and Wildlife Service" and "$1,800,000", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (354) in item number 3641 by striking the matters in the State, project description, and amount columns and inserting "MI", "River Raisin Battlefield for acquisition of historic battlefield land in Monroe County, Port of Monroe", and "$1,200,000"; respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (355) in item number 3643 by striking the matters in the State, project description, and amount columns and inserting "MI", "Phase 1 of Monroe County greenway system construction, Monroe County", and "$940,000", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (356) in item number 3645 by striking the matters in the State, project description, and amount columns and inserting "MI", "East County fueling operations consolidation at the Monroe County Road Commission and enhancement of facilities to accommodate biodiesel fuel pumps, Monroe County", and "$1,000,000", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (357) in item number 3646 by striking the matters in the State, project description, and amount columns and inserting "MI", "Greenway trail construction from City of Monroe to Sterling State Park, City of Monroe", and "$100,000"; respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (358) in item number 1883 by striking the project description and inserting "Planning for the Orangeline High Speed MAGLEV from Los Angeles County to Orange County";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (359) in item number 3757 by inserting ", including Van Asche Drive" after "Corridor";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (360) in item number 4347 by striking the project description and inserting "Alger County, to reconstruct, pave, and realign a portion of H-58 from 2,600 feet south of Little Beaver Lake Road to 4,600 feet east of Hurricane River";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (361) in item number 4335 by striking the project description and inserting "Construct an interchange at I-675 and Warren Avenue near downtown Saginaw";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (362) in item number 4891 by striking the project description and inserting "Widening U.S. 17 in Charleston County from the Isle of Palms Connector to a point at or near Darrell Creek Trail";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (363) in item number 3647 by striking the matters in the State, project description, and amount columns and inserting "AL", "Drainage and infrastructure improvements on U.S. 11 in front of Springville Middle School in Springville", and "$1,000,000", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (364) in item number 3648 by striking the matters in the State, project description, and amount columns and inserting "AL", "Transportation enhancement projects for sidewalks and streetscaping along Cahaba Road between the Botanical Gardens and the Birmingham Zoo in the City of Birmingham", and "$1,075,000", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (365) in item number 3651 by striking the matters in the State, project description, and amount columns and inserting "AL", "Engineering and right-of-way acquisition for the McWrights Ferry Road extension between Rice Mine Road and New Watermelon Road in Tuscaloosa County", and "$1,075,000", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (366) in item number 562 by striking "a designated truck route through" and inserting "roadway and sidewalk improvements in";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (367) in item number 2836 by striking the project description and inserting "Traffic calming and safety improvements to Lido Boulevard, Town of Hampstead, Nassau County";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (368) in item number 1353 by striking the project description and inserting "Improve the flow of truck traffic in Orrville";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (369) in item number 1975 by striking the project description and inserting "Hatcher Pass Ski Development Road in Matanuska-Susitna Borough";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (370) in item number 1661 by striking the project description and inserting "Hatcher Pass Ski Development Road in Matanuska-Susitna Borough";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (371) in item number 1574 by striking the project description and inserting "Construct commuter parking structure in the central business district in the vicinity of La Grange Road, and for projects identified by the Village of La Grange as its highest priorities";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (372) in item number 3461 by striking the project description and inserting "Construct Leon Pass overpass, and for projects identified by the Village of Hodgkins as its highest priorities";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (373) in item numbers 1310 and 2265 by striking the project descriptions and inserting "To construct up to 2 interchanges on U.S. Alternate Highway 72/Alabama Highway 20 from Interstate 65 to U.S. Highway 31 in Decatur, Alabama, with additional lanes as necessary";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (374) in item number 4934 by striking "connection with Hermitage Avenue" and inserting "Hermitage Avenue and pedestrian connection";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (375) in item number 1227 by striking the project description and inserting "Construct road improvements near industrial park near SR 209 and CR 345 that improve access to the industrial park";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (376) in item number 2507 by striking the project description and inserting "Texas Department of Transportation: for those projects the Department has identified as its highest priorities";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (377) in item number 3903 by striking the project description and inserting "Planning, design, and engineering study to widen (4 lanes) SR 87 from the intersection of US 90 and SR 87 South to the Alabama State line";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (378) in item number 56 by striking the project description and inserting "Bicycle and pedestrian improvements, Oregon";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (379) in item number 604 by striking the amount and inserting "$11,800,000";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (380) in item number 1299 by striking the amount and inserting "$9,800,000";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (381) in item number 1506 by striking the amount and inserting "$5,100,000";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (382) in item number 1904 by striking the project description and inserting "Study and construct access to intermodal facility in Azusa";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (383) in item number 3653 by striking the matters in the State, project description, and amount columns and inserting "MI", "Bicycle and pedestrian trails in Harrison Township", and "$2,900,000", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (384) in item number 3447 by striking the project description and inserting "Carlton, 4th Street Railroad Crossing Improvement Project: Construct a safe, at grade crossing of the railroad and necessary bridge, connecting the community's educational and athletic facilities";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (385) in item number 2321 by striking the project description and inserting "Design and construct roadway and traffic signal improvements on Stella Street and Front Street, Wormleysburg, PA"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (386) in item number 370 by striking the project description and inserting "Pedestrian paths, stairs, seating, landscaping, lighting, and other transportation enhancement activities along Riverside Boulevard and at Riverside Park South".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Unused Obligation Authority.--Notwithstanding any other provision of law, unused obligation authority made available for an item in section 1702 of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (119 Stat. 1256) that is repealed, or authorized funding for such an item that is reduced, by this section shall be made available-- &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) for an item in section 1702 of that Act that is added or increased by this section and that is in the same State as the item for which obligation authority or funding is repealed or reduced;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) in an amount proportional to the amount of obligation authority or funding that is so repealed or reduced; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) individually for projects numbered 1 through 3676 pursuant to section 1102(c)(4)(A) of that Act (119 Stat. 1158).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Transfer of Project Funds.--The Secretary of Transportation shall transfer to the Commandant of the Coast Guard amounts made available to carry out the project described in item number 4985 of the table contained in section 1702 of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (119 Stat. 1447) to carry out that project, in accordance with the Act of June 21, 1940, commonly known as the "Truman-Hobbs Act", (33 U.S.C. 511 et seq.).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (d) Additional Discretionary Use of Surface Transportation Program Funds.--Of the funds apportioned to each State under section 104(b)(3) of title 23, United States Code, a State may expend for each of fiscal years 2008 and 2009 not more than $1,000,000 for the following activities:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) Participation in the Joint Operation Center for Fuel Compliance established under section 143(b)(4)(H) of title 23, United States Code, within the Department of the Treasury, including the funding of additional positions for motor fuel tax enforcement officers and other staff dedicated on a full-time basis to participation in the activities of the Center.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) Development, operation, and maintenance of electronic filing systems to coordinate data exchange with the Internal Revenue Service by States that impose a tax on the removal of taxable fuel from any refinery and on the removal of taxable fuel from any terminal.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) Development, operation, and maintenance of electronic single point of filing in conjunction with the Internal Revenue Service by States that impose a tax on the removal of taxable fuel from any refinery and on the removal of taxable fuel from any terminal.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) Development, operation, and maintenance of a certification system by a State of any fuel sold to a State or local government (as defined in section 4221(d)(4) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) for the exclusive use of the State or local government or sold to a qualified volunteer fire department (as defined in section 150(e)(2) of such Code) for its exclusive use.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) Development, operation, and maintenance of a certification system by a State of any fuel sold to a nonprofit educational organization (as defined in section 4221(d)(5) of such Code) that includes verification of the good standing of the organization in the State in which the organization is providing educational services.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (e) Project Federal Share.--Section 1964 of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity: A Legacy for Users (119 Stat. 1519) is amended by adding at the end the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(c) Special Rule.--Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Federal share of the cost of the projects described in item numbers 1284 and 3093 in the table contained in section 1702 of this Act shall be 100 percent.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 106. NONMOTORIZED TRANSPORTATION PILOT PROGRAM.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Section 1807(a)(3) of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (119 Stat. 1460) is amended by striking "Minneapolis-St. Paul, Minnesota" and inserting "Minneapolis, Minnesota".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 107. CORRECTION OF INTERSTATE AND NATIONAL HIGHWAY SYSTEM DESIGNATIONS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Treatment.--Section 1908(a) of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (119 Stat. 1469) is amended by striking paragraph (3).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) National Highway System.--Section 1908(b) of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (119 Stat. 1470) is amended by striking "from the Arkansas State line" and inserting "from Interstate Route 540".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 108. BUDGET JUSTIFICATION; BUY AMERICA.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Budget Justification.--Section 1926 of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (119 Stat. 1483) is amended by striking "The Department" and inserting "Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Department".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Buy America.--Section 1928 of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (119 Stat. 1484) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) by redesignating paragraphs (2) through (5) as paragraphs (3) through (6), respectively; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) by inserting after paragraph (1) the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(2) the current application by the Federal Highway Administration of the Buy America test, that is only applied to components or parts of a bridge project and not the entire bridge project, is inconsistent with this sense of Congress;".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 109. TRANSPORTATION IMPROVEMENTS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; The table contained in section 1934(c) of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (119 Stat. 1486) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in item number 436 by inserting ", Saole," after "Sua";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) in item number 448 by inserting "by removing asphalt and concrete and reinstalling blue cobblestones" after "streets";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) by striking item number 451;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) in item number 452 by striking "$2,000,000" and inserting "$3,000,000";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) in item number 12 by striking "Yukon River" and inserting "Kuskokwim River";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (6) in item number 18 by striking "Engineering and Construction in Merced County" and inserting "and safety improvements/realignment of SR 165 project study report and environmental studies in Merced and Stanislaus Counties";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (7) in item number 38 by striking the project description and inserting "Relocation of the Newark Train Station";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (8) in item number 57 by striking the project description and inserting "Kingsland bypass from CR 61 to I-95, Camden County";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (9) in item number 114 by striking "IA-32" and inserting "SW" after "Construct";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (10) in item number 122 by striking the project description and inserting "Design, right-of-way acquisition, and construction of the SW Arterial and connections to U.S. 20, Dubuque County";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (11) in item number 130 by striking the project description and inserting "Improvements and rehabilitation to rail and bridges on the Appanoose County Community Railroad";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (12) in item number 133 by striking "IA-32";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (13) in item number 138 by striking the project description and inserting "West Spencer Beltway Project";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (14) in item number 142 by striking "MP 9.3, Segment I, II, and III" and inserting "Milepost 24.3";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (15) in item number 161 by striking "Bridge replacement on Johnson Drive and Nall Ave." and inserting "Construction improvements";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (16) in item number 182 by striking the project description and inserting "Improve U.S. 40, M.D. 715 interchange, and other roadways in the vicinity of Aberdeen Proving Ground to support BRAC-related growth";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (17) in item number 198 by striking the project description and inserting "Construct 1 or more grade separated crossings of I-75 and make associated improvements to improve local and regional east-west mobility between Mileposts 279 and 282";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (18) in item number 201 by striking the project description and inserting "Alger County, to reconstruct, pave, and realign a portion of H-58 from 2,600 feet south of Little Beaver Lake Road to 4,600 feet east of Hurricane River";</narrative>
  <narrative> (19) in item number 238 by striking the project description and inserting "Develop and construct the St. Mary water project road and bridge infrastructure, including a new bridge and approaches across St. Mary River, stabilization and improvements to United States Route 89, and road/canal from Siphon Bridge to Spider Lake, on the condition that $2,500,000 of the amount made available to carry out this item may be made available to the Bureau of Reclamation for use for the Swift Current Creek  and Boulder Creek bank and bed stabilization project in the Lower St. Mary Lake drainage";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (20) in item number 329 by inserting ", Tulsa" after "technology";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (21) in item number 358 by striking "fuel-celled" and inserting "fueled";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (22) in item number 374 by striking the project description and inserting "Construct a 4-lane highway between Maverick Junction and the Nebraska border";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (23) in item number 402 by striking "from 2 to 5 lanes and improve alignment within rights-of-way in St. George" and inserting ", St. George";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (24) in item number 309 by striking the project description and inserting "Streetscape, roadway, pedestrian, and parking improvements at the intersection of Meadow Lane, Chestnut Lane, Willow Drive, and Liberty Avenue for the College of New Rochelle campus in New Rochelle"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (25) in item number 462 by striking the project description and inserting "I-75 widening and improvements in Collier and Lee Counties, Florida".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 110. I-95/CONTEE ROAD INTERCHANGE DESIGN.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Section 1961 of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (119 Stat. 1518) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in the section heading by striking "STUDY" and inserting "DESIGN";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) by striking subsections (a), (b), and (c) and inserting the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(a) Design.--The Secretary shall make available the funds authorized to be appropriated by this section for the design of the I-95/Contee Road interchange in Prince George's County, Maryland."; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) by redesignating subsection (d) as subsection (b).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 111. HIGHWAY RESEARCH FUNDING.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) F-SHRP Funding.--Notwithstanding any other provision of law, for each of fiscal years 2008 and 2009, at any time at which an apportionment is made of the sums authorized to be appropriated for the surface transportation program, the congestion mitigation and air quality improvement program, the National Highway System, the Interstate maintenance program, the bridge program, or the highway safety improvement program, the Secretary of Transportation shall--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) deduct from each apportionment an amount not to exceed 0.205 percent of the apportionment; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) transfer or otherwise make that amount available to carry out section 510 of title 23, United States Code.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Conforming Amendments.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) FUNDING.--Section 5101 of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (119 Stat. 1779) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) in subsection (a)(1) by striking "509, and 510" and inserting "and 509";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) in subsection (a)(4) by striking "$69,700,000" and all that follows through "2009" and inserting "$40,400,000 for fiscal year 2005, $69,700,000 for fiscal year 2006, $76,400,000 for each of fiscal years 2007 and 2008, and $78,900,000 for fiscal year 2009"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) in subsection (b) by inserting after "50 percent" the following "or, in the case of funds appropriated by subsection (a) to carry out section 5201, 5202, or 5203 of this Act, 80 percent".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) FUTURE STRATEGIC HIGHWAY RESEARCH PROGRAM.--Section 5210 of such Act (119 Stat. 1804) is amended-- &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) by striking subsection (c); and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) by redesignating subsection (d) as subsection (c).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Contract Authority.--Funds made available under this section shall be available for obligation in the same manner as if the funds were apportioned under chapter 1 of title 23, United States Code, except that the Federal share shall be determined under section 510(f) of that title.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (d) Applicability of Obligation Limitation.--Funds made available under this section shall be subject to any limitation on obligations for Federal-aid highways and highway safety construction programs under section 1102 the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (23 U.S.C. 104 note; 119 Stat. 1157) or any other Act.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (e) Equity Bonus Formula.--Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in allocating funds for the equity bonus program under section 105 of title 23, United States Code, for each of fiscal years 2008 and 2009, the Secretary of Transportation shall make the required calculations under that section as if this section had not been enacted.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (f) Funding for Research Activities.--Of the amount made available by section 5101(a)(1) of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (119 Stat. 1779)--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) at least $1,000,000 shall be made available for each of fiscal years 2008 and 2009 to carry out section 502(h) of title 23, United States Code; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) at least $4,900,000 shall be made available for each of fiscal years 2008 and 2009 to carry out section 502(i) of that title.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (g) Technical Amendments.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) SURFACE TRANSPORTATION RESEARCH.--Section 502 of title 23, United States Code, is amended by striking the first subsection (h), relating to infrastructure investment needs reports beginning with the report for January 31, 1999.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) ADVANCED TRAVEL FORECASTING PROCEDURES PROGRAM.--Section 5512(a)(2) of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (119 Stat. 1829) is amended by striking "PROGRAM APPRECIATION.--" and inserting "PROGRAM APPLICATION.--".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) UNIVERSITY TRANSPORTATION RESEARCH.--Section 5506 of title 49, United States Code, is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) in subsection (c)(2)(B) by striking "tier" and inserting "Tier";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) in subsection (i)--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) by striking "In order to" and inserting the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(1) IN GENERAL.--In order to"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) by adding at the end the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(2) SPECIAL RULE.--Nothing in paragraph (1) requires a nonprofit institution of higher learning designated as a Tier II university transportation center to maintain total expenditures as described in paragraph (1) in excess of the amount of the grant awarded to the institution."; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) in subsection (k)(3) by striking "The Secretary" and all that follows through "to carry out this section" and inserting "For each of fiscal years 2008 and 2009, the Secretary shall expend not more than 1.5 percent of amounts made available to carry out this section".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 112. RESCISSION.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Section 10212 of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (as amended by section 1302 of the Pension Protection Act of 2006 (Public Law 109-280)) (119 Stat. 1937; 120 Stat. 780) is amended by striking "$8,593,000,000" each place it appears and inserting "$8,708,000,000".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 113. TEA-21 TECHNICAL CORRECTIONS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Surface Transportation Program.--Section 1108(f)(1) of the Transportation Equity Act for the 21st Century (23 U.S.C. 133 note; 112 Stat. 141) is amended by striking "2003" and inserting "2009".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Project Authorizations.--The table contained in section 1602 of such Act (112 Stat. 257) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in item number 1096 (as amended by section 1703(a)(11) of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (119 Stat. 1454)) by inserting ", and planning and construction to Heisley Road," before "in Mentor, Ohio";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) in item number 1646 by striking "and construction" and inserting "construction, reconstruction, resurfacing, restoration, rehabilitation, and repaving"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) in item number 614 by inserting "and for NJ Carteret, NJ Ferry Service Terminal" after "east".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 114. HIGH PRIORITY CORRIDOR AND INNOVATIVE PROJECT TECHNICAL CORRECTIONS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) High Priority Corridors.--Section 1105(c) of the Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act of 1991 (105 Stat. 2032; 119 Stat. 1212) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in paragraph (63) by striking "and United States Routes 1, 3, 9, 17, and 46," and inserting "United States Routes 1, 9, and 46, and State Routes 3 and 17,"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) in paragraph (64)--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) by striking "United States Route 42" and inserting "State Route 42"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) by striking "Interstate Route 676" and inserting "Interstate Routes 76 and 676".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Innovative Projects.--Item number 89 of the table contained in section 1107(b) of the Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act of 1991 (105 Stat. 2052) is amended in the matter under the column with the heading "INNOVATIVE PROJECTS" by inserting "and contiguous counties" after "Michigan".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 115. DEFINITION OF REPEAT INTOXICATED DRIVER LAW.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Section 164(a)(5) of title 23, United States Code, is amended by striking subparagraphs (A) and (B) and inserting the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(A) receive--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(i) a driver's license suspension for not less than 1 year; or&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(ii) a combination of suspension of all driving privileges for the first 45 days of the suspension period followed by a reinstatement of limited driving privileges for the purpose of getting to and from work, school, or an alcohol treatment program if an ignition interlock device is installed on each of the motor vehicles owned or operated, or both, by the individual;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(B) be subject to the impoundment or immobilization of, or the installation of an ignition interlock system on, each motor vehicle owned or operated, or both, by the individual;".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 116. RESEARCH TECHNICAL CORRECTION.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Section 5506(e)(5)(C) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by striking "$2,225,000"and inserting "$2,250,000".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 117. BUY AMERICA WAIVER NOTIFICATION AND ANNUAL REPORTS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Waiver Notification.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) IN GENERAL.--If the Secretary of Transportation makes a finding under section 313(b) of title 23, United States Code, with respect to a project, the Secretary shall--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) publish in the Federal Register, before the date on which such finding takes effect, a detailed written justification as to the reasons that such finding is needed; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) provide notice of such finding and an opportunity for public comment on such finding for a period of not to exceed 60 days.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) LIMITATION ON STATUTORY CONSTRUCTION.--Nothing in paragraph (1) shall be construed to require the effective date of a finding referred to in paragraph (1) to be delayed until after the close of the public comment period referred to in paragraph (1)(B).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Annual Reports.--Not later than February 1 of each year beginning after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate a report on the projects for which the Secretary made findings under section 313(b) of title 23, United States Code, during the preceding calendar year and the justifications for such findings.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 118. EFFICIENT USE OF EXISTING HIGHWAY CAPACITY.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Study.--The Secretary of Transportation shall conduct a study on the impacts of converting left and right highway safety shoulders to travel lanes.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Contents.--In conducting the study, the Secretary shall--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) analyze instances in which safety shoulders are used for general purpose vehicle traffic, high occupancy vehicles, and public transportation vehicles;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) analyze instances in which safety shoulders are not part of the roadway design;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) evaluate whether or not conversion of safety shoulders or the lack of a safety shoulder in the original roadway design has a significant impact on the number of accidents or has any other impact on highway safety; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) compile relevant statistics.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Report.--Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall transmit to Congress a report on the results of the study.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 119. FUTURE INTERSTATE DESIGNATION.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) In General.--Subject to subsection (b), the Secretary of Transportation shall designate, as a future Interstate Route 69 Spur, the Audubon Parkway and, as a future Interstate Route 66 Spur, the Natcher Parkway in Owensboro, Kentucky. Any segment of such routes shall become part of the Interstate System (as defined in section 101 of title 23, United States Code) at such time as the Secretary determines that the segment--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) meets the Interstate System design standards approved by the Secretary under section 109(b) of title 23, United States Code; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) connects to an existing Interstate System segment.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Signs.--Section 103(c)(4)(B)(iv) of title 23, United States Code, shall apply to the designations under subsection (a); except that a State may install signs on the 2 parkways that are to be designated under subsection (a) indicating the approximate location of each of the future Interstate System highways.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Removal of Designation.--The Secretary shall remove designation of a highway referred to in subsection (a) as a future Interstate System route if the Secretary, as of the last day of the 25-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, has not made the determinations under paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a) with respect to such highway.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 120. PROJECT FLEXIBILITY.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Section 1935(b)(1) of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (119 Stat. 1510) is amended by inserting "the project numbered 1322 and" before "the projects".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 121. EFFECTIVE DATE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) In General.--Except as otherwise provided in this Act (including subsection (b)), this Act and the amendments made by this Act take effect on the date of enactment of this Act.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Exception.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) IN GENERAL.--The amendments made by this Act (other than the amendments made by sections 101(g), 101(m)(1)(H), 103, 105, 109, and 201(o)) to the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (Public Law 109-59; 119 Stat. 1144) shall--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) take effect as of the date of enactment of that Act; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) be treated as being included in that Act as of that date.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) EFFECT OF AMENDMENTS.--Each provision of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users  (Public Law 109-59; 119 Stat. 1144) (including the amendments made by that Act) (as in effect on the day before the date of enactment of this Act) that is amended by this Act (other than sections 101(g), 101(m)(1)(H), 103, 105, 109, and 201(o)) shall be treated as not being enacted.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Conforming Amendment to Highway Trust Fund.--Subsections (c)(1) and (e)(3) of section 9503 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 are each amended by striking "Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users" and inserting "SAFETEA-LU Technical Corrections Act of 2008".</narrative>
  <narrative>SEC. 201. TRANSIT TECHNICAL CORRECTIONS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Section 5302&lt;/em&gt;.--Section 5302(a)(10) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by striking "charter," and inserting "charter, sightseeing,".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) &lt;em&gt;Section 5303&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) Section 5303(f)(3)(C)(ii) of such title is amended by striking subclause (II) and inserting the following:</narrative>
  <narrative> "(II) FUNDING.--For fiscal year 2008 and each fiscal year thereafter, in addition to other funds made available to the metropolitan planning organization for the Lake Tahoe region under this chapter and title 23, prior to any allocation under section 202 of title 23, and notwithstanding the allocation provisions of section 202, the Secretary shall set aside  1/2  of 1 percent of all funds authorized to be appropriated for such fiscal year to carry out section 204 of title 23, and shall  make such funds available to the metropolitan planning organization for the Lake Tahoe region to carry out the transportation planning process, environmental reviews, preliminary engineering, and design to complete environmental documentation for transportation projects for the Lake Tahoe region under the Tahoe Regional Planning Compact as consented to in Public Law 96-551 (94 Stat. 3233) and this paragraph.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) Section 5303(j)(3)(D) of such title is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) by inserting "or the identified phase" before "within the time"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) by inserting "or the identified phase" before the period at the end.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) Section 5303(k)(2) of such title is amended by striking "a metropolitan planning area serving".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Section 5307&lt;/em&gt;.--Section 5307(b) of such title is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in the heading for paragraph (2) by striking "&lt;b&gt;2007" and inserting "2009";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) in paragraph (2)(A)--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) by striking "2007" and inserting "2009"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) by striking "mass" and inserting "public";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) by adding at the end of paragraph (2) the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(E) MAXIMUM AMOUNTS IN FISCAL YEARS 2008 AND 2009.--In fiscal years 2008 and 2009--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(i) amounts made available to any urbanized area under clause (i) or (ii) of subparagraph (A) shall be not more than 50 percent of the amount apportioned in fiscal year 2002 to the urbanized area with a population of less than 200,000, as determined in the 1990 decennial census of population;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(ii) amounts made available to any urbanized area under subparagraph (A)(iii) shall be not more than 50 percent of the amount apportioned to the urbanized area under this section for fiscal year 2003; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(iii) each portion of any area not designated as an urbanized area, as determined by the 1990 decennial census, and eligible to receive funds under subparagraph (A)(iv), shall receive an amount of funds to carry out this section that is not less than 50 percent of the amount the portion of the area received under section 5311 in fiscal year 2002."; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) in paragraph (3) by striking "section 5305(a)" and inserting "section 5303(k)".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (d) Section 5309&lt;/em&gt;.--Section 5309 of such title is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in subsection (d)(5)(B) by striking "regulation." and inserting "this subsection and shall give comparable, but not necessarily equal, numerical weight to each project justification criteria in calculating the overall project rating.";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) in subsection (e)(6)(B) by striking "subsection." and inserting "subsection and shall give comparable, but not necessarily equal, numerical weight to each project justification criteria in calculating the overall project rating.";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) in the heading for paragraph (2)(A) of subsection (m) by striking "&lt;b&gt;MAJOR CAPITAL" and inserting "CAPITAL"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) in subsection (m)(7)(B) by striking "section 3039" and inserting "section 3045".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (e) Section 5311&lt;/em&gt;.--Section 5311 of such title is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in subsection (g)(1)(A) by striking "for any purpose other than operating assistance" and inserting "for a capital project or project administrative expenses";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) in subsections (g)(1)(A) and (g)(1)(B) by striking "capital" after "net"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) in subsection (i)(1) by striking "Sections 5323(a)(1)(D) and 5333(b) of this title apply" and inserting "Section 5333(b) applies".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (f) &lt;em&gt;Section 5312&lt;/em&gt;.--The heading for section 5312(c) of such title is amended by striking "&lt;em&gt;Mass Transportation" and inserting "Public Transportation".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (g) Section 5314&lt;/em&gt;.--Section 5314(a)(3) is amended by striking "section 5323(a)(1)(D)" and inserting "section 5333(b)".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (h) &lt;em&gt;Section 5319&lt;/em&gt;.--Section 5319 of such title is amended by striking "section 5307(k)" and inserting "section 5307(d)(1)(K)".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) &lt;em&gt;Section 5320&lt;/em&gt;.--Section 5320 of such title is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in subsection (a)(1)(A) by striking "intra--agency" and inserting "intraagency";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) in subsection (b)(5)(A) by striking "5302(a)(1)(A)" and inserting "5302(a)(1)";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) in subsection (d)(1) by inserting "to administer this section and" after "5338(b)(2)(J)";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) by adding at the end of subsection (d) the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(4) &lt;b&gt;TRANSFERS TO LAND MANAGEMENT AGENCIES.--The Secretary may transfer amounts available under paragraph (1) to the appropriate Federal land management agency to pay necessary costs of the agency for such activities described in paragraph (1) in connection with activities being carried out under this section.";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) in subsection (k)(3) by striking "subsection (d)(1)" and inserting "subsection (e)(1)";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (6) by redesignating subsections (a) through (m) as subsections (b) through (n), respectively; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (7) by inserting before subsection (b) (as so redesignated) the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(a) Program Name.--The program authorized by this section shall be known as the Paul S. Sarbanes Transit in Parks Program.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (j) Section 5323&lt;/em&gt;.--Section 5323(n) of such title is amended by striking "section 5336(e)(2)" and inserting "section 5336(d)(2)".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (k) &lt;em&gt;Section 5325&lt;/em&gt;.--Section 5325(b) of such title is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in paragraph (1) by inserting before the period at the end "adopted before August 10, 2005";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) by striking paragraph (2); and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) by redesignating paragraph (3) as paragraph (2).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (l) &lt;em&gt;Section 5336&lt;/em&gt;.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) &lt;b&gt;APPORTIONMENTS OF FORMULA GRANTS.--Section 5336 of such title is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) in subsection (a) by striking "Of the amount" and all that follows before paragraph (1) and inserting "Of the amount apportioned under subsection (i)(2) to carry out section 5307--";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) in subsection (d)(1) by striking "subsections (a) and (h)(2) of section 5338" and inserting "subsections (a)(1)(C)(vi) and (b)(2)(B) of section 5338"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) by redesignating subsection (c), as added by section 3034(c) of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (119 Stat. 1628), as subsection (k).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) TECHNICAL AMENDMENTS.--Section 3034(d)(2) of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (119 Stat. 1629), is amended by striking "paragraph (2)" and inserting "subsection (a)(2)".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (m) Section 5337&lt;/em&gt;.--Section 5337(a) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by striking "for each of fiscal years 1998 through 2003" and inserting "for each of fiscal years 2005 through 2009".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (n) &lt;em&gt;Section 5338&lt;/em&gt;.--Section 5338(d)(1)(B) of such title is amended by striking "section 5315(a)(16)" and inserting "section 5315(b)(2)(P)".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (o) &lt;em&gt;SAFETEA-LU.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) SECTION 3011.--Section 3011(f) of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (119 Stat. 1589) is amended by adding to the end the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(5) Central Florida Commuter Rail Transit Project.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) SECTION 3037.--Section 3037(c) of such Act (119 Stat. 1636) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) in paragraph (3) by striking "Phase II"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) by striking paragraph (10).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) SECTION 3040.--Section 3040(4) of such Act (119 Stat. 1639) is amended by striking "$7,871,895,000" and inserting "$7,872,893,000".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) SECTION 3043.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) PORTLAND, OREGON.--Section 3043(b)(27) of such Act (119 Stat. 1642) is amended by inserting "/Milwaukie" after "Mall".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) LOS ANGELES.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) PHASE 1.--Section 3043(b)(13) of such Act (119 Stat. 1642) is amended to read as follows:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(13) Los Angeles--Exposition LRT (Phase 1).".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) PHASE 2.--Section 3043(c) of such Act (119 Stat. 1645) is amended by inserting after paragraph (104) the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(104A) Los Angeles--Exposition LRT (Phase 2).".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) SAN DIEGO.--Section 3043(c)(105) of such Act (119 Stat. 1645) is amended by striking "LOSSAN Del Mar-San Diego--Rail Corridor Improvements" and inserting "LOSSAN Rail Corridor Improvements".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (D) SAN DIEGO.--Section 3043(c)(217) of such Act (119 Stat. 1648) is amended by striking "San Diego" and inserting "San Diego Transit".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (E) SACRAMENTO.--Section 3043(c)(204) of such Act (119 Stat. 647) is amended by striking "Downtown".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (F) BOSTON.--Section 3043(d)(6) of such Act (119 Stat. 1649) is amended to read as follows:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(6) Boston-Silver Line Phase III, $20,000,000.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (G) PROJECT CONSTRUCTION GRANTS.--Section 3043(e) of such Act (119 Stat. 1651) is amended by adding at the end the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(4) PROJECT CONSTRUCTION GRANTS.--Projects recommended by the Secretary for a project construction grant agreement under section 5309(e) of title 49, United States Code, or for funding under section 5309(m)(2)(A)(i) of such title during fiscal year 2008 and fiscal year 2009 are authorized for preliminary engineering, final design, and construction for fiscal years 2007 through 2009 upon the completion of the notification process for each such project under section 5309(g)(5).".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (H) LOS ANGELES AND SAN GABRIEL VALLEY.--Section 3043 of such Act (119 Stat. 1640) is amended by adding at the end the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(k) Los Angeles Extension.--In evaluating the local share of the project authorized by subsection (c)(104A) in the new starts rating process, the Secretary shall give consideration to project elements of the project authorized by subsection (b)(13) advanced with 100 percent non-Federal funds. &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(l) San Gabriel Valley--Gold Line Foothill Extension Phase II.--In evaluating the local share of the San Gabriel Valley--Gold Line Foothill Extension Phase II project authorized by subsection (b)(33) in the new starts rating process, the Secretary shall give consideration to project elements of the San Gabriel Valley--Gold Line Foothill Extension Phase I project advanced with 100 percent non-Federal funds.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) SECTION 3044.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) PROJECTS.--The table contained in section 3044(a) of such Act (119 Stat. 1652) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) in item 25--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (I) by striking "$217,360" and inserting "$167,360"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (II) by striking "$225,720" and inserting "$175,720";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) in item number 36 by striking the project description and inserting "Los Angeles County Metropolitan Transportation Authority (LACMTA) for bus and bus-related facilities in the LACMTA's service area";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (iii) in item number 71 by inserting "Metropolitan Bus Authority" after "Puerto Rico";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (iv) in item number 84 by striking the project description and inserting "Improvements to the existing Sacramento Intermodal Facility (Sacramento Valley Station)";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (v) in item number 94 by striking the project description and inserting "Pacific Transit, WA Vehicle Replacement";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (vi) in item number 120 by striking "Dayton Airport Intermodal Rail Feasibility Study" and inserting "Greater Dayton Regional Transit Authority buses and bus facilities";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (vii) in item number 152 by inserting "Metropolitan Bus Authority" after "Puerto Rico";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (viii) in item number 416 by striking "Improve marine intermodal" and inserting "Improve marine dry-dock and";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ix) in item number 457--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (I) by striking "$65,000" and inserting "$0"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (II) by striking "$67,500" and inserting "$0"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (x) in item number 458--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (I) by striking "$65,000" and inserting "$130,000";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (II) by striking "$67,500" and inserting "$135,000"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (xi) in item number 57 by striking the project description and inserting "Wilmington, NC, maintenance and operations facilities and administration and transfer facilities";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (xii) in item number 460 by striking the matters in the project description, FY08 column, and FY09 column and inserting "460. Mid-Region Council of Governments, New Mexico, public transportation buses, bus-related equipment and facilities, and intermodal terminals in Albuquerque and Santa Fe", "$500,000", and "$500,000", respectively.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (xiii) in item number 138 by striking "Design" and inserting "Determine scope, engineering, design,";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (xiv) in item number 23 by striking "Construct" and inserting "Design, engineering, right-of-way acquisition, and construction";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (xv) in item number 439 by inserting before "Central" the following: "Design, engineering, right-of-way acquisition, and construction";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (xvi) in item number 453 by inserting before "Central" the following: "Design, engineering, right-of-way acquisition, and construction";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (xvii) in item number 371 by striking the project description and inserting "Regional Transportation Commission of Southern Nevada, Sunset Bus Maintenance Facility";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (xviii) in item number 487 by striking "Central Arkansas Transit Authority Facility Upgrades" and inserting "Central Arkansas Transit Authority Bus Acquisition";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (xix) in item number 491 by striking the project description and inserting "Pace, IL, Cermak Road, Bus Rapid Transit, and related bus projects, and alternatives analysis";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (xx) in item number 512 by striking "Corning, NY, Phase II Corning Preserve Transportation Enhancement Project" and inserting "Transportation Center Enhancements, Corning, NY";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (xxi) in item number 534 by striking "Community Buses" and inserting "Bus and Bus Facilities";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (xxii) in item number 570 by striking "Maine Department of Transportation-Acadia Intermodal Facility" and inserting "MaineDOT Acadia Intermodal Passenger and Maintenance Facility";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (xxiii) in item number 80 by striking the project description and amounts and inserting "Flagler County, Florida-buses and bus facility", "$57,684", "$60,192", "$65,208", and "$67,716" respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (xxiv) in item number 135 by striking the project description and inserting "Pace Suburban Bus, IL-Purchase Vehicles";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (xxv) in item number 276 by striking the project description and amounts and inserting "Long Beach Transit, Long Beach, California, for the purchase of transit vehicles and enhancement of para-transit and senior transportation services", "$128,180", "$133,760", "$144,906", and "$150,480", respectively; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (xxvi) by adding at the end--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (I)(aa) in the project description column "666. New York City, NY, rehabilitation of subway stations to include passenger access improvements including escalators or installation of infrastructure for security and surveillance purposes"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (bb) in the FY08 column and the FY09 column "$50,000";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (II)(aa) in the project description column "667. St. Johns County Council on Aging buses and bus facilities, Florida"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (bb) in the FY06, FY07, FY08, and FY09 columns "$57,684", "$60,192", "$65,208", and "$67,716", respectively;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (III)(aa) in the project description column "668. The City of Compton, California, for the replacement of buses and paratransit vehicles"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (bb) in the FY06, FY07, FY08, and FY09 columns "$128,180", "$133,760", "$144,906", and "$150,480", respectively; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (IV)(aa) in the project description column "669. City of Los Angeles, California, for the purchase of transit vehicles in Watts and enhancement of paratransit and senior transportation services"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (bb) in the FY06, FY07, FY08, and FY09 columns "$128,200", "$133,760", "$144,908", and "$150,480", respectively.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) SPECIAL RULE.--Section 3044(c) of such Act (119 Stat. 1705) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) by inserting ", or other entity," after "State or local governmental authority"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) by striking "projects numbered 258 and 347" and inserting "projects numbered 258, 347, and 411"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (iii) by striking the period at the end and inserting: ", and funds made available for fiscal year 2006 for the bus and bus-related facilities projects numbered 176 and 652 under subsection (a) shall remain available until September 30, 2009.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (6) SECTION 3046.--Section 3046(a)(7) of such Act (119 Stat. 1708) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) by striking "hydrogen fuel cell vehicles" and inserting "hydrogen fueled vehicles";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) by striking "hydrogen fuel cell employee shuttle vans" and inserting "hydrogen fueled employee shuttle vans"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) by striking "in Allentown, Pennsylvania" and inserting "to the DaVinci Center in Allentown, Pennsylvania".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (7) SECTION 3050.--Section 3050(b) of such Act (119 Stat. 1713) is amended by inserting "by negotiating the extension of the existing agreement between mile post 191.13 and mile post 185.1 to mile post 165.9 in Rhode Island" before the period at the end.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (p) Transit Tunnels.--In carrying out section 5309(d)(3)(D) of title 49, United States Code, the Secretary of Transportation shall specifically analyze, evaluate, and consider--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) the congestion relief, improved mobility, and other benefits of transit tunnels in those projects which include a transit tunnel; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) the associated ancillary and mitigation costs necessary to relieve congestion, improve mobility, and decrease air and noise pollution in those projects which do not include a transit tunnel, but where a transit tunnel was one of the alternatives analyzed.</narrative>
  <narrative> (q) Knoxville, Tennessee, Property Acquisition.--The acquisition of property for the city of Knoxville, Tennessee, for the Knoxville, Tennessee, Central Station project shall be deemed to qualify as an acquisition of land for protective purposes pursuant to section 622.101 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act. The Secretary of Transportation may allow the costs of such acquisition to be credited toward the non-Federal share for  the project.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (r) California Transit Services.--The Secretary of Transportation shall use not more than $3,000,000 of the funds made available for use at the discretion of the Secretary for fiscal year 2007 for Federal Transit Administration Discretionary Programs, Bus and Bus Facilities to reimburse the California State department of transportation for actual and necessary costs of maintenance and operation, less the amount of fares earned, for additional public transportation services that were  provided by the department of transportation as a temporary substitute for highway traffic service following the freeway collapse at the interchange connecting Interstate Routes 80, 580, and 880 near the San Francisco-Oakland Bay Bridge, on April 29, 2007, until the reopening of that facility on June 29, 2007. The Federal share of the cost of activities reimbursed under this subsection shall be 100 percent.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;center&gt;TITLE III--OTHER SURFACE TRANSPORTATION PROVISIONS&lt;/center&gt;</narrative>
  <narrative>SEC. 301. TECHNICAL AMENDMENTS RELATING TO MOTOR CARRIER SAFETY.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Conforming Amendment Relating to High-Priority Activities.--Section 31104(f) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by striking the designation and heading for paragraph (1) and by striking paragraph (2).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) New Entrant Audits.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) CORRECTIONS OF REFERENCES.--Section 4107(b) of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (119 Stat. 1720) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) by striking "Section 31104" and inserting "Section 31144"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) in paragraph (1) by inserting "(c)" after "the second subsection".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) CONFORMING AMENDMENT.--Section 7112 of such Act (119 Stat. 1899) is amended by striking subsection (c).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Prohibited Transportation.--Section 4114(c)(1) of the such Act (119 Stat. 1726) is amended by striking "the second subsection (c)" and inserting "(f)".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (d) Effective Date Relating to Medical Examiners.--Section 4116(f) of such Act (119 Stat. 1728) is amended by striking "amendment made by subsection (a)" and inserting "amendments made by subsections (a) and (b)".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (e) Roadability Technical Correction.--Section 31151(a)(3)(E)(ii) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by striking "Act" and inserting "section".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (f) Correction of Subsection Reference.--Section 4121 of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (119 Stat. 1734) is amended by striking "31139(f)(5)" and inserting "31139(g)(5)".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (g) CDL Learner'</narrative>
  <narrative>s Permit Program Technical Correction.--Section 4122(2)(A) of such Act (119 Stat. 1734) is amended by striking "license" and inserting "licenses".</narrative>
  <narrative> (h) CDL Information System Funding Reference.--Section 31309(f) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by striking "31318" and inserting "31313". &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) Clarification of Reference.--Section 229(a)(1) of the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Improvement Act of 1999 (49 U.S.C. 31136 note; 119 Stat. 1743) is amended by inserting "of title 49, United States Code," after "31502".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (j) Redesignation of Section.--The second section 39 of chapter 2 of title 18, United States Code, relating to commercial motor vehicles required to stop for inspections, and the item relating to such section in the analysis for such chapter, are redesignated as section 40.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (k) Office of Intermodalism.--Section 5503 of title 49, United States Code, is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in subsection (f)(2) by striking "Surface Transportation Safety Improvement Act of 2005", and inserting "Motor Carrier Safety Reauthorization Act of 2005"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) by redesignating the first subsection (h), relating to authorization of appropriations, as subsection (i) and moving it after the second subsection (h).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (l) Use of Fees for Unified Carrier Registration System.--Section 13908 of title 49, United States Code, is amended by redesignating subsection (e) as subsection (f) and inserting after subsection (d) the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(e) Use of Fees for Unified Carrier Registration System.--Fees collected under this section may be credited to the Department of Transportation appropriations account for purposes for which such fees are collected and shall be available for expenditure for such purposes until expended.".</narrative>
  <narrative> (m) Commercial Motor Vehicle Definition.--Section 14504a(a)(1)(B) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by striking "a motor carrier required to make any filing or pay any fee to a State with respect to the motor carrier's authority or insurance related to operation within such State, the motor carrier" and inserting "determining the size of a motor carrier or motor private carrier's fleet in calculating the fee to be paid by a motor carrier or motor private carrier pursuant  to subsection (f)(1), the motor carrier or motor private carrier".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (n) Clarification of Unreasonable Burden.--Section 14504a(c)(2) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by striking "interstate" the last place it appears and inserting "intrastate".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (o) Contents of Agreement Typo.--Section 14504a(f)(1)(A)(ii) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by striking "or" the last place it appears.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (p) Other Unified Carrier Registration System Technical Corrections.--Section 14504a of title 49, United States Code, is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in subsection (c)(1)(B) by striking "the a" and inserting "a";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) in subsection (f)(1)(A)(i) by striking "in connection with the filing of proof of financial responsibility"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) in subsection (f)(1)(A)(ii) by striking "in connection with such a filing" and inserting "under the UCR agreement".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (q) Identification of Vehicles.--Section 14506(b)(2) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by inserting before the semicolon at the end the following: "or under an applicable State law if, on October 1, 2006, the State has a form of highway use taxation not subject to collection through the International Fuel Tax Agreement".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (r) Driveaway Saddlemount Vehicle.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) DEFINITION.--Section 31111(a)(4) of title 49, United States Code, is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) in the paragraph heading by striking "DRIVE-AWAY SADDLEMOUNT WITH FULLMOUNT" and inserting "DRIVEAWAY SADDLEMOUNT";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) by striking "drive-away saddlemount with fullmount" and inserting "driveaway saddlemount"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) by inserting "Such combination may include one fullmount." after the period at the end.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) IN GENERAL.--Section 31111(b)(1)(D) of such title is amended by striking "a driveaway saddlemount with fullmount" and inserting "all driveaway saddlemount".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 302. TECHNICAL AMENDMENTS RELATING TO HAZARDOUS MATERIALS TRANSPORTATION.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Definition of Hazmat Employees.--Section 7102(2) of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (119 Stat. 1892) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) by striking "(3)(A)" and inserting "(3)";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) in subparagraph (A) by striking "clause (i)" and inserting "clause (i) of subparagraph (A)"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) in subparagraph (B) by striking "clause (ii)" and inserting "subparagraph (A)(ii)".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Technical Correction.--Section 5103a(g)(1)(B)(ii) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by striking "Act" and inserting "subsection".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Preemption Correction.--Section 5125 of title 49, United States Code, is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in subsection (d)(1) by striking "5119(e)" and inserting "5119(f)";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) in each of subsections (e) and (g) by striking "5119(b)" and inserting "5119(f)"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) in subsection (g) by striking "(b), (c)(1), or (d)" and inserting "(a), (b)(1), or (c)".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (d) Relationship to Other Laws.--Section 7124(3) of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (119 Stat. 1908) is amended by inserting "the first place it appears" before "and inserting".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (e) Report.--Section 5121(h) of title 49, United States Code, is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in paragraph (2) by striking "exemptions" and inserting "special permits"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) in paragraph (3) by striking "exemption" and inserting "special permit".</narrative>
  <narrative> (f) Section Heading.--Section 5128 of title 49, United States Code, is amended by striking the section designation and heading and inserting the following:"&#xA7;5128. Authorization of appropriations".</narrative>
  <narrative> (g) Chapter Analysis.--The analysis for chapter 57 of title 49, United States Code, is amended in the item relating to section 5701 by striking "Transportation" and inserting "transportation".</narrative>
  <narrative> (h) Norman Y. Mineta Research and Special Programs Improvement Act.--Section 5(b) of the Norman Y. Mineta Research and Special Programs Improvement Act (49 U.S.C. 108 note; 118 Stat. 2427) is amended by inserting "(including delegations by the Secretary of Transportation)" after "All orders".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) Shipping Papers.--Section 5110(d)(1) of title 49, United States Code, is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in the subsection heading by striking "Shippers" and inserting "Offerors"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) by striking "shipper's" and inserting "offeror's".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (j) NTSB Recommendations.--Section 19(1) of the Pipeline Inspection, Protection, Enforcement, and Safety Act of 2006 (49 U.S.C. 60102 note; 120 Stat. 3498) is amended by striking "165" and inserting "1165".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 303. HIGHWAY SAFETY.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) State Minimum Apportionments for Highway Safety Programs.--Effective October 1, 2007, section 402(c) of the title 23, United States Code, is amended by striking "The annual apportionment to each State shall not be less than one-half of 1 per centum" and inserting "The annual apportionment to each State shall not be less than three-quarters of 1 percent".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Consolidation of Grant Applications.--Section 402(m) of title 23, United States Code, is amended in the first sentence--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) by striking "through" and inserting "for which"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) by inserting "is appropriate" before the period at the end.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Technical Corrections.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) Section 2002(b) of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (119 Stat. 1521) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) by striking paragraph (2); and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) by redesignating paragraphs (3) and (4) as (2) and (3), respectively.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) Section 2007(b)(1) of such Act (119 Stat. 1529) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) by inserting "and" after the semicolon at the end of subparagraph (A);&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) by striking "and" at the end of subparagraph (B); and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) by striking subparagraph (C).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) Effective August 10, 2005, section 410(c)(7)(B) of title 23, United States Code, is amended by striking "clause (i)" and inserting "clauses (i) and (ii)".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) Section 411 of title 23, United States Code, is amended by redesignating the second subsection (c), relating to administration expenses, and subsection (d) as subsections (d) and (e), respectively.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 304. CORRECTION OF STUDY REQUIREMENT REGARDING ON-SCENE MOTOR VEHICLE COLLISION CAUSATION.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Section 2003(c)(1) of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (Public Law 109-59; 119 Stat. 1522) is amended in the second sentence by striking "shall" and inserting "may".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 305. MOTOR CARRIER TRANSPORTATION REGISTRATION.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) General Requirements.--Section 31138 of title 49, United States Code, is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) by striking subsection (a) and inserting the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(a) General Requirement.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(1) TRANSPORTATION OF PASSENGERS FOR COMPENSATION.--The Secretary of Transportation shall prescribe regulations to require minimum levels of financial responsibility sufficient to satisfy liability amounts established by the Secretary covering public liability and property damage for the transportation of passengers for compensation by motor vehicle in the United States between a place in a State and--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(A) a place in another State;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(B) another place in the same State through a place outside of that State; or&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(C) a place outside the United States.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(2) TRANSPORTATION OF PASSENGERS NOT FOR COMPENSATION.--The Secretary may prescribe regulations to require minimum levels of financial responsibility sufficient to satisfy liability amounts established by the Secretary covering public liability and property damage for the transportation of passengers for commercial purposes, but not for compensation, by motor vehicle in the United States between a place in a State and--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(A) a place in another State;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(B) another place in the same State through a place outside of that State; or&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(C) a place outside the United States."; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) by striking "commercial" each place it appears in subsection (c)(4).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Transportation of Property.--Section 31139 of such title is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) by striking "commercial motor vehicle" in subsection (b)(1) and inserting "motor carrier or motor private carrier (as such terms are defined in section 13102 of this title)"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) by striking "commercial" in subsection (c).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Definitions Relating to Motor Carriers.--Paragraphs (6)(B), (7)(B), (14), and (15) of section 13102 of such title are each amended by striking "commercial motor vehicle (as defined in section 31132)" and inserting "motor vehicle".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (d) Freight Forwarders.--Section 13903(a) of such title is amended to read as follows:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(a) In General.--The Secretary shall register a person to provide service subject to jurisdiction under subchapter III of chapter 135 as a freight forwarder if the Secretary finds that the person is fit, willing, and able to provide the service and to comply with this part and applicable regulations of the Secretary and the Board.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (e) Brokers.--Section 13904(a) of such title is amended to read as follows: &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(a) In General.--The Secretary shall register, subject to section 13906(b), a person to be a broker for transportation of property subject to jurisdiction under subchapter I of chapter 135, if the Secretary finds that the person is fit, willing, and able to be a broker for transportation and to comply with this part and applicable regulations of the Secretary.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 306. APPLICABILITY OF FAIR LABOR STANDARDS ACT REQUIREMENTS AND LIMITATION ON LIABILITY.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Applicability Following This Act.--Beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, section 7 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (29 U.S.C. 207) shall apply to a covered employee notwithstanding section 13(b)(1) of that Act (29 U.S.C. 213(b)(1)).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Liability Limitation Following SAFETEA-LU.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) LIMITATION ON LIABILITY.--An employer shall not be liable for a violation of section 7 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (29 U.S.C. 207) with respect to a covered employee if--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) the violation occurred in the 1-year period beginning on August 10, 2005; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) as of the date of the violation, the employer did not have actual knowledge that the employer was subject to the requirements of such section with respect to the covered employee.</narrative>
  <narrative> (2) ACTIONS TO RECOVER AMOUNTS PREVIOUSLY PAID.--Nothing in paragraph (1) shall be construed to establish a cause of action for an employer to recover amounts paid before the date of enactment of this Act in settlement of, in compromise of, or pursuant to a judgment rendered regarding a claim or potential claim based on an alleged or proven violation of section 7 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (29 U.S.C. 207) occurring in the 1-year period referred to in paragraph (1)(A) with  respect to a covered employee.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Covered Employee Defined.--In this section, the term "covered employee" means an individual--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) who is employed by a motor carrier or motor private carrier (as such terms are defined by section 13102 of title 49, United States Code, as amended by section 305);&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) whose work, in whole or in part, is defined--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) as that of a driver, driver's helper, loader, or mechanic; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) as affecting the safety of operation of motor vehicles weighing 10,000 pounds or less in transportation on public highways in interstate or foreign commerce, except vehicles--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) designed or used to transport more than 8 passengers (including the driver) for compensation;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) designed or used to transport more than 15 passengers (including the driver) and not used to transport passengers for compensation; or&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (iii) used in transporting material found by the Secretary of Transportation to be hazardous under section 5103 of title 49, United States Code, and transported in a quantity requiring placarding under regulations prescribed by the Secretary under section 5103 of title 49, United States Code; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) who performs duties on motor vehicles weighing 10,000 pounds or less.</narrative>
  <narrative>SEC. 401. CONVEYANCE OF GSA FLEET MANAGEMENT CENTER TO ALASKA RAILROAD CORPORATION.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) In General.--Subject to the requirements of this section, the Administrator of General Services shall convey, not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, by quitclaim deed, to the Alaska Railroad Corporation, an entity of the State of Alaska (in this section referred to as the "Corporation"), all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the parcel of real property described in subsection (b), known as the GSA Fleet Management Center.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) GSA Fleet Management Center.--The parcel to be conveyed under subsection (a) is the parcel located at the intersection of 2nd Avenue and Christensen Avenue in Anchorage, Alaska, consisting of approximately 78,000 square feet of land and the improvements thereon.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Consideration.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) IN GENERAL.--As consideration for the parcel to be conveyed under subsection (a), the Administrator shall require the Corporation to--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) convey replacement property in accordance with paragraph (2); or&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) pay the purchase price for the parcel in accordance with paragraph (3).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) REPLACEMENT PROPERTY.--If the Administrator requires the Corporation to provide consideration under paragraph (1)(A), the Corporation shall--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) convey, and pay the cost of conveying, to the United States, acting by and through the Administrator, fee simple title to real property, including a building, that the Administrator determines to be suitable as a replacement facility for the parcel to be conveyed under subsection (a); and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) provide such other consideration as the Administrator and the Corporation may agree, including payment of the costs of relocating the occupants vacating the parcel to be conveyed under subsection (a).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) PURCHASE PRICE.--If the Administrator requires the Corporation to provide consideration under paragraph (1)(B), the Corporation shall pay to the Administrator the fair market value of the parcel to be conveyed under subsection (a) based on its highest and best use as determined by an independent appraisal commissioned by the Administrator and paid for by the Corporation.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (d) Appraisal.--In the case of an appraisal under subsection (c)(3)--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) the appraisal shall be performed by an appraiser mutually acceptable to the Administrator and the Corporation; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) the assumptions, scope of work, and other terms and conditions related to the appraisal assignment shall be mutually acceptable to the Administrator and the Corporation.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (e) Proceeds.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) DEPOSIT.--Any proceeds received under subsection (c) shall be paid into the Federal Buildings Fund established under section 592 of title 40, United States Code.</narrative>
  <narrative> (2) EXPENDITURE.--Funds paid into the Federal Buildings Fund under paragraph (1) shall be available to the Administrator, in amounts specified in appropriations Acts, for expenditure for any lawful purpose consistent with existing authorities granted to the Administrator; except that the Administrator shall provide to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate 30 days advance written  notice of any expenditure of the proceeds.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (f) Additional Terms and Conditions.--The Administrator may require such additional terms and conditions to the conveyance under subsection (a) as the Administrator considers appropriate to protect the interests of the United States.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (g) Description of Property and Survey.--The exact acreage and legal description of the parcels to be conveyed under subsections (a) and (c)(2) shall be determined by surveys satisfactory to the Administrator and the Corporation.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 402. CONVEYANCE OF RETAINED INTEREST IN ST. JOSEPH MEMORIAL HALL.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) In General.--Subject to the terms and conditions of subsection (c), the Administrator of General Services shall convey to the city of St. Joseph, Michigan, by quitclaim deed, any interest retained by the United States in St. Joseph Memorial Hall.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) St. Joseph Memorial Hall Defined.--In this section, the term "St. Joseph Memorial Hall" means the property subject to a conveyance from the Secretary of Commerce to the city of St. Joseph, Michigan, by quitclaim deed dated May 9, 1936, recorded in Liber 310, at page 404, in the Register of Deeds for Berrien County, Michigan.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Terms and Conditions.--The conveyance under subsection (a) shall be subject to the following terms and conditions:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) CONSIDERATION.--As consideration for the conveyance under subsection (a), the city of St. Joseph, Michigan, shall pay $10,000 to the United States.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) ADDITIONAL TERMS AND CONDITIONS.--The Administrator may require such additional terms and conditions for the conveyance under subsection (a) as the Administrator considers appropriate to protect the interests of the United States.</narrative>
  <narrative>SEC. 501. DE SOTO COUNTY, MISSISSIPPI.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Section 219(f)(30) of the Water Resources Development Act of 1992 (106 Stat. 4835; 110 Stat. 3757; 113 Stat. 334; 114 Stat. 2763A-220; 119 Stat. 282; 119 Stat. 2257) is amended by striking "$55,000,000" and inserting "$75,000,000".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 502. DEPARTMENT OF JUSTICE REVIEW.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Consistent with applicable standards and procedures, the Department of Justice shall review allegations of impropriety regarding item 462 in section 1934(c) of Public Law 109-59 to ascertain if a violation of Federal criminal law has occurred.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to the rule, the gentleman from Minnesota (Mr. Oberstar) and the gentleman from Florida (Mr. Mica) each will control 20 minutes.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair recognizes the gentleman from Minnesota.</chair>
  <chair/>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I ask unanimous consent that all Members may have 5 legislative days in which to revise and extend their remarks on the bill pending before us.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request of the gentleman from Minnesota?</chair>
  <chair>There was no objection.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker and colleagues, here we are once again for at least the fifth time in 3 years to consider technical corrections to the SAFETEA-LU legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the 109th Congress, the gentleman from Alaska, then Chair of the full committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and I worked to bring this technical corrections bill to the House floor, passed it successfully. We dealt with hundreds and hundreds of minor adjustments, changes that normally happen in the course of passing a major bill of this nature. If I recall rightly, in ISTEA in 1991, there were 600 or 700 such technical corrections in the TEA-21 bill. In 1998 there were something  like 1,200 technical corrections that had to be made. And we had a somewhat smaller number for SAFETEA-LU. We passed it three times in that Congress, and three times we could not get the other body, as we affectionately call them, to come to agreement and move the bill. We tried, in fact, after election in November,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is bipartisan. Finally, it's a bicameral agreement among all the issues under jurisdiction of our committee on the bill that we passed. Finally, the Senate passed the bill by an overwhelming margin of 88-2. In our body it passed 422-1 in August of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So we now have a number of changes here. A good many of the adjustments were requested by the DOT Modal Administrators, and we have accommodated those in this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Particularly, there were errors made in drafting the final language in the research program. Funding calculations resulted in lower than intended funding levels for several research programs. These technical fixes now will finally recapture critical research funds for the Future Strategic Highway Research program aimed at dealing with highway safety, reliability, capacity, renewal; and the University Transportation Center program that provides funding for the many disciplines in the Academic  Center that generate useful and productive ideas for the practitioners of highway and bridge construction and transit operation. We also have an important clarification to the repeat intoxicated driver law to allow for use of ignition interlock devices, strongly supported by Mothers Against Drunk Driving. This legislation gives States more flexibility to either continue with the 1-year license suspension or permit a 45-day license suspension with limited driving privileges.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We also have clarifying language to help the Federal Transit Administration to interpret section 3011 of SAFETEA-LU on new start and small start projects. I say "help." It will put them on the right course to do the right thing that we intended in House-Senate conference on the transit title of the bill. As then Chairman Young will recall, we had a very vigorous debate with the conferees from the other body on this matter, and we came out with this language, and now it's been misrepresented  over there by the Federal Transit Administration.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The number of technical corrections that we provide in this legislation will allow hundreds, maybe even thousands, of projects to move more vigorously ahead to the construction stage, and I'm quite certain that we will see a generation of at least 40,000 family-wage, highway-related construction jobs that will help lift this economy out of its doldrums. With over a million construction trades workers out of a job, we'll make at least a start in getting the economy back on track and putting them  back to work.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For bringing us to this stage, I especially want to thank the gentleman from Florida (Mr. Mica), ranking member of the committee, who has devoted a great deal of time. I know personally that he has interceded with the leadership in the other body to ask them to move this legislation along, and proceeded with one of the principal recalcitrant Members of the other body. He's really done his share of shouldering the workload and then some, and I'm grateful to the gentleman. And I appreciate  the enduring participation with the former chairman, Mr. Young, the work that we did together in the last Congress to move the SAFETEA-LU legislation and then the technical corrections portion of it, and I appreciate that participation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This really is a bipartisan initiative in the best tradition of this committee. Again, I thank the gentleman from Florida for his splendid work and the gentleman from Oregon (Mr. DeFazio) for the splendid effort he has made.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400273" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself such time as I may consume.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As we consider before the House <bill type="h" number="1195">H.R. 1195</bill>, I want to express my support for this legislation. And, first off, I'd like to thank the chairman of the committee, Mr. Oberstar, for his work and efforts, for his staff; Mr. DeFazio, who chairs the Highway Subcommittee; and also Mr. Duncan on our side of the aisle.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, I know that this bill's being here didn't come by accident. As you heard, this has passed the House at least four other times. A great deal of credit for the achievement in bringing this legislation forward also must go to the former Chair of the committee, the distinguished gentleman from Alaska (Mr. Young). Mr. Young worked closely with Mr. Oberstar in crafting legislation to deal with some of the needed changes that were necessary. When you pass a, I think it  was, $286 billion transportation and highway transit authorization bill, there are always technical corrections that are needed. It's almost impossible to pass a bill of that magnitude with that many numbers, that many projects, and not come back and make adjustments, both in some of the formulas that are required and also in some of the requests from Members. So this is part of the process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One of the most important things, as people also ask us what we are doing to move the economy forward, I think it's absolutely essential that our transportation and infrastructure projects move forward. And without this legislation that cannot be possible because, again, of some of the drafting requirements under the July, 2005, SAFETEA-LU bill that was passed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So here we are, the fifth time the House of Representatives will pass this legislation. It should be on its way to the President. As you heard, this legislation passed in the 109th Congress. It passed in the 110th Congress. Under the leadership of Chairman Young and then ranking member of the committee Mr. Oberstar, it moved forward, and now we have it in this Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The technical corrections in this bill have been clearly identified by the Department of Transportation and also by State Departments of Transportation and are mostly a conforming nature or correcting drafting errors. Again, a huge bill with many provisions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The largest section of the bill, section 105, makes changes to 386 high-priority projects in section 1702 of the SAFETEA-LU bill. These changes address surface transportation projects that cannot be executed as they are currently drafted in the current law, again, that we passed back in July of 2005. And, of course, next year we will be doing another bill, and that's why it's so important that we get this on the President's desk as soon as possible so that these technical changes clarify who  the recipients are and project descriptions and make corrections that in some instances will increase project funding levels and decrease others to achieve budget neutrality.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are many Members of Congress in the House and Senate who have written to our committee or to the Senate Committee on the Environment and Public Works or the Banking Committee in the Senate supporting specific projects and policy corrections. These requests have been submitted, I believe, through an open and transparent process. On my side of the aisle, I've tried to keep all of these requests public, available to the press, and, again, in a very transparent manner for everyone to see what  has been requested, what the projects are, and who has requested them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In this legislation there are 150 corrections made at the request of Senators, 197 corrections made at the request of House Democrats, and 138 corrections made at the request of House Republicans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I support this legislation. It's necessary, again, to move these projects forward to stimulate our economy and build our Nation's infrastructure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="">
    <paragraph>I have no further speakers on our side at this time, and I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400273" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, one of the members of our committee, the gentleman from Florida (Mr. Mack) has requested time, and I would like to yield him 2 minutes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400622" topic="">
    <paragraph>I want to thank the ranking member for the time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I rise today to lend my strong support to passage of this important legislation, which would restore $10 million to the critical widening of I-75, which is now underway in Southwest Florida. It is the same language that we included in the transportation bill when we voted on it in 2005.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By ensuring this $10 million will be spent to widen I-75 in Lee and Collier Counties in Florida, we are protecting the economic viability, quality of life, and public safety for all who rely on it. For that, I thank my colleagues for supporting this important legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While this matter has received well-deserved scrutiny, the legislative process, however flawed it has been, is now  doing what the people want and deserve. I would hope that as a result of what we have learned and what we may continue to learn that this institution will be better and that we will ensure it never happens again.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, I want to thank my colleagues for supporting this legislation and for doing what is best and right for the people of Southwest Florida.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I continue to reserve my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400273" topic="">
    <paragraph>Might I inquire as to how much time I have remaining.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from Florida has 14 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400273" topic="">
    <paragraph>I would like to yield 6 minutes to the gentleman from Alaska (Mr. Young).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, how much time remains on our time?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman has 13 1/2  minutes remaining.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield 5 minutes to the gentleman from Alaska.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman from Alaska will be recognized for 11 minutes.</chair>
  <narrative>(Mr. YOUNG of Alaska asked and was given permission to revise and extend his remarks.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400440" topic="">
    <paragraph>First, let me thank the chairman of the full committee, Mr. Oberstar, and the ranking member, Mr. Mica, for bringing this technical corrections bill to the floor. I will be supporting this bill today because it is a good bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to again thank my minority member, Mr. Oberstar. When I was chairman, we had worked very hard on TEA-LU. It was the only positive piece of legislation this Congress passed in 6 years. When I say positive, it left a part of infrastructure, not all of it, for the good of this Nation. I take great pride in that because it probably created about 185,000 new jobs, $286 billion to be spent for the infrastructure and for the economy of this great Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I bring that up because I hear some people talking about, well, we will repeal the 18.2 percent tax on fuel to help our consumers out. Then goodbye to the roads, the repairs, the new needs for the additional automobiles on our highways. I say beware. It will be a terrible disaster for this great Nation of ours. We have other ideas about solving the high gas prices, but that is probably the worst I have heard of all.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Having said that, I am going to go through a chronological order of what has occurred about the issue of Coconut Road. In 2001, I became chairman of the House Committee on Transportation, a position I held for 6 years. This committee is the largest committee in the House of Representatives, with oversight over all modes of transportation; aviation, highways, railroads, all public buildings, waterways, and emergency management.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As the only Congressman from Alaska, I worked very hard for the State of Alaska. I worked with the Governor, State legislature, and local officials. I can say with great pride we did very well for the State of Alaska because we need transportation in that State, as every other State needs it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to remind people, the responsibility of a chairman is to address the transportation needs in all of the country. As chairman, I worked with officials throughout the country, Governors, mayors, transportation officials, and, of course, all 434 Members and delegates of this body.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As we prepared for the writing of the national transportation bill, members of our committee and I traveled extensively throughout the country at the request of House Members and State and local officials. For the thousands and thousands of transportation projects requested of us, I visited as many communities as possible to meet with the Members, local officials, and public to discuss these requests.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 2004, Florida Gulf Coast University President William Merwin commissioned a study of a road improvement that would increase the university's ability to cope with hurricanes and other disasters. One of the recommendations in the report was for the construction of an on-ramp from Coconut Road to I-75.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 2005, the City of Bonita Springs hired a consultant to determine if the interchange at Coconut Road and I-75 would improve traffic congestion on Bonita Beach Road, Corkscrew Road, Old 41, I-75 and Coconut Road. The study determined that the Coconut interchange would take 9,000 cars off of Bonita Road and Corkscrew Road each day, but add about 6,000 cars per day to Coconut Road.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In February 2005, I was invited by a congressional colleague, who was a member of the Transportation Committee, to his district in Florida to hear the needs and concerns of local constituents. On February 19, a town hall meeting was held at Florida Gulf Coast University, whose arena also serves as a hurricane shelter.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This town hall meeting was attended by more than 200 local constituents, transportation officials, and elected officials. One of the issues discussed at the town hall meeting was the need for a hurricane evacuation route to ensure that people could get to safety more quickly during a national disaster. This project was to be an interchange from the heavily traveled I-75 highway to Coconut Road, which leads to the Florida Gulf Coast University in Bonita Springs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At the town hall meeting, University President William Merwin spoke of the need for a research center at the university that would focus on transportation improvements using new technologies. He also presented a study showing the need for the interchange at Coconut Road to help hurricane evacuees reach the two main shelters in south Lee County. The goal was to provide $10 million for a study, not to build, but study this interchange.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also would like to note, to the credit of the Florida delegation, this area received $81 million for the widening of I-75. This funding was totally justified and important to the area. The $10 million for the Coconut Road study did not take any money away or divert any funds of the $81 million allocated for &#xD0;I-75 widening. The $10 million for the Coconut Road was funded  separately under the national highway bill. Otherwise, it was money above the line.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This interchange study had the support of the Florida Gulf Coast University, the Technical Advisory Committee, which consisted of city and county transportation experts, and the local citizens' advisory committee. The Bonita Springs City Council and the Regional Planning Council Staff have also supported the interchange study. The Technical Advisory Committee and local citizens' advisory committee voted unanimously to include the study in the long range Lee Metropolitan Planning Organization  Transportation plan. Unanimously voted for. However, the Metropolitan Planning Organization voted not to include the interchange study in their long range plan. They instead wanted to transfer the $10 million to another project, including I-75.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While I don't agree with this organization's decision, I respect it. It's important to stress that this study funding did not go to any one person, it did not go to any one group of people. The funding was to go to the State of Florida, were they to choose to proceed with the study.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This has always been a good project. The residents of this community deserve to have a safe and effective evacuation route for themselves in case of a national disaster. With Hurricanes Katrina and Rita we saw firsthand what happens when Americans are unable to get to safety. But for now, I support these residents in their wanting to put this money towards another project. I have always supported the community's right to do what they think is best for them. The change is in this technical corrections  bill, and I support it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So why I am talking about this, other than to give the chronological order of event that occurred? Well, it's very easy. I have been the subject of much innuendo concerning my intent and motivation of this project. These accusations have little, if any, connection with what actually occurred.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I outlined my intent and motivations on this, and it is quite different from what I have been hearing lately about this study. Some of the media have made this study into being about one land owner in the area. Not one word has been mentioned about the hundreds of people who attended the town hall meeting in support of this study or about the numerous local organizations and officials who supported it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This study was included in the largest national highway bill in history.  There were more than 6,200 high priority projects, some call them earmarks, in that bill. About half of these were sponsored by the Democrats and Republicans of this body. About half were sponsored evenly by Republicans and Democrats in the other body. These 6,200 high priority project earmarks from the House and Senate totaled 5 percent of the total highway bill. Five percent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Two committees handled this bill, the Transportation and Infrastructure Committee, and the Ways and Means Committee. Four committees worked on this bill in the Senate. I did not write this bill by myself. There were six committee chairmen, six ranking members, and dozens of subcommittee chairmen and subcommittee ranking members, members of both party's leadership, and countless others who played major roles in the legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The 6,200 high priority projects, earmarks, were requested by virtually every Member in this House, other than 14 Members of the House, including Mr. Flake. This body had nothing to do with the projects requested by the other body, and they had nothing to do with those requested by this body.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This was a massive bill that was not completed until several months after the previous highway authorization had already expired. Members and staff were literally working around the clock until we were able to pass the bill in July, 2005.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As to the debate concerning the process of the enrollment of this and any other legislation, that is not a process I own or control. There are officers of the House and the Senate whose job it is to oversee this process. A committee chairman does not control the enrollment process. I have never been in an enrollment office, and I do not believe any chairman has that right.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After all the accusations and rumors about this bill, I hope this sets the record straight. This project was asked for by the community, it was supported by the Congressman from that district, and there are letters to back that up. But, the Senate is meddling in House affairs. I am supporting this bill. I welcome, if you want to welcome, an investigation into the House. I will support that. But, remember, that is a slippery, slippery road which we are about to be involved in.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have an opportunity in this bill to stimulate the economy, keep our people working. I am going to support this legislation. But keep in mind that Coconut Road was not my idea. It was created and fostered by the local people of that community.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It's not the first time in the enrollment process. Even in this bill, Jacksonville was mentioned in the bill. What we didn't know, when the Senate and the House voted on it, was that there were six Jacksonvilles in this Nation. It had to be changed, and it was changed prior going to the President's desk, and the House never voted on it. I can go on to other cases where legislation has been changed by the enrollment process when it is considered not the intent of the House.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I would inquire of the gentleman from Florida if he has other speakers. We are waiting for one speaker on our side.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400273" topic="">
    <paragraph>I do have other speakers. I would be pleased to yield 1 minute to the gentleman from Arizona (Mr. Flake).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400134" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise in opposition to this bill. <bill type="h" number="1195">H.R. 1195</bill> is purported to be a technical corrections bill. When you hear "technical corrections," you often think of missing commas or misspellings or inverted numbers or other drafting errors. We are doing far, far, far more than that here with this legislation. There are, I believe, more than 200 earmarks that are receiving so-called technical corrections here. These are substantial in nature. They are not simply technical. I think they deserve further scrutiny.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have all found out what happens when we rush legislation like this through. The underlying bill had 6,300 or 6,200 earmarks, as was mentioned. If you're making technical corrections, they should be technical. These are more than technical. They deserve more scrutiny. We don't want to find out later that we have the same problems that we had before. For that reason, I will oppose the legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I will continue to reserve my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400273" topic="">
    <paragraph>May I inquire as to how much time our side has?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The gentleman has 7 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400273" topic="">
    <paragraph>I would like to yield 5 minutes to the gentleman who heads up the Highway Subcommittee on our side, our ranking member, the gentleman from Tennessee (Mr. Duncan).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400116" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the gentleman for yielding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I first would like to thank Chairman Oberstar, Ranking Member Mica, and Mr. DeFazio, the chairman of the Highways and Transit Subcommittee, for continuing to work on this important technical corrections bill. I rise to voice my support for <bill type="h" number="1195">H.R. 1195</bill> as amended by the Senate, and I encourage my colleagues to do the same. This is the fifth time we have brought a SAFETEA-LU technical corrections bill to the House floor in the past 2 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill we are considering today is <bill type="h" number="1195">H.R. 1195</bill>. This is a bill that the House passed in March of 2007. The House also passed a more recent version of SAFETEA-LU technical corrections on August 1, 2007, <bill type="h" number="3248">H.R. 3248</bill>. As Chairman Oberstar mentioned, that bill passed the House with only one dissenting vote. The Senate has amended <bill type="h" number="1195">H.R. 1195</bill> so that the version of <bill type="h" number="1195">H.R. 1195</bill> that we are considering today includes all the changes that were made in <bill type="h" number="3248">H.R. 3248</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Once the President signs this bill, SAFETEA-LU will finally be able to accomplish what the Congress voted for it to do almost 3 years ago. There were many minor errors in policy and in Members' projects in SAFETEA-LU that needed technical correction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>We have heard from the U.S. Department of Transportation and several State DOTs regarding fixes to different programs and high priority projects. I believe this bill addresses most of the issues that have been brought to our attention.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill makes critical corrections to the Federal Highway Research Program to ensure that the department can continue essential research programs, including the Future Strategic Highway Research Program and the University Transportation Center Research Program. The bill also corrects several drafting errors regarding the Magnetic Levitation Transportation Deployment Program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is important to note that this bill does not make substantial policy changes to SAFETEA-LU. Rather, this bill corrects provisions that were not workable by State DOTs or the U.S. Department of Transportation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me just add a couple of things. Ranking Member Mica, Chairman Oberstar and others have mentioned that our economy needs this bill. Just a couple of hours ago, I met with homebuilders from my district in Tennessee. In 2000, Fortune Magazine said the Knoxville metropolitan area was the most popular place to move to in the whole country based on the number moving in in relation to fewest moving out. Ours has been a very popular, fast growing area. Yet this group of homebuilders  told me that their market was down 60 percent just from last year. I have been hearing similar stories. We have got some problems that need work.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One of the Republican Presidential candidates was talking about the stimulus package that we passed earlier and they said the problem with it was that we were going to be borrowing money from the Chinese so that people could buy Chinese products. I am not really talking about the merits or demerits of that bill, but he suggested that what we should do is have a stimulus package on infrastructure, because that would be doing things that needed to be done here in this country and the money would  be going to American workers to do that very needed work in this country. So I think that is something that we might want to consider at a later point.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But I simply will close at this time by once again thanking our great chairman, Mr. Oberstar, and my boss and good friend, Ranking Member Mica, for their persistence on this technical corrections bill. I hope all of my colleagues will join me in supporting this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself 3 minutes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One of the items in our technical corrections bill that I mentioned at the outset was clarifying language to help the Federal Transit Administration to properly interpret section 3011 of SAFETEA-LU on New Start and Small Start project justifications. The reason for that language was that in the consideration of the bill in the House and Senate, and then during conference on SAFETEA-LU, it was clear the Federal Transit Administration was trying to, by administrative action, change existing law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So we, the lawmakers, gave specific direction to FTA that rather than rely so heavily on their own fabricated cost-effectiveness index in determining authorization or approval of New Start and Small Start projects, they are giving inadequate consideration to other factors, economic development and environmental benefits among them, the investments that private sector interests make at transit stops on major projects, such as Dallas Area Rapid Transit, such as the Washington Area Metro project,  where over $20 billion in private sector capital investments have been made along the stops. In Dallas, it is over $1 billion. FTA was not taking into consideration those additional benefits that flow from the investment in a transit project.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Similarly, they were not taking those factors into consideration in evaluating the Dulles Corridor Metrorail Project extension out to Wiehle Avenue, which is otherwise known as the Dulles Metro Extension.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Well, I am delighted that even before we moved this bill through to final enactment, the Federal Transit Administration announced this morning that it intends "to approve entry into final design for the Dulles Corridor Metrorail Project," one of the most important transit projects in the entire United States. This is a vital decision. It is very important to move ahead with this project, so, frankly, we don't look like a third world country when it comes to moving people and goods in our economy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would also like to take this opportunity to note that one of the technical corrections that was so important for us to make in this legislation is for the authority to move ahead with MAGLEV development. Magnetic levitation technology was initiated in the United States going back even before ISTEA in 1991 under an amendment that I advanced with the support of the Congressional Steel Caucus to perfect magnetic levitation technology.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The time of the gentleman from Minnesota has expired.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield myself an additional 2 minutes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While we continued to study it and develop it in university research centers and in contracts with the private sector, Germany and Japan moved ahead with test track MAGLEV technology projects. One of those, the German technology version, has already been implemented in Shanghai, China, while we continue to lag behind because we have not moved ahead with sufficient authority.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Well, we have provided that authority in SAFETEA-LU, but the language wasn't precise enough to satisfy the Federal Transit Administration to move ahead. So we have corrected that ambiguity, if you will, or at least what the Department of Transportation considered to be an ambiguity, with the following language. "Fifty percent of the funds will be allocated to the Nevada Department of Transportation, who shall cooperate with the California-Nevada Super Speed Train Commission for the MAGLEV project  between Las Vegas and Primm." In addition, the other 50 percent of the funds shall be allocated "for existing MAGLEV projects located east of the Mississippi River, using such criteria as the Secretary deems appropriate."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the accompanying report, section 102 language on MAGLEV, we further specify how those funds are to be used, specifically, the 50 percent allocated to the California-Nevada Super Speed Train Commission for Las Vegas-Primm and the other 50 percent for projects east of the Mississippi. The intent of this clarification is to limit the eligible projects to three existing projects east of the Mississippi River; Pittsburgh, Baltimore-Washington and Atlanta-Chattanooga, in a competition to be determined  by and evaluated and resolved by the Secretary of Transportation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The time of the gentleman from Minnesota has again expired.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield myself an additional minute.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I earnestly hope now that after two decades of studying, evaluating and developing in very limited test modes, MAGLEV technology will now be able to move ahead with passenger MAGLEV technology.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also note for the record that the gentleman from California (Mr. Rohrabacher) and I have been working with the Port Authority of Los Angeles-Long Beach and the California Transportation Department, and Mr. Rohrabacher with the Governor's office in California, on a MAGLEV circular route, loop route, from the Port of Los Angeles to Riverside, California, to carry container cargo that can actually pay its own way to the interior of California and avoid the grade crossings and  actually haul paying passenger containers.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The time of the gentleman from Minnesota has again expired.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield myself 1 additional minute.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think these opportunities for advancing the state of the art of this very exciting magnetic levitation technology will now come to fruition with the final language in this legislation on these two projects, plus the initiative in the Port of Long Beach-Los Angeles.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I reserve the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400273" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself the balance of my time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In closing for our side, again I want to thank Mr. Oberstar and Mr. DeFazio and Mr. Duncan, who spoke previously, and Mr. Young, the previous Chair of the Transportation and Infrastructure Committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me just respond to a couple of items here. First of all, I want to join Mr. Oberstar. Both of us worked very hard and intently with the Governor of Virginia and with the delegation from Virginia, the Northern Virginia congressional delegation. I am so delighted to see that the extension of the Metrorail will continue out to Dulles.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is expensive, folks. It is not going to get any cheaper. If you are looking at solutions to help the environment and deal with congestion, that is one of them, and we have to move forward. I am very pleased, and I thank the gentleman for his efforts and our joint efforts in making that possible.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are all joined together by one common denominator in transportation, from sea to shining sea: We face congestion everywhere, in small towns, middle-sized towns, metropolitan areas. This bill, more than any other legislation that we will do this year, will move projects forward.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, there has been some criticism that this changes earmarks or redefines some earmarks. Yes, it does. These are congressional earmarks, and I say from our side of the aisle, I can tell you that we have done everything we can to make this process transparent, open, and have Members publicly state what their intent is. So I feel good about what we have done.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I can't control what the other body does. Mr. Oberstar can't either. But we have done our best to vet these projects and move the interests of this country, which is building and moving the infrastructure of this country forward. This legislation will do that. I urge Members to support this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, I know it does have a provision in here that does allow the Department of Justice to conduct an investigation on one of the projects. The leadership of the House and Senate and Mr. Young and others have agreed to move forward with this. I don't think it sets a good precedent, because the House and Senate should be the judge of their own Members under the Constitution. Be that as it may, I will still support this bill, move forward with the process, and we will try to do our best  to keep America moving forward with its infrastructure and transportation projects, which is absolutely vital to our economy at this time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask Members to support this legislation, and again thank all those involved.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield myself the balance of my time. How much remains?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Two minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield myself the balance of my time again to express my great appreciation to the gentleman from Florida for the splendid cooperation, bipartisan participation, for the efforts made here in this body and with the other body on moving them along to bring the technical corrections to a conclusion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also want to note for the record the gentleman from Florida joined with me in the appeal, in fact, he initiated the request to the Secretary of Transportation, Ms. Peters, last October, for a meeting in our committee offices with the Governor of Virginia, the Commissioner of Transportation for Virginia, the Northern Virginia bipartisan Republican and Democratic House delegation, with Senator Warner's staff and FTA Administrator Simpson to discuss this Dulles Metrorail project, to bring  to the attention of the administration that this is a bipartisan initiative, that we are together on supporting it, and to move it ahead. Now we are there. I thank the gentleman for his consistency and constancy on that initiative.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I concur also with the gentleman's remarks. These are technical corrections. There are 485 of them. Some of them, a good many of them, are just misspellings that needed to be technically corrected. There was some wording that the Federal Highway Administration wanted clarification on, that the Federal Transit Administration asked us to provide clarifying language on, and we do that in this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph/>
    <paragraph>There were other projects where Members found that a project had been designated and was not exactly what their constituents were anticipating, they wanted to change it, dollar for dollar, no increasing, no additional spending. It is appropriate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As former Chairman Bud Shuster was fond of saying: We Members of Congress are not potted plants. We are not there to just stand and look on benignly while the executive branch implements the legislation that we vote for. We are the ones who are accountable to raise the revenues; we are the ones who are accountable to put the policies in place, and we have a say in how they are carried out. And that is what we do with these Member high-priority projects.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I urge all Members to support this legislation as an affirmation of the role of the people's body in setting transportation policy.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412216" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, today the House is considering <bill type="h" number="1195">H.R. 1195</bill>, a bill to make technical corrections to the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (SAFETEA-LU). Included in this bill is an important technical correction to a previously authorized high-priority project (HPP) which would increase vehicle crossing capacity over the Mississippi River and provide congestion relief for many of my constituents in Anoka County.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Development associated with population growth in the northwestern portion of the Twin Cities metro region has significantly increased traffic volume along the Highway 101, Highway 169, and 1-94 corridors. These increases currently cause significant delays at corridor crossings over the Mississippi River during the rush hours. Congestion experienced along these existing corridors will increase markedly as the area continues to grow.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, <bill type="h" number="1195">H.R. 1195</bill> includes an error in the language referring to this project, mislabeling US 169 as US 160. In the past, typo mistakes have held up funding previously authorized by the House. I hope that my statement will serve to clarify this typo now and in the future as this important project moves forward.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, I yield back the balance of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the motion offered by the gentleman from Minnesota (Mr. Oberstar) that the House suspend the rules and concur in the Senate amendment to the bill, <bill type="h" number="1195">H.R. 1195</bill>.</chair>
  <narrative>The question was taken.</narrative>
  <chair> In the opinion of the Chair, two-thirds being in the affirmative, the ayes have it.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400299" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Speaker, on that I demand the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <chair> Pursuant to clause 8 of rule XX and the Chair's prior announcement, further proceedings on this motion will be postponed.</chair>
</record>
