<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1212508803" ordinal="47" title="REGARDING STATEMENTS MADE BY THE GOVERNMENT OF THE RUSSIAN FEDERATION THAT UNDERMINE THE REPUBLIC OF GEORGIA">
  <narrative>REGARDING STATEMENTS MADE BY THE GOVERNMENT OF THE RUSSIAN FEDERATION THAT UNDERMINE THE REPUBLIC OF GEORGIA -- (Senate - June 03, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="4988">S4988</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of Calendar No. 741, <bill type="sr" number="550">S. Res. 550</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="550">S. Res. 550</bill>) expressing the sense of the Senate regarding provocative and dangerous statements made by the government of the Russian Federation that undermine the territorial integrity of the Republic of Georgia.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, the motions to reconsider be laid on the table, with no intervening action or debate, and that any statements related to the resolution be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="550">S. Res. 550</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="550">S. Res. 550</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas, since 1993, the territorial integrity of the Republic of Georgia has been reaffirmed by the international community and 32 United Nations Security Council resolutions;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Government of the Republic of Georgia has pursued with good faith the peaceful resolution of territorial conflicts in the regions of Abkhazia and South Ossetia since the end of hostilities in 1993;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas President of Georgia Mikheil Saakashvili has offered a clear plan for resolving the conflict in Abkhazia and securing legitimate interests of the Abkhaz and South Ossetian people within a unified Georgia;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, for several years, the Government of Russia has engaged in an ongoing process of usurping the sovereignty of Georgia in Abkhazia and South Ossetia by awarding subsidies, the right to vote in elections in Russia, and Russian passports to people living in those regions;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the announcement of the Government of the Russian Federation that it will establish "official ties" with the breakaway regions of Abkhazia and South Ossetia and further involve itself in aspects of their government appears to be a thinly veiled attempt at annexation;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the statements and counter-productive behavior of the Government of the Russian Federation in these regions has undermined the peace and security of those regions, the Republic of Georgia, and the region as a whole; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the consistent effort to undermine the sovereignty of a neighbor is incompatible with the role of the Russian Federation as one of the world's leading powers and is inconsistent with the commitments to international peacekeeping made by the Government of the Russian Federation: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) condemns recent decisions made by the Government of the Russian Federation to establish "official ties" with the breakaway  regions of Abkhazia and South Ossetia, a process that further impedes reconciliation between those regions and the Government of Georgia and violates the sovereignty of the Republic of Georgia and the commitments of the Government of the Russian Federation to international peacekeeping;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) calls upon the Government of the Russian Federation to disavow this policy, which gives the appearance of being motivated by an appetite for annexation;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) affirms that the restoration of the territorial integrity of the Republic of Georgia is in the interest of all who seek peace and stability in the region;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) urges all parties to the conflicts in the Republic of Georgia and governments around the world to eschew rhetoric that escalates tensions and undermines efforts to negotiate a settlement to the conflicts; and</chair>
  <chair> (5) commends the Government of Georgia for acting with restraint in the face of serious provocation.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
