<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1197997209" ordinal="30" title="50TH ANNIVERSARY OF THE ORVIS SCHOOL OF NURSING">
  <narrative>50TH ANNIVERSARY OF THE ORVIS SCHOOL OF NURSING -- (Senate - December 18, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="15891">S15891</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, as the Senate finishes its business for the year, it is my privilege to rise today in recognition of the 50th anniversary of the Orvis School of Nursing at the University of Nevada, an important part of Nevada's health care community.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The beginnings of the Orvis School are humble. During a brief hospitalization in Reno, Arthur Orvis, a stockbroker and Nevada resident, noticed the lack of student nurses and began to wonder about the educational opportunities for health care providers in Nevada. On December 15, 1955, in a letter to University President Minard W. Stout, Orvis wrote, " I desire to give $100,000 to the University of Nevada for the establishment of a department to be known as the `Orvis School of Nursing.' This  is a free will offering with no strings attached."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a result of this generosity, the Orvis School of Nursing was founded by Arthur and Mae Orvis at the University of Nevada in 1957. When the Orvis School opened its doors in the fall of that year, there were 12 students and 5 faculty members. Unusual for the time period, the Orvis School's first class was very diverse, including one African-American student, one male student, one Asian-American student, and nine white female students.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Orvis School of Nursing has come a long way from that first class of 12 students. Today, a wide group of students attend a world-class institution that offers the highest quality of nursing education. While traditional nursing programs focus only on hospital nursing, the Orvis School is distinctive in that it offers a bachelor's of science degree in nursing, emphasizing nursing leadership, community health, and nursing research. I confidently believe that this unique focus will lead to greater  innovations and ideas for the future of health care.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In closing, I extend my most sincere gratitude to the Orvis School of Nursing, its alumni, and greater community. Nevadans are fortunate to have such a talented and skilled institution in our State.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
