<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1185163200" ordinal="34" title="75TH ANNIVERSARY OF THE INTERNATIONAL PEACE GARDEN">
  <narrative>75TH ANNIVERSARY OF THE INTERNATIONAL PEACE GARDEN -- (Senate - July 23, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="9792">S9792</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent the Senate Judiciary Committee be discharged from further consideration of <bill type="sr" number="270">S. Res. 270</bill> and that the Senate then proceed to its consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered. The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="270">S. Res. 270</bill>) honoring the 75th anniversary of the International Peace Garden.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table, en bloc, and any statements relating thereto be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="270">S. Res. 270</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="270">S. Res. 270</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas the International Peace Garden was conceived in 1928 by Dr. Henry J. Moore, a Canadian member of the National Association of Gardeners, who said the garden would be "a memorial to international friendship that shall endure to all time";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the International Peace Garden, a National Park affiliate, was dedicated in 1932, with 50,000 people in attendance, on the border between the State of North Dakota and the Province of Manitoba as a symbol of the long-standing peace, friendship, and cooperation between the United States and Canada;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas a cairn of native stone was constructed on the international border and inscribed "To God in His Glory. . . We two nations dedicate this garden and pledge ourselves that as long as men shall live we will not take up arms against one another";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas in 1934 the Civilian Conservation Corps helped plant and construct the garden on the 2,339 acres of land donated by the State of North Dakota and Province of Manitoba;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the first building built by the Civilian Conservation Corps, the Lodge, made of North Dakota granite and timber from the Duck Mountains in Manitoba, still remains in the garden today;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas more than 150,000 flowers grace the garden each year and another 2,000 to 5,000 plants and flowers comprise a large working floral clock, a centerpiece of the garden;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas symbols of peace appear throughout the garden, including the 120 foot Peace Tower honoring early immigrants, the Peace Poles donated by the Japanese government that declare "May Peace Prevail" in 28 different languages, and the Peace Chapel, the only building to straddle the international border;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the garden's bell tower has a set of Sifton chimes, cast by Gillett and Johnston of Croydon, England, that are 1 of only 4 sets that exist in the world today;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas more than 150,000 visitors travel to the International Peace Garden every year to view the floral displays, fountains, sunken garden, and other scenic vistas;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the International Peace Garden hosts the International Music Camp, which offers musical opportunities and instruction for students and adults from around the world, and the Legion Athletic Camp, one of the top student athletic training camps;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the State of North Dakota proudly declares itself the Peace Garden State in recognition and honor of the International Peace Garden;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the State of North Dakota, the Province of Manitoba, the United States, and the Canadian Governments have each contributed to the garden and its continued preservation;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the International Peace Garden is undertaking numerous restoration efforts of existing facilities and the addition of a stone-and-glass interpretive center, a tropical plant observatory, and a conflict resolution center; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas on July 14, 2007, the International Peace Garden will commemorate its 75th Anniversary: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) congratulates the International Peace Garden on its 75th anniversary;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) honors the International Peace Garden for sharing its history, beautiful gardens, and a message of peace with the public; and</chair>
  <chair> (3) urges support for continued restoration and expansion efforts at the International Peace Garden.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
