<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1209398404" ordinal="63" title="RECOGNIZING THE 15TH ANNIVERSARY OF THE FOUNDING OF SEEDS OF PEACE">
  <narrative>RECOGNIZING THE 15TH ANNIVERSARY OF THE FOUNDING OF SEEDS OF PEACE -- (Senate - April 28, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="3452">S3452</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the consideration of <bill type="sr" number="536">S. Res. 536</bill> which was submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <chair>The assistant legislative clerk read as follows:</chair>
  <chair>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="536">S. Res. 536</bill>) recognizing the 15th anniversary of the founding of Seeds of Peace, an organization promoting understanding, reconciliation, acceptance, coexistence, and peace in the Middle East, South Asia, and other regions of conflict.</chair>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="536">S. Res. 536</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="536">S. Res. 536</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas Seeds of Peace, founded by John Wallach, organizes and operates a program that brings together young people and educators from regions of conflict to study and learn about coexistence and conflict resolution;</chair>
  <chair>Whereas Seeds of Peace operates a summer camp in Otisfield, Maine, as well as regional programs around the world, such as the Facilitation Training Course in the Middle East, the Homestay Programs in South Asia, or the International Regional Conferences;</chair>
  <chair>Whereas the first International Conflict Resolution Camp welcomed Israeli, Palestinian, Jordanian, and Egyptian youth the summer of 1993, and the camp has since expanded to involve youths from other regions of conflict, including Greece, Turkey, Cyprus, the Balkans, India, Pakistan, and Afghanistan;</chair>
  <chair>Whereas Seeds of Peace utilizes the summer camp to initiate dialogue between the youth of the United States and youth from various conflict regions to dispel hatred and create religious and cultural understanding;</chair>
  <chair>Whereas hundreds of educators receive training through the regional operations of Seeds of Peace to support and teach peaceful conflict resolution techniques in their classrooms, ensuring that thousands of students around the world are exposed to those techniques;</chair>
  <chair>Whereas Seeds of Peace works to dispel fear, mistrust, and prejudice, which are root causes of violence and conflict, and to build a new generation of leaders who are committed to achieving peace;</chair>
  <chair>Whereas Seeds of Peace reveals the human face of youth who are too often exposed to hatred, by engaging campers in both guided coexistence sessions and ordinary summer camp activities, such as sharing meals, canoeing, swimming, playing sports, and exploring creativity through the arts and computers;</chair>
  <chair>Whereas the Arab-Israeli conflict, as well as India-Pakistan and Afghanistan-Pakistan tensions, are currently at critical junctures, and progress toward peace will be enhanced by the emergence of a new generation of leaders who will choose dialogue, friendship, and openness over violence and hatred;</chair>
  <chair>Whereas Seeds of Peace provides year-round opportunities, through regional programming and the innovative use of technology, to enable former participants to build on the relationships forged at camp, so that the learning processes begun at camp may continue in the participants' home countries, where they are most needed;</chair>
  <chair>Whereas youth graduates of the camp, known as "Seeds", currently number more than 4,000, with an additional 567 adult delegation leaders also having completed the camp programming;</chair>
  <chair>Whereas this graduate network receives continued support in promoting professional cooperation;</chair>
  <chair>Whereas Seeds of Peace is strongly supported by participating governments and many world leaders;</chair>
  <chair>Whereas Federal funding for Seeds of Peace demonstrates the recognized importance of Seeds of Peace in promoting the foreign policy goals of the United States; and</chair>
  <chair>Whereas it is especially important to reaffirm that youth must be involved in long-term, visionary solutions to conflicts perpetuated by cycles of violence: Now, therefore, be it</chair>
  <chair>Resolved, That the Senate--</chair>
  <chair>(1) recognizes the 15th anniversary of the founding of Seeds of Peace;</chair>
  <chair>(2) honors the accomplishments of Seeds of Peace in promoting understanding, reconciliation, acceptance, coexistence, and peace among youth from the Middle East and other regions of conflict around the world; and</chair>
  <chair>(3) recognizes Seeds of Peace as a model of hope for living together in peace and security.</chair>
</record>
