<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1179936136" ordinal="39" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="COMMITTEE ON ARMED SERVICES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the sessions of the Senate on Wednesday, May 23, 2007 at 2:30 p.m. in closed session to mark up the national defense authorization act for fiscal year 2008.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, May 23, 2007, at 10:00 a.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the hearing is to address the current moratorium that bars state and local taxes on Internet access.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND NATURAL RESOURCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources be authorized to hold a business meeting during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, May 23, 2007, at 11:30 a.m. in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the business meeting is to consider pending calendar business.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="COMMITTEE ON FINANCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Finance be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, May 23, 2007, at 10:00 a.m., in room 215 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building, to hear testimony on "Funding Social Security's Administrative Costs: Will the Budget Meet the Mission?"</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet to conduct a hearing entitled "Rising Crime in the United States: Examining the Federal Role in Helping Communities Prevent and Respond to Violent Crime" on Wednesday, May 23, 2007 at 9:30 a.m. in Dirksen Senate Office Building Room 226.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ted Kamatchus, President, National Sheriffs Association; Russ Lane, Vice President, International Association of Chiefs of Police; Tom Nee, President, National Association of Police Organizations; Douglas Palmer, Mayor of Trenton, NJ, President, United States Conference of Mayors, Trenton, NJ; James Alan Fox, Criminologist, Northeastern University; Rick Gregory, Chief of Police, New Castle, DE.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet to conduct a hearing entitled "Ending Taxation without Representation: The Constitutionality of <bill type="s" number="1257">S. 1257</bill>" on Wednesday, May 23, 2007 at 1:30 p.m. in Dirksen Senate Office Building Room 226.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Panel I: The Honorable Chris Cannon, United States Representative, R-UT, Washington, DC; The Honorable Eleanor Holmes Norton, United States Representative, D-DC Delegate, Washington, DC.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Panel II: Representative from the Department of Justice, Washington, DC, Richard P. Bress, Partner, Latham &amp; Watkins, LLP, Washington, DC; Charles J. Ogletree, Jesse Climenko Professor of Law, Harvard Law School, Cambridge, MA; Kenneth R. Thomas, Congressional Research Service, Washington, DC; Jonathan Turley, Professor, George Washington University Law School, Washington, DC; The Honorable Patricia Wald, Former Chief Judge, United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit,  Washington, DC.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="COMMITTEE ON VETERANS' AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent for the Committee on Veterans' Affairs to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, May 23, 2007 to hold a hearing on pending health legislation. The hearing will take place in room 562 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building beginning at 9:30 a.m.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="JOINT ECONIMC COMMUNITTEE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Joint Economic Committee be authorized to conduct a hearing entitled, "Is Market Concentration in the U.S. Petroleum Industry, Harming Consumers?", in Room 215 of the Hart Senate Office Building, Wednesday, May 23, 2007, from 10 a.m. to 12:30 p.m.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="SECURITY AND INTERNATIONAL TRADE AND FINANCE SUBCOMMITTEE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs Subcommittee on Security and International Trade and Finance be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on May 23, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. to conduct a hearing entitled "U.S. Economic Relations With China: Strategies and Options on Exchange Rates and Market Access."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="SECURITY AND INTERNATIONAL TRADE AND FINANCE SUBCOMMITTEE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Select Committee on Intelligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on May 23, 2007 at 10:30 a.m. to hold a closed markup.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="STRATEGIC FORCES SUBCOMMITTEE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Strategic Forces Subcommittee of the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, May 23, 2007 at 11:30 a.m., in closed session, to mark up the Strategic Forces Programs and Provisions contained in the National Defense Authorization Act for fiscal year 2008.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
