<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1209744002" ordinal="24" title="NATIONAL CHILDHOOD STROKE AWARENESS DAY">
  <narrative>NATIONAL CHILDHOOD STROKE AWARENESS DAY -- (Senate - May 02, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="3749">S3749</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of <bill type="sr" number="549">S. Res. 549</bill>, submitted earlier today by Senator Casey.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="549">S. Res. 549</bill>) expressing the sense of the Senate with respect to childhood stroke and designating May 3, 2008, as "National Childhood Stroke Awareness Day."</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table, with no intervening action or debate, and that any statements relating to the resolution be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="549">S. Res. 549</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="549">S. Res. 549</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas a stroke, also known as a "cerebrovascular accident", is an acute neurologic injury that occurs when the blood supply to a part of the brain is interrupted by a clot in the artery or a burst of the artery;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas a stroke is a medical emergency that can cause permanent neurologic damage or even death if not promptly diagnosed and treated;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas 26 out of every 100,000 newborns and almost 3 out of every 100,000 children have a stroke each year;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas an individual can have a stroke before birth;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas stroke is among the top 10 causes of death for children in the United States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas 12 percent of all children who experience a stroke die as a result;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas stroke recurs in 20 percent of children who have experienced a prior stroke;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the death rate for children who experience a stroke before the age of 1 year is the highest out of all age groups;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the average time from onset of symptoms to diagnosis of stroke is 24 hours, putting many affected children outside the window of 3 hours for the most successful treatment;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas many children who experience a stroke will suffer serious, long-term neurological disabilities, including--</chair>
  <chair>(1) hemiplegia, which is paralysis of 1 side of the body;</chair>
  <chair>(2) seizures;</chair>
  <chair>(3) speech and vision problems; and</chair>
  <chair>(4) learning difficulties;</chair>
  <chair>Whereas those disabilities may require ongoing physical therapy and surgeries;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the permanent health concerns and treatments resulting from strokes that occur during childhood and young adulthood have a considerable impact on children, families, and society;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas very little is known about the cause, treatment, and prevention of childhood stroke;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas medical research is the only means by which the citizens of the United States can identify and develop effective treatment and prevention strategies for childhood stroke;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas early diagnosis and treatment of childhood stroke greatly improves the chances that the affected child will recover and not experience a recurrence; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas The Children's Hospital of Philadelphia should be commended for its initiative in creating the Nation's first program dedicated to pediatric stroke patients: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) designates May 3, 2008 as "National Childhood Stroke Awareness Day"; and</chair>
  <chair> (2) urges the people of the United States to support the efforts, programs, services, and advocacy of organizations that work to enhance public awareness of childhood stroke.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
