<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1204045202" ordinal="12" title="EQUALIZING THE TAX TREATMENT OF HEALTH INSURANCE">
  <narrative>EQUALIZING THE TAX TREATMENT OF HEALTH INSURANCE -- (Senate - February 26, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="1158">S1158</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I wish to congratulate the Senator from North Dakota, Mr. Dorgan, and the Senator from Alaska, Ms. Murkowski, on the piece of legislation we just passed. It is extremely critical to a number of people in the United States, the Native Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It was an extremely difficult piece of legislation to do because it is such</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I do rise today, however, to talk about finding other solutions to our health care crisis. That is a part of it. We have extended the children's health insurance plan until March of 2009, so that part has been partly solved, but my wi fe Diana and I travel to different parts of Wyoming most weekends, and the No. 1 issue on people's minds is their health care. They all ask me what I am going to do to make sure they have the health care they need. I am able to tell them a lot of things I am working</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill I have put together is o ne called Ten Steps to Transform Health Care in America. That will fix many of the common complaints I hear from my constituents. Why ten steps? Well, I have discovered over the course of the years I have been in this Chamber that if you try to put together one massive comprehensive bill that solves everything, you will have one piece that 5 people don't like, another piece 8 people don't like, another 11 people don't like, and another 3 people don't like, until</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, I am just going to focus on one step; that is, the first, and that is equalizing the tax insurance treatment for all Americans, not just the ones who get heal th insurance at work. I encourage everyone watching to look at my Web site, enzi.senate.gov, to learn more about all the steps of the bill. Again, I emphasize that these are bipartisan ideas people have given me.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because the chairman of the committee has been so involved in the education portion--and we are making progress on the education portion, having sent several pieces to the President already, and we are going to finish the higher education bill, and we are going to finish No Child Left Behind--I h ave been given the flexibility to look into this health care area. The chairman and I sat down and worked on principles of health care, and then I have sought to get ideas from both sides of the aisle</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Before I go into the details of step 1, I wish to say a few things about the entire proposal.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If the Ten Steps bill were to become law, the end result would be an insurance card for everyone. Now, lots of  people have insurance cards--Members of Congress have them, people who work for big companies have them, the kids in Wyoming who participate in the State Children's Health Insurance Program have them. Lots of people have them, and most of those people who have insurance cards are happy with the care they are getting. They do not want change. And the bill doesn't change that. If you have an insurance c ard now, you can keep that card and keep getting the exact same care you are getting. The problem</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So how does the bill get everyone an insurance card, and wi ll we bust the budget in the process of getting everyone an insurance card? The bill won't bust the budget. It won't be free, but it won't bust the budget. So how is this possible? Well, in order to understand how the bill works, it is important to review a few facts about the history of health insurance in this country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Right now, about 60 percent of the folks under age 65 are getting their health insurance through their job. The question is why. Why are 60 percent of Americans getting their health ins urance through their job? Well, the short answer to that question is, because of the way employer-sponsored  health insurance is treated for tax purposes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our current health insurance system is biased toward employer-based coverage due to a historical accident.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>During World War II, we had wage controls. Wage controls increased competition among employers for recruiting the best employees, and health care incentivized employers by allowing them to offer health benefits instead of prohibited wag e increases.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1954, Congress codified a provision declaring that such a contribution would not count as taxable income--an added incentive. This tax policy made it very favorable for individuals to get their health benefits through their employers and consequently has penalized individuals who get their coverage through the individual market.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We must eliminate the unfair tax treatment of health insurance, which will expand choices in coverage and give all Americans more control over their own health</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Joint Committee on Taxation estimated that removing this tax bias--and a few related health care tax policies--would save the Federal Government $3.6 trillion over the next 10 years. That is a lot of money--even around here, that is a lot of money--that can and should be used to expand choices and access and give individuals more control over their health care.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ten Steps ensures that every American can benefit from this savings whether they get their health care from their employer, from the  individual insurance market, or they decide they want to get off of Medicaid and switch to private insurance. So how does the bill do this? The plan gives all Americans who have at least a certain amount of health insurance a standard deduction. The national above-the-line standard deduction for health insurance would equal $15,000 for a family and $7,500 for an</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me be clear. My goal is not to erode employer-based health insurance, given that Ten Steps does not alter the way e mployers treat health insurance. Rather, I wanted to provide more options for individuals who don't currently have insurance through their employer. Correcting a flawed tax code would make it easier for working Americans to buy health insurance. Jobs don't need health insurance, people need health insurance. American families who aren't insured through their employers should</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I hope we can move forward quickly on making these changes so  that every American can get health insurance. It is time for real action. We need to do something. It isn't necessary to wait for the end of a Presidential election to solve basic problems for the American people. These 10 steps will take care of a lot of things. We can do any one of them and make a difference now and show that Congress can get things done.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Wisconsin is recognized.</chair>
</record>
