<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1177387200" ordinal="57" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="COMMITTEE ON AGRICULTURE, NUTRITION, AND FORESTRY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition and Forestry be authorized to conduct a hearing during the session of the Senate on April 24, 2007, at 9:30 a.m. in SD-106. The title of this committee hearing is, "Challenges and Opportunities Facing American Agriculture Producers Today, Part II."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="COMMITTEE ON ARMED SERVICES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, April 24, 2007, at 9:30 a.m., in open session to receive testimony on United States Pacific Command, United States Forces Korea, and United States Special Operations Command in review of the defense authorization request for fiscal year 2008 and the future years defense program.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, April 24 2007, at 10 a.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The hearing will examine the state of U.S. broadband deployment and penetration. In addition, it will provide a forum for considering the state of U.S. telecommunications research and development and the consequences for competitiveness in the global economy.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENVIRONMENT AND PUBLIC WORKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Environment and Public Works be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, April 24, 2007 at 9:45 a.m. in Room 406 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The agenda to be considered: Hearing on the Implications of the Supreme Court's Decision Regarding EPA's Authorities with Respect to Greenhouse Gases under the Clean Air Act.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="COMMITTEE ON HEALTH, EDUCATION, PENSIONS, AND LABOR">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions be authorized to hold a hearing on the No Child Left Behind Reauthorization during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, April 24, 2007 at 10 a.m. in SD-628.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet to conduct a hearing on "The Insurrection Act Rider and State Control of the National Guard" on Tuesday, April 24, 2007 at 2:30 p.m. in Dirksen Senate Office Building Room 226.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Honorable Michael F. Easley, Governor, State of North Carolina, Raleigh, NC.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Lieutenant General H. Steven Blum, USA, Chief, National Guard Bureau, Alexandria, VA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Major General Timothy Lowenberg, USAF, The Adjutant General, State of Washington, Tacoma, WA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sheriff Ted G. Kamatchus, Sheriff, Marshall County Iowa, President, National Sheriffs' Association, Marshalltown, IA.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="SELECT COMMITTEE ON INTELLIGENCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Select Committee on Intelligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on April 24, 2007 at 2:30 p.m. to hold a closed hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="AD HOC SUBCOMMITTEE ON DISASTER RECOVERY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Ad Hoc Subcommittee on Disaster Recovery be authorized to meet on Tuesday, April 24, 2007, at 9:30 a.m. for a hearing titled "Beyond Trailers, Part I: Creating a More Flexible, Efficient, and Cost Effective Federal Disaster Housing Program."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="PERMANENT SUBCOMMITTEE ON INVESTIGATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations be authorized to meet on Tuesday, April 24, 2007, at 2:30 p.m., for a hearing entitled "Transit Benefits: How Some Federal Employees Are Taking Uncle Sam for a Ride."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON HUMAN RIGHTS AND THE LAW">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on Human Rights and the Law be authorized to meet on Tuesday, April 24, 2007 at 10 a.m. to conduct a hearing on "A Long Way Gone: Memoirs of a Boy Soldier" in room 226 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ishmael Beah, author, "A Long Way Gone: Memoirs of a Boy Soldier," New York, NY; Kenneth Roth, executive director, Human Rights Watch, New York, NY; Anwen Hughes, senior counsel, Refugee Protection Program, Human Rights First, New York, NY; Joseph Mettimano, director, Public Policy and Advocacy, World Vision, Washington, DC.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON READINESS AND MANAGEMENT SUPPORT">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on Readiness and Management Support be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, April 24, 2007, at 3 p.m., to receive testimony on the readiness of U.S. ground forces in review of the defense authorization request for fiscal year 2008 and the future years defense program.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
