<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1214409602" ordinal="20" title="ADDITIONAL STATEMENTS">
  <narrative>ADDITIONAL STATEMENTS -- (Senate - June 25, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="6152">S6152</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300019" topic="IN RECOGNITION OF JEANNA HENRY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today I recognize the outstanding contributions of Jeanna Henry, whose dedication to the Environmental Protection Agency earned her the Glen Witmer Award. Jeanna, noted for her dedication, resourcefulness, and sheer joy in her work, is an excellent example of the quality employees who serve us at the EPA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Glen Witmer Award is presented each year to the employee whose service is distinguished by concern for our environment, enthusiasm for environmental programs, a logical approach to problem solving, attention to detail, resourcefulness and initiative, and an ability to interact with people in a manner that fosters cooperation, understanding, and resolution of environmental problems. It is the highest award that may be presented to an employee by the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Jeanna grew up in Delmar, MD--the town too big for one State--and graduated from Salisbury State University in 1996 with a degree in environmental health and minors in biology and chemistry. Following through on a goal she set her freshman year of college, Jeanna went on to work as an environmental scientist at the EPA upon winning a National Network for Environmental Management Studies Fellowship. Currently an enforcement officer at EPA's Waste and Chemical Management Division in Wilmington,  DE, she has managed a multitude of hazardous waste and underground storage tank enforcement cases, all with motivation, professionalism, and extraordinary attention to detail.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Beyond her achievements in her field, Jeanna is most noted for her work ethic, exceptional communication skills, and for the passion that she brings to all of her undertakings. New employees often gravitate towards her because despite her heavy workload, she is never too busy to take time out to help others. She has become a mentor for new employees, a role model for her peers, and an absolute joy to her supervisors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Jeanna is not only an outstanding employee, but a remarkable person, as well. Her lifelong passion for the environment has enabled her to help shape and enrich the lives of many in her field and the lives of those lucky  enough to call her their friend. I rise today to extend my sincere congratulations to Jeanna on her award. She is a remarkable woman as well as a credit and testament to the community that she represents so well.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
