<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1191427202" ordinal="46" title="NATIONAL COURAGE MONTH">
  <narrative>NATIONAL COURAGE MONTH -- (Senate - October 03, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="12691">S12691</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of Calendar No. 398, <bill type="sc" number="45">S. Con. Res. 45</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the concurrent resolution by title.</chair>
  <chair>The bill clerk read as follows:</chair>
  <chair>A concurrent resolution (<bill type="sc" number="45">S. Con. Res. 45</bill>) commending the Ed Block Courage Award Foundation for its work in aiding children and families affected by child abuse, and designating November 2007 as National Courage Month.</chair>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the concurrent resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution and preamble be agreed to; the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table with no intervening action or debate; and that any statements be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The concurrent resolution (S. Con. Res 45) was agreed to.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The preamble was agreed to.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The concurrent resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>
      <bill type="sc" number="45">S. Con. Res. 45</bill>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>Whereas the Ed Block Courage Award was established by Sam Lamantia in 1978 in honor of Ed Block, the head athletic trainer of the Baltimore Colts and a respected humanitarian;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas each year in Baltimore, Maryland, the Foundation honors recipients from the National Football League who have been chosen by their teammates as exemplifying sportsmanship and courage;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Ed Block Courage Award has become one of the most esteemed honors bestowed upon players in the NFL;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Ed Block Courage Award Foundation has grown from a Baltimore-based local charity to the Courage House National Support Network for Kids operated in partnership with 17 NFL teams in their respective cities; and</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Whereas Courage Houses are facilities that provide support and care for abused children and their families in these 17 locations  across the country: Baltimore, Maryland, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, Chicago, Illinois, Miami, Florida, Detroit, Michigan, Dallas, Texas, Westchester County, New York, Oakland, California, Seattle, Washington, Charlotte, North Carolina, Cleveland, Ohio, Atlanta, Georgia, St. Louis, Missouri, Indianapolis, Indiana, Buffalo, New  York, San Francisco, California, and Minneapolis, Minnesota: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved by the Senate (the House of Representatives concurring), That it is the sense of Congress that--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) National Courage Month provides an opportunity to educate the people of the United States about the positive role that professional athletes can play as inspirations for America's youth; and</paragraph>
    <paragraph> (2) the Ed Block Courage Award Foundation should be recognized for its outstanding contributions toward helping those affected by child abuse.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
