<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1173200403" ordinal="35" title="STATEMENTS ON INTRODUCED BILLS AND JOINT RESOLUTIONS">
  <speaking speaker="400054" topic="Introducing S. 765. A bill to establish a grant program to improve high school graduation rates and prepare students for college and work; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="765">S. 765</bill>] Mr. President, I wish to talk about education, something many in this body take very seriously. I rise today to address the Nation's dropout crisis. Each day that our schools are open, approximately 7,000 students drop out of high school. That is 1.2 million students annually who do not complete their high school education. Almost a third of American students who enter high school in the ninth grade drop out of school and never receive their high school diploma.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I know our students, our schools, our communities can do better. To ensure that these young people have a better future and that America maintains its competitiveness in a global economy, I suggest to all my colleagues that we must do better.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>According to a Manhattan Institute study, the high school graduation rate for the class of 2003 nationwide was only 70 percent. Thirty percent of our students in this country do not cross the goal line of graduation. Even more alarming, however, is that high school graduation rates for subgroups of students in 2003 were for White students, 78 percent; African Americans, 55 percent; Hispanics, 53 percent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Graduating from high school is a 50-50 proposition in 930 of our high schools in our country. Fifty percent of the students in 930 schools do not get their high school diplomas. In 2,000 high schools, it is a 60-40 proposition. Sixty percent are going to get their diploma, 40 percent will not get their diploma.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Just last week, my home State of North Carolina released its most current data on our State's dropout crisis. Our statistics, likewise, point to an urgent need to pay attention to our public high schools and these students.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>North Carolina's statewide graduation rate was 68 percent. Yet for Black students, that rate falls to 60 percent; for low-income students, 55 percent; and for Hispanic students, 52 percent. Nearly 80 percent of the Nation's high schools that produce the highest number of dropouts are in 15 States, and I am embarrassed at the fact that North Carolina is one of them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To retain our competitive edge in the world economy, America's youths must be prepared for the jobs of today and the jobs of the future, jobs which increasingly require a postsecondary education. Unfortunately, in 2003, 3.5 million Americans ages 16 to 25 did not have a high school diploma and were not enrolled in school.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Individuals without a high school diploma experience higher rates of unemployment, incarceration, and are more likely to live in poverty and receive public assistance than individuals with at least a high school diploma.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We know the statistics, but they are worth repeating. Mr. President, 4 out of every 10 people ages 16 to 24 without a high school diploma receive some type of government assistance. A high school dropout is eight times more likely to be incarcerated than a person with a high school diploma.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am fortunate to represent a State with a rich history in its commitment to higher education. The State of North Carolina is the home of the Nation's first State university, the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, which welcomed students for the first time to its campus on January 15, 1795. All total, North Carolina has 127 degree-granting institutions of higher education--75 public and 52 private. However, North Carolina and the rest of the country cannot rest on their laurels with  their higher education systems. We should be and are proud of our high college-going rate in North Carolina. Yet while 64 percent of recent North Carolina high school graduates go on to college, that number is far too low.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is no silver bullet that will fix our educational system, including high school reform which many have talked about. I hope more and better research will give us a better direction and maybe better answers, but until then, there are a number of things that we can and we should be doing to improve what is a problem that must be addressed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In particular, we know the three Rs to making our public high schools work better for today's students are rigor, relevance, and relationships. Today, Senator JEFF BINGAMAN from New Mexico and I are introducing bipartisan legislation, the Graduate for a Better Future Act. This is to help turn the tide of our Nation's dropout crisis.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator Bingaman has been a stalwart leader in the Senate on issues relating to dropout prevention. I am proud to join him in an effort to lower high school dropout rates and to raise high school graduation and college-going rates.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation will create a competitive grant program targeted at school districts and high schools with the lowest graduation rates, focused on those three Rs of high school reform: rigor, relevance, and relationships.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Funds under this act would be used for models of excellence for academically challenging high schools to prepare all students for college and for work; to offer academic catchup programs for those students who enter high school and do not meet proficient levels in mathematics, reading, language arts, or science that enable such students to meet proficient levels and remain on track to graduate from high school with a regular high school degree; to implement early warning systems to quickly identify  students at risk of dropping out, especially systems that track student absenteeism, one of the greatest predictors that a student may drop out of high school; to implement comprehensive college guidance programs that ensure all students and their parents are regularly notified of high school graduation requirements, college requirements for entry, and provide guidance and assistance to students in applying for postsecondary education and in applying for Federal financial assistance and other State, local, and private financial</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A recent survey of high school dropouts by Civic Enterprises presents a picture of the American high school dropout that is surprising to many. I know it surprised me. Eighty-eight percent of those students who dropped out of  high school had passing grades when they dropped out. Let me say that again. Eighty-eight percent of the students who dropped out of high school had passing grades which would have enabled them to complete their high school diploma. But they dropped out. Fifty-eight percent dropped out with 2 or fewer years to complete high school; 66 percent said they would have worked harder if expectations had been higher; 81 percent recognized that a high school diploma was absolutely vital to their success  in life; and 74 percent said they would have stayed in school if they had it to do all over again.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, this is the point where we get a redo. We get an opportunity to make sure students get an opportunity in the next generation so they don't make the same mistakes the last ones did.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over the past 25 years, the difference in earnings between workers with lower and higher levels of education has grown. As my home State of North Carolina has experienced, gone are the days when an individual with only a high school diploma or GED can find a high-paying job in industries such as manufacturing, textiles, or furniture.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The global economy has changed the marketplace, and the competition is no longer the person who sits next to us. It is the person who graduates from the school we will never hear about or have an opportunity to visit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We know more education pays off. Over his or her lifetime, an individual without a high school diploma will earn approximately $1.1 million less than an individual with a bachelor's degree, $1.5 million less than an individual with a master's degree, and $2.4 million less than an individual with a doctoral degree.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What is the message to our children and our grandchildren? Is it that the future is more competitive than the past, that to be competitive in the job market means we have to raise our educational skills, and as parents and grandparents, we have to make it happen? The answer is yes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senate can no longer sit by and accept rates of 30 percent of our students who don't cross the goal line of high school and accept that without a fight. We can do better, and we should do better.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I look forward to working with my colleagues on the Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee, and with my cosponsor, Senator Bingaman, to face our Nation's dropout crisis head on. This is a first start. This is the ability to educate parents and students about not only how we engage them in the proficiencies they need to be competitive but, more importantly, how we teach them that our expectations are greater than what they felt in the past.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is time that the Senate lead by example to begin to pass legislation that has a real impact on the high school graduation rates in this country; that we can look back and say it was this legislation that started the process, and it was quickly followed up with additional legislation that helps our youth compete, regardless of where that job is and regardless of who their competition is.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As this legislation comes before the committee and comes to this floor, I urge my colleagues to pay particular attention to the impact it has on our children and our grandchildren but, more importantly, on our competitiveness in the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300022" topic="Introducing S. 766. A bill to amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to provide more effective remedies of victims of discrimination in the payment of wages on the basis of sex, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="766">S. 766</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to reintroduce the Paycheck Fairness Act in recognition of Women's History Month. I'd like to thank my colleagues Senators KENNEDY, HARKIN, BOXER, CANTWELL, DODD, FEINGOLD, KLOBUCHAR, LEAHY, MENENDEZ, MIKULSKI, MURRAY, REED, REID and SCHUMER for joining me in reintroducing this legislation to prevent, regulate and reduce pay discrimination for women across the country. I also want to acknowledge Congresswoman DELAURO for being the  champion of this legislation in the House of Representatives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As America celebrates Women's History Month, it's important that we not only take pride in how far women have come in our lifetime, but also recognize the work we must continue to achieve true pay equity in this country. Over the past four decades, we have made tremendous strides in closing the wage gap between women and men. But research still shows us that pay discrimination continues to result in women earning less than men for performing the same job.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, women working full time, year-round, still make only 77 cents for every dollar that a man makes--meaning that for every $100 she earns, a typical woman has $23 less to spend on groceries, housing, child care, or other expenses. Women of color fare even worse: African-American women earn only 67, and Latinas only 56, for every $1.00 earned by white men.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Just two weeks ago, the Wall Street Journal published an article entitled "Women Post Job Gains, Data Show." The article showcased proof of progress over the past decade. From the year 2000 through 2005, women posted a net increase of 1.7 million jobs paying above the median salary, while men gained a net increase of just over 220,000 of such positions, according to the Bureau of Labor Statistics. The issue of the wage gap, however, continues to affect women workers. In 2005, the median weekly  pay for women  was $486, or 73 percent of that for men--$663.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While we often associate the pay wage with low-paying jobs, this inequity is not exclusive to the lower class. The New York Times recently reported that Wimbledon has finally agreed to pay its women tennis champions the same amount of prize money as their male counterparts. Last year's men's champion received $1.170 million, while the tournament's women's winner got $1.117 million.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is why I am pleased to be introducing the Paycheck Fairness Act--a bill that will build on the promise of the Equal Pay Act and help close the pay gap.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Paycheck Fairness Act has three main components.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, it prevents pay discrimination before it starts. By helping women strengthen their negotiation skills and providing outreach and technical assistance to employers to ensure they fairly evaluate and pay their employees, the Paycheck Fairness Act gives employers the tools they need to level the playing field between men and women.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second, the Paycheck Fairness Act creates strong penalties to punish those who do violate the act. By strengthening the penalties for employers who violate the Equal Pay Act, this bill sends a strong message--Equal Pay is a matter to be taken seriously.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And finally, the Paycheck Fairness Act ensures that the Federal Government, which should be a model employer when it comes to enforcing Federal employment laws, uses every tool in its toolbox to ensure that women are paid the same amount as men for doing the same jobs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is no question that we have come a long way since the Equal Pay Act became law 44 years ago. But we still have a lot of work to do.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>According to the National Committee on Pay Equity, working women stand to lose $250,000 over the course of their career because of unequal pay practices--a difference in pay that cannot be fully explained by experience, education, or other qualifications. And the pay gap follows women into retirement: unmarried women in the workforce today will receive, on average, about $8,000 per year less in retirement income than their male counterparts. As a result, millions of American families lose out  because equal pay is still not a reality.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is my hope that many more of my colleagues will join me in recognizing this is more than a women's issue--it is a family issue. It is in all of our interests to allow women to support their families and to live with the dignity and respect accorded to fully engaged members of the workforce.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="Introducing S. 766. A bill to amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to provide more effective remedies of victims of discrimination in the payment of wages on the basis of sex, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, one of the most profound economic shifts of the past century has been the entry of women into the workforce in tremendous numbers. In 1900, women made up only 18.4 percent of the working population. Today, more than 46 percent of the workers who claim a paycheck each week are women.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, while America's women are working harder than ever, they are not being fairly compensated for their contributions to our economy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Discrimination against women continues to be prevalent in the workplace. Women earn about 77 cents for each dollar earned by men, and the gap is even greater for women of color. In 2004, African-American women earned only 67 percent of the earnings of White men, and Hispanic women earned only 56 percent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, the problem is not getting better. The current wage gap of 23 cents is the same gap that existed in 2002. Since 1963, when the Equal Pay Act was passed, the wage gap has narrowed by less than half of a penny a year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While many argue that this persistent pay gap is a consequence of women's choosing to take time out of the workforce, the evidence shows that other factors, including discrimination, are a significant cause. In 2004, the Census Bureau concluded that the substantial gap in earnings between men and women could not completely be explained by differences in education, tenure in the workforce, or occupation. Similarly, a recent General Accounting Office report concluded that the difference in men  and women's working patterns does not explain the entire disparity in their wages. Discrimination plays a significant role as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is appalling and unacceptable that such discrimination still exists in America, and we need to combat it with Federal legislation. The issue is simple fairness, and Congress needs to act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am proud to join with Senator Clinton and Senator Harkin in introducing the Paycheck Fairness Act today. This important legislation will give America's working women the tools they need to fight for fair pay. It will make sure our fair pay laws apply to everyone, and it will strengthen the penalties for employers that are not playing by the rules.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These important reforms are long overdue. I urge my colleagues to stand up for working women and end wage discrimination by passing the Paycheck Fairness Act.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400629" topic="Introducing S. 768. A bill to increase fuel economy standards for automobiles and for other purposes; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="768">S. 768</bill>] Mr. President, 33 years ago, this Nation faced a crisis that touched every American. In 1973, in the shadow of a war against Israel, the Arab nations of OPEC decided to embargo shipments of crude oil to the West.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The economic effects were devastating. For American drivers, the price at the gas pump rose from a national average of 38.5 cents per gallon in May 1973 to 55.1 cents per gallon in June 1974. The stock market fell, and countries across the world faced terrible cycles of inflation and recession that lasted well into the 1980s.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Lawmakers in Washington reacted by calling for a nationwide daylight savings time and a national speed limit. They established a new Department of Energy that eventually created a strategic petroleum reserve. Perhaps most important, Congress enacted the Corporate Average Fuel Economy standards, or CAFE, the first-ever requirements for automakers to improve gas mileage on the vehicles we drive.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At the time, auto executives protested, saying there was no way to increase fuel economy without making cars smaller. One company predicted that Americans would all be driving sub-compacts as a result of CAFE. But CAFE did work, and under the direction of Congress, the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, NHSTA, nearly doubled the average gas mileage of cars from 14 miles per gallon in 1976 to 27.5 mpg for cars in 1985. Today, CAFE standards save us about 3 million barrels of oil per  day, making it the most successful energy-saving measure ever adopted.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now 30 years later, Americans again are feeling the pain at the pump. The price of oil has reached up to $78 a barrel, and Americans have paid more than $3.00 a gallon for gas. America's 20-million-barrel-a-day habit costs our economy $800 million a day, or $300 billion annually. Because we import 60 percent of our oil, much of it from the Middle East, our dependence on oil is also a national security issue as well. Al-Qaida knows that oil is America's Achilles heel. Osama bin Laden has urged  his supporters to "Focus your operations on oil, especially in Iraq and the gulf area, since this will cause them to die off."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At a time when the energy and security stakes couldn't be higher, CAFE standards have been stagnant. In fact, because of a long-standing deadlock in Washington, CAFE standards that initially increased so quickly have remained stagnant for the last 20 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since 1985, efforts to raise the CAFE standard have been stymied by opponents who have argued that Congress does not possess the expertise to set specific benchmarks and that an inflexible congressional mandate would result in the production of less safe cars and a loss of American jobs. This has been a bureaucratic logjam that  has ignored technological innovations in the auto industry and crippled our ability to increase fuel efficiency.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To attempt to break this two-decade-Iong deadlock and start the U.S. on the path towards energy independence, I have joined with Senators LUGAR, BIDEN, SMITH, BINGAMAN, COLEMAN, and Specter to introduce the Fuel Economy Reform Act of 2007. This bill would set a new course by establishing regular, continual, and incremental progress in miles per gallon, targeting 4 percent annually, but preserving NHTSA expertise and flexibility on how to meet those targets.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over the past 20 years, NHTSA's efforts to improve fuel economy have been encumbered with loopholes and resistance. With this bill, CAFE standards would increase by 4 percent every year unless NHTSA can justify a deviation in that rate by proving that the increase is technologically unachievable, does not materially reduce the safety of automobiles manufactured or sold in the U.S., or can prove it is not cost-effective when comparing with the economic and geopolitical value of a gallon of gasoline  saved. We specifically define the grounds upon which NHTSA can determine cost-effectiveness. By flipping the presumption that has served as a barrier to action, we replace the status quo of continued stagnation with steady, measured progress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under this system, if the 4 percent annualized improvement occurs over ten years, this bill would save 1.3 million barrels of oil per day--or 20 billion gallons of gasoline per year. If gasoline is just $2.50 per gallon, consumers will save $50 billion at the pump in 2018. By 2018, we would be cutting global warming pollution by 220 million metric tons of carbon dioxide equivalent gases.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Fuel Economy Reform Act also would provide fairness and flexibility to domestic automakers by establishing different standards for different types of cars. Currently, manufacturers have to meet broad standards over their whole fleet of cars. This disadvantages companies like Ford and General Motors that produce full lines of small and large cars and trucks rather than manufacturers that only sell small cars.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In order to enable domestic manufacturers to develop advanced-technology vehicles, this legislation provides tax incentives to retool parts and assembly plants. This will strengthen the U.S. auto industry by allowing it to compete with foreign hybrid and other fuel efficient vehicles. It is our expectation that NHTSA will use its enhanced authority to bring greater market-based flexibility into CAFE compliance by allowing the banking and trading of credits among certain vehicle types and between  manufacturers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, the bill also would expand the tax incentives that encourage consumers to buy advanced technology vehicles. The bill would lift the current 60,000-per-manufacturer cap on buyer tax credits to allow more Americans to buy ultra-efficient vehicles like hybrids.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By ending a 20-year stalemate on CAFE, the Fuel Economy Reform Act will recapture the innovation that Congress and the auto industry launched in response to the OPEC crisis. In the process, we will safeguard our national security, protect our economy, reduce consumer pain at the pump, and protect our climate, environment, and public health. I urge my colleagues to join our bipartisan coalition and support the Fuel Economy Reform Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of these two bills be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bills were ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400619" topic="Introducing S. 769. A bill to amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to ensure that participants in the Troops to Teachers program may teach at a range of eligible schools; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="769">S. 769</bill>] Mr. President, today I am introducing the Troops to Teachers Improvement Act of 2007, which will help more of our veterans and service members find second careers in our classrooms. This bill will expand the accessibility of this program, so that more military personnel will be able to enroll, receive $5,000 toward their teaching certification, and teach in a school near their home. I am proud to be joined by Senator Chambliss, Senator Collins, and Senator Allard  in introducing this legislation. On the House side, Congressman Petri and Congresswoman Matsui have introduced a companion to this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since it was created in 1994, the Troops to Teachers program has helped place over 10,000 new teachers in classrooms around the country. The program provides guidance, teacher certification assistance, and bonuses for military personnel who give at least three years of service in the classroom.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When Congress established the Troops to Teachers program, it created two levels of bonuses for military personnel and veterans who participate. An individual was eligible for a $5,000 stipend so long as he or she taught in any school in a district that received Title I funding under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act. This meant that an individual could teach three years in any of a vast majority of schools in the country and still be eligible for the $5,000 bonus.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress allowed a person to receive an additional $5,000 if he or she taught three years in a school that served a high percentage of disadvantaged students. The total bonus of $10,000 was meant to draw these talented new teachers into schools that needed them most.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For over a decade, this bonus structure was highly successful. In Colorado alone, the program has provided around 80 new hires a year to schools where new teachers are desperately needed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But in 2005, the Department of Education limited the number of schools that were eligible to participate and therefore made it more difficult for individuals to receive the baseline $5,000 bonus. The Department of Education was able to do this because when the Troops to Teachers program was reauthorized under the No Child Left Behind Act, there was a mistake in the reauthorization language that created confusion about which schools an individual may teach in order to be eligible for the $5,000  bonus. As I pointed out a moment ago, when Congress created the Troops to Teachers program, it said that an individual could receive the bonus if he or she taught in a "high-need" school, that is, in any school in a district that received Title 1 funding. In Colorado, that meant that around 98 percent of school districts qualified.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a result of this change, enrollments in the Troops to Teachers program have dwindled over the past two years. Western and rural States, in particular, have been negatively impacted. In Colorado, new hires out of Troops to Teachers have dropped from 79 for the 2003-2004 school year to 43 for the 2006-2007 school year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This drop-off in new hires from Troops to Teachers is problematic for several reasons. First, we should be finding ways of attracting new teachers to our classrooms, not devising bureaucratic barriers that keep them out. Experts predict that we will need approximately 2 million new teachers in the next decade, and we need teachers who will give more than a year or two of service. Today, half of newcomers to the teaching profession last less than five years. The good news is that Troops to Teachers  has an 83 percent retention rate for its teachers. A full 223 of the 343 original participants are still teaching today, more than a decade after the program's creation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Troops to Teachers also helps fill a need for diversity in the classroom--83 percent of program participants are male, compared to 18 percent of teachers nationally, and 37 percent are ethnic minorities, compared to 15 percent of teachers nationally.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The second problem with the new eligibility criteria is that it disproportionately hurts rural veterans and rural school districts. It's hard to find a school district in western Colorado or on the eastern plains that has 10,000 students. Are we expecting a Troops to Teacher participant living in Yuma County, population 9,789 to drive to Denver to teach in an eligible school there so they can receive the $5,000 stipend?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The third problem with the new criteria is that it hurts retiring service members who want to pursue a second career in education. This country has a long history of providing educational benefits to our men and women in uniform through the 1944 GI Bill and successive legislation. Troops to Teachers furthers this great cause by helping our men and women in uniform extend their education and earn a teaching certificate. With over 1.3 million veterans from Iraq and Afghanistan, many of whom are  currently transitioning back to civilian life, we have an opportunity to bring the best and the brightest who are now serving in the military straight into the classrooms, where they can continue to extend their service to their country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill I'm introducing today provides a simple fix to the problems that arose for the Troops to Teachers program under the No Child Left Behind Act. The bill simply says that if there is no school within 50 miles of the home of a Troops to Teachers participant, the individual may teach in any school in a district that receives Title 1 funding and receive the initial $5,000 bonus. This bill will allow thousands of retiring service members in rural communities to take advantage of the Troops  to Teachers incentives and transition to a second career in the classroom. I also want to point out that this bill still prioritizes schools that fit the current definition of "high need"--that is, schools with over 10,000 students or with 20 percent of its students from families below the poverty line--but it also</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am hopeful that when we reauthorize the No Child Left Behind Act, we take another look at Troops to Teachers to help make it more accessible to veterans from Iraq and Afghanistan, National Guard members, and reservists. Troops to Teachers is a good program that should be strengthened and supported when it is reauthorized. Yet, we shouldn't wait until then to fix this needless problem that is hampering the program's effectiveness today. I urge my colleagues to support this problem, today, by  supporting the quick, straightforward solution that this bill provides.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of this bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="Introducing S. 769. A bill to amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to ensure that participants in the Troops to Teachers program may teach at a range of eligible schools; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, our Nation faces a public health crisis of the first order. Poor diet and physical inactivity are contributing to growing rates of chronic disease in the U.S. These problems do not just affect adults, but increasingly affect the health of our children as well. Research suggests that one-third of American children born today will develop type II diabetes at some point. For some minority children, the numbers are even more shocking, as high as 50 percent. At the same  time, since 1963, rates of obesity have quadrupled among children ages 6 to 11 and tripled among children ages 12 to 19. Even our youngest children are not immune. Since 1971, among children ages 2 to 5, obesity rates have tripled.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are many reasons for this public health crisis, and accordingly, addressing the crisis will require multiple solutions as well. One place where we can start is with our schools, which have been inundated with foods and drinks having little or no positive nutritional value. A recent study from the Government Accountability office found that 99 percent of high schools, 97 percent of middle schools, and 83 percent of elementary schools sell foods from vending machines, school stores, or a-la-carte  lines in the cafeteria. And it is not fresh fruits and vegetables and other healthy foods that are being sold. No, the vast majority of the foods being sold in our schools outside of Federal meal programs are foods that contribute nothing to the health and development of our children and are actually detrimental to them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Not only does the overconsumption of these foods take a toll on the health of our children, but they also have a negative impact of the investment of taxpayer dollars in the health of our kids. Every year the Federal Government spends nearly $10 billion to reimburse schools for the provision of meals through the National School Lunch Program and School Breakfast Program. In order to receive reimbursement, these meals must meet nutrition standards based upon the Dietary Guidelines for All Americans,  the official dietary advice of the U.S. government. However, sales of food elsewhere in our schools do not fall under these guidelines. Therefore, as children consume more and more of the foods typically sold through school vending machines and snack bars, it undermines the nearly $10 billion in federal reimbursements that we spend on nutritionally balanced school meals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, the heavy selling of candy, soft drinks and other junk food in our schools undermines the guidance, and even the instruction and authority of parents who want to help their children consume sound and balanced diets. The American public agrees. A Robert Wood Johnson Foundation poll from several years ago found that 90 percent of parents would like to see schools remove the typical junk food from vending machines and replace it with healthier alternatives. My bill seeks to restore the  role and authority of parents by ensuring that schools provide the healthy, balanced nutrition that contributes to health and development.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What really hurts children and undermines parents is the junk food free-for-all that currently exists in so many of our schools. How does it help kids if the school sells them a 20-ounce soda  and a candy bar for lunch when their parents have sent them to school with the expectation that they will have balanced meals from the school lunch program?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, along with my colleague Senator MURKOWSKI of Alaska, I will introduce bipartisan legislation to address this problem--and to do what is right for the health of our kids. This bill has broad support in both the education and the public health communities and is supported by the National PTA, the National Education Association, the American Federation of Teachers, the American Medical Association, the Center for Science in the Public Interest, the School Nutrition Association, the  Food Research and Action Center, the American Heart Association, the American Dietetic Association, the American Diabetes Association, and the American Academy of Pediatrics, among others.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Child Nutrition Promotion and School Lunch Protection Act of 2007 does two very simple but important things:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, it requires the Secretary of Agriculture to initiate a rulemaking process to update nutritional standards for foods sold in schools. Currently, USDA relies upon a very narrow nutritional standard that is nearly 30 years old. Since that definition was formulated, children's diets and dietary risk have changed dramatically. In that time, we have also learned a great deal about the relationship between poor diet and chronic disease. It is time for public policy to catch up with the science.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second, the bill requires the Secretary of Agriculture to apply the updated definition everywhere on school grounds and throughout the school day. Currently, the Secretary can only issue rules limiting a very narrow class of foods, and then only stop their sales in the actual school cafeteria during the meal period. As a result, a child only needs to walk into the hall outside the cafeteria to buy a lunch consisting of soda, a bag of chips and a candy bar. This is a loophole that is big enough  to drive a soft drink delivery truck through--literally. It is time to close it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill is supported in the Senate by a bipartisan group of Senators. Joining me in introducing the bill are Senator MURKOWSKI of Alaska, Senator DURBIN of Illinois, Senator VOINOVICH of Ohio, Senator MENENDEZ of New Jersey, Senator LIEBERMAN of Connecticut, Senator SCHUMER of New York, Senator CANTWELL of Washington, and Senator CARPER of Delaware. The diverse group of supporters of this bill cuts across ideological lines and shows that  when the health of our children is at stake, we can put aside our differences in the interest of our children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill, by itself, will not solve the problem of poor diet and rising rates of chronic disease among our children and adults. But it is a start. Scientists predict that--because of obesity and preventable chronic diseases--the current  generation of children could very well be the first in American history to live shorter lives than their parents. If this isn't a wake up call, I don't know what is.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our children are at risk. The time to act is now. And that's why I am pleased to introduce the Child Nutrition Promotion and School Lunch Protection Act of 2007.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300061" topic="Introducing S. 772. A bill to amend the Federal antitrust laws to provide expanded coverage and to eliminate exemptions from such laws that are contrary to the public interest with respect to railroads; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="772">S. 772</bill>] Mr. President, as Chairman of the Senate Antitrust Subcommittee, I believe it is my role to investigate and help end--monopolistic practices that exploit American consumers. In that spirit, I rise today to introduce along with my colleagues, Senators COLEMAN, FEINGOLD, VITTER and ROCKEFELLER, the Railroad Antitrust Enforcement Act of 2007. This legislation will eliminate obsolete antitrust exemptions that protect freight railroads from competition.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Consolidation in the railroad industry, allowed under the exemptions my legislation would repeal, has resulted in only four Class I railroads providing over 90 percent of the nation's freight rail transportation. The lack of competition was recently documented in a Government Accountability Office October 2006 report. That report found that, "concerns about competition and captivity, in the rail industry, remain as traffic is concentrated in fewer railroads." The report also stated that the  Surface Transportation Board, the entity charged with ensuring that the industry remains competitive, has failed to do so. In August 2006, the Attorneys General of 17 states and the District sent a letter to Congress citing problems due to a lack of competition and asked that the antitrust exemptions be removed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The ill-effects of this consolidation are exemplified in the case of "captive shippers"--industries served by only one railroad. Over the past several years, these captive shippers faced spiking rail rates. They are the victims of the monopolistic practices and price gouging by the single railroad that serves them, price increases which they are forced to pass along into the price of their products, and ultimately, to consumers. And in many cases, the ordinary protections of antitrust law are  unavailable to these captive shippers--instead, the railroads are protected by a series of exemptions from the normal rules of antitrust law to which all other industries must abide.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These exemptions have put the American consumer at risk, and in Wisconsin, victims of a lack of railroad competition abound. A coalition has formed, consisting of about 40 affected organizations--Badger CURE. From Dairyland Power Cooperative in La Crosse to Wolf River Lumber in New London, companies in my State are feeling the crunch of years of railroad consolidation. To help offset a 93 percent increase in shipping rates in 2006, Dairyland Power Cooperative had to raise electricity rates by  20 percent. The reliability, efficiency, and affordability of freight rail have all declined, and Wisconsin consumers feel the pinch.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And similar stories exist across the country. That is why I'm joining with my colleagues to introduce the Railroad Antitrust Enforcement Act of 2007. This legislation will force railroads to play by the rules of free competition like all other businesses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The current antitrust exemptions protect a wide range of railroad industry conduct from scrutiny by governmental antirust enforcers. Railroad mergers and acquisitions are exempt from antitrust law and are reviewed solely by the Surface Transportation Board. Railroads that engage in collective ratemaking are also exempt from antitrust law. Railroads subject to the regulation of the Surface Transportation Board are also exempt from private antitrust lawsuits seeking the termination of anti-competitive  practices via injunctive relief. Our bill will eliminate these exemptions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>No good reason exists for them. While railroad legislation in recent decades--including most notably the Staggers Rail Act of 1980--deregulated much railroad rate setting from the oversight of the Surface Transportation Board, these obsolete antitrust exemptions remained in place, insulating a consolidating industry from obeying the rules of fair competition.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our bill will bring railroad mergers and acquisitions under the purview of the Clayton Act, allowing the Federal Government, State attorneys general and private parties to file suit to enjoin anti-competitive mergers and acquisitions. It will restore the review of these mergers to the agencies where they belong--the Justice Department's Antitrust Division and the Federal Trade Commission. It will eliminate the exemption that prevents FTC's scrutiny of railroad common carriers. It will eliminate  the antitrust exemption for railroad collective ratemaking. It will allow State attorneys general and other private parties to sue railroads for treble damages and injunctive relief for violations of the antitrust laws, including collusion that leads to excessive and unreasonable rates.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In sum, by clearing out this thicket of outmoded antitrust exemptions, railroads will be subject to the same laws as the rest of the economy. Government antitrust enforcers will finally have the tools to prevent anti-competitive transactions and practices by railroads. Likewise, private parties will be able to utilize the antitrust laws to deter anti-competitive conduct and to seek redress for their injuries.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is time to put an end to the abusive practices of the Nation's freight railroads. On the Antitrust Subcommittee, we have seen that in industry after industry, vigorous application of our Nation's antitrust laws is the best way to eliminate barriers to competition, to end monopolistic behavior, to keep prices low and quality of service high. The railroad industry is no different. All those who rely on railroads to ship their products--whether it is an electric utility for its coal, a farmer  to ship grain, or a factory to acquire its raw materials or ship out its finished product--deserve the full application of the antitrust laws to end the anti-competitive abuses all too prevalent in this industry today. I urge my colleagues to support the Railroad Antitrust Enforcement Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300084" topic="Introducing S. 772. A bill to amend the Federal antitrust laws to provide expanded coverage and to eliminate exemptions from such laws that are contrary to the public interest with respect to railroads; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I am proud today to join with my colleagues, Senator Kohl, Senator Coleman, Senator Feingold, and Senator Vitter, to introduce the Railroad Antitrust Enforcement Act of 2007. If enacted, this bill would close an incomprehensible legal loophole that has allowed our Nation's freight railroads the unfettered ability to act in anti-competitive ways for too many years. Since before I came to the United States Senate I have been quite stunned at the ability of railroad  companies, by virtue of an exemption from our antitrust laws, to ignore the legitimate complaints of their customers, to sidestep the appropriate concerns of elected officials and leaders in the private sector alike, and to consolidate operations and power to the detriment of the consumer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Railroad Antitrust Enforcement Act would benefit businesses, employees, and consumers by providing meaningful government oversight where none exists currently. It will give our Nation's shippers--long captive to monopoly abuses courts were powerless to check, the Surface Transportation Board was unwilling to acknowledge--remedies that will make for a more open and competitive freight rail marketplace.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In my home State of West Virginia and in towns all across the country, companies and consumers are negatively impacted by lack of competitive rail transportation options--a phenomenon often referred as a shipper being "captive" to one railroad. Because the antitrust exemptions in place allowed railroads to ignore the rules by which virtually all other American corporations are required to operate, railroads have refused to negotiate in good faith with their customers over the costs of shipping  important rail-dependent commodities such as coal, bulk chemicals, and grains and other agricultural products. Manufacturers have been left at the mercy of the railroads and are forced to pay exorbitant transportation rates to ship their goods. Many manufacturers struggle to be competitive with competitors here and abroad because they simply do not have real transportation choices. The bottom line, which should come</paragraph>
    <paragraph>How has this been allowed to come to pass? It will probably come as a shock to members of the Senate, but the railroad industry is exempt from the Nation's antitrust laws related to mergers, acquisitions, and pooling arrangements approved by the Surface Transportation Board (STB). They are also exempt from antitrust laws that would otherwise influence ratemaking. Under the current exemptions, private parties cannot file antitrust suits against railroad companies to halt what in would be for every  other industry illegal practices. Under current law, railroads are allowed to continue a wide range of anti-competitive practices that severely inhibit the ability of our Nation's businesses from shipping their goods at reasonable rates. What this Nation has experienced in the more than 25 years since the Staggers Act</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Specifically, the Railroad Antitrust Enforcement Act will alter exemptions in current law to allow for the following: Permit the Justice Department and the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to review mergers under the Clayton and Sherman Acts, and allow them to bring legal action to block anti-anticompetitive railroad mergers. Remove antitrust exemptions that have allowed railroads to merge, acquire new properties, set rates collectively, and otherwise coordinate policies across the entire freight  rail market. Allow State Attorneys-General and other private parties to sue for treble damages for violations of antitrust laws, including for collusive activity leading to excessive and unreasonable  rates. Allow State Attorneys General and private parties to sue for court orders to halt anticompetitive conduct. Expand the jurisdiction of the FTC to allow it to enforce antitrust law in the railroad industry.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By granting consumers and shippers long-denied access to the protections of our antitrust laws with regard to the freight rail industry, the Railroad Antitrust Enforcement Act may make strides toward creating the competitive freight rail marketplace envisioned by Congress when it passed the Staggers Act in 1980. I hope so. However, because I believe rail customers and retail consumers need greater protection still, along with some of my cosponsors today and others, later this month I will be  introducing additional, broader rail policy legislation to declare the rights shippers were meant to have, and the responsibilities railroads were meant to have, when Congress passed the Staggers Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For the system to work, there must be a meaningful way to seek redress of grievances and punish wrongdoing. The Railroad Antitrust Enforcement Act will go a long way toward correcting some of the glaring problems those of us who pay attention to the rail marketplace have known about for a long time. It will not fix all the problems in the system, but perhaps its provisions will encourage railroads to negotiate with their customers in good faith. The lack of fairness in the current system is devastating  to businesses in my state of West Virginia, and to companies and consumers in every part of the country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I again express my support for the Railroad Antitrust Enforcement Act of 2007, and I urge my colleagues to do the same. This is a problem that affects rural America and urban America, the Grain Belt and the Coalfields, and all points on the compass. Indeed, no American consumer is unaffected by this problem, and all American consumers should take heart: If we enact this bill, help will be on the way.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300099" topic="Introducing S. 773. A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow Federal civilian and military retirees to pay health insurance premiums on a pretax basis and to allow a deduction for TRICARE supplemental premiums; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="773">S. 773</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to introduce legislation to provide some relief for our Nation's retired Federal employees from the severe increases in Federal Employee Health Benefit program (FEHBP) premiums. This measure extends premium conversion to Federal and military retirees, allowing them to pay their health insurance premiums with pre-tax dollars.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Access to affordable health care is a critical issue for everyone. While Federal employees enjoy the ability to choose among a wide variety of health plans to best suit their needs, substantial increases in FEHBP premiums threaten to make health insurance coverage cost prohibitive for many Federal employees, their dependents, and Federal retirees.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In response to these cost increases, a Presidential directive issued in 2000 extended premium conversion to current Federal employees who participate in the Federal Employees Health Benefits Program. Premium conversion allows individuals to pay their health insurance premiums with pre-tax dollars. It is a benefit already available to many private sector employees and State and local government employees. While premium conversion does not directly affect the amount of the FEHBP premium, it helps  to offset some of the cost by reducing an individual's Federal tax liability. Regrettably, our retired civil servants, who pay the same premiums as Federal employees, do not have this same opportunity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Extending this benefit to Federal retirees requires a change in the tax law, specifically Section 125 of the Internal Revenue Code. This legislation makes the necessary change in the tax code.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under the legislation, the benefit is concurrently afforded to our Nation's military retirees to assist them with increasing health care costs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A number of organizations representing Federal and military retirees, including the National Association of Retired Federal Employees and the Military Coalition, have come out strongly in support of this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My support for this legislation spans four Congresses. In the 109th Congress, my premium conversion bill received considerable bipartisan support with 64 cosponsors. It is my sincere hope that this legislation will be passed by Congress this session. I encourage my colleagues to join me in supporting this critical legislation and to show their support for our Nation's dedicated Federal civilian and military retirees. I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="Introducing S. 773. A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow Federal civilian and military retirees to pay health insurance premiums on a pretax basis and to allow a deduction for TRICARE supplemental premiums; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300019" topic="Introducing S. 775. A bill to establish a National Commission on the Infrastructure of the United States; to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="775">S. 775</bill>] Mr. President, today I join my good friend, Sen. GEORGE VOINOVICH, in introducing a bill to study the current state and future needs of our national infrastructure, including rail, airports, wastewater  treatment facilities, waterways and levees.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The American Society of Civil Engineers estimates that $1.6 trillion is needed over a five-year period to bring the Nation's infrastructure to a good condition. Clearly, we need to look at our needs and find a better way to maintain the infrastructure we have, while meeting new demand--all in a way that is fiscally sustainable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last Congress, during the debate about the surface transportation reauthorization, we discussed the problems facing our roadways. Poor road conditions cost U.S. motorists $54 billion per year in repairs and operating costs and 3.5 billion hours a year in traffic. Over 27 percent of the Nation's bridges are structurally deficient or functionally obsolete. While transit use increased faster than any other mode of transportation--up 21 percent--between 1993 and 2002, the Federal Transit Administration  estimates $14.8 billion is needed annually to maintain conditions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In Delaware, while population growth grew a robust 23 percent from 1990 to 2003, vehicle travel on our highways increased 38 percent. And driving on roads in need of repair cost Delaware motorists $160 million a year in extra vehicle repairs and operating costs. To take a look at what must be done to maintain our highways and transit as well as address future needs, and ways to pay for all of that, Congress created a commission to study these issues in SAFETEA-LU and report back to Congress with  recommendations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But there are more types of infrastructure in need of attention than just highways and transit. Air travel has reportedly surpassed pre-September 11, 2001, levels and is projected to grow 4.3 percent annually through 2015. Aging wastewater management systems discharge billions of gallons of untreated sewage into U.S. surface waters each year. And the EPA estimates that $390 billion over the next 20 years will be needed to replace existing systems and build new ones to meet increasing demands.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Further, limited rail capacity has created significant chokepoints and delays, as freight rail tonnage is expected to increase at least 50 percent by 2020 and intercity passenger rail ridership has increased to approximately 25 million a year. To accommodate both freight and passenger rail demand, $12-13 billion a year in investments will be needed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After Hurricane Katrina led to the failure of floodwalls in New Orleans, Congress asked the Corps of Engineers to inspect other flood control structures to identify other repair needs. The Corps found that 146 levees in 28 States, Puerto Rico and the District of Columbia are in danger of failing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In Delaware, vehicle travel on our highways has increased 38 percent from 1990 to 2003, costing Delaware motorists $160 million a year in extra vehicle repairs and operating costs--$273 per motorist. Delaware also has $304 million in drinking water infrastructure needs over the next 20 years and $288 million in wastewater infrastructure needs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Understanding the problem and plotting a plan of attack are essential for attracting and maintaining business and investment in our economy and communities. The legislation we are proposing today would give the National Commission on the Infrastructure of the United States until February 15, 2009, to complete a study of the Nation's infrastructure, in consultation with the appropriate Federal, State and local agencies as well as private sector stakeholders. The Commission would study the age  and condition of public infrastructure, the capacity to sustain current and anticipated economic development, the methods used to finance public infrastructure, and the return to the economy from public works investment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many times, when we debate infrastructure needs, people simply call for additional funds. Unfortunately, the taxpayer is losing confidence in the way we invest their tax dollars. Failures, like the floodwalls in New Orleans, harm confidence in the government's ability to protect communities from natural disasters. The fact that we've made no changes to the Corps' flood control program in the wake of that catastrophic failure has further damaged government credibility.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Increasing traffic in spite of the investment of billions of dollars every year in highways and bridges reduces confidence in government's ability to address traffic congestion. Failure to invest in rail while both freight usage and passenger ridership is at all time highs makes the taxpayer doubt that government is spending their tax dollars according to the needs of the people.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Part of the solution is, likely, greater funding. But the American people need to be confident in the products we provide before they are going to sign a check for more funding. That is why the Commission will study innovative financing, such as tax-credit bonds and private investment. But also, the Commission will study the impact of State and local governments' land use and economic development decisions on Federal infrastructure costs, and provide Congress with some insight as to how the various  levels of government can better coordinate to gain greater efficiencies from our infrastructure investment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Stronger coordination, greater investment and creativity are the keys to maintaining our infrastructure and investing in future needs--as well as a healthy and robust economy. I look forward to guidance from this Commission as to how Congress can better do just that.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300029" topic="Introducing S. 777. A bill to repeal the imposition of withholding on certain payments made to vendors by government entities; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="777">S. 777</bill>] Mr. President, today I am reintroducing the Withholding Tax Relief Act of 2007, which would repeal Section 511 of the Tax Increase Prevention and Reconciliation Act of 2005.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last year, Congress answered Americans' calls for tax relief when it passed the Tax Increase Prevention and Reconciliation Act of 2005. The lower taxes on capital gains and dividends--and the higher alternative minimum tax exemption amounts--contained in the legislation assisted small businesses, encouraged the kind of investment that creates jobs and makes our economy grow, and ensured fairer tax treatment for middle-income families who would otherwise be left picking up the bill for a tax intended  for the wealthy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Alongside these essential tax relief provisions, however, conferees quietly inserted Section 511, a last-minute $7 billion tax penalty on government contractors, into the bill. Thus, the bill, whose aim was "tax increase prevention," actually raised taxes. On the same day the President signed the Tax Increase Prevention and Reconciliation Act into law, I introduced the Withholding Tax Relief Act of 2006 and made good on my promise to work to repeal Section 511. Today, I am renewing that promise.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Section 511--the largest revenue-raiser by far in the Tax Increase Prevention and Reconciliation Act--imposes a sweeping new 3 percent tax withholding on all government payments for products and services made by the Federal Government, State governments, and local governments with expenditures of $100 million or more. It affects payments for goods and services under government contracts and payments to any person for a service or product provided to a government entity--for example, Medicare  and certain grants--beginning in 2011.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Section 511 will not close the tax gap--or the difference between what American taxpayers owe and what they actually pay--as proponents of the provision argue. Section 511 is estimated to "increase" revenue by $7 billion from 2011 to 2015, but raises $6 billion of that amount due solely to accelerated tax receipts and not an actual revenue increase from tax compliance. It generates only $215 million in 2012 and increases slightly in each of the three years thereafter hardly the $290 billion  annual tax gap the IRS estimates. Further, Section 511 is based on revenues from government payments with no relationship to a company's taxable income or tax liability. Section 511 hurts honest taxpaying businesses without providing any additional enforcement mechanisms for tax delinquents.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Section 511's costs to businesses are substantial. Although proponents of Section 511 call the 3 percent withholding rate "low" and "conservative," in most cases, businesses make substantially less than 3 percent profit on their contracts and sometimes, turn no profit at all. Section 511 will effectively withhold entire paychecks--interest free--thereby impeding the cash  flow of small businesses, eliminating funds that can be used for reinvestment  in the business, and forcing companies to pass on the added costs to customers or finance the additional amount.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Section 511 will also impose significant administrative costs on the Federal, State, and local governments--costs so high, in fact, that the Congressional Budget Office (CBO) said the provision constitutes an unfunded mandate on the state and local governments. The projected costs of Section 511, says CBO, will far exceed the allowable $50 million annual threshold.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>More than the costs to government, though, Section 511 stands to negatively impact nearly every sector of the economy--from health care and technology to building and transportation--and there is already talk of expanding the provision's reach and accelerating its effective date. What there wasn't talk of, though--at the inception of Section 511--was the provision itself. Congress never debated the merits of an expanded withholding requirement--as a revenue-raiser or as a way to narrow the tax  gap--in a committee or on either chamber's floor. If it had, Congress would have realized that it does neither of these things well. Section 511 is the start of years of bad tax policy. We can do better than this, and I urge my colleagues to join me in working to repeal this unfair tax penalty.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="Introducing S. 778. A bill to amend title IV of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 in order to authorize the Secretary of Education to award competitive grants to eligible entities to recruit, select, train, and support Expanded Learning and After-School Fellows that will strengthen expanded learning initiatives, 21st century community learning center programs, and after-school programs, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="778">S. 778</bill>] Mr. President, today I am introducing the Teaching Fellows for Expanded Learning and After-School Act to tap the idealism, energy, and talent of 2-year and 4-year college graduates to serve as teaching fellows in our Nation's highest need schools.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Act will establish a new cadre of talented leaders to establish, expand or improve expanded learning initiatives, 21st century community learning center programs and after-school programs. These programs will build essential academic and youth development skills for all students in targeted grade levels in expanded-day programs. They will also assist teachers during the school day in linking the school curriculum more closely with after school programming.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As we know most Olympic athletes train harder when a gold medal is in sight. Employees work overtime when a business launches a breakthrough product. Communities rally to provide material relief and comfort when natural disasters strike. When success matters most, increased effort is essential for achieving a worthy goal, and that fundamental principle can work in education too.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The time has come for the Nation to go the extra mile to meet our education goals and ensure that all children develop the skills they need to participate fully in our economy and in the civic life of their communities. If students are to learn more--the core premise of the No Child Left Behind Act--they must have more time to meet these expectations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Teaching Fellows recruited under this bill will receive intensive training by experienced high-quality after-school programs and will serve for two years. The Act will also enable Teaching Fellows to pursue a bachelor's or graduate degree in education, in order to give communities a pipeline of leaders ready for future involvement in education and youth development.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For the most part, reform efforts to date have equated education reform with school reform. As a result our attention has been focused on the 1,000 hours a year children are in school, while largely overlooking the 4,000 hours a year when children are awake and out of school.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Teachers must, of course, remain at the heart of our strategy to improve education. But they need help. We need to expand learning time, involve caring adults in the lives of children, and make learning more relevant and engaging, especially for students who are struggling.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The school calendar today is largely a relic of the agrarian age. It fails to respond to the realities that students must develop new skills for modem needs, and that in most families, parents are working during many of the after-school hours. Fourteen million children come back to empty homes after school. Voters across party lines, demographic groups, and geographic areas have said for 5 consecutive years that they overwhelmingly support after-school programs for all. Police chiefs, sheriffs  and prosecutors overwhelmingly agree that investing in after-school programs is more effective in reducing youth violence and crime than hiring more police officers or stiff penalties. Diverting less than one percent of at-risk youth from a life of crime</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Teaching Fellows for Expanded Learning and After-School Act draws on the impressive experience of after-school programs and schools that have developed, and tested these ideas and shown they can work. The Act is inspired by the Teaching Fellowship Program created by Citizen Schools, a national network of after-school programs with a track record of significant impact on academic achievement. A rigorous, long-term evaluation has shown that such students outperform their peers on six out of  seven measures of school success.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Act also draws on the superb work of LA's BEST and After-School All-Stars, as well as the experience and innovations of other schools and programs across the country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under the Act, the Department of Education will make grants to partnerships between local education agencies and strong community organizations, institutions of higher education, and community learning centers. These partnerships will recruit and place Teaching Fellows to work full-time in high-need schools that serve low-income students. Grants from the Department of Education will be at least $15,000 per Fellow annually, so that recipients can recruit, select, train, and support the Fellows.  Fellows will also be able to earn a national service education award for each term of service. Partnerships will be required to obtain non-federal matching funds to leverage the federal government's investment and to involve the private sector in expanding these educational opportunities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Expanded learning time and after-school programs are the new frontier of education reform in America. Teaching Fellows recruited under the Act will complement the outstanding efforts of classroom teachers and infuse new energy, talent, and idealism in the after-school sector. They will also be an essential resource for the nation's parents, encouraging students to understand their potential and helping them to see the true promise of the American Dream.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill is supported by thirty-seven groups representing education and after-school communities. I ask unanimous consent that their letters of support be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the letters were ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300029" topic="Introducing S. 779. A bill to reauthorize the Secure Rural Schools and Community Self-Determination Act of 2000; to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="779">S. 779</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to introduce a one year only reauthorization of the Secure Rural Schools and Community Self-Determination Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For the last six years, this Act has provided critical funding to our rural schools and counties and has built collaboration on the ground through the accomplishments of the Resource Advisory Committees.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately Congress has not been able to reauthorize P.L. 106-393 and I do not feel the schools and counties should become victims while we in Congress negotiate a path forward.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thus, I am introducing this bill today and will work to include it in any legislation that is being considered by the Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Act has been an enormous success in achieving and even surpassing the goals of Congress. This Act has restored programs for students in rural schools and prevented the closure of numerous isolated rural schools. It has been a primary funding mechanism to provide rural school students with educational opportunities comparable to suburban and urban students. Over 4,400 rural schools receive funds because of this Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Next, the Act has allowed rural county road districts and county road departments to address the severe maintenance backlog. Snow removal has been restored for citizens, tourists, and school buses. Bridges have been upgraded and replaced and culverts that are hazardous to fish passage have been upgraded and replaced.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, over 70 Resource Advisory Committees, or RACs have been formed. These RAC's cover our largest 150 forest counties. Nationally these 15-person diverse RAC stakeholder committees have studied and approved over 2,500 projects on Federal forestlands and adjacent public and private lands. These projects have addressed a wide variety of improvements drastically needed on our National Forests. Projects have included fuels reduction, habitat improvement, watershed restoration, road maintenance  and rehabilitation, reforestation, campground and trail improvement, and noxious weed eradication.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The accomplishments of this Act over the last few years are positive and substantial. This law should be extended so it can continue to benefit the forest counties, their schools, and continue to contribute to improving the health of our National Forests.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If we do not work to reauthorize this Act, all of the progress of the last six years will be lost. Schools in timber dependant communities will lose a substantial part of their funding. These school districts will have to start making tough budget decisions such as keeping or canceling after school programs, sports programs, music programs, and trying to determine what is the basic educational needs of our children. Next, counties will have to reprioritize road maintenance so that only the essential  services of the county are met because that is all they will be able to afford.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300063" topic="Introducing S. 783. A bill to adjust the boundary of the Barataria Preserve Unit of the Jean Lafitte National Historical Park and Preserve in the State of Louisiana, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="783">S. 783</bill>] Mr. President, I come before the Senate today to re-introduce--with some changes--a bill that I first introduced on April 6, 2004, in the 108th Congress and which I reintroduced in the 109th Congress. This bill will transfer 3,083 acres of Federal land to the Barataria Preserve Unit of the Jean Lafitte National Historical Park, and authorize the Park to purchase up to 821 acres of neighboring private lands from willing sellers. The lands in question contain important freshwater  wetlands, and would allow the park boundary to conform to existing waterways and levee corridors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As of today, the Senate has twice passed--once in the 108th Congress and once in the 109th Congress--a form of this bill by unanimous consent. I trust that few will find anything too objectionable about these provisions in the 110th Congress either. After all, it simply places lands that are already under Federal control under the management authority of the National Park Service, which already manages neighboring lands and helps protect their environmental, cultural and historic integrity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The first major tract in question is the Bayou aux Carpes wetlands, which were acquired by the Justice Department in 1996 as a result of the settlement of a lawsuit. Although the National Park Service has constructive possession of the deeds, it lacks legal management authority. The area has exemplary natural resource values and has been designated by the Environmental Protection Agency as a wetland of significant value. Most importantly, because of the hydrologic connection between the two areas,  the environmental health of the Jean Lafitte Park's Barataria Preserve is dependent on the continued health of the Bayou aux Carpes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The second major tract is the Bayou Segnette wetlands, which are presently managed by the Army Corps of Engineers. The inclusion of this area in the Barataria Unit will allow for better control over water entering the park from outside sources.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My bill also authorizes the acquisition, from willing sellers, of approximately 821 acres of privately owned lands which are adjacent to the park. Approximately half of this area is designated as jurisdictional wetlands, with limited access and no potential for development. All of this land has been included within the boundary at the request of the owners. This provision was also included in the earlier versions of this bill that were passed in the 108th and 109th Congresses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Lastly, allow me to explain what is new about this bill: this bill also authorizes the Jean Lafitte National Historic Park and Preserve to acquire the Fleming-Berthoud Plantation--previously known as the Mavis Grove Plantation. This plantation is one of the southernmost early sugar plantations and surrounds a prehistoric Indian mound and historic cemetery on the edge of the bayou, which is one of the most scenic and most photographed cemeteries around New Orleans. Recently, it was highlighted  in the recent Cabildo exhibition and book on historic cemeteries of New Orleans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The original plantation contained more than 10,000 acres and was a large sugar plantation. After floods destroyed area sugar plantations in the 19th century, this was turned into one of the larger cypress tree lumbering plantations. The Berthoud family bought it in the late 19th century and the Fleming family bought it in the early 20th century.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The 1,000-year-old prehistoric Indian mound and historic above-ground tombstone cemetery are relatively well preserved and have been twice declared eligible for the National Register of Historic Places by state officials; though no action has yet been taken on that designation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Currently, many of the historic plantation structures are unrestored, vacant and in poor condition. But the main plantation house remains in good condition. I have been told that it was photographed for the cover of National Geographic Magazine in the 1930s and has been the setting for close to 10 Hollywood movies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The other buildings include a 75-foot, 175-year-old brick sugar refining chimney, in relatively good condition; an overseer's Creole style cottage from the mid 1800s cited by historians as a fine early example of island architecture; a 19th Century annex building connected to the original plantation house, now in poor condition; a 1920s house built on the original sugar refinery foundations; an early blacksmith shop and several other barns and buildings, most in poor condition.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My bill will authorize the National Park Service to acquire this land from the family, who I am told support the transaction and the restoration of the land and buildings. I am also told that historic preservation organizations may step forward to provide private funding in support of the National Park Service's acquisition of the land.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In all, I think that this bill marks an important day for Louisiana. We are authorizing the management and preservation of several ecological, cultural and historic gems. I hope that my colleagues will fully support this endeavor as they have in the past.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the legislation be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="Introducing S. 784. A bill to amend the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 to require commercial nuclear power plant operators to transfer spent nuclear fuel from the nuclear fuel pools of the operators into spent nuclear fuel dry casks at independent spent fuel storage installations of the operators that are licensed by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission, to convey to the Secretary of Energy title to all such transferred spent nuclear fuel, to provide for the transfer to the Secretary of the independent spent  fuel storage installation operating responsibility of each plant together with the license granted by the Commission for the installation, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="784">S. 784</bill>] Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300034" topic="Introducing S. 785. A bill to amend title 4 of the United States Code to limit the extent to which States may tax the compensation earned by nonresident telecommuters; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="785">S. 785</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today, together with my colleague Senator Lieberman, to introduce the Telecommuter Tax Fairness Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Telecommuter Tax Fairness Act of 2007 will end an outdated legal doctrine that unfairly penalizes thousands of workers in Connecticut and across the country whose only offense is that they sometimes work from home.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Technology continues to transform the way business is conducted in America and all over the world. Telecommunications advances such as cell phones, email, the Internet, and mobile networking have not only made Americans more productive, they have also given people greater flexibility in where they can work without compromising productivity. As a result, more Americans now have the freedom to work from home or other alternative offices when their physical presence is not required at their primary  place of work.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This option to telecommute offers tremendous benefits for businesses, families, and communities. It helps employers lower costs and raise worker productivity, and individuals better manage the demands of work and family. It also reduces congestion on our roads and rails, and in so doing, lowers pollution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Despite the many benefits of telecommuting, some states continue to maintain and enforce outdated laws that unfairly penalize people who choose to work from home. New York, in particular, has been among the most aggressive.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under its so-called "convenience of the employer" rule, New York requires out-of-State residents who work for an employer in New York to pay New York taxes on income earned outside the State, even if the State in which the employee is physically present also applies tax to the same income. New York only allows exceptions for cases of "necessity," as opposed to "convenience," and the State has determined that telecommuting falls into the latter, taxable category. While there are several  States that have "convenience of the employer" rules, no other State applies it with the same rigor as New York.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under this rule, if a Connecticut resident who normally works in New York--as thousands of Connecticut residents do--chooses to work from home some days, New York forces her to pay taxes for income earned on those days not only to Connecticut, the state in which she is physically present, but also to New York. This rule unfairly subjects the many workers who telecommute from their homes or other sites outside of New York to a double tax on the part of their income earned from home.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>According to Connecticut's attorney general, thousands of Connecticut residents alone are affected by this unfair double taxation. However, it isn't only Connecticut residents who are at risk.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thomas Huckaby is a Tennessee-based computer programmer that telecommuted for a firm in Queens, New York. In 1994 and 1995, Mr. Huckaby spent 75 percent of his time working in Tennessee and the remaining 25 percent working in the Queens office and attempted to apportion his income accordingly. New York, however, sought to tax 100 percent of his income and was successful due to its "convenience of employer" rule. On March 29, 2005, the New York Court of Appeals upheld New York's rule in a 4  to 3 decision. The Supreme Court declined to hear his appeal.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A similar story involves Arthur Gray, a New Hampshire resident who worked for the New York office of Cowen &amp; Co. as an investment counselor from 1976 through 1996 and paid New York state income taxes during that time. In 1997, Arthur Gray, per his employer's request, opened and managed an office from his home in New Hampshire. Several times during the year, Mr. Gray worked in New York, but most of his days were spent in New Hampshire. When paying his taxes during this time, he paid New York state  income taxes for the days he was in New York, but not for the days he worked in New Hampshire. New York, however, sought to tax 100 percent of his income and was successful due to its "convenience of the employer" rule.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These are only two examples of the far-reaching consequences of this "convenience of employer" rule. There are thousands of individuals across the country who are adversely impacted by this rule. Most, however, lack the time, money, or energy to take their case to court.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This potential for double taxation is not only unfair, it also discourages people from telecommuting when we should be doing the opposite.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Legislation is needed to protect these honest workers who deserve fair and equitable treatment under the law. The Telecommuter Tax Fairness Act of 2005 accomplishes this by specifically preventing a State from engaging in the current fiction of deeming a nonresident to be in the taxing state when the nonresident is actually working in another state. In doing so, it will eliminate the possibility that citizens will be double-taxed when telecommuting.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Establishing a "physical presence" test--as this legislation does--is the most logical basis for determining tax status. If a worker is in a State, and taking advantage of that State's infrastructure, the worker should pay taxes in that State.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Some suggest that the double-taxation quandary can easily be fixed by  having other States provide a tax credit to those telecommuters. However, why should Connecticut, or any other State, be required to allow a credit on income actually earned in the State? If a worker is working in Connecticut, he or she is benefiting from a range of services paid for and maintained by Connecticut, including roads, water, police, fire protection, and communications  services. It's only fair that Connecticut ask that worker to help support the services that he or she uses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is not just an issue that deals with a small group of citizens from one small state.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rather, this is an issue that affects workers all over the country. It will only grow more pressing as people and businesses continue to seek to take advantage of new technologies that influence the way we live and work.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I hope our colleagues will favorably consider this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="Introducing S. 786. A bill to amend the Agricultural Marketing Act of 1946 to foster efficient markets and increase competition and transparency among packers that purchased livestock from producers; to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="786">S. 786</bill>] Mr. President, Senator FEINGOLD and I have in the past sponsored the Transparency for Independent Livestock Producers Act, or what we have generally referred to as the "Transparency Act." Today we are once again working together in a bipartisan fashion to reintroduce this important legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My sponsorship of the packer ban this Congress is based on the belief that independent producers should have the opportunity to receive a fair price for their livestock. Over the years we have seen widespread consolidation and concentration in the packing industry. Add on the trend toward vertical integration among packers and there is no question why independent producers are losing the opportunity to market their own livestock during profitable cycles in the live meat markets.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The past CEO of a major packer in 1994 explained that the reason packers own livestock is that when the price is high the packers use their own livestock for the lines and when the price is low the packers buy livestock. This means that independent producers are most likely being limited from participating in the most profitable ranges of the live market. This is not good for the survival of the independent producer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bipartisan legislation would guarantee that independent producers have a share in the marketplace while assisting the Mandatory Price Reporting system. The proposal would require that 25 percent of a packer's daily kill comes from the spot market.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By requiring a 25 percent spot market purchase daily, the mandatory price reporting system, which has been criticized due to reporting and accuracy problems, would have consistent, reliable numbers being purchased from the spot market, improving the accuracy and transparency of daily prices. In addition, independent livestock producers would be guaranteed a competitive position due to the packers need to fill the daily 25 percent spot/cash market requirement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The packers required to comply would be the same packers required to report under the Mandatory Price Reporting system. Those are packs that kill either 125,000 head of cattle, 100,000 head of hogs, or 75,000 lambs annually, over a 5 year average.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Packers are arguing that this will hurt their ability to offer contracts to producers, but the fact of the matter is that the majority of livestock contracts pay out on a calculation incorporating Mandatory Price Reporting data. If the Mandatory Price Reporting data is not accurate, or open to possible manipulation because of low numbers on the spot market, contracts are not beneficial tools for producers to manage their risk. This legislative proposal will hopefully give confidence to independent  livestock producers by improving the accuracy and viability of the Mandatory Price reporting system and secure fair prices for contracts based on that data.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It's just common sense, when there aren't a lot of cattle and pigs being purchased on the cash market, it's easier for the Mandatory Price reporting data to be inaccurate or manipulated. The majority of livestock production contracts are based on that data, so if that information is wrong, the contract producers suffer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation will guarantee independent livestock producers market access and a fair price. It will accomplish these goals by making it more  difficult for the Mandatory Price Reporting System to be manipulated because of low numbers being reported by the packs. The Transparency Act is crucial legislation to guarantee livestock producers receive a fair shake at the farm gate and I am looking forward to working on this legislation in a bipartisan fashion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD. </paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
</record>
