<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1228842003" ordinal="37" title="ACKNOWLEDGING THE ACCOMPLISHMENTS AND GOALS OF THE YOUTH IMPACT PROGRAM">
  <narrative>ACKNOWLEDGING THE ACCOMPLISHMENTS AND GOALS OF THE YOUTH IMPACT PROGRAM -- (Senate - December 09, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="10837">S10837</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate now proceed to the consideration of <bill type="sr" number="725">S. Res. 725</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="725">S. Res. 725</bill>) acknowledging the accomplishments and goals of the Youth Impact Program.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="725">S. Res. 725</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="725">S. Res. 725</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas many at-risk young men in the inner cities of the United States face a challenging and uncertain future; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the future success of at-risk young men can be greatly enhanced through sustained mentorship; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas effective working partnerships between and within the public and private sectors can have a lasting and positive impact on the future of at-risk young men; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas participation in organized sports has provided a creative and disciplined outlet and a path to a better life for many at-risk young men; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Youth Impact Program combines the disciplines of football, mentoring, and academics in partnerships between local National Football League franchises and universities to promote discipline, learning, and positive values; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Youth Impact Program is a community-based program that has proven its value over the past 2 years in raising the outlook and aspirations of at-risk young men and has provided at-risk young men greater exposure to academics, core values, and life skills; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Youth Impact Program provides year-round mentoring to its participants, a proven formula for building success; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the National Football League, the National Football League Players Association, the University of Southern California, and Tulane University have provided critical support to the Youth Impact Program; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Youth Impact Program will be expanded to 3 additional cities in partnership with local National Football League franchises and universities; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Youth Impact Program seeks to establish a presence in each city with a local National Football League franchise; and &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas under the vision and leadership of Mr. Riki Ellison, the founder of the Youth Impact Program, a 10-year veteran of the National Football League, a 3-time Super Bowl champion, and a University of Southern California alumnus, the Youth Impact Program has expanded from a regional program to a program with a growing national presence: Now, therefore, be it &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate-- &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) recognizes the ongoing and significant contributions of those organizations that support the Youth Impact Program; and</chair>
  <chair> (2) encourages the expansion of the Youth Impact Program to inner cities across the United States.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
