<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1173974406" ordinal="46" title="SENATE RESOLUTION 108--DESIGNATING THE FIRST WEEK OF APRIL 2007 AS &quot;NATIONAL ASBESTOS AWARENESS WEEK&quot;">
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise in support of the resolution introduced by Senator Baucus to designate the first week of April 2007 as "National Asbestos Awareness Week." It is my hope this resolution will raise public awareness of this dreadful substance and the pain and suffering that it has caused. It is also a reminder of our responsibility to the victims of asbestos in Nevada, in Libby, MT, and all over America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We know too well that the effect of exposure can be deadly. Diseases caused by asbestos include cancers of the lung, digestive tract, colon, larynx, esophagus, kidney and some types of lymphoma; pleural disease; asbesostis; and, of course, mesothelioma. These devastating illnesses take the lives of 30 Americans each day and as many as 10,000 Americans each year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>According to the Occupational Safety and Health Administration, OSHA, 1.3 million Americans still face significant asbestos exposure in their workplaces. However, the danger is not confined to the Nation's shipyards, mines, or construction sites. Countless others are exposed in their neighborhoods, in schoolyards and at home; mothers and children who would otherwise have no clue that their very health is in jeopardy from this poisonous substance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The cases of disease and death caused by asbestos exposure are not abstractions. Real lives are affected and destroyed by this dreadful substance. I have received countless letters from victims of asbestos-related diseases and their families. Each one shares another story of loss and of pain, of sickness and of tragedy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>James Baxter, a retired railroad worker from Carson City, NV, suffers from lung damage and respiratory problems. Richard Strauss from Las Vegas, NV, lost his father 3 years ago from asbestos exposure. Like many others, these two men contacted me seeking help in dealing with the hardship and tragedy they have endured.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Margy Urnberg from Carson City, NV, had a father, Ronald Johnson, who died from asbestos exposure. He worked in a vermiculite mine and received secondhand exposure from living in Libby, MT. Connie Peck-Youso was born and raised in Libby, MT. Although she never worked in a mine, she bares the scarring in her lungs from the same type of secondhand exposure that had such terrible consequences for Mr. Johnson.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Alan Reinstein, the cofounder and former Director of Communications of the Asbestos Disease Awareness Organization, suffered with acute mesothelioma. Alan fought bravely and responded to his illness as a call to action. Sadly, he lost his battle with his terrible disease last year. The Alan Reinstein Memorial Award was created to honor those, like Alan, who have brought awareness to the victims of asbestos. Les Skramstad will be honored posthumously this year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last year, the Senate debated a bill to remove asbestos liability cases from the court system and compensate victims from a trust fund. I strongly opposed that bill because it was unfair to asbestos victims. The bill would have made it too difficult for seriously injured victims to recover damages, and the trust fund would have been inadequate. Rather than deprive asbestos victims of their day in court, we should pass legislation to ban asbestos and heighten public awareness of this fatal disease.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am also pleased to be a cosponsor of the legislation recently reintroduced by Senator Murray, the Ban Asbestos in America Act of 2007, which would ban asbestos by prohibiting asbestos-containing products from being imported, manufactured, processed, or distributed in the United States. While it has been banned in over 40 countries around the world, we continue to import over $100 million worth of asbestos products annually. This is more than 30 million pounds of asbestos that is imported  for use throughout the Nation. Additionally, the bill calls for a public awareness campaign to help educate patients, workers, family members, and health care providers on the dangers of exposure to asbestos, along with possible treatment options. Asbestos is killing far too many people. We can and should do more. Senator Murray's bill and the National Asbestos Awareness Week are a step in that direction.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
