<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1211299202" ordinal="37" title="MILITARY CONSTRUCTION AND VETERANS AFFAIRS AND RELATED AGENCIES APPROPRIATIONS ACT, 2008--Continued">
  <narrative>MILITARY CONSTRUCTION AND VETERANS AFFAIRS AND RELATED AGENCIES APPROPRIATIONS ACT, 2008--Continued -- (Senate - May 20, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="4475">S4475</bill>]</narrative>
  <chair> A message from the House is the pending measure.</chair>
  <chair>The Senator from New Jersey is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400272" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I raise a point of order that title VIII in its entirety, section 1004 of title X, and section 1005 of title X, each violates paragraph 4 of Senate rule XVI in the Reid motion to concur in the House amendment No. 2, with an amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The point of order is sustained. The motion to concur with the amendment falls.</chair>
  <chair>AMENDMENT NO. 4803 &lt;center&gt;(Purpose: In the nature of a substitute) &lt;/center&gt;</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I appreciate the patience of my friend from New Jersey. He was here much earlier in the day. For a number of reasons we were unable to have him recognized at that time, but he is always such a team player who is willing to wait. I appreciate my friend from New Jersey very much.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At this time I now move to concur with House amendment No. 2, with the amendment which is at the desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>Mr. REID moves to concur in the House amendment No. 2 to Senate amendment to <bill type="h" number="2642">H.R. 2642</bill> with an amendment 4803.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent the reading of the amendment be dispensed with.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <narrative>(The amendment is printed in today's RECORD under "Text of Amendments.")</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask for the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there a sufficient second?</chair>
  <chair>There is a sufficient second.</chair>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I have a second-degree amendment at the desk and I now ask for its consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>The Senator from Nevada [Mr. REID] proposes an amendment numbered 4804 to amendment No. 4803.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent the reading of the amendment be dispensed with.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <narrative>(The amendment is printed in today's Record under "Text of Amendments.")</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>I now send a cloture motion to the desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The cloture motion having been presented under rule XXII, the Chair directs the clerk to read the motion.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>Cloture Motion</narrative>
  <narrative>We, the undersigned Senators, in accordance with the provisions of rule XXII of the Standing Rules of the Senate, hereby move to bring to a close debate on the motion to concur in the House amendment No. 2 to <bill type="h" number="2642">H.R. 2642</bill>, the Supplemental Appropriations bill, with an amendment, Senate amendment No. 4803.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>I now ask unanimous consent the mandatory quorum required under rule XXII be waived.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I have had a number of conversations with the distinguished Republican leader and I  have told him where we are going to try to get by the end of the work week on this matter now before the Senate, and he is mulling over my suggestions that I made to him this afternoon. We will meet again and talk about this tomorrow.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We also have now the budget conference report that has been filed. That was done this afternoon. Tomorrow I am going to ask consent that we move to that. There is a 48-hour rule. Under the 48-hour rule we can't get to that until Thursday at 4 o'clock. I think it would be to everyone's interest to see if we could get rid of that--I don't know if "get rid of" are the right words, but see if we can move on to that and adopt that report tomorrow.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We also received from the House the veto message--I am sorry, the farm bill. We are going to have to, at some time before we leave here, have a vote on overriding the President's veto on the farm bill. So there are things we have to do.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The budget has a statutory time. I am not certain we will need to use the whole 10 hours. I rather doubt it. We have the veto override. That is very privileged. We can spend a lot of time on that or whatever time people want. We hope we could get to that very quickly and see where the votes are.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And then we still have the supplemental to dispose of. So we have a lot to do in the next few days, but with some cooperation I think we can get to where we need to get. I certainly hope so. I hope that is important and understandable to the Senators.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
