<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1181577623" ordinal="19" title="REMEMBERING SENATOR CRAIG THOMAS">
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I honor a colleague, a friend, and a great Senator, Senator Craig Thomas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>No words that I can speak will ease the sadness of this loss. Nothing my colleagues and I say can fill the emptiness that his passing has left or lessen the pain that so many feel.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I feel compelled to speak of Senator Thomas not for the effect of my words. Instead, I speak to recognize the effect of his words, his actions, and his service.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>His were words, actions, and service that have improved the lives and futures of Americans. His words and actions will leave a legacy long after our sadness passes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator Thomas represented Wyoming effectively and with dignity. I was proud to work with him.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We both loved the open beautiful spaces of our home States, and we worked to keep them clean, safe, and sustainable. We collaborated to improve the Endangered Species Act and the Safe Drinking Water Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We also worked to safeguard our constituents' livelihoods--establishing the wool trust fund, keeping open global beef markets, and making sure that our trading partners played by the rules.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We worked together to safeguard our natural resources, improve rural energy infrastructure, and plan for a sustainable energy future with clean coal technologies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These and many other accomplishments will be Senator Thomas's legacy. It is a legacy for which he deserves recognition, remembrance, and honor. It is a legacy for which our Nation is grateful.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But many will remember Senator Thomas more for who he was than for what he did. They will remember someone with a quick wit, an easy smile, and a generous helping hand.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I will remember Senator Thomas as I met him when he first joined the Senate in 1989. Back then, I recognized in him something very familiar. Senator Thomas was a man of the American West. He embodied the values and the character of the people whom he represented.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>You always knew where Senator Thomas stood. Like many in the West, Senator Thomas was quiet, unassuming, and unpretentious--but he was never intimidated.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He was gentle and decent. When he gave you his word, he kept it. And as we all saw in these final months of his life, when he had to, he could fight like hell.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is the man I will miss and it is the man I wish to recognize today--an honorable Senator and a great man of the American West.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300036" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, this last Saturday, I traveled with my wife Nancy and many of our colleagues in the Senate to Casper, WY, for the funeral service of my friend Senator Craig Thomas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>During the service I was particularly impressed by the words of Minority Leader McConnell and I would like to thank him for so eloquently eulogizing Senator Thomas. So appropriately did his words honor Senator Thomas that I hope all our colleges in the Senate will take the time to read them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that this transcript of Senator McConnell's comments be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
</record>
