<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1182355236" ordinal="53" title="CONGRATULATING THE ARIZONA WILDCATS">
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate now proceed to the immediate consideration of <bill type="sr" number="245">S. Res. 245</bill>, which was submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300062" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today I am pleased to join with Senator MCCAIN in support of this resolution to acknowledge the athletic achievement of a tremendous group of young women. On June 6, the University of Arizona women's softball team won the 2007 National Collegiate Athletic Association Division I Softball Championship. By defeating the University of Tennessee Lady Volunteers 5 to 0, the Wildcats claimed their 8th title since 1991.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The victory was a team effort that was marked by a number of special accomplishments. Taryne Mowatt, pitcher for the Wildcats, set a Women's College World Series record by pitching 60 innings and was named the tournament's Most Outstanding Player. Centerfielder Caitlin Lowe had a record-tying 4 hits in the national title game. Shortstop Kristie Fox tied the record with 12 hits in the series. On 4 occasions Fox faced the best pitcher in the country, Tennessee's Monica Abbott. Second baseman Chelsie  Mesa can take credit for hitting a 3-run home run off Abbott to break open the game and send the Wildcats to victory. Taryne Mowatt, Kristie Fox, Jenae Leles, and Caitlin Lowe were selected to be on the all-tournament team because of the skill they demonstrated</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The team's success was guided by their coach, Mike Candrea, who just completed his 22nd season as coach of the University of Arizona softball program. A highly decorated coach, Candrea has won 18 coach-of-the-year honors. He boasts a 1,131 to 228 overall win-loss record. In 2004, Candrea took a  year off to coach the USA Olympic softball team, which went on to take the gold medal.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator MCCAIN and I introduce this resolution today so that this body can send a well-deserved congratulations to the University of Arizona Wildcats and their coach for the hard work and skill they demonstrated in winning the championship.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
