<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1169571615" ordinal="18" title="FAIR MINIMUM WAGE ACT OF 2007--Continued">
  <chair> Under the previous order, there are now 30 minutes equally divided on amendment No. 103, as modified. Who yields time?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I yield myself 3 minutes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator is recognized for 3 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today in support of the amendment offered by Senator Snowe, Senator Landrieu, and others, to provide regulatory assistance to our Nation's small businesses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment requires that when Federal agencies issue new rules and regulations that impact small business, they also must issue compliance guides for small businesses. The amendment also requires that the compliance guides be written in plain English and made available in a timely manner.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think this is a commonsense requirement. It not only reduces the administrative costs for small business, but it also increases the level of compliance with such new rules and regulations. I think the work opportunity tax credit is an example. That isn't a program that a lot of small businesses have taken advantage of. Part of it is because they don't know about it, and part is they don't know how to comply with it. They don't have the opportunity to hire the specialists that might be needed  to understand it or to do the recordkeeping on it. So they don't take advantage of it to the level they could. It is a provision in the tax bill that could make quite a difference to small employers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many small employers simply lack the resources, the outside consultants, the experts necessary to continually advise them of changes in Federal rules that impact the way they must run their business. As it now stands, smaller businesses currently pay disproportionate per employee compliance costs when compared to larger employers. The average per employee cost for Federal regulatory compliance in a business with less than 20 employees is 45 percent higher than the same cost for a business with  500 or more employees. So it is about $7,600 for a small business to comply versus $5,200 for a big business to comply. Those numbers stagger me--the cost for small business to comply with Federal rules and regulations. That doesn't count the cost of complying with the Tax Code, which is a whole other range of costs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Cost mandates, such as a minimum wage increase, impose significant financial burdens on our small employers. We must do everything we can to help alleviate this burden and ensure that small businesses remain the well-run engine of our economy, and providing the kind of compliance assistance called for in Senator Snowe's amendment is one of the ways we can assist small businesses in meeting the administrative costs associated with Federal regulation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I commend Senator Snowe for her efforts on behalf of small businesses and am proud to be a cosponsor of this legislation with her. She has put in diligent efforts to hold hearings and get this into place in the committee that she chaired, the Small Business Committee, on which she is now the ranking member.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this amendment that not only provides assistance that reduces employer costs but also assistance that increases employer compliance. That is two goals. This amendment will do both of those. I ask for your support.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor and suggest the absence of a quorum, and I ask unanimous consent that the time be equally divided between the sides.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will call the roll.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, we still anticipate a vote at 2:45 p.m. As I mentioned, we are going to urge the Senate to accept the amendment offered by Senator Snowe. I think it is an important contribution to small businesses and their understanding of the kinds of rules and regulations that have been out there and do it in ways that are understandable and in a timely way and to ensure that the relevant committee is going to find out how that is being implemented. We are certainly in  strong support of that concept and idea. I commend those who have been involved in it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are going to vote at 2:45. We have amendments that are related to the Finance Committee. I talked with Senator Baucus during the noon hour. His staff is working on some that have been offered by Senator Sessions, and we are in the process of trying to work with the Senator to see what progress can be made, and the Finance Committee staff, as well as Senator Baucus, is attentive to those issues.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator Roberts has an amendment dealing with childcare and small business. It was a subject matter he talked about during our hearing in the Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee. He will come over to the floor now and address the Senate about that issue. We have been trying to work with him. We think most of us have been strong supporters in terms of childcare. Senator Dodd has been a real leader with Senator Hatch in the past with the block grant childcare  program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have a childcare program that is also tied in with the Social Security program, and we have a very effective childcare program in the military which receives awards. It is very close, actually, to the bill that was initially introduced by Senator Dodd a number of years ago.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We will have a chance to consider those amendments in a short period of time. I will take a few minutes now to review for the Senate what will be the first vote tomorrow, and that will be on what we call the line-item veto amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We had an excellent debate and discussion on that amendment yesterday. I refer any of those interested to read the RECORD, the excellent comments that were made on this issue by the chairman of the Appropriations Committee, Senator Byrd, and also the chairman of the Budget Committee, Senator Conrad, enormously, I think, comprehensive comments on it. I urge they read the comments of Senator Gregg as well, who is the proponent of the amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator Conrad and Senator Byrd made excellent presentations. We will be considering that early tomorrow. I hope those who are interested in the amendment will take a few moments and look back at the RECORD. It is a very complete record on that issue. I stand with Senator Conrad and Senator Byrd, for the reasons they have outlined, in opposition to the Gregg amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Next we will have a chance to vote on what we call a clean increase in the minimum wage. That means a vote on the increase in the minimum wage over a 2-year period to rise from $5.15 to $7.25 an hour.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I strongly urge our colleagues to vote for what we call a clean bill on the minimum wage. I do so for a number of reasons.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, this is the area of need. It is among workers who haven't gotten a raise in the last 10 years. For 10 years, the longest time since we had a minimum wage increase, they have lost effectively 20 percent of their purchasing power, and they are working in tough and difficult jobs. These are men and women of great pride and dignity. They do hard, difficult, trying work, and they do it to the best of their ability. They deserve to have a raise.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I don't think any of us in this country thought the minimum wage would be a permanent wage for millions of Americans, and yet, nonetheless, if one looks at the figures, effectively 40 percent of those earning the minimum wage were earning the minimum wage 4 years ago. That they have been able to make ends meet over this amount of time is extraordinary, particularly when they have members of their family to look after.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This country has said if one works hard 40 hours a week, 52 weeks of the year, one shouldn't have to live in poverty in the richest nation in the world. That is an issue of fairness. It is a moral issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As we demonstrated earlier, the Members of the great face of this country have all spoken about the morality of this issue. It is part of our Constitution that talks about the general welfare, how are we going to treat each other. It is as old as the Mayflower Compact. In my State of Massachusetts, before landing, the Pilgrims gathered together near Provincetown. Most people think they landed at Plymouth Rock, but they landed at Provincetown, MA. Before they landed--they had been at sea for close  to 100 days, and many had died and many suffered from disease--they got together and talked about their Compact, their willingness to work together for a common purpose and common respect for their fellow human beings. That was going to be the essence of their whole life experiment in the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is reflected in the actions that have been taken in this body with the minimum wage. On only one occasion in the last nine occasions when we raised the minimum wage have we added a tax provision.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, the minimum wage has lost 20 percent of all of its purchasing power. It was a good deal higher in the sixties, seventies, and eighties. It has dropped and dropped significantly over time and has lost that purchasing power.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Secondly, only once in 1996 did we pair a minimum wage increase with tax cuts. Previous increases had strong bipartisan support, despite the lack of tax cuts. In 1989, the minimum wage was raised with no tax cuts and passed by a margin of 89 to 8. In 1977, with no giveaways, an increase passed 63 to 24. We have seen what has happened. Only one time--it didn't happen in 1938, 1949, 1955, 1961, 1966, 1974, 1977, 1989--only in 1996. And look in the last 10 years what has happened in terms of the  reduction of taxes for corporations and for small businesses. In corporations, it is $276 billion in tax breaks; small businesses, $36 billion; and no raise for minimum wage workers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We didn't hesitate. We were around here to provide tax benefits to small businesses and large corporations. Where were the voices to say let's give the minimum wage workers a little boost?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, all of a sudden, we are trying to get minimum wage workers a little boost, and everybody is running around to get an increase in tax provisions. Fair is fair, Mr. President; fair is fair.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have seen what has happened in productivity. Over the last 10 years--here are the statistics from the Bureau of Labor Statistics--profits are up 45 percent, productivity is up 29 percent, and the minimum wage is down 20 percent. These minimum wage workers haven't even had the opportunity to get an increase in their salaries in spite of the fact that we have seen a real increase in productivity. Historically, when we saw an increase in productivity, that was reflected in an increase in the  minimum wage. That was all true in the 1960s, 1970s, up to the 1980s. As productivity increased, so did the minimum wage increase over a considerable period of time, but not in the last few years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As I have pointed out, a recent Gallup Poll found that 86 percent of small business owners do not think the minimum wage affects their businesses. Three out of four small businesses said an increase in the minimum wage would have no effect on their company. Many small businesses are already paying higher wages to recruit and retain quality workers. A higher minimum wage actually benefits them because it levels the playing field and allows them to compete with the bigger business.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What we have found over time, when we provide a decent wage to workers--and this is demonstrated; I mentioned it here, I spelled it out in some greater degree on yesterday--what we find is we get workers who are loyal to the business. We find there is less of a turnover when there was an increase in the minimum wage to a living wage.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator's time has expired.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Our time has expired. That is interesting. Have we reserved the last 5 minutes for debate on the Snowe amendment?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> That was not the unanimous consent agreement. There is 30 minutes equally divided.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the Chair.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Wyoming.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, how much time is remaining on our side?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator has 6 1/2  minutes remaining.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300041" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the Chair.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I appreciate the comments of the Senator from Massachusetts and the diligence with which he has worked on this issue and the number of times we have debated it. I appreciate the majority leader making it possible for us to consider amendments on this bill. I understand how some people would like  to have this as a clean amendment, that we just do the increase. The debate the last three times we have done it has been about whether we can have some provisions  for small businesses to offset the impact of the raise in the minimum wage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to bring a more personal face to this small business. We confuse that sometimes even with General Motors and some of the airlines. Those are big corporations. In fact, the ones I am particularly concerned about are the ones with 50 employees or less, and even more concerned about the ones that only have 2 or 3 employees. The impact and their ability to adjust is much more limited. We are talking about the inventors in their garages who have an idea and who will employ another person to  help put their product together and market it. We are talking about the corner grocery store. We are talking about the laundry. We are talking about the little shoe store, the independent one.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These are families that are eking out a living. These are not families that are getting rich. These are families that took on a lot of risk for the American dream. They are hoping that with all of the loans they put in place to be able to do this business that they always dreamed of doing, they might make a return on their investment and enough to keep their family going. But there is no guarantee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These are the people who--and I know; I used to be a small businessman. I used to own shoe stores. One of my definitions of a small businessman is the guy who wakes up, sits up straight in bed in the middle of the night and says: Tomorrow is payday; how do I meet payroll? And they figure out a way because the employees get paid first.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These are people worrying about how to stay in business, how to make a living, and taking on a whole lot of risk to make sure other people have jobs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have to remember that the small businessman will be forced to come up with additional funds to pay his or her workers on what we are mandating today. Those funds don't come from a money tree or some pot of gold at the end of the rainbow. They come out of the pockets of the Nation's small businessmen. It is the penalty they pay for taking the risk associated with running a small business.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have about 3 minutes. I yield the remainder of the time to the Senator from Maine.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Maine is recognized for 3 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300091" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I thank the Senator from Wyoming for his leadership on this amendment that is so important to the small business sector of our economy. I also thank Chairman Kennedy as well for bringing this legislation to the floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise today in support of the pending modified amendment we will be voting on shortly that has been offered by the Senator from Wyoming, Mr. Enzi, the Senator from Louisiana, Ms. Landrieu, as well by the Senator from Massachusetts, Mr. Kennedy, to enhance compliance assistance for small businesses. I truly appreciate all those joining me in this effort.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent to add Senators KERRY, BOND, SUNUNU, and ROBERTS as cosponsors to this amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300091" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I want to say to Members of the Senate, this amendment would significantly help to reduce the regulatory burden imposed on small businesses throughout this country. The amendment is designed to clarify an existing Federal law that the Senate unanimously passed back in 1996. The Government Accountability Office has suggested that we needed to have further clarification to the existing law because many Federal agencies are circumventing the law. These agencies are using  loopholes to ignore requirements under the law that the agencies publish small business compliance guides so that small businesses know how to comply with complex Federal regulations. The agencies have used ambiguity in the law as a rationale for not assisting small businesses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment would clarify existing Federal rules and regulations, by requiring that Federal agencies produce compliance assistance materials to help small businesses satisfy their regulatory obligations. Because the GAO has found widespread and pervasive disregard of this law by agencies, we felt it was very important to clarify the law so that small business not only gets the assistance it requires but also can meet the regulatory requirements promulgated by the Federal government.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As we well know, small businesses face a disproportionate burden of the impact of regulations in rules issued by Federal agencies. In fact, employers with 20 or fewer employees face 44.8 percent more of a regulatory burden than companies with 500 or more employees, in terms of compliance costs per employee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So you can see that for our Nation's small businesses, we clearly need to do better so they can continue to drive our economy, by creating three-quarters of all the net new jobs each year. This amendment will go a long way toward easing the impact of the cost of small business regulatory compliance and making sure the agencies comply with requirements under existing law to provide the support small businesses rightly deserve.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> All time has expired.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, have the yeas and nays been ordered?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> They have not been ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask for the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there a sufficient second? There is a sufficient second.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>I announce that the Senator from South Dakota (Mr. JOHNSON) is necessarily absent.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Are there any other Senators in the Chamber desiring to vote?</chair>
  <narrative>The result was announced--yeas 99, nays 0, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300068" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I move to reconsider the vote, and I move to lay that motion on the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, the Senator from Kansas has an amendment. He has brought it up during the course of meetings of our Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee, and he has been advocating for it for some period of time. He wishes to address the Senate at this time, if we could have order so that the Senator could be heard.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Kansas is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300083" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I rise today to offer amendment No. 102.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As we debate the issue of minimum wage, we can't forget the impact on the employers who hire these minimum wage workers. Small businesses pay 45 percent of the payroll in the United States, and they have created 60 to 80 percent of new jobs over the last decade. In my home State of Kansas, small businesses actually employ the brunt of hard-working families. I often hear from these employers who agree with their workers that they deserve a fair wage for a fair day's work, but they  &lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page:  <bill type="s" number="891">S891</bill>]&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/center&gt;</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, if the Senator will yield, maybe we could have order. We are making good progress on this legislation. This is an important amendment. The Senator has spent a good deal of time, and we welcome the opportunity to hear him on it. We would ask our colleagues and friends if they would be good enough to take their conversations to another part of the Senate so we can hear the Senator.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Senators, please remove your conversations out of the well.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300083" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the Senator from Massachusetts and I thank the Presiding Officer and I thank my colleagues to my right who, hopefully, will take their conversation from the floor of the Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, small businesses generally do not have the resources required to start up and support a childcare center like happens in many areas in urban America and big cities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When I came to the Senate in 1997, one of the first bills I introduced was the Small Business Child Care Act, which authorized a short-term flexible grant as a program to encourage small businesses to work together or with other local childcare agencies to provide childcare services for their employees. This amendment includes the bipartisan language of the Small Business Child Care Act that was passed out of the HELP Committee in August of 2005 as part of the larger childcare and development  block grant.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under the amendment, small businesses are eligible for grants up to $500,000 for startup costs and training and scholarships and other related activities, with priority given to grantees who work with other small businesses or local childcare organizations. These grants all have a matching requirement which encourages self-sustaining facilities that will go on well after the program ends.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In many small Kansas towns, childcare facilities can be very scarce, as I have said before. This amendment would alleviate the strain on working families who often have to close the door on the opportunity to be a double-income family because of the lack of childcare options in their communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When I first ran for the House back in 1980, I was going door to door in Dodge City. I was in south Dodge and I knocked on a door and a young lady came to the door and two children were immediately right there with her. I handed her a brochure, and I said: I am running for Congress. What can I do for you? Is there anything I can do for you as a candidate?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>She looked at me with the two kids behind her--she was obviously a single mother--and she said: Mr. Roberts, it's your world, I'm just living in it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That made a big impression on me.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I said: What do you need more than anything else?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>She said: If there could be a possibility that there could be any childcare for these two children, I could go to work. I could go back to work.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But that was not the case at that particular time. Then I promised myself that we would try our very best so that in a small community with a bank, the implement dealer, and, say, a restaurant, they could come together, and with these kinds of grants offer affordable childcare.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I am very hopeful we can get this amendment passed. It is a small change that will make a big difference in the lives of many employees and employers who see a need for childcare in their communities. I hope my colleagues will join me in supporting this amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Connecticut.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300034" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I rise to thank the Senator from Kansas for offering this amendment. Back about 20 years ago, the Senator from Utah and I, along with Senator Kennedy and others, authored the first childcare development block grant ever to be proposed by the Congress. We had hoped in those days that we would be able to expand the availability, affordability, and quality of childcare to millions of Americans and their children who are lacking those resources.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over the years, we have provided some good assistance. I am grateful to my colleagues over the years who have been supportive.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have gone stale on the commitment over the last 5 or 6 years. The funding has not gone up at all and demand continues to grow. We have done a fairly good job in serving some of the working poor. We must do better, however. We have not done a good job, in my view, on the most critical issue most parents and others care about, and that is the quality of childcare. This amendment gets to the quality of child care by providing small businesses the opportunity to use the grant for facilities and  to create partnerships with local organizations such as health departments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What is happening with our colleague's amendment is that it is trying to expand opportunities for families, and I am grateful to him for proposing it. Everyday I hear about the communities in which the demand for child care for exceeds the supply. This amendment would increase the supply and allow more parents to go to work knowing that their children are safe.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am supporting it. I think it is worthwhile, and it will help make a difference of expanding quality and access.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is good for everyone involved. A lot of times we offer legislation with winners and losers. Here, everybody wins. From a business standpoint, they are retaining good employees, allowing parents' minds to be focused on their jobs. In no small measure, this depends on how you feel, where your children are, who is caring for them, and what the conditions are. In terms of productivity and retention, all the elements businesses desire for employees, childcare is a major component. For the parents,  obviously, not to be worried or concerned about the quality of the care their children receive and whether they can afford it is a major issue. I am preaching to the choir for those who understand what I am talking about. Obviously, from the child's perspective, it's essential to be able to have that good, nurturing environment. There is not a guarantee they will get it in every case, but it is more likely if this amendment passes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The difficult area is with smaller businesses. Many larger corporations have installed childcare facilities onsite. In fact, in some cases they have offered less in salaries and wages in exchange for providing better childcare; I am not saying that is great, but people are so hungry to have a good, safe, childcare environment, they will opt for lesser wage or salary in exchange for the assurance their children are in a safe place. Smaller businesses cannot do that. Some of them are at shopping  malls, and they develop consortiums and set aside space. There are a lot of creative ideas. But it is the hardest thing in the world for smaller business to provide child care. It is not that they do not recognize the need for it. They understand the value</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While I am here, I would like to talk about the underlying bill, to raise the minimum wage. Exactly because of what the Senator from Kansas has offered, it is important to know that his amendment is a related matter when it comes to children. The increase in the minimum wage has a huge impact on children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I am taking advantage of a couple of minutes on his amendment to highlight this point. In the last 5 years, we have watched child poverty in this country increase by 1.3 million children. This figure is from the U.S. Census Bureau, not a private think tank making this up. Nearly 12.9 million children in this country live in poverty.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Obviously, that is a matter of great concern, I hope to all of us. What is bothersome to me and should be to every single one of us--I don't care what your politics are or your political persuasion--the fact that the United  States of America, at the outset of the 21st century, has one of the highest rate of child poverty among all the industrialized nations. That is something that ought to concern each and every one of us, not just because of what a shameful  statistic that is. As we look to the 21st century, watching our country grow, meeting the challenges in front of us, we have to do a better job if we are going to have a well-prepared generation to meet the challenges.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Aside from providing decent child care, we know by increasing the earning capacity of parents we make a difference. In fact, nearly 6 million children will benefit from a minimum wage increase.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Children whose parents are economically secure--and this increase is not going to guarantee security, but it moves a family closer to it--have better attendance in school and have a higher concentration on the work they are asked to do. Performance levels go up, test scores go up, and graduation rates increase when a family's economic circumstances are far more stable. In addition, children have stronger immune systems, better health, fewer expensive hospital visits and fewer run-ins with the  juvenile justice system. Those are facts when you have a family doing better economically. For the families who have the greatest economic stability at home, these statistics improve in almost every category.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of what the Senator from Kansas has offered, focusing on childcare, combined with what the Senator from Massachusetts, Senator Kennedy, is leading today on the minimum wage, we can make a difference for these children. That is the point I wanted to make to my colleagues.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I commend them both. It is long overdue. My hope is that the amendment from my friend from Kansas will be a forerunner this year for increasing our commitments to child care. My colleague from Maine, Senator Snowe, has been terrific on this issue over the years. Senator Hatch was my principal cosponsor on this many years ago. It was courageous of him then. A lot of people did not realize the value of it. I am remiss not mentioning those who played a significant role. And let  me add my colleague, Senator Roberts, for his leadership on this issue. I thank him immensely. I thank Senator Kennedy for his leadership on minimum wage. We can make a difference for children with both of these proposals.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Massachusetts.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I thank my friend and colleague for his excellent presentation. He has been the leader of the children's caucus and a leader on this issue of childcare.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have 14,000 family members now waiting, parents who are waiting for childcare slots in my State of Massachusetts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have listened to the Senator give the statistics nationwide. This is all related to work. It is obviously related to lower income because those at the lower income levels have less opportunity as far as affordability.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I can remember when the Senator first offered the childcare legislation. I remember the debates we had about limiting the childcare legislation. We debated for about 10 days or so while it was constantly adjusted, altered, and changed. Eventually, it passed. The childcare block grant has done an enormous amount of good.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senator has been very much involved in the other childcare programs that have come out through the CDBG and the other Social Security programs. There is a third childcare program, the one in the military. If you read back in the history books, that particular program passed by over 90 votes. This, effectively, was the legislation the Senator from Connecticut introduced. Today, when we have comparisons about which childcare programs work the best, everyone points to the military. The Senator  from Connecticut can give the reasons for it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The point is, this is a matter of enormous importance to working families, with the whole change in the workforce, the increasing number of women in the workforce, the increasing number of women with children, the increasing demands upon those women, in particular, but not exclusively.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We appreciate the fact that the Senator from Kansas would give focus and attention to this issue. We wish to work with the Senator. We can do part of the job in terms of the authorization. We are going to rely on him to help get limited resources to make sure we bring life to this program. I thank the Senator for his statements and comments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We look forward to hearing from my friend and colleague from Wyoming, hopefully, urging acceptance of the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Wyoming.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I echo what the Senator from Massachusetts said, that this does provide for authorization. There is room for that to be included, and we can help look for the resources to do something on that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I commend both Senator Roberts and Senator Dodd for their tenaciousness and their active work to be able to bring this to the Senate at this point in time. I note that Senator Roberts has been working on this for about 10 years. Six years is the average for a bill around here. That should qualify.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask we make this part of that package.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Kansas.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300083" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I say to the Senator from Connecticut, I thank him very much for his comments. He has been absolutely tenacious, as described by the Senator from Wyoming.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I can remember, it was about, what, 5, 6, 7 years ago, that we all were over, on a cold day, at the childcare center that is offered for employees on Capitol Hill over by the Hart building. We had a press conference. Senator Kennedy was there, I was there, Senator Dodd was there, I think Senator Jeffords was there at that time. That was 4 or 5 years ago.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So we should be moving on these things. I pledge my support to see what we can do down the road.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise to call up Senate amendment 102.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection the pending amendments are set aside.</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will report.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300083" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent the reading of the amendment be dispensed with.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I see the Senator from Alabama looking for recognition. He has filed some amendments. Hopefully, I will have an opportunity to discuss some of those.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Alabama.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300088" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank Senator Kennedy and Senator Enzi for their courtesy as we discuss some of the issues I have raised by my amendments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What is the pending business?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The pending question is amendment 118 offered by Senator Kyl.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300088" topic="">
    <paragraph>I call for the regular order with respect to Senate amendment 106 and send a modification to the desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator has that right.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300088" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, it is important as we think about low- and middle-income, middle-class workers in America today, to think about how they are getting along and whether they are saving adequately. Savings is a part of any person's financial security. It makes a difference between how a person thinks about his life, how he or she thinks about her job, and how they can live in the latter years. Most Americans today depend upon Social Security to finance their retirement as Social Security  provides 73 percent of the retirement income of the typical household. That is not enough money for the average American to live on adequately. The truth is, they can have so much more so easily. I would like to talk about that today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To live the comfortable life that Americans deserve after 40-plus years of work, most need to supplement their Social Security income with additional savings, either through an employer-sponsored plan or their own savings plan. Yet despite this need, most Americans are not putting aside money for their future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Statistic after statistic tragically shows this. The personal savings rate in the United States, as this chart demonstrates, is at its lowest ebb since the Great Depression. It is a matter of national importance, as the Chairman of the Reserve Board and others have discussed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Look at this chart. It shows, since 1946, our savings rate has fallen steadily; in 2006, it is below zero. We are spending our savings now more than we are saving. It is a very troubling matter. We have to do something about it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After having averaged better than 7 percent throughout most of the post-World War II period, the personal savings rate dipped into negative territory by 2005 for the first time since 1933. This trend continued last year as the personal savings rate remained in negative territory for the first three quarters of 2006, with the fourth quarter numbers not yet reported.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These statistics indicate that the average American household has been spending more during the last 2 years by either drawing down past savings or selling assets or borrowing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An alarming number of Americans also lack any financial resources beyond personal income. According to a Federal Reserve 2004 survey of consumer finances, 17 percent of all households have zero or a negative net worth, while 30 percent have a net worth of less than $10,000. This is especially a problem for African-American households, as they are more than twice as likely to have zero or a negative net worth.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Perhaps most troubling, as this next chart demonstrates, almost half of the 152 million Americans who worked in 2004, 71.5 million employees, worked for an employer that did not sponsor a retirement plan of any kind. Another 17 million did not participate in the plan their employer offered. That means over 58 percent of working Americans in 2004 were not participating in an employer-sponsored retirement plan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Higher income people take care of their plans, but the average working American tends to focus his savings through his business and employer. In particular, younger workers are much less likely to participate in their employer's 401(k) plan, as only about one-third of workers age 21 to 30 participate in any retirement plan at work. Even if a worker is participating in an employer-sponsored retirement plan, he or she is unlikely to be saving sufficiently for the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The average American worker holds nine jobs by the time they are 35, meaning that he or she often leaves the job before their retirement benefits become vested. In fact, frequently they cash it out. I had the opportunity to be on an airplane recently with a young man, 37, with two kids. He is beginning to work for the Federal Government. He is going to be saving through the thrift plan. I asked him what he had done before about savings. I told him the average person had nine jobs. He said: I  had nine jobs. And when asked about savings, he said: I cashed in my plans. I just had a few hundred dollars in this one and a few hundred in that one. It didn't make sense to hold on to them. I cashed them in and paid my penalties. So at 35 with two kids, he has missed those first 10 or 15 or 20 years of work</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As this next chart shows, if we considered business and Government savings, we find that the United States has the lowest national savings rate of any of the group of 20 industrial nations. Whereas Japan's savings rate was 10.8 percent in 2003, Germany's was 5.4 percent, and India's was 15.4 percent, the United States had a net national savings rate of 1.6 percent in 2003. This is a World Bank chart. We can see we have the lowest rate on the chart. That is significant, not only for individuals,  most importantly for individual working Americans, but also for our economy because economists tell us that this is a major detriment to our economy. In fact, all but two of the nations listed on the chart I just showed have a net national savings rate of more than twice that of the United States, if not more than 10 times our savings rate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The lack of personal savings is a particular problem in my State of Alabama. An A.G. Edwards study rated Alabama the Nation's 46th lowest savings State. This lack of personal savings is a national tragedy, as few Americans are putting money aside to ensure their financial security upon retirement, during a time where we have growth and relative prosperity in our Nation. I will repeat that. Think about the tragedy that is occurring when people are not setting aside even a small percentage of their  salary, when if they do, they could retire with hundreds of thousands of dollars in a savings account at age 65. This is very realistic. It is very possible. I will talk about it a little bit more in a minute. But as anybody knows who has studied the compound interest factor, the earlier you save, the more important it is. So it is</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Increasing savings also allows Americans to achieve greater control and choice over their lives. According to the Center for Social Development, the presence of savings is even associated with improved health and psychological well-being.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The benefits of increasing our Nation's personal savings rate go beyond the financial security of individual families. By increasing household savings, we will be providing the investment capital our Nation needs to ensure long-term economic growth and create more and better jobs. Increasing savings will allow the United States to depend less on foreign capital. America's current account deficit, the amount of domestic investment financed by borrowing from abroad, hit a record high of over 6  percent of GDP in 2005. Foreign capital can sustain our economy in the short run, but I don't know if we can depend on that in the long run. Moreover, we, as a country, benefit from the interest and dividends our assets generate when we own them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So what can we do to increase personal savings for retirement? I will soon be introducing a bill to help solve our savings problem by creating a national savings system that would give every American the opportunity to retire a half-millionaire. Not a chicken in every pot, not a car in every garage, we desire that every American be able to retire with half a million dollars in the bank. That is possible, realistic, so easily within our grasp if we set forth the right plans today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under the plan I will be introducing, individual savings accounts, or PLUS Accounts--for Portable, Lifelong, Universal Savings accounts--would be created for every working American. One percent of every paycheck earned would be deposited automatically, pretax, into individual PLUS Accounts, along with a 1-percent match from every employer, and invested in a new system like our Federal thrift system, a new 401(k)-type system. Under this plan, a savings account would be established for every American  at birth, endowing these accounts with $1,000.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a proposal which the British are already doing. The UK has a plan similar to this plan. They are very excited about how well it is working. Savings among families in Britain has gone up 40 percent since they started this plan. It has educated people to the power of savings and compound interest.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senators, such as Mr. Schumer, Mr. Santorum, and others, have previously offered legislation of this kind.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So these funds contributed to PLUS Accounts would be the legal property of each account holder, but they could not be spent until age 65. Any funds remaining when an individual died would be passed on as they chose to their spouse, children, grandchildren, or any one of the holder's choosing, including a favorite charity. Account assets would be protected from creditors and would not be considered in determining eligibility for any federally funded benefits or in calculating estate tax liability.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, my plan would simply serve as a supplement to Social Security, not altering the</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Social Security system in any way. I supported the President's idea of changes in Social Security. I thought it made sense. We did not have the votes to do that in this Congress. So I say, let's do it on top of Social Security.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe this can work. If we begin PLUS Accounts at birth and require a portion of every paycheck to be invested, the first check you get, the first job you go to work at, the average American citizen could retire with a rather sizable nest egg. For example, given a reasonable rate of return, someone who makes $46,000 a year--the median household income in 2005--and only contributes 1 percent of each paycheck would retire with almost $300,000 in the bank. Think about that. You put in 1 percent,  your employer puts in 1 percent. You have a $1,000 deposit at birth. With no more money put in there other than what you pay out, you would retire with $300,000 in your account. What a remarkable and great country this is. At age 65, this account could be converted to an annuity that would pay the recipient $2,100 per month for life, which is probably more than they will get from Social Security. If the same individual were to contribute 3 percent, if they would</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have to say, I was talking with Senator Corker from Tennessee, a successful businessman, about this issue. He said: I believe in savings. We have a savings plan in my company that our people all sign up for.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I said: Tell me about it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He said: We put in 10 percent, if they will put in 5 percent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Think about that. That is what Senator Corker does. A lot of businesses would do this. A lot of businesses would put in more. Many already are, but many businesses would step up to the plate and put in more than 1 percent. But if the employee put in 3 percent and the employer put in 1, at age 65, it would be worth half a million dollars, if you are operating at median income. That is remarkable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thus, I would say that if we care about working Americans, if we really want to do something historic, I believe we have an opportunity, a bipartisan opportunity to establish a savings program for Americans. That program should be modeled, in my view, although I am open to other suggestions, on the Federal thrift plan that our employees admire so much and they value so much, you couldn't take it from them with a crowbar. The Federal employees like it. They pay Social Security, and they get a  thrift plan where the Government puts in 5 percent if they put in 5 percent. And they can put in more than that. Many of these young people working today who work a career in the Government are going to retire with a very sizable nest egg, something they own, an asset they have earned themselves from their work, and they will be able to retire comfortably, whereas otherwise they may be dependent on Social Security.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is a national tragedy that we are not educating our children to save. It is a national tragedy that our savings rate has fallen below zero. I believe we can do better. I am offering this sense-of-the-Senate resolution to have the Senate think about it, to affirm its commitment to increasing savings. As we go forward in the weeks to come, we could be talking about the various proposals that are out there to actually make this happen.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I see Senator Kennedy is off the floor. As I understand, we will set the vote on this resolution for an appropriate time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Hopefully, we will have strong support from my colleagues.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Kentucky is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300014" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I call up amendment No. 119.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the pending amendment is set aside.</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will report.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300014" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that reading of the amendment be dispensed with.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300014" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, this is an important amendment for many of our seniors because it deals with the taxes on Social Security benefits. I have brought this issue before this Chamber before, so it should be familiar to many of my colleagues.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When the Social Security program was created, benefits were not taxed. However, in 1983, Congress changed the rules of the game by passing legislation to begin taxing up to 50 percent of a senior's Social Security benefit if their income was over $25,000 for a single individual or $32,000 for a couple.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many seniors across the country were hit with a tax they never anticipated and were forced to send a portion of their Social Security benefits back to the IRS.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1993, Congress felt taxing 50 percent of benefits wasn't good enough. That year, Congress passed and President Clinton signed a bill that allows 85 percent of a senior's Social Security benefits to be taxed if their income is above $34,000 for a single and $44,000 for a couple. This was known as the "Clinton senior citizens tax."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The additional money this tax raises doesn't even go into helping Social Security solvency; instead, it goes into a Medicare Part A program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I was a Member of the House of Representatives in 1993, and I opposed this tax then and I oppose this tax today, 14 years later.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Some people think this tax only affects "rich" seniors, but that is not the case. In fact, the income thresholds both for the 50-percent tax and the 85-percent tax haven't changed since they were first enacted back in 1983 and 1993. This means more and more seniors are paying these taxes every year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In fact, it is estimated that of the 40 million Social Security beneficiaries, about 15 million--or 39 percent--of seniors pay taxes on their Social Security benefits. Of these, it is estimated that over 9.5 million pay taxes on up to 85 percent of their Social Security benefit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On one hand, we tell seniors to plan and save for retirement and, on the other hand, we tax them for doing that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the past, there have been efforts by Members of Congress, including myself, to remove this unfair tax. During debate on the Senate 2006 budget resolution, I offered an amendment that provided Congress with the budget resources to remove this unfair tax on benefits. My amendment passed 55 to 45. Unfortunately, the tax reconciliation instructions were scaled back during conference.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, I am offering another amendment to finally repeal the 1993 tax on Social Security benefits. This means the 85-percent tax tier would be eliminated and the maximum amount of Social Security benefits that could be taxed would be 50 percent. Millions of seniors would be able to keep more of their Social Security benefits, and Congress gets an opportunity to end this unfair tax on seniors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is also important to point out that the Medicare Program is not harmed by my amendment. As I already said, this tax funds the Medicare program. Therefore, my amendment transfers to Medicare any amount it would have received due to this tax from the general fund.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This was an unfair tax on our seniors, and it is time we repeal it. I urge my colleagues to support this amendment. I thank the Chair for the time. We will look for a time later to bring up the amendment again.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Vermont is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400357" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I rise today in strong support of the Fair Minimum Wage Act of 2007. I commend Senator Kennedy for his leadership on this issue. This important legislation would increase the Federal minimum wage from the abysmally low $5.15 an hour to $7.25 an hour over a 2-year period.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let us make no mistake about it, this bill will benefit millions of workers and their families. It is very long overdue. Anyone who works 40 hours a week in the United States of America should not be living in abject poverty. It is a moral disgrace that Congress has not increased the minimum wage since 1997. Yes, Congress has provided hundreds of billions of dollars in tax breaks to people who don't need it, but somehow, over a 10-year period, Congress has not reached out to millions of workers  making the minimum wage and raised that wage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today's minimum wage workers have less buying power than minimum wage workers did back in 1955, when Dwight Eisenhower was President. Simply put, a job should keep you out of poverty, not keep you in poverty.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At the current Federal minimum wage of $5.15 an hour, a person working full time makes less than $11,000 per year before taxes, which is approximately $6,000 below the Federal poverty line for a family of three.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Moreover, while the cost of living has skyrocketed, the value of the minimum wage has eroded by over 20 percent since the last increase. Today, nearly 13 million workers, 10 percent of the United States workforce, would directly or indirectly benefit from a raise in the minimum wage to $7.25 an hour; 5.5 million workers would benefit directly, 7.4 million workers would benefit indirectly, and more than 60 percent of those who would benefit are women.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to workers, millions of American families would benefit from a raise in the minimum wage, including nearly 6 million children who would see their parents' earnings increase.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But some will argue that an increase in the minimum wage will primarily benefit teenagers. I think the evidence is quite strong that that is not the case. Further, recently, over 650 economists, including Nobel Prize winners and past presidents of the American Economics Association, released a statement calling for a raise in the minimum wage. They confirm that "a modest increase in the minimum wage would improve the well-being of low-wage workers and would not have the adverse effects that  critics have claimed. ..... The weight of the evidence suggests that modest increases in the minimum wage have very little or no effect on employment."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Moreover, and interestingly, a recent Gallup Poll revealed that 86 percent of small business owners today do not believe that an increase in the minimum wage would hurt their business. Three-fourths of small business owners thought a 10-percent increase would have no effect on them. In fact, nearly half of those polled thought the minimum wage should be increased.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While I believe it is important to raise the minimum wage to $7.25 an hour, it is clear to me that much more needs to be done. We should see this increase--long overdue--in the minimum wage as simply a start to address the disgraceful reality that more and more of our fellow Americans are living in poverty, and it is an outrage that  today in the United States of America we have, by far, the highest rate of childhood poverty in the industrialized world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the last 10 years, what we have seen in our country is a proliferation of millionaires and billionaires. We have seen the wealthiest people become ever wealthier. But what we have also seen, since President Bush has been in office, is that over 5 million more Americans have slipped into poverty. The rich become richer, the poor become poorer, and the middle class continues to shrink. In my view, raising the minimum wage is an important start in attempting to address the crisis of poverty in  America, but it is clear to me that we have to do much more. Among many other things we have to do, we must address the reality in America today that we are losing millions of good-paying manufacturing jobs and good-paying white-collar information technology jobs because of our disastrous trade agreements.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The time is now to begin to fundamentally rethink our trade agreements so we can begin to create good-paying jobs here in the United States, so our young people will be able to make it to the middle class rather than to continue to struggle year after year in poverty.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have to take a hard look at the National Labor Relations Act and the National Labor Relations Board, which today make it increasingly hard for workers to form unions. If workers are able to collectively negotiate a contract, very often the wages they get will be substantially higher than if they did not have a union. So in raising the minimum wage, what we are doing today is saying to millions of workers who are struggling desperately to keep  their  heads above water, we understand what you are going through. We understand it is an outrage that for a 10-year period this Congress has not raised the minimum wage, and the purchasing value of the minimum wage has declined. But I hope that what we are doing this week is simply a start to address the very serious economic problems facing not only low-income Americans but the middle class as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I hope that this Senate, this Congress, will begin focusing its attention on the decline of the middle class, the increase of poverty, and come up with economic and fiscal policies that benefit all Americans and not just the wealthy and large multinational corporations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from South Carolina is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300047" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent to speak for 5 minutes as in morning business.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300047" topic="NEW STRATEGY IN IRAQ">
    <paragraph>Madam President, the reason I rise to take the floor is this afternoon--I think the Presiding Officer was present in the Armed Services Committee hearing when General Petraeus testified about the new strategy in Iraq. I hope that over time more Americans will be familiar with him and his view of what we can do to go forward.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In his testimony, General Petraeus clearly indicated we have made a lot of mistakes in Iraq. We never had enough troops to secure the country, and the debaathification program basically was a mistake. Other agencies involved in nationbuilding have not done their part. Militias have grown. The biggest event in the sectarian violence was the bombing of the Shia Golden Dome Mosque, and since that event, which was al-Qaida-inspired, we have been going backward instead of forward and the sectarian  violence in Baghdad has gotten worse.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But General Petraeus believes this new strategy is not more people doing the same thing. It is a fundamentally different shift in policy. I agree with him and hope the country will listen closely to what he says. I have a lot of confidence in General Petraeus. I intend to support him.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I will not vote for any resolution that declares a strategy of failure before he has a chance to implement it because if we do that, it is going to be a very bad sendoff for our troops going into battle. It will embolden the enemy and weaken the moderates we eventually have to rely on in the Mideast to help us in the war on terror.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The strategy will be similar to this: We will be increasing reinforcements on all fronts. We have had enough military people in Iraq to clear territory but never hold it. We never lost a battle with insurgents. We can clear out a town or sector of Baghdad, but once we leave, we turn it over to an immature Iraqi Army or corrupt police force.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What we are doing by having 21,500 more troops is it doubles the combat capability of American forces in Baghdad to 17,500, and that will allow some soldiers to stay behind with the Iraqis to hold territory. Hold for what purpose? To give the political leadership in Iraq a chance to reconcile their differences through the political process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ask General Petraeus: Do you believe Iraq is part of the overall global war on terror?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I do.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If you believe it is a Vietnam which is a lost cause and not worth fighting for and we need to get out, don't pass a resolution condemning the action. Cut off funding. If you believe it is part of the global war on terror, as I do, we need to fight to win. I think that is exactly what we are trying to do. We are going to reinforce the military so we can hold, to give the Iraqi leadership a chance to reconcile the problems politically. I don't believe any political group could find democracy or  common ground in this much violence. It is hard enough for us to find a solution to immigration and none of us being shot at. Can you imagine trying to reconcile a country oppressed by dictators for over 30 years with this level of violence?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If we can control the violence, I think it will lead to a better political result. They have to share the oil revenues with the Sunnis. The Sunnis have to have something to fight for, not against. That has to happen. At the end of the day, a million troops won't change Baghdad or Iraq if the Iraqi people are not willing to make the accommodations they need to make. They are under siege. They need reinforcements.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On the economic front, 70 percent of our casualties come from improvised explosive devices, somebody planting a bomb along the side of the road. Some people are planting those bombs because they don't have a job. They don't have any way to support their family, so they are taking money from the insurgents. Let's create an economy to give them an option other than planting bombs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Secondly, some people are planting bombs because there is no downside. Once you get caught, you get released. We need a robust rule of law. If you want to change the way our troops are treated in Iraq, put people in jail for a very long time for attacking our troops. That will be a deterrent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, more military presence will put pressure on those making these explosive devices. This is a surge on all fronts. He is confident this plan will work. He understands the Iraqi political leadership has to do their part. The Iraqi military has to do their part. But the sectarian violence has come about because al-Qaida hit the motherload when they blew up the Golden Mosque. We cannot let al-Qaida win in destabilizing Iraq. They went to Iraq behind us because they understand that the consequences  of success in Iraq are not confined to Iraq. If you can have a stable, functioning democracy that is tolerant, then it will spread to other areas of the Mideast and will be a mighty blow to the al-Qaida agenda.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We need to understand that a failed state in Iraq creates chaos for not just us but the world. Iran becomes a big winner. The south of Iraq becomes a puppet state of Iran. We could have a war between Turkey and the Kurds in the north. And if there is a bloodbath in Bagdad, which there surely will be if we leave, then Sunni Arab nations are going to get involved, and the whole region becomes much more unstable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to listen to General Petraeus and ask the question: Do you have confidence in this man to do what he says he can do? And if the answer is yes, don't undermine him before he leaves. Give him the resources he needs. If you don't have confidence in him and our military and our leadership to change policy and strategy and be successful, don't let one more person go to Iraq to get killed or wounded in a lost cause. You should have the courage of your convictions to cut off funding.  A middle-ground solution is the worst of all worlds.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam President, I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Wyoming.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, on behalf of Senator Ensign, I call up amendments Nos. 152, 153, and 154.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered. The clerk will report.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that the reading of the amendments be dispensed with.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, in a while, we will take some action on Senator Sessions' amendment. I would like to make a couple comments on that amendment before we get to that point. This might be an appropriate time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last year, Congress undertook the most sweeping changes to pension law since the enactment of ERISA. It was a major milestone and resulted in the most comprehensive change to workers' and their families' pension and retirement savings in the past 32 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Pension Protection Act could not have been enacted without bipartisan cooperation, but it took more than Republicans and Democrats working together. The Pension Protection  Act resulted from a deep commitment toward cooperation between the Finance Committee, which oversaw the tax provisions of the bill, and the Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee, which oversaw the pensions provisions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On the Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee, we had previously taken a strong bipartisan look at retirement issues and retirement savings as part of our pension oversight duties. The new chairman of the committee has stated he will continue the committee's strong pension oversight responsibilities in order to protect and strengthen the retirement savings so that workers and their families may prosper long into their retirement years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The sense-of-the-Senate resolution before us expresses the sentiment that saving for retirement is important. We all agree with that point. The fact is that savings opportunities are available almost everywhere, but many workers do not take advantage of it. By this sense-of-the-Senate resolution, we are not advocating any particular retirement programs or initiatives over others on the books already or proposed to be introduced. We are simply saying that people ought to save enough to maintain  their standard of living during their golden years, and they ought to invest prudently so that their savings will be safe when they do retire.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Better financial education and investment advice is needed. Automatic enrollment rules that were enacted in the Pension Protection Act will help people learn to save. New default investment regulations, when finalized, will help too.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In that respect, progress has been made in saving for retirement, but much needs to be done.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am happy to join with my colleagues in reiterating the commitment by supporting the sense-of-the-Senate resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Massachusetts.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I expect we will vote at a quarter to 5 or so on the Sessions amendment. I will vote in favor and urge my colleagues to vote in favor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Americans who have worked hard and played by the rules for a lifetime deserve a secure retirement. They deserve to be able to enjoy their golden years, spend time with their families, and rest after a lifetime of hard work. We need to be sure they have the income they need for gasoline, prescription drugs, and other needs of daily living.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As my friend and colleague, Senator Enzi, pointed out, we passed a comprehensive bill last year. It was the result of years of work by the HELP and Finance Committees. That work took steps to strengthen our pension system and increase retirement savings, but we still have a long way to go. Half of Americans have no type of pension plan at all in their workplace. And today, Americans have negative savings rates for the first time since the Great Depression.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In order to guarantee a secure retirement for Americans, we need to ensure that the three legs of retirement security are all there: Social Security, private pensions, and personal savings. Each one of these legs plays a vital role, and we need to strengthen all three--Social Security, private pensions, and personal savings.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I know the Senator from Alabama has proposed ideas for creating and expanding personal savings. Our staff has been talking about these ideas and many proposals are being developed by Senator Baucus, Senator Bingaman, Senator Conrad, and others. I look forward to continuing to work with Senator Enzi, Senator Mikulski, and Senator Byrd on our Retirement Security Subcommittee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is an area of enormous concern for working families in this country--what is going to happen during their golden years. They look forward to Social Security, and we are going to have to address that issue. We are going to have to address the Medicare issue, which will begin to run out of funds in, I believe, 2018.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We know that defined benefit programs have been collapsing over the years, and 401(k)s that have tried to fill in have not played the role that defined benefit plans played in terms of giving answers to workers, and we have seen that the personal savings accounts brought out during the discussions by Senator Enzi and Senator Sessions have been in rapid decline.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The indicators are all moving in the wrong direction, in terms of a firm, secure, dependable, and reliable retirement program for working families in this country. We should find ways to work to encourage a change in that policy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At the appropriate time, when the Senator comes back, we will dispose of the Senator's amendment. We are at an appropriate time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that at 4:45 p.m. today, the Senate proceed to a vote on or in relation to the Session's amendment No. 106, as modified; that there be 2 minutes of debate equally divided and controlled between Senator Kennedy and Senator Sessions prior to the vote; and that no second-degree amendment be in order to the amendment prior to the vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, too often when we debate the issue of minimum wage, we focus on abstract ideas and proposals and fail to consider the impact of our actions on the small business community that lives and breathes in the real world. I appreciate the cooperation with Senator Reid and others, focused around Senator Baucus and Senator Grassley, working in a very bipartisan way to put together a package that would help to relieve some of the impact of the minimum  wage increase. I hope everyone has noticed that in the minimum wage debate we have been having, the debate has not been over whether to raise the minimum wage. The debate has been on what we can do to alleviate some of the impact on small business. I hope that is the way we can continue the discussion on this, too.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I mentioned earlier today that you need to meet some of these small businessmen. They are in your neighborhood. You can meet them easily. They run the laundry, corner grocery, little retail stores. For the most part they are families who are eking out a living while they are taking on a lot of risk. They do have these moments that they wonder why they undertook that risk and how they are going to continue to fund that risk. Sometimes they are paying employees when they can't even afford to pay  themselves, and their families are relying on the business to support them as a family, too, particularly considering all the risks they are taking.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sometimes they are forced to come up with additional funds to pay their workers on what we will be mandating. Those funds do not come from a money tree or some pot of gold at the end of the rainbow. They come out of the pockets of the Nation's small businessmen. It is the penalty they pay for taking the risks associated with running a small business.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The first hearing I held in Wyoming was as part of the Small Business Committee. We had a hearing on some of the problems of small business. When it was over, one of the reporters came up and said: You only had about 100 small businessmen attend this. Why do you suppose it was such a poor turnout?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I said: That wasn't a poor turnout from small business. If small business had an extra employee to send to a day's conference, they would fire him. They can't afford extra people.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With that realization, it was a good turnout and there were a lot of good suggestions. I always like to go back to Wyoming and meet with the people and actually talk to the guy on the end of the shovel because he usually has the best suggestions for changing the shovel. I found that to be true of the small businessmen.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This afternoon we agreed to an amendment that will provide for easier compliance with Federal rules and regulations, and I appreciate the bipartisan action that was taken. That will make a huge difference to small businessmen.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We could consider that the action we are about to take will be making it bad business for people to hire people who need some help and support in developing their skills by that method, making them higher wage workers. That cannot help but cost some people their jobs. In other instances, the hours they need will be cut back, hours that they need to get a good paycheck.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We cannot leave the floor today feeling better about having helped ease the income strain for many of the workers of our States but having left the employers wondering how to pay for the increases we have mandated. Once again, we have the best of intentions, but, once again, we have to remember one simple rule: It is not our money. We are, once again, reaching into the pockets of the small businessmen in our community and taking their money and telling them the amount of wages they will pay their  employees without regard to the talents and abilities of the employees they can hire.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have this huge job training corps out there. It is called small businesses. They take people who don't have the skills that are necessary for the small business they are operating and they teach them how to run a cash register, how to count change, how to interact with a customer, how to dress appropriately.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>You might think these are all things that might be covered in school classes, and they are, if you take the right classes. But there are a lot of people who not only don't take the right classes, they drop out of school. They need to earn a living and they have to start somewhere earning a living. To earn that living they have to have some training, some basic job training. A lot of these small businesses are where they get that basic business training, and they kind of get it for free. The businessmen  provide that information, and most of the people in the minimum wage level move up rather quickly. As they learn those skills, they get paid more. I know a lot of businesses where they have the minimum wage situation that lasts about 3 weeks if the people learn enough to advance so they can actually wait on the customer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What we are talking about is a blanket increase that will warm the hearts of those who lack the skills for higher wage jobs as it leaves the employers out in the cold, unless we do the Reid package. Any increase in the minimum wage must be offset by a small business tax incentive package.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a former small business owner of mom-and-pop shoe stores, let me walk through the realities of how business owners may address a mandated Federal minimum wage hike. Raising the minimum wage to $7.50 imposes a 41-percent increase in labor costs for a small employer with minimum wage workers. Every employer must face the very real issue of how he or she will deal with this increase in the costs and still meet the payroll week after week.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These are very real and difficult questions that impact our smallest employers most heavily. These increases must be paid for by employers and, as I said before, the money doesn't grow on trees. An employer must make hard decisions about how to meet these increased payroll obligations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When costs go up, most businesses first look to cut expenses. The choices they have can be difficult and have often already been used. To meet higher mandated payroll costs, a small employer may be forced to consider cutting back on benefits such as health insurance, retirement, or leave plans--although a lot of small businesses can't afford to provide those in the first place.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is simply too easy to forget that fringe benefits have a significant cost. Most employees don't realize the benefit they are getting when they get those. If a small  employer has to reduce expenses to meet payroll, those are often the costs that go.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I know of a video store--I was talking to a young man who works in the Senate now, and he used to work in the Senate and part-time in a video store. When the minimum wage went up last time, what the video store did was instead of having two people at the store at the close of business, they only had one, and only having one isn't nearly as safe as having two. But that was the choice that the owner had to make in order to be able to meet the payroll.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have seen some charts where, in States where there has been a raise in minimum wage, there has been an increase in number of jobs as well. I appreciate those charts and believe those charts to be accurate. What those charts are doing, though, is aggregating for the entire State. What we are doing is imposing this on one business at a time, one employee at a time. It really gets down to as local as politics ever gets. Those small businessmen believe that individuals matter, that people matter,  and they are forced into some of these choices. There are not a whole lot of ways they can compensate for the change.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have a chart that shows how to cut costs when there are none to cut. This came from the Washington Post. It says:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We're at the bottom. If the minimum wage went up, I don't know how we would make the cuts to cover it ..... the employee said.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The lone salaried employee, she works 80 hours a week to make up for the lack of workers. "I have mixed feelings," she continued. "I know that people can't afford to live on $5.15 an hour. But on the business side, small businesses can't afford to pay it."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are examples like that that are real-life situations that do make it difficult. That is the lone employee in a store.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Beyond cutting fringe benefits, small businesses may need to consider cutting back work hours, eliminating overtime, or laying off workers. Such actions are traditional and often necessary responses to meeting increased costs--not just the increased costs of the minimum wage. Unfortunately, these actions ultimately hurt the very workers the minimum wage increase is designed to help.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Some would say raise the prices. That is not always possible in the short run. In the long run there may be some flexibility because this is going to be imposed on everybody and will drive up prices. Of course, when it drives up prices, it kind of eliminates the benefit of the increase in the minimum wage. In the real world, small employers have to consider these types of options to cope with mandated increases in wages. Small business owners who themselves favor a minimum wage increase nonetheless  recognize that any increase may result in having to make these tough choices.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In a recent front-page Washington Post article, the owner of a discount store in Kansas noted that, while he felt a wage of $7.25 seemed fair, he also noted that his profit margin was thin and that wages are his biggest controllable expense. He said: If wages go up, hours will have to come down. And the question will become: Whose, his stockman who works 6 hours a day and takes care of a wife who is blind and arthritic or should it be another worker who is ill and is on a waiting list for an  organ transplant and needs more hours rather than fewer or yet another employee who is 22 years old and pregnant? These are hard realities that are faced by many small employers and those who work with them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that an article from the Washington Post that came out recently--I congratulate the writer of that article--be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300041" topic="THE WAL-MART FACTOR">
    <paragraph>The author of the article is really a master at showing how all of these things are intertwined. It is very revealing and makes a good case for the increase in the minimum wage. But it does show some of the decisions that will have to be made and how that will affect other people, some of whom will be in a similar situation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In a similar vein, when confronted by higher labor costs, employers will naturally gravitate toward filling positions with their most highly skilled, experienced, and productive workers available. Once again, this phenomenon of replacing low-skilled with high-skilled workers in the face of rising labor costs winds up harming the very workers an increase in the minimum wage seeks to help. The minimum wage positions are very often the entryway into the world of work for those who lack skills and  experience. I can't say that enough. I am hoping the Workforce Investment Act will kind of come out of this whole process, too, and provide some additional training so people with less skills can have more skills and get some of the choice jobs that this country has to offer. But mandated increases in the minimum wage run the risk of closing that entryway to many.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Another option, of course, for employers that has to be considered is automation as an alternative to a paid employee. Does this sound farfetched? Consider how the automated teller machines, the ATMs, have replaced tellers, how the self-checkout lane at many establishments has replaced the clerk, and the drive-through has replaced the waiter, and in toll booths the EZ Pass has replaced the toll collector--not all of them, but a lot of them who use the EZ Pass eliminate toll collectors. We have  seen some charts on how productivity goes up when the minimum wage goes up. Sometimes productivity goes up when machines are instituted in place of people. They can work 24 hours a day, 7 days a week, 365 days a year. We don't pay them any health benefits. We may have a little bit of maintenance done on them. They don't get any vacation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Employees are still necessary. I keep telling people that you can't outsource the fact when your toilet is plugged and you need some help or when your electric switch doesn't work, there are a lot of hands-on things that absolutely require people. But they are figuring out ways to automate a lot of these things. In Gillette, WY, where I am from, we have this huge worker shortage, and as I have said a number of times, I keep encouraging people to go west and find the new frontier and get some  good jobs. But when they are pinched, they come up with some other ways of doing things. The drive-up for our McDonald's is actually handled out of California. When you drive up to the little window and you order your Big Mac, you are actually talking to someone in California who uses the</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Beyond these cost-cutting measures of eliminating benefits, reducing hours, downsizing, laying off employees, reducing low-skill and entry-level employment, and automating, employers may also have to face up to the prospect of increasing the price of their goods and services. Price increases caused by mandated cost increases bring their own catalog of ills. Such increases drive inflation and cause all consumers to ultimately pay the price of these mandates. The irony is that as the cost of these  labor increases is passed to the consumers, it affects everyone, including the minimum wage worker, whose recently increased wages are suddenly devalued by the increased price for goods and services that impact them as well. So on this ladder of success, we have kind of removed the lower rung of it. So it is a little bigger step to get up there, and some of them aren't going to be able to make the step because of some of the ways that it has to be adjusted.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the same Washington Post article I mentioned earlier, another small employer who owns two convenience stores noted that he simply does not have the option of cutting hours to meet his increased payroll burden. Instead, he noted: I am going to have to raise my prices. He indicated if he had the chance to talk with Speaker Pelosi about the minimum wage, he would ask one question, and that is: Where does she think the money will come from? Of course, it can be argued that his customers,  if he raises the price for the candy bar or the cup of coffee, will go somewhere where it is cheaper, and that is a good possibility. That means that in order to maintain  the business, if he is going to raise those prices, he has to have employees who give</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe almost all of us recognize these economic realities and that none of us want them to come about. It is for those precise reasons that the substitute amendment contains provisions designed to enable our smallest employers to meet the obligations imposed by a minimum wage increase without resorting to the difficult personnel choices, the consumer price increases or all of the other things I mentioned.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Yesterday, I spoke briefly about the fact that in legislating, it is often important to find a third way. In this instance, the third way is one that will provide an increase in the minimum wage but also provide relief to the most affected small businesses so that they don't experience employee dislocation, a reduction in employment opportunities for low-skilled and entry-level workers or an increase in consumer prices that takes away the real value of any wage increase.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The third way is represented by the real value of any  wage increase. The third way is represented by the substitute amendment that was the product of extensive bipartisan support, Democrats and Republicans working together, acknowledging the fact that mandated cost increases can have negative economic effects. So together we developed a means of addressing those concerns in the form of a bipartisan substitute amendment. I can't emphasize enough how pleased I am with the cooperation I saw as people worked out different alternatives. There were certainly  a wide variety of them that were done and I think with some concentration particularly on how they would affect small business. I would reiterate the bipartisan support of that small business tax incentive package. There are key Democratic leaders who have acknowledged the need for the package to offset any wage increase in order to not disenfranchise the employers and their workers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I hope we won't make this partisan now. As I mentioned yesterday, the Senator from Massachusetts, Mr. Kennedy, and I have gone head to head on raising the minimum wage three times in the past several years. Each time, the votes were set up for each side to fail. This time around, we worked to come up with a third way in order to get the job done. I hope that all efforts to try and unravel this third way that will most likely result in a minimum wage increase isn't abandoned for the  sake of making partisan messages. I urge my colleagues to continue to support the small business incentive package as a much-needed offset to the increased Federal wage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think this is a tremendous opportunity for us to do the right thing in all aspects, and I hope there will be good bipartisan support. I understand the desire to have a clean minimum wage, but that is what we have been going through for a couple of years now, and we are finally talking bipartisan. I think that was something that came out of the elections. I am pleased to see it is operating, and we will see how long it continues. I hope it continues through the entire session.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that the Sessions amendment No. 108 be modified with the changes at the desk, and I urge its adoption, as modified.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered. The amendment is so modified.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I move to reconsider the vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>I move to lay that motion on the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The motion to lay on the table was agreed to.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that the Sessions amendment No. 107 be withdrawn.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, in about 6 or 7 minutes, we will be having a vote, and then I would expect the President's State of the Union Address will place demands on the Members, so that will mean we will probably move over until tomorrow. As I mentioned earlier, I hope our colleagues will vote in support of the Sessions amendment for the reasons I have outlined.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think an important message ought to go out to families and to workers all over this country and many others who have worked long and hard to try and urge the Senate of the United States to move on the minimum wage issue and raise the minimum wage, as it has been stuck for the last 10 years at $5.15. There are people who have knocked on doors, there are people who have stuffed envelopes and there are people who have phoned into radio stations and people who have written letters to the editors  and people who have met with Members of Congress all over this country. People have marched, attended parades, and demonstrated. They have spoken out for fairness and justice for workers. Tomorrow we will have a real opportunity to respond to that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am very hopeful, as a result of the votes tomorrow, we will be well on the way toward this body supporting action that has taken place in the House of Representatives and a vote for an increase in the minimum wage. There will be those who will go to bed tonight who have been working long and hard for $5.15 an hour. They may work one job, and many of them, 300,000 Americans, work two full-time jobs. They probably keep saying a prayer, and they are keeping their fingers crossed that in the Senate,  tomorrow will provide at least some additional breath of hope to them and to their families, to their loved ones, that can make a difference in terms of their lives and what a difference this can make.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As we have mentioned, it may be more than a year's worth of groceries to some families or it may be the tuition for a community college. It could be 20 months of child care for some workers. It could be heating and electric bills for 19 months, all measured in a few months, for things that so many of us, certainly in this body, take for granted. But out there in so many communities across the country, people fight and struggle to try and achieve those goals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So this is a very important vote. We have important votes and some not so important votes in this body, but tomorrow will be one of great importance and consequence. I think it will be a defining issue about what kind of society we are; what is the measure of our decency and the measure of our humanity in this body. So I am very hopeful as to the outcome, and we urge our colleagues to give us their support. We will have an opportunity to make comments tomorrow morning briefly before we vote on  these measures. We thank all of our Members for all of their cooperation and their help to Senator Enzi and myself over the last several days. So with that I would indicate to our colleagues that in approximately 2 minutes or so we will begin the vote on the Sessions amendment, an amendment which both I and Senator Enzi support.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam President, I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300041" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield back, with the consent of both sides, the 2 minutes that was to be available on both sides. I yield back that time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300041" topic="">
    <paragraph>I request the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there a sufficient second?</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will call the roll.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>I announce that the Senator from Delaware (Mr. BIDEN) and the Senator from South Dakota (Mr. JOHNSON) are necessarily absent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I further announce that, if present and voting, the Senator from Delaware (Mr. BIDEN) would vote "yea."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Are there any other Senators in the Chamber desiring to vote?</chair>
  <narrative>The result was announced--yeas 98, nays 0, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>I move to reconsider the vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="">
    <paragraph>I move to lay that motion on the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The motion to lay on the table was agreed to.</narrative>
</record>
