<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1201626002" ordinal="72" title="HONORING THE UNITED STATES COAST GUARD">
  <narrative>HONORING THE UNITED STATES COAST GUARD -- (Senate - January 29, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="456">S456</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to <bill type="sr" number="429">S. Res. 429</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="429">S. Res. 429</bill>) honoring the brave men and women of the United States Coast Guard whose tireless work, dedication, and commitment to protecting the United States have led to the confiscation of over 350,000 pounds of cocaine at sea during 2007.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I watch The Weather Channel sometimes, and they have these pieces on what the Coast Guard does in violent seas. The Chair, being from Rhode Island, probably doesn't appreciate it as much as I do, being from the desert, but the Coast Guard rides some rough seas. So they are entitled to this resolution tonight.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motions to reconsider be laid on the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="429">S. Res. 429</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="429">S. Res. 429</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas the estimated import value of the 350,000 pounds of cocaine confiscated by the United States Coast Guard in 2007 is more than $4,700,000,000, or nearly  1/2  of the Coast Guard's annual budget;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Coast Guard's at-sea drug interdictions are making a difference in the lives of United States citizens, as evidenced by the reduced supply of cocaine in more than 35 major cities throughout the United States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas keeping illegal drugs from reaching our shores, where they undermine American values and threaten families, schools, and communities, continues to be an important national priority;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, through robust interagency teamwork, collaboration with international partners, and ever more effective tools and tactics, the Coast Guard has removed more than 2,000,000 pounds of cocaine during the past 10 years and will continue to tighten the web of detection and interdiction at sea; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the men and women of the Coast Guard who, while away from family and hundreds of miles from our shores, execute this dangerous mission, as well as other vital maritime safety, security, and environmental protection missions, with quiet dedication and without need of public recognition, continue to display selfless service in protecting the Nation and the American people: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) honors the United States Coast Guard, with its proud 217-year legacy of maritime law enforcement and border protection, along with the brave men and women whose efforts clearly demonstrate the honor, respect, and devotion to duty that ensure the parents of the United States can sleep soundly knowing the Coast Guard is on patrol; and</chair>
  <chair> (2) recognizes the tireless work, dedication, and commitment that have allowed the Coast Guard to confiscate over 350,000 pounds of cocaine at sea in 2007.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
