<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1172595604" ordinal="27" title="RETIREMENT OF RICK SHAPIRO">
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today I wish to honor Rick Shapiro, who recently retired as executive director of the Congressional Management Foundation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I became acquainted with Rick early in my Senate career, when I asked Rick to help me and my staff strengthen the management of my Senate office. That began a very useful relationship with Rick and CMF.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under his leadership, CMF grew in size, scope, and impact. Rick has made CMF an integral part of the early organization of nearly every new House and Senate office, through CMF's practical publications and its role in new office orientations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For many offices like mine, Rick used his skills in organizational management to help members and their senior staff improve how they run their offices and serve their constituents. His confidential counsel and evaluation, and that of a strong staff that he recruited and supported, has allowed many Senators and Members of Congress to focus on their jobs as legislators, with the confidence that their offices would be well run.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rick also used his extensive knowledge of strategic planning to ensure offices have a strategic vision and the means to deliver on that vision. He and his staff have facilitated hundreds of staff retreats, helping House and Senate offices produce ambitious, but realistic, plans for their work.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rick was the driving force behind CMF's research into cutting edge topics. For example, CMF's research and guidance on the Internet and electronic communications has been the single most important force in bringing many  offices into the 21st century in their use of new technology.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Before joining CMF, Rick worked in the U.S. House of Representatives, first as a staff investigator and later as the staff director of two House committees. He brought his significant knowledge of the workings of the Congress to CMF and it progressed under his leadership.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>All of us who know him and have benefited from his work wish him well, and look with interest to his next project.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
