<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1201021201" ordinal="37" title="FURTHER CHANGES TO S. CON. RES. 21">
  <narrative>FURTHER CHANGES TO <bill type="sc" number="21">S. CON. RES. 21</bill> -- (Senate - January 22, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="84">S84</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300026" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, pursuant to section 302 of <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>, I filed revisions to <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>, the 2008 budget resolution. Those revisions were made for legislation that improved certain services for and benefits to wounded or disabled military personnel and retirees, veterans, and their survivors and dependents.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress cleared the conference report accompanying <bill type="h" number="1585">H.R. 1585</bill>, the National Defense Authorization Act for fiscal year 2008, on December 14, 2007. Unfortunately, <bill type="h" number="1585">H.R. 1585</bill> was not signed into law by the President. Consequently, I am further revising the 2008 budget resolution and reversing the adjustments previously made pursuant to section 302 to the aggregates and the allocation provided to the Senate Armed Services Committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, last week the House passed <bill type="h" number="4986">H.R. 4986</bill>, a bill that is substantially similar to <bill type="h" number="1585">H.R. 1585</bill> and that also meets the conditions of the reserve fund for veterans and wounded servicemembers. Consequently, for the information of my colleagues, I will be further revising the 2008 budget resolution pursuant to section 302 of <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill> for Senate consideration of <bill type="h" number="4986">H.R. 4986</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the following revisions to <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill> be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
</record>
