<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1217260803" ordinal="6" title="UNANIMOUS-CONSENT REQUEST--S. 3268">
  <narrative>UNANIMOUS-CONSENT REQUEST--S. 3268 -- (Senate - July 28, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="7541">S7541</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that when the Senate considers <bill type="s" number="3268">S. 3268</bill>, the bill be considered in the following manner: there be 3 hours of general debate on the bill, equally divided and controlled between the leaders or their designees; that the only first-degree amendments in order be those listed in this agreement and that second-degree amendments which are relevant to the first degree to which offered be in order; provided further that if the managers and leaders acting  jointly determine that a side-by-side amendment strategy is the appropriate manner to address the amendments in order, then in lieu of a second degree a side-by-side amendment would be in order, with the majority side getting the first vote if that were the case; that debate time on any amendment, first or second degree, in this agreement be limited to 2 hours equally divided and controlled in the usual form; that each amendment, first and second-degree, be subject to an affirmative 60-vote threshold; that if it achieves that threshold, then it be agreed to and the motion to</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, before the distinguished Republican leader decides what to do on this, basically this is on the energy package to set this up where there would be, as indicated here, four amendments on each side. Ours could either be second degrees or, if we wanted a side by side, we could do that. There would be, as has been the standard around here on issues such as this, a 60-vote threshold. This would take care of issues that we understand are important to the minority: offshore drilling,  oil shale exploration, nuclear energy, and the omnibus package that they put together.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <chair>The Republican leader is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300072" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, reserving the right to object, let me say to my good friend, the majority leader, I think we are getting very close to being able to reach an agreement to go forward. This is a significant step in the direction I had hoped we might take.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask my good friend, I have a leadership meeting in an hour or so. I wish to consult with my leadership team about the proposal he has offered. But I think----</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I withdraw the consent request and will renew it at a later time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300072" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, let me say, I am very encouraged by this  development. I thank my good friend for his offer, and I should be able to get back to him within a couple of hours or less, after having a chance to talk about it  with my team. I thank him very much.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, the other consent I was going to ask is consent that <bill type="s" number="3268">S. 3268</bill>--that is the Energy bill that is before us now, the speculation bill--remain the pending business, notwithstanding the adoption of a motion to proceed to a nonprivileged item; namely, it would be the Coburn package. The reason that is important is, if we do that now--we have a vote at 4 o'clock or 4:20, whatever the case might be--I wanted to make sure that one of the arguments used against that going forward,  which is that energy would not remain as the pending business, that this agreement would take care of that. So if people want to object to proceeding on the matter we now have before us, that we are going to be voting on in a short period of time, if they want to use the excuse it is going to take us off energy, this consent agreement would not do that.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300072" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, reserving the right to object, as I understand it, this consent, if entered, would have the effect of moving us off of energy, and it is my view, and I think close to the unanimous view of my conference, that we ought to stay on this energy speculation bill, as it might be amended, and proceed to amendments such as we have in good faith discussed here a few moments ago. So I at this time would object to this.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I say to my friend, this does not take us off energy. But anyway, the objection has been heard. So I thank the Chair.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The objection is heard.</chair>
</record>
