<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1201798802" ordinal="33" title="ANNUAL REPORT FOR 2007--SELECT COMMITTEE ON ETHICS">
  <narrative>ANNUAL REPORT FOR 2007--SELECT COMMITTEE ON ETHICS -- (Senate - January 31, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="538">S538</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent, for myself as chairman of the Select Committee on Ethics and for Senator Cornyn as vice chairman of the committee, that the following "Annual Report for 2007--Select Committee on Ethics" be printing in the Record. The committee issues this report today as required by the Honest Leadership and Open Government Act of 2007.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>Annual Report for 2007--Select Committee on Ethics</narrative>
  <narrative>The Honest Leadership and Open Government Act of 2007 (the "Act") calls for the Select Committee on Ethics of the United States Senate to issue an annual report no later than January 31 of each year providing information in certain categories describing its activities for the preceding year. Reported below is the information describing the Committee's activities in 2007 in the categories set forth in the Act:</narrative>
  <narrative>(1) The number of alleged violations of Senate rules received from any source [in 2007], including the number raised by a Senator or staff of the Committee: 95. (This figure does not include 16 alleged violations from the previous year carried into 2007.)</narrative>
  <narrative>(2) The number of alleged violations that were dismissed--</narrative>
  <narrative>(A) For lack of subject matter jurisdiction or in which, even if the allegations in the complaint are true, no violation of Senate rules would exist: 71. (This figure includes 5 matters originating in the previous year.)</narrative>
  <narrative>(B) Because they failed to provide sufficient facts as to any material violation of the Senate rules beyond mere allegation or assertion": 15. (This figure includes 2 matters originating in the previous year.)</narrative>
  <narrative>(3) The number of alleged violations in which the Committee staff conducted a preliminary inquiry: 16. (This figure includes 9 matters from the previous year carried into 2007 and includes 5 inquiries continuing into 2008.)</narrative>
  <narrative>(4) The number of alleged violations that resulted in an adjudicatory review: 0.</narrative>
  <narrative>(5) The number of alleged violations that the Committee dismissed for lack of substantial merit: 11. (This figure includes 7 matters from the previous year carried into 2007.)</narrative>
  <narrative>(6) The number of private letters of admonition or public letters of admonition issued: 0.</narrative>
  <narrative>(7) The number of matters resulting in a disciplinary sanction: 0.</narrative>
  <narrative>(8) Any other information deemed by the Committee to be appropriate to describe its activities in the previous year:</narrative>
  <narrative>In 2007, the Committee, through its staff, conducted 121 ethics educational briefings and seminars, including 72 sessions for individual Member or Committee offices and 37 sessions for a general Senate audience.</narrative>
  <narrative>In 2007, Committee staff handled over 16,000 telephone inquiries for ethics advice and guidance.</narrative>
  <narrative>In 2007, the Committee wrote over 1,000 ethics advisory letters and responses, including over 700 advisories concerning gifts or travel.</narrative>
  <narrative>The Committee issued over 3,500 letters concerning financial disclosure filings by Senators, Senate staff and Senate candidates, including over 1,200 letters concerning required amendments to these disclosure filings.</narrative>
</record>
