<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1176220802" ordinal="47" title="NOTICES OF HEARINGS/MEETINGS">
  <speaking speaker="300037" topic="COMMITTEE ON INDIAN AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to announce that the Committee on Indian Affairs will meet on Thursday, April 12, 2007, at 9:30 a.m. in Room 485 of the Russell Senate Office Building to conduct a business meeting to consider pending legislation, to be followed immediately by an oversight hearing on Tribal Colleges and Universities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Those wishing additional information may contact the Indian Affairs Committee at 224-2251.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND NATURAL RESOURCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to announce for the information of the Senate and the public  that a hearing has been scheduled before the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The hearing will be held on Monday, April 16, 2007, at 2:30 p.m., in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the hearing is to receive testimony on <bill type="s" number="731">S. 731</bill>, the National Carbon Dioxide Storage Capacity Assessment Act of 2007 and <bill type="s" number="962">S. 962</bill>, the Department of Energy Carbon Capture and Storage Research, Development, and Demonstration Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Due to the limited available for the hearing, witnesses may testify by invitation only. However, those wishing to submit written testimony for the hearing record should send it to the Committee on Energy and Natural &#xD0;Resources, U.S. Senate, Washing-&#xD0;ton, DC 20510-6150, or by e-mail to &#xD0;Gina Xweinstock@energy.senate.gov.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For further information, please contact Allyson Anderson or Gina Weinstock.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, April 10, 2007, at 2:30 p.m., in Room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The hearing entitled "Voice over Internet Protocol (VoIP) and the Future of 911 Services," will examine current issues and future challenges related to the provision of enhanced 911 (E911) services, and <bill type="s" number="428">S. 428</bill>, the "IP-Enabled Voice Communications and Public Safety Act of 2007."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
