<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1195146001" ordinal="62" title="EXECUTIVE REPORTS OF COMMITTEES">
  <narrative>EXECUTIVE REPORTS OF COMMITTEES -- (Senate - November 15, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="14487">S14487</bill>]</narrative>
  <narrative>The following executive reports of nominations were submitted:</narrative>
  <narrative>By Mr. LEVIN for the Committee on Armed Services.</narrative>
  <narrative>*Douglas A. Brook, of California, to be an Assistant Secretary of the Navy.</narrative>
  <narrative>*John J. Young, Jr., of Virginia, to be Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition, Technology, and Logistics.</narrative>
  <narrative>*Robert L. Smolen, of Pennsylvania, to be Deputy Administrator for Defense Programs, National Nuclear Security Administration.</narrative>
  <narrative>Air Force nomination of Lt. Gen. Carrol H. Chandler, 9115, to be General.</narrative>
  <narrative>Army nomination of Col. Donald L. Rutherford, 5430, to be Brigadier General.</narrative>
  <narrative>Army nominations beginning with Colonel Joseph Caravalho, Jr. and ending with Colonel Keith W. Gallagher, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record on October 18, 2007.</narrative>
  <narrative>Army nomination of Lt. Gen. Thomas F. Metz, 5686, to be Lieutenant General.</narrative>
  <narrative>Army nomination of Maj. Gen. Jeffrey A. Sorenson, 3510, to be Lieutenant General.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, for the Committee on Armed Services I report favorably the following nomination lists which were printed in the RECORDS on the dates indicated, and ask unanimous consent, to save the expense of reprinting on the Executive Calendar that these nominations lie at the Secretary's desk for the information of Senators.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>Air Force nomination of Michael V. Siebert, 6633, to be Captain.</chair>
  <chair>Air Force nominations beginning with Brian D. O'neil and ending with Frank R. Vidal, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record on November 1, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>Army nomination of Anthony Barber, 5447, to be Colonel.</chair>
  <chair>Army nomination of Tim C. Lawson, 5165, to be Colonel.</chair>
  <chair>Army nomination of Richard D. Fox II, 3613, to be Colonel.</chair>
  <chair>Army nomination of John G. Goulet, 3964, to be Colonel.</chair>
  <chair>Army nomination of David L. Patten, 9398, to be Colonel.</chair>
  <chair>Army nominations beginning with Mark J. Benedict and ending with Gustav D. Waterhouse, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record on November 1, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>Marine Corps nomination of Melvin L. Chattman, 5718, to be Lieutenant Colonel.</chair>
  <chair>Marine Corps nominations beginning with Dana R. Brown and ending with Mark R. Reid, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record on November 1, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>Navy nominations beginning with Julian D. Arellano and ending with Jared W. Wyrick, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record on November 1, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>By Mr. LEAHY for the Committee on the Judiciary.</chair>
  <chair>Reed Charles O'Connor, of Texas, to be United States District Judge for the Northern District of Texas.</chair>
  <chair>Amul R. Thapar, of Kentucky, to be United States District Judge for the Eastern District of Kentucky.</chair>
  <chair>*Nomination was reported with recommendation that it be confirmed subject to the nominee's commitment to respond to requests to appear and testify before any duly constituted committee of the Senate.</chair>
  <narrative>(Nominations without an asterisk were reported with the recommendation that they be confirmed.)</narrative>
</record>
