<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1189440002" ordinal="34" title="TRIBUTE TO PETER A. MAYER ADVERTISING, INC.">
  <narrative>TRIBUTE TO PETER A. MAYER ADVERTISING, INC. -- (Senate - September 10, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="11322">S11322</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300063" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to take a moment to pay tribute to Peter A. Mayer Advertising, Inc., which on Friday celebrated its 40th anniversary.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This firm represents that Louisiana really is "open for business" following the devastating 2005 storms, Katrina and Rita. Not only is this agency profitable and strong, but part of its business practice is to contribute to our great city and region in the aftermath of the storms that completely destroyed 18,000 businesses in Louisiana alone.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When Katrina hit, the Agency evacuated to Baton Rouge and Monroe and provided housing and accommodations for employees and their families. Soon the firm was up and running again in New Orleans and promoting the city's recovery. For instance, it was the Peter A. Mayer agency that developed the "Come fall in love all over again" television and print tourism campaign. Tourism is our State's second largest industry, and the agency's help getting the word out that we are ready for tourists was invaluable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Not only did the agency help the city and region, but it looked inward to create a support network for its own employees whose common thread was recovering from Katrina. The agency created a Web site, LivesConnected.com, where employees, though oral history, told their Katrina stories.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Peter Mayer founded the firm in 1967 with just three employees and $200,000 in billing. It has become one of the largest advertising, public relations and marketing agencies in the South  and an economic anchor in New Orleans, with a staff of 125 and annual billings of more than $75 million. The news media has recognized the agency's famed corporate culture, with New Orleans City Business and Gambit Weekly each naming it one of the top places to work  in New Orleans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In celebration of its 40th anniversary and in an effort to help beautify our city, the agency last week began planting 40 trees in City Park to replace those lost in Katrina. On Friday evening, the agency celebrated its history with all past and present employees at the Audubon Tea Room. I thank the Senate for recognizing this outstanding agency for its commitment to excellence and public service.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
