<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1210262403" ordinal="23" title="THE MATTHEW SHEPARD ACT OF 2007">
  <narrative>THE MATTHEW SHEPARD ACT OF 2007 -- (Senate - May 08, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="3972">S3972</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300090" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today to speak about the need for hate crimes legislation. Each Congress, Senator Kennedy and I introduce hate crimes legislation that would strengthen and add new categories to current hate crimes law, sending a signal that violence of any kind is unacceptable in our society. Likewise, each Congress I have come to the floor to highlight a separate violent crime that has occurred in our country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On the night of April 4, 2008, a 17-year-old Black man was traveling by bus from Wilmington, DE, to New Castle, DE, when three White men engaged him in a physical altercation. David and Lloyd Walker, 27 and 23 years old respectively, were identified by witnesses and arrested, but their accomplice, known only as "Ritchie," is still at large. According to police, the three men began to argue with the young man when he complained that they were bumping into him. When the 17-year-old man got off  the bus, the three men followed and attacked him, yelling racial slurs and threatening to kill him. Police say David Walker stabbed the teen five times in the back, puncturing one of his lungs and inflicting more stab wounds on his forearm.  The three men fled the scene immediately after the stabbing. Both David and Lloyd Walker were charged with first-degree assault, possession of a deadly weapon during a felony, felony hate crime, and conspiracy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe that the Government's first duty is to defend its citizens, to defend them against the harms that come out of hate. Federal laws intended to protect individuals from heinous and violent crimes motivated by hate are woefully inadequate. This legislation would better equip the Government to fulfill its most important obligation by providing the resources necessary to adequately investigate and prosecute violent crimes. I believe that by passing this legislation and changing current law,  we can change hearts and minds as well.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
