<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1181145609" ordinal="40" title="SENATE CONCURRENT RESOLUTION 36--SUPPORTING THE GOALS AND IDEALS OF NATIONAL TEEN DRIVER SAFETY WEEK">
  <speaking speaker="412246" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today to introduce, along with my colleagues, Senators SPECTER, DURBIN and OBAMA, a Senate concurrent resolution that will recognize a National Teen Driver Safety Week during the third week of October. This resolution will focus increased public attention and positive action upon the No. 1 cause of death of adolescents in our country--motor vehicle crashes. The fatality rate for drivers ages 16 to 19 is approximately four times that of drivers ages  25 to 69. In 2005, approximately 7,500 of our Nation's teenagers were involved as drivers in fatal car crashes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>According to data from the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, 13 of 67 counties in Pennsylvania had six deaths or more in 2005 as a result of traffic accidents involving teens. In Lackawanna County alone, where I reside, there were 13 accidents among drivers ages 19 and under that resulted in death or an incapacitating injury.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is essential that we focus a heightened degree of public attention and awareness upon this tragic--and preventable--crisis. A majority of teen driver crashes are due to driver error and speeding. We must provide more numerous and effective interventions that will help reduce accidents involving teen drivers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We all know that learning to drive is an important rite of social passage and independence for teenagers. The Children's Hospital of Philadelphia, in partnership with the State Farm Insurance Companies, is conducting ongoing research on teen drivers and recently completed the National Young Driver Survey, questioning thousands of students across the country. The survey was designed to be representative of the 10.6 million public high school students in the United States. Thanks to this new data,  we know more about what teens themselves think about driving and how we can more effectively instill safe driving habits.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to mention three key findings from this survey:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>1. The critical role of parents. As parents, we are often our children's first driving teachers. But our role does not end when our children get their licenses. Parents play a major role in setting and enforcing safe driving behavior, supervising their teen drivers, and ensuring that teens assume responsibility for driving, including financial responsibility.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>2. The prevalence of risky distractions. With 80 percent of teen drivers reporting that they own cell phones, these technological advances pose a serious threat to our children's safety while driving. Nearly all--93 percent of--teens in the survey report that they witness distractions such as cell phone calls, loud music, other teens in the car, and their own emotions. Nearly half of all teens say they have witnessed road rage in fellow teen drivers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>3. The prevalence of risky driving behaviors. While 50 percent of teens report seeing other teens drive drunk, nearly three fourths of teens report seeing their peers drive while fatigued. Half of teens report driving 10 miles over the speed limit at least some of the time. Only 65 percent of teens say they consistently use seat belts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This superb research from Children's Hospital will continue to provide us greater insight and strategies for reaching our young people.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our resolution will designate the third week in October, when schools are back in session, as a time for intensive outreach and programming to encourage teens to drive more safely--to minimize risky driving conditions, to manage peer-to-peer interactions around driving, and to learn the skills they need to detect and react to hazards more appropriately.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a member of the Senate, and as a father, I want to do everything in my power to ensure our children are safe on the road. Losing even one child to a preventable death is a tragedy beyond words. I urge my colleagues to support this resolution recognizing a National Teen Driver Safety Week.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
