<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1193846401" ordinal="43" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <narrative>AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET -- (Senate - October 31, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="13644">S13644</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300037" topic="AD HOC SUBCOMMITTEE ON DISASTER RECOVERY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Ad Hoc Subcommittee on Disaster Recovery of the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, October 31, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. in order to conduct a hearing entitled, "Post-Catastrophe Crisis: Addressing the Dramatic Need and Scant Availability of Mental Health Care in the Gulf Coast."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300037" topic="COMMITTEE ON BANKING, HOUSING, AND URBAN AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on October 31, 2007, at 2:30 p.m., in order to conduct a hearing entitled "Climate Disclosure: Measuring Financial Risks and Opportunties."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300037" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENVIRONMENT AND PUBLIC WORKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Environment and Public Works be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, October 31, 2007 at 10 a.m. in room 406 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building, in order to conduct a hearing entitled, "Examination of the Licensing Process for the Yucca Mountain Repository."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300037" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, October 31, 2007, at 11 a.m. in order to hold a business meeting.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300037" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet, during the session of the Senate, in order to conduct a hearing entitled "FISA Amendments: How to Protect America's Security and Privacy and Preserve the Rule of Law and Government Accountability" on Wednesday, October 31, 2007. The hearing will commence at 10 a.m. in room 226 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Panel I: Kenneth L. Wainstein, Assistant Attorney General, National Security Division, U.S. Department of Justice.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Panel II: Edward Black, President and CEO, Computer &amp; Communications Industry Association, Washington, DC; Patrick F. Philbin, Partner, Kirkland &amp; Ellis, Washington, DC; Morton H. Halperin, Director of U.S. Advocacy, Open Society Institute, Washington, DC.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300037" topic="COMMITTEE ON VETERANS' AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent for the Committee on Veterans' Affairs to be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, October 31, 2007, in order to conduct a hearing on the Uniformed Services Employment and Reemployment Rights Act. The Committee will meet in room SD-562 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building, at 9:30 a.m.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
