<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1185422400" ordinal="27" title="BUDGET SCOREKEEPING REPORT">
  <narrative>BUDGET SCOREKEEPING REPORT -- (Senate - July 26, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="10133">S10133</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300026" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise to submit to the Senate the second set of budget scorekeeping reports for the 2008 budget resolution. The reports, which cover fiscal years 2007 and 2008, were prepared by the Congressional Budget Office pursuant to section 308(b) and in aid of section 311 of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974, as amended.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The reports show the effects of congressional action through July 24, 2007, and includes legislation that was enacted and or cleared for the President's signature since I filed my first report last month. The new legislation includes: Public Law 110-42, an act to extend the authorities of the Andean Trade Preference Act until February 29, 2008; Public Law 110-48, a bill to provide for the extension of transitional medical assistance, TMA, and the abstinence education program through the end of  fiscal year 2007, and for other purposes; and <bill type="hj" number="44">H.J. Res. 44</bill>; pending Presidential action, a joint resolution approving the renewal of import restrictions contained in the Burmese Freedom and Democracy Act of 2003, and for other purposes. The estimates of budget authority, outlays, and revenues used in the reports are consistent with the technical and economic assumptions of S. Con Res. 21, the 2008 budget resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For 2007, the estimates show that current level spending equals the budget resolution for both budget authority and outlays while current level revenues exceed the budget resolution by $4.2 billion. For 2008, the estimates show that current level spending is below the budget resolution by $928.1 billion for budget authority and $586.7 billion for outlays while current level revenues exceed the budget resolution level by $34.6 billion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the letters and accompanying tables from CBO be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows.</narrative>
  <narrative>U.S. CONGRESS,</narrative>
  <narrative>CONGRESSIONAL BUDGET OFFICE,</narrative>
  <narrative>Washington, DC, July 26, 2007.</narrative>
  <narrative>DEAR MR. CHAIRMAN: The enclosed report shows the effects of Congressional action on the fiscal year 2007 budget and is current through July 24, 2007. This report is submitted under section 308(b) and in aid of section 311 of the Congressional Budget Act, as amended.</narrative>
  <narrative>The estimates of budget authority, outlays, and revenues are consistent with the technical and economic assumptions of <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>, the Concurrent Resolution on the Budget for Fiscal Year 2008, as approved by the Senate and the House of Representatives.</narrative>
  <narrative>Pursuant to section 204(a) of <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>, provisions designated as emergency requirements are exempt from enforcement of the budget resolution. As a result, the enclosed current level report excludes these amounts (see footnote 1 of Table 2 of the report).</narrative>
  <narrative>Since my last letter, dated June 27, 2007, the Congress has cleared and the President has signed:</narrative>
  <narrative>An act to extend the authorities of the Andean Trade Preference Act until February 29, 2008 (Public Law 110-42); and</narrative>
  <narrative>A bill to provide for the extension of Transitional Medical Assistance (TMA) and the Abstinence Education Program through the end of the fiscal year 2007, and for other purposes (Public Law 110-48).</narrative>
  <narrative>The effects of those actions are detailed on Table 2.</narrative>
  <narrative>Sincerely,</narrative>
  <narrative>Robert A. Sunshine,</narrative>
  <narrative>U.S. CONGRESS,</narrative>
  <narrative>CONGRESSIONAL BUDGET OFFICE,</narrative>
  <narrative>Washington, DC, July 26, 2007.</narrative>
  <narrative>DEAR MR. CHAIRMAN: The enclosed report shows the effects of Congressional action on the fiscal year 2008 budget and is current through July 24, 2007. This report is submitted under section 308(b) and in aid of section 311 of the Congressional Budget Act, as amended.</narrative>
  <narrative>The estimates of budget authority, outlays, and revenues are consistent with the technical and economic assumptions of <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>, the Concurrent Resolution on the Budget for Fiscal Year 2008, as approved by the Senate and the House of Representatives.</narrative>
  <narrative>Pursuant to section 204(a) of <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>, provisions designated as emergency requirements are exempt from enforcement of the budget resolution. As a result, the enclosed current level report excludes these amounts (see footnote 1 of Table 2 of the report).</narrative>
  <narrative>Since my last letter, dated June 27, 2007, the Congress has cleared and the President has signed:</narrative>
  <narrative>An act to extend the authorities of the Andean Trade Preference Act until February 29, 2008 (Public Law 110-42); and</narrative>
  <narrative>A bill to provide for the extension of Transitional Medical Assistance (TMA) and the Abstinence Education Program through the end of the fiscal year 2007, and for other purposes (Public Law 110-48).</narrative>
  <narrative>In addition, the Congress has cleared for the President's signature a joint resolution approving the renewal of import restrictions contained in the Burmese Freedom and Democracy Act of 2003, and for other purposes (<bill type="hj" number="44">H.J. Res. 44</bill>).</narrative>
  <narrative>The effects of those actions are detailed on Table 2.</narrative>
  <narrative>Sincerely,</narrative>
  <narrative>Peter R. Orszag,</narrative>
  <narrative>&lt;pre&gt;--&lt;/pre&gt;</narrative>
</record>
