<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1206979203" ordinal="42" title="NOTICES OF HEARINGS">
  <narrative>NOTICES OF HEARINGS -- (Senate - March 31, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="2237">S2237</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND NATURAL RESOURCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to announce for the information of the Senate and the public that a hearing has been scheduled before the Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</paragraph>
    <paragraph> The hearing will be held on Tuesday, April 15, 2008, at 10 a.m. in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph> The purpose of this hearing is to consider <bill type="s" number="2438">S. 2438</bill>, a bill to repeal certain provisions of the Federal Lands Recreation Enhancement Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph> Because of the limited time available for the hearing, witnesses may testify by invitation only. However, those wishing to submit written testimony for the hearing record should send it to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, United States Senate, Washington, DC 20510-6150, or by e-mail to rachel</paragraph>
    <paragraph> For further information, please contact Rachel Pasternack at (202) 224-0883 or David Brooks at 202-224-9863.</paragraph>
    <paragraph> SUBCOMMITTEE ON WATER AND POWER</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to announce for the information of the Senate and the public that a hearing has been scheduled before the Subcommittee on Water and Power of the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. The hearing will be held on April 8, 2008, at 2:30 p.m. in room 366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building in Washington, DC.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the hearing is to receive testimony on the following bills: <bill type="s" number="2259">S. 2259</bill>/H.R. 813, to amend the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to participate in the Prado Basin Natural Treatment System Project, to authorize the Secretary to participate in the Lower Chino Dairy Area desalination demonstration and reclamation project, and for other purposes; <bill type="h" number="31">H.R. 31</bill>, to amend the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and  Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to participate in the Elsinore Valley Municipal Water District Wildomar Service Area Recycled Water Distribution Facilities and Alberhill Wastewater Treatment and Reclamation Facility Projects; <bill type="h" number="716">H.R. 716</bill>, to amend the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to participate in the Santa Rosa Urban Water Reuse Plan; <bill type="h" number="786">H.R. 786</bill>, to amend the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to participate in the Los Angeles County Water Supply Augmentation Demonstration Project, and for other purposes; <bill type="h" number="1140">H.R. 1140</bill>, to authorize the Secretary, in cooperation with the City of San Juan Capistrano, California, to participate in the design, planning, and construction of an advanced water treatment plant facility and recycled water system, and for other purposes; <bill type="h" number="1503">H.R. 1503</bill>, to amend the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of the limited time available for the hearing, witnesses may testify by invitation only. However, those wishing to submit written testimony for the hearing record should send it to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, United States Senate, Washington, DC 20510-6150, or by email to Gina</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For further information, please contact Michael Connor at (202) 224-5479 or Gina Weinstock at (202) 224-5684.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
