<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1184644800" ordinal="56" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <narrative>AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET -- (Senate - July 17, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="9495">S9495</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412249" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, July 17, 2007, at 10 a.m. room 253 ofthe Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The hearing will focus on creative solutions to improve air service to small and rural communities.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412249" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENVIRONMENT AND PUBLIC WORKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Environment and Public Works be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, July 17, 2007 at 10 a.m. Room 406 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building for a hearing to consider pending nominations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Robert Lance Boldrey, nominated to be a Member of the Board of Trustees, Morris K. Udall Scholarship and Excellence in National Environmental Policy Foundation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Kristine L. Svinicki, nominated to be a Member of the Nuclear Regulatory Commission.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Robert Lyle Laverty, nominated to be the Assistant Secretary for Fish, Wildlife, and Parks, Department of the Interior.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The Mr. WEBB. Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, July 17, 2007, at 10 a.m. to hold a hearing on democracy in Africa.</chair>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, July 17, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. to hold a hearing on intellectual property and tax treaties.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412249" topic="COMMITTEE ON HOMELAND SECURITY AND GOVERNMENTAL AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs be authorized to meet on Tuesday, July 17, 2007, at 10 a.m. in order to conduct a hearing entitled "Federal Acquisition: Ways to Strengthen Competition and Accountability."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412249" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet in order to conduct a hearing entitled "Hearing to Examine the Prosecution of Ignacio Ramos and Jose Compean" on Tuesday, July 17, 2007, at 10 a.m. Dirksen Senate Office Building, room 226.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Panel I: David V. Aguilar, Chief, Office of Border Patrol, U.S. Customs and Border Protection, Washington, DC; Johnny Sutton, United States Attorney, Western District of Texas, San Antonio, TX.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Panel II: T.J. Bonner, President, National Border Patrol Council, Campo, CA; Luis Barker, Deputy Chief, Office of Border Patrol, U.S. Customs and Border Protection, Washington, DC; David L. Botsford, Appellate Counsel for Mr. Ramos, Austin, RX.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="COMMITTEE ON VETERANS' AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Veterans' Affair be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, July 17, to conduct a vote on the nomination of Charles L. Hopkins to be an Assistant Secretary of Veterans Affairs (Operations, Preparedness, Security and Law Enforcement). The Committee will meet in the Reception Room, off the Senate Floor immediately after the first roll call vote of the Senate on Tuesday, July 17.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="COMMITTEE ON VETERANS' AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Veterans' Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, July 17, 2007, to conduct a hearing on VA and DOD Education Issues. The hearing will begin at 2:30 p.m.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON FEDERAL FINANCIAL MANAGEMENT, GOVERNMENT INFORMATION, FEDERAL SERVICES, AND INTERNATIONAL SECURITY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs' Subcommittee on Federal Financial Management, Government Information, Federal Services and International Security be authorized to meet on Tuesday, July 17, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. in order to conduct a hearing entitled Preparations for 2010: Is the Census Bureau Ready for the Job Ahead?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON RETIREMENT AND AGING">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions' Subcommittee on Retirement and Aging be authorized to hold a hearing on the Federal response to the Alzheimer's epidemic during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, July 17, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. in room 628 of the Senate Dirksen office building.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="PRIVILEGES OF THE FLOOR">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that David Azaria and Rachael Creswell of my staff be granted floor privileges for the duration of today's session.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300056" topic="PRIVILEGES OF THE FLOOR">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that Dane Balker, Senator WEBB's national security detainee, be given floor privileges for the duration of this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400576" topic="PRIVILEGES OF THE FLOOR">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that Major Thomas Rogers, a Department of Defense fellow in Senator Pete Domenici's office, be granted the privilege of the floor for the duration of the debate on the fiscal year 2008 Defense authorization bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
