<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1181232007" ordinal="28" title="STATEMENTS ON INTRODUCED BILLS AND JOINT RESOLUTIONS">
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="Introducing S. 1561. A bill to amend title 11, United States Code, with respect to exceptions to discharge in bankruptcy for certain qualified educational loans; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1561">S. 1561</bill>] Mr. President, I would like to tell you about Connie Martin from Sycamore, IL. Connie's son decided to go to culinary school in Chicago 5 years ago at the age of 25. To pay for tuition, he borrowed $58,000 in private loans from Sallie Mae at 18 percent interest. His first payment was $1,100 a month--his entire monthly salary at a downtown eatery where he worked after graduation. His loan balance, including government-backed loans, is now $100,000. Connie's son has been working hard,  and she and her husband have been trying to help him make the payments. I worry for borrowers like Connie's son who can't start over and will have debt that will likely haunt him for the rest of his life.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Chicago Sun-Times recently ran a story that described the devastating effect large student loan debt has on the lives of borrowers. Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the following article from the Chicago Sun-Times be inserted for the Record.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Private student loans are the fastest growing and most profitable sector of the student loan industry. As college tuition continues to rise, the private loan market flourishes. According to the College Board, tuition, fees, room and board at public 4-year schools have risen by 42 percent over the past 5 years from $9,032 to $12,796. Add books, supplies, transportation and other living expenses, and the total increases to $16,357 for those paying instate tuition and $26,304 for those paying out-of-state  tuition. Students rely on private loans to pay for any unmet need that Federal loans and grants fail to cover. According to the College Board, since 2001 the market for private student loans has grown at an annual rate of 27 percent to $17.3 billion in 2006--roughly 20 percent of total student borrowing. Ten years ago, only 5 percent of total education loan volume was in private loans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Private student loans are more profitable than Federal student loans because lenders can charge whatever interest rate students will pay, barring State usury laws. The interest rates and fees on private loans can be as onerous as credit cards. There are reports of private loans with interest rates of at least 15 percent and often much higher. Unlike Federal student loans, there is no government-imposed loan limit on private loans and no regulation over the terms and cost of these loans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, I am pleased to introduce a bill that will give students, who find themselves in dire financial straits, a chance at a new beginning. My bill takes the bankruptcy law, as it pertains to private student loans, back to where it was before the law was amended in 2005. Under this legislation, privately issued student loans will once again be dischargeable in bankruptcy. My bill also clarifies that existing protections are specific to loans that were issued by or are guaranteed by State and  Federal Government.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Federally issued or guaranteed student loans have been protected during personal bankruptcy since 1978. This provision protects Federal investments in higher education. In 2005, a provision was added to law to protect the investments of private lenders participating in the student loan industry. This change in the law creates a couple of problems. First, extending protections to private lenders of student loans but not to other potential creditors who are at risk in a bankruptcy disposition is  inherently unfair. Second, such protections are unfair to the debtor. Repayment schedules--with accumulating interest--can extend for decades.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With the 2005 protections in place, there is essentially no risk to lenders making high-cost private loans to people who may not be able to afford them. There is no risk to private lenders extending credit to students at schools with low graduation rates and even lower job placement rates.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Giving private loans such high status in bankruptcy also puts other creditors at a significant disadvantage. No one seems to know how or why private student loans gained this status in 2005. There is nothing in the Congressional Record explaining the reasons behind the change. Why should a private student loan lender be able to jump to the front of the creditor line--in front of the local furniture store or the neighborhood plumber? This bill seeks to restore treatment of privately issued  student loans in bankruptcy to the same treatment as any other debt.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is justification for making Federal loans hard to discharge: they are backed by taxpayer dollars, and they come with some borrower protections in cases of economic hardship, unemployment, death and disability. However, private loans involve only private profit and do not have the protections that government borrowers enjoy, including caps on interest rates, flexible repayment options, and limited  cancellation rights. Why should student borrowers,  who are trying to better themselves and our country, be treated in the same manner as people trying to escape child support payments, alimony, overdue taxes, and criminal fines?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The 1950s and 1960s saw the democratization of higher education. The GI Bill provided money for returning WWII veterans to attend college. The National Defense Education Act made college a possibility by making low-interest education loans available for countless students all across the country. Talented kids from working families began realizing the possibility of college, and enrollment at colleges swelled. But since then, college costs have gone through the roof. And students--heeding the  call to obtain a good education--are also earning themselves years of debt. The average student is graduating with nearly $20,000 in debt and in many cases--much, much more--just look at Connie Martin's son. Our country has made great strides in making college a reality for countless students. Let's not reverse the positive trend we started over 50 years ago. That is why I am introducing this bill--to give students a chance at a fresh start.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill and an article of support be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300008" topic="Introducing S. 1562. A bill to direct the Secretary of Energy to provide grants to States for the distribution of compact fluorescent lights; to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1562">S. 1562</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to introduce the Fluorescent Light Implementation Program to Save Americans Value and Energy, or FLIP-to-SAVE. This bill does something very simple to save Americans money and make us more energy efficient. It distributes compact fluorescent light-bulbs. We can save green two ways by changing our light-bulbs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Compact fluorescent light-bulbs, or CFLs, are highly efficient light-bulbs that use less than a quarter of the energy of traditional incandescent bulbs. The FLIP-to-SAVE program will spend $50 million to increase public awareness of how CFLs save money and the environment and to distribute them to households across the Nation. It is modeled after a successful program in my home State of Delaware, which distributed 140,000 CFLs through public libraries. The FLIP-to-SAVE program will give States  grants, to allow each State to develop a program that suits it best, though I expect many will be modeled after Delaware's system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Through this program, we can expect to replace 16 million inefficient incandescent bulbs with CFLs, reducing total residential energy bills by over $60 million each year. That means the program ought to pay for itself in terms of savings to families in just one year. And that's without considering the environmental benefits.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By reducing our energy consumption in the equivalent of 127,000 homes, about the size of Buffalo, NY, we can help alleviate our energy dependence and reduce our greenhouse gas emissions. In fact, one equivalent CFL replacing a 60 watt incandescent will prevent 1000 pounds of carbon dioxide through reductions in coal-powered electricity. That is 1.1 million tons of carbon dioxide each year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Energy efficiency is a key to our efforts to address climate change. There are many simple steps we can take to use less energy, and this is one. The FLIP-to-SAVE program will not just reduce carbon emissions, but also reduce electric bills for American families by more than its price tag. I ask that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="Introducing S. 1563. A bill to require the disclosure of certain activities relating to the petroleum industry of Sudan, to increase the penalties for violations of sanctions provisions, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1563">S. 1563</bill>] Mr. President, the suffering in Darfur and Sudan on the continent of Africa continues today as it has every day for too many years. I rise again to urge my colleagues that we must do more to end this crisis in Sudan. Two weeks ago, before the Memorial Day recess, I came to the floor to highlight some of the positive steps taken thus far by Congress, the Bush administration, the business community, and nonprofits to pressure the Sudanese regime to end this genocide. I said then and  I will repeat today: We must do more.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In that speech I urged the President to follow through on what he promised to do in April at the Holocaust museum just down the street in Washington. To the President's credit, last week he took steps forward. He tightened United States economic sanctions on Sudan. He targeted sanctions against more individuals responsible for the violence, and he vowed to push for a strong new United Nations Security Council resolution that would further pressure the Sudanese regime. I applaud the President  for his leadership. But I repeat, we must do more.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On March 28, as Treasury Secretary Paulson testified in front of the Appropriations subcommittee I chair, I asked the Secretary: What resources does the Treasury Department need to put more pressure on the Sudanese Government to end the genocide? His answer:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>..... We'd like the flexibility to charge a larger fine, because $50,000 may not be enough.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He was talking about civil and criminal penalties that violators of American sanctions on Sudan should face and the fact that the current penalties are not much of a deterrent. It was a concrete suggestion from the administration, and I agreed to accept his challenge. Based on that testimony, more discussions with the Treasury Department, the Securities and Exchange Commission, the State Department, and other agencies, we created the Sudan Disclosure and Enforcement Act which I introduce today.  This act provides the administration and all Americans with more resources and tools and information so we can each do our part to end the genocide and bring peace to Darfur. It creates real consequences for those who support the Sudanese regime and, perhaps most importantly, it requires the administration and Congress to meet in 90 days to reassess the steps that need to be taken to help to end the crisis.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For my colleagues who are considering supporting this legislation, here is what the bill will do in specifics: first, express the sense of Congress that the international community should continue to bring pressure against the Government of Sudan to convince that regime that the world would not allow this crisis to continue; second, authorize greater resources for the Office of  Foreign Assets Control within the Department of the Treasury to strengthen  its capabilities in tracking Sudanese economic activity and pursuing sanctions violators; third, require more detailed SEC disclosures by United States listed companies that operate in the Sudanese petroleum sector so investors can make informed decisions regarding divestment from these companies; fourth, dramatically increase</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am proud to introduce this legislation with bipartisan support. I particularly thank the ranking member of the Financial Services and General Government Appropriations Subcommittee, my friend and colleague Senator SAM BROWNBACK of Kansas, for all of his great work on this issue. I am pleased to be joined by all of the other original cosponsors as well: Senators DODD, who also chairs the Banking Committee and is a great ally; Senators KLOBUCHAR, MIKULSKI, BILL NELSON, OBAMA,  and WYDEN.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge all my colleagues on both sides of the aisle to join this effort. As we move around our States and visit parts of the country, occasionally a person will come up after a meeting and say to me: Senator, what are you doing about Darfur? Didn't your country, America, declare a genocide? What are you doing?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Frankly, aside from speeches on the floor and an occasional resolution, bills of very little consequence, there hasn't been much to point to. I hope my colleagues who face that same question and worry that the response is so inadequate will take a good look at this legislation. I hope they will join me in cosponsoring this effort. We should pass this measure, work with our House colleagues and do the same, send this bill to the President. The President said in April:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>You who have survived evil know that the only way to defeat it is to look it in the face and not back down. It is evil that we are now seeing in Sudan, and we're not going to back down.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The President went on to say:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>No one who sees these pictures can doubt that genocide is the only word for what is happening in Darfur and that we have a moral obligation to stop it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I completely agree with the President. It has been more than 2 1/2  years since the President called what is taking place in Darfur, Sudan by its rightful name--genocide. Yet even as an estimated 200,000 to 400,000 people have been killed, even as over 2 million men, women, and tiny children have been forced from their homes by violence and killing, even as the violence continues as we meet in the safety and comfort of this great Nation, America and the entire international community have not  done enough to help. We must do more. This bill moves in the right direction. It gives our Government the tools and the encouragement to act and act quickly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300008" topic="Introducing S. 1565. A bill to provide for the transfer of naval vessels to certain foreign recipients; to the Committee on Foreign Relations.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1565">S. 1565</bill>] Mr. President, today, Senator LUGAR and I are introducing the Naval Vessel Transfer Act of 2007, a bill to permit the transfer of certain U.S. Navy vessels to particular foreign countries. All of the proposed ship transfer authorizations have been requested by the U.S. Navy, with the approval of the Office of Management and Budget.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Pursuant to section 824(b) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1994, as amended, 10 U.S.C. 7307(a), a naval vessel that is in excess of 3,000 tons or that is less than 20 years of age may not be disposed of to another nation unless the disposition of that vessel is approved by law enacted after August 5, 1974. The bill we are introducing today would provide that required approval for eight transfers: two guided missile frigates and two minehunter coastal ships for Turkey;  two minehunter coastal ships for Lithuania; and two minehunter coastal ships for Taiwan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also contains provisions that are traditionally included in ship transfer bills, relating to transfer costs and repair and refurbishment of the ships, and exempting the value of a vessel transferred on a grant basis from the aggregate value of excess defense articles in a given fiscal year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The authority provided by this bill would expire 2 years after the date of enactment of the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Similar legislation was passed by the Senate last year, but was objected to in the House of Representatives because of concern regarding the proposal to transfer minehunter coastal ships. That issue was also raised by Members of the Senate Armed Services Committee, but members of that committee were persuaded by the Executive branch that the transfers would not degrade U.S. Navy capabilities. We invite interested colleagues to let us know if there is any residual concern among Members of the  Senate, so that we can arrange for the Executive branch to brief members and determine if there is any objection to expeditious passage of this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, the Department of Defense has provided the following information on this bill:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill would authorize the President to grant transfer five excess naval vessels to Turkey and Lithuania and to sell three excess naval vessels to Taiwan and Turkey.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These proposed transfers would improve the United States' political and military relationships with close allies. They would support strategic engagement goals and regional security cooperation objectives. Active use of former naval vessels by coalition forces in support of regional priorities is more advantageous than retaining vessels in the Navy's inactive fleet and disposing of them by scrapping or another method.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The United States would incur no costs in transferring these naval vessels. The recipients would be responsible for all costs associated with the transfers, including maintenance, repairs, training, and fleet turnover costs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill does not alter the effect of the Toxic Substances Control Act, or any other law, with regard to their applicability to the transfer of ships by the United States to foreign countries for military or humanitarian use. The laws and regulations that apply today would apply in the same manner if this bill were enacted.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Department of Defense estimates that the sale of these vessels may net the United States $52.7 million in fiscal year 2008.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There being no ojection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>
      <bill type="s" number="1565">S. 1565</bill>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "Naval Vessel Transfer Act of 2007".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. TRANSFER OF NAVAL VESSELS TO CERTAIN FOREIGN RECIPIENTS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Transfers by Grant.--The President is authorized to transfer vessels to foreign recipients on a grant basis under section 516 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (22 U.S.C. 2321j), as follows:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) TURKEY.--To the Government of Turkey--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) the OLIVER HAZARD PERRY class guided missile frigates GEORGE PHILIP (FFG-12) and SIDES (FFG-14); and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) the OSPREY class minehunter coastal ship BLACKHAWK (MHC-58).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) LITHUANIA.--To the Government of Lithuania, the OSPREY class minehunter coastal ships CORMORANT (MHC-57) and KINGFISHER (MHC-56).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Transfers by Sale.--The President is authorized to transfer vessels to foreign recipients on a sale basis under section 21 of the Arms Export Control Act (22 U.S.C. 2761), as follows:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) TAIWAN.--To the Taipei Economic and Cultural Representative Office of the United States (which is the Taiwan instrumentality designated pursuant to section 10(a) of the Taiwan Relations Act (22 U.S.C. 3309(a))), the OSPREY class minehunter coastal ships ORIOLE (MHC-55) and FALCON (MHC-59).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) TURKEY.--To the Government of Turkey, the OSPREY class minehunter coastal ship SHRIKE (MHC-62).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Grants Not Counted in Annual Total of Transferred Excess Defense Articles.--The value of a vessel transferred to a recipient on a grant basis pursuant to authority provided by subsection (a) or (c) shall not be counted against the aggregate value of excess defense articles transferred in any fiscal year under section 516 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (d) Costs of Transfers.--Any expense incurred by the United States in connection with a transfer authorized by this section shall be charged to the recipient.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (e) Repair and Refurbishment in United States Shipyards.--To the maximum extent practicable, the President shall require, as a condition of the transfer of a vessel under this section, that the recipient to which the vessel is transferred have such repair or refurbishment of the vessel as is needed before the vessel joins the naval forces of the recipient performed at a shipyard located in the United States, including a United States Navy shipyard.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (f) Expiration of Authority.--The authority to transfer a vessel under this section shall expire at the end of the 2-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300042" topic="Introducing S. 1569. A bill to establish a pilot program on the provision of legal services to assist veterans and members of the Armed Forces receive health care, benefits and services, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1569">S. 1569</bill>] Mr. President, today I am introducing the Veterans Advocacy Act of 2007. This bill would create a grant program for organizations providing pro bono legal representation to servicemembers and veterans to ensure that they receive the health care and benefits to which they are entitled.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The men and women of the Armed Services have served this Nation honorably and deserve the best health care and benefits available. However, as recent revelations about the extent of bureaucratic delays at the Walter Reed Army Medical Center demonstrate, these brave individuals face a series of hurdles as they navigate the health care and disability compensation processes. Many of them are forced to turn to their representatives in Congress for help cutting through the red tape. I have heard from  many military personnel and veterans who are frustrated with the system or unaware of Federal health care and other benefits for which they may be eligible. I regret that the system too often makes the burden of proving that a condition is related to military</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Numerous reports have detailed the range of administrative and legal hurdles injured servicemembers will face when they return home. Service members returning with unprecedented rates of post traumatic stress disorder, PTSD, and traumatic brain injury, TBI, will struggle to get the medical records they need to file benefits claims. Those with severe TBI that does not show up on brain scans will have an even harder time establishing that they need compensation. Those with profound TBI may be prematurely  relegated to care in a nursing home when, with proper assistance, they may be fully capable of living independent lives in the community. The Government Accountability Office reported  that over 75 percent of servicemembers who screen positive for PTSD will not be referred to a mental health professional. Members of the Guard and Reserves face additional hurdles to gain access to military doctors. This is unacceptable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I commend my colleagues for their support of increased funding for the military and veterans' health care systems in the 2007 emergency supplemental. However, I am concerned that unless veterans have independent advocates to ensure that they are receiving top notch care and that they are aware of the benefits to which they are entitled, these additional funds may be mismanaged. Last November, the Government Accountability Office reported that for the last two years the Department of Veterans  Affairs has not expended all the funds allocated for mental health initiatives. My bill would ensure that service members and veterans who have trouble accessing the care to which they are entitled will have an advocate outside the chain of command who can negotiate with the Departments to ensure proper care.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to helping ensure that service members and veterans receive top notch care, my bill would help service members and veterans overcome legal barriers to obtaining benefits. During the Veterans' Affairs Committee's hearing on benefits legislation, Meredith Beck of the Wounded Warrior Project summarized the problem as follows: "In many of the cases we have seen, the creation of new benefits wasn't needed to aid the service member, rather, the wounded warrior just needed to have the existing  benefits systems better explained and untangled in order to understand what was available to them."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Fortunately, service members and veterans benefit from the services of a nationwide system of veterans and military service organizations. However, the system is simply overwhelmed. It will be further inundated when the over 170,000 servicemembers deployed in Iraq and Afghanistan return home. I want to be clear that the purpose of this legislation is to supplement the existing network of advocates to ease the caseload of overburdened service officers and allow them to spend more time per case  helping veterans and service members.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress has a responsibility to simplify the system and ensure that it gives service members and veterans the benefit of the doubt when they seek assistance for service-connected disabilities. It is my hope that the majority of veterans will not need legal representation. But the reality is that many veterans face unnecessary delays and appeals of legitimate compensation claims that could be avoided if there were enough advocates to ensure that every veteran's case is carefully developed from  the beginning. Several judges of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims have described the importance of ensuring that veterans have legal representation throughout the claim process. Judge Holdaway summarized the need as follows:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If you get lawyers involved at the beginning, you can focus in on what is this case about. I think you would get better records, you would narrow the issue, there would be screening . . . I think if we had lawyers involved at the beginning of these cases, it would be the single most fundamental change for the better that this system could have.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While the need for legal representation in complicated cases is clear, I do not believe that veterans should have to pay for legal representation just to get the benefits they earned through their service. I have been troubled when I have heard that service members are seeking expensive legal assistance to help them overcome daunting administrative and legal hurdles. Fortunately, there are legal service organizations and attorneys who are willing to provide assistance to these service members  and veterans free of charge. The purpose of this bill is to help these organizations get the training they need to help veterans and service members.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill would establish a pilot program of one-year grants to organizations that have experience serving veterans or persons with disabilities. The Veterans Administration will be charged with appointing a committee to disburse the grants. The committee shall be composed of veterans and military service officers, veterans and disability legal service attorneys, and representatives of the Department of Veterans Affairs employees and the Department of Defense. The Secretary of Veterans Affairs  will be required to submit a report to Congress on the number of individuals served and the kinds of assistance they received as a result of the pilot program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In order to avoid adding to our country's sizable debt, the $1 million cost of this program is taken from the $3 billion appropriated to the defense health program by the 2008 supplemental spending bill. The grant program will help ensure that these funds are spent wisely.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Veterans and military service organizations that currently employ attorneys will be eligible to receive the grants either to provide legal services at no charge or to provide training to other pro bono attorneys. The bill will also help servicemembers and veterans access the services of the federally funded and mandated protection and advocacy system for persons with disabilities. This system has lawyers in every state who are trained to help people with disabilities obtain the benefits, health  care and services they need to live independent lives. These attorneys are uniquely qualified to, for example, ensure that veterans with PTSD are properly diagnosed and treated and to prevent those with TBI from being placed in nursing homes when they are capable of living in the community. Many veterans have been seeking</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I commend my colleagues who have offered bills to increase funding for the care of service members and veterans, to expand necessary benefits and to ensure that our military and veterans health care systems offer the best care available. In order to ensure that service members and veterans are able to capitalize on these important reforms, they need independent advocates who can help them cut through the red tape. My bill would help expand the cadre of experienced advocates who will do just that.  The bill has been endorsed by the National Organization of Veterans Advocates, the Vietnam Veterans of America and the Protection and Advocacy System's National Disability Rights Network.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill and supporting material be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300091" topic="Introducing S. 1571. A bill to reform the essential air service program, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1571">S. 1571</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to join my colleagues, Senators BINGAMAN, HAGEL, and NELSON of Nebraska to introduce the bipartisan Rural Aviation Improvement Act. I am proud to join my colleagues, each one a steadfast and resolute guardian of commercial aviation service to all communities, particularly rural areas that would otherwise be deprived of any air service.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have always believed that reliable air service in our Nation's rural areas is not simply a luxury or a convenience. It is an imperative. All of us who come from rural States know how critical aviation is to economic development, vital to move people and goods to and from areas that may otherwise have dramatically limited transportation options. Quite frankly, I have long held serious concerns about the impact deregulation of the airline industry has had on small and medium size cities in rural  areas, like Maine. That fact is, since deregulation, many small and medium-size communities, in Maine and elsewhere, have experienced a decrease in flights and size of aircraft while seeing an increase in fares. More than 300 have lost air service altogether.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation will serve to improve the Essential Air Service program. Additional resources will augment the resources available to the program, reducing the impact on the general fund while providing small communities with a greater degree of certainty when planning future improvements to their airports. The bill also gives those same communities a greater role in retaining and determining the sort of air service which they receive.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Increasingly, the Essential Air Service program has been plagued with a decline in the number of airlines willing to provide this critical link to the national transportation network. A few "bad actors" have jeopardized commercial aviation for entire regions by submitting low-ball contracts to the Department of Transportation and then reneging on their commitment to the extent and quality of their service. Our bill will not only establish a system of minimum requirements for contracts to protect  these small cities that rely on EAS, but it will also extend those contracts to 4 years from the current 2. This gives a heightened degree of stability in terms of air service, rather than having communities negotiating new contracts or receiving service from entirely new carriers every 18 months.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In closing, the truth is, everyone benefits when our Nation is at its strongest economically. Most importantly in this case, greater prosperity everywhere, including in rural America, will, in the long run, mean more passengers for the airlines. Therefore, it is very much in our national interests to ensure that every region has reasonable access to air service. That is why I strongly believe the Federal Government has an obligation to fulfill the commitment it made to these communities in 1978;  to safeguard their ability to continue commercial air service.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="Introducing S. 1571. A bill to reform the essential air service program, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I wish today to join with my colleague, Senator Snowe to introduce the bipartisan Rural Aviation Improvement Act. Senator Snowe has been a longtime champion of commercial air service in rural areas, and I applaud her continued leadership on this important legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One of the goals of our bill is to preserve and improve the Essential Air Service Program. Congress established the Essential Air Service Program in 1978 to ensure that communities that had commercial air service before airline deregulation would continue to receive scheduled service. The Essential Air Service Program currently ensures commercial air service to over 100 communities in 35 States. EAS supports an additional 39 communities in Alaska. Without EAS, many rural communities would have  no commercial air service at all. I believe our bill makes a number of important improvements to EAS to ensure rural communities continue to have the commercial air service that is so vital to their futures.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our bill also extends through 2011 the Department of Transportation's authority to provide grants to cities under the Small Community Air Service Development Program, which was first established in 2000. The program helps rural communities establish new air service or to promote and improve their existing air service. Since it was first enacted, a number of New Mexico communities have won grants, including most recently Gallup in 2006.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>All across America, small communities face ever-increasing hurdles to promoting their economic growth and development. Today, many rural areas lack access to interstate or even four-lane highways, railroads, or broadband  telecommunications. Business development in rural areas frequently hinges on the availability of scheduled air service. For small communities, commercial air service provides a critical link to the national and international transportation  system. I do believe Congress must help ensure that affordable, reliable, and safe air service remains available in rural America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senate Commerce Committee and its Aviation Subcommittee are well along in developing a reauthorization of aviation programs this year. I look forward to working with my colleagues Chairmen INOUYE and ROCKEFELLER and Ranking Members STEVENS and LOTT to improve commercial air service programs for rural areas. I believe our bill is one important step in that process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1572">S. 1572</bill>] Mr. President, the landmark 1999 Surgeon General's report on mental health brought a hidden mental health crisis to the attention of the U.S. public. According to that report, 13.7 million children in our country--about one in five--suffer from a diagnosable emotional or behavioral disorder. Such disorders as Anxiety Disorders, Attention-Deficit/Hyperactivity Disorder, and Depression are among the most common in this age group. Yet more than two-thirds of these children do not receive  any treatment. Long waiting lists for children seeking services, including those in crisis, are not uncommon. The primary reason is that severe shortages exist in qualified mental health professionals, including child psychiatrists, psychologists, social workers, and counselors. The President's New Freedom Commission on Mental Health also found that "the supply of well-trained mental health professionals is inadequate in most areas of the country ..... particular</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The situation in my home State of New Mexico is a case in point. Estimates suggest that 56,000 children and adolescents in New Mexico have an emotional or behavioral disorder. Of these, roughly 20,000 have serious disturbances that impair their ability to fulfill the demands of everyday life. In 2001, there were a total of 44 child and adolescent psychiatrists in the entire State of New Mexico. The impact of this shortage on the affected children and their communities is disconcerting. Research  shows that children with untreated emotional and behavioral disorders are at higher risk for school failure and dropping out of school, violence, drug abuse, suicide, and criminal activity. For New Mexico youth, the suicide rate is twice the national average, the fourth highest in the nation, and the third leading cause of death. By one estimate, roughly one in seven youth in New Mexico detention centers are in need of mental health treatment that is just not available.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>New Mexico is not alone in its struggle to address the needs of these children. Nationwide, over 1600 urban, suburban, and rural communities have been designated Mental Health Professional Shortage Areas by the Federal Government due to their severe lack of psychiatrists, psychologists, social workers, and other professionals to serve children and adults. Rural areas are especially hard hit. For example, in New Mexico there is one psychiatrist per 20,000 residents in rural areas, whereas in urban  areas there is one per 3000 residents. In rural and frontier counties, it is not unusual for the parents of a child in need of services to travel 60 to 90 miles to reach the nearest psychiatrist, psychologist, or other mental health provider. In States like Alaska and Wyoming, the distance may be even farther.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, graduate programs providing the vital pipeline for the child mental health workforce have not sufficiently increased their funding, class sizes, and training programs to meet the ever growing need for these specialists. In the U.S., only 300 new child and adolescent psychiatrists are trained each year, despite projections by the Bureau of Health Professions that the shortage of child and adolescent psychiatrist will grow to 4,000 by the year 2020. Federal grant funding for graduate psychology  education has also been significantly reduced in the past two years, which could reduce the numbers of child and adolescent psychologists entering the profession.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Clearly something needs to be done to address this serious shortage in mental health professionals to meet the growing needs of our Nation's youth. It is for this reason that I rise today with my colleagues Senator COLLINS of Maine, Senator LEAHY of Vermont, Senator DURBIN of Illinois, Senator Reed of Rhode Island, Senator Harkin of Iowa, Senator Stabenow of Michigan, Senator Dodd of Connecticut, and Senator Sanders of Vermont  to offer The Child Health Care Crisis Relief Act of 2007. This bill creates incentives to help recruit and retain mental health professionals providing direct clinical care, and to help create, expand, and improve programs to train child mental health professionals. It provides loan repayments and scholarships for child mental health and school-based service professionals as well as internships and field placements in child mental health services and training for paraprofessionals who work in children's mental health</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, The Child Health Care Crisis Relief Act of 2007 requires the Secretary to prepare a report on the distribution and need for child mental health and school-based professionals, including disparities in the availability of services, on a State-by-State basis. This report will help Congress more clearly ascertain the mental health workforce needs that are facing our Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill and my statement be printed in the RECORD. I also ask unanimous consent that the appended letter from the Mental Health Liaison Group, representing 40 national professional and mental health advocacy organizations in support of The Child Health Care Crisis Relief Act of 2007, be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, material was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300034" topic="Introducing S. 1573. A bill to promote public-private partnerships to strengthen investment in early childhood development for children from birth to entry into kindergarten in order to ensure healthy development and school readiness for all children; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1573">S. 1573</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today, to introduce The Early Childhood Investment Act of 2007 to create and enhance public-private partnerships to strengthen investment in early childhood development programs, considering the needs of all children from birth to their entry in kindergarten. Investing in our youngest children is essential to promote their healthy development and school readiness. I pleased that two of my colleagues from Connecticut in the House of Representatives--Congresswoman</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have a body of knowledge on early childhood development that must be put into practice through policies that aid the crucial emotional, social and intellectual development that occurs in the first 3 years of life. Research indicates that investments in the early years of a child's life pay dividends later through improved health, readiness for school, and economic well-being. The return on investment also includes more successful transition to kindergarten; reduced special education and remedial  education placements; better employment opportunities and higher earnings; and lower incidence of crime and dependence on public welfare. Our Nation's economy benefits from early childhood investments through a better prepared workforce, stronger growth, and</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many States have an Early Learning Council or an advisory council that coordinates and aligns various programs serving children from birth to kindergarten entry. These entities facilitate collaboration among early childhood development activities in each State, but do not necessarily provide additional funding. Resources from Federal and State governments alone are not adequate to provide access to quality  early childhood development programs for all  children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Currently the Federal Government provides funding for a variety of early childhood development programs including the Child Care and Development Block Grant, and Head Start, which have been essentially flat funded in recent years. States supplement this funding and also provide funding for State and local prekindergarten programs and parent development and support programs, such as home visiting. However, the Federal and State resources alone are not enough to reach all of our Nation's young  children. In order to get closer to the goal of providing access to quality programs for all children before they enter kindergarten, the private sector also plays an important role. In addition, the Federal Government should provide resources to reward innovation at the state and community level and to leverage additional resources for continued innovation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In States such as Washington, Georgia, Michigan, Minnesota, Oklahoma, North Carolina, Arizona, Nebraska, Illinois, Vermont, and Virginia, public-private partnerships leverage resources to provide for the varied health and learning needs of children from birth to kindergarten entry and their families. Public-private partnerships have the ability to leverage the assets of public and private entities in terms of financial resources, expertise, and infrastructure in order to maximize and align investments  in early childhood development. Federal funding authorized by this legislation will create incentives for more States to develop such partnerships and leverage further investment in young children and enhance existing partnerships in states.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the Early Childhood Investment Act of 2007 is to establish or enhance existing public-private partnerships that will strengthen investment in early childhood development by awarding grants to local community initiatives and programs that serve young children and their families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill is fairly straightforward. It requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a competitive grant program to award grants to a public-private partnership, in each State that applies, which will leverage resources to supplement existing State and Federal funds. The partnership will then award subgrants to State and local community initiatives to improve access to and quality of early childhood development for children from birth through age five and their families. The  partnerships will leverage funding from nonprofit or for-profit organizations, private entities and State government to invest in high quality early childhood development programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Early Childhood Investment Act of 2007 authorizes $8 billion for fiscal year 2008, $10 billion for fiscal year 2009 and such sums as necessary in the following years. The Federal share represents 50 percent of total expenditures by a partnership in the first year, 40 percent in the second year and 30 percent in the outyears. I know I will hear that this cost is too large for the government to bear, but I would argue that the cost of not investing would be even greater. Children represent  only a quarter of our population, but they are 100 percent of our future and each of our children deserves an opportunity to reach his or her potential.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill has been endorsed by America's Promise Alliance, First Focus, National Association for the Education of Young Children, National Association of Child Care Resource and Referral Agencies, and the National Women's Law Center. I hope that my colleagues will join me in supporting this important legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400629" topic="Introducing S. 1574. A bill to establish Teaching Residency Programs for preparation and induction of teachers; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1574">S. 1574</bill>] Mr. President, we will soon begin consideration of legislation to educate America's students, with Head Start, the Elementary and Secondary Education Act, and the Higher Education Act all slated for reauthorization. One of the most important aspects of No Child Left Behind is its provision for a highly qualified teacher for every child, in every classroom in America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Expert teachers are the most important educational resource in our schools, and also the most inequitably distributed. In the United States, too many students in high-need schools are taught by inadequately prepared teachers, who are often not ready for the challenges they face, and thus leave the classroom too soon. High-poverty schools lose one-fifth of their teaching staff each year. This constant turnover of inexperienced, inadequately prepared teachers undermines efforts to create stable  learning cultures and to sustain school improvement, especially in schools with greatest need.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many schools are being identified as in need of improvement, and many students are asked to be successful in schools where success is a rare commodity. Rather than being a leader in a competitive world where educational attainment is precious, America has one of the lowest high school graduation rates in the industrialized world. Three out of every 10 ninth-grade students will not graduate on time, and about half of all African American and Hispanic ninth graders will not earn a diploma in four  years. Less than 2 out of every 10 students who begin high school will receive a postsecondary degree within a reasonable time. Students of color, new immigrants, and children living in poverty are all being left behind. A good education is granted to some, but denied to others, denied not only to children of color in our cities, but also to children living in poverty in our rural areas. We must end this.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We must recruit the best and the brightest Americans to become teachers and we must transform teaching, restoring its luster as a profession, so that when new teachers join it, they are successful, and want to stay. As teachers and principals are increasingly being held individually responsible for student success, it is increasingly important that we adequately prepare teachers to become successful.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Research shows that inexperienced teachers are less effective than teachers with several years of experience, but good preparation programs can make novice teachers effective more rapidly. We must help novice teachers get the training and coaching they need. Teacher preparation seldom provides the opportunity to learn under the supervision of expert teachers working in schools that effectively serve high-need students. Most new teachers lack such support, and so leave the profession before achieving  success.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today I am proud to introduce the Teaching Residency Act, which builds on a successful model of teacher preparation similar to medical residencies. Teaching Residency Programs are school-based teacher preparation programs in which prospective teachers teach alongside a mentor teacher for one academic year, receive master's level coursework in teaching the content area in which they will become certified, and attain certification prior to completion of the program. Once certified, graduates of  the program are placed in high-needs schools, and continue to receive strong mentoring and coaching for their first years of teaching. This bill proposes establishing Teaching Residency Programs as a provision of Title II of the Higher Education Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am particularly proud to introduce this legislation today, because it is a model of effective teacher preparation that I have supported since before I was elected to the Senate in 2004. I have seen the power of teacher residencies through the very successful Academy for Urban School Leadership in my home State of Illinois. And I am pleased to be supported in this effort by the introduction of legislation in the House by my good friend, Congressman RAHM EMANUEL. </paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is critical to develop programs that increase the probability that recruits will succeed and stay in those classrooms where they are most needed. Teaching Residency Programs are based on what we know works best to improve teacher preparation. We know that mentoring is critical to help young teachers develop in the early years of their career and to retain many of new teachers who would otherwise leave the profession in their first years. We cannot afford to lose any more high quality teachers  because they do not feel supported or do not feel that they are progressing professionally.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I hope my colleagues will support this important legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="Introducing S. 1576. A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to improve the health and healthcare of racial and ethnic minority groups; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1576">S. 1576</bill>] Mr. President, serious and unjustified health disparities continue to exist in our Nation today. Forty five million Americans have no health insurance and often don't get the health care they need or get it too late. We know that the uninsured are more likely to delay doctor visits and needed screenings like mammograms and other early detection tests which can help prevent serious illness and death. The Institute of Medicine estimates that at least 18,000 Americans die prematurely  each year because they lack health coverage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Some of the most shameful health disparities involve racial and ethnic minorities. African Americans have a lower life expectancy than Whites. They are much more likely to die from stroke, and their uninsurance rates are much higher than those of their White counterparts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many Americans want to believe such disparities don't exist, but ignoring them only contributes more to the widening gap between the haves and have-nots.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is a scandal that people of color have greater difficulty obtaining good health care than other Americans. Your health should not depend on the color of your skin, the size of your bank account, or where you live. In a nation as advanced as ours, with its state-of-the-art medical technology for preventing illness and caring for the sick, it is appalling that so many health disparities continue to exist.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is the reason why I am introducing the Minority Health and Health Disparity Elimination Act, as part of our effort to reduce or eliminate these unacceptable differences in the health and health care of racial and ethnic minorities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill includes grants and demonstration projects that will help communities promote positive health behaviors and improve outreach, participation, and enrollment of racial and ethnic minorities in available health care programs. The bill will also establish collaborative partnerships led by community health centers. In particular it will support the Delta Health Initiative Rural Health, Education, and Workforce Infrastructure Demonstration Program to address longstanding, unmet health and  health care needs in the Mississippi Delta</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, the bill codifies the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention's Racial and Ethnic Approaches to Community Health Program, so that this successful program can continue to assist communities to mobilize and organize resources to support effective and sustainable programs to help close the health and health care gap. It also establishes Health Action Zones to support State, tribal or local initiatives to improve minority health in communities that have been historically burdened  by health disparities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Greater diversity in the health care workforce is essential to creating a healthy America. Studies demonstrate that minority health professionals are more likely to care for minority patients, including those who are low-income and uninsured. African Americans, Hispanic Americans, and Native Americans account for only 6 percent of the Nation's doctors and 5 percent of nurses and dentists, even though they are almost one-quarter of the U.S. population. The disparity in the health workforce must  be closed, not just to fulfill our commitment to equality and opportunity, but also because of the impact it has on the health of America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The act reauthorizes the title VII health care workforce diversity programs, including the Centers of Excellence at Historically Black Colleges and Universities and institutions that educate Hispanic and Native American students.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A diverse health care workforce is essential for a healthy country. Emphasizing workforce diversity does not mean that health care workers should not be prepared to work with diverse patients. We must also make a more serious effort to train culturally competent health care professionals, and to create a health care system that is accessible for the more than 48 million Americans who speak a language other than English at home. The bill creates an Internet clearinghouse to increase cultural competency  and improve communication between health care providers and patients. It also supports the development of curricula on cultural competence in health professions schools.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Language barriers in health care obviously contribute to reduced access and poorer care for those who have limited English proficiency or low health literacy. The legislation recognizes the importance of this issue for the quality of our health care system and provides funds for activities to improve and encourage services for such patients.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill reauthorizes the National Center for Minority Health and Health Disparities that was created as part of the Minority Health and Health Disparities Research and Education Act of 2000. It strengthens the center's role in coordinating and planning research that focuses on minority health and health disparities at the National Institutes of Health. The bill also requires the Agency for Health care Research and Quality to establish a grant program to support private research initiatives and  a public-private partnership to evaluate and identify the best practices in disease management strategies and interventions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, the bill ensures that research on genetic variation within and between populations includes a focus on racial and ethnic minorities. It also promotes the participation of racial and ethnic minorities in clinical trials and intensifies efforts throughout the Department of Health and Human Services to increase and apply knowledge about the interaction of racial, genetic, and environmental factors that affect people's health.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, the bill reinforces and clarifies the duties of the Office of Minority Health and instructs the office to develop and implement a comprehensive department-wide plan to improve minority health and eliminate health disparities. It also encourages greater cooperation among federal agencies and departments in meeting these serious challenges.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have worked diligently with a wide variety of organizations on this bill that are eager for strong legislation to eliminate health disparities. The following groups have expressed their support: Aetna, American Association of Colleges of Pharmacy, American Heart Association/American Stroke Association, American Public Health Association, Asian American and Pacific Islander Health Forum, Association for Community Affiliated Plans, Association of Minority Health Professions Schools, California  Pan-Ethnic Network, Charles R. Drew University of Medicine and Science, Families USA, Harvard Medical School, Massachusetts General Hospital, Meharry Medical College, Morehouse School of Medicine, National Association of Community Health Centers, National Association of Public Hospitals and Health Systems, National Coalition for Hispanic Health--Campaign for Tobacco Free Kids, Hispanic Association of Colleges and Universities,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I look forward to working with these dedicated groups as we work towards final passage of this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I greatly appreciate the cooperation of Senator Cochran, Senator Obama, Senator Bingaman, Senator Clinton, Senator Brown, and Senator Durbin on this legislation, and I look forward to working with my colleagues to enact this much needed legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400629" topic="Introducing S. 1576. A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to improve the health and healthcare of racial and ethnic minority groups; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, this Nation has witnessed dramatic improvements in public health and health care technology and practice over the last century. Diseases that were once life-threatening are now curable; conditions that once devastated are now treatable. Our Federal investment in  medical research has paid off handsomely, with new and more effective tests and treatments and near daily reports of new scientific breakthroughs. Yet still today too  many Americans have not and will not derive full benefit from these advances.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We know that minority Americans and other vulnerable populations needlessly continue to experience higher rates of disease and lower rates of survival, and this is simply unacceptable. As we in the Congress work to combat the serious health issues that threaten the well-being of all Americans, we must also remain vigilant and committed in our fight to address the persistent and pervasive health disparities that affect millions of minorities, low-income individuals and other at-risk populations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress has passed legislation before to address the health of minority populations and eliminate health disparities--the Minority Health and Health Disparities Research and Education Act of 2000. That bill created the National Center for Minority Health and Health Disparities, supported the landmark IOM report Unequal Treatment, required annual reporting on health care disparities by AHRQ, and strengthened the research base for many HBCU's, among many other provisions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since that bill passed, our knowledge and understanding about the root causes of these disparities has dramatically increased. Efforts to strengthen the research infrastructure needed to investigate health concerns among people of color have been quite effective. Momentum has also accelerated in the medical and public health communities as advocates' voices are heard more and more, with new interventions being implemented and evaluated. All of these positive steps and advances have helped to  raise minority health as a national priority. However, despite this activity, much work remains to be done in order to close the gap and eliminate health and health care disparities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Study after study reveals the stark line of health disparity drawn between minorities and whites. In cancer alone, the numbers are hard to overlook. In 2004, African American men were 2.4 times as likely to die from prostate cancer, as compared to white men. For heart disease, the statistics are equally compelling: 2004 data show that when compared to white men, African American men were 30 percent more likely to die from heart disease, and American Indian adults were 30 percent more likely to  have high blood pressure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The underlying factors for health disparities are multi-factorial. Our individual genetic makeup certainly contributes to differences in rates of disease and mortality in diverse populations. However, other factors play an equal if not greater role. We know that minority and low-income Americans are disproportionately less likely to live in communities that promote healthy behaviors and choices through access to wholesome foods and opportunities for physical activity, and that protect from exposure  to environmental toxins and violence. In addition, minority Americans are less likely to have health coverage and thus more likely to experience difficulties accessing the health care system, which leads to delayed diagnoses and foregone care. And last but not least, we know that minority Americans are less likely to receive</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For all of these reasons, I am joining my colleagues Senator KENNEDY and Senator COCHRAN in introducing the Minority Health Improvement and Health Disparity Elimination Act of 2007. This critical legislation has a number of important provisions to help us achieve our goal to improve the health status of minority and other underserved populations. First, this bill strengthens education and training in cultural competence and communication, which is the cornerstone of quality health  care for all patients. It also reauthorizes the pipeline programs in title VII of the Public Health Service Act, which seek to increase diversity in the health professions. We all know that the door to opportunity is only half open for minority students in the health professions. The percentage</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Lack of workforce diversity has serious implications for both access and quality of health care. Minority physicians are significantly more likely to treat low-income patients, and their patients are disproportionately minority. Studies have also shown that minority physicians provide higher quality of care to minority patients, who are more satisfied with their care and more likely to follow the doctor's recommendations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second, this bill expands and supports a number of initiatives to increase access to quality care. Specifically, the legislation authorizes demonstration grants to improve access to healthcare, patient navigators, and health literacy education services. Additionally, partnerships modeled after the Health Disparity Collaboratives at the Bureau of Primary Health Care are supported through established grants. The REACH program at Centers for Disease Control and Prevention--designed to assist communities  in mobilizing and organizing resources to support effective and sustainable programs to reduce health disparities--is established under this bill. And I am pleased that the Health Action Zone Initiative has also been authorized. This new environmental public health program was introduced as part of the Healthy Communities Act of 2007 that I introduced earlier this year, and guides and strengthens community efforts to improve health in comprehensive and sustained fashion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A third area of focus is expansion and acceleration of data collection and research across the agencies, including the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality and the National Institute of Health, with special emphasis on translational research. The tremendous advances in medical science and health technology, which have benefited millions of Americans, have remained out of reach for too many minorities, and translational research will help to remedy this problem. The National Center on Minority  Health and Health Disparities, which has a leadership role in establishing the disparities research strategic plan at the National Institutes of Health, is reauthorized. And a new advisory committee has been established at the Food and Drug Administration to focus on pharmacogenomics and its safe and appropriate use in minority populations, another issue area that I championed as part of my Genomics and Personalized Medicine Act of 2006.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last but not least, I want to highlight that the bill strengthens and clarifies the duties of the Office of Minority Health. This office has been critical in providing the leadership, expertise and guidance for health improvement activities across the agencies of the Department of Health and Human Services, and has helped to ensure coordination, collaboration and integration of such efforts as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In conclusion, I want emphasize that it is past time to expand and accelerate our work in a of minority health beyond the initial bipartisan effort Congress achieved in 2000. We have got to translate the knowledge we have gained into practical and effective interventions that will improve minority health and eliminate disparities, and this bill will help us do just that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to join me in cosponsoring and passing this critical legislation. Regardless of how you measure it, whether by needless suffering, lost productivity, financial costs, or lives lost, disparities in health and health care are a tremendous problem and a moral imperative for our Nation, and one that is within our power to address right now.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300022" topic="Introducing S. 1576. A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to improve the health and healthcare of racial and ethnic minority groups; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I am pleased to join Senators KENNEDY, COCHRAN, BINGAMAN, OBAMA, DURBIN and BROWN in introducing the Minority Health Improvement and Health Disparity Elimination Act 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As we debate health care issues, we often discuss what is wrong with our health care system: Costs are spiraling upward, the ranks of uninsured have  increased, and the strains on our system and its ability to provide quality care have worsened. And while the impact of these situations are felt by all Americans, the problems with our health care system often disproportionately impact our racial and ethnic minority populations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We continue to have disparities in health care for our minority populations--disparities in access, disparities in quality, and disparities in outcomes. The Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ) tracks these in its annual National Healthcare Disparities Report, aggregating data from a variety of Federal health surveys and databases. And the findings from the report are staggering, inc1uding the following: Minorities had worse access to care than whites; Blacks and Hispanics received  poorer quality care than Whites on more than 70 percent of the measures used by AHRQ; and While gains were made on approximately one-quarter of the quality indicators, disparities actually got worse for all minority populations on one-third of the quality indicators.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These system wide disparities have translated into increased burden of disease for our racial and ethnic minority populations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>HIV/AIDS is devastating our African-American communities. Blacks account for about half of all new HIV/AIDS diagnoses. In New York City, the rate of new HIV diagnoses is six times higher among Blacks than Whites. In addition, the AIDS case rate among Hispanic populations is about 3.5 times higher than that of Whites.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The incidence of asthma is highest among Puerto Rican populations, with 22 percent of these individuals receiving a diagnosis of asthma, a rate roughly double that of White populations. Although African-Americans have slightly higher rates of asthma than White populations, they experience disparities in asthma management and access to care. The emergency department visit rate for Blacks seeking asthma treatment was 350 percent higher than that of the rates for Whites, while the hospitalization  rate for Blacks with asthma was 240 percent higher than that for Whites with asthma.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One out of every 10 Asian Americans will be diagnosed with diabetes. Among all Americans with diabetes, Blacks are about two times more likely to require amputations, two to five times more likely to have kidney disease, and twice as likely to suffer from diabetes-related blindness.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The impact of health disparities are experienced not only by racial and ethnic minority communities but by all of us. They are symptomatic of the underuse and misuse of health care. And the costs associated with these disparities--such as delayed diagnoses and complications that result from lack of access to primary care--add unnecessary costs to our health care system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Minority Health Improvement and Health Disparity Elimination Act of 2007 would allow us to address healthcare disparities through a variety of mechanisms.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill will create a cultural competency clearinghouse, helping providers to understand, first of all, the concept of cultural competence, and second, how to better tailor care to their patients of diverse backgrounds. We cannot, for example, ask a person with diabetes to make changes to their diet if we do not understand what foods are part of their diet. Having a culturally competent health care system is especially important in my home State of New York, where our residents come from all  over the world. With the information that will be available in this clearinghouse, we will make it easier for both patients and providers to communicate and understand essential concepts of care.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Minority Health Improvement and Health Disparity Elimination Act will improve health professions programs that increase recruitment and retention of underrepresented minorities in the health professions. New York's population is 15 percent Black and 15.6 percent Hispanic, yet the percentage of Black physicians practicing in our State is 3.2 percent, and the percentage of Hispanic physicians practicing in our State is 2.3 percent. This bill will reauthorize the Centers of Excellence established  by the Health Resources and Services Administration, HRSA--a program that has benefited the Mt. Sinai School of Medicine--and establish new programs to train mid-career individuals in the health professions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It will codify currently existing health promotion and disease prevention activities targeted toward racial and ethnic minorities, including the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention's Racial and Ethnic Approaches to Community Health, REACH. REACH grantees working in northern Manhattan have managed to increase childhood immunization rates by 10 to 15 percent. It will also codify the Health Disparities Collaboratives program operated by HRSA, through which health centers across the country  focus on improving their treatments for specific diseases, or implementing models to improve patient care. These centers include Whitney Young Health Center in Albany, NY, which, through this collaborative, successfully helped more than 200 patients learn how to manage their asthma.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation will establish new programs to increase community health workers, address environmental health concerns, and improve outreach and enrollment, thus reducing barriers to accessing care. It will increase support for the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality's research into healthcare disparities and help to improve overall data collection.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Minority Health Improvement and Health Disparity Elimination Act will reauthorize the National Center for Minority Health and Health Disparities at the National Institutes of Health, which is designed to conduct and support health disparities research; disseminate information about disparities, and reach out to racial and ethnic minority disparity communities. Through the Center, New York University received support for its Center for the Study of Asian American Health, a collaboration between  researchers, health providers, and community organizations that is designed to reduce the disparities faced by Asian Americans in New York City.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, the legislation would reauthorize and strengthen the Office of Minority Health, OMH, at HHS, requiring it to develop a National Action Plan to address disparities in collaboration with other Federal health agencies. The OMH has provided support to New York's Office of Minority Health, as well as community-based organizations in Syracuse, Buffalo, and Lower Manhattan, and this reauthorization of the office will allow them to support and sustain more programs at the State and local level.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am excited about this legislation because I have seen what happens in communities when we come together--providers, researchers, and neighborhood leaders--to address these concerns. Last month, the University of Rochester and the Monroe County Health Department announced that an initiative to increase pneumococcal immunization rates in African-American seniors resulted in a more than 30-percent gain in immunization rates--protecting more New Yorkers against pneumonia and reducing the vaccination  disparity between Blacks and Whites.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe that the Minority Health Improvement and Health Disparity Elimination Act will allow us to create, maintain, and support this type of collaboration across the Nation. It will make a real change in the health care for our minority communities and improve the quality of care received by all Americans. I look forward to working with my colleagues in Congress to pass this legislation as quickly as possible.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="Introducing S. 1576. A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to improve the health and healthcare of racial and ethnic minority groups; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, Abraham Lincoln once said, "The declaration that `all men are created equal' is the great fundamental principle upon which our free institutions rest."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a Senator representing the distinguished land of Lincoln, I take seriously our Nation's promise for equality, particularly when it comes to health care.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise today as a strong and proud cosponsor of the Minority Health Improvement and Health Disparity Elimination Act of 2007--an important piece of legislation, long in the making, and long overdue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Not since 2000 has our Congress made a concerted effort to address the health of some of our most at-risk populations--people of color.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In these 7 years, we have not seen a substantial improvement in the health status of people of color.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Cervical cancer, a disease that can be greatly reduced by effective health care, is five times more common among Vietnamese women in the United States than it is among Caucasian women.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>African Americans with diabetes are seven times more likely to have amputations and develop kidney failure than are Caucasians with diabetes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In Chicago's Latino community, you will likely find one in two Latino children who are obese, a condition that often leads to the onset of diabetes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the hospitals of East St. Louis, it's likely that African-American babies die at more than double the rate of White infants.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the small town of Cairo, families have to travel hours to other parts of the State and sometimes even to other States to obtain the right care.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In general, we are making progress in prolonging life. Death rates for Whites, African Americans, and Latinos from many of our most debilitating diseases have declined during the last decade. But what progress are we making on quality of life during those extra years? Is the answer different depending on the racial or ethnic minority groups? Simply speaking, yes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Even when controlling for insurance coverage and economic status, racial and ethnic minorities tend to have less access to health care and a lower quality of health care than their Caucasian counterparts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention has reported that, among a wide range of health indicators, "relatively little progress has been made toward the goal of eliminating racial/ethnic disparities."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In general, yes, Americans are healthier, but the shameful gaps between minority groups and Caucasians remain nearly the same as a decade ago.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When will we as a nation demand more and work harder to reach that ideal of equality that is a pillar of our Nation's moral strength?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation is a critical step toward achieving that notion of equality: the belief that we are all created equal and as such should have equal access to quality care.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Why is it that this country spends so much more than any other industrialized country on its health care, but has consistently lagged behind other countries in delivering better health outcomes? Why is it that one in six Americans, almost one in three African Americans, almost one in two Latino Americans, are uninsured? Why do our health outcomes not reflect the $2 trillion investment we make in health care each year? There is a disconnect between the rhetoric around our Nation's health crisis  and where our resources are placed. It is a shame, and we can do better.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our health workforce should reflect, understand, and respect the backgrounds, experiences, and perspectives of the people it serves. We need to recruit, train and retain health care professionals from underrepresented groups and underserved areas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In areas like downstate Illinois, small communities rely heavily on Federal incentives, such as loan repayment, the Health Careers Opportunity Program, and Centers of Excellence to create a critical pipeline of professionals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Graduates of title VII programs are more likely to serve in underserved areas. That is the outcome we want, so we need to support successful programs like these.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to improving the diversity of our workforce, we need to redouble efforts to fight diseases that disproportionately affect racial and ethnic minorities--diseases like diabetes, heart disease, breast cancer and so many others.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To accurately respond to the presence of health care disparities and try to address them, we need better data on health care access and utilization that includes race, ethnicity, primary language, and socio-economic status. To develop accurate solutions, we need accurate information on prevalence, contributing factors, and effects of health care disparities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Minority Health Improvement and Health Disparity Elimination Act of 2007 is a critically important step toward improving the access, workforce, research and information that will close the color gap that exists in health care today. I look forward to working with my colleagues to improve the health of all Americans and, specifically, to eliminate health disparities that hurt our communities of color, and all of us.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I did not always agree with the former majority leader, Senator William H. Frist, but I couldn't agree more with his statement that, "Inequity is a cancer that can no longer be allowed to fester in health care."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support the health disparity legislation introduced today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300061" topic="Introducing S. 1577. A bill to amend titles XVIII and XIX of the Social Security Act to require screening, including national criminal history background checks, of direct patient access employees of skilled nursing facilities, nursing facilities, and other long-term facilities and providers, and to provide for nationwide expansion of the pilot program for national and State background checks on direct patient access employees of long-term care facilities or providers; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1577">S. 1577</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to introduce the Patient Safety and Abuse Prevention Act with Senators DOMENICI, MCCASKILL, STABENOW, LINCOLN, LEVIN and CLINTON. </paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill is supported by the Elder Justice Coalition, the National Citizens' Coalition for Nursing Home Reform, the American Association of Homes and Services for the Aging, AARP and many other organizations dedicated to protecting our Nation's vulnerable citizens. If enacted, this legislation could help to prevent many of the tragic tales of physical and financial elder abuse that we hear about from our constituents and read about in our local newspapers. I strongly urge this Congress to do  what the States cannot: create a nationwide system of background checks for workers who care for our Nation's frail elders and those who are living with disabilities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The vast majority of long-term care workers are selfless and dedicated. Yet there are a few with violent criminal histories who pose a clear threat to the defenseless individuals needing long-term care services. Under the disorganized, patchwork system of background checks that exists today, employers trying to hire caregivers do not always know which applicants have records of abuse or a history of committing violent crimes. As a result, predators are sometimes hired to take care of our most  vulnerable citizens, allowing them to work in situations where they can cause enormous harm. For example, in just the last 6 weeks, three stories of such elder abuse created headlines across the country:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last year, Pat Torano, at the age of 89, was partially paralyzed by a stroke. He realized he no longer could care for his 95-year-old wife, who by then was blind and suffering from dementia. Intent on staying at home, the Toranos contracted with Visiting Angels, a network of private home-care agencies that matches clients with caretakers. They expected to find an honest professional to help them with household chores and other non-medical needs. Instead they got convicted felon Gina Treveno,  who stole their house just five months later by tricking the couple into placing the deed in her name.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Attorney General Andrew M. Cuomo today announced the sentencing of William Morrison, a former aide at the Rome Memorial Hospital Residential Health Care Facility, who was convicted last month of raping and sexually assaulting a 90-year-old resident of the nursing home....... The background check would have revealed that Morrison was previously convicted for one felony drug offense in 1992 and several misdemeanors in the 1990s.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An 84-year-old man allegedly assaulted at a nursing home last month is suing the facility, claiming it failed to protect him from the employee accused of punching him in his bed. Earl Gates of Bozeman claims Evergreen Bozeman Health and Rehabilitation center didn't do a background check on his accused attacker, Joshua Fowler, 23, who has a prior assault conviction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill that I am introducing today with Senators DOMENICI, STABENOW, MCCASKILL, LINCOLN, LEVIN, and CLINTON proposes to take action to stop predators from working in all long-term care settings. It would close gaping loopholes in our current system of background checks through a nationwide expansion of a pilot program that Congress enacted as part of the Medicare Modernization Act of 2003.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under the MMA, the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services has been conducting a pilot program in seven states to implement efficient, equitable systems that cost-effectively screen out certain applicants for employment in long-term care facilities. Applicants excluded are those whose backgrounds include findings of substantiated abuse and/or a serious criminal history.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The seven pilot States are Alaska, Idaho, Illinois, Michigan, Nevada, New Mexico and Wisconsin. These States have significant flexibility in several key areas under the grant. For example, each State establishes parameters for the definition of a "direct patient access employee" for workers who must be checked, and defines specific criteria for "disqualifying" crimes that prohibit a long-term care employer from hiring workers with such histories.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In other areas, the pilot States must meet Federal standards. They must cover a broad range of long-term care providers, including nursing homes, home health agencies and intermediate care facilities for the mentally retarded. States must require each applicant to submit a written statement disclosing any disqualifying information, and to authorize a State and national criminal record check.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As is currently required under Federal law, providers must search any available registry that is likely to contain disqualifying information about an applicant. Forty-one States already require a criminal background check of some variety, mostly at the State level. The pilot States have integrated their systems to coordinate these checks in a single streamlined process and added a Federal background check through the FBI's Integrated Automated Fingerprint Identification System. Applicants who  are subsequently found to have a record of substantiated abuse or a serious criminal history cannot be hired. But individuals who are denied employment can appeal the background check results. Finally, facilities can use the results of the background checks only for the purpose of determining suitability of employment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is the basic structure of the pilot program that Congress enacted 4 years ago. Since then, we have learned important lessons from the pilot States' experiences. For example, federal funds have been used for a variety of purposes. States have used pilot funds to hire new staff to administer background checks; to purchase mobile digital scanners; to pay for the cost of fingerprint checks; to provide technical assistance to facilities; and to build online systems that applicants and providers  can readily access,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>and which serve to integrate information from various registries and entities, and as storage and retrieval systems.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>States have passed legislation under the pilot program that treat disqualifying crimes somewhat differently. For example, Michigan has created a tiered system, under which certain disqualifying crimes carry time-limited prohibitions on working in long-term care facilities. By comparison, Wisconsin has chosen to enact legislation defining disqualifying crimes as those that carry a lifetime ban only. Alaska has established a "variance" process to permit certain individuals to work who have committed  crimes but who have subsequently shown evidence of recovery. Similarly, in Idaho, some disqualifying crimes result in an "unconditional" denial that carries a lifetime ban on working in long-term care settings, while others result in "conditional" denials that apply to less serious crimes that may be waived under certain circumstances, following an "exemption review" by the Department of Health and Welfare.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The data on results from the pilot programs are impressive. Among the seven States, Michigan's information is the most complete. In the first year of operation, Michigan excluded more than 3,000 people with records of abuse or a disqualifying criminal history. As of April 30, 2007, 625 of these were excluded through a fingerprint check. Twenty-five percent of these exclusions were identified through an FBI check only, a fact that State officials believe indicates that these individuals committed  crimes in other States, or have been avoiding prosecution within the State. Information for Nevada, while less complete, suggests similar results. As of last December, Nevada was identifying an even higher percentage of individuals with criminal histories on the basis of an FBI check only.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The director of Michigan's workforce background check program, Orlene Christie, recently testified before the Special Committee on Aging about the State's program. "The applicants that have been excluded from employment are not the types of people Michigan could ever allow to work with our most vulnerable citizens," she said. "We have prevented hardened criminals that otherwise would have access to our vulnerable population from employment."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ms. Christie also noted that "of the criminal history reports examined, fraudulent activity and controlled substance violations account for 25 percent of all disqualifying crimes. Fraudulent activity includes such things as embezzlement, identity theft, and credit card fraud. This is particularly alarming giving the projected increase in financial abuse of the elderly."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Importantly, Michigan has implemented a "rap back" system where the Michigan State Police notifies the health agency of any subsequent arrest, which in turn notifies the employer. This is a key component of the bill we are introducing today. It will allow the States, as well as the FBI, to ensure that an employer will be automatically notified as soon as a worker's criminal history record is updated.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To find out what providers think of the pilot program, Idaho conducted a survey of participating facilities, which found 87 percent believed the background checks were successfully screening out workers who shouldn't be hired. Additionally, 63 percent said that the quality of employees hired has improved since the pilot began.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The pilot program demonstrates that participating States are successfully excluding individuals who have a history of abuse or a disqualifying criminal background. If this model is expanded, the resulting nationwide system would greatly enhance the probability of identifying individuals with criminal backgrounds who can now easily escape detection. If all States had parallel, multi-level, comprehensive systems in place, very few potentially abusive workers would be hired into positions of caring  for the extremely vulnerable residents of our Nation's long-term care facilities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The MMA pilot program is scheduled to end this September. I urge the Senate not to let this initiative simply expire. Rather, I hope that we will take the logical step of expanding on the success of this program, and provide limited federal funding for all other States to create similar programs. The Patient Safety and Abuse Prevention Act also lays out sensible standards for creating a nationwide system that will prevent predators, who now go undetected, from being hired into positions where  they can harm society's most vulnerable people. I sincerely hope that all of my colleagues will join me in this effort.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the bill and supporting material be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, material was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300056" topic="Introducing S. 1578. A bill to amend the Nonindigenous Aquatic Nuisance Prevention and Control Act of 1990 to establish vessel ballast water management requirements, and or other purposes; to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1578">S. 1578</bill>] Mr. President, the United States has more than 95,000 miles of coastline, and its ocean territory is larger than the combined land area of all 50 States. We rely on our oceans for such diverse benefits as recreation, food, transportation, and energy. All Americans, regardless of whether they reside in the Nation's heartland or along the coast, are impacted by the ocean.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is why I rise today, joined by Vice Chairman TED STEVENS and several other Commerce Committee colleagues, in introducing a group of bills to provide for sustainable use and protection of our ocean and coastal areas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our oceans and coasts provide us with tremendous economic and recreational opportunities. It is critical that use of ocean resources and coasts is sustainable and that we address the many existing and emerging risks to their well-being. As the U.S. Commission on Ocean Policy has thoroughly documented, our oceans and coasts are faced with many threats, including those posed by pollution, increasing population growth and coastal development, overfishing, climate change, and ocean acidification.  All of the bills my colleagues and I are introducing today implement recommendations of the Ocean Commission.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, the Coral Reef Conservation Amendments Act of 2007 would reauthorize the Coral Reef Conservation Act of 2000 and provide critical authorities for preserving, restoring, and managing in a sustainable manner our coral reef ecosystems. Coral reefs are one of the oldest and most diverse ecosystems on the planet, and they provide environmental and economic benefits such as shoreline protection as well as critical habitat for approximately half of all federally-managed fisheries.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second, the Hydrographic Services Improvement Act Amendments of 2007 would reauthorize and strengthen authorities to survey and analyze the physical condition of our Nation's coasts and waterways, along with elements that impact safe navigation. Conducting surveys of our Nation's coasts and waterways is a core mission for the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and provides valuable services to the maritime industry and to Federal agencies responsible for maritime transportation,  homeland security, and emergency response.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Third, the Ballast Water Management Act of 2007 would amend the Nonindigenous Aquatic Nuisance Prevention and Control Act of 1990 and establish ballast water management requirements to mitigate the introduction and spread of invasive species from ships. The bill would also seek to prevent the introduction of invasive species from ship equipment or hulls. Invasive species brought into the United States from other countries have caused billions of dollars in damage to the U.S. economy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to the initiatives I have highlighted, a number of other ocean-related bills are being introduced today by colleagues on the Commerce Committee. These include a bill by Senator Lautenberg to establish a much-needed Federal program to conduct research, monitoring, and education to examine the processes and consequences of ocean acidification, and a bill by Senator Snowe to reauthorize the Coastal Zone Management Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This week we celebrate Capitol Hill Ocean Week. Many organizations and agencies are using this opportunity to educate and raise public awareness about the impact of our oceans on our society and economy. The bills that my colleagues and I are introducing today address many of those needs being highlighted. I urge my Senate colleagues to support the Commerce Committee's bipartisan efforts to improve the health and management of our oceans and coasts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300091" topic="Introducing S. 1579. A bill to amend the Coastal Zone Management Act; to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1579">S. 1579</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to introduce the Coastal Zone Enhancement Reauthorization Act of 2007. I am pleased to have my colleague, Senator Cantwell, join me in cosponsoring this bill, which will enable our Nation to improve the management of our valuable, yet vulnerable, coastal resources.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>More than half of all Americans reside in coastal zones, and each year their number grows by more than 3,600. Yet, coastal regions comprise just 17 percent of the land area in the contiguous United States. People are drawn to our oceans and Great Lakes to experience the economic opportunities, natural beauty, and recreational bounty that these regions have to offer. Part of that value, both the tangible and intangible, comes from the habitat these ecosystems provide for a variety of plants and  animals, ranging from rare microscopic organisms to commercially valuable fish stocks. As population pressures increase, we must work diligently to maintain a balance between human use of these delicate regions and their natural, ecological functions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When Congress passed the CZMA in 1972, it established a unique State-Federal framework for facilitating sound coastal planning. The law gives States the opportunity to create a coastal zone management plan which, once approved, makes States eligible for matching Federal funds to carry out the goals of its plan. This system allows States to tailor plans to their individual needs, but permits the Federal Government to ensure that marine resources, which often overlap political boundaries, are managed  responsibly nationwide. As a result of this program's success, more than 99.9 percent of the United States' 95,376 shoreline miles are managed under this system, including, 34 of the 35 coastal and Great Lakes states and territories. The 35th, Illinois, has submitted a plan for Federal approval.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The CZMA has not been reauthorized in over a decade, and the program has been operating with authorization levels and mandates that expired in 1999. Much has changed in the interim, and persistent threats to coastal areas, such as increasing rates of nonpoint source water pollution and constriction of working waterfront areas, have out-paced states' abilities to maintain an appropriate balance between development and conservation. The Coastal Zone Enhancement Reauthorization Act of 2007 would  encourage states to take additional voluntary steps to combat these problems through the Coastal Community Program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Each year, we also learn more about threats to our coasts from impacts of global climate change, yet the CZMA currently provides no foundation to manage these problems. Mounting evidence indicates that increasing concentrations of atmospheric carbon dioxide, approximately a third of which is absorbed in our oceans, is affecting marine chemistry and acidifying sea water. As global temperatures rise, we are also experiencing an increase in ocean temperatures which can affect the migratory patterns  and range of marine species distribution. The problems of potential sea level rise have also been well-documented in academic journals and the mainstream media. The bill I introduce today contains a provision giving states the authority to adapt their coastal zone management plans to address these potential impacts and develop potential mitigation and adaptation measures.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Coastal Zone Enhancement Reauthorization of 2007 also significantly increases the authorization levels for the Coastal Zone Management Program, enabling States to better achieve their coastal management goals. The bill authorizes $170 million for fiscal year 2008 and increases the authorization levels to $193.5 million for fiscal year 2012. This adjustment in funding  would enable the States' coastal programs to achieve their full potential.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Coastal Zone Management Program has a long record of helping states achieve their coastal area management goals by enhancing their ability to maintain clean, safe, and productive coastlines that ultimately serve the best interest of our Nation. This program enjoys widespread support among coastal States, as demonstrated by the near unanimous participation by eligible States, and the many Commerce Committee members who have worked with me to strengthen this program over the past several years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am pleased to introduce this legislation that would provide our coastal states with the funding and management frameworks necessary to meet the ever-increasing conservation and development challenges facing our coastal communities, and I urge my colleagues to support it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Additionally, as Ranking Member of the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation's subcommittee on Oceans, Atmosphere, Fisheries, and Coast Guard, I would like to commend my colleagues for their hard work that has resulted in today's introduction of six ocean-related bills. As you are aware, we are in the midst of Capitol Hill Oceans Week, and I am pleased that we can commemorate that occasion by bringing these critical marine issues to the fore. I look forward to working with my fellow  Committee members and the rest of the Senate as we improve management of our Nation's invaluable coastal and ocean resources for the benefit of all Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300064" topic="Introducing S. 1581. A bill to establish an interagency committee to develop an ocean acidification research and monitoring plan and to establish an ocean acidification program within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration; to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1581">S. 1581</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to introduce legislation that would establish a comprehensive Federal research plan and program to address ocean acidification, which poses a growing threat to the health of our oceans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our oceans help reduce global warming by absorbing carbon dioxide from the atmosphere. To date, about one-third of all human-generated carbon emissions have dissolved into the ocean. However, the increase in carbon dioxide lowers ocean pH, and causes the oceans to become more acidic. This increase in acidity is corrosive to marine shells and organisms that form the base of the food chain for many fish and marine mammals. These changes in ocean chemistry also threaten coral reef ecosystems, habitats  so rich in biodiversity they are called he rain forests of the sea. Even a mild increase in ocean acidity could make these organisms more vulnerable to disease, pollution and other environmental stresses. If the acidic conditions increase significantly, marine shells could actually begin to dissolve.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ocean acidification demands our immediate attention. Current projections of carbon dioxide emissions suggest that the acidity of our oceans is likely to accelerate significantly in the coming years. NOAA scientists have said that ocean acidity has increased 30 percent since the industrial revolution and they estimate by the end of this century the acidity of the oceans may increase 150 percent. They also project that current trends could result in a decrease in ocean pH to the lowest levels in  20 million years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ocean acidification threatens our marine ecosystems and could result in significant social and economic costs. The rich biodiversity of marine organisms is an important contribution to the national economy providing food, tourism, and aesthetic benefits, but they are vulnerable to human activity. Ocean acidification threatens fish and all calcifying organisms including corals, scallops, clams, crabs, lobsters, and plankton.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is important to note the potential economic impacts of ocean acidification. Coastal and marine commercial fishing generates upwards of $30 billion per year and employs nearly 70,000 people. Many of these fisheries also rely upon healthy coral habitats. Increased ocean acidification reduces the ability of corals and shellfish to produce their skeletons. Globally, coral reefs are home to more than 4,000 kinds of fish, and generate $30 billion per year in fishing, tourism, and protection to coasts  from storms. Scientists have estimated that, due to excess carbon dioxide in the oceans, corals may be unable to form their skeletons by mid-century, and could begin to dissolve by the end of this century. Destroying these ecosystems will have staggering environmental, social and economic consequences.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, ocean acidification directly threatens numerous commercially and recreationally important fish and shellfish species from coast to coast. Carbon dioxide-rich waters have been shown to decrease the body weight of Pacific salmon and increase the mortality rate of Alaskan blue king crab. Over 50 percent of our commercial catch in the United States is shellfish. In New Jersey, sea scallops and clams are some of the State's most valuable fisheries, valued at $121 million. These and other  important shellfish species are threatened by growing acidification.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Research on the processes and consequences of ocean acidification is still in its infancy. The urgency of developing interagency collaboration to address this far-reaching environmental problem is widely recognized in the scientific community. In January, the Administration Ocean Research Priorities Plan, ORPP, identified ocean acidification as a research priority. Consistent with the ORPP, my legislation will establish a comprehensive research and monitoring program within the National Oceanic  and Atmospheric Administration, NOAA. This is critical for ocean management in the long-term because many questions on the effect of increasing atmospheric carbon dioxide on ocean chemistry and marine life remain unanswered.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My legislation also establishes an interagency committee to develop a comprehensive ocean acidification research and monitoring plan designed to improve the understanding of the environmental and economic impacts of increased ocean acidification. The plan will identify priority research areas and strengthen relevant programs within our federal agencies. The plan will also address commercially and recreationally important species, as well as vulnerable ecosystems including coral reefs and coastal  and polar oceans threatened by acidification.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The rise of carbon dioxide in our atmosphere has been measured continuously since 1958. Known as the "Keeling Curve", these measurements are a cornerstone of our understanding of man-made increases in carbon dioxide causing global warming and ocean acidification. It is vital that we establish a program for long-term global measurements of ocean pH to understand the processes and consequences of ocean acidification. A key component in our bill directs federal agencies to establish a long-term  monitoring program of pH levels in the ocean utilizing existing global ocean observing assets.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress has been hearing from our Nation experts on ocean acidification since 2004. Now is the time for national investment in a coordinated program of research and monitoring to improve understanding of ocean acidification, and strengthen the ability of marine resource managers to assess and prepare for the harmful impacts of ocean acidification on our marine resources.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to thank Senator Cantwell for her cosponsorship and support on this important issue. I look forward to working with my colleagues in the Senate to ensure passage of this legislation so that we can fill this vital research need and protect our valuable marine resources.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
</record>
