<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1184299200" ordinal="34" title="HONORING LADY BIRD JOHNSON">
  <narrative>HONORING LADY BIRD JOHNSON -- (Senate - July 13, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="9225">S9225</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of <bill type="sr" number="271">S. Res. 271</bill>, submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="271">S. Res. 271</bill>) honoring Lady Bird Johnson.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table, and that any statements relating to the resolution be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="271">S. Res. 271</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="271">S. Res. 271</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas Americans throughout the nation are mourning the passing of Claudia Taylor (Lady Bird) Johnson, who served as First Lady with honor and grace during the Administration of her husband, President Lyndon Baines Johnson;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Mrs. Johnson was born near Karnack, Texas and received the nickname "Lady Bird" as a young child;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Lady Bird Johnson was known as an excellent student and graduated from the University of Texas;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Lady Bird Johnson met Lyndon Johnson in 1934 and the 2 were married later that year;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Lady Bird Johnson was a successful businesswoman who helped build a small radio station into a multimillion-dollar radio and television enterprise;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas throughout her husband's political career in Congress and the White House, Lady Bird Johnson played an important supportive role as a partner and confidante;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas as wife of the Vice President, Lady Bird Johnson visited 33 foreign countries as an ambassador of goodwill;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, as First Lady, Lady Bird Johnson earned widespread respect and affection not only for the tone of dignity with which she represented her husband and the Nation, but for her active involvement in efforts to serve the public, such as her work to improve the environment and to address the problem of poverty in the United States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas millions of travelers and commuters have Lady Bird Johnson to thank for the colorful flowers that line many of our roads, which represent a living, lasting legacy of the woman who guided the Highway Beautification Act of 1965 (23 U.S.C. 131, 135 note, 136, 319) into law;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas after leaving the White House, Lady Bird Johnson continued to serve the Nation in many ways, including helping to found the National Wildflower Research Center, supporting the Lyndon Baines Johnson Library, and serving on the Board of the National Geographic Society as a trustee emeritus; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, in addition to her service to the Nation, Lady Bird Johnson was a devoted and loving mother to her 2 daughters, Lynda Bird and Luci Baines, as well as her 7 grandchildren and 10 great-grandchildren: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) notes with deep sorrow and solemn mourning the death of Claudia Taylor (Lady Bird) Johnson;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) extends its heartfelt sympathy to Mrs. Johnson's family;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) honors and, on behalf of the nation, expresses deep appreciation for Lady Bird Johnson's important service to her country; and</chair>
  <chair> (4) directs the Secretary of the Senate to transmit a copy of this resolution to the family of Mrs. Johnson. &lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
