<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1185249600" ordinal="55" title="NOTICES OF HEARINGS">
  <narrative>NOTICES OF HEARINGS -- (Senate - July 24, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="9851">S9851</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND NATURAL RESOURCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to announce for the information of the Senate and the public that an oversight hearing has been scheduled before the Subcommittee on Energy of the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The hearing will be held on Tuesday, July 31, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of this hearing is to receive testimony on renewable fuels infrastructure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of the limited time available for the hearing, witnesses may testify by invitation only. However, those wishing to submit written testimony for the hearing record should send two copies of their testimony to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, United States Senate, Washington, DC 20510-6150, or by e-mail to britni Xrillera@energy.senate.gov.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For further information, please contact Tara Billingsley or Britni Rillera.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to announce for the information of the Senate and the public that an oversight hearing has been scheduled before the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The hearing will be held on Wednesday, August 1, 2007, at 9:30 a.m. in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of this hearing is to receive testimony on recent advances in clean coal technology, including the prospects for deploying these technologies at a commercial scale in the near future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of the limited time available for the hearing, witnesses may testify by invitation only. However, those wishing to submit written testimony for the hearing record should send two copies of their testimony to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, United States Senate, Washington, DC 20510-6150, or by e-mail to rachel Xpasternack@energy.senate.gov.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For further information, please contact Michael Carr or Rachel Pasternack.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to announce for the information of the Senate and the public that an oversight hearing has been scheduled before the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The hearing will be held on Tuesday, August 7, 2007, from 9 to 11 a.m., in the Galisteo Room of the Albuquerque Convention Center, 401 2nd Street, Albuquerque, New Mexico.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of this hearing is to receive testimony on Reducing Barriers to Growth of Emerging Energy Technologies--Relationships Between Federal, State and Local Governments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of the limited time available for the hearing, witnesses may testify by invitation only. However, those wishing to submit written testimony for the hearing record should send two copies of their testimony to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, United States Senate, Washington, DC 20510-6150, or by e-mail to rachel Xpasternack@energy.senate.gov.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For further information, please contact Jonathan Epstein or Rachel Pasternack.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300037" topic="COMMITTEE ON INDIAN AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to announce that the Committee on Indian Affairs will meet on Thursday, July 26, 2007, at 9:30 a.m. in room 485 of the Russell Senate Office Building to conduct a hearing on the nomination of Charles W. Grim to be Director of the Indian Health Service.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Those wishing additional information may contact the Indian Affairs Committee at 224-2251.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
