<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1171386003" ordinal="33" title="SUBMITTED RESOLUTIONS">
  <speaking speaker="300042" topic="SENATE CONCURRENT RESOLUTION 11--PROVIDING THAT ANY AGREEMENT RELATING TO TRADE AND INVESTMENT THAT IS NEGOTIATED BY THE EXECUTIVE BRANCH WITH ANOTHER COUNTRY COMPLY WITH CERTAIN MINIMUM STANDARDS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I am pleased to again submit a measure to begin to address one of the central problems our Nation faces, namely the loss of family-supporting jobs because of our flawed trade policies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today's announcement that the U.S. trade deficit for 2006 rose to $764 billion, setting a record for the fifth consecutive year, is a stark reminder of just how seriously flawed our trade policies are. Those policies have far reaching consequences, and they require a multifaceted response.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One response must be to take on the trade deficit directly, and I have been pleased to join the Senator from North Dakota, Mr. Dorgan, to do just that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But we also must change the agreements into which we enter with our trading partners.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The record of the major trade agreements into which our Nation has entered over the past few years has been dismal. Thanks in great part to the flawed fast track rules that govern consideration of legislation implementing trade agreements, the United States has entered into a number of trade agreements that have contributed to the significant job loss we have seen in recent years, and have laid open to assault various laws and regulations established to protect workers, the environment, and our  health and safety. Indeed, those agreements undermine the very democratic institutions through which we govern ourselves.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The loss of jobs, especially manufacturing jobs, to other countries has been devastating to Wisconsin, and to the entire country. When I opposed the North American Free Trade Agreement, the Uruguay round of the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade,  Permanent Normal Trade Relations for China, and other flawed trade measures, I did so in great part because I believed they would lead to a significant loss of jobs. But even as an opponent of those agreements,  I don't think I could have imagined just how bad things would get in so short a time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The trade policy of this country over the past several years has been appalling. The trade agreements into which we have entered have contributed to the loss of key employers, ravaging entire communities. But despite that clear evidence, we continue to see trade agreements being reached that will only aggravate this problem.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This has to stop. We cannot afford to pursue trade policies that gut our manufacturing sector and send good jobs overseas. We cannot afford to undermine the safeguards we have established for workers, the environment, and our public health and safety. And we cannot afford to chip way at our democratic heritage by entering into trade agreements that supercede our right to govern ourselves through open, democratic institutions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation I am introducing today addresses this problem, at least in part. It establishes some minimum standards for the trade agreements into which our Nation enters. It sets forth principles for future trade agreements. It is a break with the so-called NAFTA model, and instead advocates the kinds of sound trade policies that will spur economic growth and sustainable development.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The principles set forth in this resolution are not complex. They are straightforward and achievable. The resolution calls for enforceable worker protections, including the core International Labor Organization standards.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It preserves the ability of the United States to enact and enforce its own trade laws.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It protects foreign investors, but states that foreign investors should not be provided with greater rights than those provided under U.S. law, and it protects public interest laws from challenge by foreign investors in secret tribunals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It ensures that food entering into our country meets domestic food safety standards.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It preserves the ability of Federal, State, and local governments to maintain essential public services and to regulate private sector services in the public interest.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It requires that trade agreements contain environmental provisions subject to the same enforcement as commercial provisions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It preserves the right of Federal, State, and local governments to use procurement as a policy tool, including through Buy American laws, environmental laws such as recycled content, and purchasing preferences for small, minority, or women-owned businesses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It requires that trade negotiations and the implementation of trade agreements be conducted openly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These are sensible policies, and will advance the goal of increased international commerce.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The outgrowth of the major trade agreements into which we have entered has been a race to the bottom in labor standards, environmental standards, health and safety standards, in nearly every aspect of our economy. A race to the bottom is a race in which even the winners lose.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For any who doubt this, I invite you to ask the families in Wisconsin who have watched their jobs move to China.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We can't let this continue to happen. We need to turn our trade policies around. We need to pursue trade agreements that will promote sustainable economic growth for our Nation and for our trading partners. This resolution will begin to put us on that path, and I urge my colleagues to support it.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
