<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1192464001" ordinal="18" title="SUPPORTING THE WORK OF FIREFIGHTERS">
  <narrative>SUPPORTING THE WORK OF FIREFIGHTERS -- (Senate - October 15, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="12853">S12853</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the consideration of <bill type="sr" number="345">S. Res. 345</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="345">S. Res. 345</bill>) supporting the work of firefighters to educate and protect the Nation's communities, and the goals and ideals of Fire Prevention Week, October 7-13, 2007, as designated by the National Fire Protection Association.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="345">S. Res. 345</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="345">S. Res. 345</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas firefighters have maintained their dedication to the health and safety of the American public since the first American fire departments were organized in the colonial era;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas today's firefighters provide a multitude of services, including emergency medical services, special rescue response, hazardous material and terrorism response, and public safety education;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas more than 1,130,000 firefighters protect the United States through their heroic service;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Nation's fire departments respond to emergency calls nearly once per second and dispatch to fire emergencies every 20 seconds;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas approximately 1,600,000 fires are reported annually;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas firefighters respond with courage to all disasters, whether they be acts of terrorism, natural disasters, or other emergencies;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas 343 firefighters sacrificed their lives responding heroically to the events of September 11, 2001;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas firefighters from across the Nation responded with remarkable selflessness throughout the areas affected by Hurricane Katrina;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas 89 firefighters lost their lives in 2006, and over 80,000 were injured in the line of duty;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas we have honored firefighters for educating the American public since President Harding declared the first Fire Prevention Week in 1922;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the National Fire Protection Association has designated the week of October 7-13, 2007 as Fire Prevention Week; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas educating Americans on methods of fire prevention and escape planning continues to be a priority for all firefighters: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) supports the work of firefighters to educate and protect the Nation's communities; and</chair>
  <chair> (2) supports the goals and ideals of Fire Prevention Week, October 7-13, 2007, as designated by the National Fire Protection Association.  &lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
