<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1212768002" ordinal="6" title="MORNING BUSINESS">
  <narrative>MORNING BUSINESS -- (Senate - June 06, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="5350">S5350</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that there now be a period for the transaction of morning business, with Senators permitted to speak for up to 10 minutes each, and that Senator Chambliss be the first to be recognized.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, reserving the right to object, but I will not object, I ask to have printed in the Record a statement by Senator McCain. If he were here, he would have voted for cloture.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300071" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today, Senator JOHN MCCAIN released the following statement on <bill type="s" number="3036">S. 3036</bill>, the Lieberman-Warner Climate Security Act of 2008:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Global climate change is the most important environmental challenge facing not only our nation, but the entire world. I am confident that given the will, the federal government can be a lead advocate for ensuring that America is doing its part to reduce global warming, and join in the global effort that is needed to address this world-wide environmental issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Like many of my colleagues, I believe this legislation needs to be debated, amended, improved, and ultimately, enacted. While my schedule precludes me from being in Washington, DC, tomorrow to cast my vote, if I were able, I would vote to invoke cloture on the substitute amendment. That does not mean I believe the pending bill is perfect, and in fact, it is far from it. For example, the provisions to impose Davis Bacon mandates should be removed. Most importantly, it must include provisions championed  by Senator Graham and myself that would ensure that nuclear power, a proven and clean energy source, is included among the technologies supported in our efforts to address global warming. Nuclear energy is an emission-free source of electricity for the nation, which is why it simply must be part of the comprehensive solution to addressing climate change, and if it is not, I could not support the legislation's final passage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, despite the commitment and tireless efforts of the bill sponsors, Senators LIEBERMAN and WARNER, it appears that for now, the Senate, at the direction of the Majority Leader, will choose to put politics above policy, and Congress will fail to act yet again on this critical issue. But rest assured, we will not give up until we finally succeed in enacting needed, comprehensive cap and trade legislation to address this urgent problem.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from California.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I thank our colleagues. I wish to say, in addition to the names Senator Warner put in yesterday, we had statements from Senators OBAMA, CLINTON, BIDEN, and KENNEDY, which means if all had been here, the vote would have been 54 votes. We are very pleased with this and we thank them very much.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Georgia.</chair>
</record>
