<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1228842003" ordinal="33" title="DRIVE SAFER SUNDAY">
  <narrative>DRIVE SAFER SUNDAY -- (Senate - December 09, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="10835">S10835</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Judiciary Committee be discharged from further consideration of <bill type="sr" number="718">S. Res. 718</bill> and the Senate proceed to its immediate consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will report the resolution by title.</narrative>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="718">S. Res. 718</bill>) designating November 30, 2008, as "Drive Safer Sunday."</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="718">S. Res. 718</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="718">S. Res. 718</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas motor vehicle travel is the primary means of transportation in the United States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas everyone driving on the roads and highways needs to do so more safely to reduce deaths and injuries resulting from motor vehicle accidents;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, according to the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, wearing a seat belt saved 15,434 lives in 2004, 15,632 lives in 2005, and 15,383 lives in 2006;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Secretary of Transportation Mary Peters has urged all people of the United States to understand the life-saving importance of wearing a seat belt and has encouraged motorists to drive safely, not just during the holiday season, but each time they get behind the wheel; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Sunday after Thanksgiving is the busiest highway traffic day of the year: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) encourages--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) high schools, colleges, universities, administrators, teachers, primary schools, and secondary schools to launch campus-wide educational campaigns to urge students to drive safely;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) national trucking firms to alert truck drivers to focus on driving safely on the Sunday after Thanksgiving, and to publicize the importance of the day using Citizen's Band ("CB") radios and truck stops across the United States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) clergy to remind members to travel safely en route to religious services and gatherings;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (D) law enforcement personnel to remind drivers and passengers to drive safely on the Sunday after Thanksgiving; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (E) all people of the United States to use the Sunday after Thanksgiving as an opportunity to educate themselves about highway safety; and</chair>
  <chair> (2) designates November 30, 2008, as "Drive Safer Sunday".&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
