<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1190822402" ordinal="21" title="CHILDREN'S HEALTH INSURANCE PROGRAM REAUTHORIZATION ACT OF 2007">
  <narrative>CHILDREN'S HEALTH INSURANCE PROGRAM REAUTHORIZATION ACT OF 2007 -- (Senate - September 26, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="12122">S12122</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask the Chair lay before the Senate the message from the House to accompany <bill type="h" number="976">H.R. 976</bill>, the children's health insurance bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Presiding Officer laid before the Senate the following message from the House of Representatives:</narrative>
  <narrative>Resolved, That the House agree to the amendments of the Senate to the bill (<bill type="h" number="976">H.R. 976</bill>) "an Act to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1968 to provide tax relief for small businesses, and for other purposes," with amendments.</narrative>
  <narrative>CLOTURE MOTION &lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I move to concur with the House amendment, and I send a cloture motion to the desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The cloture motion having been presented under rule XXII, the Chair directs the clerk to read the motion.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>Cloture Motion</narrative>
  <narrative>We, the undersigned Senators, in accordance with the provisions of rule XXII of the Standing Rules of the Senate, do hereby move to bring to a close debate on the motion to concur in the House amendments to the Senate amendments to <bill type="h" number="976">H.R. 976</bill>, SCHIP.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask the mandatory quorum call under rule XXII be waived.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I move to concur in the first House amendment, with the amendment that is at the desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>The Senator from Nevada [Mr. REID] proposes an amendment numbered 3071 to the House amendment to the text of <bill type="h" number="976">H.R. 976</bill>.</narrative>
  <narrative>The amendment is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>At the end of the amendment add the following:</narrative>
  <narrative>This section shall take effect 3 days after date of enactment.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask for the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there a sufficient second? There appears to be a sufficient second.</chair>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask now that the clerk report the second-degree amendment which is at the desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>The Senator from Nevada [Mr. Reid] proposes an amendment numbered 3072 to amendment No. 3071.</narrative>
  <narrative>In the amendment strike 3 and insert 1.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I think I interrupted my distinguished friend. Did he have more business to conduct?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Republican leader is recognized.</chair>
</record>
