<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1189180801" ordinal="36" title="ESTABLISHMENT OF A MUSEUM OF THE HISTORY OF AMERICAN DIPLOMACY">
  <narrative>ESTABLISHMENT OF A MUSEUM OF THE HISTORY OF AMERICAN DIPLOMACY -- (Senate - September 07, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="11279">S11279</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400050" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of Calendar No. 243, <bill type="sr" number="253">S. Res. 253</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="253">S. Res. 253</bill>) expressing the sense of the Senate that the establishment of a Museum of the History of American Diplomacy through private donations is a worthy endeavor.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400050" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table, and that any statements relating thereto be printed in the Record, without further intervening action or debate.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="253">S. Res. 253</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="253">S. Res. 253</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas the role of diplomacy in the foreign policy of the United States deserves recognition;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the day-to-day efforts of American diplomats serving in overseas embassies and in the United States also deserve recognition;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, in 1998, the Department of State began to explore the feasibility of establishing a Museum of the History of American Diplomacy (in this resolution referred to as the "Museum");&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Foreign Affairs Museum Council (in this resolution referred to as the "Council"), a 501(c)(3) charitable foundation, was created subsequently to raise funds for the Museum through donations from private sector organizations, former diplomats, and concerned citizens;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas no taxpayer funds will be used for the establishment of the Museum;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas former Secretaries of State Henry Kissinger, Alexander Haig, George Schultz, James Baker III, Lawrence Eagleburger, Warren Christopher, Madeleine Albright, and Colin Powell serve as Honorary Directors of the Council;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas experienced and noteworthy diplomats and foreign policy experts, including Elizabeth Bagley, Keith Brown, Frank Carlucci, Elinor Constable, Leslie Gelb, William Harrop, Arthur Hartman, Herbert Hansell, Stephen Low, Thomas Pickering, Richard Solomon, and Terence Todman, serve on the Board of Directors of the Council;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas former members of the Senate, including the Honorable Paul Sarbanes, and of the House of Representatives, including the Honorable Lee Hamilton, also serve on the Board of Directors of the Council;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Honorable Charles "Mac" Mathias, a former Senator and member of the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, is the Chairperson of the Board of Directors of the Council;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Council has already raised over $1,300,000 through private donations; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas $300,000 has been spent to complete an initial concept design for the Museum: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That it is the sense of the Senate that--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) the diplomats of the United States serving overseas and in the United States are in many cases the front line of our national security policy;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) the people of the United States deserve a better understanding of the efforts of these brave men and women;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) talented young people and their families should be encouraged to consider careers in foreign affairs as an important contribution to their country;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) the establishment of a Museum of the History of American Diplomacy that highlights the work of these men and women throughout the history of the United States is a worthy endeavor; and</chair>
  <chair> (5) the current plan of the Foreign Affairs Museum Council to fund the museum through private donations is appropriate and deserves the support of the Department of State.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
