<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1211299202" ordinal="24" title="EXECUTIVE SESSION">
  <narrative>EXECUTIVE SESSION -- (Senate - May 20, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="4440">S4440</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300087" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I now ask unanimous consent that the Senate resume executive session.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The Senator from Florida.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400621" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I wish to speak on the executive business of the Senate. I am proud today to speak on behalf of my brother, Ralph Martinez, who has been nominated by the President.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The minority has no time remaining.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400621" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that I be allowed 3 minutes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400621" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, my brother, Ralph Martinez, has been nominated by the President to be a member of the Foreign Claims Settlement Commission of the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am extremely proud of Ralph. He is someone, such as myself, who has adopted this country as his own and who, after the struggles of all immigrants, succeeded in life. He is the proud father of three wonderful children and has raised a wonderful family. He also has excelled in the practice of law in central Florida. I am delighted he is going to have an opportunity to serve this Nation in this very important capacity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am also delighted to thank Leader Reid and Leader McConnell for expediting his confirmation, as well as Chairman Leahy and Ranking Member Specter for their courtesies throughout this process for Ralph Martinez.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I know he will serve this Nation well. I am proud to second his nomination and urge the Senate to confirm him swiftly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I yield the floor. I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Will the Senator withhold?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400621" topic="">
    <paragraph>Yes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
