<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1171515600" ordinal="70" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="COMMITTEE ON ARMED SERVICES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, February 15, 2007, at 9:30 a.m., in open and closed sessions to receive testimony on the current and future readiness of the Army and Marine Corps.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Thursday, February 15, 2007, at 9:30 a.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building. The purpose of the hearing is to evaluate the administration's proposal to reauthorize the Federal Aviation Administration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND NATURAL RESOURCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Thursday, February 15, 2007, at 9:30 a.m. in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building. The purpose of the hearing is to consider the President's proposed budget for FY 2008 for the Department of the Interior.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="COMMITTEE ON FINANCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Finance be authorized to meet during the session on Thursday, February 15, 2007, at 10 a.m., in 215 Dirksen Senate Office Building, to hear testimony on "The Administration's 2007 Trade Agenda."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, February 15, 2007, at 9:15 a.m. to hold a nomination hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="COMMITTEE ON HOMELAND SECURITY AND GOVERNMENTAL AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs be authorized to meet on Thursday, February 15, 2007, at 9 a.m. for a business meeting to consider pending committee business.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Agenda</paragraph>
    <paragraph>1. <bill type="s" number="4">S. 4</bill>, Improving America's Security by Implementing Unfinished Recommendations of the 9/11 Commission Act of 2007;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>2. <bill type="s" number="343">S. 343</bill>, a bill to extend the District of Columbia College Access Act of 1999;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>3. <bill type="s" number="457">S. 457</bill>, a bill to extend the date on which the National Security Personnel System will first apply to certain defense laboratories;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>4. <bill type="s" number="550">S. 550</bill>, a bill to preserve existing judgeships on the Superior Court of the District of Columbia.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>1. <bill type="s" number="171">S. 171</bill>, to designate the facility of the USPS located at 301 Commerce Street in Commerce, Oklahoma, as the "Mickey Mantle Post Office Building;"</paragraph>
    <paragraph>2. <bill type="s" number="194">S. 194</bill>/H.R. 49, to designate the facility of the USPS located at 1300 North Frontage Road West in Vail, Colorado, as the "Gerald R. Ford Jr. Post Office Building;"</paragraph>
    <paragraph>3. <bill type="s" number="219">S. 219</bill>/H.R. 335, to designate the facility of the USPS located at 152 North 5th Street in Laramie, Wyoming, as the "Gale W. McGee Post Office;"</paragraph>
    <paragraph>4. <bill type="s" number="303">S. 303</bill>, to designate the facility of the USPS located at 324 Main Street in Grambling, Louisiana, as the "Coach Eddie Robinson Post Office Building;"</paragraph>
    <paragraph>5. <bill type="s" number="412">S. 412</bill>/H.R. 521, to designate the facility of the USPS located at 2633 11th Street in Rock Island, Illinois, as the "Lane Evans Post Office Building;"</paragraph>
    <paragraph>6. <bill type="h" number="433">H.R. 433</bill>, to designate the facility of the USPS located at 1700 Main Street in Little Rock, Arkansas, as the "Scipio A. Jones Post Office Building;"</paragraph>
    <paragraph>7. <bill type="h" number="514">H.R. 514</bill>, to designate the facility of the USPS located at 16150 Aviation Loop Drive in Brooksville, Florida, as the "Sergeant Lea Robert Mills Brooksville Aviation Branch Post Office;"</paragraph>
    <paragraph>8. <bill type="h" number="577">H.R. 577</bill>, to designate the facility of the USPS located at 3903 South Congress Avenue in Austin, Texas, as the "Sergeant Henry Ybarra III Post Office Building."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="COMMITTEE ON INDIAN AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Indian Affairs be authorized to meet on Thursday, February 15, 2007, at 9:30 a.m. in room 485 of the Russell Senate Office Building to conduct a hearing on the President's fiscal year 2008 budget request for tribal programs.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet to conduct a markup on Thursday, February 15, 2007, at 10 a.m. in room <bill type="s" number="216">S. 216</bill> of the Capitol Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Beryl Howell, to be a Member of the United States Sentencing Commission.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="316">S. 316</bill>, the Preserve Access to Affordable Generics Act, Kohl, Grassley, Leahy, Schumer, Feingold.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="236">S. 236</bill>, the Federal Agency Data Mining Reporting Act of 2007, Feingold, Sununu, Leahy, Akaka, Kennedy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="378">S. 378</bill>, the Court Security Improvement Act of 2007, Leahy, Specter, Durbin, Cornyn, Kennedy, Hatch.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="442">S. 442</bill>, the John R. Justice Prosecutors and Defenders Incentive Act of 2007, Durbin.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="sr" number="41">S. Res. 41</bill>, honoring the life and recognizing the accomplishments of Tom Mooney, president of the Ohio Federation of Teachers, Brown, Voinovich.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="sr" number="47">S. Res. 47</bill>, honoring the life and achievements of George C. Springer, Sr., the Northeast regional director and a former vice president of the American Federation of Teachers, Dodd.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="sr" number="49">S. Res. 49</bill>, recognizing and celebrating the 50th anniversary of the entry of Alaska into the Union as the 49th State, Stevens, Murkowski.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="sr" number="53">S. Res. 53</bill>, congratulating Illinois State University as it marks its sesquicentennial, Durbin, Obama.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="sr" number="69">S. Res. 69</bill>, a resolution recognizing the African-American spiritual as a national treasure, Menendez.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="SELECT COMMITTEE ON INTELLIGENCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Select Committee on Intelligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on February 15, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. to hold a closed hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="SPECIAL COMMITTEE ON AGING">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Special Committee on Aging be authorized to meet Thursday, February 15, 2007, from 10 a.m. to noon in Dirksen 562 for the purpose of conducting a hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
