<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1206979203" ordinal="48" title="NATIONAL CEREBRAL PALSY AWARENESS DAY">
  <narrative>NATIONAL CEREBRAL PALSY AWARENESS DAY -- (Senate - March 31, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="2250">S2250</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412247" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the Judiciary Committee be discharged from further consideration of <bill type="sr" number="484">S. Res. 484</bill> and that the Senate now proceed to its immediate consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will report the resolution by title.</narrative>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="484">S. Res. 484</bill>) designating March 25, 2008, as "National Cerebral Palsy Day."</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412247" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="484">S. Res. 484</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="484">S. Res. 484</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas cerebral palsy is any number of neurological disorders that appear in infancy or early childhood and permanently affect  body movement and the muscle coordination necessary to maintain balance and posture;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas cerebral palsy is caused by damage to 1 or more specific areas of the brain, usually occurring during fetal development, before, during, or shortly after birth, or during infancy;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the majority of children are born with cerebral palsy, although it may not be detected until months or years later;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas 75 percent of individuals with cerebral palsy also have 1 or more additional developmental disabilities including epilepsy, intellectual disability, autism and visual impairments, or blindness;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention recently released information indicating an increase in the prevalence of cerebral palsy and that the rate is now about 1 in 278 children;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas 800,000 Americans are affected by cerebral palsy;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, while there is no current cure for cerebral palsy, some treatment will often improve a child's capabilities and scientists and researchers are hopeful that breakthroughs will be forthcoming;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas researchers across the Nation are conducting important research projects involving cerebral palsy; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Senate is an institution that can raise awareness in the general public and the medical community of cerebral palsy: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) designates March 25, 2008, as "National Cerebral Palsy Awareness Day";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) recognizes that all people of the United States should become more informed and aware of cerebral palsy; and</chair>
  <chair> (3) respectfully requests the Secretary of the Senate to transmit a copy of this resolution to Reaching for the Stars: A Foundation of Hope for Children with Cerebral Palsy.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
