<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1186027200" ordinal="73" title="DESIGNATING SEPTEMBER 2007 AS &quot;NATIONAL BOURBON HERITAGE MONTH&quot;">
  <speaking speaker="300080" topic="COMMENDING FAYETTEVILLE, NORTH CAROLINA, FOR HOLDING A CELEBRATION OF THE 250TH ANNIVERSARY OF THE BIRTH OF THE MARQUIS DE LAFAYETTE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate now proceed en bloc to the consideration of the following Senate resolutions which were submitted earlier today: <bill type="sr" number="294">S. Res. 294</bill>, <bill type="sr" number="295">S. Res. 295</bill>, <bill type="sr" number="296">S. Res. 296</bill>, <bill type="sr" number="297">S. Res. 297</bill>, and <bill type="sr" number="298">S. Res. 298</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolutions.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300052" topic="COMMENDING FAYETTEVILLE, NORTH CAROLINA, FOR HOLDING A CELEBRATION OF THE 250TH ANNIVERSARY OF THE BIRTH OF THE MARQUIS DE LAFAYETTE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today to speak in honor of an organization that has, over the last century, worked so amazingly hard to serve the people and communities of my home State of Utah. This year, the Utah League of Cities and Towns celebrates its 100th Anniversary.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Utah League of Cities and Towns, ULCT, has done a wonderful job of representing hundreds of cities and towns throughout a large and growing State for 100 years now. Senator Bennett and I are very proud of the way it has advocated for the success of each city and town throughout Utah and we would like to honor its wonderful accomplishment by introducing this resolution to celebrate its 100th anniversary. I urge my colleagues to join with me in supporting this resolution and in wishing  the members of the ULCT another 100 years of success in the century to come.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300080" topic="COMMENDING FAYETTEVILLE, NORTH CAROLINA, FOR HOLDING A CELEBRATION OF THE 250TH ANNIVERSARY OF THE BIRTH OF THE MARQUIS DE LAFAYETTE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolutions be agreed to, the preambles be agreed to, and the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table, en bloc.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
