<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1192636802" ordinal="47" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <narrative>AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET -- (Senate - October 17, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="13023">S13023</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="COMMITTEE ON BANKING, HOUSING, AND URBAN AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on October 17, 2007, at 10 a.m., in order to conduct a markup on an original bill entitled the Sudan Accountability and Divestment Act of 2007; an original bill entitled the Terrorism Risk Insurance Program Reauthorization Act of 2007; and an original bill entitled the Flood Insurance Reform and Modernization Act of 2007.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, October 17, 2007, at 10 a.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At this hearing, the Committee will hear testimony regarding consumer practices of the wireless industry.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, October 17, 2007, at 2:30 p.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At this hearing, the Committee will explore the status of the digital television transition including consumer education efforts, the operation and implementation of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration converter box program, and other issues related to a smooth and effective transition from analog to digital television.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, October 17, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. to hold a nomination hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="COMMITTEE ON HOMELAND SECURITY AND GOVERNMENTAL AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, October 17, 2007, at 10 a.m. in order to conduct a hearing entitled "Is DHS Too Dependent on Contractors to Do the Government's Work?"</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate Committee on the Judiciary be authorized during the session of the Senate in order to meet to conduct a hearing on the nomination of Michael B. Mukasey to be Attorney General of the United States, on Wednesday, October 17, 2007, at 10 a.m. in the Hart Senate Office Building room 216.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="COMMITTEE ON VETERANS' AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent for the Committee on Veterans' Affairs to be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, October 17, 2007, in order to conduct an oversight hearing on VA and DOD collaboration, the hearing will focus on the report of the President's Commission on Care For America's Returning Wounded Warriors, the report of the Veterans Disability Benefit Commission and other related reports.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Committee will meet in 562 Dirksen Senate Office Building, at 9:30 a.m.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON SUPERFUND AND ENVIRONMENTAL HEALTH">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Environment and Public Works, Subcommittee on Superfund and Environmental Health, be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, October 17, 2007, at 9:30 a.m. in room 406 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building in order to hold a hearing entitled, "Oversight Hearing on the Federal Superfund Program's Activities to Protect Public Health."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
