<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1222099204" ordinal="65" title="ALBUQUERQUE INDIAN SCHOOL ACT">
  <narrative>ALBUQUERQUE INDIAN SCHOOL ACT -- (Senate - September 22, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="9218">S9218</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent the Senate now proceed to Calendar No. 925, <bill type="s" number="1193">S. 1193</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the bill by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A bill (<bill type="s" number="1193">S. 1193</bill>) to direct the Secretary of the Interior to take into trust 2 parcels of Federal land for the benefit of certain Indian Pueblos in the State of New Mexico.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the bill.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the bill be read the third time and passed, the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table, and that any statements relating to this matter be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The bill (<bill type="s" number="1193">S. 1193</bill>) was ordered to be engrossed for a third reading, was read the third time, and passed, as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="s" number="1193">S. 1193</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "Albuquerque Indian School Act".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. DEFINITIONS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; In this Act:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) 19 PUEBLOS.--The term "19 Pueblos" means the New Mexico Indian Pueblos of--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) Acoma;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) Cochiti;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) Isleta;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (D) Jemez;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (E) Laguna;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (F) Nambe;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (G) Ohkay Owingeh (San Juan);&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (H) Picuris;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (I) Pojoaque;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (J) San Felipe;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (K) San Ildefonso;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (L) Sandia;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (M) Santa Ana;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (N) Santa Clara;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (O) Santo Domingo;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (P) Taos;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (Q) Tesuque;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (R) Zia; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (S) Zuni.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) SECRETARY.--The term "Secretary" means the Secretary of the Interior (or a designee).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) SURVEY.--The term "survey" means the survey plat entitled "Department of the Interior, Bureau of Indian Affairs, Southern Pueblos Agency, BIA Property Survey" (prepared by John Paisano, Jr., Registered Land Surveyor Certificate No. 5708), and dated March 7, 1977.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 3. LAND TAKEN INTO TRUST FOR BENEFIT OF 19 PUEBLOS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Action by Secretary.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) IN GENERAL.--The Secretary shall take into trust all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the land described in subsection (b) (including any improvements and appurtenances to the land) for the benefit of the 19 Pueblos.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) ADMINISTRATION.--The Secretary shall--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) take such action as the Secretary determines to be necessary to document the transfer under paragraph (1); and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) appropriately assign each applicable private and municipal utility and service right or agreement.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Description of Land.--The land referred to in subsection (a)(1) is the 2 tracts of Federal land, the combined acreage of which is approximately 18.3 acres, that were historically part of the Albuquerque Indian School, more particularly described as follows:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) TRACT B.--The approximately 5.9211 acres located in sec. 7 and sec. 8 of T. 10 N., R. 3 E., of the New Mexico Principal Meridian in the city of Albuquerque, New Mexico, as identified on the survey.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) TRACT D.--The approximately 12.3835 acres located in sec. 7 and sec. 8 of T. 10 N., R. 3 E., of the New Mexico Principal Meridian in the city of Albuquerque, New Mexico, as identified on the survey.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Survey.--The Secretary may make minor corrections to the survey and legal description of the Federal land described in subsection (b) as the Secretary determines to be necessary to correct clerical, typographical, and surveying errors.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (d) Use of Land.--The land taken into trust under subsection (a) shall be used for the educational, health, cultural, business, and economic development of the 19 Pueblos.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (e) Limitations and Conditions.--The land taken into trust under subsection (a) shall remain subject to any private or municipal encumbrance, right-of-way, restriction, easement of record, or utility service agreement in effect on the date of enactment of this Act.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 4. EFFECT OF OTHER LAWS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) In General.--Except as otherwise provided in this section, land taken into trust under section 3(a) shall be subject to Federal laws relating to Indian land.</chair>
  <chair> (b) Gaming.--No gaming activity (within the meaning of the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act (25 U.S.C. 2701 et seq.)) shall be carried out on land taken into trust under section 3(a).&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
