<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1211472002" ordinal="60" title="EXECUTIVE REPORTS OF COMMITTEES">
  <narrative>EXECUTIVE REPORTS OF COMMITTEES -- (Senate - May 22, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="4791">S4791</bill>]</narrative>
  <narrative>The following executive reports of nominations were submitted:</narrative>
  <narrative>By Mr. LEVIN for the Committee on Armed Services.</narrative>
  <narrative>Air Force nomination of Col. Kimberly A. Siniscalchi, to be Major General.</narrative>
  <narrative>Air Force nomination of Maj. Gen. Mark D. Shackelford, to be Lieutenant General.</narrative>
  <narrative>Air Force nomination of Maj. Gen. Philip M. Breedlove, to be Lieutenant General.</narrative>
  <narrative>Air Force nomination of Maj. Gen. Charles E. Stenner, Jr., to be Lieutenant General.</narrative>
  <narrative>Army nomination of Lt. Gen. Stanley A. McChrystal, to be Lieutenant General.</narrative>
  <narrative>Army nomination of Brig. Gen. John F. Mulholland, Jr., to be Lieutenant General.</narrative>
  <narrative>Army nominations beginning with Brigadier General Stephen E. Bogle and ending with Colonel Joe M. Wells, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record on April 29, 2008.</narrative>
  <narrative>Army nomination of Lt. Gen. Peter W. Chiarelli, to be General.</narrative>
  <narrative>Navy nomination of Rear Adm. Harry B. Harris, Jr., to be Vice Admiral.</narrative>
  <narrative>Navy nominations beginning with Rear Adm. (lh) Julius S. Caesar and ending with Rear Adm. (lh) Garland P. Wright, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record on February 14, 2008.</narrative>
  <narrative>Navy nomination of Rear Adm. William H. McRaven, to be Vice Admiral.</narrative>
  <narrative>Navy nomination of Rear Adm. Michael C. Vitale, to be Vice Admiral.</narrative>
  <narrative>Navy nomination of Rear Adm. (lh) Raymond E. Berube, to be Rear Admiral.</narrative>
  <narrative>Navy nominations beginning with Rear Adm. (lh) Richard R. Jeffries and ending with Rear Adm. (lh) David J. Smith, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record on March 3, 2008.</narrative>
  <narrative>Navy nominations beginning with Capt. David F. Baucom and ending with Capt. Vincent L. Griffith, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record on March 31, 2008.</narrative>
  <narrative>Navy nominations beginning with Capt. David C. Johnson and ending with Capt. Thomas J. Moore, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record on March 31, 2008.</narrative>
  <narrative>Navy nominations beginning with Capt. Donald E. Gaddis and ending with Capt.  Maude E. Young, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record on March 31, 2008.</narrative>
  <narrative>Navy nominations beginning with Capt. Michael H. Anderson and ending with Capt. William R. Kiser, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record on March 31, 2008.</narrative>
  <narrative>Navy nomination of Capt. Norman R. Hayes, to be Rear Admiral (lower half).</narrative>
  <narrative>Navy nomination of Capt. William E. Leigher, to be Rear Admiral (lower half).</narrative>
  <narrative>Navy nomination of Rear Adm. William E. Gortney, to be Vice Admiral.</narrative>
  <narrative>Navy nomination of Vice Adm. Melvin G. Williams, Jr., to be Vice Admiral.</narrative>
  <narrative>Navy nomination of Rear Adm. David J. Dorsett, to be Vice Admiral.</narrative>
  <narrative>Navy nomination of Rear Adm. (lh) Kevin M. McCoy, to be Vice Admiral.</narrative>
  <narrative>Navy nomination of Vice Adm. William D. Crowder, to be Vice Admiral.</narrative>
  <narrative>Navy nomination of Rear Adm. Peter H. Daly, to be Vice Admiral.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, for the Committee on Armed Services I report favorably the following nomination lists which were printed in the Records on the dates indicated, and ask unanimous consent, to save the expense of reprinting on the Executive Calendar that these nominations lie at the Secretary's desk for the information of Senators.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>Air Force nominations beginning with Lonnie B. Barker and ending with Jerry P. Pitts, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record on March 11, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>Air Force nominations beginning with Eric L. Bloomfield and ending with Deborah L. Mueller, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record on April 28, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>Air Force nominations beginning with Mary J. Bernheim and ending with Kelli C. Mack, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record on May 13, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>Air Force nominations beginning with James E. Ostrander and ending with Frank J. Nocilla, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record on May 13, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>Army nomination of Cheryl Amyx, to be Major.</chair>
  <chair>Army nomination of Deborah K. Sirratt, to be Major.</chair>
  <chair>Army nominations beginning with Mark A. Cannon and ending with Michael J. Miller, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record on April 23, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>Army nominations beginning with Gene Kahn and ending with James D. Townsend, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record on April 23, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>Army nominations beginning with Lozay Foots III and ending with Margaret L. Young, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record on April 23, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>Army nominations beginning with Phillip J. Caravella and ending with Paul S. Lajos, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record on April 23, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>Army nomination of Jimmy D. Swanson, to be Colonel.</chair>
  <chair>Army nomination of Ronald J. Sheldon, to be Colonel.</chair>
  <chair>Army nominations beginning with Brian M. Boldt and ending with Christopher L. Tracy, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record on May 8, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>Army nomination of James K. McNeely, to be Major.</chair>
  <chair>Navy nominations beginning with Stanley A. Okoro and ending with David B. Rosenberg, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record on April 24, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>Navy nomination of Robert S. McMaster, to be Lieutenant Commander.</chair>
  <chair>Navy nomination of Christopher S. Kaplafka, to be Lieutenant Commander.</chair>
  <chair>Navy nomination of David R. Eggleston, to be Lieutenant Commander.</chair>
  <chair>Navy nominations beginning with Katherine A. Isgrig and ending with Jason C. Kedzierski, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record on May 13, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>Navy nominations beginning with Robert D. Younger and ending with Jeffrey W. Willis, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record on May 13, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>By Mr. LIEBERMAN for the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</chair>
  <chair>*Paul A. Schneider, of Maryland, to be Deputy Secretary of Homeland Security.</chair>
  <chair>By Mrs. FEINSTEIN for the Committee on Rules and Administration.</chair>
  <chair>*Cynthia L. Bauerly, of Minnesota, to be a Member of the Federal Election Commission for a term expiring April 30, 2011.</chair>
  <chair>*Caroline C. Hunter, of Florida, to be a Member of the Federal Election Commission for a term expiring April 30, 2013.</chair>
  <chair>*Donald F. McGahn, of the District of Columbia, to be a Member of the Federal Election Commission for a term expiring April 30, 2009.</chair>
  <chair>By Mr. LEAHY for the Committee on the Judiciary.</chair>
  <chair>Elisebeth C. Cook, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Attorney General.</chair>
  <chair>William Walter Wilkins, III, of South Carolina, to be United States Attorney for the District of South Carolina for the term of four years.</chair>
  <chair>*Nomination was reported with recommendation that it be confirmed subject to the nominee's commitment to respond to requests to appear and testify before any duly constituted committee of the Senate.</chair>
  <narrative>(Nominations without an asterisk were reported with the recommendation that they be confirmed.)</narrative>
</record>
