<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1182355236" ordinal="48" title="PRIVILEGES OF THE FLOOR">
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the following fellows, interns, and detailees of the staff of the Finance Committee be allowed on the Senate floor for the duration of debate on the Energy bill: Mary Baker, Tom Louthan, Sara Shepherd, Amy Branger, Jennifer Donohue, Lindsay Erickson, David Lee, Alex Mazuro, Jennifer Smith, and Erik Willborg.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I also ask unanimous consent that the following individuals who are interns in my office be given floor privileges during the pendency of <bill type="h" number="6">H.R. 6</bill>: Samantha Currier, Allison Freedman, Gregory Gonzales, Kori Higgins, Blake Peterson, Sarah Pike, Heather Roach, Shannon Saltclah, Joshua Sanchez, and Claire Smith.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that Paul Keppy, Anne Freeman, and Lynda Simmons of my Senate Committee Finance staff be given the privilege of the floor during the debate on the Energy bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="">
    <paragraph>Additionally, Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that John Kalitka, who is on detail to my staff from the Commerce Department, be granted the privilege of the floor during the debate on the Energy bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the following fellows, interns, and detailees of the staff of the Finance Committee be allowed on the Senate floor for the duration of the debate on the Energy bill: George Serletis, Brandon Perkins, Brett Youngerman, Suzanne Payne, Tom Kornfield, Avi Salzman, Grace Stephens, Alex Hart, and Elise Stein.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
