<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1197997209" ordinal="52" title="HONORING DENIS O'DONOVAN">
  <narrative>HONORING DENIS O'DONOVAN -- (Senate - December 18, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="15901">S15901</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the following resolution from the HELP Committee to be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows.</narrative>
  <narrative>Resolution commending Denis O'Donovan with deepest sincerity for his dedicated and skillful work to improve the health and well-being of the American people.</narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas Denis O'Donovan has served with distinction and skill for 10 years as Chief Clerk of the Committee on Health, Education, Labor and Pensions of the Senate;</narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas Denis O'Donovan exemplifies the best traditions of selfless public service, having devoted 40 years to improving the lives of all Americans through service to the Senate;</narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas Denis O'Donovan has met every Member of the Committee and their staffs with cheerfulness and consideration;</narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas the faultless competence of Denis O'Donovan has enabled the Committee to function effectively under Chairmen of both parties;</narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas Denis O'Donovan will begin a well-earned retirement next month; and</narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas Denis O'Donovan may be gone as of this date, but he will never be forgotten by those who had the fortune to work with him: Now, therefore, be it</narrative>
  <narrative>Resolved, That the Committee on Health, Education, Labor and Pensions of the Senate--</narrative>
  <narrative>(1) commends Denis O'Donovan with deepest sincerity for his dedicated and skillful work to improve the health and well-being of the American people; and</narrative>
  <narrative>(2) wishes Denis O'Donovan all happiness and fulfillment in retirement.</narrative>
</record>
