<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1214409602" ordinal="15" title="CHANGES TO S. CON. RES. 70">
  <narrative>CHANGES TO <bill type="sc" number="70">S. CON. RES. 70</bill> -- (Senate - June 25, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="6147">S6147</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300026" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, section 323(d) of <bill type="sc" number="70">S. Con. Res. 70</bill>, the 2009 budget resolution, permits the chairman of the Senate Budget Committee to make appropriate adjustments in aggregates, allocations, and other levels assumed in the resolution to reflect the budgetary impact of certain legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am filing adjustments pursuant to section 323(d) for legislation that Congress cleared prior to the adoption of <bill type="sc" number="70">S. Con. Res. 70</bill> but for which the necessary information to incorporate their budgetary effects was not available at the time the conference report was filed. The revisions are for public law 110-232, the Strategic Petroleum Reserve Fill Suspension and Consumer Protection Act of 2008, and public law 110-245, the Heroes Earnings Assistance and Relief Tax Act of 2008.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For the information of my colleagues, the combined effect of the adjustments, including accompanying changes in debt service, is to reduce the on-budget deficit assumed in <bill type="sc" number="70">S. Con. Res. 70</bill> by $965 million in 2008, while increasing it by $933 million in 2009 and by roughly $1 billion over the 2009 to 2013 period. On a unified basis, the legislation is expected to lower deficits by $322 million over the 2008 to 2013 period. Because the revisions are being made for legislation that has already cleared  Congress, they will neither raise nor lower the amount of room available to Congress under the budgetary aggregates and committee allocations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent to have printed in the Record a set of tables which show the revised allocations, aggregates, and other levels for <bill type="sc" number="70">S. Con. Res. 70</bill>, the 2009 budget resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
</record>
