<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1189526401" ordinal="40" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <narrative>AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET -- (Senate - September 11, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="11433">S11433</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="COMMITTEE ON ARMED SERVICES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, September 11, at 2 p.m. in open session to receive testimony on the situation in Iraq and progress made by the Government of Iraq in meeting benchmarks.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="COMMITTEE ON FINANCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Finance be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, September 11, 2007, at 10 a.m., in room 215 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building, to hear testimony on the "U.S.-Peru Trade Promotion Agreement."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, September 11, 2007, at 9:30 a.m. to hold a hearing on Iraq.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, September 11, 2007, at 2:15 p.m. to hold a business meeting.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="SELECT COMMITTEE ON INTELLIGENCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Select Committee on Intelligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on September 11, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. to hold a closed business meeting.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON NATIONAL PARKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on National Parks of the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, September 11, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the hearing is to receive testimony on the following bills: <bill type="s" number="127">S. 127</bill>, to amend the Great Sand Dunes National Park and Preserve Act of 2000 to explain the purpose and provide for the administration of the Baca National Wildlife Refuge; <bill type="s" number="327">S. 327</bill> and <bill type="h" number="359">H.R. 359</bill>, to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a special resource study of sites associated with the life of Cesar Estrada Chavez and the farm labor movement; <bill type="s" number="868">S. 868</bill>, to amend the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate segments  of the Taunton River in the Commonwealth of Massachusetts as a component of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System <bill type="s" number="1051">S. 1051</bill>, to authorize National Mall Liberty Fund D.C. to establish a memorial on Federal land in the District of Columbia at Constitution Gardens previously approved to honor free persons and slaves who fought for independence, liberty, and justice for all during the American Revolution; <bill type="s" number="1184">S. 1184</bill> and <bill type="h" number="1021">H.R. 1021</bill>; to direct the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a special resources study regarding the suitability and feasibility of designating certain historic buildings and areas in Taunton, Massachusetts, as a unit of the National Park System, and for other purposes; <bill type="s" number="1247">S. 1247</bill>, to amend the Weir Farm National Historic Site Establishment Act of 1990 to limit the development of any property acquired by the Secretary of</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
