<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1184558400" ordinal="38" title="NATIONAL PURPLE HEART RECOGNITION DAY">
  <narrative>NATIONAL PURPLE HEART RECOGNITION DAY -- (Senate - July 16, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="9291">S9291</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300081" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Armed Services Committee be discharged from further consideration of <bill type="sc" number="27">S. Con. Res. 27</bill> and that the Senate then proceed to its consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will report the concurrent resolution by title.</narrative>
  <narrative>The assistant legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A concurrent resolution (<bill type="sc" number="27">S. Con. Res. 27</bill>) supporting the goals and ideals of "National Purple Heart Recognition Day."</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the concurrent resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300081" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the amendment at the desk be considered and agreed to, the resolution, as amended, be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table en bloc, and that any statements relating thereto be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The amendment (No. 2269) was agreed to, as follows:</chair>
  <chair>On page 2 line 8 strike "requests that the President issue a proclamation calling on" and insert "calls upon".</chair>
  <chair>The concurrent resolution (<bill type="sc" number="27">S. Con. Res. 27</bill>), as amended, was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The concurrent resolution, as amended, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sc" number="27">S. Con. Res. 27</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas the Purple Heart is the oldest military decoration in the world in present use;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Purple Heart is awarded in the name of the President of the United States to members of the Armed Forces who are wounded in a conflict with an enemy force or are wounded while held by an enemy force as prisoners of war, and is awarded posthumously to the next of kin of members of the Armed Forces who are killed in a conflict with an enemy force or who die of wounds received in a conflict with an enemy force;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Purple Heart was established on August 7, 1782, during the Revolutionary War, when General George Washington issued an order establishing the Honorary Badge of Distinction, otherwise known as the Badge of Military Merit;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the award of the Purple Heart ceased with the end of the Revolutionary War, but was revived in 1932, the 200th anniversary of George Washington's birth, out of respect for his memory and military achievements; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas observing National Purple Heart Recognition Day is a fitting tribute to George Washington and to the more than 1,535,000 recipients of the Purple Heart, approximately 550,000 of whom are still living: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved by the Senate (the House of Representatives concurring), That Congress--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) supports the goals and ideals of "National Purple Heart Recognition Day";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) encourages all people in the United States to learn about the history of the Purple Heart and to honor its recipients; and</chair>
  <chair> (3) calls upon the people of the United States to conduct appropriate ceremonies, activities, and programs to demonstrate support for members of the Armed Forces who have been awarded the Purple Heart. &lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
