<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1205251202" ordinal="27" title="50TH ANNIVERSARY OF LAS TRAMPAS">
  <narrative>50TH ANNIVERSARY OF LAS TRAMPAS -- (Senate - March 11, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="1872">S1872</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I take this opportunity to recognize the 50th anniversary of Las Trampas, a nonprofit organization dedicated to supporting adults with developmental disabilities located in Contra Costa County.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Founded in 1958 in Lafayette, CA, Las Trampas has grown to include four State-licensed group residential homes throughout Contra Costa County. Through the work of its staff, volunteers, and board of directors, Las Trampas actively assists adults with developmental disabilities to discover their capabilities so that they may live their lives as independently as possible.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Las Trampas is committed to helping each of its clients succeed in all aspects of daily living. It offers programs  that emphasize a life-long educational process, including self-advocacy skills, risk evaluation, emotion management, and clear communication skills. Two programs of note include the Adult Vocational Program and the Adult Development Program. The Adult Vocational Program provides employment services and skills development, and has helped  many Las Trampas clients gain employment with local businesses. The Adult Development Program caters to small groups and highlights educational development in the areas of daily living tasks, communications, social interaction, and employment. Most importantly, Las Trampas works with every person to help them practice each of these skills in real life situations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The support services and programs provided by Las Trampas offer those with developmental disabilities the opportunity to turn the dream of full inclusion in the community into a reality. I commend the Las Trampas staff and volunteers for their dedicated work in assisting adults with developmental disabilities lead fuller lives in their home, at work, and in the community.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I congratulate Las Trampas for its dedicated work on this special occasion, and I send my best wishes for many future successes over the next 50 years.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
