<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1183953600" ordinal="56" title="NATIONAL WATERMELON MONTH">
  <narrative>NATIONAL WATERMELON MONTH -- (Senate - July 09, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="8880">S8880</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Judiciary Committee be discharged from further consideration of and the Senate now proceed to <bill type="sr" number="262">S. Res. 262</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered. The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <chair>The assistant legislative clerk read as follows:</chair>
  <chair>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="262">S. Res. 262</bill>) designating July 2007 as "National Watermelon Month."</chair>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="262">S. Res. 262</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="262">S. Res. 262</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas watermelon production constitutes an important sector of the agricultural industry of the United States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, according to the January 2006 statistics compiled by the National Agricultural Statistics Service of the United States Department of Agriculture, the United States produces 4,200,000,000 pounds of watermelon annually;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas watermelon is grown in 49 States, is purchased and consumed in all 50 States, and is exported to Canada;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas evidence indicates that eating 2 1/2  to 5 cups of fruits and vegetables daily as part of a healthy diet will improve health and protect against diseases such as cancer, high blood pressure, stroke, and heart disease;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas proper diet and nutrition are important factors in preventing diseases such as childhood obesity and diabetes;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas watermelon has no fat or cholesterol and is an excellent source of the vitamins A, B6, and C, fiber, and potassium, which are vital to good health and disease prevention;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas watermelon is also an excellent source of lycopene;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas lycopene, an antioxidant found only in a few red plant foods, has been shown to reduce the risk of certain cancers;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas watermelon is a heart-healthy food that has qualified for the heart-check mark from the American Heart Association;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas watermelon has been a nutritious summer favorite from generation to generation; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas it is important to educate citizens of the United States regarding the health benefits of watermelon and other fruits and vegetables: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) supports the goals and ideals of "National Watermelon Month";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) calls on the Federal Government, States, localities, schools, nonprofit organizations, businesses, other entities, and the people of the United States to observe the month with appropriate programs and activities; and</chair>
  <chair> (3) designates July 2007 as "National Watermelon Month".&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
