<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1179871463" ordinal="7" title="SCHEDULE">
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, as you just announced, there will be a period for the transaction of morning business for 1 hour. Following morning business, we will resume consideration of the immigration legislation. Senator Sessions, under a previous order entered, is to be recognized for 2 hours. He will speak until 12:30 p.m. Today, the regular party conferences will be held beginning at 12:30 p.m., so Senator Sessions will complete his remarks after 2:15 p.m.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is my understanding that the first amendment that has been agreed to be laid down will be by Senator Dorgan. I don't know if there is a consent agreement to that effect. Is there one, Madam President?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> There is not.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I think this has been cleared on both sides. I ask unanimous consent that the first amendment be offered by Senator Dorgan, after the remarks of Senator Sessions.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, if there is any problem with this procedure, the two managers can ask unanimous consent, and we will all agree to change it. But I think that is the agreement which has been made. If it has not, we can start over. That is the general agreement. What we plan to do during consideration of the legislation is to alternate back and forth--Democrat and Republican, Democrat and Republican. That is what we did the last time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The only thing I will announce--I told both managers and I think Senator McConnell agrees with this, and if not, it is something we need to do for an orderly process here--is that we do an amendment at a time. The last time on this bill, we wound up with 30, 40 amendments pending. I am saying we are not going to do that this time. We are going to do one amendment at a time, unless there is something extraordinary to come along to change that procedure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have a long amendment list. The substitute amendment was laid down last night. It is now available to all Members.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Tonight, I should announce, as has been announced in the past, there is going to be a dinner in the Botanic Garden to honor the spouses of the Senate. I hope all Members will attend this event.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Who seeks time? The Senator from New Hampshire.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300049" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I believe I am to be recognized for 15 minutes; is that correct?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> That is correct.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300049" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the Chair.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(The remarks of Mr. Gregg pertaining to the introduction of <bill type="s" number="15">S. 15</bill> are printed in today's Record under "Statements on Introduced Bills and Joint Resolutions.")</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300049" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Utah.</chair>
</record>
