<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1184817600" ordinal="37" title="NOTICE OF HEARINGS">
  <narrative>NOTICE OF HEARINGS -- (Senate - July 19, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="9641">S9641</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON NATIONAL PARKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to announce for the information of the Senate and the public that a hearing has been scheduled before the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, Subcommittee on National Parks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The hearing will be held on August 2, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the hearing is to receive testimony on <bill type="s" number="1253">S. 1253</bill>, a bill to establish a fund for the National Park Centennial Challenge, and for other purposes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of the limited time available for the hearing, witnesses may testify by invitation only. However, those wishing to submit written testimony for the hearing record should send it to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, U.S. Senate, Washington, DC 20510-6150, or by e-mail to,&#xD0; rachel Xpasternack@energy.senate.gov.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For further information, please contact David Brooks at (202) 224-9863 or Rachel Pasternack at (202) 224-0883.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to announce for the information of the Senate and the public that a hearing has been scheduled before the Subcommittee on Water and Power of the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. The hearing will be held on July 26, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. in room 366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building in Washington, DC.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the hearing is to receive testimony on the following bills: <bill type="s" number="300">S. 300</bill>, to authorize appropriations for the Bureau of Reclamation to carry out the Lower Colorado River Multi-Species Conservation Program in the States of Arizona, California, and Nevada, and for other purposes; <bill type="s" number="1258">S. 1258</bill>, to amend the Reclamation Safety of Dams Act of 1978 to authorize improvements for the security of dams and other facilities; <bill type="s" number="1477">S. 1477</bill>, to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to carry out the Jackson  Gulch rehabilitation project in the State of Colorado; <bill type="s" number="1522">S. 1522</bill>, to amend the Bonneville Power Administration portions of the Fisheries Restoration and Irrigation Mitigation Act of 2000 to authorize appropriations for fiscal years 2008 through 2014, and for other purposes; and <bill type="h" number="1025">H.R. 1025</bill>, to authorize the Secretary of the Interior</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of the limited time available for the hearing, witnesses may testify by invitation only. However, those wishing to submit written testimony for the hearing record should send it to the Committee on Energy and Natural  Resources, U.S. Senate, Washington, DC 20510-6150, or by e-mail to Gina XWeinstock@energy.senate.gov.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For further information, please contact Michael Connor at (202) 224-5479 or Gina Weinstock at (202) 224-5684.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
