<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1204822801" ordinal="14" title="CONSUMER PRODUCT SAFETY">
  <narrative>CONSUMER PRODUCT SAFETY -- (Senate - March 06, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="1669">S1669</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300080" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, again today, we hope it is going to be a short day for the Senate. We hope we will be able to pass the Consumer Product Safety Commission Reform Act on which we have all worked so hard. I thank my colleagues for the fact that every single amendment that has been offered has been germane. That is great.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The fact that everybody stayed focused on the subject matter has helped.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I know Senator Stevens, who is on the floor now, will concur that it has been exemplary how Senators have conducted themselves on this bill. We thank everyone, all the Senators and the staff, for keeping the amendments germane. It is very important to getting this bill done this week.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The other good news is, our staffs burned the midnight oil last night, Democrats and Republicans. We have been putting together a managers' package, to give a quick status report on that. We think there are about 12 or so amendments in that managers' package right now that have been agreed to. It looks as if maybe we have around eight amendments that are pending. We are hoping we can work out some issues on some of those amendments. We understand there may be a small number of amendments still  coming, but we have run our traps here, so to speak.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, the good news is we think we have a manageable number of amendments. We know we are going to have a vote in about 15 minutes. It will be on an amendment that is pending. Again, that is great. We will try to dispense with that amendment, however it comes out. Then we will move on to have further amendments throughout the day.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are very encouraged. I thank Senator Stevens for his leadership and his staff. They have been great. We appreciate their efforts to try to shepherd this bill through.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I do not want to make a prediction because I don't know and I don't pretend to know how this is going to turn out, but it appears to me that it is possible we could easily finish this bill today. It is possible--I don't want to jinx myself--but maybe even this afternoon. Instead of going into the late evening hours tonight, it is conceivable we might be able to finish it this afternoon if we work hard and stay on task.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I wanted to give the Senate an update. We look forward to the collegial spirit everyone has shown so far. We hope it continues today. I thank everybody for their cooperation and assistance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Oklahoma.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300055" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, it is my understanding we are scheduled for a vote at 11 o'clock; is that correct?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> There will be 15 minutes of debate once the Senate lays down the bill.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300055" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that I be recognized for up to 10 minutes as in morning business.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300094" topic="">
    <paragraph>I do believe we have an agreement, Mr. President, to vote at a time certain. Does the Senator wish to postpone that vote?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300055" topic="">
    <paragraph>I inquire of the Chair, is there a time certain for a vote?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
