<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1222444802" ordinal="124" title="INDIAN LEASE ACT">
  <narrative>INDIAN LEASE ACT -- (Senate - September 26, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="9858">S9858</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412247" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of Calendar No. 1041, <bill type="s" number="3192">S. 3192</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the bill by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A bill (<bill type="s" number="3192">S. 3192</bill>) to amend the Act of August 9, 1955, to authorize the Cow Creek Band of Umpqua Tribe of Indians, the Coquille Indian Tribe, and the Confederated Tribes of the Siletz Indians of Oregon to obtain 99-year lease authority for trust land.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the bill, which had been reported from the Committee on Indian Affairs with an amendment to strike all after the enacting clause and insert in lieu thereof the following:</narrative>
  <narrative>SECTION 1. LEASES OF RESTRICTED LAND.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Subsection (a) of the first section of the Act of August 9, 1955 (25 U.S.C. 415(a)), is amended in the second sentence--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) by inserting ", land held in trust for the Cow Creek Band of Umpqua Indians of Oregon, land held in trust for the Coquille Tribe of Oregon, and land held in trust for the Confederated Tribes of the Siletz Reservation, Oregon" after "Devils Lake Sioux Reservation"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) by inserting "and except leases of land held in trust for the Morongo Band of Cahuilla Mission Indians of the Morongo Reservation, California, which may be for a term not to exceed 50 years," before "and except".</narrative>
  <narrative>Amend the title so as to read: "A bill to amend the Act of August 9, 1955, to authorize the Cow Creek Band of Umpqua Indians of Oregon, the Coquille Tribe of Oregon, and the Confederated Tribes of the Siletz Reservation, Oregon, to obtain 99-year lease authority for trust land, and to authorize the Morongo Band of Cahuilla Mission Indians of the Morongo Reservation, California, to obtain 50-year lease authority for trust land.".</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412247" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the committee-reported substitute amendment be agreed to; the bill, as amended, be read a third time and passed; the title amendment be agreed to; the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table, with no intervening action or debate; and that any statements relating to this measure be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The committee amendment in the nature of a substitute was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The bill (<bill type="s" number="3192">S. 3192</bill>), as amended, was ordered to be engrossed for a third reading, was read the third time, and passed.</chair>
  <chair>The title was amended so as to read:</chair>
  <chair>"A bill to amend the Act of August 9, 1955, to authorize the Cow Creek Band of Umpqua Indians of Oregon, the Coquille Tribe of Oregon, and the Confederated Tribes of the Siletz Reservation, Oregon, to obtain 99-year lease authority for trust land, and to authorize the Morongo Band of Cahuilla Mission Indians of the Morongo Reservation, California, to obtain 50-year lease authority for trust, land.".</chair>
</record>
