<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1210694402" ordinal="25" title="125TH ANNIVERSARY OF JAMESTOWN, NORTH DAKOTA">
  <narrative>125TH ANNIVERSARY OF JAMESTOWN, NORTH DAKOTA -- (Senate - May 13, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="4101">S4101</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300026" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I am pleased to honor a community in North Dakota that is celebrating its 125th anniversary. From June 28 to July 6, the residents of Jamestown will come together to celebrate their community and its historic founding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Founded in 1883 on the intersection of the Pipestem and James Rivers, Jamestown was named by GEN Thomas La Fayette Rosser whose hometown was Jamestown, VA, which was also located on a James River. In 1883 and again in 1932, the city of Jamestown made an attempt, though unsuccessful, to become the capital of the State. Jamestown is known as the "Pride of the Prairie"--and it has much to be proud of.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The city's dedication to promoting both conservation and tourism resulted in the construction of the World's Largest Buffalo. This massive 60-ton monument, which began as an art project of students from Jamestown College, draws visitors from all over the country. The buffalo is the center of the Frontier Village, a gathering of genuine Frontier-era buildings and the National Buffalo Museum--all of these together attracting over 100,000 visitors a year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Adding to Jamestown's celebrity is the presence of two of only a few albino bison in North America. The first, known as White Cloud, gave birth to an albino calf this last year, bringing another albino bison to the herd tended by the National Buffalo Museum. The rarity of this occurring is immense and has added to interest in the city.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Jamestown has also helped shape the direction of North Dakota. And, for many, as the city that brought us Louis L'Amour and Peggy Lee, Jamestown has helped shape a generation. Coming into its 125th year, I am certain that Jamestown will continue in its role to provide leadership to many of our communities for years to come.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Jamestown will be commemorating this special occasion with over a week of fireworks, car shows, races, banquets, socials, air shows, golf tournaments, school reunions, presentations, and parades.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask the U.S. Senate to join me in congratulating Jamestown, ND, and its residents on their 125th anniversary and in wishing them well for the future. By honoring Jamestown we keep the pioneering, frontier spirit alive for future generations. It is places such as Jamestown that have helped to shape this country into what it is today, which is why this fine community is deserving of our recognition.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Jamestown has a proud past and a very bright future.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
