<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1176998405" ordinal="38" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="COMMITTEE ON ARMED SERVICES">
    <paragraph>Mr President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, April 19, 2007, a 9:30 a.m., in open session to receive testimony on the Department of Defense's management of costs under the Logistics Civil Augmentation Program (LOCGAP) contract in Iraq.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Thursday, April 19, 2007, at 10 a.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building. The purpose of this hearing is to discuss the importance of basic research to U.S. competitiveness in science.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="KLOBUCHUR" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Finance be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, April 19, 2007, at 10 a.m., in 2125 Dirksen Senate Office Building, to hear testimony on "Grains, Cane, and Automobiles: Tax Incentives for Alternative Fuels and Vehicles".</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet to conduct hearing on "Department of Justice Oversight" on Thursday, April 19, 2007 at 9:30 a.m., in Hart Senate Office Building room 216.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Honorable Alberto Gonzales, Attorney General, United States Department of Justice, Washington, DC.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="SELECT COMMITTEE ON INTELLIGENCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Select Committee on Intelligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on April 19, 2007 at 2:30 p.m. to hold a hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="SPECIAL COMMITTEE ON AGING">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Special Committee on Aging be authorized to meet Thursday, April l9, 2007 from 10 a.m. to noon in Dirksen 562 for the purpose of conducting a hearing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Biodentical Hormones.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON FEDERAL FINANCIAL MANAGEMENT, GOVERNMENT INFORMATION, FEDERAL SERVICES, AND INTERNATIONAL SECURITY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on Federal Financial Management, Government Information, Federal Services and International Security be authorized to meet on Thursday, April 19, 2007 at 2 p.m. for a hearing entitled, "The Road Ahead: Implementing Postal Reform."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON STRATEGIC FORCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on Strategic Forces be authorized to meet in open and closed sessions during the session of the Senate on Thursday, April 19, 2007, at 2:30 p.m., to receive testimony on military space programs in review of the defense authorization request for fiscal year 2008 and the future years defense program.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON STRATEGIC FORCES">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
