<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1193241604" ordinal="25" title="HONORING OUR ARMED FORCES">
  <narrative>HONORING OUR ARMED FORCES -- (Senate - October 24, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="13355">S13355</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400619" topic="STAFF SERGEANT JARRED SETH FONTENOT">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today to honor the memory of SSG Jarred Seth Fontenot of the 2nd Battalion, 12th Infantry Regiment, 2nd Infantry Division, out of Fort Carson, CO. Sergeant Fontenot was killed last Thursday in an engagement with insurgents in Baghdad. He died of injuries from an explosion and small arms fire that rained down on his patrol. Sergeant Fontenot was 35 years old, a loving husband, and a father of four.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Jarred Fontenot grew up in a family steeped in military tradition. His grandfather, who helped raise Jarred after his parents died at an early age, served in the Army. His two great uncles attended West Point, later joining the Navy and Marines. One of his great uncles died in Korea, a place Jarred would later serve.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Jarred's family speaks of him as a man who loved his job and who embraced the virtues of military service. "He loved being a soldier," his grandmother recalls, "and he died doing what he loved."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sergeant Fontenot was on his second tour in Iraq, on a mission to help bring security and stability to a region torn by violence and tragedy. Every day, he and his unit put themselves in harm's way to give Iraqi citizens a chance at a society governed by the rule of law, free from the threats of sectarian strife, terrorism or autocratic rule. He served bravely and was highly decorated, earning the Overseas Service Ribbon, the Parachute Badge, and the Army Commendation Medal, an honor bestowed  upon those who have distinguished themselves by their service and acts of heroism.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Between deployments, Jarred devoted himself to law enforcement in his hometown of Port Barre, LA. On his days off, he would volunteer his expertise and his time to help his fellow peace officers. Needless to say, he earned the respect and appreciation of those with whom he served.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, how can we properly honor the deeds of a man such as Jarred Fontenot, so devoted to his country, his family, and to those with whom he served? No words can match the magnitude of his virtue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Pericles, the great Athenian general, suggested that we honor the sacrifices of soldiers like Jarred Fontenot by reflecting not only on his life and loss, but also on the rewards that he and other soldiers have delivered to the nation for which they fought.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At a funeral oration to honor soldiers who had died in one of the first battles of the Peloponnesian War, Pericles told the crowd that:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Any one can discourse to you for ever about the advantages of a brave defense, which you know already. But instead of listening to him I would have you day by day fix your eyes upon the greatness of Athens, until you become filled with the love of her; and when you are impressed by the spectacle of her glory, reflect that this empire has been acquired by men who knew their duty and had the courage to do it, who in the hour of conflict had the fear of dishonor always present to them, and who,  if ever they failed in an enterprise, would not allow their virtues to be lost to their country, but freely gave their lives to her as the fairest offering which they could present at her feast.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In this Chamber, the greatest deliberative body in the world, I ask that we honor Sergeant Fontenot by fixing our eyes on those freedoms which, for more than two centuries, have endured and prospered in this Chamber and across America. Our freedom of speech, our freedom of assembly, our freedom of self-determination, our freedom from tyranny and violence--these are the rewards that the American soldier has delivered, generation after generation, to a grateful and humble nation. So long as the  United States remains a beacon for freedom, democracy, and justice, their sacrifices will never be forgotten.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To the family of SSG Jarred Fontenot--to his wife, Dana, his four children, to his grandparents Charles and Dorthy, and to his sister--I know of no words that can describe or assuage the pain you feel. I pray that in time you can find comfort in the knowledge that Jarred was doing something he truly loved, of which he was extraordinarily proud, and for which his country is eternally grateful.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>"For where the rewards of virtue are greatest," Pericles reminded the departing Athenian crowd, "there the noblest citizens are enlisted in the service of the state." Jarred Fontenot was among the noblest of our citizens. May his legacy endure in the strength of our democracy.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300064" topic="STAFF SERGEANT JARRED SETH FONTENOT">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, another 2 months have passed, and more American troops lost their lives overseas in Iraq and Afghanistan. It is only right that we take a few moments in the U.S. Senate to honor them. Outside my office here in Washington, we have a tribute called "Faces of the Fallen." Visitors to the Senate from across the country have stopped by the memorial. I encourage my colleagues to come see this tribute on the third floor of the Hart Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I last came to the Senate floor to honor our fallen troops in early August. Since that time, the Pentagon has announced the deaths of 182 troops in Iraq and in Operation Enduring Freedom, including in Afghanistan. They will not be forgotten. So today I will read their names into the RECORD:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To date, more than 3,800 American men and women have lost their lives in Iraq. And more than 440 have lost their lives in Operation Enduring Freedom, including in Afghanistan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This list includes five soldiers from NJ: PFC Luigi Marciante Jr. of Elizabeth, NJ, CPL Terrence P. Allen, of Pennsauken, NJ, LCPL Jon T. Hicks Jr., of Atco, NJ, SSGT Jason M. Butkus, of West Milford, NJ and CPL Kareem R. Khan, of Manahawkin, NJ.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We will not forget them and the Nation will not forget their sacrifice.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
