<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1186027200" ordinal="33" title="INTERNET GAMBLING">
  <speaking speaker="300035" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to share a letter received by our colleagues in the House of Representatives on the issue of Internet gambling from the National Football League, Major League Baseball, National Basketball Association, National Hockey League, and National Collegiate Athletic Association. I would like to include this letter in the Record, which alerts us to the serious threat that <bill type="h" number="2046">H.R. 2046</bill> poses to the integrity of American athletics, as well as our national sovereignty  over gambling regulation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many of us on this side of the Capitol may not be aware that there are efforts afoot in the House of Representatives to legalize Internet gambling, less than a year after we enacted the Unlawful Internet Gambling Enforcement Act of 2006. I strongly supported UIGEA, and supported its inclusion in the SAFE Ports Act, so that after more than 10 years of overwhelming bipartisan support for doing something to stop illegal Internet gambling in this country, we finally have an enforcement law with teeth.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But now, before the regulations for UIGEA have even been written, international gambling interests are telling our colleagues in the House that Internet gambling can never be stopped, so we might as well legalize, regulate, and tax it. We might as well decide that everyone speeds on the George Washington Parkway, so we should just eliminate the speed limits and make it a toll road. Internet gambling is just as dangerous--its 24/7 accessibility from any location, speed, and anonymity make it the</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2046">H.R. 2046</bill> would license Internet gambling companies to do business with U.S. customers and override every other Federal or State law that would interfere with this business. The proponents of this legalization scheme will argue that the bill allows States and sports leagues to "opt out" of legalization, but don't be fooled. The "opt-outs" are vulnerable to legal challenge, both in U.S. courts and in the World Trade Organization. And if the opt-outs fall, <bill type="h" number="2046">H.R. 2046</bill> would result in the greatest  expansion of gambling ever enacted in the history of the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The sports organizations are very concerned because <bill type="h" number="2046">H.R. 2046</bill> would reverse decades of Federal policy by endorsing sports gambling. We have all seen in the past couple of weeks how damaging gambling can be to the integrity and image of professional sports. When a player or a referee taints the game for gambling profits, all of the participants and all of the fans are betrayed. And even when there is no fraud, pervasive gambling on a sport robs its character as family entertainment celebrating  the pursuit of athletic achievement, turning it into a seedy vehicle for making money at the expense of others. Congress must not in any way endorse this degradation of our national pastimes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I hope that my colleagues here in the Senate will join me on the lookout for Internet gambling legalization efforts and will firmly reject and rebuff any such proposals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent to have printed in the Record the letter prepared by the professional and collegiate sports associations.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
</record>
