<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1208448002" ordinal="6" title="WELCOMING POPE BENEDICT XVI TO THE UNITED STATES">
  <narrative>WELCOMING POPE BENEDICT XVI TO THE UNITED STATES -- (Senate - April 17, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="3105">S3105</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that we now proceed to the consideration of <bill type="sr" number="519">S. Res. 519</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="519">S. Res. 519</bill>) welcoming Pope Benedict XVI to the United States and recognizing the unique insights his moral and spiritual reflections bring to the world stage.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="519">S. Res. 519</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="519">S. Res. 519</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas Pope Benedict XVI will travel to the United States for his first pastoral visit as Pope and will visit Washington, DC, and New York;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Pope Benedict XVI was elected as the 265th Bishop of Rome on April 19, 2005, succeeding the much beloved Pope John Paul II;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the visit of Pope Benedict XVI will mark the 9th visit of a pope to the United States, recognizing the historical importance of the Catholic Church in American  life, the deep faith and charity of its members, and the responsibilities of the United States in world affairs;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Pope Benedict XVI has spoken approvingly of the vibrance of religious faith in the United States, a faith nourished by a constitutional commitment to religious liberty;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Pope Benedict XVI remains committed to ecumenical dialogue and, during his trip to the United States, will meet with leaders of world religions and representatives of other Christian denominations and will visit a synagogue in New York City, all demonstrating his commitment to sincere dialogue and unity among all members of the human family;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Pope Benedict XVI has authored 2 encyclical letters inviting the world to meditate on the virtues of love and hope, "Deus caritas est" and "Spe salvi";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas millions of Americans have discovered in Pope Benedict 's words a renewed faith in the power of hope over despair and love over hate;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Pope Benedict XVI has been a clear and courageous voice for the voiceless, working tirelessly for the recognition of human dignity and religious freedom across the globe;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Pope Benedict XVI has spoken out for the weak and vulnerable;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Pope Benedict XVI seeks to advance a "civilization of love" across our world; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Catholics in parishes and schools across the Nation, and countless other Americans as well, eagerly await the visit of Pope Benedict XVI to the United States: Now, therefore, be it</chair>
  <chair> Resolved, That the Senate welcomes Pope Benedict XVI on the occasion of his first pastoral visit to the United States and recognizes the unique insights his moral and spiritual reflections bring to the world stage.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
