<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1182873603" ordinal="53" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <speaking speaker="412247" topic="COMMITTEE ON ARMED SERVICES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, June 26, 2007, at 9:30 a.m., in closed session to receive an updated briefing from the Joint Improvised Explosive Device Defeat Organization.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412247" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, June 26, 2007, at 10 a.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The hearing on the Impact of Media Violence on Children hearing will focus on issues related to the impact of violent television programming on children, including issues raised by the recently released Federal Communications Commission (FCC) report, Violent Television Programming and Its Impact on Children.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412247" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND NATURAL RESOURCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, June 26, 2007, at 9:30 a.m. in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the hearing is to consider the preparedness of Federal land management agencies for the 2007 wildfire season and to consider recent reports on the agencies' efforts to contain the costs of wildfire management activities has been rescheduled.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412247" topic="COMMITTEE ON RULES AND ADMINISTRATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Rules and Administration be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, June 26, 2007, at 10 a.m. to conduct a hearing to receive testimony on Smithsonian Institution governance reform and a report by the Smithsonian's Independent Review Committee.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412247" topic="COMMITTEE ON SMALL BUSINESS AND ENTREPRENEURSHIP">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate for a markup of <bill type="s" number="1671">S. 1671</bill> "Entrepreneurial Development Act of 2007," <bill type="s" number="1622">S. 1622</bill> "Small Business Venture Capital Act of 2007," and other pending business on Tuesday, June 26, 2007, beginning at 10 a.m. in room 428A of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412247" topic="SELECT COMMITTEE ON INTELLIGENCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Select Committee on Intelligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on June 26, 2007 at 1:30 p.m. to hold a closed hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412247" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON HOUSING, TRANSPORTATION, AND COMMUNITY DEVELOPMENT">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs Subcommittee on Housing, Transportation, and Community Development be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on June 26, 2007, at 2:30 p.m., to conduct a hearing entitled "Ending Mortgage Abuse: Safeguarding Homebuyers."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
