<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1167946162" ordinal="55" title="TRIBUTE TO MARVIN VAN HAAFTEN">
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to take this opportunity to offer my congratulations and gratitude to an extraordinary Iowan. Marvin Van Haaften is stepping down from his distinguished position as director of the State of Iowa's Office of Drug Control Policy. He assumed this position after being named by Governor Tom Vilsack in 2002 and has served the State with honor and distinction since accepting the appointment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to take this opportunity to show Marvin Van Haaften the appreciation that the country, the State of Iowa, and myself personally have for his extensive commitment as a public servant. With more than 32 years of law enforcement experience, Marvin has taught extensively in the field of rural law enforcement, particularly death investigation and domestic violence crimes. He has provided local and national leadership on the role of law enforcement in strategic victim safety and offender  apprehension, and is presently on the board of directors of the National Center for Rural Law Enforcement. Marvin also served on many local and State committees such as the Iowa Criminal and Juvenile Justice Planning Advisory Council, the board of the Mid-Iowa Narcotics Enforcement Task Force, the board of the 18-county South Central Iowa Clandestine Laboratory Task Force, and was the third vice president on the board of directors of the Iowa Association</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Marvin knows firsthand the true value and significance of a loving family. He has been married to his wife Joyce for 42 wonderful years and has the blessings of 5 grown children and the joy of 11 grandchildren. It is through Marvin's love of family and law enforcement experience that enabled him to expose the destruction that drug abuse wreaks on families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I share my appreciation for Marvin Van Haaften along with my fellow Iowans for the invaluable service he has provided to our State and country. He has proven himself to be versatile and fully capable of accepting and mastering the tasks placed before him. His enduring commitment to the safety of Americans is cause for admiration.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, I offer my congratulations and sincere appreciation to Marvin Van Haaften for his remarkable achievements throughout his extensive and highly regarded career. His hard work and determination will be missed in Iowa and throughout the Nation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
