<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1211472002" ordinal="75" title="CLIMATE SECURITY ACT OF 2008--MOTION TO PROCEED">
  <narrative>CLIMATE SECURITY ACT OF 2008--MOTION TO PROCEED -- (Senate - May 22, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="4837">S4837</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, if there were someone here from the minority, I would ask consent that on Monday, June 2, 2008, following a period of morning business, the Senate proceed to the consideration of Calendar No. 742, <bill type="s" number="3036">S. 3036</bill>, the Lieberman-Warner Climate Security Act. I have been told that if someone were here, they would object. So I accept that as an objection.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In light of that objection, I now move to proceed to Calendar No. 742, <bill type="s" number="3036">S. 3036</bill>, and I send a cloture motion to the desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The cloture motion having been presented under rule XXII, the Chair directs the clerk to read the motion.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>Cloture Motion</narrative>
  <narrative>We, the undersigned Senators, in accordance with the provisions of rule XXII of the Standing Rules of the Senate, hereby move to bring to a close debate on the motion to proceed to Calendar No. 742, <bill type="s" number="3036">S. 3036</bill>, the Lieberman-Warner Climate Security Act of 2008:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I now ask unanimous consent that the cloture vote occur on Monday, June 2, at 5:30 p.m., that the time between 4:30 and 5:30 be equally divided and controlled between the leaders or their designees, and the mandatory quorum be waived.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>I now withdraw the motion.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The motion is withdrawn.</chair>
</record>
