<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1175184011" ordinal="67" title="DESIGNATING THE FIRST WEEK OF APRIL 2007 AS &quot;NATIONAL ASBESTOS AWARENESS WEEK&quot;">
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Judiciary Committee be discharged from further consideration of <bill type="sr" number="131">S. Res. 131</bill> and the Senate then proceed to its consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will report the resolution by title.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise to talk to you about an important resolution that the Senate adopted today: the Asbestos Awareness Week resolution. This resolution recognizes the first week in April as National Asbestos Awareness Week.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This resolution acknowledges the dangerous nature of asbestos. Importantly, it gives tribute to hundreds of thousands of people who have died from exposure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To me, this resolution is very personal Deaths from exposure to asbestos are common in my home State of Montana--all too common. Libby, MT is a small community in the western part of Montana. Libby is a very unique place.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is surrounded by the beauty and splendor of the Cabinet Mountains. But it is also plagued with sickness and disease. The extent of asbestos contamination in Libby, the number of people who are sick, the amount of people who have died from asbestos exposures just staggering.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The community of Libby suffers from asbestos related diseases at 40 to 60 times higher than the rest of the country. Folks in Libby are diagnosed with mesothelioma, the deadly form of cancer from asbestos, at 100 times higher than the average rate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mesothelioma recently took the life of a very dear friend of mine from Libby--Les Skramstad. Just a few weeks ago, I came to the floor to talk about Les and how he was an outspoken advocate for Libby.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Until the day he died, Les worked tirelessly to share his story and the story of Libby's quiet emergency.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The first night I met Les in January of 2000, he challenged me to help all those in Libby suffering from asbestos-related diseases. Les challenged me "to do something."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He said: Max, please, as a man like me--as someone's father too, as someone's husband, as someone's son, help me. Help us. Help us make this town safe for Libby's sons and daughters not even born yet. They should not suffer my fate too. I was a miner and  breathed that dust in. Everyday I carried that deadly dust home on my clothes. I took it into our house and I contaminated my own wife and each of my babies with it too. I just don't know how  to live with the pain of what I have done to them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If we can make something good come of this, maybe I'll stick around to see that, maybe that could make this worthwhile.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I told him I would do all that I could, that I wouldn't back down, and that I wouldn't give up. Les accepted my offer and then pointed his finger and said to me: I'll be watching, Senator.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have kept my promise to Les and I have worked hard to help people in Libby. I will continue to do all I can to help Libby.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I know that now even though Les is not with us today he is still watching. Les is my inspiration.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of Les's work and other advocates in Libby, we launched the Center for Asbestos Related Diseases in Libby--called the CARD clinic. CARD has screened and provided health care to hundreds of Libby residents.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Screening is an essential part of making sure people get the help they need. Spreading the word about asbestos exposure is also vital to ensure that people who are sick get the treatment they deserve.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Asbestos Disease Awareness Organization is a leader in this fight. They work tirelessly to advocate on behalf of asbestos victims so that thousands more in the future should not suffer the same fate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Along with the Asbestos Disease Awareness Organization, others in the Libby community such as Gayla Benefield and Dr. Brad Black have worked to educate people about the dangers of asbestos exposure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Then there are also those who have left Libby, but continue to advocate on behalf of asbestos victims such as Margy Urnberg and Kenny and Karen Moss, all former residents of Libby and remarkable volunteers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An asbestos awareness week will help spread the word about the deadliness of these fibers and bring relief to those who suffer from asbestos-related diseases. I will continue to fight for those like Les, whose lives have been taken by asbestos. I made a promise to Les and I won't stop until I have fulfilled that promise.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table, and that any statements relating to the resolution be printed in the Record as if given, with no intervening action or debate.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
