<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1173286803" ordinal="36" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="COMMITTEE ON AGRICULTURE, NUTRITION, AND FORESTRY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry be authorized to conduct a hearing during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, March 7, 2007 at 9:30 a.m. in 328A, Senate Russell Office Building. The purpose of this committee hearing will be to discuss investing in our Nation's future through agricultural research.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, March 7, 2007, at 9:30 a.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building. The purpose of the hearing is to evaluate policy implications of pharmaceutical importation from Canada.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, March 7, 2007, at 2:30 p.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building. The purpose of the hearing is to review national imperatives for Earth science research.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND NATURAL RESOURCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Thursday, March 7, 2007, at 9:30 a.m. in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building. The purpose of the hearing is to investigate market constraints on large investments in advanced energy technologies and investigate ways to stimulate additional private-sector investment in the deployment of these technologies.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENVIRONMENT AND PUBLIC WORKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Environment and Public Works be authorized to meet for a hearing on Wednesday, March 7, 2007, at 3 p.m. in SD-406. The purpose of the hearing is to conduct oversight on the President's FY 2008 EPA budget.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="COMMITTEE ON HEALTH, EDUCATION, LABOR, AND PENSIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, March 7, 2007 at 9:30 a.m. in SD-430.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet to conduct a hearing on "The McCarran-Ferguson Act and Antitrust Immunity: Good for Consumers?" on Wednesday, March 7, 2007 at 9:30 a.m. in Dirksen Senate Office Building Room 226.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Panel I: The Honorable Trent Lott, U.S. Senator, R-MS; the Honorable Mary L. Landrieu, U.S. Senator, D-LA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Panel II: Michael Homan, Homeowner, New Orleans, LA; J. Robert Hunter, Insurance Director, Consumer Federation of America, Washington, DC; Marc Racicot, President, American Insurance Association, Washington, DC; Susan E. Voss, Iowa Insurance Commissioner, National Association of Insurance Commissioners, Des Moines, IA.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet to conduct a hearing on "Oversight of the Enforcement of the Antitrust Laws" on Wednesday, March 7, 2007 at 2 p.m. in Dirksen Senate Office Building Room 226.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Honorable Thomas O. Barnett, Assistant Attorney General for the Antitrust Division, U.S. Department of Justice, Washington, DC; the Honorable Deborah Platt Majoras, Chairman Federal Trade Commission, Washington, DC.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="COMMITTEE ON VETERANS' AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Veterans' Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, March 7, 2007 at 9:30 a.m. in room 418 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building to conduct a hearing on the VA Claims Adjudication Process.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="PERMANENT SUBCOMMITTEE ON INVESTIGATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations be authorized to meet on Wednesday, March 7, 2007, at 10 a.m., for a hearing entitled "Credit Card Practices: Fees, Interest Rates, and Grace Periods."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
