<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1193760002" ordinal="45" title="EXECUTIVE REPORTS OF COMMITTEES">
  <narrative>EXECUTIVE REPORTS OF COMMITTEES -- (Senate - October 30, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="13579">S13579</bill>]</narrative>
  <narrative>The following executive reports of nominations were submitted:</narrative>
  <narrative>By Mr. LEVIN for the Committee on Armed Services.</narrative>
  <narrative>Air Force nomination of Maj. Gen. Edward A. Rice, Jr., 4508, to be Lieutenant General.</narrative>
  <narrative>Air Force nomination of Maj. Gen. Glenn F. Spears, 2012, to be Lieutenant General.</narrative>
  <narrative>Army nomination of Brig. Gen. Carroll F. Pollett, 9096, to be Major General.</narrative>
  <narrative>Army nomination of Maj. Gen. Benjamin R. Mixon, 7168, to be Lieutenant General.</narrative>
  <narrative>Army nomination of Maj. Gen. David H. Huntoon, Jr., 1919, to be Lieutenant General.</narrative>
  <narrative>Army nomination of Maj. Gen. Eric B. Schoomaker, 8284, to be Lieutenant General.</narrative>
  <narrative>Army nomination of Brig. Gen. David A. Rubenstein, 6677, to be Major General.</narrative>
  <narrative>Marine Corps nomination of Maj. Gen. Samuel T. Helland, 6309, to be Lieutenant General.</narrative>
  <narrative>Navy nomination of Rear Adm. Bernard J. McCullough III, 4147, to be Vice Admiral.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, for the Committee on Armed Services I report favorably the following nomination lists which were printed in the RECORDS on the dates indicated, and ask unanimous consent, to save the expense of reprinting on the Executive Calendar that these nominations lie at the Secretary's desk for the information of Senators.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>Air Force nomination of Ernest Valdez, 4767, to be Major.</chair>
  <chair>Air Force nominations beginning with Laura M. Hunter and ending with George W. Ryan, Jr., which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record on September 27, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>Air Force nomination of Cheryl A. Kearney, 6145, to be Colonel.</chair>
  <chair>Air Force nomination of Noel P. Kornett, 0523, to be Lieutenant Colonel.</chair>
  <chair>Air Force nomination of Michael Maine, Jr., 4513, to be Major.</chair>
  <chair>Air Force nominations beginning with Michael T. Butler and ending with Robert Cannon, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record on October 18, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>Army nomination of Max B. Bullen, 0248, to be Major.</chair>
  <chair>Army nominations beginning with John A. McHenry and ending with Alan S. Waller, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record on September 27, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>Army nominations beginning with Edward F. Frederick and ending with Gregory Charlton, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record on September 27, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>Marine Corps nomination of Kevin M. Gonzalez, 5053, to be Lieutenant Colonel.</chair>
  <chair>Marine Corps nomination of Thomas J. Keating, 2706, to be Colonel.</chair>
  <chair>Marine Corps nomination of Gerald R. Brown, 2925, to be Lieutenant Colonel.</chair>
  <chair>Navy nomination of Stephen T. Vargo, 7730, to be Lieutenant Commander.</chair>
  <chair>Navy nominations beginning with Gary Tabach and ending with Kelvin L. Reed, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record on October 18, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>By Mr. INOUYE for the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</chair>
  <chair>Todd J. Zinser, of Virginia, to be Inspector General, Department of Commerce.</chair>
  <chair>*Robert Clarke Brown, of Ohio, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority for a term expiring November 22, 2011.</chair>
  <chair>*Coast Guard nomination of Capt. Steven E. Day, 3035, to be Rear Admiral (Lower Half).</chair>
  <chair>*Coast Guard nominations beginning with Capt. Kevin S. Cook and ending with Capt. James A. Watson, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record on September 12, 2007.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300056" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, for the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation I report favorably the following nomination lists which were printed in the RECORDS on the dates indicated, and ask unanimous consent, to save the expense of reprinting on the Executive Calendar that these nominations lie at the Secretary's desk for the information of Senators.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>Coast Guard nominations beginning with Albert R. Agnich and ending with Michael B. Zamperini, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record on October 16, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration nominations beginning with Michael S. Gallagher and ending with Mark K. Frydrych, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record on October 16, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>*Nomination was reported with recommendation that it be confirmed subject to the nominee's commitment to respond to requests to appear and testify before any duly constituted committee of the Senate.</chair>
  <narrative>(Nominations without an asterisk were reported with the recommendation that they be confirmed.)</narrative>
</record>
