<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1195146001" ordinal="75" title="NAMING OF EMANCIPATION HALL">
  <narrative>NAMING OF EMANCIPATION HALL -- (Senate - November 15, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="14568">S14568</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400619" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Rules Committee be discharged from further consideration of <bill type="s" number="1679">S. 1679</bill> and that the Senate then proceed to its immediate consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered. The clerk will report the title of the bill.</chair>
  <chair>The assistant legislative clerk read as follows:</chair>
  <chair>A bill (<bill type="s" number="1679">S. 1679</bill>) to provide that the great hall of the Capitol Visitor Center shall be known as Emancipation Hall.</chair>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the bill.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400619" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the bill be read a third time, passed, and the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table; that any statements relating to the bill be printed in the Record, without intervening action or debate.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The bill (<bill type="s" number="1679">S. 1679</bill>) was ordered to be engrossed for a third reading, was read the third time, and passed, as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="s" number="1679">S. 1679</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. DESIGNATION OF GREAT HALL OF THE CAPITOL VISITOR CENTER AS EMANCIPATION HALL.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) In General.--The great hall of the Capitol Visitor Center shall be known and designated as "Emancipation Hall", and any reference to the great hall in any law, rule, or regulation shall be deemed to be a reference to Emancipation Hall.</chair>
  <chair> (b) Effective Date.--This section shall apply on and after the date of the enactment of this Act. &lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
