<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1211472002" ordinal="80" title="NATIONAL INTERNET SAFETY MONTH">
  <narrative>NATIONAL INTERNET SAFETY MONTH -- (Senate - May 22, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="4845">S4845</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent to proceed to Calendar No. 746, <bill type="sr" number="567">S. Res. 567</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="567">S. Res. 567</bill>) designating June 2008 as National Internet Safety Month.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="567">S. Res. 567</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="567">S. Res. 567</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas there are more than 1,000,000,000 Internet users worldwide;  &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, in the United States, 35,000,000 children in kindergarten through grade 12 have Internet access;  &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas approximately 86 percent of the children of the United States in grades 5 through 12 are online for at least 1 hour per week;  &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas approximately 67 percent of students in grades 5 through 12 do not share with their parents what they do on the Internet;  &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas approximately 30 percent of students in grades 5 through 12 have hidden their online activities from their parents;  &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas approximately 31 percent of the students in grades 5 through 12 have the skill to circumvent Internet filter software;  &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas 61 percent of the students admit to using the Internet unsafely or inappropriately;  &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas 12 percent of middle school and high school students have met face-to-face with someone they first met online;  &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas 42 percent of students know someone who has been bullied online;  &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas 56 percent of parents feel that online bullying of children is an issue that needs to be addressed;  &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas 47 percent of parents feel that their ability to monitor and shelter their children from inappropriate material on the Internet is limited; and  &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas 61 percent of parents want to be more personally involved with Internet safety: Now, therefore, be it  &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--  &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) designates June 2008 as "National Internet Safety Month";  &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) recognizes that National Internet Safety Month provides the citizens of the United States with an opportunity to learn more about--  &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) the dangers of the Internet; and  &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) the importance of being safe and responsible online;  &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) commends and recognizes national and community organizations for--  &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) promoting awareness of the dangers of the Internet; and  &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) providing information and training that develops critical thinking and decision-making skills that are needed to use the Internet safely; and</chair>
  <chair> (4) calls on Internet safety organizations, law enforcement, educators, community leaders, parents, and volunteers to increase their efforts to raise the level of awareness for the need for online safety in the United States. &lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
