<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1193328001" ordinal="44" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <narrative>AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET -- (Senate - October 25, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="13464">S13464</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300019" topic="COMMITTEE ON AGRICULTURE, NUTRITION, AND FORESTRY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, October 25, 2007 at 9 a.m. in room SR-328A of the Russell Senate Office building. The Committee will continue its markup of the 2007 farm bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300019" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to conduct a hearing during the session of the Senate on Thursday, October 25, 2007, at 9:30 a.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At this hearing, the subcommittee will examine sweatshop conditions in Chinese factories where toys and other children's products are manufactured.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300019" topic="COMMITTEE ON FINANCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Finance be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, October 25, 2007, at 10 a.m., in room 215 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building, in order to hear testimony on "Small Business Health Insurance: Building a Gateway to Coverage."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300019" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate in order to conduct an Executive Business Meeting on Thursday, October 25, 2007, at 10 a.m. in room 226 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building. The agenda is attached.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Agenda</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="1946">S. 1946</bill>, Public Corruption Prosecution Improvements Act (Leahy, Cornyn).</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="sr" number="347">S. Res. 347</bill>, Designating May 2008 as "National Be Bear Aware and Wildlife Stewardship Month" (Baucus, Tester).</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="sr" number="346">S. Res. 346</bill>, Expressing heartfelt sympathy for the victims of the devastating thunderstorms that caused severe flooding during August 2007 in the States of Illinois, Iowa, Minnesota, Ohio and Wisconsin. (Coleman, Durbin, Grassley, Feingold, Kohl).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>John Daniel Tinder, to be United States Circuit Judge for the Seventh Circuit.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300019" topic="SELECT COMMITTEE ON INTELLIGENCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Select Committee on Intelligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on October 25, 2007 at 2:30 p.m. in order to hold a closed hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300019" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON FEDERAL FINANCIAL MANAGEMENT, GOVERNMENT INFORMATION, FEDERAL SERVICE, AND INTERNATIONAL SECURITY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Governmental Affairs' Subcommittee on Federal Financial Management, Government Information, Federal Services, and International Security be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, October 25, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. in order to conduct a hearing entitled, "Single Audits: Are They Helping to Safeguard Federal Funds?"</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300019" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON TRANSPORTATION SAFETY, INFRASTRUCTURE SECURITY, AND WATER QUALITY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Environment and Public Works, Subcommittee on Transportation Safety, Infrastructure Security, and Water Quality, be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, October 25, 2007 at 10 a.m. in room 406 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building in order to conduct a hearing on effectiveness of Federal drunk driving programs.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
