<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1177948807" ordinal="19" title="PRESCRIPTION DRUG USER FEE AMENDMENTS OF 2007">
  <chair> Under the previous order, the Senate will proceed to the consideration of <bill type="s" number="1082">S. 1082</bill>, which the clerk will report by title.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, this week the Senate has the opportunity to set a new and better direction for the safety of the prescription drugs and medical devices that make such a profound difference in the lives of our people.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Every day, families across America rely on the Food and Drug Administration in ways they barely realize. When they put dinner on the table, they are counting on the FDA to see that the food is free from contamination. They trust the FDA to make sure the drugs they take are safe and effective. From prescription drugs, to pacemakers, to chemotherapy, to the food we eat, the FDA protects the health of hundreds of millions of Americans and monitors products that account for a quarter of the Nation's  economy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The FDA should be the "gold standard" for safety, but its luster has been tarnished in recent years for failure to protect the American people from unsafe drugs. The public was shocked that the arthritis drug Vioxx was able to stay on the market for 5 years, even though it nearly doubled the risk of heart attack and stroke. Antidepressants used by millions were found to increase the risk of suicide in adolescents. Millions of Americans have needlessly been put at risk, and they want action  by Congress to reform and strengthen the agency.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are responding now with bipartisan legislation that is the product of months of work in our committee. I commend my colleague and friend in this effort, Senator Enzi, for his work on this proposal that will improve the way FDA oversees the safety of drugs. Almost half of all Americans take at least one pill a day, so this legislation will make a difference in the lives of every American family. Our proposals were strengthened by our colleague from New Hampshire, Senator Gregg.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Safety is at the core. Our legislation was guided by the recommendations of the impressive report by the Institute of Medicine on the "Future of Drug Safety." Its major recommendations for reform are included in this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This chart I have in the Chamber gives the major recommendations for the Food and Drug Administration: Build the internal epidemiology and informatics capacity in order to improve the postmarket assessment of drugs, have postclinical trial results in a public database, have regularly analyzed postmarket study results. This aspect about postmarketing surveillance is a key in terms of drug safety. We have included their recommendations. Another is: Give the FDA better enforcement tools. I am going  to refer to that in a moment. Another is: Conduct regular evaluation of new drug safety profiles. We have included that. I will expand on that point in a few moments. Another is: Substantially increase drug safety resources available to the FDA. We have also included those.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So those were recommendations from the Institute of Medicine. We have reviewed the same subject matter. We evaluated those very carefully and we have taken the major recommendations in terms of safety and included them in this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A small number of health systems in America--now referring to postmarketing surveillance and the use of electronic records--effectively links the surveillance of various kinds of prescription drugs to safety databases. These systems--Kaiser Permanente, Mayo Clinic, Veterans' Administration--have the means to examine whether Vioxx and other drugs were being used effectively. They found these drugs were being prescribed inappropriately, and they took steps to curb their overuse. As a result, they  approved the use of these medications only for patients who had no other options. Overuse went down and safety improved.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The use of these databases should not be limited to the few health systems that currently use them. FDA should make use of every aspect of modern health care technology to safeguard the public's health. Mark McClellan, the former FDA Commissioner, calls these kinds of systems health IT for drug safety. Our proposal includes his recommendations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Surveillance is essential, but effective action is needed when a safety problem is detected. Each drug has unique risks and benefits. There can be no one-size-fits-all approach to drug safety. That is why our legislation includes a flexible but effective program for safety. We call it a risk evaluation and management system. It can be tailored to the unique characteristics of each drug. It gives the FDA the authority to act when action is needed to protect public health, but it also contains  safeguards to prevent such action from being imposed when there is no reason to do so.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For some drugs, it is essential to require postmarket studies, yet FDA today lacks the basic authority to require such trials to be conducted. FDA can request them but it cannot require them, and has few ways to see they are completed. As a result, companies routinely promise to conduct studies that are never even started, much less completed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This chart I have in the Chamber shows how, under current law, postmarket studies are not completed. These are the studies that have been requested by the FDA because they are for sound safety reasons. Yet 71 percent of them were not even started. Our legislation says when they are required and recommended by the company, they must move ahead.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In its recent report on drug safety, GAO pointed out the failure of the current system. Its report states:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the absence of specific authority, FDA often relies on drug sponsors voluntarily agreeing to conduct such postmarketing studies. But the postmarketing studies that drug sponsors agree to conduct have not consistently been completed. The FDA has little leverage to ensure that the studies are carried out by imposing administrative penalties.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our legislation solves this problem. It gives the FDA clear authority to require the conduct of the postmarketing studies when there is a public health need to do so, and it gives the FDA the ability to assess fines on those who ignore their responsibilities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Databases and postmarketing studies help detect problems, but the FDA needs the ability to take other action to protect the public health. Here, too, the current law is inadequate. FDA lacks clear authority to require measures to protect public health. When lives are on the line, doctors are making the critical decisions. But because FDA's authority is so unclear, it must first call the lawyers for their opinion as to whether the agency can act. The Institute of Medicine identified this major  weakness of</paragraph>
    <paragraph>current law and called on Congress to give FDA the authority to require risk management programs when needed to protect health. These programs can be as simple as new information on a drug label or an advisory notice to doctors or as sophisticated as special monitoring of programs for patients who use a particular drug. The legislation does not make the decision about which measures should be taken for which drugs, but it does give the FDA the authority to make the right choice for the public  health. This authority has been lacking in the past.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For Vioxx, it took 14 months to change the drug's label to warn doctors and patients of the danger. Because FDA had weak authority, it had to ask the manufacturer to change the label voluntarily, and the manufacturer stalled and stalled. When patients are in danger, FDA should not have to wait to get legal opinions to decide how to protect health. It should be able to act immediately, and our bill gives them that authority.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In many cases, companies have hidden evidence of safety problems. Our bill addresses this abuse by including a public database of all clinical trials and their results. Listen to that: all clinical trials and their results. We protect the trademark aspects of the particular item but require the publication of all clinical trials and their results. A company will no longer be able to hide the results if they do not show what the company wanted.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Some would say any increase in drug safety will inevitably decrease access to needed drugs, but that is a false argument. Consider the situation now. When the FDA is confronted with a new drug that may impose safety risks, or where additional study may be required, with little expectations that those risks will be mitigated by a voluntary approach--and with no ability to ensure that the studies are going to be conducted--FDA might reasonably conclude the risks of approving the drug are too great  and, therefore, not approve it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under our legislation, the calculation is reversed. With this bill in place, FDA could allow patients to have access to the drug, secure in the knowledge that effective safety measures were in place. That is not my judgment; it is the judgment of a coalition of advocacy organizations representing over 30 million patients. This coalition, the Alliance for Drug Safety and Access, wrote Congress a letter saying:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>[T]his legislation gives the FDA the ability to continue to study the safety of drugs after approval, flexible enforcement tools necessary to ensure compliance with these new safety protections, and additional funding to support these new activities. Allowing the agency to act on clear safety signals could actually allow the FDA to approve drugs more quickly, knowing it will have the ability to respond on behalf of patients if safety concerns appear postmarket.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is support from the organization that has been put together that is protecting safety for the consumers. That is the balance our legislation strikes: greater safety, hand in hand with better access.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As our debate continues, I will discuss additional aspects of the legislation, especially its new ideas for accelerating drug development, its renewal of our commitment to safe and effective drugs for children, and its provisions to improve drug science, and increase the transparency of the FDA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are also working with our colleagues from Iowa and Kansas, Senator Harkin and Senator Roberts, on ways to refine our provisions on direct-to-consumer advertising, to make certain they are consistent with the Constitution. We are working with Senator Durbin and other colleagues on the committee on proposals for food safety on pet food. These bipartisan proposals are being readied for floor action shortly. I look forward to further discussions on them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our committee will continue to work to improve the ways FDA can monitor and improve food safety. In this new era of life sciences, medical advances will continue to bring immense benefit for our citizens. To fulfil the potential of that bright future, we need not only brilliant researchers to develop the drugs of tomorrow but also strong and vigilant watchdogs for public health to guarantee that new drugs and medical devices are safe and beneficial, and that they actually reach the patients who  urgently need them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress has ample power to restore the luster the FDA has lost in recent years. The legislation we are now considering represents a bipartisan consensus on the best way to get the job done.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to mention a few additional items. I am quoting now from the FDA's report brief on 2006:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Food and Drug Administration's authorities must be clarified and strengthened to empower the agency to take rapid, decisive action when necessary and appropriate. FDA lacks the clear, unambiguous authority needed to enforce sponsor compliance with regulatory requirements and, instead, relies on the process of productive negotiations with the industry.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have taken that. That is their No. 1 statement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Included in that we have--this is the IOM committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The committee recommends that the FDA ensure that the FDA has the ability to require postmarketing risk assessment and to monitor and ensure the safe use of drugs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have done it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These conditions may be imposed both before and after approval of a new drug, a new indication or a new dosage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have incorporated those concepts, as well as the identification of some new contraindications or patterns of adverse effects.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It talks about the distribution, conditioned on compliance, with agency-initiated changes and drug labels. We have achieved that. Conditioned on specific warnings, proposal materials, distribution conditioned on a moratorium, on direct consumer advertising. We have at least addressed that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It also includes distribution of restrictions for special training, if need be, for pharmacists and physicians. It also has distribution conditions on the performance of specific medical procedures. It talks about clinical trials. FDA needs increased enforcement authority, better enforcement tools directed at drug sponsors which should include fines and injunctions and withdrawal of drug approval.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We haven't taken every one of these recommendations--not every one precisely--but we have taken the essence of these recommendations, and we have included those that are as a result of our extensive hearings. I could go on with this, and will later on perhaps, but I won't today. I wish to mention, finally, the various groups.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We mentioned the Alliance for Drug Safety and Access. I will include these letters of support. This is to Senators KENNEDY and ENZI:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On behalf of the Alliance for Drug Safety and Access, we write today to express our support for the goals of titles I and II of <bill type="s" number="1082">S. 1082</bill>, the Food and Drug Administration Revitalization Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It will continue the timely access of patients to new therapies and will improve the ability of the Food and Drug Administration to ensure safety of drugs already on the market.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="1082">S. 1082</bill> takes a life-cycle approach to the risk-benefit assessment of drugs and biologics--</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is so, though we have not included biologics in this proposal with regard to drugs as endorsed by the Alliance and recommended by the Institute.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are pleased that this legislation gives the FDA the ability to continue to study the safety of drugs after approval, flexible enforcement tools necessary to ensure compliance with the new safety protections, and additional funding to support these new activities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It allows the FDA to approve drugs more quickly, knowing it will have the ability to respond to the patients if safety concerns appear afterwards.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This represents a group of at least 30 different health organizations that have followed this most closely.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have a letter that has been sent to Senator Enzi and myself, Senator Dodd and Senator Clinton, talking about how this legislation impacts children and giving special recognition, as they should, to our colleagues and friends, Senator Dodd, who has been such a leader in this area, and Senator Clinton as well, who has been so thoughtful in this area.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It points out the Pediatric Medical Device Safety Improvement Act of 2000 provides a comprehensive approach to ensure that children are not left behind in cutting-edge research and revolutionary technologies for medical devices. It talks about swift action and passage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The American Psychiatric Association talks about how the provisions of this bill will ensure the Food and Drug Administration is equipped with the necessary tools to enhance its consistency, transparency, and accountability in ensuring the safety of drugs postapproval.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The American Psychiatric Association advocates for patient safety and supports further postmarket research of medications to ensure the safety and efficacy of medications used to treat mental illnesses. The letter says:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We look forward to working with you to rebuild the Administration's reputation and creating a universal drug safety monitoring system that is reliable and dependable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>They indicate their strong support for the legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, another letter of support from the American College of Pharmacy, and it talks about the particular emphasis we have placed on improving science knowledge, which improves their decisionmaking regulatory oversight. Science knowledge grows on a daily basis. We know we are in the life science century. We want that agency, the FDA, to have the best in terms of science and science knowledge, and we have included special provisions to enhance that particular effort, and this association has recognized  that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We also have a letter from the Consumers Union, and they talk about their strong support for this legislation. They oppose any weakening amendments of this important legislation. It also has some reference to some of the recent polls which point out that 96 percent of Americans agree that Government should have the power to require warning labels if safety problems are identified, with 80 percent of those strongly agreeing to that authority. Right now the FDA has to negotiate safety warnings.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It also talks about the strong support the American people have for the FDA, which doesn't have the authority to provide studies to be performed once the drug is on the market. The American people are way ahead of us. They also show strong support to make public the clinical trial studies. This bill does that. Sixty-eight percent of the American people strongly agree the drug studies should be made public.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Eighty-four percent of the American people believe advertising for prescription drugs with safety concerns should be prohibited. Then it continues: Three-quarters of consumers agree that drug ads lead to overprescribing, with 38 percent strongly agreeing and 59 percent agreeing that the Government should restrict advertising by pharmaceutical companies altogether. We haven't gone that route, but we have taken safety considerations to heart.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Then the other letters from the Cardiovascular Association that talk about the particular provisions dealing with children, the pediatric provisions in here which are enormously important, and other letters. I ask unanimous consent that the appropriate representative group of letters be printed  in the Record and the references to some of the editorials from across the country--I am not going to ask that they all be printed, but I will ask that  selected ones be printed in the RECORD and that other newspapers be referenced showing strong support.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="THE SOCIETY FOR CARDIOVASCULAR">
    <paragraph>Madam President, we have very solid legislation that is going to make a very important difference--very important difference in protecting the American consumer. We now have in place leadership at the Food and Drug Administration; for 5 of the last 6 years that has not been so. We have in place leadership, and we are going to give that agency the kind of tools necessary for protection the American people are entitled to and to restore the kind of luster that should go with the Food  and Drug Administration, which is so important to the health and well-being of American families.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Wyoming is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300041" topic="THE SOCIETY FOR CARDIOVASCULAR">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I wish to thank the Senator from Massachusetts, Senator Kennedy, for his outstanding presentation on what is in the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise to speak about <bill type="s" number="1082">S. 1082</bill> as well. It is a comprehensive bill to enhance drug safety and provide key resources to the Food and Drug Administration--the FDA--for the review of new drugs, for the review of medical devices, and to ensure that drugs and devices for children are safe and effective. It has been a long and careful road for this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senate Committee on Health, Education, Labor and Pensions embarked on a top-to-bottom review of the FDA's drug safety and approval process over 2 years ago. This bill is the culmination of our review and the input of hundreds of stakeholders. I wish to speak for a few minutes discussing why the drug safety components and the changes that are being made are so critical to restoring the  peace of mind to Americans who want to be assured the drugs they  purchase to address illnesses and chronic medical conditions can be relied on and trusted.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>"Bipartisan" is a word that is kind of thrown around in this Chamber a lot, and sometimes it means that one person from one party joins several people from the other party. For Senator Kennedy and me, bipartisan means you actually work together to find out what the problem is, what the potential solutions are, and how you can meet those needs. I mentioned it has been a long process--over 2 years--and it is still a work in progress--and we are making progress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We held hearings on the FDA. A lot of those hearings were held in the heat of the moment, when certain drugs were having problems, and we recognize that is a problem. One of the problems with Congress is we usually see that if it is worth reacting to, it is worth overreacting to. We have always taken a very careful view in our committee to make sure that was not the case.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Other committees held hearings on the FDA, even though the FDA is under the jurisdiction of our committee, and we have no problem with that. We have taken the suggestions we have gotten through those hearings and considered them for this legislation. Then we drew up a list of principles, and we took that to the stakeholders to see what all the people involved thought about the principles we had. Then we did the tough part. We drafted the details. It is easy to sell concepts, but details are tough.  Until you have those details put down in writing and have people look at every word that is in them, you can't tell whether you have a bill. But we went through that process. We took it back to the stakeholders. We redrafted. We filed the bill. We had more hearings. This year, we have had more hearings on FDA, and we have had a markup. That is when all the Committee Members are offered a chance to request or suggest amendments to the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We probably had about 50 amendments and we worked on the 12 major categories of amendments. Some of those were worked into the bill as part of the markup. Some of them have been put into the manager's amendment. I mentioned this is a work in progress. We are still looking at some of those, figuring out what is needed and how to get there. I appreciate the cooperation we have had from the Members with their suggestions and the staffs of the Members with their suggestions, because throughout the  last weekend, there were hours and hours and hours spent by Senator Kennedy's staff and my staff and the interested Senators and their staffs to arrive at the best possible solution. We are not there yet. We are close. That is the way we work on bills--a long process with decisions being made up to the last possible moment so that we can have the best possible solution for the people of this country. That is bipartisan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It was mentioned there have been some hearings on food safety. Recently, there has been some real criticism of the FDA on food safety. We held hearings on food safety. I don't want the people of this country to think it is all bad. In fact, I was amazed that three Federal agencies have to work together on a food problem. The CDC, the Department of Agriculture, and the Food and Drug Administration have to work together because each of them has a role in discovering whether there is a problem.  I was amazed to find out that with as few as 50 cases spread out across the whole United States, they can diagnose and determine there is a problem and get products off the market. If you are not amazed with that, you are not paying attention. We have agencies that work together, and they work together in critical times to solve problems for</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But when you consider the number of producers in this country and other countries, they have a tremendous job, and we have to be sure they have the tools to do that job as well. But that is a job that is in addition to the drug approvals. This bill concentrates on the drug approvals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Vioxx was one of the triggers of these discussions. As we saw with Vioxx, the FDA doesn't have enough tools to deal with newly identified risks when those risks become evident after a drug has been on the market for some time. Most of the FDA's current authority is based on information and plans available at the time of approval. They have a massive job determining if a drug is ready to go to market. What is amazing is that once they have given that approval, their options are very limited. Now,  that creates a little bit of a dilemma for them. They don't know everything that will happen with that drug. Yes, it has been through clinical trials. What is a clinical trial? It is a controlled study of people taking the drug, and sometimes people who are not taking the drug--a</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The FDA's choice has been to take the information and approve the drug and then monitor the drug, but have relatively few tools after that point. What can be the result of that? The FDA can say let's really be careful before we approve this because we will have expended our toolbox. They have said: If you will give us a bigger toolbox for after the approval, we can approve the drugs quicker. We can have some assurance that because of the controlled study things will be fine. But we won't have  to worry quite as much about preapproval because we will have tools after approval--tools for quick recognition of additional problems as it goes out to the major markets.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We need to have that happen if we are going to have safe drugs in this country. We have always relied on that, and we expect that. The FDA, for the most part, has delivered.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So much more needs to be done to clarify the FDA's authority, to give them the bigger toolbox so that FDA can proactively react to additional safety information whenever that safety information is discovered. That is the purpose of this underlying legislation. The FDA does have some authority to manage the risks of drugs--for drugs such as novel cancer therapies approved under subpart H for accelerated approval. Is that faster approval? The FDA has the authority to apply restrictions on distribution  and use for those drugs at the time of approval to provide further safeguards against misuse and adverse reactions. However, if such a risk is determined after the drug is on the market, the only option FDA has now is to pull the drug from the market, disrupting patient care.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Some of the people who have that drug are deriving a tremendous benefit from it and are not having the adverse reaction and would feel hurt if it is pulled away from them as the only option that the FDA has. The FDA does not want to disrupt patient care. The FDA just wants to protect patients. Those who need the protection they want to help; those who don't need the protection ought to be able to get the continuing patient care. The option now, I repeat, is to pull the drug from everybody. Then,  of course, they can put it back on the market so it can apply those special risk management tools. We have chosen to give the FDA in this bill the authority to impose those restrictions after a drug comes on the market, too, so there is no disruption in patient care.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also makes several key improvements to how patients get their information through advertising and labeling. The changes ensure that patients get access to new and changing information in a timely manner. As Vioxx made clear, FDA has very little authority to require labeling changes postmarket. Those changes are primarily negotiated and they don't have any time limits on the two parties coming to agreement to the labeling change.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, we have included provisions that ensure that those discussions between the FDA and a drug manufacturer come to a close, rather than relying on the FDA's "nuclear option,"  which is pulling the drug from the market. It hurts a lot of patients and disrupts their care.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Imagine a system that gives the FDA, through sound science and remarkable innovation, the tools to get drugs to the market quickly and efficiently, especially when lives are on the line and people need new drugs and therapies. Imagine a system that gives the FDA new authority to take swift, appropriate, and decisive action to ensure patient safety and protect consumers when new information comes to light to expose unexpected risks. We can make this a reality with the passage of this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>FDA doesn't have a current mechanism for active, routine surveillance of potential safety problems. Thus, it cannot as readily detect safety problems after a drug has been put on the market--short of a catastrophe. FDA has minimal authority to require additional observational studies or clinical trials after the product is already on the market. FDA cannot even make companies finish studies they have agreed to pursue concerning safety impacts on patients.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Given the current FDA limitations, I strongly felt it was necessary to correct those problems and ensure that FDA has the right tools and toolbox to address drug safety after the drug is on the market. That is why this bill creates the risk evaluation and mitigation strategy, or REMS. The REMS gives FDA a full toolbox of options for dealing with potential safety problems, even if they are discovered after a drug is first marketed. I hope you are noticing a trend.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With this new toolbox, FDA has the ability to identify side effects after the drug is marketed through active surveillance. FDA also has the authority to request a separate study or clinical trial to learn more about a particular potential safety problem. FDA can also obtain timely label changes for the first time under the new REMS system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>How does this all work together? A house cannot be built without a foundation. Routine, active safety monitoring using large linked databases--what I like to call "health IT for drug safety"--is the foundation. Risk evaluation and mitigation strategy, or REMS, is the house.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank the Senator from New Hampshire, Mr. Gregg, for all of his work on health IT for drug safety and his emphasis on being able to have the right surveillance and the right triggers to be able to put these things into place at an appropriate time. In designing that house, you can have a small, simple house, or you can have a big fancy  house. The size and complexity of your house should match your needs. The REMS is customizable, buildable to address whatever risks are present for the drug in question. The REMS allows you to build an addition for your house if your family grows, for example. You can also move into a smaller home if you find you don't need so much space.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let's talk about how this would work. Let's say drug A treats high blood pressure, has very few side effects. Therefore, the label and use of routine, active safety monitoring will be enough to manage the risk. Drug A doesn't need a REMS. However, drug B, which also treats high blood pressure, has serious side effects, including occasional liver failure. The label and use of routine, active safety monitoring is not enough to manage the risk. Therefore, drug B needs REMS.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The REMS will include extra warnings on the label, perhaps periodic letters to doctors to remind them of the risks, and require testing and a system to test patients for liver enzyme levels before they are allowed to fill a prescription. As I said, not every drug needs a REMS. However, every drug will need a very active FDA with all of the necessary tools to identify and quickly manage additional risks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Like everyone else, when I purchase a product for myself, my children, or my grandchildren, I want the assurance that the product is safe and beneficial. This bill gives the FDA the necessary resources and tools so that moms and dads are able to trust that product at the pharmacy counter and know that it is safe and effective.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As I mentioned, this bill is still a work in progress. There are a dozen amendments, several of which have been in the managers' amendment, and several are still being worked on. We do want faster drug approval, but we want assurances that as the whole population becomes a clinical trial, connections can be made quickly to any problems without the need to pull the drug off the market and away from those who could benefit. I will have more to say about other potential things that will not be in  this bill that I think would complicate the bill or maybe be adverse to what we are trying to do in the bill, and some of them that have not had enough study yet. I will comment on those as they come up, if they come up.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At this point, I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Ohio is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400050" topic="THE SOCIETY FOR CARDIOVASCULAR">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I appreciate the words of my colleague, the Senator from Wyoming, Mr. Enzi. <bill type="s" number="1082">S. 1082</bill> is a major piece of legislation that aims to--and will--achieve a profoundly important goal. It will improve the public health.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When it is riskier to take a drug than to skip it, the public health is compromised. When a lifesaving prescription drug or medical device languishes at the FDA because of backlogs in the approval process, the public health is compromised.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When pediatricians are forced to fly by the seat of their pants because there is no data to guide the use of a drug or medical device in children specifically, the public health is compromised.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When FDA has the responsibility but lacks the tools to assess the safety or effectiveness of a new drug or device, the public health is compromised.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="1082">S. 1082</bill> tackles each of these problems. It gives FDA more authority and drugmakers a greater incentive to assure the safety of medicines before and after drug approval.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It reauthorizes user fees, an additional source of funding that enables FDA to speed up the approval of new prescription drugs and medical devices.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It reauthorizes financial incentives to encourage drugmakers to test their products for use in children, and it establishes similar incentives for medical device manufacturers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At the same time, it puts more teeth in FDA's authority to require studies when the health or safety of children is clearly at risk.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="1082">S. 1082</bill> creates a new institute charged with developing up-to-date methods of assessing the safety and effectiveness of cutting-edge medical interventions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>You are no doubt going to hear complaints about this bill. Some Members will tell you that it is overly bureaucratic. Coincidentally, that is exactly what the brand-name drug industry says about it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nobody can accuse the drugmakers of inconsistency. They consistently place their own self-interest ahead of health care safety, access, and affordability.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The drug industry doesn't want FDA to take additional steps to prevent prescription-drug-related injury or death, although the drug industry is open to being shielded from liability when those tragedies happen.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When Members of this body stand up and claim this bill is too bureaucratic, don't buy into it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a carefully crafted bipartisan bill. It is less stringent than consumer groups want and more stringent than the drug industry wants. In other words, it is a compromise--a compromise that will improve the public health. There will be amendments to this bill. As Members on both sides of the aisle review them, I urge them to remember this: Amendments that improve drug safety will benefit consumers and reduce health care costs. Amendments that increase price competition in the prescription  drug market will benefit consumers and reduce health care costs. And amendments that weaken this bill or block price competition in the marketplace will benefit--who else--the brand-name drug industry.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The drug industry has more than 3,000 lobbyists here and in the House of Representatives. Last year alone, the drug industry spent more than $150 million lobbying at the Federal level. That is quite a home court advantage. As one might imagine, people who have lost loved ones to unsafe drugs and people who cannot afford to fill their prescriptions don't have quite as deep pockets as the drug industry. Still, this is a drug safety bill, this is a drug access bill, this is not a drug industry bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I hope every Member will consider the bill and every amendment in that  context because in that context, when we vote on the final bill, if we vote yes, we will be voting to improve the public health.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam President, I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="THE SOCIETY FOR CARDIOVASCULAR">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="THE SOCIETY FOR CARDIOVASCULAR">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I was necessarily absent from the Senate at the conclusion of Senator Enzi's remarks. I again thank him for an excellent presentation, with the emphasis on the safety aspects of this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think all of us are reassured we are on the right track, not only as a result of the extensive hearings we held but the very extensive review the Institute of Medicine gave, a highly regarded, highly respected agency. During the course of the hearings, we had very good attendance and exchange of the representatives of the Institute of Medicine, and we have worked with them subsequently in terms of the language and refinements.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As we said, we didn't just copy everything, but the essential aspect of the safety provisions in our legislation is, quite frankly, preferable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I look forward to working closely with Senator Enzi as well on the other areas of public policy in terms of food safety and the follow-on biologics which we are very much involved in as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank the Senator from Ohio for his comments. We know him for being someone who has spent a great deal of time making sure safe drugs are going to get to people who need them. There are many dimensions to this debate. He has certainly been one whom, over the course of time, on the Health Committee in the House of Representatives, I have had an opportunity to work with on a number of health issues. He has been very active and involved with this issue on our committee and also on making sure  we are going to have not only safe drugs but also have access to them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I will take a moment, because I think it is probably worthwhile in the opening presentation, to go through one of the real safety crises we had with prescription drugs and look at what existing authority was there and then how that could have been handled under that legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>People will look through this legislation--it is not all that long, but it is complex. The results are enormously important and very basic and very fundamental. I use Vioxx as a point of illustration, which I think most Americans remember the circumstances where hundreds of thousands of Americans with heart needs were put at risk.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This was really the question--this is the FDA Reauthorization Act--how we could have averted the Vioxx disaster. I think people are beginning to study this legislation, and also our colleagues who are reviewing the record ask about how this legislation can make a difference on a particular drug. This chart is very useful in understanding that point.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Can the FDA quickly detect safety problems with a drug? Vioxx, no. Under our legislation, the answer is yes. Senator Enzi gave an excellent presentation about how that can be done using the most modern technology, using the greatest availability of public and private collections of adverse reactions, and bringing those together within the agency. We know all of that is going to gradually expand in the future, so that agency will have the best of science. They will be able to protect  safety. The answer with this legislation is yes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Can the FDA require label changes to warn of safety problems? The answer with Vioxx was no. They spent 14 months trying to negotiate the issue of the labels. Under our legislation, they would be able to do that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I mention that as one of the things they will be able to do. They can either take the drug off the market--they have the power to do it. It is not done because you don't want to take the chance that there may be some people in the public, given the health risks, who are justified in taking that particular medication, but for the great mass of people, it might not be. Can we put label changes on? They would be able to do it very quickly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Are companies stopped from hiding safety problems? This comes back to what both Senator Enzi and I referenced in making public clinical trials. That is enormously important. Senator Mikulski has been very involved in the transparency parts of this legislation. I hope those in the Senate who are interested and concerned about the issues of transparency might take a moment and talk with Senator Mikulski. Hopefully, she will speak on these issues because she has made a  very important contribution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Part of this transparency is that these clinical trials will be available, to understand the significance of any safety problems, which hasn't been the case, but they will also be available to people who may want to enroll in a clinical trial, who have a particular illness, a particular disease and know there is a particular trial that is going to take place and say: I think I want to enroll in that particular trial because it is taking place. People don't know that now. That is enormously important  and valuable to people. Whoever becomes part of a clinical trial and finds out a particular drug can be lifesaving, it is of enormous importance and consequence.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have the knowledge of the clinical trial in terms of safety but also in terms of the opportunities that are coming up, particularly in this period of life sciences, with these extraordinary breakthroughs we are seeing now--the mapping of the human genome, sequencing of the gene, and I think before long in stem cell research we are going to see incredible possibilities, and people are going to want to become part of clinical trials.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But with regard to responding to this--are companies stopped from hiding safety problems, yes; does FDA have flexible tools to enforce safety decisions--it was expressed very well by Senator Enzi. He was talking about the big toolbox. That is the way we should look at it. There is a variety of tools in that toolbox. He explained that. There are a number of different ways that those who are committed to safety can titrate these different availabilities to ensure safety. Some may require  a heavier hand than others. What we want, obviously, is to do enough to provide protection but not enough to discourage use where it is necessary.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, is FDA the gold standard for protecting public health and assuring access? We are strongly committed to making sure it is. We believe that with the safety protections we have put in the bill and also the inclusions, working with the pharmaceutical industry in terms of PDUFA and MDUFA to try to always find ways of expediting the consideration of these lifesaving drugs--that was one of the very important purposes, giving emphasis for research of many of the areas of health that are of  such concern to the American people: cancer, cardiovascular issues, Parkinson's disease, Alzheimer's disease, juvenile diabetes disease, the AIDS virus, and many others--we</paragraph>
    <paragraph>can try to move toward a better relationship between the companies and FDA, in the sense that we can move this process, move more quickly, but do it more safely. That is what we are attempting to do, to ensure, in this life science century, that these breakthrough opportunities are going to be available and also do it in a way that will be safe. This is an example of one of the challenges the country has been facing recently, between the old and the new.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have tried this afternoon to describe in greater detail the various provisions of the legislation. We have not spent a great deal of time on the provisions which were supported by the Senator from Wyoming and myself with regard to children. Our committee has recognized, through the good work of Senator Dodd and Senator Clinton, the fact that children are not just little grownups; they are children. Many of these substances have different reactions, different impacts in terms  of their development. It has taken special kinds of focus and attention to try to be more responsive to those needs. Our committee has done that. As a result, we see strong support from the American Pediatric Society and others for the way we have addressed</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We will probably have an opportunity to get into some greater detail in discussion of those provisions. As I mentioned briefly in our comments, we have recognized the importance of developing and upgrading the science function in this agency. We think the FDA--at a time we are having breakthroughs in knowledge, in science, in so many areas, we want to make sure the FDA is out there on the cutting edge with respect to these breakthroughs and know where they are going. We have paid particular attention  to those as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Then the Udall-Reagan Foundation is to try to look longer term at ways in which the agency functions and take a longer look to make recommendations to the private sector and to the public sector about how it can be more effective generally. That kind of idea has not been included in the past. It can very well be enormously valuable and helpful to legislators in the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have tried to get legislation that will provide the protection presently, help and assist breakthrough technologies, and provide a faster track for the American people in the future, but to do it with greater safety protections for all families, and to recognize we are at a time of breakthrough science, which that agency has to have, and there are going to be breakthroughs in different modalities in that agency working in the future. We have tried to build into this an agency that can give  us advice so we can be more effective in the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I hope we will be able to move ahead. I know we have gone through, in careful detail, the administration's positions over the weekend. We certainly respect those. We have had a good exchange with the administration.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For those who are interested, if they read through the letter they sent to Senator Enzi and myself, and then if they look at the recommendation of the Institute of Medicine, they will find we are much closer to the recommendations of the Institute of Medicine. We may face some amendments in those areas. We look forward to having a good discussion and debate and the opportunity to expand some of the points we have made this evening.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300041" topic="THE SOCIETY FOR CARDIOVASCULAR">
    <paragraph>I thank particularly Secretary Leavitt and those people on his staff. We had discussions over the weekend. They had some suggestions for changes. We asked for more detail on those changes. We also asked for them to be prioritized. I was pleased they were delivered within a matter of a very short period of time. That shows people in Government can work together and that they do work on the weekends to get these things done. A lot of people think when we go into recess for a weekend,  all work around here stops. But there are dedicated staff who put their best effort into getting together and working together, sometimes in very tense situations and long hours, mostly through the night--last night. Then they have to draft what has actually been decided. It is a very difficult process. We owe them a great deal of credit. I want the American people to know that, too.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Massachusetts is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="THE SOCIETY FOR CARDIOVASCULAR">
    <paragraph>Madam President, we have the legislation before us. We hope those who have an interest and have some ideas, have some amendments, will be in touch with Senator Enzi and ourselves through this late afternoon, early evening, or first thing in the morning. We want to try to address those amendments early in the day, as early as we can. We understand both parties have their lunches and have important matters to discuss, and I am sure this will be among them. But we are ready  for any of the amendments, as I underline what Senator Enzi has said. We had great participation in our markup with the members of our committee. As he mentioned as well, we have had enormous involvement of our committee members and many others over the period since the legislation was reported out of our committee until now.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are still in the process of trying to do business because we think this legislation is so important. We hope those who do have amendments will be in touch with us at the earliest possible time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
