<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1184126400" ordinal="40" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <narrative>AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET -- (Senate - July 11, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="9056">S9056</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="COMMITTEE ON BANKING, HOUSING, AND URBAN AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on July 11, 2007, at 9 a.m., in order to conduct a hearing on the nominations of the Honorable Bijan Rafiekian, of California, to be a member of the Board of Directors of the Export-Import Bank of the United States; Ms. Diane G. Farrell, of Connecticut, to be a member of the board of directors of the Export-Import Bank of the United States; Mr. William Herbert Heyman, of New York, to be a director  of the Securities Investor Protection Corporation; Mr. William S. Jaisen, of Virginia, to be a Director of the Securities Investor Protection Corporation; and Mr. Mark S. Shelton, of Kansas, to be a Director of the Securities Investor Protection Corporation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, July 11, 2007, at 10 a.m. room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The hearing will examine the weather and environmental satellite programs of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, including the role of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration in developing such satellites.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="COMMITTEE ON FINANCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Finance be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, July 11, 2007, at 10 a.m., in room 215 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building, to hear testimony on "Carried Interest, Part 1."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="COMMITTEE ON HOMELAND SECURITY AND GOVERNMENTAL AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate, on Wednesday, July 11, 2007, at 10 a.m. in order to conduct a hearing entitled "Strengthening the Unique Role of the Nation's Inspectors General."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate in order to conduct a hearing entitled "Preserving Prosecutorial Independence: Is the Department of Justice Politicizing the Hiring and Firing of U.S. Attorneys?--Part VI" on Wednesday, July 11, 2007, at 10 a.m. in Dirksen Senate Office Building, room 226.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sara M. Taylor, Formerly Deputy Assistant to the President and Director of Political Affairs, The White House.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="SELECT COMMITTEE ON INTELLIGENCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Select Committee on Intelligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on July 11, 2007 at 2:30 p.m. to hold a closed hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON CLEAN AIR AND NUCLEAR SAFETY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on Clean Air and Nuclear Safety be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, July 11, 2007, at 10 a.m. in room 406 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building in order to conduct a hearing entitled, "Review of EPA's Proposed Revision to the Ozone NAAQS."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
