<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1192723202" ordinal="52" title="20TH ANNIVERSARY OF UNITED STATES-MONGOLIA RELATIONS">
  <narrative>20TH ANNIVERSARY OF UNITED STATES-MONGOLIA RELATIONS -- (Senate - October 18, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="13131">S13131</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate now proceed to the consideration of <bill type="sr" number="352">S. Res. 352</bill>, submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="352">S. Res. 352</bill>) expressing the sense of the Senate regarding the 20th anniversary of United States-Mongolia relations.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="352">S. Res. 352</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair> <bill type="sr" number="352">S. Res. 352</bill></chair>
  <chair>Whereas the United States established diplomatic relations with the Government of Mongolia in January 1987 and established its first embassy in Ulaanbaatar in June 1988;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the United States and Mongolia are both fully democratic states committed to the rule of law;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, in 1991, the United States established normal trade relations with Mongolia and began a Peace Corps program that now boasts approximately 100 volunteers;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the United States has a continued commitment to Mongolia's economic and political development and has contributed over $150,000,000 in aid for that purpose since 1991;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the United States has supported Mongolia's participation in the International Monetary Fund, the World Bank, and the Asian Development Bank;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the United States and Mongolia strengthened their trade relationship through the signing of a Trade and Investment Framework Agreement in 2004 to boost bilateral commercial ties and resolve trade disputes;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Mongolia continues to work with the United States to combat global terrorism and, since April 2003, has contributed engineers, troops, and medical personnel to Operation Iraqi Freedom and has participated in training National Army artillery units in Afghanistan;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Mongolia has demonstrated an expanding desire to join the United States in global peacekeeping activities by sending a contingent of 250 soldiers to protect the Special Court for Sierra Leone, a platoon to participate in the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) mission in Kosovo, and personnel to serve as United Nations observers in Sudan, Ethiopia, and Eritrea;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the United States and Mongolia share an interest in promoting peaceful cooperation in south central Asia; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Mongolia was named eligible for Millennium Challenge Compact assistance on May 6, 2004, submitted its official proposal on October 13, 2005, and had its proposal approved by the Millennium Challenge Corporation on September 12, 2007: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That it is the sense of the Senate that-- &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) the strength and endurance of the partnership between the United States and Mongolia should be acknowledged and celebrated;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) the United States should encourage continued economic cooperation with Mongolia, including in areas such as mining, construction, information technology, tourism, and meat processing, to the betterment of both our economies;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) the United States should continue to work with the International Monetary Fund, the World Bank, and the Asian Development Bank to improve Mongolia's economic system;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) the United States should provide Mongolia assistance under the Millennium Challenge Compact and work to finalize the compact in a timely fashion; and</chair>
  <chair> (5) the United States should encourage greater academic and cultural exchanges with Mongolia. &lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
