<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1181145609" ordinal="37" title="SENATE RESOLUTION 222--SUPPORTING THE GOALS AND IDEALS OF PANCREATIC CANCER AWARENESS MONTH">
  <speaking speaker="300022" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today to introduce a resolution which supports the goals and ideals of Pancreatic Cancer Awareness Month. This resolution is an important step toward bringing the public awareness, funding for research, and congressional attention that is essential for addressing one of the most lethal cancers we face as a Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I doubt that there is one person who hasn't lost a friend or family member to cancer, or knows someone who has. The American Cancer Society tells us that pancreatic cancer is the fourth leading cause of cancer death in the United States. The reality is that pancreatic cancer will take over 33,000 American lives this year, more than 2,330 in New York. And yet, there are no early detection methods and our best treatment is a surgical procedure that is more than 70 years old.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe that we can do better. This resolution encourages communities across the country to use the month of November to bring attention to what we have left to tackle. We need research dollars to create early detection methods, to find effective treatments, and to raise awareness about this deadly disease.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am proud to introduce the Pancreatic Cancer Awareness Month resolution today, and I hope my colleagues will join me in supporting this critical health issue.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300090" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today in support of a resolution that recognizes November as National Pancreatic Cancer Awareness Month. I am pleased to be joining my colleague, Senator CLINTON, in introducing this resolution, which represents a way to educate communities across the Nation about pancreatic cancer and the need for increased research funding, early detection methods, and effective treatments and programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Like many Americans, I have seen the ramifications of cancer first hand. I support this resolution in honor and loving memory of the millions of Americans who have been diagnosed with pancreatic cancer and their families, and for my mother, Jessica Udall Smith, whom I lost to pancreatic cancer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Pancreatic cancer is hard to detect in its early stages as it doesn't cause symptoms right away. Also, because the pancreas is hidden behind other organs, health care providers cannot see or feel the tumors during routine  exams. Because there are no early detection methods, pancreatic cancer often is found late and spreads quickly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This year, more than 37,000 Americans will receive a diagnosis of pancreatic cancer and for over 33,000 of them, it will be their killer. While overall cancer death rates have declined, the number of people diagnosed with pancreatic cancer is actually increasing. It is projected that this year, 440 Oregonians will die from pancreatic cancer. That represents a 17-percent increase in pancreatic cancer deaths in Oregon over the last 3 to 4 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Individuals fighting pancreatic cancer continue to face discouragingly low odds of survival. In 1975, the 5 year survival rate for pancreatic cancer was 2 percent. Twenty-five years later, the survival rate remain at an unacceptably low level of 5 percent, making this cancer the fourth leading cause of cancer-related death. Indeed, pancreatic cancer is considered the deadliest cancer, of which 75 percent of patients diagnosed with this disease die within the first year and most within the first  3 to 6 months. Early detection tools, such as those that currently are available for ovarian, colon, breast and prostate cancer, would make a significant impact on pancreatic cancer, but those tools require a new investment in basic scientific research at the National Cancer Institute, NCI.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In recent years, funding for cancer research has fallen behind the promise made during the doubling of the budget for the National Institutes for Health, NIH. When NIH funding was first doubled, success rates for first submissions of grant requests to the NCI were 30 percent overall and 15 percent for new investigators. Those rates now have dropped to an average of 10 percent across the board. Unfortunately, we are anticipating cuts to other NCI programs that advance research, such as the Specialized  Programs of Research Excellence program, which provides vital opportunities to explore new areas of research.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I support biomedical research and the great promise it holds in the development of new treatments and possible cures for the many types of cancer, including pancreatic cancer. Past investments at the NCI have helped drive new discoveries that led to the decline in overall cancer deaths in the U.S. for the second consecutive year. Now is the time to expand our efforts in the fight against pancreatic cancer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask that my colleagues support this resolution, which will help increase research, education and awareness for pancreatic cancer.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
