<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1204822801" ordinal="6" title="MEASURES PLACED ON THE CALENDAR--S. 2709, S. 2710, S. 2711, S. 2712, S. 2713, S. 2714, S. 2715, S. 2716, S. 2717, S. 2718, S. 2719, S. 2720, S. 2721, AND S. 2722">
  <narrative>MEASURES PLACED ON THE CALENDAR--S. 2709, <bill type="s" number="2710">S. 2710</bill>, <bill type="s" number="2711">S. 2711</bill>, <bill type="s" number="2712">S. 2712</bill>, <bill type="s" number="2713">S. 2713</bill>, <bill type="s" number="2714">S. 2714</bill>, <bill type="s" number="2715">S. 2715</bill>, <bill type="s" number="2716">S. 2716</bill>, <bill type="s" number="2717">S. 2717</bill>, <bill type="s" number="2718">S. 2718</bill>, <bill type="s" number="2719">S. 2719</bill>, <bill type="s" number="2720">S. 2720</bill>, <bill type="s" number="2721">S. 2721</bill>, AND <bill type="s" number="2722">S. 2722</bill> -- (Senate - March 06, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="1661">S1661</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, it is my understanding there are 14 bills at the desk due for a second reading.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will read the titles of the bills for the second time.</chair>
  <chair>The assistant legislative clerk read as follows:</chair>
  <chair>A bill (<bill type="s" number="2709">S. 2709</bill>) to increase the criminal penalties for illegally reentering the United States and for other purposes.</chair>
  <chair>A bill (<bill type="s" number="2710">S. 2710</bill>) to authorize the Department of Homeland Security to use an employer's failure to timely resolve discrepancies with the Social Security Administration after receiving a "no match" notice as evidence that the employer violated section 274A of the Immigration and Nationality Act.</chair>
  <chair>A bill (<bill type="s" number="2711">S. 2711</bill>) to improve the enforcement of laws prohibiting the employment of unauthorized aliens and for other purposes.</chair>
  <chair>A bill (<bill type="s" number="2712">S. 2712</bill>) to require the Secretary of Homeland Security to complete at least 700 miles of reinforced fencing along the Southwest border by December 31, 2010, and for other purposes.</chair>
  <chair>A bill (<bill type="s" number="2713">S. 2713</bill>) to prohibit appropriated funds from being used in contravention of section 642(a) of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996.</chair>
  <chair>A bill (<bill type="s" number="2714">S. 2714</bill>) to close the loophole that allowed the 9/11 hijackers to obtain credit cards from  United States banks that financed their terrorist activities, to ensure that illegal immigrants cannot obtain credit cards to evade United States immigration laws, and for other purposes.</chair>
  <chair>A bill (<bill type="s" number="2715">S. 2715</bill>) to amend title 4, United States Code, to declare English as the national language of the Government of the United States, and for other purposes.</chair>
  <chair>A bill (<bill type="s" number="2716">S. 2716</bill>) to authorize the National Guard to provide support for the border control activities of the United States Customs and Border Protection of the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</chair>
  <chair>A bill (<bill type="s" number="2717">S. 2717</bill>) to provide for enhanced Federal enforcement of, and State and local assistance in the enforcement of, the immigration laws of the United States, and for other purposes.</chair>
  <chair>A bill (<bill type="s" number="2718">S. 2718</bill>) to withhold 10 percent of the Federal funding apportioned for highway construction and maintenance from States that issue driver's licenses to individuals without verifying the legal status of such individuals.</chair>
  <chair>A bill (<bill type="s" number="2719">S. 2719</bill>) to provide that Executive Order 13166 shall have no force or effect, and to prohibit the use of funds for certain purposes.</chair>
  <chair>A bill (<bill type="s" number="2720">S. 2720</bill>) to withhold Federal financial assistance from each country that denies or unreasonably delays the acceptance of nationals of such country who have been ordered removed from the United States and to prohibit the issuance of visas to nationals of such country.</chair>
  <chair>A bill (<bill type="s" number="2721">S. 2721</bill>) to amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to prescribe the binding oath or affirmation of renunciation and allegiance required to be naturalized as a citizen of the United States, to encourage and support the efforts of prospective citizens of the United States to become citizens, and for other purposes.</chair>
  <chair>A bill (<bill type="s" number="2722">S. 2722</bill>) to prohibit aliens who are repeat drunk drivers from obtaining legal status or immigration benefits.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I object to any further proceedings with respect to these bills en bloc.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <chair>The bills will be placed on the calendar.</chair>
</record>
