<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1228755603" ordinal="42" title="EXECUTIVE SESSION">
  <narrative>EXECUTIVE SESSION -- (Senate - December 08, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="10817">S10817</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400064" topic="EXECUTIVE CALENDAR">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to executive session to consider the following nominations: Calendar Nos. 813 to and including 827, except 815; and all nominations on the Secretary's desk in the Air Force, Army, Marine Corps, and Navy; that the nominations be confirmed en bloc and the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table; that no further motions be in order; that any statements relating to the nominations be printed in the RECORD; and  that the President be immediately notified of the Senate's action.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The nominations considered and confirmed en bloc are as follows:</chair>
  <chair> IN THE AIR FORCE</chair>
  <chair>The following named officer for appointment in the United States Air Force to the grade indicated under title 10, U.S.C., section 624:</chair>
  <chair>To be major general &lt;br&gt;Brig. Gen. David J. Scott</chair>
  <chair>The following named officer for appointment in the Reserve of the Air Force to the grade indicated under title 10, U.S.C., section 12203:</chair>
  <chair>To be brigadier general&lt;br&gt;James N. Stewart</chair>
  <chair>The following named officer for appointment in the United States Air Force to the grade indicated while assigned to a position of importance and responsibility under title 10, U.S.C., section 601:</chair>
  <chair>To be lieutenant general &lt;br&gt;Maj. Gen. John C. Koziol</chair>
  <chair>The following named officer for appointment in the United States Air Force to the grade indicated under title 10, U.S.C., section 624:</chair>
  <chair>To be major general &lt;br&gt;Brig. Gen. Stephen L. Hoog</chair>
  <chair>The following named officer for appointment in the United States Air Force to the grade indicated while assigned to a position of importance and responsibility under title 10, U.S.C., section 601:</chair>
  <chair>To be lieutenant general &lt;br&gt;Maj. Gen. Loren M. Reno</chair>
  <chair>The following named officer for appointment in the United States Air Force to the grade indicated under title 10, U.S.C., section 624:</chair>
  <chair>To be brigadier general &lt;br&gt;Col. James K. McLaughlin</chair>
  <chair>The following named officer for appointment in the United States Air Force to the grade indicated while assigned to a position of importance and responsibility under title 10, U.S.C., section 601:</chair>
  <chair>To be lieutenant general &lt;br&gt;Maj. Gen. Mark A. Welsh, III</chair>
  <chair>The following named officer for appointment in the United States Navy to the grade indicated while assigned to a position of importance and responsibility under title 10, U.S.C., section 601:</chair>
  <chair>To be vice admiral &lt;br&gt;Rear Adm. John M. Mateczun</chair>
  <chair>The following named officer for appointment in the United States Army to the grade indicated under title 10, U.S.C., section 624:</chair>
  <chair>To be major general &lt;br&gt;Brigadier General Gina S. Farrisee</chair>
  <chair>The following named officer for appointment to the grade indicated under title 10, U.S.C., section 3037:</chair>
  <chair>To be lieutenant general &lt;br&gt;Maj. Gen. Scott C. Black</chair>
  <chair>The following named officer for appointment in the United States Army to the grade indicated while assigned to a position of importance and responsibility under title 10, U.S.C., section 601:</chair>
  <chair>To be lieutenant general &lt;br&gt;Maj. Gen. James H. Pillsbury</chair>
  <chair>The following Army National Guard of the United States officer for appointment in the Reserve of the Army to the grade indicated under title 10, U.S.C., sections 12203 and 12211:</chair>
  <chair>To be brigadier general &lt;br&gt;Col. David N. Blackorby</chair>
  <chair>The following named officer for appointment in the United States Army to the grade indicated under title 10, U.S.C., section 624:</chair>
  <chair>To be major general &lt;br&gt;Brig. Gen. James E. Rogers</chair>
  <chair>The following named officer for appointment in the Reserve of the Army to the grade indicated under title 10, U.S.C., section 12203:</chair>
  <chair>To be brigadier general &lt;br&gt;Col. Margaret W. Boor</chair>
  <chair>Nominations Placed on the Secretary's Desk</chair>
  <chair>PN2091 AIR FORCE nominations (2) beginning DARRYL D. BYBEE, and ending MARCO V. GALVEZ, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of September 26, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2105 AIR FORCE nominations (3) beginning RICHARD BRINKER, and ending NADIA C. SHOCKLEY, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of September 26, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2137 AIR FORCE nomination of Kathleen V. Reder, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 17, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2138 AIR FORCE nominations (2) beginning SAMANTHA S. BOUSIGUES, and ending JOHN J. LINNETT, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 17, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2139 AIR FORCE nominations (3) beginning JOHN M. BEENE II, and ending MARK E. SANBORN, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 17, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2181 AIR FORCE nomination of Richard W. Jost, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 19, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2182 AIR FORCE nomination of Clevis T. Parker, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 19, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2092 ARMY nomination of Britt B. Hill, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of September 26, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2093 ARMY nomination of Kenneth Carlson, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of September 26, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2094 ARMY nominations (4) beginning RAYMOND L. CAPPS, and ending SHANE RUSSELLJENKINS, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of September 26, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2095 ARMY nominations (2) beginning ANTHONY H. SAVAGE, and ending KARL F. WOODMANSEY, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of September 26, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2096 ARMY nominations (2) beginning GRACE LACARA, and ending CHESLEY D. OVERBY, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of September 26, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2106 ARMY nomination of John F. Kasel, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of September 26, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2107 ARMY nominations (2) beginning MAX L. DIVINE, and ending NORMA TORRES, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of September 26, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2108 ARMY nominations (2) beginning MICHAEL L. NIPPERT, and ending ROBERT C. TURNER, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of September 26, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2109 ARMY nominations (3) beginning LAURENCE W. GEBLER, and ending VISETH NGAUY, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of September 26, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2140 ARMY nomination of Gregg A. Bliss, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 17, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2141 ARMY nomination of Stuart A. Mellon, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 17, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2142 ARMY nomination of Robert S. Gatewood, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 17, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2143 ARMY nomination of Steven P. Jahner, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 17, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2144 ARMY nomination of William H. Smithson, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 17, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2145 ARMY nomination of James O. McLinnaham, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 17, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2146 ARMY nomination of Gregory R. Ebner, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 17, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2147 ARMY nomination of Paul E. Webb, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 17, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2148 ARMY nominations (2) beginning RANDY R. COTE, and ending MICHAEL P. STEELY, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 17, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2149 ARMY nominations (5) beginning EROL AGI, and ending PATRICK C. SEAN, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 17, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2150 ARMY nominations (3) beginning RICHARD S. GLASS, and ending VICTOR F WALLACE, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 17, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2151 ARMY nominations (5) beginning JERZEY J. CHACHAJ, and ending JOHN E. WILLIAMS, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 17, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2152 ARMY nominations (5) beginning MALISSA A. HILL, and ending SOMA R.  WEBB, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 17, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2153 ARMY nominations (6) beginning DWIGHT Y. SHEN, and ending JEFFREY R. LONG, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 17, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2154 ARMY nominations (2) beginning MICHAEL C. AHN, and ending RICHARD P. MARTIN, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 17, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2155 ARMY nominations (5) beginning CHARLES K. ARIS, and ending JOHN R. WORSTER, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 17, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2156 ARMY nominations (4) beginning ERIC C. BUSH, and ending JON A. JENSEN, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 17, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2157 ARMY nominations (7) beginning EDWARD J. BRIAND, and ending JOHN C. SMITH, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 17, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2158 ARMY nominations (3) beginning MELANIE J. CRAIG, and ending PAUL D. STONEMAN, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 17, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2159 ARMY nominations (27) beginning CYNTHIA J. ABBADINI, and ending JUSTIN A. WOODHOUSE, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 17, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2160 ARMY nominations (46) beginning DERRICK F. ARINCORAYAN, and ending D060674, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 17, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2161 ARMY nominations (154) beginning WILLIAM J. ADAMS, and ending D060291, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 17, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2162 ARMY nominations (135) beginning RICHARD K. ADDO, and ending D060598, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 17, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2163 ARMY nominations (256) beginning KENNETH P. ADGIE, and ending D070487, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 17, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2183 ARMY nomination of Lynn F. Abrams, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 19, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2184 ARMY nomination of Catherine A. Oliver, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 19, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2185 ARMY nomination of Timothy S. Allisonaipa, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 19, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2186 ARMY nomination of Daniel A. Strode, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 19, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2187 ARMY nomination of Joseph S. Selken, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 19, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2188 ARMY nominations (3) beginning THOMAS A. BRYANT, and ending JAMES P. McGINNIS, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 19, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2189 ARMY nominations (3) beginning JAMES A. GRIGGS, and ending PAUL R. HUNT, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 19, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2190 ARMY nominations (3) beginning PETER H. GUEVARA, and ending WALTER W. SHRATZ, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 19, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2164 MARINE CORPS nominations (8) beginning CHRISTOPHER M. BRANNEN, and ending ERICH H. WAGNER, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 17, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2097 NAVY nomination of John E. Murrain, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of September 26, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2098 NAVY nomination of Dana Stombaugh, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of September 26, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2099 NAVY nomination of Paul J. Foster, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of September 26, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2100 NAVY nomination of Deborah A. Hinkley, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of September 26, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2165 NAVY nomination of Mark C. Holley, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 17, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2166 NAVY nomination of Michael C. Collins, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 17, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2167 NAVY nomination of Channing J. Thomas, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 17, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2168 NAVY nomination of Evan B. Williams, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 17, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2169 NAVY nominations (2) beginning GERALD C. LOWE, and ending VICTOR D. OLIVER, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 17, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2170 NAVY nominations (3) beginning EDWARD J. ARRISON, and ending CLEVIS T. PARKER SR., which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 17, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>PN2171 NAVY nominations (36) beginning GREGORY R. ADAMS, and ending DONOVAN B. WORTHAM, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of November 17, 2008.</chair>
</record>
