<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1191513602" ordinal="6" title="THE GUEST CHAPLAIN">
  <narrative>THE GUEST CHAPLAIN -- (Senate - October 04, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="12695">S12695</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300078" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, it is my privilege to start off this session by making some comments about our guest Chaplain, who has been a personal friend of mine in Orlando for the last three decades. He has pastored over those three decades the very significant and very dynamic First Baptist Church of Orlando, just recently handing over the reins to his successor after a transition period of some number of years which have seen that particular church become one of the dominant institutions  in the State of Florida; among spiritual institutions, one of the giants.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Jim Henry is, indeed, a great leader in the church, not only among his flock, which was Orlando, but having risen to the position as the head of the Southern Baptist Convention. All of us in this political realm know the enormous tensions that have been raised in the religious community over various doctrines, the interpretation of the Scriptures, differences that arise and cause strife. As the leader of the Southern Baptist Convention, Jim Henry was the great healer, the great reconciler, bringing  together the various sides to, in effect, emulate what Jesus of Nazareth taught.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is interesting, in Jim's prayer this morning, he asked that we all become servant leaders. Isn't that true about the role model that was set by Jesus of Nazareth, a servant leader who said that if you want to be first, you should be last; if you want to be the master, you should be the servant? That principle, laid out in the Scriptures, is one of the greatest principles for us to follow as public servants. What is our obligation? To serve as servants of the public we represent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is with great privilege that I welcome my dear friend and one of the great spiritual leaders of America, Pastor Jim Henry, and thank him for his service as the Chaplain in the Senate for the day.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
