<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1195059601" ordinal="58" title="FEED AMERICA THURSDAY">
  <narrative>FEED AMERICA THURSDAY -- (Senate - November 14, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="14418">S14418</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate now proceed to the consideration of <bill type="sr" number="379">S. Res. 379</bill>, which was submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="379">S. Res. 379</bill>) designating Thursday, November 15, 2007, as "Feed America Thursday."</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300052" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I wish to speak regarding an effort that, in recent years, has received the support of many of us in the Senate. "Feed America Thursday" is an effort, promoted by a number of charitable organizations, aimed at fostering our Nation's spirit of selflessness and sacrifice in order to help those in need.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>According to the Department of Agriculture's most recent numbers, roughly 35 million Americans, including 12 million children, live in households that do not have an adequate supply of food. As I have said in the past, it is simply inexcusable that, in the most prosperous nation on Earth, so many children go to bed hungry at night. While there are often disputes as to how we should address these problems, I believe there are steps that every American can take to help those in need.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The leaders and participants in "Feed America Thursday" encourage all Americans to sacrifice two meals on the Thursday before Thanksgiving Day and to donate the money they would have used for food to a charity or religious organization of their choice. The charities and churches, in turn, are encouraged to use these funds to feed the hungry.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, as I have in previous Congresses, I introduced a resolution that would designate this Thursday, November 15, 2007, as "Feed America Thursday." I urge my Senate colleagues and every American to join me in feeding the hungry and affirming the values that make our Nation great.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="379">S. Res. 379</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="379">S. Res. 379</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas Thanksgiving Day celebrates the spirit of selfless giving and an appreciation for family and friends;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the spirit of Thanksgiving Day is a virtue upon which the Nation was founded;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, according to the Department of Agriculture, roughly 35,000,000 people in the United States, including 12,000,000 children, continue to live in households that do not have an adequate supply of food; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas selfless sacrifice breeds a genuine spirit of thanksgiving, both affirming and restoring fundamental principles in our society: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) designates Thursday, November 15, 2007, as "Feed America Thursday"; and</chair>
  <chair> (2) encourages the people of the United States to sacrifice 2 meals on Thursday, November 15, 2007, and to donate the money that they would have spent on food to a religious or charitable organization of their choice for the purpose of feeding the hungry. &lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
