<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1196787602" ordinal="45" title="WELCOMING FIRST MINISTER DR. IAN PAISLEY AND DEPUTY FIRST MINISTER MARTIN McGUINNESS OF NORTHERN IRELAND">
  <narrative>WELCOMING FIRST MINISTER DR. IAN PAISLEY AND DEPUTY FIRST MINISTER MARTIN McGUINNESS OF NORTHERN IRELAND -- (Senate - December 04, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="14746">S14746</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300037" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of <bill type="sc" number="58">S. Con. Res. 58</bill> submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the concurrent resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A concurrent resolution (<bill type="sc" number="58">S. Con. Res. 58</bill>) welcoming First Prime Minister Dr. Ian Paisley and Deputy First Minister Martin McGuinness of Northern Ireland to the United States.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the concurrent resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300037" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the concurrent resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table en bloc, and any statements relating to the concurrent resolution be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The concurrent resolution (<bill type="sc" number="58">S. Con. Res. 58</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The concurrent resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sc" number="58">S. Con. Res. 58</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas, on May 8, 2007, power was restored to the Assembly of Northern Ireland, opening a new chapter in the history of Northern Ireland;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Dr. Ian Paisley became First Minister and Martin McGuinness became Deputy First Minister of Northern Ireland;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Dr. Paisley and Mr. McGuinness have been working to solidify the peace agreement and to govern Northern Ireland effectively; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Dr. Paisley and Mr. McGuinness are making their first trip together to the United States: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved by the Senate (the House of Representatives concurring), That Congress--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) welcomes First Minister Dr. Ian Paisley and Deputy First Minister Martin McGuinness of Northern Ireland to the United States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) commends Dr. Paisley and Mr. McGuinness for showing the world that it is possible to rise above decades of bitter sectarian violence to achieve peace; and</chair>
  <chair> (3) expresses hope that Northern Ireland will continue to be peaceful and stable in the future. &lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
