<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1206979203" ordinal="24" title="20TH ANNIVERSARY OF THE MEYERHOFF SCHOLARSHIP PROGRAM">
  <narrative>20TH ANNIVERSARY OF THE MEYERHOFF SCHOLARSHIP PROGRAM -- (Senate - March 31, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="2226">S2226</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400064" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I wish to recognize the 20th anniversary of the Robert and Jane Meyerhoff Scholarship Program at the University of Maryland Baltimore County, UMBC.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Meyerhoff Scholarship Program is among the most successful undergraduate diversity programs in our Nation, helping thousands of minority students reach their full potential in mathematics, the sciences, and engineering fields. Since its inception, Meyerhoff scholars number more than 800, with 557 graduates across the Nation and 267 undergraduates and graduate fellows enrolled at UMBC.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>More than two decades ago, UMBC president Dr. Freeman A. Hrabowski, a mathematician, author, and education innovator, lamented that there were few minorities in the sciences and that the education pipeline did not suggest that that situation would change.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Through the generosity and vision of Robert and Jane Meyerhoff, Dr. Hrabowski was able to establish the Robert and Jane Meyerhoff Scholarship Program at UMBC. The program seeks and attracts top-notch minority high school students and is able to provide  university educational expenses as well as a demanding academic program concentrating in science, math, and engineering. The UMBC corporate community is able to use the talents of the students while providing  internships, jobs, and research opportunities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Meyerhoff Scholarship Program has become a leading national model for diversifying America's scientific and engineering workforce, preparing large numbers of African Americans and others for careers in science, medicine, engineering, information technology, teaching, and public health.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On April 4 and 5, the Meyerhoff Scholarship students, their mentors, professors, and families will gather for a research symposium to celebrate their 20 years of progress and success. I ask my colleagues to join me in saluting the vision and perseverance of UMBC president Dr. Freeman A. Hrabowski and the generosity of Robert Meyerhoff and his late wife Jane. Together they have changed lives and expectations.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
