<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1210176002" ordinal="50" title="TEMPORARILY EXTENDING PROGRAMS UNDER THE HIGHER EDUCATION ACT OF 1965">
  <narrative>TEMPORARILY EXTENDING PROGRAMS UNDER THE HIGHER EDUCATION ACT OF 1965 -- (Senate - May 07, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="3929">S3929</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300034" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask the Chair to lay before the Senate a message from the House on the bill, <bill type="s" number="2929">S. 2929</bill>, to temporarily extend the programs under the Higher Education Act of 1965.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The PRESIDING OFFICER laid before the Senate the following message from the House of Representatives:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>
      <bill type="s" number="2929">S. 2929</bill>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph> Resolved, That the bill from the Senate (<bill type="s" number="2929">S. 2929</bill>) entitled "An Act to temporarily extend the programs under the Higher Education Act of 1965", do pass with the following amendment:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>SECTION 1. EXTENSION OF HIGHER EDUCATION PROGRAMS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Extension of Programs.--Section 2(a) of the Higher Education Extension Act of 2005 (Public Law 109-81; 20 U.S.C. 1001 note) is amended by striking "April 30, 2008" and inserting "May 31, 2008".</paragraph>
    <paragraph> (b) Rule of Construction.--Nothing in this section, or in the Higher Education Extension Act of 2005 as amended by this Act, shall be construed to limit or otherwise alter the authorizations of appropriations for, or the durations of, programs contained in the amendments made by the Higher Education Reconciliation Act of 2005 (Public Law 109-171) or by the College Cost Reduction and Access Act (Public Law 110-84) to the provisions of the Higher Education Act of 1965 and the Taxpayer-Teacher  Protection Act of 2004.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Effective Date.--The amendment made by subsection (a) shall take effect as if enacted on April 30, 2008.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the Senate concur in the House amendment, and the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table with no intervening action or debate.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
