<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1197565202" ordinal="52" title="BREAST CANCER STAMP REAUTHORIZATION">
  <narrative>BREAST CANCER STAMP REAUTHORIZATION -- (Senate - December 13, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="15568">S15568</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask the Chair to lay before the Senate a message from the House with respect to <bill type="s" number="597">S. 597</bill>, Breast Cancer Stamp Reauthorization.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The PRESIDING OFFICER laid before the Senate the following message:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="s" number="597">S. 597</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative>Resolved, That the bill from the Senate (<bill type="s" number="597">S. 597</bill>) entitled "An Act to extend the special postage stamp for breast cancer research for 4 years", do pass with the following amendments:</narrative>
  <narrative>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert:</narrative>
  <narrative>SECTION 1. EXTENSION OF AUTHORITY.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Section 414(h) of title 39, United States Code, is amended by striking "2007" and inserting "2011".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. REPORTING REQUIREMENTS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; The National Institutes of Health and the Department of Defense shall each submit to Congress and the Government Accountability Office an annual report concerning the use of any amounts that it received under section 414(c) of title 39, United States Code, including a description of any significant advances or accomplishments, during the year covered by the report, that were funded, in whole or in part, with such amounts.</narrative>
  <narrative> Amend the title so as to read: "An Act to amend title 39, United States Code, to extend the authority of the United States Postal Service to issue a semipostal to raise funds for breast cancer research.".</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate concur in the House amendments and the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
