<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1201798802" ordinal="53" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <narrative>AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET -- (Senate - January 31, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="555">S555</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300078" topic="COMMITTEE ON BANKING, HOUSING, AND URBAN AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on January 31, 2008, at 10 a.m., in order to conduct a hearing entitled "Strengthening Our Economy: Foreclosure Prevention and Neighborhood Preservation."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300078" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND NATURAL RESOURCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, January 31, 2008, at 10 a.m., in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building, for the purposes of conducting a hearing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the hearing is to receive testimony on the regulatory aspects of carbon capture, transportation, and sequestration and to receive testimony on two related bills: <bill type="s" number="2323">S. 2323</bill>, a bill to provide for the conduct of carbon capture and storage technology research, development and demonstration projects, and for other purposes; and <bill type="s" number="2144">S. 2144</bill>, a bill to require the Secretary of Energy to conduct a study of the feasibility relating to the construction and operation of pipelines and carbon dioxide  sequestration facilities, and for other purposes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300078" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENVIRONMENT AND PUBLIC WORKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Environment and Public Works be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, January 31, 2008, at 10 a.m., in room 406 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building in order to conduct a hearing entitled, "A Hearing to Receive the Report of the National Surface Transportation Policy and Revenue Study Commission."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300078" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate, in order to conduct an executive business meeting on Thursday, January 31, 2008, at 4 p.m., in room SD-226 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I. Bills: S. l638, Federal Judicial Salary Restoration Act of 2007 (LEAHY, HATCH, FEINSTEIN, GRAHAM, KENNEDY); <bill type="s" number="352">S. 352</bill>, Sunshine in the Courtroom Act of 2007 (GRASSLEY, SCHUMER, LEAHY, SPECTER, GRAHAM, FEINGOLD, CORNYN, DURBIN); <bill type="s" number="2450">S. 2450</bill>, a bill to amend the Federal Rules of Evidence to address the waiver of the attorney-client privilege and the work product doctrine (LEAHY, SPECTER, GRAHAM); <bill type="s" number="2304">S. 2304</bill>, Mentally Ill Offender Treatment and Crime Reduction Reauthorization and Improvement  Act of 2007 (DOMENICI, KENNEDY, SPECTER, LEAHY)</paragraph>
    <paragraph>II. Nominations: Mark R. Filip to be Deputy Attorney General, Department of Justice; Ondray T. Harris to be Director, Community Relations Service, Department of Justice; David W. Hagy to be Director, National Institute of Justice, Department of Justice.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300078" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, January 31, 2008, at 9:30 a.m. in order to hold a hearing on Afghanistan.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300078" topic="PERSONNEL SUBCOMMITTEE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Personnel Subcommittee of the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, January 31, 2008, at 9:30 a.m., in open session to hold an oversight hearing on military recruiting.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300078" topic="SPECIAL COMMITTEE ON AGING">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Special Committee on Aging be authorized to meet on Thursday, January 31, 2008 from 10:30 a.m.-12:30 p.m. in SH-216 for the purpose of conducting a hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300078" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON FEDERAL FINANCIAL MANAGEMENT GOVERNMENT INFORMATION FEDERAL SERVICES, AND INTERNATIONAL SECURITY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs' Subcommittee on Federal Financial Management, Government Information, Federal Services, and International Security be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, January 31, 2008, at 2:30 p.m. in order to conduct a hearing entitled, "Eliminating Agency Payment Errors."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
