<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1209744002" ordinal="12" title="FLOOD INSURANCE REFORM AND MODERNIZATION ACT OF 2007--MOTION TO PROCEED">
  <narrative>FLOOD INSURANCE REFORM AND MODERNIZATION ACT OF 2007--MOTION TO PROCEED -- (Senate - May 02, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="3742">S3742</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I now move to proceed to Calendar No. 460, <bill type="s" number="2284">S. 2284</bill>, the National Flood Insurance Act Amendments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Before sending a cloture motion to the desk, I told the minority leader yesterday I was filing this and that this would be the thing we would go to as soon as we finish FAA. I hope that it is not necessary to have a vote for cloture. I hope they will allow us to move to FAA on Tuesday. If they do, we will proceed quickly to move to this flood insurance act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I sent a cloture motion to the desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the motion.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>Cloture Motion</narrative>
  <narrative>We, the undersigned Senators, in accordance with the provisions of rule XXII of the Standing Rules of the Senate, hereby move to bring to a close debate on the motion to proceed to Calendar No. 460, <bill type="s" number="2284">S. 2284</bill>, the National Floor Insurane Act Amendments.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent, notwithstanding an adjournment of the Senate, that Monday, May 5, count as the intervening day under rule XXII; further, that this cloture vote not occur prior to the previously ordered cloture vote on the Rockefeller substitute amendment No. 4627; provided further, that the mandatory quorum be waived, and I now withdraw the motion.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
