<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1185249600" ordinal="60" title="NATIONAL IDIOPATHIC PULMONARY FIBROSIS AWARENESS WEEK">
  <narrative>NATIONAL IDIOPATHIC PULMONARY FIBROSIS AWARENESS WEEK -- (Senate - July 24, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="9853">S9853</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate now proceed to consideration of <bill type="sc" number="42">S. Con. Res. 42</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the concurrent resolution by title.</chair>
  <chair>The assistant legislative clerk read as follows:</chair>
  <chair>A concurrent resolution (<bill type="sc" number="42">S. Con. Res. 42</bill>) recognizing the need to pursue research into the causes, treatment, and eventual cure for idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis, supporting the designation of a National Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis Awareness Week, and for other purposes.</chair>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consideration of the concurrent resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent the concurrent resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motion to reconsider be laid on the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The concurrent resolution (<bill type="sc" number="42">S. Con. Res. 42</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The concurrent resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sc" number="42">S. Con. Res. 42</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis is a serious lung disorder that causes progressive, incurable lung scarring;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis is 1 of about 200 disorders that are called "interstitial lung diseases";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis is the most common form of interstitial lung disease;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis is a debilitating and generally fatal disease marked by progressive scarring of the lungs that causes an irreversible loss of the ability of the lung tissue to transport oxygen;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis progresses quickly, often causing disability or death within a few years;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas there is no proven cause of idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas more than 128,000 people in the United States have idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis, and more than 48,000 new cases are diagnosed each year;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas there has been a 156-percent increase in mortality from idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis since 2001;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis is often misdiagnosed or under-diagnosed;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the median survival rate for patients with idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis is 2 to 3 years, about  2/3  of patients with idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis die within 5 years, and approximately 40,000 patients with idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis die each year; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas there is a pressing need to increase awareness and detection of this misdiagnosed and under-diagnosed disorder, and of all interstitial lung diseases: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved by the Senate (the House of Representatives concurring), That Congress--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) recognizes the need to pursue research into the causes, treatment, and eventual cure for idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) supports the work of advocates and organizations in educating, supporting, and providing hope for individuals who suffer from idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis, including efforts to organize a National Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis Awareness Week;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) congratulates advocates and organizations for their efforts to educate the public about idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis while funding research to help find a cure for this disorder;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) supports the designation of an appropriate week as National Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis Awareness Week;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) welcomes the issuance of a proclamation designating an appropriate week as National Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis Awareness Week; and</chair>
  <chair> (6) supports the goals and ideals of a National Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis Awareness Week.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
