<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1197651602" ordinal="50" title="RELATIVE TO THE HANGING OF NOOSES FOR THE PURPOSE OF INTIMIDATION">
  <narrative>RELATIVE TO THE HANGING OF NOOSES FOR THE PURPOSE OF INTIMIDATION -- (Senate - December 14, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="15704">S15704</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to Calendar No. 543, <bill type="sr" number="396">S. Res. 396</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="396">S. Res. 396</bill>) expressing the sense of the Senate that the hanging of nooses for the purpose of intimidation should be thoroughly investigated by Federal, State, and local law enforcement authorities and that any criminal violations should be vigorously prosecuted.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution which had been reported from the Committee on the Judiciary with an amendment and an amendment to the preamble and an amendment to the title, as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>[Strike out all after the resolving clause and insert the part printed in italic.]</narrative>
  <narrative>[Strike the preamble and insert the part printed in italic.]</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="sr" number="396">S. Res. 396</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative>[Whereas, in the fall of 2007, nooses have been found hanging in or near a high school in North Carolina, a Home Depot store in New Jersey, a school playground in Louisiana, the campus of the University of Maryland, a factory in Houston, Texas, and on the door of a professor's office at Columbia University;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;[Whereas the Southern Poverty Law Center has recorded between 40 and 50 suspected hate crimes involving nooses since September 2007;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;[Whereas, since 2001, the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission has filed more than 30 lawsuits that involve the displaying of nooses in places of employment;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;[Whereas nooses are reviled by many Americans as symbols of racism and of lynchings that were once all too common;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;[Whereas, according to Tuskegee Institute, more than 4,700 people were lynched between 1882 and 1959 in a campaign of terror led by the Ku Klux Klan;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;[Whereas the number of victims killed by lynching in the history of the United States exceeds the number of people killed in the horrible attack on Pearl Harbor (2,333 dead) and Hurricane Katrina (1,836 dead) combined; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;[Whereas African-Americans, as well as Italian, Jewish, and Mexican-Americans, have comprised the vast majority of lynching victims, and only when we erase the terrible symbols of the past can we finally begin to move forward on issues of race in the United States: Now, therefore, be it]&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, in the fall of 2007, nooses have been found hanging in or near a high school in North Carolina, a Home Depot store in New Jersey, a school playground in Louisiana, the campus of the University of Maryland, a factory in Houston, Texas, and on the door of a professor's office at Columbia University;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Southern Poverty Law Center has recorded between 40 and 50 suspected hate crimes involving nooses since September 2007;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, since 2001, the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission has filed more than 30 lawsuits that involve the displaying of nooses in places of employment;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas nooses are reviled by many Americans as symbols of racism and of lynchings that were once all too common;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, according to Tuskegee Institute, more than 4,700 people were lynched between  1882 and 1959 in a campaign of terror led by the Ku Klux Klan;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the number of victims killed by lynching in the history of the United States exceeds the number of people killed in the horrible attack on Pearl Harbor (2,333 dead) and Hurricane Katrina (1,836 dead) combined; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas African-Americans, as well as Italian, Jewish, and Mexican-Americans, have comprised the vast majority of lynching victims, and, by erasing the terrible symbols of the past, we can continue to move forward on issues of race in the United States: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, [That it is the sense of the Senate that--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; [(1) the hanging of nooses is a reprehensible act when used for the purpose of intimidation and, under certain circumstances, can be criminal;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; [(2) the hanging of nooses for the purpose of intimidation should be investigated thoroughly by Federal, State, and local law enforcement; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; [(3) any criminal violations involving the hanging of nooses should be vigorously prosecuted.]&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;That it is the sense of the Senate that--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) the hanging of nooses is a reprehensible act when used for the purpose of intimidation and, under certain circumstances, can be criminal;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) incidents involving the hanging of a noose should be investigated thoroughly by Federal, State, and local law enforcement, and all private entities and individuals should be encouraged to cooperate with any such investigation; and</narrative>
  <narrative> (3) any criminal violations involving the hanging of nooses should be vigorously prosecuted.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that the committee-reported amendment be considered and agreed to; that the resolution, as amended, be agreed to; that the amendment to the preamble be agreed to; that the preamble, as amended, be agreed to; that the title amendment be agreed to; that the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table en bloc; and that any statements relating to the resolution be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The committee amendment was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="396">S. Res. 396</bill>), as amended, was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The amendment to the preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble, as amended, was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <narrative>(The resolution will be printed in a future edition of the RECORD.)</narrative>
  <narrative>The title amendment was agreed to, as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>"Expressing the sense of the Senate that the hanging of nooses should be thoroughly investigated by Federal, State, and local law enforcement authorities and that any criminal violations should be vigorously prosecuted.".</narrative>
</record>
