<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1201280402" ordinal="39" title="CONGRATULATING THE STANFORD UNIVERSITY WOMEN'S CROSS COUNTRY TEAM">
  <narrative>CONGRATULATING THE STANFORD UNIVERSITY WOMEN'S CROSS COUNTRY TEAM -- (Senate - January 25, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="366">S366</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the consideration of <bill type="sr" number="426">S. Res. 426</bill>, submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="426">S. Res. 426</bill>) congratulating the Stanford University women's cross country team on winning the 2007 National Collegiate Athletic Association Division I Championship.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution and the preamble be agreed to en bloc, the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table, with no intervening action, and that any statements relating to the resolution be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="426">S. Res. 426</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="426">S. Res. 426</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas the Stanford University Cardinal won the 2007 National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA) Women's Cross Country Championship on November 19, 2007, in Terre Haute, Indiana;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Cardinal won every postseason race and maintained a top ranking throughout the 2007 season;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas in 2007 the Cardinal won a Division I women's cross country title for the 3rd year in a row and the 5th time in school history;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Arianna Lambie, Lauren Centrowitz, and Katie Harrington were honored as All-Americans for their exceptional contributions during the 2007 season; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the 2007 Stanford women's cross country team members are players Arianna Lambie, Lauren Centrowitz, Katie Harrington, Alexandra Gits, Teresa McWalters, Lindsay Allen, Kate Niehaus, Alicia Follmar, Maddie Omeara, and Lindsay Flacks, and coaches Peter Tegen and David Vidal: Now, therefore, be it</chair>
  <chair> Resolved, That the Senate congratulates the Stanford University women's cross country team for winning the 2007 National Collegiate Athletic Association Division I Championship. &lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
