<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1210608002" ordinal="6" title="TRAGEDY IN BURMA">
  <narrative>TRAGEDY IN BURMA -- (Senate - May 12, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="3988">S3988</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, over the past several days, we have seen a terrible tragedy unfold in Burma. The official death toll from that cyclone is unknown. But we know the number is in the tens of thousands. We have tens of thousands missing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>International aid organizations fear we are still in the beginning stages of this catastrophe. It is estimated that more than a million and a half people remain in desperate need of help. They are becoming more desperate every day.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Without international aid and expertise, many of these men, women, and children will likely lose their lives to starvation, dehydration, and disease--cholera, typhoid are two among them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The relationship between the Burmese regime and the global community is complicated, and that is an understatement. In this hour of staggering desperation, the junta must put politics aside and accept the outstretched hand the world is extending to them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Burma is a government run by dictators. They are nondemocratic. We have had problems with them for years. Senator McConnell has spoken on this floor over the years focusing attention on the nondemocratic process in Burma and how the international community should join the United States in doing something about this.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, finally, one American plane was allowed to land in the country--one. This is a start, but it is far few too many loads of supplies. Not only are the supplies having difficulty getting in, but the military folks in Burma are not allowing the international community to help, and they are the ones who have the expertise.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Each day that goes by is a sad day in that country. We have seen the pictures over the weekend of the children lying dead, having died from typhoid.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The junta must allow more supplies, provide visas to aid workers from around the world, and allow those workers access to regions and communities that are suffering very much.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator McConnell and I join together to say to the junta: Let the world in. Let us help.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
