<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1197997209" ordinal="35" title="FURTHER CHANGES TO S. CON. RES. 21">
  <narrative>FURTHER CHANGES TO <bill type="sc" number="21">S. CON. RES. 21</bill> -- (Senate - December 18, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="15893">S15893</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300026" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, section 207(c) of <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>, the 2008 budget resolution, permits the chairman of the Senate Budget Committee to adjust the section 207(b) discretionary spending limits and allocations pursuant to section 302(a) of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 for legislation reported by the Senate Appropriations Committee that provides a certain level of funding for fiscal year 2008 for four program integrity initiatives. The initiatives are continuing disability reviews  and supplemental security income redeterminations, Internal Revenue Service tax enforcement, health care fraud and abuse control, and unemployment insurance improper payment reviews.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On July 23, 2007, I revised both the discretionary spending limits and the allocation to the Senate Appropriations Committee for discretionary budget authority and outlays to reflect that the committee had reported legislation that met the conditions of 207(c) for the four program integrity initiatives. The total amount of that adjustment was an additional $1,042 million in budget authority and $699 million in outlays for fiscal year 2008.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The level of funding provided for each of the program integrity initiatives in <bill type="h" number="2764">H.R. 2764</bill>, the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2008, however, is lower than the levels mandated by section 207(c). Consequently, I am reversing the adjustments made on July 23, 2007, to both the discretionary spending limits and the allocation to the Senate Appropriations Committee for discretionary budget authority and outlays.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent to have the following revisions to <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill> printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
</record>
