<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1195059601" ordinal="31" title="RETIREMENT OF BRIGADIER GENERAL WILLIAM T. BESTER">
  <narrative>RETIREMENT OF BRIGADIER GENERAL WILLIAM T. BESTER -- (Senate - November 14, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="14395">S14395</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300056" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I wish to recognize the service of a great public servant, outstanding Army officer, and dedicated academic leader.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In his latest stint of public service, BG William T. Bester, U.S. Army retired, distinguished himself by exceptionally meritorious service to the Graduate School of Nursing, Uniformed Services University of the Health Sciences, Bethesda, MD, as acting dean from 10 July 2006 to 30 December 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>During this period, the outstanding leadership and ceaseless efforts of General Bester resulted in major contributions to the Graduate School of Nursing, GSN, and to the Uniformed Services University, USU. He assumed his duties during a period of significant change and growth in the history of the GSN and the USU. He lead efforts in dealing with substantial change in the GSN: planning for a new psychiatric/mental health nurse practitioner master's option, facilitating the merger of the GSN and  Navy nurse anesthesia master's option, fostering renewed collaboration with the Federal nursing service chiefs, FNSCs, assisting the USU with the search for a new brigade commander and GSN dean, and dealing with base closure and realignment strategy and requirements. He focused on every issue with unwavering directness, a spirit of community participation, collegial respect, enthusiasm, and a wonderful sense of humor and fair play. His leadership</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Working closely with my office, he was instrumental in solidifying DOD core budgeting for the GSN. He negotiated an expansion of faculty research support with the School of Medicine and the USU vice president for research. He established a sense of calm and collaborative team building by fostering a common vision, always listening to the faculty and staff issues, and addressing their concerns. As a genuine and dedicated ambassador of the university, General Bester often represented the USU president  at external senior level meetings. His career interdisciplinary leadership experiences and the respect he maintains within the Department of Defense always provided credibility as spokesperson when he represented the university and its president. These same qualities allowed him to be an essential advisor to President Rice during a time of significant change within USU, on the Bethesda campus, and in emerging military and Federal health cooperative concerns. Brigadier General</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Uniformed Services University of the Health Sciences continues to fulfill our vision as a key part of the Nation's academic health education enterprise because of the dedication of its faculty and administrative leadership. General Bester exemplifies the best of the best. We owe a debt of gratitude for his years of public service, and I wish to take this opportunity to thank him along with his family: his wife Cheryl, his son Jason, daughter Jodi, and grandsons Will and Jake.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We wish General Bester Godspeed as he returns to his family and Texas where his children and grandchildren now live.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
