<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1201194002" ordinal="37" title="NOTICES OF HEARINGS">
  <narrative>NOTICES OF HEARINGS -- (Senate - January 24, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="300">S300</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND NATURAL RESOURCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to announce for the information of the Senate and the public that a hearing has been scheduled before the Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. The hearing will be held on Wednesday, February 6, 2008, at 10 a.m., in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the hearing is to receive testimony on the U.S. Department of Energy's budget for fiscal year 2009.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of the limited time available for the hearing, witnesses may testify by invitation only. However, those wishing to submit written testimony for the hearing record may do so by sending it to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, United States Senate, Washington, D.C. 20510-6150, or by e-mail to Rosemarie</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For further information, please contact Jonathan Epstein or Rosemarie Calabro.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to announce for the information of the Senate and the public that an oversight hearing has been scheduled before the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The hearing will be held on Thursday, February 14, 2008, at 9:30 a.m. in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the hearing is to consider the President's fiscal year 2009 budget request for the USDA Forest Service.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of the limited time available for the hearing, witnesses may testify by invitation only. However, those wishing to submit written testimony for the hearing record should send two copies of their testimony to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, United States Senate, Washington, D.C. 20510-6150, or by e-mail to rachel</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For further information, please contact Scott Miller or Rachel Pasternack.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
