<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1171688400" ordinal="9" title="CONDITIONAL RECESS OR ADJOURNMENT OF BOTH HOUSES OF CONGRESS">
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, the Republicans did not want to adjourn the other day because they wanted another chance to vote on Iraq. The majority of the Senate just voted on Iraq and the majority of the Senate is against the escalation in Iraq. We have had that other vote they have chosen, so now I ask the Senate to turn to the consideration of <bill type="hc" number="67">H. Con. Res. 67</bill>, the adjournment resolution, and that the Senate proceed to vote on passage of the resolution, with no intervening action or debate.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300091" topic="">
    <paragraph>Reserving the right to object.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300091" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask for the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there a sufficient second?</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will call the roll.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>I announce that the Senator from South Dakota (Mr. JOHNSON), the Senator from Massachusetts (Mr. KENNEDY), the Senator from New Jersey (Mr. LAUTENBERG), and the Senator from Florida (Mr. NELSON) are necessarily absent.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300069" topic="">
    <paragraph>The following Senators were necessarily absent: the Senator from Utah (Mr. BENNETT), the Senator from Missouri (Mr. BOND), the Senator from Kansas (Mr. BROWNBACK), the Senator from North Carolina (Mr. BURR), the Senator from Georgia (Mr. CHAMBLISS), the Senator from Mississippi (Mr. COCHRAN), the Senator from Tennessee (Mr. CORKER), the Senator from Nevada (Mr. ENSIGN), the Senator from Utah (Mr. HATCH), the Senator from  Georgia (Mr. ISAKSON), the Senator from Arizona (Mr. KYL), the Senator from Arizona (Mr. MCCAIN), the Senator from Alaska (Ms. MURKOWSKI), the Senator from Pennsylvania (Mr. SPECTER), the Senator from Alaska (Mr. STEVENS), and the Senator from Ohio (Mr. VOINOVICH).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Are there any other Senators in the Chamber desiring to vote?</chair>
  <narrative>The result was announced--yeas 47, nays 33, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400064" topic="">
    <paragraph>I move to reconsider the vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412244" topic="">
    <paragraph>I move to lay that motion on the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The motion to lay on the table was agreed to.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400064" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
