<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1208966402" ordinal="35" title="SUBMITTED RESOLUTIONS">
  <narrative>SUBMITTED RESOLUTIONS -- (Senate - April 23, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="3309">S3309</bill>]</narrative>
  <narrative>Mr. SPECTER (for himself and Mr. CASEY) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="sr" number="529">S. Res. 529</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas the Greater Philadelphia Association of Realtors, which was 1 of the 3 original chapters of the National Association of Realtors, was founded January 10, 1908, in the City of Philadelphia;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Greater Philadelphia Association of Realtors has worked to improve the neighborhoods, business communities, and real estate markets in the City of Philadelphia and its suburbs; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the members of the Greater Philadelphia Association of Realtors continue to do excellent work in strengthening the economy of the United States and making the American dream of homeownership a reality: Now, therefore, be it</narrative>
  <narrative> Resolved, That the Senate commemorates the 100th Anniversary of the founding of the Greater Philadelphia Association of Realtors.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300092" topic="SENATE RESOLUTION 529--COMMEMORATING THE 110TH ANNIVERSARY OF THE FOUNDING OF THE GREATER PHILADELPHIA ASSOCIATION OF REALTORS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I have sought recognition to introduce a Senate resolution congratulating the Greater Philadelphia Association of Realtors on its 100th anniversary.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Greater Philadelphia Association of Realtors was founded on January 10, 1908, as the Philadelphia Real Estate Brokers Association, when loosely knit neighborhood broker groups joined together and brought order to Philadelphia's real estate market. It was one of the three original chapters of the National Association of Realtors. Since that time, the Association has become the most influential professional real estate association in the Philadelphia region.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over its 100 year existence, the Greater Philadelphia Association of Realtors has sought to improve the neighborhoods, business communities, and real estate markets in Philadelphia and its suburbs. I commend the Association for its work to improve Philadelphia's communities by helping individuals and families achieve the American Dream of homeownership.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to join me in congratulating the Greater Philadelphia Association of Realtors.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
