<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1167946162" ordinal="37" title="AGENDA FOR COLORADO">
  <speaking speaker="300003" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today we start the 110th Congress of the United States. We embark on a 2-year journey to submit, consider, debate, improve, and eventually pass legislation on behalf of the greater good of our constituents and the American people. Accordingly, I have here today a package of legislative proposals which I believe will benefit Colorado and the country. This package is the first chapter of what I hope becomes a legislative agenda for Colorado and the Nation. These 15 bills  address matters from healthcare to housing, land usage to veterans, and Homeland Security to drug trafficking prevention.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These bills are:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Methamphetamine Trafficking Enforcement Act of 2007;  the Medicare Cost Contract Extension and Refinement Act of 2007;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>the Mark-to-Market Extension Act of 2007; the National Domestic Preparedness Consortium Expansion Act of 2007;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>the National Trails System Willing Seller Act of 2007; the Pikes Peak Regional Veteran's Cemetery Act of 2007;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>the Pinon Canyon Expansion Citizen's Input Act of 2007; the Arkansas Valley Conduit Act;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>the Increase Computer Efficiency Study Act of 2007;  the Mesa Verde National Park Boundary Expansion Act of 2007;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>the Baca National Wildlife Refuge Purpose Act;  the Cache la Poudre River National Heritage Area Technical Amendments Act of 2007;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>the Satellite and Cable Access Act of 2007;  the Granada Relocation Center National Historic Site Act of 2007;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>and a Ronald Reagan U.S. Capitol Artistic Tribute Resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, this agenda of 15 bills represents many hours of work with Colorado citizens, officials, interested parties, and stakeholders. It is a set of fairly controversy-free proposals that will solve problems and offer solutions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I intend to return to this floor with a second round of legislative proposals, proposals that I am now working on with colleagues, State officials, and Colorado stakeholders. Other measures I plan to address this session include Good Samaritan mine cleanups, bark beetle eradication legislation, Rocky Mt. National Park Wilderness, National ID theft/Social Security number protection, renewable energy tax credits, reverse mortgages, the need for public health veterinarians, oil shale royalties,  and manufactured housing reform.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I look forward to working with my colleagues on getting these bills through the legislative process and being able to tell Coloradans that we in Washington are engaged on their behalf.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(The remarks of Mr. ALLARD pertaining to the submission of <bill type="sc" number="1">S. Con. Res. 1</bill> are located in today's RECORD under "Submission of Concurrent and Senate Resolutions.")</narrative>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400619" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
