<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1209398404" ordinal="61" title="SUPPORTING UKRAINE AND GEORGIA BECOMING MEMBERS OF NATO">
  <narrative>SUPPORTING UKRAINE AND GEORGIA BECOMING MEMBERS OF NATO -- (Senate - April 28, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="3451">S3451</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of Calendar No. 710, <bill type="sr" number="523">S. Res. 523</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <chair>The assistant legislative clerk read as follows:</chair>
  <chair>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="523">S. Res. 523</bill>) expressing the strong support of the Senate for the declaration of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization at the Bucharest Summit that Ukraine  and Georgia will become members of the alliance.</chair>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I further ask the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table, with no intervening action or debate, and any statements be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="523">S. Res. 523</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="523">S. Res. 523</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas, prior to the Bucharest Summit in April 2008, the Government of Georgia and the Government of Ukraine each expressed the desire to join the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO), have committed their countries to programs of reforms consistent with membership in the Euro-Atlantic community, and have worked consistently for membership in NATO; and</chair>
  <chair>Whereas, in April 2008 at the Bucharest Summit, the assembled leaders of NATO issued the following statement: "NATO welcomes Ukraine's and Georgia's Euro-Atlantic aspirations for membership in NATO. We agreed today that these countries will become members of NATO. Both nations have made valuable contributions to Alliance operations. We welcome the democratic reforms in Ukraine and Georgia and look forward to free and fair parliamentary elections in Georgia in May. MAP is the next step for Ukraine  and Georgia on their direct way to membership. Today we make clear that we support these countries' applications for MAP. Therefore we will now begin a period of intensive engagement with both at a high political level to address the questions still outstanding</chair>
  <chair> (3) urges the foreign ministers of NATO member states at their meeting in December 2008 to consider favorably the applications of the governments of Ukraine and Georgia for Membership Action Plans.    &lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
