<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1191513602" ordinal="63" title="EXECUTIVE SESSION">
  <narrative>EXECUTIVE SESSION -- (Senate - October 04, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="12825">S12825</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="EXECUTIVE CALENDAR">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to executive session to consider the following nominations: Executive Calendar Nos. 303, 304, 310 through 331, and the nominations reported earlier today by the Judiciary Committee: Thomas P. O'Brien, of California, to be U.S. attorney, and Edward Meacham Yarbrough, of Tennessee, to be U.S. attorney; that the nominations be confirmed, the motions to reconsider be laid on the table, the President be immediately notified of  the Senate's action, and the Senate then return to legislative session.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The nominations considered and confirmed are as follows:</chair>
  <chair>Patrick P. Shen, of Maryland, to be Special Counsel for Immigration-Related Unfair Employment Practices for a term of four years.</chair>
  <chair>Donald M. Kerr, of Virginia, to be Principal Deputy Director of National Intelligence.</chair>
  <chair>Robert Charles Tapella, of Virginia, to be Public Printer.</chair>
  <chair>Kristine Mary Miller, of Colorado, to be a Member of the Board of Trustees of the Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Arts Development for a term expiring May 19, 2010.</chair>
  <chair>Brenda L. Kingery, of Texas, to be a Member of the Board of Trustees of the Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Arts Development for a term expiring May 19, 2012.</chair>
  <chair>Julie E. Kitka, of Alaska, to be a Member of the Board of Trustees of the Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Arts Development for a term expiring May 19, 2012.</chair>
  <chair>Sonya Kelliher-Combs, of Alaska, to be a Member of the Board of Trustees of the Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Arts Development for a term expiring May 19, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>Perry R. Eaton, of Alaska, to be a Member of the Board of Trustees of the Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Arts Development for a term expiring May 19, 2012.</chair>
  <chair>James Russell Dedrick, of Tennessee, to be United States Attorney for the Eastern District of Tennessee for the term of four years.</chair>
  <chair>Paul J. Hutter, of Virginia, to be General Counsel, Department of Veterans Affairs.</chair>
  <chair>Thomas P. O'Brien, of California, to be United States Attorney for the Central District of California for the term of four years.</chair>
  <chair>Edward Meacham Yarbrough, of Tennessee, to be United States Attorney for the Middle District of Tennessee for the term of four years.</chair>
</record>
