<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1222444802" ordinal="121" title="PECHANGA BAND OF LUISENO MISSION INDIANS LAND TRANSFER ACT OF 2007">
  <narrative>PECHANGA BAND OF LUISENO MISSION INDIANS LAND TRANSFER ACT OF 2007 -- (Senate - September 26, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="9851">S9851</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412247" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of Calendar No. 1081, <bill type="h" number="2963">H.R. 2963</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the bill by title.</chair>
  <chair>The assistant legislative clerk read as follows:</chair>
  <chair>A bill (<bill type="h" number="2963">H.R. 2963</bill>) to transfer certain land in Riverside County, California, and San Diego County, California, from the Bureau of Land Management to the United States to be held in trust for the Pechanga Band of Luiseno Mission Indians, and for other purposes.</chair>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the bill, which had been reported from the Committee on Indian Affairs, with amendments, as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>[Omit the part within boldface brackets and insert the part printed in italic]</narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "Pechanga Band of Luiseno Mission Indians Land Transfer Act of 2007".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. TRANSFER OF LAND IN TRUST FOR PECHANGA BAND OF LUISENO MISSION INDIANS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Transfer and Administration.--</narrative>
  <narrative> (1) TRANSFER.--Effective on the date of the enactment of this Act and subject to valid existing rights, all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the Federal lands described in subsection (b) (including all improvements thereon, appurtenances thereto, and rights to all minerals thereon or therein, including oil and gas, water, and related resources) shall be held by the United States in trust for the Pechanga Band of Luiseno Mission Indians, a federally recognized  Indian tribe. Such transfer shall not include the 12.82 acres of lands more or less, including the facilities, improvements, and appurtenances associated with the existing 230 kV transmission line in San Diego County and its 300 foot corridor, more particularly described as a portion of sec. 6, T.</narrative>
  <narrative> (B) under any Federal law (including the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act (25 U.S.C. 2701 et seq.) (including any regulations promulgated by the Secretary or the National Indian Gaming Commission under that Act)).&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412247" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the committee-reported amendments be agreed to, the bill, as amended, be read a third time and passed, the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table, with no interviewing action or debate, and any statements relating to this measure be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The committee amendments were agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The amendments were ordered to be engrossed and the bill to be read a third time.</chair>
  <chair>The bill (<bill type="h" number="2963">H.R. 2963</bill>), as amended, was read the third time, and passed.</chair>
</record>
