<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1175184011" ordinal="9" title="U.S. TROOP READINESS, VETERANS' HEALTH, AND IRAQ ACCOUNTABILITY ACT, 2007">
  <chair> Under the previous order, the Senate will resume consideration of <bill type="h" number="1591">H.R. 1591</bill>, which the clerk will report.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I understand under the order that there will be 4 minutes equally divided before each amendment. The first amendment we are considering is the Ensign amendment; is that correct?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> That is correct.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="">
    <paragraph>I see the Senator from Nevada is on the floor, so I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300040" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I understand a modification of my amendment is at the desk. I call it up.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> That is correct. The clerk will report.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300040" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the reading of the amendment be dispensed with.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300040" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, very simply, this amendment reduces spending for the Educational and Cultural Exchange Program fund in order to provide spending for implementation of the Adam Walsh Act. My amendment provides funding for the United States Attorneys to prosecute sexual predators who target children and also for the United States Marshals to track down the nearly 100,000 sex offenders in the United States who have failed to register as a sex offender as required by law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill before the Senate is an emergency spending bill. I strongly believe that funding the critical programs contained in the Adam Walsh Act is an emergency: 100,000 predators on our streets who are unregistered as sex offenders. They need to be registered. So that parents know where they are so that they can protect their children. That is an emergency.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I know some people hold the sincere belief that the Educational and Cultural Exchange program is very worthwhile. I don't question their opinion, but I question whether funding it is truly an emergency. I want to give a few examples of the kind of projects that the Educational and Cultural Exchange program funds. Last year, according to the State Department Web site, this program funded the following: We sent a bluegrass band to China. We taught weaving and dyeing techniques with Uzbek women.  We sent jazz musicians to Madagascar. We paid for breakdancers to tour Denmark, Argentina, Croatia, and Kiev. Those may be worthy cross-cultural activities to pursue, but I cannot stand here and suggest they are emergencies that are of greater need to fund than providing law enforcement with the resources need to protect our children, especially at a time of war.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let's use emergency funding for real emergencies in this country. If you are a parent today and you have children out there, knowing where those sex offenders are so you can keep your children safe I would say does constitute an emergency. I recommend and urge my colleagues to support this important amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, as a former prosecutor I am a strong supporter of the Marshals Service.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have the Commerce, Justice, Science appropriations bill to fund the U.S. Marshals Service, and there is already $25 million in this bill to support their important work, which is $11 million more than was requested by the President.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The amendment offered by the Senator from Nevada has a lot of appeal. Who would not want to support additional funding for the U.S. Marshals Service, or for a whole lot of other programs, for that matter. Police, fire departments, hospitals, schools--the list is limitless.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is unfortunate that the Senator's amendment would be paid for by cutting $15 million in this supplemental bill, requested by the President, to fund international educational and cultural exchange programs. In other words, he reaches across subcommittees to a completely different budget from that which funds the Marshals Service. That is a mistake. It is a road we should not go down.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Should we also take money to train teachers in Afghanistan and use it instead to refurbish public schools in the United States? What about cutting funding for reconstruction in Lebanon to pay for new vehicles and equipment for our police and fire departments? Or we could cut the funding in this bill to combat the spread of avian flu and use it instead for victims of crime programs or drug treatment programs here at home.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Any of those amendments would pass overwhelmingly in the Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But is that really how we want to do our business? The reputation of the United States today has taken a beating unparalleled in our history. We are reviled in the Muslim world. Even our traditional allies have lost faith in our leadership. During his recent trip to Latin America, President Bush encountered this hostility at every stop.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our image has been tarnished, our influence badly eroded. This is an emergency bill to combat terrorism, and  these educational exchange programs, which provide Muslim students and professionals the opportunity to come to the United States for education and training, are among the most effective ways we have of combating extremism.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Exchanges have been shown to reverse negative perceptions and the spread of hatred. There are far too few tools at our fingertips that are this effective.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These funds would support, for example, a first-ever Islamic dialogue two-way exchange program to foster interfaith dialogue, sports exchanges to engage youth and provide the opportunity to visit the United States and summer programs for Muslim students to learn English. This amendment would cut $15 million in this bill for these programs, leaving only $10 million for educational and cultural exchanges for the whole world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I share the Senator's concerns about the Adam Walsh Child Safety and Protection Act. We should increase funding for the Marshals Service. But this bill is not the place to do that. This bill is about combating terrorism and responding to humanitarian emergencies overseas. It would be a serious mistake to reduce funding for exchange programs that have strong bipartisan support. The President requested these funds, and he was right to do so. We cannot only look inward. We must look outward as well.  No programs are more effective in countering the negative attitudes about America than the exchanges that bring people here from countries such as Egypt, Indonesia, Lebanon, and Pakistan to meet Americans and experience what life is like in the world's oldest democracy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I support the intent of the amendment of the Senator from Nevada and will reluctantly vote for it, but if he had been willing, I would have been happy to have worked with him to obtain additional funds for the Marshals Service in the appropriate funding bill. Unfortunately he was not.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300042" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I supported that Ensign amendment today because it is vitally important that we protect our children against sexual predators. I did so despite my serious concern about the offset used to pay for the program. We should not be cutting funding from the State Department's Bureau of Education and Cultural Exchange, ECA. I strongly believe that people-to-people exchange is one of the most effective public diplomacy tools we have, and I hope that funding for the ECA will  be restored in conference.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the remainder of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Washington.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, the Ensign amendment, as modified, is an amendment that is acceptable to this side. I ask my colleague from Nevada if he is willing to take a voice vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300040" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask for the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I understand the Senator wants a rollcall vote on this amendment. We will move to that vote. We support the amendment on this side and yield back our time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask for the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there a sufficient second? There appears to be a sufficient second.</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will call the roll.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>I announce that the Senator from Indiana (Mr. Bayh), the Senator from New York (Mrs. Clinton), the Senator from Hawaii (Mr. Inouye), the Senator from South Dakota (Mr. Johnson), the Senator from Connecticut (Mr. Lieberman), and the Senator from Florida (Mr. Nelson) are necessarily absent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I further announce that, if present and voting, the Senator from New York (Mrs. Clinton) and the Senator from Florida (Mr. Nelson) would each vote "yea."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300069" topic="">
    <paragraph>The following Senator is necessarily absent: the Senator from Wyoming (Mr. Enzi).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Are there any other Senators in the Chamber desiring to vote?</chair>
  <narrative>The result was announced--yeas 93, nays 0, as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> The Senator from Washington is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, we are moving quickly to finish this bill. It will take the cooperation of all Senators. I ask everyone to make sure you are in the Senate Chamber because rollcall votes will be 10 minutes from here on.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We now turn to the Senator from South Carolina.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from South Carolina is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent to call up amendment No. 704 and ask for its immediate consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent the reading of the amendment be dispensed with.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, my amendment simply states that no funds in this act shall be used to make payments to spinach producers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The House version of this bill includes $25 million for spinach growers, which all of us know has no place in this bill. Last week, the Senate spoke unanimously and we voted to block this spending from our budget process last year. I am asking all my colleagues to support the removal of this wasteful spending in this emergency war supplemental bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Washington.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, the amendment by the Senator from South Carolina is a solution looking for a problem. I sit on the Appropriations Committee. I was there throughout the entire committee markup. There was never any money for spinach in the Senate version of this bill. There is not now any money for spinach in the Senate version of this bill, so adoption of this amendment will not change the substance of this bill one iota. But if the Senator insists, we will go ahead and move forward  on his amendment. We are happy to take it by a voice vote if the Senator would consider that.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="">
    <paragraph>I think it is important this body be on record. This will be a matter of conference, and I think we all need to be on record showing we do not want it in the final bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask for the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="">
    <paragraph>How much time do I have remaining?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator has 1 minute 14 seconds.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I tell my colleagues on this side of the aisle, there is no money in the Senate bill for spinach. We do know there are issues out there affecting our agricultural communities across the Nation. The bill that is before us addresses many of those critical issues. This is a supplemental emergency bill, and when there are emergencies, we are responsible for taking care of them. But the amendment of the Senator from South Carolina will make no difference in this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The majority leader is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I will use leader time. Mr. President, we are trying to get a lot of things done today to finish this bill. There are important committees wanting to meet. Everyone should understand every Democrat is going to vote for this amendment. This is a waste of time. Everyone who is going to be on conference knows the Senate is voting for this amendment. I think it is an effort to slow things down today. I think it is unnecessary. We are all going to vote for this, but if we want to waste 15  minutes of the people's time, we can do that. The Senator has that right.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the Senator. I ask for the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there a sufficient second? There is a sufficient second. The question is on agreeing to the amendment. The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>I announce that the Senator from Indiana (Mr. BAYH) and the Senator from South Dakota (Mr. JOHNSON) are necessarily absent.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300069" topic="">
    <paragraph>The following Senator is necessarily absent: the Senator from Wyoming (Mr. ENZI).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Are there any other Senators in the Chamber desiring to vote?</chair>
  <narrative>The result was announced--yeas 97, nays 0, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I move to reconsider the vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300023" topic="">
    <paragraph>I move to lay that motion on the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The motion to lay on the table was agreed to.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="CHANGE OF VOTE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, on rollcall vote No. 123, I voted "nay." It was my intention to vote "yea." Therefore, I ask unanimous consent that I be permitted to change my vote as it will not affect the outcome.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <narrative>(The foregoing tally has been changed to reflect the above order.)</narrative>
  <chair> The Senator from Washington is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, the next amendment in order is the Coburn amendment, No. 649. We are ready to take this on a voice vote. If there is no one who wants to speak on the other side, we can move to the amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I yield back all time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, all time is yielded back.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I move to reconsider the vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>I move to lay that motion on the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The motion to lay on the table was agreed to.</narrative>
  <chair> The Senator from Washington is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, the next amendment in order is the Sanders amendment, No. 737. This amendment has also been agreed to on both sides. If the Senator from Vermont wishes to, he may speak.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Vermont is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400357" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I will be very brief.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Pursuant to the agreement reached last night, I call up an amendment I have at the desk, Sanders amendment No. 737, as modified by No. 808.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400357" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the reading of the amendment be dispensed with.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400357" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, this amendment is a bipartisan amendment cosponsored by Senators Sununu, Bingaman, Menendez, Kerry, Harkin, Dodd, Wyden, and Clinton. It is also strongly supported by the AARP.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This modification, which has the bipartisan support of the Appropriations Committee, would partially restore funding for weatherization programs. The amendment does not use new money. It simply instructs the Department of Energy to use its fiscal year 2007 appropriations to increase the amount it will spend on weatherization by $25 million over its current plan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think all of my colleagues know the weatherization program is important for a number of reasons. First, when people have a limited amount of money, it is absurd that their scarce resources simply go up into the air because they do not have the money to adequately insulate their walls or their roofs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Secondly, if we are serious about global warming, we had better move toward energy efficiency. We are wasting huge amounts of energy by seeing people living in homes with inadequate weatherization.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would ask strong support from my colleagues for this amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Washington.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, this amendment has been agreed to on both sides. I believe we can do it on a voice vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I yield back all time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, all time is yielded back.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I move to reconsider the vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300023" topic="">
    <paragraph>I move to lay that motion on the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The motion to lay on the table was agreed to.</narrative>
  <chair> The Senator from Washington.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, we are moving rapidly to a finish. We have one final amendment that needs to be voted on. Then we will have a manager's package and final passage shortly. I yield to the Senator from Delaware.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Delaware.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300008" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I call up amendment No. 739.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300008" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the reading of the amendment be dispensed with.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300008" topic="">
    <paragraph>This amendment is very straightforward. This amendment moves up $1.5 billion into the supplemental from the 2008 budget. The effect will be, it will add an additional 2,500 MRAP vehicles into the field faster. These are the vehicles with the V-shaped hull. This increases the security of our troops inside these vehicles--who are now riding in humvees--three to four times.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What it will mean is it is an opportunity to provide 10,000 to 30,000 of our troops four times more protection than they now get riding around in the humvees when they are attacked by IEDs. That is tens of thousands of Americans who won't be severely injured or killed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Commandant of the Marine Corps and the Chief of Staff of the Army both have said they need this money moved up so they can get these additional vehicles into the field earlier. I cannot think of a better way to explain this amendment than using the words of the Commandant of the Marine Corps when I spoke to him yesterday.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He said: Senator, this is the highest moral imperative I have as a Commandant of the Marine Corps.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I hope we will move this money up. I hope we will pass this amendment. It literally, not figuratively, will save lives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor, and I ask for the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there a sufficient second?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I yield back all time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, all time is yielded back.</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will call the roll.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>I announce that the Senator from South Dakota (Mr. JOHNSON) is necessarily absent.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300069" topic="">
    <paragraph>The following Senator is necessarily absent: the Senator from Wyoming (Mr. ENZI).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The result was announced--yeas 98, nays 0, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="">
    <paragraph>I move to reconsider the vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300023" topic="">
    <paragraph>I move to lay that motion on the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The motion to lay on the table was agreed to.</narrative>
  <chair> The Senator from Arizona.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300062" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I raise a point of order. Under rule XVI, section 1711 of the bill is legislation on an appropriations bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Section 1711 of the substitute amendment makes changes to the immigration code's bars on entry to the United States for individuals tied to terrorist activity or groups. Although I agree with the stated purpose of this provision--to allow the Hmong and other groups that do not pose a threat to the United States to enter this country--I object to the language of this provision and have introduced two amendments to correct that language.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Everyone agrees that groups such as the Hmong and the Montagnards, who fought bravely alongside U.S. forces during the Vietnam war, should not be barred from entering this country. If section 1711 were tailored to aid the Hmong and other groups that do not pose a threat to the United States, I would have no objection to such a legislative proposal.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, the text of section 1711 does much more than simply allow the Hmong to remain in this country. The provision in this bill would extend the waiver authority in current law to groups that are definitely not friends of the United States--including to members of groups that the Secretary of State has designated as Foreign Terrorist Organizations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Current law bars, without exception, anyone who is a member or a representative of a terrorist organization from gaining admission to the United States. Section 1711 would remove this categorical bar and allow members of even Tier I terrorist organizations to seek a waiver and admission to this country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Tier I terrorist organizations include groups such as the Al-Aqsa Martyrs Brigade, the group that has been responsible for the majority of suicide bombings in Israel in recent years. Section 1711 would extend waiver authority to the Armed Islamic Group and to the Salafist Group for Call and Combat, the two principal terrorist groups that have carried out a bloodthirsty campaign massacres, abductions, and rapes in Algeria over the last 15 years. The provision in the Senate substitute would extend  waiver authority to Hamas, Hezbollah, and Palestinian Islamic Jihad, and the Senate bill would even extend waiver authority to al-Qaida.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I do not think that there is a single Member of this body who believes that any member of al-Qaida, Hamas, or Hezbollah should ever be considered for admission to this country. Yet the Senate bill would allow members or representatives of all of these groups to be considered for entry to the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Another problem posed by section 1711 of the Senate bill is that it would also make it very difficult to bar entry to someone who has given material support to a terrorist organization. The section would effectively require the Department of Homeland Security to prove a negative--to show that an individual did not act under duress--when it seeks to bar someone who has given material support to terrorism from entering this country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Imagine a situation, for example, where DHS learns that an Iraqi seeking admission to this country had helped plant improvised explosive devices in Iraq. Approximately 1,000 U.S. soldiers have been killed by IEDs since the beginning of the Iraq war. And suppose  that this hypothetical individual claimed that he acted under duress--that some unnamed person forced him to plant IEDs. Under the Senate bill, DHS would have to prove that this person did not  act under duress in order to bar him from the United States. This makes no sense. If we learn that someone has provided material support to terrorism, and that person seeks a waiver and entry to this country, at the very least, it is that person who should bear the burden of proving that he acted only under duress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As I mentioned earlier, I have filed two amendments that are designed to address these problems with section 1711. I have concluded, however, that there is no reason at all to enact this provision on the emergency war supplemental. There is no reason that this measure cannot be enacted through regular order. To that end, I will introduce legislation this week that will provide relief from terrorism-related immigration bars to the Hmong and other groups that do not pose a threat to the United  States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Everyone agrees that groups such as the Hmong should not be barred from the United States. Moving such a bill through regular order will also protect the rights of the minority, and allow the full Senate to ensure that this legislation does not include the excesses that appear in section 1711. We all agree that we should help the Hmong. But I would venture that we would also all agree that we should not extend immigration waiver authority to members of Hamas and al-Qaida.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, the supplemental contains a provision, section 1711, which was carefully worked out through discussions between my office, the offices of Senator Specter, Senator Brownback, Senator Kennedy, Senator Coleman and Senator Feingold, as well as with representatives of the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Justice, the Department of State, and the National Security Council.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This provision contains six subsections, (a) through (f).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Subsections (a) and (d) were written by the administration.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Subsections (b) and (f) were written by the Senator from Arizona, Senator Kyl.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Subsection (c) provides an exception for cases involving duress, which is consistent with the administration's policy except that this provision would codify it into law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Section (e) is a reporting requirement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is the whole provision. It represents months of discussion and compromise on an issue that has been a focus of concern of faith-based organizations and humanitarian organizations, conservative and liberal, Democratic and Republican.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Here is the background.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Current law, as a result of overbroad amendments in the PATRIOT Act and Real ID Act, has been used to bar refugees and asylum seekers who were either members of groups who fought on the side of the United States, such as the Hmong, the Montagnards, and the Northern Alliance in Afghanistan, or who were the victims of terrorist groups and forced to provide "material support," such as food, shelter, or other services.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Administration officials have acknowledged that they have been inexcusably slow to deal with this problem. Thousands of refugees and hundreds of asylum seekers have been in limbo as a result. We now face the additional problem of Iraqi refugees, 7,000 of whom the President says should be admitted to the United States, being barred from admission unless we fix the law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After considerable prodding, the administration has moved in the right direction. Two weeks ago, it took another welcome step, although we have not yet seen the results of this reported change of policy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The number of refugees admitted to the United States would not be increased or decreased by this provision. That is determined by the numerical limit set by the President each year and by the amount we appropriate for refugee admissions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Numerous editorials have described the horrific consequences for refugees who have been victimized by current law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Just the titles of these editorials tell the story: "Shutting Out Terrorism's Victims," "Doctors Without Refuge," "Anti-terror laws keeping out old Vietnam allies," "Punishing the Persecuted," "U.S. denies refuge to friends, the abused," "The Refugee Mess," "Excluding Friends," and finally, "Fix This Law."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I will ask that just three of these editorials be printed in the Record at the close of my remarks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This provision is a compromise that would get our law back in sync with our values, but now the Senator from Arizona, Mr. Kyl, has raised a rule XVI point of order against this provision and had it stricken from the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is regrettable that one Senator, for whatever reason, has decided to torpedo this bipartisan effort. We have worked with the administration. We have worked with refugee organizations that know the hardship current law is causing for thousands of innocent people, legitimate refugees and asylum seekers, who have been denied admission. We have worked to find a reasonable middle ground.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But that isn't good enough for the Senator from Arizona, so we are back to square one. Individuals who fought alongside the United States in Vietnam, in Afghanistan, and elsewhere will continue to be barred under current law. Our provision would have fixed this illogical, unfair result, but now that provision has been stricken so those former allies--the Hmong, the Montagnards and others--will remain excluded.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Innocent victims of the material support bar will continue to wait for the Federal bureaucracy to address their cases--a wait that is well into its third year. Victims of terrorist groups like the FARC in Colombia or the Lord's Resistance Army in Uganda get no help from the Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I regret this action by the Senator from Arizona. By striking this provision he ensures the perpetuation of a policy that is contrary to our values, to our morals, and to our national traditions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I wish to thank all Senators who have joined in this effort but particularly Senator Brownback, Senator Specter, Senator Kennedy, Senator Coleman, and Senator Feingold. I also wish to thank representatives of the humanitarian and other groups who have provided helpful information and advice, as well as officials in the administration who have made a sincere effort to work with us.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While the Senator from Arizona has singlehandedly prevented us from moving forward at this time, we will continue to work together to fix the law in a manner that reaffirms our commitment to the words that are carved in the Statue of Liberty.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the aforementioned editorials be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> The point of order is well taken.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the following amendments be agreed to en bloc: amendment No. 661 by Senator Kohl; amendment No. 664, Obama, as modified; No. 677, Leahy; No. 679, Collins, as modified; No. 681, Leahy, as modified; No. 683, Senator Dorgan; No. 722, Senators Domenici and Bingaman, as modified; No. 726, Kerry, as modified; No. 728, Bond, as modified; No. 754, Mikulski  and Shelby, as modified; No. 757, Byrd; No. 759, Clinton; No. 771, Senator Snowe; No. 784, Senator Durbin; No. 799, Senators Lugar and Kennedy, as modified; and ask for their immediate consideration. I send the modifications to the desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300023" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, reserving the right to object, I will be compelled to object to that request in that there are some items here that have not been cleared on this side of the aisle. That has just been brought to my attention. To give us an opportunity to check each one of these items in the request, I do object.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="">
    <paragraph>Having heard the objection, it is unfortunate. We have been trying to work through a number of what we had hoped would be agreed-upon amendments, but since they can't be considered at this time, all debate time has expired, and I understand we will move to third reading.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from South Carolina.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300047" topic="CHANGE OF VOTE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, on rollcall vote 118, I voted "yea." It was my intention to vote "nay." Therefore, I ask unanimous consent that I be permitted to change my vote since it will not affect the outcome.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="CHANGE OF VOTE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I make a point of order that section 431, dealing with the tree assistance program, starting on page 150, line 13 and ending on page 151, line 15, violates rule XVI of the Standing Rules of the Senate.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300023" topic="CHANGE OF VOTE">
    <paragraph>Reserving the right to object, would the Senator state what the substance of this matter is in the bill?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="CHANGE OF VOTE">
    <paragraph>This section of the bill deals with the tree assistance program. It has no business being in a war supplemental. It is clearly legislating on an appropriations bill, and I believe it violates rule XVI.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Washington.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="CHANGE OF VOTE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I raise the defense of germaneness on this point of order.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is, Is the section germane?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="CHANGE OF VOTE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask for the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there a sufficient second?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300014" topic="CHANGE OF VOTE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, may we have a clarification of what is going on?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is, Is the section germane to language in the underlying House bill?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300014" topic="CHANGE OF VOTE">
    <paragraph>Wait a minute. Would you continue? If this language is germane and a point of order has been lodged against it, is that----</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> A point of order has been lodged against the section.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300014" topic="CHANGE OF VOTE">
    <paragraph>How does the Parliamentarian rule?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> It is a vote of the Senate as to whether there is sufficient language in the House bill for the defense of germaneness.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300014" topic="CHANGE OF VOTE">
    <paragraph>In other words, the Parliamentarian is throwing it back to the Senate to vote whether it is germane?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> As required by the rule.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300014" topic="CHANGE OF VOTE">
    <paragraph>OK.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Washington.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="CHANGE OF VOTE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, could we ask for a ruling from the Chair on the germaneness of the underlying section?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is, Is the section germane?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="CHANGE OF VOTE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask for the yeas and nays and encourage my colleagues to vote "no."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there a sufficient second?</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will call the roll.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="CHANGE OF VOTE">
    <paragraph>I announce that the Senator from South Dakota (Mr. JOHNSON) is necessarily absent.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300069" topic="CHANGE OF VOTE">
    <paragraph>The following Senator is necessarily absent: the Senator from Wyoming (Mr. ENZI).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Are there any other Senators in the Chamber desiring to vote?</chair>
  <narrative>The result was announced--yeas 57, nays 41, as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> The section is voted germane and the point of order falls.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="CHANGE OF VOTE">
    <paragraph>I move to reconsider the vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300023" topic="CHANGE OF VOTE">
    <paragraph>I move to lay that motion on the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The motion to lay on the table was agreed to.</narrative>
  <chair> The Senator from Washington.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="CHANGE OF VOTE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, what is the regular order?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The regular order is that other points of order remain in order.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300002" topic="CHANGE OF VOTE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I raise a point of order that section 3001 constitutes general legislation and is not in order to a general appropriations bill under rule XVI.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The point of order is sustained. The language is stricken.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300002" topic="CHANGE OF VOTE">
    <paragraph>I thank the Chair.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300094" topic="CHANGE OF VOTE">
    <paragraph>I turn now to an issue that should be of concern to us all, and that is the safe transport of our civilian contractors into and out of Iraq and Afghanistan. On occasion, these U.S. citizens are flying on poorly regulated charter aircraft that are ultimately paid for by funds provided by Congress to the Department of Defense and the Department of State.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300056" topic="CHANGE OF VOTE">
    <paragraph>I believe that I recently read about this issue in the press. I am concerned as well that the lack of regulation and oversight of these charter aircraft put our citizens at risk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300094" topic="CHANGE OF VOTE">
    <paragraph>I am also informed that the aircraft, air carriers, and air charter providers being used to provide the charters for our contractors in Iraq are, in some cases, using poorly trained crews to fly outdated and poorly maintained aircraft. The Senate Armed Services Committee will most likely address this matter during their consideration of the fiscal year 2008 Defense authorization bill. We should consider requiring that air charter operates in Iraq and Afghanistan, funded either directly  or indirectly by congressional appropriations, meet safety and maintenance standards equal to those required by charters in the U.S.and European Union.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300056" topic="CHANGE OF VOTE">
    <paragraph>I agree that air transport safety of our citizens in Iraq and in Afghanistan is an important issue and I endorse your comments on this matter. We should work to take the steps needed to ensure the safety of our civilian contractors.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="GEOTHERMAL ENERGY RESEARCH FUNDING">
    <paragraph>I rise to enter into a brief colloquy with Senator Dorgan, chairman of the Energy and Water Development Appropriations Subcommittee, regarding section 3201 of title III of Senate amendment No. 641 to <bill type="h" number="1591">H.R. 1591</bill>, the emergency supplemental appropriations bill for fiscal year 2007. I thank the Senator for including in the committee's substitute amendment the language that I requested to ensure that important geothermal energy research can continue in fiscal year 2007, instead  of being closed down pursuant to the administration's ill-advised spending plan.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300037" topic="GEOTHERMAL ENERGY RESEARCH FUNDING">
    <paragraph>I thank the leader for his support and continuing interest in geothermal and renewable energy. The committee's substitute amendment provides $22,762,000 for geothermal energy research at the Department of Energy in fiscal year 2007. This is the same level of funding as provided in fiscal year 2006. After the administration proposed terminating the geothermal research program in its fiscal year 2007 budget request, the Senate Appropriations Committee rejected that proposal last year  in its report accompanying the fiscal year 2007 energy and water appropriations bill, S. Rept. 109-274. Section 3201 will ensure continuation of this vital program.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="GEOTHERMAL ENERGY RESEARCH FUNDING">
    <paragraph>I thank the Senator from North Dakota for his support for the geothermal energy program and his leadership on national energy policy. As the Senator knows, geothermal energy is a very important resource for Nevada and all Western States to develop to help address our national energy and environmental security problems. There have been several new reports in the past few months from the Geothermal Energy Association, the National Renewable Energy Laboratory, and the Massachusetts Institute  of Technology that show the tremendous untapped potential of this renewable resource. Geothermal energy is clearly an important resource that can provide very valuable clean, baseload power. Its advantages are many and obvious, and the Department of Energy should be expanding its efforts in this area not reducing them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Given the hostility of the Department of Energy, DOE, and the administration toward expanding our Nation's massive geothermal energy potential through research and deployment, can the chairman of the Energy and Water Subcommittee convey any specific intent about how the appropriated funds in this amendment should be used?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300037" topic="GEOTHERMAL ENERGY RESEARCH FUNDING">
    <paragraph>First of all, the department should continue critical efforts to support new technology and deployment, including funding of existing contracts and awards under previous solicitations, but the department should be rapidly implementing and supporting the geothermal provisions of the Energy Policy Act of 2005.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Based upon the studies and reports the Senator from Nevada has mentioned, it should also be a priority for the department to support resource development and exploration technology, including continued both existing and new Geothermal Resource Exploration and Development, GRED, efforts that are underway at the DOE.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="GEOTHERMAL ENERGY RESEARCH FUNDING">
    <paragraph>I thank the Senator from North Dakota for his comprehensive answer. I hope that as we consider the fiscal year 2008 energy and water appropriations bill, Congress will provide expanded support for the geothermal energy program, along with more specific guidance as needed by the distinguished chairman.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300037" topic="GEOTHERMAL ENERGY RESEARCH FUNDING">
    <paragraph>I appreciate the Senator's views on the importance of this program and share the Senator's commitment to ensuring an effective DOE geothermal program that works to expand our Nation's use of this important, renewable energy resource.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300092" topic="GEOTHERMAL ENERGY RESEARCH FUNDING">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I seek recognition to discuss a matter of the utmost importance, a pay raise for judges and justices of the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The salaries of article III judges are inadequate for the stature and duties that are attendant to the job. The low salaries threaten the independence and excellence of the judiciary.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Framers sought to ensure that the Federal judges would be independent--free from persuasion--to impartially apply the law. Alexander Hamilton wrote in the Federalist No. 79: "Next to permanency in office, nothing can contribute more to the independence of the judges than a fixed provision for their support....... In the general course of human nature, a  power over a man's subsistence amounts to a power over his will."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For this reason, though Congress was charged with providing for the judiciary's support, judges were given salary protection in the compensation clause in article III, section 1 of the U.S. Constitution. This clause provides that "the Judges, both of the supreme and inferior Courts, shall hold their offices during good Behavior, and shall, at stated Times, receive for their Services a Compensation which shall not be diminished during their Continuance in Office." The Framers gave judges salary  protection so that they could be independent, free from the threat of salary diminution by Congress. They recognized that independence was key to the ability of judges to implement the rule of law without fear or favor. Judicial independence is the cornerstone of our legal system, which has been the model for judiciaries throughout the world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This constitutional protection against salary diminution, so central to judicial independence, is undermined when judicial salaries are allowed to steadily decline through neglect. And the independent judiciary our forefathers envisioned is undermined when Congress fails to attend to the needs of its principals and insists on tying of their salaries to those of elected leaders.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The last time Congress significantly raised the pay of Federal judges was in 1989, when the Ethics Reform Act raised their salaries by 25 percent. At the same time, however, the act curtailed judges' ability to earn outside income. Although the act provided for annual cost-of-living adjustments, these annual increases have not been realized due to congressional inaction in 5 of the last 13 years. Thus, the real pay of judges has continued to decline--12 percent since the Ethics Reform Act was  enacted. The decline of judicial salaries since 1969 is even starker--the real pay of district judges has decreased by nearly 25 percent since 1969. During the same time period, the salary for the average American worker increased by about 19 percent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Obviously, we cannot equate the judges' pay with that of ordinary working Americans. No one would argue that Federal judges' salaries are worse than those of the vast majority of American taxpayers. However, Federal judges' pay has not kept pace with the salary increases of their peers within the legal profession. In 1969, Federal judges' salaries exceeded those of top law school deans by 21 percent. Today, in contrast, Federal district judges earn about half as much as deans at these law schools.  In fact, the salary of a district judge today--$165,200--is a mere $20,000 more than what a first year associate at a New York law firm earns. Partners in law firms often earn an excess of $1 million per year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nor have judicial salaries kept up with the salaries of other government servants. The Chief Justice of the United States earns $212,100, while the Chief Learning Officer at the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation earns up to $257,134. Many other government employees can receive in excess of $200,000 per year in compensation, while judges for the courts of appeal earn $175,100 and district court judges earn $165,200.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Chief Justice Roberts and Justice Kennedy have both recently addressed the toll that these comparatively low judicial salaries are taking on his fellow justices and judges. On February 14, 2007, Justice Kennedy addressed the Judiciary Committee and related that in more than 30 years as a judge, he has never seen his "colleagues so dispirited as at the present time." He testified that "if there is a continued neglect of compensation needs," he is concerned that low morale will lead to a judiciary  that "will be diminished in its stature and its capacity." Chief Justice Roberts also addressed this problem, devoting his entire 2006 Year End Report on the Federal Judiciary to the topic. He raised concerns that the low salaries of judges threaten the ability of the judiciary to draw the best and the brightest legal minds into service. The Chief Justice raised the alarm that "without fair judicial compensation we cannot preserve the quality and independence</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On a related note, I would like to address the notion that judicial salaries should be linked to salaries for Senators and Members of the House. Judges should not be held hostage because political winds make it difficult for elected leaders to raise their own salaries. It is high time to dispense with the idea that the two ought to be linked. The judicial branch is separate but equal to the legislative branch, each with its own needs, each of equivalent stature. We cannot continue to humble the  judiciary, neglecting our constitutional mandate to provide for its support, ignoring its independence, by tying judges' compensation to our own.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The problems of inadequate judicial compensation and the linking of judicial salaries to those of elected leaders are not new. Chief Justice Rehnquist raised the inadequacy of judicial compensation for nearly 20 years, and the National Commission on the Public Service--the "Volcker Commission"--addressed judicial pay increases and linkage in its 2003 report on revitalizing the Federal Government. The Commission recommended a substantial pay raise for judges, calling the judicial compensation</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is imperative that Congress address a judicial salary increase soon and decouple the salaries of judges with those of Members of Congress. I urge my colleagues to join me in this effort to ensure that the salaries for our judicial brethren are commensurate with the duties and stature of their positions and that salary policy respects the independence of this coequal branch of government. Our failure to act prevents us from showing proper respect to a coordinate branch of our constitutional  government.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300071" topic="GEOTHERMAL ENERGY RESEARCH FUNDING">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, this emergency supplemental appropriations bill contains $121.7 billion in funding, approximately $19 billion above the President's request, and is replete with earmarks and other nonemergency spending. Additionally, this bill would establish a timeline for the withdrawal of American troops from Iraq, regardless of the conditions there. Such a mandate would have grave consequences for the future of Iraq, the stability of the Middle East and the security of Americans  at home and abroad. For these reasons, I do not support this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I support full funding for our troops in this time of war, and I believe that Congress, which authorized the wars in Iraq and Afghanistan, is obligated to give American troops everything they need to prevail in their missions. Unfortunately, the must-pass nature of this bill has proven all too tempting for Senators who could not restrain their profligate impulses to pile on spending unrelated to fighting the global war on terror.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill exhibits little evidence that Congress respects the solemn responsibility to be custodians of the taxpayers' dollars. In a time of war, with large Federal budget deficits, at a time when Americans deserve to keep more of their earnings at home, any rational observer would counsel restraint. Yet this emergency supplemental bill is stuffed with scarce dollars for the special interests, just as the measure approved by the House last week.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Dallas Morning News editorial board wrote last week with respect to the House-passed bill that "turning the President's $100 billion supplemental war spending request into a $124.6 billion, pork-laden mess" is no way to show support for the troops, adding  that "support for the troops takes the odd form of $25 million for spinach growers . . . $1.48 billion for livestock farmers . . . and $74 million `to ensure the proper storage of peanuts.' "</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, the Senate has chosen to follow the House's misguided lead by adding a host of nonemergency and unrequested provisions to the measure pending before us--a measure that is desperately needed to fund the ongoing military missions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me mention some of the unrequested items contained in this bill:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is $3 million for sugar cane growers, of which the entire amount will go to one Hawaiian cooperative. Just last year Congress provided up to $40 million for Florida sugar cane growers in an emergency supplemental bill. I suppose no "emergency supplemental" bill is complete without a sweetener for sugar cane growers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is $165.9 million for fisheries disasters. Just last year Congress provided $95 million in another emergency supplemental bill to assist fishermen in recovering from fisheries disasters and to aid oyster bed and shrimp ground rehabilitation. This year, Congress's generous aid moved from the eastern seaboard to the west coast with over $60 million alone to assist salmon fishermen in Oregon and California.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is $3,500,000 for the Capitol Guide Service and Special Services Office, to be available until September 2008. I was unaware that we had emergency tour guide needs in addition to our emergency troops' funding needs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is $13 million for research to develop mine safety technology. Congress provided $35 million in last year's emergency supplemental bill to hire an additional 217 mine safety inspectors, and $10 million for mine safety research, so I must question why this latest funding cannot wait for the regular appropriations process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is $22.76 million for geothermal energy research. While I support renewable energy research to reduce our dependency on oil, this funding was not part of the administration's budget request. Does geothermal energy research qualify as an emergency spending need? No, it does not.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is $7 million for water quality research at pig farms in Missouri. Specifically, the bill directs the EPA to provide a $7 million grant to Water Environment Research Foundation in Alexandria, VA, to research water quality issues related to pig farms in Missouri. As many of us have stated, there is true "pork" in this bill as this earmark illustrates.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is $2 million for the University of Vermont's Educational Excellence Program. This project is essentially identical to an earmark that was proposed last year. It was rejected in last year's final bill, and should not be included again this year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is $40 million for a "Tree Assistance Program," to aid "fruit and nut tree producers" and other producers of a "Christmas tree" or "potted shrub" or "ornamental tree." This bill is not only a big Christmas gift to special interests, but it also comes with a Christmas tree.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is $95 million to dairy producers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is $20 million for reimbursements to Nevada, Idaho and Utah for "insect damage" from grasshoppers, crickets, and others. These pesky insects are now richer than most residents in those States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is $24 million to sugar beet producers as compensation for production losses. These producers should be "beet red" over this handout.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is $13 million for the Ewe Lamb Replacement and Retention Program. Under this program, eligible livestock owners receive $18 for each qualifying ewe lamb.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That means this provision would cover up to 722,222 sheep. Perhaps my colleagues think increasing our Nation's sheep stocks is somehow a viable alternative to the President's troop increase in Iraq? I doubt the troops appreciate the priority that we have placed on ewe lambs breeding in this bill. It is a "baad" earmark.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is $6 million for crops damaged by floods in North Dakota. Yet another repeated attempt for funding that was rejected in last year's emergency supplemental.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is $5 million for irrigation repairs in Montana. Of the $35 million provided to the USDA Emergency Conservation Programs, which was not requested by the administration, the bill earmarks $5 million for repairs to damaged irrigation ditches and pipelines in the State of Montana.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is $30 million for the Farm Service Agency. On top of all the aforementioned programs, the bill provides $30 million for administration costs at the Farm Service Agency to ensure the Federal Government has enough employees to actually carry out all the new programs and new spending under this agriculture title. Here we see the underreported runaway effect of porkbarrel politics: more pork translates into bigger government, bigger government means larger administrative overhead, and large  administrative overhead means greater costs to American taxpayers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is $388.9 million for funding a backlog of old Department of Transportation highway projects. The taxpayers just provided over $24 billion in unauthorized highway projects in 2005, but Congress in its infinite wisdom has seen fit to provide another $388 million in this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This appropriations bill also includes numerous authorizing provisions, such as section 3001, which uses the emergency supplemental to authorize certain outdoor signs that were damaged, abandoned, or discontinued as a result of a hurricane in certain regions to be repaired, replaced, or reconstructed within 24 months of enactment. The bill also restricts authorization to the Department of Transportation to implement a provision authorized by Congress in the North American Free Trade Agreement  that would allow Mexican and U.S. trucks to operate across the border, thereby facilitating free trade and benefiting the economy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Once again, the appropriators have included a massive agriculture disaster assistance package in the emergency supplemental. The language before us today is strikingly similar to language that appeared in the 2006 emergency supplemental and to an amendment that was rejected just last December. As my colleagues surely remember, the 2006 Senate-passed emergency supplemental faced a veto threat because of the unrequested agricultural disaster package it contained. It faces the same threat today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Most shockingly still, the bill actually underfunds the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps and Defense-Wide Operation and Maintenance accounts by nearly $1.4 billion, withholding funds from accounts directly related to fulfilling the wartime needs of the military. This is disgraceful.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This spending would be laughable if it weren't so tragic. We are at war--a war that has cost us a great deal in blood and treasure and which inevitably will cost us more still. Our troops, who fight so bravely on our behalf and who so love their country that they are willing to sacrifice everything--everything--in order to defend it, show incredible courage in carrying out their duties in Iraq and Afghanistan. And so it is only right that we, the elected leaders entrusted to preserve the common  welfare, show just a modicum of the sacrifice, courage, and restraint that these warriors exhibit every day.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Baltimore Sun editorialized last Sunday:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>President Bush requested that Congress quickly fund the troops serving in Iraq and Afghanistan and debate the war strategy separately. Yet Congress chose to hold troop funding hostage to pork-barrel spending and to provide terrorists with a countdown clock to America's exit from Iraq. Lawmakers must show that [past] promises of fiscal restraint were not meaningless by providing a clean bill for President Bush to sign. The troops deserve no less.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I agree it is time to exercise the fiscal discipline commensurate with the responsibilities entrusted to us by the American people and to provide our troops with the support necessary to win the war in Iraq. This bill, which provides insufficient funding for our Armed Forces and a damaging withdrawal deadline, sends the wrong message to our troops, our enemies, and the American taxpayer. The Dallas Morning News continued in its editorial:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>[S]etting an arbitrary date for withdrawal only handcuffs the troops trying to carry out their mission--and gives hope to their ene- mies . . . We hope--the supplemental war-spending bill does not prove to be a reminder to Americans why the Constitution invested commander-in-chief responsibilities in one president, instead of 435 members of Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill will be vetoed, and I will strongly support sustaining that veto. This bill is a perfect example of why I have long supported a President having line-item veto authority. There is some necessary funding in this bill that is urgently needed to support our troops in Iraq, but, unfortunately, the bill is saddled with too much wasteful spending and a regrettable war strategy to allow me to support it.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="GEOTHERMAL ENERGY RESEARCH FUNDING">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I heard the Senator from Tennessee arguing about a provision in the disaster recovery portion of the supplemental relating to the private property rights of billboard owners. First let me note that the bill we voted on was not simply the Iraq supplemental. From the start, it has always been a supplemental that also included provisions for hurricane and natural disaster recovery efforts. Obviously, the Iraq portion of the supplemental is the most important part of the  bill, but the supplemental has always also had a disaster recovery title, which is why we saw a majority of members of both Chambers supporting these disaster-related provisions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I respect the Senator from Tennessee and appreciate his sincerity on the important issue he spoke on. I was disappointed, though, that there was much in what the Senator said that was just plain wrong.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senator claimed that the provision at issue was "amnesty for illegal billboards." I don't know what it is these days with the use of the term "amnesty," but some people don't seem to understand what the word means in any context.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>All of the billboards affected by the provision are legal. Some of them have been standing legally for decades. But we are not talking about creaky old billboards; many of the billboards at issue are only a few years old, and in more recent years the state they are in happened to changed density or zoning requirements, but sensibly grandfathered in the existing structures.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many of the billboards at issue provide advertising for small businesses, important information for U.S. drivers, public service announcements, and fuel local tourism industries throughout America. In short, the types of billboards at issue are very common, are a source of information and revenue for States, and are regulated by states.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Saying they are illegal or that we are providing amnesty is a nice rhetorical flourish but is just plain wrong.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The reality is that for decades, the Federal Government, in compliance with law and regulation, deferred to the States in determining whether billboards could be rebuilt or not after a hurricane or other natural disaster. For decades, this issue was not an issue. Then, in recent years, the Federal Government did an about-face and began dictating terms to the States, threatening to withhold Federal highway funds if the States did not trample on private property rights.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ironically, Tennessee was one of the States that felt the heavy hand of the Federal Government's purse strings. "Tennessee had a decades-long history-of allowing billboards to be rebuilt after natural disasters. There are probably hundreds of letters from Tennessee granting permission to rebuild after natural disasters, including many from within the past year. Recently, however, the Federal Government told Tennessee it needed to change its policies or it would lose millions of dollars in Federal  funding. Tennessee felt that it had no choice, so it changed its policy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The provision at issue is very simple, it returns us to where we were before the Federal Government changed its policy. It respects States rights and private property rights--principles that people in the West understand well. I am surprised that a small group of Members on the other side of the aisle are opposed to States rights and private property rights. This is especially so, since other Members on the other side of the aisle have traditionally supported this provision, including Members  from Louisiana and Mississippi, two of the States hit hardest by the new Federal Government stance on this issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The proposal ensures that states that want to allow these billboards to be rebuilt will have that option. If the State does not want to allow the billboards, it does not have to. That was the way things worked for decades.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But, under the new approach by the Federal Government, even if a State thinks the billboards provide a valuable source of revenue or public service and wants to allow them to be rebuilt, the Federal Government stands in the way and prohibits the State from allowing the billboard to go back up. It is about states rights.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So the gentlemen from Tennessee, Florida, and Alabama, are all basically taking a position that the Federal Government knows better than their own States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Further, the proposal is about private property rights. It ensures that companies and small businesses whose billboards have been destroyed by the hurricane will not lose all of the value of their property.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is just a matter of basic fairness. The Katrina portion of the supplemental included billions of dollars to help people rebuild their houses, to help private schools rebuild their facilities and programs, and to help small businessowners rebuild their businesses. The Katrina portion of the supplemental was all about rebuilding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But, a small group of my colleagues on the other side of the aisle seems to think that this group of private property owners should be the exception--they should not be able to rebuild and reclaim their property just because their property is disfavored by some. I don't know why these folks are opposed to private property rights and States rights.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, let me note the wide support for this proposal. The Governors of Mississippi and Louisiana support the proposal. The American Hotel Lodging Association supports it. The National Restaurant Association supports it. The Association of National Advertisers supports it. The "America's Most Wanted" TV show endorses the proposal because billboards have been helpful in catching criminals. A variety of America's best known brandnames support the proposal, as well--Accor, Best Western, Bob  Evans, Cracker Barrel, Dairy Queen, Ford Motor Company, Wendy's, and White Castle.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300091" topic="GEOTHERMAL ENERGY RESEARCH FUNDING">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today to discuss the way forward for a recapitalization effort critical to our national security and the safety of America's seafarers. I speak of the effort to modernize the fleet of the U.S. Coast Guard known as the Integrated Deepwater Program. There is no question that the Coast Guard desperately requires new assets with which to carry out its missions, and it is our duty to ensure that they receive those tools at the best value to the American taxpayer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For over two centuries, the Coast Guard has protected our shores, and the service has come a long way from its beginnings under the auspices of the U.S. Revenue Cutter Service and the U.S. Lifesaving Service. Following the events of September 11, 2001, the Coast Guard was transferred from the Department of Transportation to the Department of Homeland Security, a change that brought with it an increase in missions. Today, its roles include search-and-rescue missions and marine safety enforcement;  securing our Nation's ports, waterways, and coasts; carrying out drug and illegal immigrant interdiction operations; protecting our marine environment; and ensuring safety and ease of navigation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>President Bush has called the Coast Guard "the world's premiere lifesaving service," and given the new tasks assigned to the service under the Department of Homeland Security, that label now extends far beyond rescuing mariners in duress or stranded hurricane victims. The Coast Guard is also our first line of defense against waterborne terrorist attacks, from suicide bombers such as those who attacked the USS Cole in Yemen, to potential weapons of mass destruction that could be brought  to our ports on board container ships.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, the assets we have provided the world's premiere lifesaving service to carry out their critical missions are anything but the world's premiere equipment. The valiant men and women who protect our shores serve aboard vessels that collectively comprise the third oldest naval fleet in the  world. These are the same individuals who rescued over thirty thousand people from the rooftops of the gulf coast after Hurricane Katrina, and who, in a single  action just last week, prevented over 4,200 pounds of cocaine from reaching America's streets, and schoolyards--the biggest single drug bust ever recorded. Our service men and women deserve better, and the American people deserve better.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Which is why the Coast Guard has chosen to modernize its fleet using a program of unprecedented scope. This recapitalization effort, called Deepwater, is a single acquisition program designed to completely overhaul the Coast Guard's entire fleet of ships and aircraft, as well as its communications system and interoperability components. In effect, rather than attempting to manage each asset individually, we chose to manage the new system of assets as a whole, allowing the Coast Guard and the  taxpayer to reap the benefits of economies of scale and lack of duplicative effort. When the call for proposals was announced, the group Citizens Against Government Waste called Deepwater "an innovative answer to the federal acquisition process' systematic waste."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In June of 2002, the Coast Guard awarded a contract to a joint venture comprised of executives from Lockheed Martin and Northup Grumman and representatives from the Coast Guard itself. This entity is called Integrated Cost Guard Systems, or ICGS. And now, not 5 years later, we have arrived at a crossroads with the Deepwater program that has has found itself in rough seas. High-profile failures of acquisitions, such as the 123-foot patrol boats, and questions about the suitability of the new fleet's  flagship, the national security cutter, have led Congress to re-examine the acquisition process. An innovative design for one ship, the fast response cutter, has proven to be a failure, and the Coast Guard, to its credit, has removed that ship from ICGS's control, will soon put forth a request for design proposals, and plans to manage that acquisition independently.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many of these problems stem from the manner in which the Coast Guard structured its Deepwater contract. Too much control was given to ICGS in the contract's first term, including the authority to override Coast Guard engineering decisions, and the ability to "self-certify" its own designs and work as meeting the Coast Guard's requirements. To make matters worse, these contracts were structured in such a way that if the assets in development failed to meet the required standards, the contractor  would be paid an additional fee to fix the very problem it had created in the first place. I am convinced that it is this contract--and not the concept of a system of systems approach to major acquisitions--that has brought us to where we are today with the Deepwater program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now the Coast Guard is in negotiations with ICGS for extension of the contract, and there is no question that oversight of the program must change. Several legislative solutions have been proposed, including provisions in both <bill type="s" number="965">S. 965</bill> and <bill type="h" number="1571">H.R. 1571</bill>. While I am pleased to know that the appropriators in both Houses of Congress recognize the importance of Deepwater to the Coast Guard and to the Nation, I strongly disagree with the way in which they have chosen to handle its revision.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ultimately, oversight of Deepwater falls not to the appropriators, but to the service's authorizing committee the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation's Subcommittee on Oceans, Atmosphere, Fisheries, and the Coast Guard, on which I serve as the ranking member. The Chair of that Subcommittee, Senator Cantwell, and I have worked together on innumerable Coast Guard issues for years, and we have a detailed understanding of the intricate issues involved both in management of  the Coast Guard as a whole and this program in particular. The language in neither the House nor the Senate Appropriations bill provides the best way forward for Deepwater or the Coast Guard. If passed, either version would lead to delays in production and</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator Cantwell and I have offered an alternative. Last week, we introduced the Integrated Deepwater Program Reform Act, <bill type="s" number="924">S. 924</bill>. This bill places restrictions on the structure of any agreements between the Coast Guard and its contractors; mandates full and open competition for all Deepwater assets not yet under contract; requires the Coast Guard to conduct an analysis of alternatives to ensure that its Deepwater plan remains the best way to recapitalize the service at the lowest possible  cost; and increases reporting requirements to Congress so we can be kept abreast of the program's progress as well as any stumbling blocks that may arise. But most importantly, while this analysis is ongoing, our bill will allow work to continue on assets that have been proven capable of meeting the demands of the Coast Guard's mission portfolio, thereby avoiding costly delays and dangerous patrol gaps.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Despite the mistakes of Deepwater's past, I believe we must move forward with this critical modernization of The Coast Guard's fleet. The simple fact is this: The Coast Guard needs new vessels, and a program run as a system of systems, rather than on an asset-by-asset basis will lead to a more efficient and more cost-effective recapitalization.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I respectfully ask that the members of the Appropriations Committees in both the House and the Senate remove the clauses in their bills that contain authorization language for the Deepwater program and allow the authorizing committee to do its job through passage of <bill type="s" number="924">S. 924</bill>. We have the best interests of the American people at heart, and we have the necessary expertise to ensure that the Coast Guard and our maritime security do not suffer unintended consequences of even the best-intentioned efforts.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300042" topic="GEOTHERMAL ENERGY RESEARCH FUNDING">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I am pleased to vote in favor of the fiscal year 2007 supplemental because it contains binding language that effectively ends the current misguided military mission in Iraq and requires the President to begin withdrawing U.S. troops from Iraq. While this action is long overdue, it is a big step in the right direction and it brings us closer to ending our involvement in this disastrous war.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am also pleased that the supplemental includes necessary funding to address conflicts throughout the world, especially in Sudan, Somalia, and the Democratic Republic of Congo, to assist Iraqi refugees and internally displaced persons fleeing their homes, and to help pay for U.S. arrears to the U.N.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The supplemental also contains a 1-month extension of the Milk Income Loss Contract, MILC, program, which fixes a quirk that could have put family dairy farmers on unequal footing during the upcoming farm bill debate. I was glad this provision was included in the supplemental and will work with my colleagues to retain it during conference.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am extremely disappointed at the removal of a provision in the supplemental spending bill that would have fixed a glaring problem in immigration law that effectively labeled the Hmong as terrorists. We will forever be indebted to the Hmong who fought alongside and supported the United States during the Vietnam war. I will continue working to make sure that Hmong and other legitimate refugees who are not threats to our national security do not face lengthy and unnecessary delays as the Federal  agencies involved determine whether they are eligible for a waiver that would permit them to resettle in the United States or adjust their immigration status.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I remain concerned at the continued practice of funding the war in Iraq through emergency spending bills. We should not be using such bills to bypass the regular appropriations process. That is why I supported efforts to remove certain spending provisions that do not appear to address true emergencies, including an amendment offered by Senator Coburn to remove funding for next year's political conventions.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on the engrossment of the amendments and third reading of the bill.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="GEOTHERMAL ENERGY RESEARCH FUNDING">
    <paragraph>I ask for the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there a sufficient second?</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will call the roll.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="GEOTHERMAL ENERGY RESEARCH FUNDING">
    <paragraph>I announce that the Senator from South Dakota (Mr. JOHNSON) is necessarily absent.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300069" topic="GEOTHERMAL ENERGY RESEARCH FUNDING">
    <paragraph>The following Senator is necessarily absent: the Senator from Wyoming (Mr. ENZI).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Are there any other Senators in the Chamber desiring to vote?</chair>
  <narrative>The result was announced--yeas 51, nays 47, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="GENERAL PROVISIONS--THIS ACT">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I move to reconsider the vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300023" topic="GENERAL PROVISIONS--THIS ACT">
    <paragraph>I move to lay that motion on the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The motion to lay on the table was agreed to.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="GENERAL PROVISIONS--THIS ACT">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, there will be no more votes today. I express my appreciation to the managers of the bill. Senator Byrd, because of his other responsibilities, couldn't be here. The Senator from Washington, Mrs. Murray, worked hard on this bill. She has done a wonderful job. We are all indebted to her. Senator Thad Cochran is always very good, thorough, direct, and to the point. We appreciate very much his being the person he is.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Washington is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="GENERAL PROVISIONS--THIS ACT">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate insist on its amendments, request a conference with the House on the disagreeing votes of the two Houses, and the Chair be authorized to appoint conferees with a ratio of 15 to 14.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300072" topic="GENERAL PROVISIONS--THIS ACT">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, let me also congratulate Senator Murray for her work and particularly my good friend, the ranking member of the Appropriations Committee, Senator Cochran, for his usual flawless effort in moving legislation across the floor. This was a challenging bill with a lot of interesting issues that divide the Senate in many ways. I express my gratitude and appreciation for the fine work of Senator Cochran.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="GENERAL PROVISIONS--THIS ACT">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, on behalf of the majority, I know conferees will be all of the Democratic members of the Appropriations Committee.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300072" topic="GENERAL PROVISIONS--THIS ACT">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I will also be sending a list of conferees to the Chair.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
