<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1191427202" ordinal="28" title="ADDITIONAL STATEMENTS">
  <narrative>ADDITIONAL STATEMENTS -- (Senate - October 03, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="12529">S12529</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412251" topic="TRIBUTE TO ROY SCUDERI">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today I bring to the attention of this body and the Nation the remarkable service of Roy Scuderi. For over 18 years, Roy has served A Presidential Classroom for Young Americans with diligence, dedication and commitment. Roy has helped make Presidential Classroom the premiere civic education program for high school students in America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On October 5, 2007, Roy Scuderi will retire from his position as chief financial officer and vice president of this national nonprofit organization. In his role, Roy has established financial projections, overseen investments, negotiated contracts, and facilitated the annual audits--all of this done with professionalism and integrity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Roy Scuderi's commitment to Presidential Classroom's success and performance has inspired the well-deserved trust and affection of the board members and his colleagues. His judgment has improved every aspect of Presidential Classroom. Roy's daily efforts to ensure the program's quality and viability have sustained a record of unmatched dedication and achievement over the course of the organization's nearly 40-year history.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have had the personal honor and privilege as a board member, chairman of the board, and now as honorary board member of Presidential Classroom to work closely with Roy Scuderi throughout his entire career with Presidential Classroom.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Presidential Classroom is stronger as a result of Roy's dedication and commitment to the classroom. Throughout his 18 years, the staff and board members of Presidential Classroom have relied on Roy Scuderi for his outstanding leadership and service.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, we salute Roy Scuderi for the central role that he has played in helping Presidential Classroom fulfill its mission of inspiring and challenging the leaders of tomorrow to devote their talents and energies in the service of our constitutional government on behalf of a better nation and a better world.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
