<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1177084810" ordinal="17" title="VIRGINIA TECH TRAGEDY">
  <speaking speaker="300002" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I have one other short comment I would like to make, and then I will yield the floor or note the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Governor of Virginia has asked our country to take a moment of silence to remember the tragedy this week at Virginia Tech at noon today. It is also a good time for us to think about our responsibilities in the U.S. Congress. There is hardly any way we can express our grief to these families and to that university for what they have been through this week. It is of such a scale that it is hard to imagine. We want them to know we have been thinking about them, and we would like to do whatever  we can to help them and to help make sure nothing like this happens again.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So while Virginia Tech and the Commonwealth of Virginia are reviewing their responsibilities in light of the tragedy this week at Virginia Tech, we in the Federal Government ought to be reviewing our responsibilities too. Our focus should be on whether Federal laws or regulations unwisely restrict or limit how universities are able to deal with students who have mental health problems or who otherwise exhibit behavior about which parents, authorities, or other third parties should know.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Generally, and many Americans do not know this, under Federal law universities cannot tell parents about  their child's problems or their grades without their student's consent. At least one professor at Virginia Tech who was tutoring the shooter has been quoted as saying that she felt that Federal laws prevented her from going to his parents or to others about her concerns. Therefore, I am sending a letter today to Senator Kennedy and to Senator</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would hope that Secretary Spellings could review not only the laws and the rules, but also the implementation of these rules on campus. I am a former president of a university. I understand it may very well be that faculty members, and perhaps even some administrators, are unaware of the rules, or at least uncertain about how to apply them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My hope would be that Secretary Spellings could complete her review within 120 days, and after that our committee might hold a hearing or roundtable to determine whether there is action we need to take.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent to have printed in the Record at this point a copy of my letters to Senator Kennedy and Senator Enzi and an article from the New York Times dated April 19 entitled, "Laws Limit Options When a Student Is Mentally Ill," which describes very well the situation in which many university faculty members find themselves.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, on Monday America was devastated by the deadliest shooting rampage in our Nation's history. A gunman using two semi-automatic handguns, shot and killed 32 students and teachers and injured several dozen others before turning one of his guns on himself. Witnesses described scenes of chaos and grief, with students jumping from second-story windows to escape gunfire, while others heroically blocked their classroom doors to shield them from the gunman.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many of us watched this tragedy unfold on the news, finding it difficult to grasp the true magnitude of it. Parents and grandparents across America were thinking about the horror of one's child being caught in the middle of such chaos. There is little that could be worse for a parent than sending a child off to college, only to lose them to a senseless act of gun violence.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I express condolences to the family, friends, and community touched by the tragedy at Virginia Tech. I know I reflect the feelings of the people of Michigan when I say that our thoughts and prayers are with them in this hour of pain and grief.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400194" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today I express my sympathy and I know the sympathy of all of the Members of the Senate and the people of the United States of America on the tragic losses this week at Virginia Tech.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>None of us can understand what happened in Blacksburg, VA, but all of us recognize the profound tragedy and the loss of youth in its prime.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I learned this week that one of those losses was a Georgian by the name of Christopher James "Jamie" Bishop, and I, from the floor of the Senate, send to Pine Mountain, GA, my sympathy on the tragic loss of Jamie.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Jamie, who was passionate about his art and an avid amateur photographer, grew up in Pine Mountain, GA, and was valedictorian of Harris County High School. He received his bachelor's degree in German from my alma mater, the University of Georgia, and was a Fulbright scholar at Christian-Albrechts-University in Kiel, Germany. He returned to the University of Georgia to earn his master's degree in German linguistics.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Jamie, who was known for wearing his hair in a ponytail, had been a German instructor at Virginia Tech since 2005. His wife, Stefanie Hofer, is an assistant professor of German there. By all accounts, Jamie was an intelligent, clever and passionate individual.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am very proud as a Georgian to have known of his accomplishments, and I send his wife Stefanie and his parents Michael and Jeri my prayers and my hopes that they will accept our sympathy as they endure the heartbreak of the loss of Jamie.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To the families of all of those professors, employees, and students who lost their lives or were hurt in Blacksburg, VA, I extend my sympathy and my deepest prayers that we will find reconciliations out of tragedy.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
