<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1189008002" ordinal="49" title="CONGRATULATING THE WARNER ROBINS AMERICAN LITTLE LEAGUE TEAM OF WARNER ROBINS, GEORGIA, FOR WINNING THE CHAMPIONSHIP GAME OF THE LITTLE LEAGUE WORLD SERIES">
  <narrative>CONGRATULATING THE WARNER ROBINS AMERICAN LITTLE LEAGUE TEAM OF WARNER ROBINS, GEORGIA, FOR WINNING THE CHAMPIONSHIP GAME OF THE LITTLE LEAGUE WORLD SERIES -- (Senate - September 05, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="11125">S11125</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300081" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate now proceed to the consideration of <bill type="sr" number="308">S. Res. 308</bill>, which was submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="308">S. Res. 308</bill>) congratulating the Warner Robins American Little League team of Warner Robins, Georgia, for winning the championship game of the Little League World Series.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300021" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise to encourage my colleagues to join Senator Isakson and myself in support of a resolution congratulating the 2007 Little League World Series champions, the Warner Robins American Little League team of Warner Robins, GA. Warner Robins and Houston County, where Warner Robins is located, have a very proud athletic tradition. Warner Robins High School and Houston County High School have been in the same region as my home high school over the last several  years and I have seen my high school win and lose against teams coming out of Houston County. The tradition in Houston County goes way back.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is also a town in Houston County called Perry, and Perry, GA is the home of a former all-State basketball player by the name of Sam Nunn who served in this great institution for a period of 24 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Success in Houston County and Warner Robins from an athletic standpoint is nothing new. But on August 26, 2007, the Warner Robins American Little League team defeated the Tokyo Kitasuna Little League team of Tokyo, Japan by a score of 3-2 after Dalton Carriker hit a solo walk-off home run in the bottom of the eighth inning. This victory concluded their impressive season with a record of 20 wins and only 1 loss. Considering the fact that more than 7,000 Little League All-Star teams took the field  in July, this accomplishment is extremely impressive.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Their talent, hard work, and sportsmanship allowed them to become the third team from the State of Georgia to win the Little League World Series and, in doing so, they captured the hearts of people all across Georgia and in many parts of the Nation who love the game of baseball.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a former Little League coach myself, during the years when my wife, Julianne, and I were raising our children in Moultrie, GA, I was proud to  participate in the longstanding tradition of Little League baseball as a coach for my son's team, the Destiny Dawgs. I have seen firsthand the uncontested confidence, determination, and hard work that Little League baseball instills in our youth.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I wish to recognize the 12 young men of the Warner Robins American team individually for their great accomplishment: Keaton Allen, Dalton Carriker, Zane Conlon, Hunter Jackson, Taylor Lay, Nick Martens, Payton Purvis, Kendall Scott, Hunt Smith, David Umphreyville, Micah Wells, and Clint Wynn. Their manager Mickey Lay and coaches Mike Conlon, Tommy Morris, and Mike Smith each deserve strong recognition for guiding these young men to victory.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Moreover, I would be remiss if I did not recognize the teachers and students of these young men's schools, the fans who represented their community, and the State of Georgia, for their enthusiasm and their support for this team's efforts. It is with great pride that I extend my heartfelt congratulations to the Warner Robins American Little League team and their families. I am extremely proud of each of them and their accomplishments. I wish them great success in the future and urge my colleagues  to support this resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Georgia.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400194" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I thank Senator Chambliss for this opportunity. I am pleased to join him in paying tribute to the Warner Robins Little League. I associate myself with all his remarks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dalton Carriker's walk-off home run in extra innings was a thrill. Kendall Scott's great relief pitching was a thrill. But what was the most thrilling thing of all, because I got home in time to watch the end of that game, were the actions of those kids in response to the despair of the Japanese kids. In fact, I want to quote from a news article. A reporter interviewed Kendall Scott, the winning pitcher, after the end of the game when he gazed across the field and saw the Japanese players all  on their knees in tears, disappointed in their loss. Kendall Scott said the following:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>They don't disrespect, they're very disciplined and they're some of the nicest kids you'll ever meet in your entire life. Just seeing them fall down and cry, you just couldn't let them do that--you gotta pick them up.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Having had two boys who went through Little League, having worked in baseball as a youngster myself, I know one of the goals of Little League is to instill good sportsmanship and teamwork on behalf of players. I commend manager Mickey Lay and coaches Mike Conlon, Tommy Morris, and Mike Smith for the discipline, the teamwork, and the respect they instilled in these young men, because at the height of their victory, zenith of their young careers, they stopped their celebration to console those  they had defeated on the field. That shows that Little League and its goals of teaching teamwork and sportsmanship are alive and well, not just in Warner Robins, GA but throughout the United States. I am pleased to join my colleague and commend the Warner Robins Little League on their victory and remind everyone, that is back to back for Georgia. Columbus, GA won last year. Warner Robins won this year. We will try for a trifecta next year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300081" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="308">S. Res. 308</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="308">S. Res. 308</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas, on August 26, 2007, the Warner Robins American Little League team defeated the Tokyo Kitasuna Little League team of Tokyo, Japan, by 3 runs to 2 runs to win the 61st annual Little League Baseball World Series;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Warner Robins American Little League team had an impressive record of 20 wins and only 1 loss;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the success of the Warner Robins American Little League team depended on the tremendous dedication and sportsmanship of the team, including--</chair>
  <chair>(1) Keaton Allen, who played outfield and pitched for the team;</chair>
  <chair>(2) Dalton Carriker, who played shortstop and pitched for the team;</chair>
  <chair>(3) Zane Conlon, who played 2nd base, shortstop, outfield, and pitched for the team;</chair>
  <chair>(4) Hunter Jackson, who played 3rd base;</chair>
  <chair>(5) Taylor Lay, who played 2nd base and outfield;</chair>
  <chair>(6) Nick Martens, who played 2nd base and outfield;</chair>
  <chair>(7) Payton Purvis, who played outfield;</chair>
  <chair>(8) Kendall Scott, who pitched and caught for the team;</chair>
  <chair>(9) Hunt Smith, who played 1st base and outfield;</chair>
  <chair>(10) David Umphreyville, who played outfield and caught for the team;</chair>
  <chair>(11) Micah Wells, who played 1st base; and</chair>
  <chair>(12) Clint Wynn, who played outfield and pitched for the team;</chair>
  <chair>Whereas the Warner Robins American Little League team was managed by Mickey Lay and coached by Mike Conlon, Tommy Morris, and Mike Smith, each of whom demonstrated leadership, professionalism, and respect for the players they led and the game of baseball;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the fans of the Warner Robins American Little League team showed enthusiasm, support, and courtesy for the game of baseball and all of the players and coaches;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the performance of the Warner Robins American Little League team demonstrated to parents and communities throughout the United States that athletic participation builds character and leadership in children;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Warner Robins American Little League team became the second consecutive team from the State of Georgia to win the Little League World Series, following the win by the Columbus Northern Little League team in 2006;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Georgia is only the 4th State to produce back-to-back champions in the 61-year history of the Little League World Series and the first State to win back-to-back titles since 1992-1993;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas every team from the State of Georgia that has participated in the Little League World Series has won the Championship; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Warner Robins American Little League team brought pride and honor to the State of Georgia and the United States: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) congratulates and honors the Warner Robins American Little League team and the loyal fans who supported the team on winning the 61st annual Little League Baseball World Series;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) recognizes and commends the hard work, dedication, determination, and commitment to excellence of the members, parents, coaches, and managers of the Warner Robins American Little League team;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) recognizes and commends the people of Warner Robins, Georgia, for the outstanding loyalty and support that they displayed for the Warner Robins American Little League team throughout the season;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) commends Little League Baseball for continuing the tradition of encouraging the development of sportsmanship and confidence in youth by sponsoring world-class baseball; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) respectfully requests--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) that the American people recognize the achievements of the Warner Robins American Little League team; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) that the Secretary of the Senate transmit an enrolled copy of this resolution to--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) the City of Warner Robins; and</chair>
  <chair> (ii) the Warner Robins American Little League Baseball team for appropriate display.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
