<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1190304002" ordinal="46" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <narrative>AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET -- (Senate - September 20, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="11913">S11913</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENVIRONMENT AND PUBLIC WORKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Environment and Public Works be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, September 20, 2007 at 9:55 a.m. in room 406 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building in order to conduct a business meeting to consider several General Services Administration Resolutions and <bill type="s" number="589">S. 589</bill>, a Bill to provide for the transfer of certain Federal property to the United States Paralympics, Incorporated, a subsidiary of the  United States Olympic Committee, to be followed immediately with a hearing entitled, "Oversight Hearing to Examine the Condition of our Nation's Bridges."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="COMMITTEE ON FINANCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Finance be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, September 20, 2007, at 10 a.m., in room 215 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building, to hear testimony on "Frozen Out: A Review of Bank Treatment of Social Security Benefits" .</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet in order to conduct a markup on Thursday, September 20, 2007, at 10 a.m. in the Dirksen Senate Office Building Room 226.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Agenda</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="1845">S. 1845</bill>, A bill to provide for limitations in certain communications between the Department of Justice and the White House (Whitehouse, Leahy).</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="772">S. 772</bill>, Railroad Antitrust Enforcement Act of 2007 (Kohl, Coleman, Feingold).</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="1267">S. 1267</bill>, Free Flow of Information Act of 2007 (Lugar, Dodd, Graham).</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="1703">S. 1703</bill>, Trafficking in Persons Accountability Act of 2007 (Durbin, Coburn).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Jennifer Walker Elrod to be United States Circuit Judge for the Fifth Circuit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Patrick Shen, Special Counsel for Immigration Related Unfair Employment Practices.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="COMMITTEE ON SMALL BUSINESS AND ENTREPRENEURSHIP">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate in order to conduct a hearing entitled "Expanding Opportunities for Women Entrepreneurs: The Future of Women's Small Business Programs:" on Thursday, September 20, 2007, beginning at 10 a.m. in room 428A of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="COMMITTEE ON VETERANS' AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent for the Committee on Veterans' Affairs to be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, September 20, 2007, in order to conduct a Joint Hearing to receive the 2007 legislative presentation by the American Legion. The Committee will meet in 345 Cannon House Office Building, at 9:30 a.m.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="SELECT COMMITTEE ON INTELLIGENCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Select Committee on Intelligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on September 20, 2007 at 2:30 p.m. to hold a hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON FEDERAL FINANCIAL MANAGEMENT, GOVERNMENT INFORMATION, FEDERAL SERVICES, AND INTERNATIONAL SECURITY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on Federal Financial Management, Government Information, Federal Services, and International Security of the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs be authorized to meet on Thursday, September 20, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. for a hearing entitled "High Risk IT Investments: Is Poor Management Leading to Billions in Waste."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON PUBLIC LANDS AND FORESTS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests of the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Thursday, September 20, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the hearing is to receive testimony on <bill type="s" number="1377">S. 1377</bill>, to direct the Secretary of the Interior to convey to the city of Henderson, NV, certain Federal land located in the city, and for other purposes; <bill type="s" number="1433">S. 1433</bill>, to amend the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act to provide competitive status to certain Federal employees in the State of Alaska; <bill type="s" number="1608">S. 1608</bill> and <bill type="h" number="815">H.R. 815</bill>, to provide for the conveyance of certain land in Clark County, NV, for use by the Nevada National Guard; <bill type="s" number="1740">S. 1740</bill>,  to amend the act of February 22, 1990, and the act of July 2, 1862, to provide for the management of public land trust funds in the State of North Dakota; <bill type="s" number="1802">S. 1802</bill>, to adjust the boundaries of the Frank Church River of No Return Wilderness in the State of Idaho; <bill type="s" number="1939">S. 1939</bill>, to provide for the conveyance of certain land in the Santa Fe National Forest, NM; and <bill type="s" number="1940">S. 1940</bill>, to reauthorize the Rio Puerco Watershed Management Program, and for other purposes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And to receive testimony on two additional bills added to the hearing: <bill type="s" number="1143">S. 1143</bill>, to designate the Jupiter Inlet Lighthouse and the surrounding Federal land in the State of Florida as an Outstanding Natural Area and as a unit of the National Landscape System, and for other purposes; and <bill type="s" number="2034">S. 2034</bill>, to amend the Oregon Wilderness Act of 1984 to designate the Copper Salmon Wilderness and to amend the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate segments of the North and South Forks of the Elk River in the  State of Oregon as wild or scenic rivers, and for other purposes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
