<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1201712403" ordinal="26" title="HELSINKI COMMISSION">
  <narrative>HELSINKI COMMISSION -- (Senate - January 30, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="487">S487</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300090" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today to speak on the work of the Helsinki Commission.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Helsinki Commission yesterday held an important hearing on combating anti-Semitism in the OSCE region. I would like to commend the two panelists who testified, Professor Gert Weisskirchen, MP and Dr. Kathrin Meyer. Professor Weisskirchen serves as the OSCE's chair-in-office personal representative on anti-Semitism, and Dr. Meyer serves as the advisor on anti-Semitism issues in the OSCE's Office for Democratic Institutions and human rights. Both of these scholars have been fighting against  anti-Semitism for years, and their good work should be recognized. Modern anti-Semitism is an appalling relic of a past horror; and though it is not yet as acceptable as in ages past, its resurgence today is no less troubling.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We forget, sometimes, just how much the world is indebted to the Jewish  community. The world's culture has been immeasurably enriched by Jewish writers, scientists, artists, philosophers, and medical pioneers. All those contributions, however, mattered little when the shadow of fascism fell across Europe, and European nations began to destroy some of their most valuable sons and daughters.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We may have thought that the horrors of World War Two and the Holocaust had finally cauterized the old festering sore of anti-Semitism. And indeed, for some years, that seemed to be the case. Europe committed itself to ensuring that never again would its states do violence against their Jewish minority, to which it owed so much. But time is a powerful sedative. Today, much of the same toxic nationalism is again on the rise. One of the most troubling aspects to me of the past two decades has been  the reemergence of virulently nationalist and xenophobic political parties. These groups have often drawn on the iconography and ideology of Axis powers during the Nazi period, with some going so far as to hold public rallies and marches. Others resort to violence, both openly and in the shadows. These gangs are not acceptable within European political society--not yet--but their emergence</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But this problem is not limited to the East. In much of Europe, in the highest centers of learning and culture, a new phenomenon serves to buttress these old prejudices. The Middle East, where the world's only Jewish state faces a sea of hostile terrorists, is particularly ripe for anti-Semitic propagandists. The world today sees much anti-Semitism masquerading as criticism of Israel. August world bodies, dedicated to forging peace, have seen some of their instruments twisted almost beyond recognition.  When great institutions cannot rouse themselves to end appalling human rights abuses in virtually every corner of the world, but instead focus again and again and again on a tiny nation, liberal and democratic, alone in a hostile region--then the instruments of those institutions</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The active steps to combat anti-Semitism proposed yesterday by Professor Weisskirchen and Dr. Meyer could prove exceptionally useful in rolling back today's creeping advance of radicalism and anti-Semitism. Only through vigorous and proactive measures can we identify the seedlings of hate and discrimination, and uproot them, and ensure that never again would Europe or the world fall prey to the ancient base ugliness of the mob.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
