<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1222876803" ordinal="5" title="SCHEDULE">
  <narrative>SCHEDULE -- (Senate - October 01, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="10189">S10189</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, following leader remarks, the Senate will consider <bill type="h" number="7081">H.R. 7081</bill>, the United States-India nuclear agreement. This is an issue that has been worked on long and hard for months and months. Finally, we are having the opportunity to get to it. Senators DORGAN and BINGAMAN have amendments to the bill that will be debated this morning. Under an agreement reached yesterday, there will be up to 60 minutes for debate on the bill and 60 minutes on each amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Following the debate on the United States-India nuclear legislation, the Senate will proceed to consider <bill type="h" number="1424">H.R. 1424</bill>, the legislative vehicle used for the economic rescue legislation. The only amendments in order are a Sanders amendment regarding high-income individuals and a Dodd amendment regarding economic stabilization. The Sanders amendment has 60 minutes for debate, and the Dodd amendment has 90 minutes for debate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senate will recess from 12:30 until 2:15 for the caucus luncheons.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At 7 p.m., the Senate will resume consideration of the House message with respect to the rail safety-Amtrak legislation, <bill type="h" number="2095">H.R. 2095</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At approximately 7:30 p.m., the Senate will proceed to a series of up to seven rollcall votes in relation to Amtrak-rail safety, the United States-India nuclear agreement, and the economic rescue package. The Sanders amendment will be determined by voice vote. Votes will be in relation to the following items: motion to concur with respect to <bill type="h" number="2095">H.R. 2095</bill>, Amtrak; the Dorgan amendment regarding clarifying the policy in the event of an Indian nuclear test; the Bingaman amendment reporting requirement  in the event of an Indian nuclear test; passage of <bill type="h" number="7081">H.R. 7081</bill>, the India-United States nuclear agreement, which has a 60-vote threshold--as do the two amendments, the Sanders amendment  regarding tax on high-income individuals and the Dodd amendment regarding economic stabilization, which is a 60-vote threshold--and passage of <bill type="h" number="1424">H.R. 1424</bill>, and there is a 60-vote threshold there.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
