<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1183953600" ordinal="54" title="PRIVILEGES OF THE FLOOR">
  <narrative>PRIVILEGES OF THE FLOOR -- (Senate - July 09, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="8879">S8879</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that Jacqueline Beatty-Smith, a fellow in my office, be granted the privileges of the floor during consideration of <bill type="h" number="1585">H.R. 1585</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>On behalf of Senator Clinton, I ask unanimous consent that privileges of the floor be granted to the following fellows in her office during consideration of <bill type="h" number="1585">H.R. 1585</bill>: Jaime Martinez, Nicole Wilett, and Eleanor Edson.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300077" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that Mark Carlton, a Marine Corps Fellow in Senator Kennedy's office, be granted the privilege of the floor during the consideration of <bill type="h" number="1585">H.R. 1585</bill>, the Defense Authorization bill for fiscal year 2008.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300099" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, on the Defense bill, I ask unanimous consent that Scott Suozzi, a military fellow in my office, be granted floor privileges.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="LEARY" of="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that LCDR Christopher Martin, a U.S. Coast Guard fellow in Senator Christopher Dodd's office, be granted the privilege of the floor for the duration of debate on <bill type="h" number="1585">H.R. 1585</bill>, the national Defense authorization bill, and for votes during that time.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300055" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. Presdient, I ask unanimous consent that Jeffrey Gonzalez and Mathew Pollard, both of the Senate Budget Committee, be granted floor privileges during consideration of <bill type="h" number="1585">H.R. 1585</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300055" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent to allow Air Force Fellow Daniel Wolf of my staff floor privileges for the duration of the consideration of the National Defense Authorization Act, <bill type="s" number="1547">S. 1547</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
