<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1181750406" ordinal="55" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="COMMITTEE ON HOMELAND SECURITY AND GOVERNMENTAL AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs be authorized to meet on Wednesday, June 13, 2007, at 10 a.m. in order to conduct a business meeting to consider pending committee business.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Agenda</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="1257">S. 1257</bill>, District of Columbia House Voting Rights Act of 2007;</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="274">S. 274</bill>, Federal Employee Protection of Disclosures Act;</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1254">H.R. 1254</bill>, Presidential Library Donation Reform Act of 2007;</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="sr" number="22">S. Res. 22</bill>, a resolution reaffirming the constitutional and statutory protections accorded sealed domestic mail, and for other purposes;</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="967">S. 967</bill>, Federal Supervisor Training Act of 2007;</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="1046">S. 1046</bill>, Senior Professional Performance Act of 2007;</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="1099">S. 1099</bill>, a bill to amend chapter 89 of title 5, United States Code, to make individuals employed by the Roosevelt Campobello International Park Commission eligible to obtain Federal health insurance;</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="597">S. 597</bill>, a bill to extend the special postage stamp for breast cancer research for 2 years;</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1255">H.R. 1255</bill>/S. 886, Presidential Records Act Amendments of 2007;</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="381">S. 381</bill>, Commission on Wartime Relocation and Internment of Latin Americans of Japanese Descent Act.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="COMMITTEE ON RULES AND ADMINISTRATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Rules and Administration be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, June 13, 2007, at 10 a.m., to conduct a hearing on nominations to the Federal Election Commission.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="COMMITTEE ON VETERANS' AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent for the Committee on Veterans' Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, June 13, 2007 at 9:30 a.m. in room 562 of the Dirksen Building to conduct an oversight hearing on Department of Labor, Department of Defense, VA cooperation, and collaboration to meet the employment needs of returning service members.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
