<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1171688400" ordinal="22" title="SURFACE TRANSPORTATION AND RAIL SECURITY ACT OF 2007--MOTION TO PROCEED">
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that on Tuesday, February 27, at 11:30 a.m., the Senate proceed to the consideration of <bill type="s" number="184">S. 184</bill>, Calendar No. 26, a bill to provide improved rail and surface transportation security.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300072" topic="">
    <paragraph>Reserving the right to object, my understanding is the Senate would next turn to the so-called 9/11 bill on which the Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee worked. That bill is not yet on the calendar and will be filed sometime this week.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I understand that the pending unanimous consent request is that we turn to a different bill, which has been reported by the Commerce Committee. At this point, I am compelled to object to this unanimous consent request and say to the majority leader, once the 9/11 bill is available and Members have had an opportunity to review the legislation, I will be happy to revisit this consent request. So I, therefore, object.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, in response to my friend, he is absolutely right. We had every intention of moving to the Homeland Security bill, but it wasn't reported out of the committee. The matter I read, Calendar No. 26, is part of a big bill. I, frankly, understand why there is an objection. We are going to file a cloture motion. Hopefully, in the interim period of time, when people have a chance to look at this bill, we will get consent from the Republicans to move forward.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The reason I am moving to this bill now is I didn't want to waste Tuesday. Time is so precious around here that I wanted to get to this or some vehicle as soon as we can. We will do our best in the next few days to try to work this out.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Republican leader already objected to my request?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> That is correct.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I now move to proceed to <bill type="s" number="184">S. 184</bill> and send a cloture motion to the desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The cloture motion having been presented under rule XXII, the Chair directs the clerk to read the motion.</chair>
</record>
