<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1207756802" ordinal="26" title="RECOGNIZING BERRY, FOWLES &amp; CO.">
  <narrative>RECOGNIZING BERRY, FOWLES &amp; CO. -- (Senate - April 09, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="2815">S2815</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300091" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, as tax time is once again upon us, I recognize the contributions that small businesses have made, and continue to make, toward ensuring that our Nation's financial sector operates in a fair and effective manner. In particular, I must highlight a Maine business that has excelled in taking care of both its customers and employees. Berry, Fowles &amp; Co., a small, full-service accounting firm located in Falmouth, recently earned the prestigious distinction of being named  the 2007 Small Business Best Place to Work in Maine.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The "Best Places to Work in Maine" program is sponsored by the Society for Human Resource Management Maine State Council, in partnership with several other entities, including The Employment Times and the Maine State Chamber of Commerce. Awards are issued in categories of large, medium, and small businesses operating in Maine, and determinations are based on employer benefits and policies, as well as employee responses to satisfaction surveys.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Berry, Fowles &amp; Co. is clearly deserving of this acknowledgement of its remarkable steps to maintain its employees' well-being.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Doing business under various names since 1915, Berry, Fowles &amp; Co. has consistently impressed its clientele by adhering to a strong set of core values, including a philosophy of empowerment and community involvement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Offering an array of services, including auditing, accounting, and tax preparation, Berry, Fowles &amp; Co. serves cities and towns, businesses, individuals, local governments, and nonprofits across Maine. The company offers free consultations for its services, from personal financial planning to small business accounting.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The company's Web site is an invaluable source for both the client and the public. Replete with a plethora of financial guides on investment, tax, and business strategies, the Web site provides readers with clear and comprehensive information. Additionally, the site contains links to a number of calculators that compute everything from college and retirement savings to the monthly payment of an auto loan. Combined with an online newsletter proposing perceptive counsel in a number of areas, Berry,  Fowles &amp; Co.'s Web site is a goldmine for the financially curious.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While the company's services are wide-ranging, what positions Berry, Fowles &amp; Co. so well in today's fast-paced world is the time it takes to appreciate and celebrate the work and welfare of its 16 dedicated employees. Berry, Fowles &amp; Co. provides its workers with a wide range of benefits, including health and life insurance, cutting-edge technology, and a retirement pension plan. And while all of us may cringe at the thought of April 15, the employees at Berry, Fowles &amp; Co. know firsthand the  stress that comes with a tax filing deadline. That is why the company has designed a tax-season wellness program for its employees, which includes enjoyable games and giveaways, healthy snacks, Saturday lunches, and even massages! To me, that certainly adds up to a great place to work!</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over the past century, Berry, Fowles &amp; Co. and its predecessors have made a name for themselves by helping others succeed financially. Now, the company is attracting just recognition because of its sound efforts to support its employees. Berry, Fowles &amp; Co. lays claim to a distinctly successful business model that presents all small businesses a magnanimous example upon which to draw. I congratulate the team at Berry, Fowles &amp; Co. and wish them well at tax time and beyond.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
