<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1195059601" ordinal="55" title="RECOGNIZING THE FESTIVAL OF DIWALI">
  <narrative>RECOGNIZING THE FESTIVAL OF DIWALI -- (Senate - November 14, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="14416">S14416</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Judiciary Committee be discharged from further consideration of <bill type="sr" number="299">S. Res. 299</bill> and the Senate then proceed to its immediate consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered. The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="299">S. Res. 299</bill>) recognizing the religious and historical significance of the festival of Diwali.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the amendment at the desk be considered and agreed to, the resolution, as amended, be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, the motions to reconsider be laid on the table, and any statements be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The amendment (No. 3677) was agreed to, as follows:</chair>
  <chair> On page 2, strike lines 4 and 5 and insert the following:</chair>
  <chair> (2) in observance of Diwali, the festival of lights, expresses its deepest respect for Indian Americans and the Indian diaspora throughout the world on this significant occasion. &lt;p&gt;</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="299">S. Res. 299</bill>), as amended, was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, as amended, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="299">S. Res. 299</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas Diwali, a festival of great significance to Indian Americans and South Asian Americans, is celebrated annually by Hindus, Sikhs, and Jains throughout the United States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas there are nearly 2,000,000 Hindus in the United States, approximately 1,250,000 of which are of Indian and South Asian origin;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the word "Diwali" is a shortened version of the Sanskrit term "Deepavali", which means "a row of lamps";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Diwali is a festival of lights, during which celebrants light small oil lamps, place them around the home, and pray for health, knowledge, and peace;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas celebrants of Diwali believe that the rows of lamps symbolize the light within the individual that rids the soul of the darkness of ignorance;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Diwali falls on the last day of the last month in the lunar calendar and is celebrated as a day of thanksgiving and the beginning of the new year for many Hindus;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas for Hindus, Diwali is a celebration of the victory of good over evil;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas for Sikhs, Diwali is feted as the day that the sixth founding Sikh Guru, or revered teacher, Guru Hargobind, was released from captivity by the Mughal Emperor Jehangir; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas for Jains, Diwali marks the anniversary of the attainment of moksha, or liberation, by Mahavira, the last of the Tirthankaras (the great teachers of Jain dharma), at the end of his life in 527 B.C.: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) recognizes the religious and historical significance of the festival of Diwali; and</chair>
  <chair> (2) in observance of Diwali, the festival of lights, expresses its deepest respect for Indian Americans and the Indian diaspora throughout the world on this significant occasion. &lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
