<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1193932801" ordinal="66" title="EXECUTIVE SESSION">
  <narrative>EXECUTIVE SESSION -- (Senate - November 01, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="13714">S13714</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="EXECUTIVE CALENDAR">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to executive session to consider calendar Nos. 152, 357 through 370, and all nominations on the Secretary's desk; that the nominations be confirmed with the exception of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration nominations; the motions to reconsider be laid on the table; the President be immediately notified of the Senate's action and the Senate then return to legislative session.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The nominations considered and confirmed en bloc are as follows:</chair>
  <chair>Charles Darwin Snelling, of Pennsylvania, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority.</chair>
  <chair>The following named officer for appointment in the United States Air Force to the grade indicated while assigned to a position of importance and responsibility under title 10, U.S.C. section 601:</chair>
  <chair>To be lieutenant general&lt;br&gt;Maj. Gen. Edward A. Rice, Jr., 4508</chair>
  <chair>The following named officer for appointment in the United States Air Force to the grade indicated while assigned to a position of importance and responsibility under title 10, U.S.C., section 601:</chair>
  <chair>To be lieutenant general &lt;br&gt;Maj. Gen. Glenn F. Spears, 2012</chair>
  <chair>The following named officer for appointment in the United States Army to the grade indicated under title 10, U.S.C., section 624:</chair>
  <chair>To be major general &lt;br&gt;Brig. Gen. Carroll F. Pollett, 9096</chair>
  <chair>The following named officer for appointment in the United States Army to the grade indicated while assigned to a position of importance and responsibility under title 10, U.S.C., section 601:</chair>
  <chair>To be lieutenant general &lt;br&gt;Maj. Gen. Benjamin R. Mixon, 7168</chair>
  <chair>The following named officer for appointment in the United States Army to the grade indicated while assigned to a position of importance and responsibility under title 10, U.S.C., section 601:</chair>
  <chair>To be lieutenant general &lt;br&gt;Maj. Gen. David H. Huntoon, Jr., 1919</chair>
  <chair>The following named officer for appointment as the Surgeon General, United States Army, and appointment to the grade indicated while assigned to a position of importance and responsibility under title 10, U.S.C., sections 601 and 3036:</chair>
  <chair>To be lieutenant general &lt;br&gt;Maj. Gen. Eric B. Schoomaker, 8284</chair>
  <chair>The following named officer for appointment in the United States Army to the grade indicated under title 10, U.S.C., sections 624 and 3064:</chair>
  <chair>To be major general &lt;br&gt;Brig. Gen. David A. Rubenstein, 6677</chair>
  <chair>The following named officer for appointment to the grade of lieutenant general in the United States Marine Corps while assigned to a position of importance and responsibility under title 10, U.S.C., section 601:</chair>
  <chair>To be lieutenant general &lt;br&gt;Maj. Gen. Samuel T. Helland, 6309</chair>
  <chair>The following named officer for appointment in the United States Navy to the grade indicated while assigned to a position of importance and responsibility under title 10, U.S.C., section 601:</chair>
  <chair>To be vice admiral &lt;br&gt;Rear Adm. Bernard J. McCullough, III, 4147</chair>
  <chair>Robert Clarke Brown, of Ohio, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority.</chair>
  <chair>The following named officer for appointment in the United States Coast Guard Reserve to the grade indicated under title 10, U.S.C., section 12203:</chair>
  <chair>To be rear admiral&lt;br&gt;Capt. Steven E. Day, 3035</chair>
  <chair>The following named officers for appointment in the United States Coast Guard to the grade indicated under title 14, U.S.C., section 271:</chair>
  <chair>To be rear admiral&lt;br&gt;Capt. Kevin S. Cook, 5918</chair>
  <chair>Daniel D. Heath, of New Hampshire, to be United States Alternate Executive Director of the International Monetary Fund.</chair>
  <chair>Sean R. Mulvaney, of Illinois, to be an Assistant Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development.</chair>
  <chair>Nominations Placed on the Secretary's Desk</chair>
  <chair>PN965 AIR FORCE nomination of Ernest Valdez, which was received by he Senate and appeared in he Congressional Record of September 27, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN966 AIR FORCE nominations (3) beginning LAURA M. HUNTER, and ending GEORGE W. RYAN JR., which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of September 27, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN999 AIR FORCE nomination of Cheryl A. Kearney, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of October 18, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN1000 AIR FORCE nomination of Noel P. Kornett, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of October 18, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN1001 AIR FORCE nomination of Michael Maine Jr., which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of October 18, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN1002 AIR FORCE nominations (2) beginning MICHAEL P BUTLER, and ending ROBERT CANNON, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of October 18, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN967 ARMY nomination of Max B. Bullen, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of September 27, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN969 ARMY nominations (4) beginning JOHN A. MCHENRY, and ending ALAN S. WALLER, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of September 27, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN970 ARMY nominations (2) beginning EDWARD F. FREDERICK, and ending GREGORY CHARLTON, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of September 27, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN981 COAST GUARD nominations (158) beginning ALBERT R. AGNICH, and ending Michael B. Zamperini, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of October 16, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN393-2 MARINE CORPS nomination of KEVIN M GONZALEZ, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of March 22, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN957 MARINE CORPS nomination of Thomas J. Keating, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of September 20, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN971 MARINE CORPS nomination of Gerald R. Brown, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of September 27, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN974 NAVY nomination of Stephen T. Vargo, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of October 1, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN1003 NAVY nominations (4) beginning GARY TABACH, and ending KELVIN L. REED which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of October 18, 2007.</chair>
</record>
