<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1190736002" ordinal="21" title="NATIONAL DEFENSE AUTHORIZATION ACT FOR FISCAL YEAR 2008">
  <narrative>NATIONAL DEFENSE AUTHORIZATION ACT FOR FISCAL YEAR 2008 -- (Senate - September 25, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="12023">S12023</bill>]</narrative>
  <chair> Under the previous order, the Senate will resume consideration of <bill type="h" number="1585">H.R. 1585</bill>, which the clerk will report.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A bill (<bill type="h" number="1585">H.R. 1585</bill>) to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2008 for military activities of the Department of Defense, for military construction, and for defense activities of the Department of Energy, to prescribe military personnel strengths for such fiscal year, and for other purposes.</narrative>
  <narrative>Pending:</narrative>
  <narrative>Nelson (NE) (for Levin) amendment No. 2011, in the nature of a substitute.</narrative>
  <narrative>Warner (for Graham/Kyl) amendment No. 2064 (to amendment No. 2011), to strike section 1023, relating to the granting of civil rights to terror suspects.</narrative>
  <narrative>Kyl/Lieberman amendment No. 3017 (to amendment No. 2011), to express the sense of the Senate regarding Iran.</narrative>
  <narrative>Biden amendment No. 2997 (to amendment No. 2011), to express the sense of Congress on federalism in Iraq.</narrative>
  <narrative>AMENDMENT NO. 2064 &lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I call for the regular order with respect to the Graham amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The amendment is now pending.</chair>
  <chair>AMENDMENT NO. 3035 TO AMENDMENT NO. 2064 &lt;center&gt;(Purpose: To provide Federal assistance to States, local jurisdictions, and Indian tribes to prosecute hate crimes, and for other purposes) &lt;/center&gt;</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I do have an amendment at the desk and ask it be reported.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the amendment.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>The Senator from Nevada [Mr. REID], for Mr. Kennedy, for himself and Mr. Smith, proposes an amendment numbered 3035 to the language proposed to be stricken by amendment No. 2064.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that reading of the amendment be dispensed with.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <narrative>(The amendment is printed in today's Record under "Text of Amendments.")</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I have a cloture motion at the desk and ask it be reported.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The cloture motion having been presented under rule XXII, the Chair directs the clerk to read the motion.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>Cloture Motion</narrative>
  <narrative>We, the undersigned Senators, in accordance with the provisions of rule XXII of the Standing Rules of the Senate, hereby move to bring to a close debate on amendment No. 3035 regarding hate crimes.</narrative>
</record>
