<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1201107603" ordinal="6" title="MEASURE PLACED ON THE CALENDAR--H.R. 4040">
  <narrative>MEASURE PLACED ON THE CALENDAR--H.R. 4040 -- (Senate - January 23, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="157">S157</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I have a matter at the desk that is due for its second reading, <bill type="h" number="4040">H.R. 4040</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the bill by title.</chair>
  <chair>The assistant legislative clerk read as follows:</chair>
  <chair>A bill (<bill type="h" number="4040">H.R. 4040</bill>) to establish consumer product safety standards and other safety requirements for children's products and to reauthorize and modernize the Consumer Product Safety Commission.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I object to any further proceedings on this legislation at this time but alert everyone we are going to try to get to this legislation before this work period ends. We do have a few things to do. It seems the best laid plans sometimes have to be delayed because now we have the stimulus package we have to worry about completing. But this is something I want to do. Senator Pryor and others have worked very hard. So we are going to move forward as quickly as we  can.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <chair>The bill will be placed on the calendar.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <chair>The assistant legislative clerk proceeded to call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
