<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1176220802" ordinal="53" title="CONGRATULATING ZACH JOHNSON ON HIS VICTORY IN THE 2007 MASTERS GOLF TOURNAMENT">
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate now proceed to consideration of <bill type="sr" number="145">S. Res. 145</bill>, which was submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, as long as I do have the floor, I thought I might at least talk about the resolution we just considered, <bill type="sr" number="145">S. Res. 145</bill>. Senator Grassley and I cosponsored it. It is congratulating Zach Johnson on his victory in the 2007 Masters tournament. Basically, I might as well read it. It is not that long:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>
      <bill type="sr" number="145">S. Res. 145</bill>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>Whereas, on April 8, 2007, Zach Johnson, a native Iowan, won the Masters Tournament at the Augusta National Golf Club in Augusta, Georgia;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, the Masters has been won by some of golf's greatest champions, including Byron Nelson, Sam Snead, Ben Hogan, Arnold Palmer, Gary Player, Jack Nicklaus, Tiger Woods, Phil Mickelson, and many others;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, Zach Johnson's final round of three-under-par 69 for a total score of 289 was two strokes better than that of any other competitor;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, in a final day on which six different players led, Zach Johnson showed great skill, patience and will to withstand the challenge of the weather and the course;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, Zach Johnson is the first Iowan to win the Masters, and the first Iowan to win a major championship in golf since Jack Fleck's playoff victory over Ben Hogan in the 1955 U.S. Open; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, Zach Johnson has brought great pride and honor to his family, friends, and the citizens of Iowa with his victory: Now, therefore, be it</paragraph>
    <paragraph> Resolved, That the Senate congratulates Zach Johnson on his outstanding accomplishment in winning the 2007 Masters golf tournament.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
