<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1191254402" ordinal="55" title="RECOGNIZING THE EFFORTS AND CONTRIBUTIONS OF HISPANIC SCIENTISTS">
  <narrative>RECOGNIZING THE EFFORTS AND CONTRIBUTIONS OF HISPANIC SCIENTISTS -- (Senate - October 01, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="12388">S12388</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400050" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the consideration of <bill type="sr" number="340">S. Res. 340</bill>, which was submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <chair>The assistant legislative clerk read as follows:</chair>
  <chair>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="340">S. Res. 340</bill>) recognizing the efforts and contributions of outstanding Hispanic scientists in the United States.</chair>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400050" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="340">S. Res. 340</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="340">S. Res. 340</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas the purpose of the National Hispanic Scientist of the Year Award is to recognize outstanding Hispanic scientists in the United States who promote a greater public understanding of science and motivate Hispanic youth to develop an interest in science;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the 7th annual National Hispanic Scientist of the Year Gala will be held at the Museum of Science &amp; Industry in Tampa, Florida, on Saturday, October 6, 2007;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas proceeds from the National Hispanic Scientist of the Year Gala support scholarships for Hispanic boys and girls to participate in the Museum of Science &amp; Industry's Youth Enriched by Science Program, known as the "YES! Team"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas a need to acknowledge the work and effort of outstanding Hispanic scientists in the United States has led to the selection of Dr. Louis A. Martin-Vega as the honoree of the 7th annual National Hispanic Scientist of the Year Award, in recognition of his accomplishments developing foundation-wide programs aimed at integrating research and education in science and engineering and in increasing the participation of women and underrepresented minorities in these fields; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Dr. Martin-Vega is also to be commended for his years of leadership in engineering education at such fine institutions as the University of Puerto Rico at Mayaguez, the University of Florida, Florida Institute of Technology, Lehigh University, the University of South Florida, and North Carolina State University, and for his service at the National Science Foundation: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) recognizes efforts to educate, support, and provide hope for the Hispanic community, including efforts to honor outstanding Hispanic scientists in the United States at the annual National Hispanic Scientist of the Year Gala and to organize a "Meet the Hispanic Scientist Day"; and</chair>
  <chair> (2) congratulates the 2007 National Hispanic Scientist of the Year designated by the Museum of Science &amp; Industry, for ongoing dedication to improving the quality of, and access to, science and engineering research and education.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
