<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1185336000" ordinal="24" title="ADDITIONAL STATEMENTS">
  <narrative>ADDITIONAL STATEMENTS -- (Senate - July 25, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="9913">S9913</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300036" topic="RECOGNIZING IRVIN L. TRUJILLO">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I wish to recognize Mr. Irvin L. Trujillo for receiving the National Endowment for the Arts National Heritage Fellowship Award. He is one of only 11 artists nationally recognized with this award for his work. The chairman of the NEA, Dana Gioia, will personally deliver the award to Mr. Trujillo this Sunday in Santa Fe. Mr. Trujillo, a Chimayo native, is part of the ever-growing population of talented artists that reside in New Mexico. He is a seventh-generation  Chimayo weaver.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Art is such a big part of the New Mexican way of life. Artists from all over the world dream of showcasing their art in one of the many New Mexico Art galleries. Art is a great outlet of creativity and emotion for those who experience its beauty and wonder. Art can take up many avenues; it can be a painting or a piece of pottery, a woven rug or even a photograph. New Mexico is home to many galleries featuring such pieces of art. I am proud to represent a State so full of culture and creativity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am proud to be from a State with such a rich artistic culture. Taos and Santa Fe are famous for their world-renowned art galleries. Other areas of the State also demonstrate creative ideas. The deep Native American culture of New Mexico's tribes brings ornate turquoise jewelry and handmade pottery. Las Vegas and Ruidoso also have a vibrant art scene. New Mexico continues to be in the forefront of ever-evolving art community.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congratulations again, Mr. Trujillo, on your prestigious award. Thank you for your continued pledge to explore and demonstrate your artistic abilities for all of us to enjoy.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
