<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1178035204" ordinal="53" title="NATIONAL CHARTER SCHOOLS WEEK">
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the consideration of <bill type="sr" number="183">S. Res. 183</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300063" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today I wish to honor National Charter School Week. The role of charter schools has become increasingly important as these institutions have become one of the fastest growing innovative forces in education policy. The District of Columbia and 40 States have laws that allow charter schools. There are over 4,000 public charter schools serving more than 1.1 million students and there are many more students on waiting lists who want to attend.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As many of you know, I have been a part of that charter school growth, both here in Washington, DC, and in my home, Louisiana. Today, more than 30 percent of all DC public school students attend charter schools and are largely successful. These charter school projects are largely successful. These charter schools not only help to better educate students, but are also helping to build a better, stronger, more prosperous city.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to having an impact in Washington, DC, charter schools are also helping to rebuild the school system in New Orleans. Hurricanes Katrina and Rita did not just wash away our levees--they also washed away our homes and schools. We must seize upon this opportunity and build a better, stronger school system for New Orleans and throughout Louisiana.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Charter schools are key players in this process by not only rebuilding our school system, but reinventing it. Every step in this process is based on what is best for our students, with the goal of delivering learning and achievement for all students. The new school system effectively eliminates the previous system of have and have-nots, allowing parents to choose from any school in the network, making quality school options available to all students and raising the bar for educators throughout  the system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The new Educational Network Model will organize schools, the majority of them charters, into small groups to provide support, foster collaboration and ensure accountability. This will shift the majority of money and decisionmaking to the school level, where it can be managed based on the needs of the students in each school. It will also create a lean district office focused on academic standards and performance monitoring, allowing more dollars to go to schools. Finally, it will migrate toward  a single, aligned and highly-effective governing board that provides a stable leadership team with skills to oversee successful implementation of the plan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, over 50 percent of our schools in New Orleans have reopened as charter schools. They have provided us with an expedient means to restart public education in New Orleans. It is my hope that we can continue this trend by utilizing the Educational Network Model for these schools and others nationwide by engaging community involvement and support through a shared services model.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed, the preamble be agreed to, the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table, and that any statements relating to the resolution be printed in the Record, with no intervening action or debate.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
