<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1197910803" ordinal="33" title="NATIONAL TEEN DATING VIOLENCE AWARENESS AND PREVENTION WEEK">
  <narrative>NATIONAL TEEN DATING VIOLENCE AWARENESS AND PREVENTION WEEK -- (Senate - December 17, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="15790">S15790</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300034" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of Calendar No. 541, <bill type="sr" number="388">S. Res. 388</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="388">S. Res. 388</bill>) designating the week of February 4 through February 8, 2008, as "National Teen Dating Violence Awareness and Prevention Week."</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300034" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table, and that any statements relating to the resolution be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="388">S. Res. 388</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="388">S. Res. 388</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas 1 in 3 female teenagers in a dating relationship has feared for her physical safety;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas 1 in 2 teenagers in a serious relationship has compromised personal beliefs to please a partner;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas 1 in 5 teenagers in a serious relationship reports having been hit, slapped, or pushed by a partner;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas 27 percent of teenagers have been in dating relationships in which their partners called them names or put them down;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas 29 percent of girls who have been in a relationship said that they have been pressured to have sex or to engage in sexual activities that they did not want;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas technologies such as cell phones and the Internet have made dating abuse both more pervasive and more hidden;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas 30 percent of teenagers who have been in a dating relationship say that they have been text-messaged between 10 and 30 times per hour by a partner seeking to find out where they are, what they are doing, or who they are with;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas 72 percent of teenagers who reported they'd been checked up on by a boyfriend or girlfriend 10 times per hour by email or text messaging did not tell their parents; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas parents are largely unaware of the cell phone and Internet harassment experienced by teenagers;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Native American women experience higher rates of interpersonal violence than any other population group;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas violent relationships in adolescence can have serious ramifications for victims, putting them at higher risk for substance abuse, eating disorders, risky sexual behavior, suicide, and adult revictimization;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the severity of violence among intimate partners has been shown to be greater in cases where the pattern of violence has been established in adolescence; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the establishment of National Teen Dating Violence Awareness and Prevention Week will benefit schools, communities, and families regardless of socio-economic status, race, or sex: Now, therefore be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) designates the week of February 4 through February 8, 2008, as "National Teen Dating Violence Awareness and Prevention Week"; and</chair>
  <chair> (2) calls upon the people of the United States, high schools, law enforcement, State and local officials, and interested groups to observe National Teen Dating Violence Awareness and Prevention Week with appropriate programs and activities that promote awareness and prevention of the crime of teen dating violence in their communities.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
