<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1207152003" ordinal="36" title="SENATE RESOLUTION 497--EXPRESSING THE SENSE OF THE SENATE THAT PUBLIC SERVANTS SHOULD BE COMMENDED FOR THEIR DEDICATION AND CONTINUED SERVICE TO THE NATION DURING PUBLIC SERVICE RECOGNITION WEEK, MAY 5 THROUGH 11, 2008">
  <narrative>SENATE RESOLUTION 497--EXPRESSING THE SENSE OF THE SENATE THAT PUBLIC SERVANTS SHOULD BE COMMENDED FOR THEIR DEDICATION AND CONTINUED SERVICE TO THE NATION DURING PUBLIC SERVICE RECOGNITION WEEK, MAY 5 THROUGH 11, 2008 -- (Senate - April 02, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="2362">S2362</bill>]</narrative>
  <narrative>Mr. AKAKA (for himself, Mr. VOINOVICH, Mr. LIEBERMAN, Ms. COLLINS, Mr. LEVIN, Mr. STEVENS, Mr. CARPER, Mr. WARNER, Mr. OBAMA, and Mrs. MCCASKILL) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="sr" number="497">S. Res. 497</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas Public Service Recognition Week provides an opportunity to recognize and promote the important contributions of public servants and honor the diverse men and women who meet the needs of the Nation through work at all levels of government;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas millions of individuals work in government service in every city, county, and State across America and in hundreds of cities abroad;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas public service is a noble calling involving a variety of challenging and rewarding professions;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Federal, State, and local governments are responsive, innovative, and effective because of the outstanding work of public servants;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the United States of America is a great and prosperous Nation, and public service employees contribute significantly to that greatness and prosperity;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Nation benefits daily from the knowledge and skills of these highly trained individuals;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas public servants--</narrative>
  <narrative>(1) defend our freedom and advance United States interests around the world;</narrative>
  <narrative>(2) provide vital strategic support functions to our military and serve in the National Guard and Reserves;</narrative>
  <narrative>(3) fight crime and fires;</narrative>
  <narrative>(4) ensure equal access to secure, efficient, and affordable mail service;</narrative>
  <narrative>(5) deliver social security and medicare benefits;</narrative>
  <narrative>(6) fight disease and promote better health;</narrative>
  <narrative>(7) protect the environment and the Nation's parks;</narrative>
  <narrative>(8) enforce laws guaranteeing equal employment opportunity and healthy working conditions;</narrative>
  <narrative>(9) defend and secure critical infrastructure;</narrative>
  <narrative>(10) help the Nation recover from natural disasters and terrorist attacks;</narrative>
  <narrative>(11) teach and work in our schools and libraries;</narrative>
  <narrative>(12) develop new technologies and explore the earth, moon, and space to help improve our understanding of how our world changes;</narrative>
  <narrative>(13) improve and secure our transportation systems;</narrative>
  <narrative>(14) promote economic growth; and</narrative>
  <narrative>(15) assist active duty service members and veterans;</narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas members of the uniformed services and civilian employees at all levels of government make significant contributions to the general welfare of the United States, and are on the front lines in the fight against terrorism and in maintaining homeland security;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas public servants work in a professional manner to build relationships with other countries and cultures in order to better represent America's interests and promote American ideals;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas public servants alert Congress and the public to government waste, fraud, abuse, and dangers to public health;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the men and women serving in the Armed Forces of the United States, as well as those skilled trade and craft Federal employees who provide support to their efforts, are committed to doing their jobs regardless of the circumstances, and contribute greatly to the security of the Nation and the world;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas public servants have bravely fought in armed conflict in defense of this Nation and its ideals and deserve the care and benefits they have earned through their honorable service;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas government workers have much to offer, as demonstrated by their expertise and innovative ideas, and serve as examples by passing on institutional knowledge to train the next generation of public servants;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas May 5 through 11, 2008, has been designated Public Service Recognition Week to honor America's Federal, State, and local government employees; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Public Service Recognition Week is celebrating its 24th anniversary through job fairs, student activities, and agency exhibits: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) commends public servants for their outstanding contributions to this great Nation during Public Service Recognition Week and throughout the year;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) salutes government employees for their unyielding dedication and spirit for public service;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) honors those government employees who have given their lives in service to their country;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) calls upon a new generation to consider a career in public service as an honorable profession; and</narrative>
  <narrative> (5) encourages efforts to promote public service careers at all levels of government.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise to introduce a resolution honoring the dedication, commitment, and noble service of Federal, State, and local government employees during Public Service Recognition Week.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For the past 23 years, the first full week of May is reserved to recognize the men and women of the military and civilian workforces diligently serving our Nation and celebrate their achievements.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Throughout the history of this Nation, public servants have been the first in many fields. Public servants are the first to respond to an emergency. They were the first to walk on the moon, the first to subnavigate the North Pole, and the driving force behind the creation of the Internet. However, there are lesser known achievements of public servants that improve all of our lives. Researchers at NIH were the first to make a discovery that lead to the Human Papillomavirus vaccine. They were the  first to create a program allowing States and localities to analyze DNA evidence on thousands of cases. And, they have been the first to discover hormones produced by the heart that have profound benefits in treating many deadly diseases.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Public Service Recognition Week is a time for all Americans to recognize the contributions which public servants make to this country that are often overlooked. We are familiar with the police officers who patrol our streets, the teachers who teach our children, the public officials we elect to govern, and the war fighters so bravely defending our country. However, there are many other public servants who protect and care for our National Parks, provide care to veterans, protect the water we  drink, build the roads we drive on, archive American history and the American experience, and curate our public museums that work behind the scenes without much attention or praise. These are just some of the silent servants who are the backbone of America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Public servants have chosen a career path that does not often exalt or glorify their work. We rarely hear about the support the civilians in the Department of Defense are providing to the military during this time of war or the doctors and nurses at the Veterans' Affairs Administration who provide care to the many men and women returning home from combat while struggling with insufficient resources. PSR week is a time we thank them for their service and recognize their efforts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This week is not just a time for us to honor their work, but a time for us to get to know the groundbreaking efforts made by the military and civil servants. Across the country, mayors, State governments, Governors, county governments, and many other civic organizations are participating in Public Service Recognition Week through proclamations, honorary events, awards, and exhibits. In Washington, DC, Federal agencies are coming together on the National Mall to demonstrate to the public all that  they do for America. The military will show its might with planes, helicopters, tanks, and other machinery located throughout the exhibit. The civil service will show innovations in scientific research, advances in criminal detection and law enforcement, and ways it is improving the lives of Americans everyday.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We sit on the edge of great change in the Federal workforce. According to the Office of Personnel Management, an estimated 40 percent of the 1.8 million federal employees will retire in the next 10 years as many more become eligible to retire. According to a number of recent reports published by the Partnership for Public Service, we know that young people want meaning in their careers. They can find both meaning and nobility in public service. Our challenge is to show the next generation of  employees that public service offers a range of options for meaningful experiences and dynamic opportunities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As we celebrate the 24th annual Public Service Recognition Week May 5-11, I encourage all Americans to take time out of their busy schedules to learn more about the work of public servants and recognize them for their commitment and dedication.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
