<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1182268804" ordinal="44" title="STATEMENTS ON INTRODUCED BILLS AND JOINT RESOLUTIONS">
  <speaking speaker="300042" topic="Introducing S. 1649. A bill to provide for 2 programs to authorize the use of leave by caregivers for family members of certain individuals performing military service, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1649">S. 1649</bill>] Mr. President, today I introduce legislation that should, and could, have been law 1 year ago, the Military Family Support Act. This bill provides modest but significant relief for the families of the brave American soldiers deployed overseas. I was disappointed that, after passing the Senate last year as an amendment to the fiscal year 2007 Defense Department authorization bill, this provision was removed in conference. I am pleased to be joined in this effort by Senator Casey.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As part of the predeployment process, military personnel with dependent children or other dependent family members designate a caregiver for their dependents. Dependents may be children, elderly parents, an ill sibling; anyone who requires care. These caregivers act in the deployed personnel's place to provide care during the period of deployment. The caregiver could be a spouse, parent, sibling, or other responsible adult who is capable of caring, and willing to care, for the dependents in question.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill that I am introducing today, the Military Family Support Act, would create two programs to provide additional leave options for persons who have been designated as caregivers. The bill would require the Office of Personnel Management, OPM, to create a program under which Federal employees who are designated as caregivers could use accrued annual or sick leave, leave bank benefits, and other leave available to them under title 5 for purposes directly relating to or resulting from their  designation as a caregiver.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The second program would be administered by the Department of Labor for private sector employees. The Department would create a voluntary program, allowing private sector companies to create similar programs for their employees. Many companies across the country are already working with employees to provide support when an employee or a family member of an employee is called to active duty. I commend these companies for their compassion and understanding, and I hope that this program would expand  such options to more workers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Lastly, this bill would require a report from the Government Accountability Office evaluating both the OPM and voluntary private sector program. If the report demonstrates that the program has helped military families, which I believe it will, Congress may act to expand the programs or make them permanent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to be clear that the legislation I am introducing today specifically exempts Family Medical Leave Act leave from the types of leave that can be used by designated caregivers under this legislation. Last Congress, I introduced legislation to expand the FMLA to cover leave for designated caregivers. That legislation, however, met with opposition from some Members who object to the FMLA itself. While I continue to believe that this opposition is misguided and that family members of deployed  servicemembers should be able to take leave under the FMLA, I have drafted this compromise measure to address those concerns.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation has been endorsed by the National Military Family Association, the National Partnership for Women and Families, and the Military Officers Association of America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In small towns and big cities all over this country, family members of deployed servicemembers are struggling to care for their children without their spouses' help. In addition, many servicemembers care for elderly parents and this responsibility often falls to a sibling or spouse when that servicemember is deployed abroad. While we may not be able to promise the safe return of each one of these brave men and women, we can provide this modest relief to their families here at home. I urge my  colleagues to support this legislation and I yield the floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill and letters of support be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="Introducing S. 1651. A bill to assist certain Iraqis who have worked directly with, or are threatened by their association with, the United States, and for other purposes; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1651">S. 1651</bill>] Mr. President, because of the war in Iraq, more than 2 million Iraqis have been internally displaced in their own country, and 2 million other Iraqis are in neighboring countries throughout the region, primarily Jordan and Syria.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The humanitarian needs of the refugees and internally displaced Iraqis are immense. If their needs are not quickly and adequately met, these populations could become a fertile recruiting ground for terrorists.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Iraqi refugees are also a significant financial burden on countries in the region. As the Iraq Study Group concluded, if the refugee crisis "is not addressed, Iraq and the region could be further destabilized."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many Iraqis who have worked in critical positions in direct support of the U.S. Government in Iraq have been killed or injured in reprisals for their support of our effort. Many more Iraqis associated with the United States have fled their country in fear of being killed or injured.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Clearly, we cannot resettle all of Iraq's refugees in the United States, but we have a fundamental obligation to help the vast number of Iraqis displaced in Iraq and throughout the region by the war and the associated chaos, especially those who have supported America's efforts in Iraq.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In April 2007, Assistant Secretary of State Ellen Sauerbray said the United States "could resettle up to 25,000 Iraqi refugees this year." In May 2007, Under Secretary Paula Dobriansky said, "We are committed to honoring our moral debt to those Iraqis who have provided assistance to the United States military and embassy." On June 8, Secretary Rice said "the people that I'm most worried about in the near term are the people who've worked with us who might be subject to recrimination and  reprisal. And we're trying to step up our efforts on their behalf."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is essential for the United States to develop a comprehensive and effective approach to meet the rapidly growing needs of Iraq's refugees and internally displaced persons, especially those who are associated with the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation I am introducing today with Senators Smith, Biden, Hagel, Leahy, Levin, and Lieberman seeks to accomplish these goals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, the legislation would create a special category of applicants for refugee status in Iraq. Those eligible for this program, a P-2 category for refugees of special humanitarian concern, would be the Iraqis most closely associated with the United States. Iraqis who qualify would be those, 1. who have been employed by or worked directly with the U.S. Government in Iraq; or, 2. who were employed in Iraq by a media or nongovernmental organization based in the United States or by an organization  or entity that has received a grant from, or entered into a cooperative agreement or contract with, the U.S. Government; or, 3. who are spouses, children, sons, daughters, siblings and parents of those who worked for or with us; or, 4. who are members of religious or minority communities and have close family members in the U.S.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Those eligible would not have to be referred to our Government by the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees or a U.S. Embassy. All applicants, however, would need to demonstrate a well-founded fear of persecution. Applicants would be required to go through recently approved extensive security screening.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>P-2 visas for these refugees would come out of the overall authorized admissions number for the refugee program, currently established at 70,000. That figure is determined every year by the President in close consultation with the Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to the new P-2 category of refugee applications, the legislation would expand the current U.S. Government program which provides special immigrant visas only to Iraqi and Afghan translators and interpreters. Those eligible for the expanded special immigrant visa program are Iraqis who have been employed by or worked directly with the United States for 1 year in the aggregate since 2003, and need not have served as a translator or interpreter for the military or Department of State.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Applicants for SIV visas would not need to demonstrate a well-founded fear of persecution, but they would need to meet security requirements, demonstrate that they provided faithful service to our Government, and provide a recommendation or evaluation. The Secretary of State would be required to provide applicants with protection or immediate removal from Iraq if they are in immediate danger. Five thousand of these visas would be available yearly for 5 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Importantly, our legislation requires the Secretary of State to establish a program for processing P-2 refugees and SIV applicants in Iraq and in countries in the region. The Secretary would be required to report to the Congress within 60 days on plans to establish this program. Currently, there is no mechanism for applying for refugee status in Iraq. Those fleeing persecution and seeking refugee status must find their way to Jordan or Syria, locate an official from the United Nations High Commissioner  for Refugees, and then be referred to the U.S. Government by the United Nations. Because of the growing violence and risk for those associated with the United States, we need to find a way to address this problem for Iraqis inside Iraq. Our bill does not eliminate the referral system through the United Nations, or any other existing system, but it does create an essential mechanism for direct applications in country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To oversee the implementation of this new program, the Secretary of State would be required to establish in the Embassy in Baghdad a Minister</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Counselor for Refugees and Internally Displaced Persons. This senior official would be responsible for overseeing the in-country processing of P-2 refugee and special immigrant visa applicants, and would have authority to refer them directly to the U.S. refugee resettlement program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A parallel position would be created in the American embassies in Egypt, Jordan, Lebanon, and Syria to oversee the application process of P-2 refugees of special humanitarian concern. SIV applicants would work through regular consular channels in embassies in those countries.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Recognizing that the United States can only resettle a small number of the most vulnerable refugees within our borders, the Secretary of State would be required to consult with other countries about resettlement of refugee populations, develop mechanisms in countries with significant populations of displaced Iraqis to ensure the refugees' well-being and safety, and provide assistance to the countries in doing so.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, the legislation would allow Iraqis denied asylum after March 2003 based on changed conditions to file a new petition with an immigration judge to reopen their cases. Those denied asylum, for example, on the grounds that Saddam Hussein is no longer in power and the United States is committed to building democracy in Iraq should be permitted to make their case again before a judge.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After 90 days, and annually thereafter, the President would be required to submit an unclassified report to  Congress with a classified annex if necessary, assessing the financial, security, personnel, considerations and resources necessary to establish the programs required in the act. After 90 days, the Secretary of Homeland Security would be required to submit a report to Congress outlining plans to expedite processing of Iraqi refugees, including  a temporary expansion of the Refugee Corps, and plans to enhance existing systems for conducting background and security checks for Iraqis applying through the program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>More than 5 years ago, Arthur Helton, perhaps this country's staunchest advocate for the rights of refugees wrote, "Refugees matter ..... for a wide variety of reasons ..... Refugees are a product of humanity's worst instincts--the willingness of some persons to oppress others--as well as some of its best instincts--the willingness of many to assist and protect the helpless ..... In personal terms, we care about refugees because of the seed of fear that lurks in all of us that can be stated  so simply: it could be me."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A year later, Arthur Helton gave his life for his beliefs. He was killed in Baghdad in 2003 while meeting with U.N. Special Envoy Sergio Vieira de Mello when a bomb destroyed the U.N. headquarters in Iraq.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But his words resonate today, especially when we consider the very human cost of the war in Iraq, and its tragic effect on the millions of Iraqis, men, women, and children, who have fled their homes and their country to escape the violence of a nation at war with itself.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>America has a special obligation to keep faith with the Iraqis who now have a bulls-eye on their back because of their association with our Government.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At a hearing in the Senate Judiciary Committee in January, chilling testimony was presented about the dangers Iraqis face because of their association with America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One Iraqi, Sami, was a translator for U.S. and Coalition forces and who now lives in the United States. He said, "I too, have been targeted for my death. My name was listed on the doors of several mosques calling for my death. Supposed friends of mine saw my name on the list and turned on me because  they believed I was traitor ..... In June 2006, I learned that I had been granted special status. As a result, today I live free from the fear of persecution and threats to my life that I faced on a daily basis in Iraq. My hope is that all brave Iraqis who worked and braved so much will have the same chance as I have had to live in freedom."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Another Iraqi, John, worked as a water service man for U.S. troops. He said, "My wife, my six children and myself fled Iraq after terrorist groups targeted me and my family because I aided the Americans by supplying water to their service camps."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ken Bacon, president of Refugees International, summed it up well when he said, "There is a large group of Iraqis who have risked their lives to support the United States ..... people are sacrificing their lives to help the United States."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation has been endorsed by organizations including Refugees International, Refugee Council USA which encompasses Amnesty International USA, Arab-American and Chaldean Council, Chaldean Federation of America, Church World Service/Immigration and Refugee Program, Episcopal Migration Ministries, Hebrew Immigrant Aid Society, Human Rights First, International Rescue Committee, Jesuit Refugee Service/USA, Jubilee Campaign USA, Lutheran Immigration and Refugee Services, Migration &amp; Refugee  Services/United States Conference of Catholic Bishops, Southeast Asia Resource Action Center, U.S. Committee for Refugees and Immigrants, Women's Commission for Refugee Women and Children, and WorId Relief, the International Rescue Committee, and the PEN American center.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this legislation in order to keep the faith with those many brave Iraqis whose lives are in jeopardy because of their association with our forces in Iraq.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the letters of suport be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="HUMAN RIGHTS FIRST">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I am pleased to join Senators Kennedy, Smith, Levin, Hagel, Biden, and Lieberman to introduce this important legislation. In January of this year, the Judiciary Committee held a hearing to examine the plight of Iraq's refugees, during which we heard from the State Department, the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees, nongovernmental organizations and individuals, and Iraqi citizens who had been targeted for assisting the United States. This  hearing brought the enormity of the Iraq refugee situation into sharp focus and made clear that we must do more to address this crisis and provide assistance especially to those Iraqis who have assisted the United States with its mission. If enacted, this bill would help the United States fulfill the promises it has made to the people of Iraq.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In February of this year, the Bush administration announced that 7,000 Iraqi refugees would be permitted to enter the United States in 2007. Over the last 8 months, however, only 70 Iraqis have been allowed into the United States as refugees. Each year there are 20,000 unallocated slots for refugees that could be applied to Iraq, and an additional 5,000 for the Middle East. Yet the Department of Homeland Security has admitted approximately 700 Iraqis since the war began in 2003. We have an obligation  to do better than this when an estimated 4 million Iraqis have been displaced within Iraq or have fled the country due to our involvement there. And we have a special obligation to do all we can for those Iraqis who have made tremendous sacrifices on behalf of the United States and who continue to live under the threat of torture and death.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Refugees International has called the Iraq refugee crisis the fastest growing refugee crisis in the world. It is estimated that nearly 2 million Iraqis have been internally displaced, while another 2 million have fled the country, with little more than they could carry. With this bill, we show our commitment not to repeat the tragic and immoral mistake from the Vietnam era and leave friends without refuge and subject to violent reprisals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The United States has an obligation to the people of Iraq, and especially to those who have assisted the American military in its efforts there. When an Iraqi man or woman makes the choice to help the United States--whether as an interpreter or in some other role--and puts his or her life on the line, the United States bears a special responsibility to do what it can to reciprocate the loyalty that so many Iraqis have shown us.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill we introduce today will create a new P2 category for Refugees of Special Humanitarian Concern. Individuals who have assisted the United States, or who have worked for a company, NGO, or other entity that has received a grant or contract from the U.S. Government would be eligible for status as a refugee of special humanitarian concern. In order to implement this new program, the legislation would direct the establishment of consular processing facilities in Iraq to expedite the resettlement  process for those Iraqis and their immediate families who qualify under the bill for special relief.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also sets up a special immigrant visa category for individuals who have worked as interpreters or translators for the United States for an aggregate of 1 year between 2003 and the present. This new program would augment current efforts to provide protection for those individuals who have assisted the United States by providing interpreter or translation services.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation would also direct the Secretary of State to establish an office of Minister Counselor in the U.S. Embassy in Baghdad. This office would be responsible for overseeing the new programs set up under this bill, and would be the primary point of contact for eligible individuals seeking protection. This official would also have the authority to refer individuals directly to the United States Refugee Resettlement Program. Additionally, parallel Minister Counselor offices would be established  in Egypt, Jordan, Syria, and Lebanon to effectuate the P2 refugee program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Secretary of State would also be required to work with other nations currently hosting Iraqi refugees in order to provide support and to help ensure the safety and well-being of Iraqis located in countries surrounding Iraq. The legislation would also allow Iraqis who applied for asylum in the United States after 2003, and who were denied based on changed country conditions due to the overthrow of Saddam Hussein, to have those denials reviewed due to the continuing violence and dangerous conditions  in the country. This change will allow our laws to reflect the current reality in Iraq.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation will help provide some relief to the brave men and women who have assisted the United States in Iraq, and will help renew the commitment of the United States to the cause of protecting those who turn to us for help. I hope all Senators can join with us in support of the bill we introduce today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300062" topic="Introducing S. 1654. A bill to prohibit the sale or provision of caller ID spoofing services; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1654">S. 1654</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to introduce a bill that would prohibit the sale or provision of caller ID spoofing services. This bill would enact a legislative proposal that was made by the Justice Department in a letter to members of this committee. To facilitate commentary on this bill, I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill and a letter from the Justice Department be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="Introducing S. 1655. A bill to establish improved mandatory standards to protect miners during emergencies, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1655">S. 1655</bill>] Mr. President, last year, the Nation was stunned by the terrible tragedies at the Sago, Alma, and Darby mines. Those disasters exposed the many failures in our laws on mine safety and mine health, and made clear that it is essential to bring these protections into the modern world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last year, Congress came together to take a vital step toward protecting the Nation's miners with the passage of the MINER Act, which addressed critical lapses in mine safety and accident response, but advances in scientific research and technological development show us that there is much more to be done. In part through the new scrutiny that is taking place under the MINER Act, we have learned a great deal more about what puts miners in danger and how to prevent it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We need to begin to address these other pressing safety and health needs. That is why today I am introducing the Miner Health and Safety Enhancement Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is much we can do in the area of mine safety emergencies to increase miners' chances of survival, and this legislation encourages the development of technologies to do so. It requires stronger seal barriers to protect miners from explosions in hazardous mining areas. It also requires mine companies to adopt more sophisticated communications technology to stay in touch with miners underground, and to install rescue chambers to protect miners in the event of an explosion or fire.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill does more to eliminate dangerous conditions in mines before they harm miners, by banning the unsafe practice of ventilating mines in the same passageway as coal-dust laden conveyor belts. This practice, unfortunately, has been approved by the Bush administration, and it contributed to the tragic fire at Alma mine last year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Other reforms are essential as well. Establishing a national call center can quickly coordinate emergency information and enhance mine rescue and recovery operations. To see that accident investigations are objective and thorough, the legislation requires an independent investigation to be conducted if miners or their families ask for one.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Successful prevention depends also on the willingness of miners to tell the truth about their working conditions. Safeguards are needed to allow them to speak out about on-the-job hazards without fearing for their jobs. The bill establishes an independent ombudsman, so miners' safety complaints can be heard and fully addressed, without jeopardizing miners who blow the whistle on job hazards.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Tragically, we continue to see miners developing symptoms of black lung disease and other deadly respiratory illnesses of the past. To protect them, the bill requires operators to provide miners with personal dust monitors developed and certified by the National Institute of Occupational Safety and Health. To make underground air safer, the bill adopts the Institute's levels for exposure to coal dust, silica dust, and other air contaminants. It also adopts the higher OSHA standard for asbestos.  We cannot continue to allow miners to work without the protection of these important health standards.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mining is an essential industry, and the nation's miners deserve the safest possible working conditions. We have a responsibility to see that our mine safety laws make our mines the safest and healthiest in the world. America's miners deserve no less. I urge my colleagues to support the Mine Health and Safety Enhancement Act of 2007.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="Introducing S. 1655. A bill to establish improved mandatory standards to protect miners during emergencies, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I am pleased to cosponsor the Miner Health and Safety Enhancement Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is critical that the Congress continue to review the statutory safeguards for our Nation's coal miners. I want to do everything I can to encourage that effort.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Given reports recently about alarmingly aggressive cases of black lung around southern West Virginia, the Congress ought to seriously consider new standards for dust monitoring and control. I also support the bill's language requiring the installation of atmospheric monitoring systems in underground coal mines and requiring the Mine Safety and Health Administration, MSHA, to randomly test emergency breathing devices every 6 months.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also very much support provisions in the bill that would clarify the intentions of the MINER Act and require the Department of Labor to issue regulations mandating the installation of refuge chambers and restricting the use of belt-air ventilation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These are all good initiatives and something that the Congress should be advocating to ensure safer working conditions for miners. Nevertheless, I do have reservations about some of the provisions in the Miner Health and Safety Enhancement Act, which I hope can be addressed before the Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions, HELP, Committee takes any action on this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The MINER Act that the Congress passed last year set a deadline requiring coal operators to install wireless emergency communications and tracking equipment by June 2009. In order to meet this deadline, the Congress appropriated $23 million through the fiscal year 2008 for NIOSH to expedite its research of emergency communications and tracking.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is important that the Congress adhere closely to that schedule. To suddenly rewrite it, mandating the installation of technologies before NIOSH has completed its research, could undermine the intentions of the MINER Act and complicate the efforts of MSHA and the Congress to ensure timely compliance. Let us not revisit timelines that have already been resolved and where implementation has already begun. It is better for the Congress to hold operators to the schedule outlined in the MINER Act  and to allow NIOSH to perform the critical research that has already been mandated and funded.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Congress should continue to exercise its oversight function to ensure rapid implementation of the MINER  Act and also to review non-MINER Act priorities to ensure statutory safeguards are adequate. I proudly join the sponsors of this bill in that endeavor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300091" topic="Introducing S. 1656. A bill to authorize loans for renewable energy systems and energy efficiency projects under the Express Loan Program of the Small Business Administration; to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1656">S. 1656</bill>] Mr. President, as Ranking Member of the Senate Committee Small Business and Entrepreneurship, I rise today with Senator Kerry to introduce the Small Business Energy Efficiency Act of 2007. The energy debate now underway in this body is a positive initial step for our country, but it is only a first step. Frankly, America must become more innovative and invest in infrastructure that provides a lifetime of savings, both for its citizens and our global neighbors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This year the Senate Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship, of which I am the Ranking Member, has paid particular attention to the effects of climate change and escalating fuel costs on small businesses, and the role America's entrepreneurs can play in affecting change in these areas. Chairman Kerry and I have already devoted two hearings during the 110th Congress to these subjects. Clearly, rising gas prices and global warming are having a devastating affect on the health  of small business in this country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As we all know, small business is the backbone of our Nation's economy. As the leading Republican on the Small Business Committee and as a longstanding steward of the environment, I firmly believe that small business has a pivotal role to play in finding a solution to global climate change. According to a recent survey conducted by the National Small Business Association, 75 percent of small businesses believe that energy efficiency can make a significant contribution to reducing greenhouse gas  emissions. And yet, only 33 percent of those had successfully invested in energy efficiency programs for their businesses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We need to significantly improve energy efficiency investment by small businesses. To that end, our measure will ensure that the SBA completes its requirements under the Energy Policy Act of 2005. Within 90 days of enactment, the SBA, through a final rulemaking, would be required to complete all of its requirements under the Energy Policy Act, including setting up a Energy Clearinghouse that builds on the Environmental Protection Agency's Energy Star program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our bill would also create the position of Assistant Administrator for Small Business Energy Policy within the SBA. The duties of this position include: 1. the oversight and administration the Small Business Energy Clearinghouse Program; and 2. the promotion of energy efficiency efforts and the reduction of energy costs for small businesses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It would also create a Small Business Energy Efficiency Pilot Grant Program. This pilot, competitive grant program would be administered through the national network of Small Business Development Centers, SBDCs, which would provide "energy audits" to small businesses to enhance their energy efficiency practices, as well as providing access to information and resources on energy efficiency practices. These practices would include "on-bill financing" options.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our bill would also encourage innovation in energy efficiency. Federal agencies shall give priority to Small Business Innovation Research, SBIR, and Small Business Technology Transfer, STTR, program solicitations by small businesses that participate in or conduct energy efficiency or renewable energy system research and development. The SBA will issue guidelines to assist Federal agencies and departments in determining whether priority has been given.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, our bill would make the SBA's Express Loan Program available to small businesses who wish to purchase renewable energy systems or make energy efficiency improvements to their existing businesses. I firmly believe that the SBA Express Loan will be an attractive option to small business owners looking to make their businesses more energy efficient and environmentally sound because of the program's quick turnaround time and the ability of participating lenders to use their own forms and  procedures for approval. Furthermore, lenders and borrowers can negotiate the interest rate, which can result in more favorable terms for a small business owner. The Express Program is the most widely used of SBA's loan products, representing 69 percent of all loans made. In fact, the SBA Express lender network is made up of almost 2,000 financial institutions nationwide.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many small businesses are already leading the charge in combating global warming. For instance, in my home state of Maine, Oakhurst Dairy, an 86-year-old business, recently announced that it has converted its fleet of over 100 trucks and trailers to a bio-diesel fuel blend. Oakhurst's President Stanley Bennett sent me a letter stating: "We firmly believe that doing the right thing environmentally is almost always the right thing to do for your business." It is my hope that our bill will spur  more small firms to make the same investment in the environment and their businesses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As we engage in this debate, we must remain mindful that potential solutions must fully consider the economic realities facing small businesses. According to the SBA Office of Advocacy, compliance with environmental regulations costs 364 percent more in small businesses than in larger businesses. So, in developing solutions Senator Kerry and I have worked to ensure that small businesses possess a range of cost-effective alternatives and have avoided a one-sized-fits-all approach.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In conclusion, this bipartisan measure will enable small businesses to play a leading role in combating global climate change. Assisting small firms in this regard will not only help the environment, but will also significantly lower the energy costs for cash-strapped small businesses.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300060" topic="Introducing S. 1657. A bill to establish a small business energy efficiency program, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1657">S. 1657</bill>] Mr. President, in March of this year, I convened a hearing in the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship to look at what small businesses can do to confront global warming. In February, the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change put forward a report that has been referred to as "the smoking gun" on global warming, written by more than 600 scientists, reviewed by another 600 experts, and edited by officials from 154 governments, the report provides indisputable evidence  that the ice caps are melting, the sea level is rising, and the earth's surface is heating up at an alarming and potentially catastrophic rate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator Snowe and I have worked together on a number of initiatives to combat global warming, including introducing the Global Warming Reduction Act of 2007, an effort to reduce greenhouse gas emissions by 65 percent by the year 2050. Today, we continue this partnership as chairman and ranking member of the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship by introducing the Small Business Energy Efficiency Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are nearly 26 million small businesses in this country, nearly 26 million business owners that are focused on keeping their doors open and putting food on the table for their families. And while climate change and national energy security sometimes seem like distant threats compared to rising health care costs and staying competitive in an increasingly global economy, small business owners are telling us that energy costs are indeed a concern. The National Small Business Association recently  conducted a poll of its members, asking how energy prices affected their business decisions. Seventy-five percent said that energy prices had at least a moderate effect on their businesses, with roughly the same number saying that reducing energy costs would increase their profitability. Despite these numbers, only 33 percent have invested in energy efficient programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Environmental Protection Agency estimates that small businesses consume roughly 30 percent of the commercial energy consumed in this country, that is roughly 2 trillion kBtu of  energy per year, and it is costing small business concerns approximately $29 million a year. Through efforts to increase energy efficiency, small businesses can contribute to America's energy security, help to combat global warming, and add to their bottom line all at the  same time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Small Business Energy Efficiency Act of 2007 seeks to assist small business owners in doing all of these things. First, the bill requires the Small Business Administration, SBA, to implement an energy efficiency program that was mandated in the 2005 Energy Policy Act. To date, the SBA has dragged its feet in implementing a program that could help small business owners to become more energy efficient. Administrator Preston should implement this important program today, and this bill directs  him to do so.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second, the bill establishes a program to increase energy efficiency through energy audits at Small Business Development Centers, SBDCs. The Pennsylvania SBDC currently operates a similar program, and has successfully assisted hundreds of businesses to become more energy efficient. As a result of the program, six of the eight winners of the 2006 ENERGY STAR Small Business Awards given by the EPA went to Pennsylvania businesses. This program should be replicated so that small businesses across  the country have the same opportunity to cut energy costs through the efficiency measures.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, this bill authorizes the Administrator to guarantee on-bill financing agreements between businesses and utility companies, to cover a utility company's risk in entering into such an agreement. The federal government should encourage utility companies to pursue these agreements with businesses, where an electric utility will cover the up-front costs of implementing energy efficiency measures, and a business will repay these costs through the savings realized in their energy bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill also encourages telecommuting through a pilot program at SBA. The Administrator is authorized to establish a program that produces educational materials and performs outreach to small businesses on the benefits of telecommuting.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, the bill encourages increased innovation by providing a priority status within the SBIR and STTR programs that ensures high priority be given to small business concerns participating in energy efficiency or renewable energy system research and development projects.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a Nation, we have much to do to secure our future energy supply and to solve the international crisis that is global warming. This bill represents one step in that process--to engage our small business owners in this effort, and to assist them in becoming more aware of what is possible. I urge my colleagues to support this bill, and I thank Senator Snowe for her work in this area.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300049" topic="Introducing S. 1658. A bill to amend the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act to provide protection for child custody arrangements for parents who are members of the Armed Forces deployed in support of a contingency operation; to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1658">S. 1658</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to speak about several of the personal problems currently being experienced by some military families due to the deployment of one or both parents and to introduce three pieces of legislation, the language of which is included in the recently passed House of Representatives Defense authorization bill, which are designed to help alleviate those problems.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But first, I would like to express my sincere thanks to the fathers and mothers, husbands and wives, sisters and brothers, and the sons and daughters of our Nation, who in these very tumultuous and dangerous times have volunteered to join our Armed Forces and serve our country around the world. In December 1776, another of the tumultuous times for our Nation, Thomas Paine wrote "These are the times that try men's souls: The summer soldier and the sunshine patriot will, in this crisis, shrink  from the service of his country; but he that stands it now, deserves the love and thanks of man and woman." Our modern day Patriots, who are now serving in the Army, Navy, Marine Corps, Air Force and Coast Guard, also heard and answered our country's call and they surely deserve the love and thanks of our Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In some cases, while a military parent is deployed overseas, courts have overturned custody arrangements of their child or children; this while the deployed military custodial parent was unable to appear before the court. The first piece of legislation, <bill type="s" number="1658">S. 1658</bill>, would provide protection of child custody arrangements for Armed Forces parents who are deployed in contingency operations. The legislation states that if a motion for change of custody of a child of a servicemember is filed while the  servicemember is deployed in support of a contingency operation, no court may enter an order modifying or amending any previous judgment or order, or issue a new order that changes the child custody arrangement that existed as of the deployment date. An exception is allowed whereby the court may enter a temporary custody order if there is clear and convincing evidence</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The second piece of legislation, <bill type="s" number="1659">S. 1659</bill>, is intended to preclude some of the tension and anxiety that a child may suffer from the simultaneous deployment of both parents, as well as the grief that would result if both those parents were to lose their lives while simultaneously deployed. This bill would provide a limitation on simultaneous deployment to combat zones of dual-military couples who have minor dependents. It states that in the case of a member of the Armed Forces with minor dependents  who has a spouse who is also a member of the Armed Forces, and the spouse is deployed in an area for which imminent danger pay is authorized, the member may request a deferment of a deployment to such an area until the spouse returns from such deployment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And the third piece of legislation, <bill type="s" number="1660">S. 1660</bill>, would initiate studies that could hopefully lead to improved support services for families of members of the National Guard and Reserve who are undergoing deployment. This legislation would direct the Secretary of Defense to conduct a study of possible methods to enhance support services for children of members of the National Guard and Reserve who are deployed. Additionally, the legislation would require the Pentagon to carry out a study on establishment  of a program on family-to-family support for families of deployed members of the National Guard and Reserve.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask that my fellow Senators consider these bills.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300037" topic="Introducing S. 1661. A bill to communicate United States travel policies and improve marketing and other activities designed to increase travel in the United States from abroad; to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1661">S. 1661</bill>] Mr. President, today I am introducing, along with Senators Stevens and Inouye, the Travel Promotion Act of 2007. We seek with this bill to increase travel to the United States and rebuild the country's place in the global travel market. After 9/11, the number of overseas travelers to the United States decreased dramatically and has still not recovered. Travel and tourism are a crucial part of our export industry, but other countries have gained market share to our  detriment. Foreign travelers are going elsewhere.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The absence of federal leadership in travel promotion has resulted in States having to step in to fill that void. An example is the effort made by my home State of North Dakota, where tourism is the State's second largest industry, with visitors spending $3.36 billion in 2004. The investment that North Dakota made to encourage travel and tourism has reaped enormous benefits, with the State getting a return of investment of almost $82 for each dollar spent on travel promotion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While States have made inroads to attracting travelers, the lack of a coordinated federal campaign creates a comparative disadvantage with countries that have centralized ministries or offices to encourage international travel to their countries. The example of North Dakota should be a lesson for the entire country. The United States offers unique and diverse destinations for travelers--a small investment in national coordination has the potential to create a significant windfall for our economy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Travel Promotion Act of 2007 will promote travel to the U.S., including areas not traditionally visited, highlighting the United States as a premier travel destination. The bill  will improve communication of United States travel policies and perceptions of the process. Negative perceptions can often deter foreigners from traveling to the United States. Our communities will benefit from growth of this multi-billion dollar industry. With an increase  in visitors they will experience an increase in jobs and expansion of local economies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill initiates a nationally coordinated travel promotion campaign established in a public-private partnership to increase international travel to the United States. It creates a Corporation for Travel Promotion, an independent, nonprofit corporation, to run the travel promotion campaign. The program will be funded equally by a small fee paid by foreign travelers visiting the U.S. and matching contributions from the travel industry.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a great country, and we should welcome visitors to our shores to meet our people and experience our culture. I thank the Chair and Vice-Chair of the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation for joining with me to develop this campaign and promote travel to our Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300056" topic="Introducing S. 1661. A bill to communicate United States travel policies and improve marketing and other activities designed to increase travel in the United States from abroad; to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, the travel and tourism industry is a driving force for our Nation's economy. In 2006, the industry generated a $7.3 billion trade surplus. In 2006, international receipts for travel-related tourism spending reached $107.8 billion. Travel and tourism supported 8.3 million American jobs in 2006, of which 1.1 million were supported by international travel and tourism. In Hawaii, tourism is the largest industry bringing in approximately $12 billion annually, $4 billion  of which derives from international visitor spending.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>International tourism brings more than economic returns. International travelers who visit our country can advance our standing overseas. Studies have shown that, after visiting the United States and interacting with Americans, 74 percent of visitors have a more favorable opinion of our country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In recent years, overseas travel to the United States has suffered. In the wake of the September 11, 2001, terrorist attack, the United States made a number of necessary changes in the visa and entry processes to improve security, but some of those changes have confused and deterred visitors from even the friendliest countries. Many in the travel industry have continued to express concerns about the perception that the U.S. entry process is unnecessarily antagonistic.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In order to strengthen our competitiveness and recover lost international market share, we must improve and better explain the process for travelers coming to America. The world needs to know that the United States welcomes business and leisure travelers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addressing these concerns, and in recognizing the benefits of travel promotion, I am pleased to join my colleagues, Senator Dorgan and Vice Chairman Stevens, in introducing the Travel Promotion Act of 2007. The bill establishes a nonprofit, independent corporation charged with reaching out to potential international travelers, clarifying the ease of travel to America, and encouraging them to visit. As experts have testified in hearings before the Commerce Committee, a unified  effort to promote tourism to all areas of the United States is necessary and cannot be achieved by the industry alone.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The proposed corporation will be run by 14 board members, appointed by the Secretary of Commerce, who represent all aspects of the travel industry, including State tourism boards, hotels, and airlines, as well as the Federal Government. A small fee collected from international travelers to the United States will help fund the corporation, but its costs will be truly shared with industry. In order to receive the funds collected by the Government, the corporation will need to raise matching funds  from the travel industry. By working together, the Federal and State governments and business will be able to revitalize the travel industry and make America a stronger and more welcoming destination.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In most developed countries, the minister of tourism is one of the most powerful and important positions in the government. For too long, our Government has relegated travel and tourism to a second tier status. The bill seeks to improve that status by creating an Under Secretary of Commerce for Travel Promotion who would work with the State Department and the Department of Homeland Security, as well as the corporation, to improve travel promotion efforts and the entry process for international  travelers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The travel and tourism industry helps drive the U.S. economy. The Travel Promotion Act of 2007 will enhance our competitiveness while improving our image abroad, and I urge my colleagues to support this measure.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300060" topic="Introducing S. 1662. A bill to amend the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to reauthorize the venture capital program, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1662">S. 1662</bill>] Mr. President, today I am introducing legislation with my colleague, Senator Snowe, to increase access to venture capital for small businesses. This type of financing is essential to grow a company, but it's hard to come by, particularly for start-up firms. The Small Business Administration, SBA, has played an important role in filling this gap for almost 50 years with the Small Business Investment Company, SBIC, program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since the SBIC program's inception in 1958, SBIC firms have invested $48 billion in more than 100,000 small businesses. For fiscal year 2006 alone, 30 percent of all SBIC investment dollars went to companies that had been in business for two years or less. Overall in that year, SBIC financing supported more than 2,000 small businesses which employed a total of 286,000 Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many extremely successful companies that received their start from SBIC financing are now household names: Intel, Federal Express, Jenny Craig, and Outback Steakhouse are all SBIC success stories. Companies receiving SBIC financing have also consistently appeared on a variety of prominent business lists, including Inc. 500, BusinessWeek's "Hot Growth Companies" and "Hot Growth Hall of Fame," Fortune magazine's "Best Companies to Work For" and "Most Admired Companies," and the FSB 100.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Given the important contribution SBIC funds have made to our economy, our bill reauthorizes the SBIC program for another 3 years, through 2010, ensuring the continued availability of this important small business financing tool. Additionally, the legislation simplifies the program's regulations to attract new investors and allow existing investors to increase their involvement. These provisions will ensure that dependable capital is available for small businesses for years to come.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Entrepreneurs may start out small, but the contribution they make to our economy is huge--and particularly important in underserved communities. This legislation will also increase the leverage cap for small businesses owned by women and minorities as well as those located in low-income areas. It will simplify existing incentives for investing in the smallest businesses in order to give every entrepreneur a fighting chance. Finally, we have included a provision which ensures that SBICs licensed  under the participating securities program will be able to easily make follow-up investments in successful companies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Small businesses are responsible for more than two-thirds of all new jobs in America. They employ more than half of the private sector work force, and pump over $900 billion into the economy annually. As small business owners are living the American dream, they should be able to count on the government to help create an environment where they can do what they do best: innovate, compete, and create good jobs for Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank Senator Snowe for joining me in introducing this bill, and I ask my colleagues to support it when it comes before the full Senate for consideration. Mr. President, I ask that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300091" topic="Introducing S. 1662. A bill to amend the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to reauthorize the venture capital program, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, as Ranking Member of the Senate Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship, I rise today to join with Chairman Kerry in introducing the "Small Business Venture Capital Act of 2007," a bill to reauthorize and improve the Small Business Administration's (SBA) Small Business Investment Company (SBIC) Program. I am deeply committed to supporting our nation's small businesses by increasing their access to capital. Small businesses employ more than half (57  percent) of the total private-sector workforce and are responsible for the creation of more than two-thirds of all new jobs. Clearly, increasing investments in small businesses is crucial to our on-going economic success.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill, a product of genuine bipartisan negotiation, will reform and enhance the SBIC program, which is so  vital to fostering innovation, growth, and job creation in small businesses throughout our country. SBICs are privately owned and managed venture capital investment companies that are licensed and regulated by the SBA. SBICs use their own capital, combined with funds borrowed from other private investors and supported by an SBA guarantee, to  make equity and debt investments in qualifying small businesses. The SBA shares in the profits of SBICs. The structure of the program is unique and has been a model for similar public-private partnerships around the world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The program has been successful in mobilizing private venture capital investment and leveraging private investment with additional funds supported by SBA guarantees. According to the SBA's annual reports to Congress, the SBIC program has provided billions in financing to small businesses since its inception. For example, companies like Staples, FedEx, Outback Steakhouse, America Online, Costco, Apple Computers, and Intel have all received SBIC investments at one time in their history.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Each year, financing brought about by the SBIC program allows small businesses to create or retain tens of thousands of jobs. For example, during Fiscal Year 2006, the SBIC program invested $2.987 billion in 2,121 small businesses. Of these, 40 percent were located in government-designated Low and Moderate Income (LMI) areas of the county. Those LMI-district companies received $669 million of the total dollars invested by SBICs in 2006. Since its beginning in 1958, the SBIC program has provided  approximately $48 billion of long-term debt and equity capital to more than 100,000 small businesses. In fact, in my home State of Maine, SBICs invested nearly $21 million during FY 2006.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A key proposal in this bill is a technical change made to simplify the maximum leverage limits contained in the current statute. Under current law, the maximum leverage cap or the maximum amount of government-guaranteed capital an SBIC can control for Fiscal Year 2007, is $127.2 million for any one SBIC or for multiple SBICs controlled by the same management team. The cap increases automatically on an annual basis by the percentage increase in the Consumer Price Index (CPI). The problem with  current law is that because the leverage cap applies to a whole family of SBICs, it is often impossible for a successful SBIC to operate a second or third fund due to a lack of available leverage. Additional leverage would remedy this issue. Accordingly, the bill increases the leverage cap for anyone fund to $150 million, and the cap for multiple funds held under one management team to $225 million.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Furthermore, this bill will increase leverage available for investment in minority- and women-owned businesses, which are having trouble accessing SBIC dollars. In Fiscal Year 2004, minority-owned firms received 5.2 percent of financing dollars. Women-owned businesses obtained just 2.2 percent of financing dollars. To try to increase financing available to such small businesses, the bill increases leverage limits to $175 million for a single fund and $250 million for a group of funds held under  an SBIC license if the SBIC certifies that at least 50 percent of its investments are made in companies that are owned by either women or minorities, or are located in a low-income geographic area.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I urge my colleagues to support this bill. Too much is at stake for small businesses, and the economy as a whole, to allow this critical legislation to languish. Failing to advance this bill would diminish our chances for innovation, and stifle the entrepreneurial opportunities this program has and will continue to produce.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300060" topic="Introducing S. 1663. A bill to amend the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to reauthorize the New Markets Venture Capital Program, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1663">S. 1663</bill>] Mr. President, in addition to introducing a bill to reauthorize the Small Business Investment Company, SBIC, program, Senator Snowe and I are introducing a bill to extend the New Markets Venture Capital, NMVC, program. The Securing Equity for the Economic Development of Low Income Areas Act of 2007, or the SEED Act, is important to states like Massachusetts and Maine.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Both of our States are home to pioneers in the field of development venture capital, which uses the discipline of traditional venture investing to focus on economic development in low-income areas. We know the benefits of this type of investment and believe the model should be expanded to other parts of the country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our support is not new. In my case, I was the sponsor of the Community Development and Venture Capital Act of 1999, which created the New Markets Venture Capital program. Its purpose was to stimulate economic development through public-private partnerships that invest venture capital in smaller businesses located in impoverished rural and urban areas or that employ low-income people.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Both innovative and fiscally sound, this program was built on two of the Small Business Administration's most popular programs. It developed a financial structure similar to that of the successful Small Business Investment Company, SBIC, program, mentioned earlier, while also incorporating a technical assistance component similar to that of SBA's microloan program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, unlike the SBIC program, which focuses on small businesses with high-growth potential, the New Markets Venture Capital program focuses on small businesses that show promise of both financial and social returns--what is referred to as a "double bottom line." These businesses have special needs, and they tend to want intensive, ongoing financial, management and marketing assistance, be higher risk, and need longer periods to pay back money than SBIC investments. However, they more than  balance out the equation by providing good, stable jobs and creating wealth in our neediest communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, the program expired in 2006, and it has been operating under temporary authority since then. The SEED Act seeks to reauthorize, expand, and improve this important program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, the bill will reauthorize the program for the next 3 years until 2010, making it possible for the SBA to license up to 20 more New Markets Venture Capital funds. Those funds will have the potential to invest $250 million in small businesses in low-income areas, by leveraging $150 million in debentures. Building on experiences with this program and the Rural Business Investment Company Program, which proved the matching requirement unreasonable and inefficient, the bill changes the operational  assistance grants so that firms can get up to $1 million in funding in order to provide the companies they invest in with management assistance services. This support is absolutely necessary to make their business a success. Also important to making future funds successful, we have clarified that new markets venture capital companies have two years to raise their private capital. The committee has been troubled by the Agency's interpretation of the NMVC statute, which they viewed as giving SBA the authority to choose how much time it can give conditionally approved NMVCs to raise private-sector matching money. The chosen time frames were unreasonable and not what Congress</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On behalf of the Nation's small businesses and entrepreneurs, I urge my colleagues to support this important legislation. Mr. President, I ask that the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300091" topic="Introducing S. 1663. A bill to amend the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to reauthorize the New Markets Venture Capital Program, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, as ranking member of the Senate Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship, I rise today to join with Chairman Kerry in introducing the Securing Equity for the Economic Development of Low Income Areas Act of 2007, a bill to reauthorize the New Markets Venture Capital, NMVC, Program. The NMVC program specializes in providing investment dollars to small businesses in underserved, low-wealth urban and rural communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Selected by the SBA through a competitive process, NMVC companies are privately owned and managed for-profit entities. They use their own private capital plus debentures obtained at favorable rates with SBA guarantees for investing. In addition, they provide technical assistance to the low-income enterprises in which they invest or intend to invest, by using private resources matched by the SBA in the form of operational assistance grants. While the Consolidated Appropriations Act of 2001, which  established the program, contemplated 15 NMVC companies, unfortunately, only six NMVC companies have received final approval.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Despite the shortfall in the final numbers of approved companies, the NMVC program has achieved some remarkable success since Congress created it in 2000. According to the Community Development Venture Capital Alliance, as of March 31, 2006, the six NMVC companies had invested more than $13.4 million of capital into 29 small businesses. Not only have the NMVC Companies brought investment dollars to underinvested areas, but they have also created or maintained 1,626 jobs in low-income communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although the statistics I have just cited pertain to the entire Nation, I want to share an example of how the NMVC program has been a tremendous benefit to my home State of Maine. In 2003, Mike Cote purchased Look's Canning Company in Whiting, ME, which had become one of the last of what had been dozens of canneries along Maine's coast. After changing the canning company's name to Look's Gourmet Food Company, Mike worked with Wiscasset, Maine, based Coastal Enterprises, Inc., a New Markets Venture  Capital Company, to help grow the business. Look's Gourmet Food Company is now thriving by selling all-natural, high-quality, shelf-stable seafood products under the "Bar Harbor T" and "Atlantic T" brands all over the country. As Look's took off, it was able to create 18 new jobs with benefits in Maine's</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Other than reauthorizing the NMVC Program, this bill will make other changes to ensure the program is given the full opportunity to achieve its full potential. For example, the bill will  conform the definition of "low-income geographic area" used in the NMVC program to the definition of a "low-income community" as defined by the New Markets Tax Credit, NMTC, program. This amendment is beneficial because many investors participate in both the NMVC  and NMTC programs, and a uniform definition between the two programs would improve coordination between the two programs. This change would allow NMVC companies to invest in businesses that benefit a low-income population, as well as businesses located in low-income census tracts. This flexibility to serve low income "targeted</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The entrepreneurial spirit of our 26 million small businesses dates back to our Nation's founding. Small businesses are the cornerstone of economic growth and job creation, and it is critical that we support the NMVC program that enables aspiring entrepreneurs to obtain the crucial financing dollars they need to start and grow their businesses. As ranking member of the Senate Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship, I have long fought to ensure the success and vitality of our country's  small business sector. An investment in small business is an investment in the long-term economic prosperity of America, and I encourage my colleagues to support this vital legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
