<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1216224002" ordinal="30" title="CHANGES TO S. CON. RES. 70">
  <narrative>CHANGES TO <bill type="sc" number="70">S. CON. RES. 70</bill> -- (Senate - July 16, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="6864">S6864</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300026" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, section 312(c) of <bill type="sc" number="70">S. Con. Res. 70</bill>, the 2009 budget resolution, permits the chairman of the Senate Budget Committee to adjust the section 312(b) discretionary spending limits and allocations pursuant to section 302(a) of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 for legislation reported by the Senate Appropriations Committee that provides a certain level of funding for fiscal year 2009 for four program integrity initiatives. The initiatives are: continuing disability reviews  and supplemental security income redeterminations, Internal Revenue Service tax enforcement, health care fraud and abuse control, and unemployment insurance improper payment reviews.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senate Appropriations Committee reported <bill type="s" number="3230">S. 3230</bill>, the Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2009, on July 8, 2008. That bill contains provisions that fulfill the conditions of section 312(c) for adjustments related to continuing disability reviews and supplemental security income redeterminations, health care fraud and abuse control, and unemployment insurance improper payment reviews.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, the Senate Appropriations Committee reported <bill type="s" number="3260">S. 3260</bill>, the Financial Services and General Government Appropriations Act, 2009, on July 14, 2008. That bill contains provisions that fulfill the conditions of section 312(c) for Internal Revenue Service tax enforcement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a result, for fiscal year 2009, I am revising both the discretionary spending limits and the allocation to the Senate Appropriations Committee for discretionary budget authority and outlays. The amount of the adjustment is $968 million in budget authority and $892 million in outlays. The revised discretionary limits and allocations for discretionary budget authority and outlays are the appropriate levels to be used for enforcement during consideration of the fiscal year 2009 appropriations  bills.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the following revisions to <bill type="sc" number="70">S. Con. Res. 70</bill> be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
</record>
