<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1221753612" ordinal="73" title="SENATE RESOLUTION 668--TO COMMEND THE AMERICAN SAIL TRAINING ASSOCIATION FOR ITS ADVANCEMENT OF CHARACTER BUILDING UNDER SAIL AND FOR ITS ADVANCEMENT OF INTERNATIONAL GOODWILL">
  <narrative>SENATE RESOLUTION 668--TO COMMEND THE AMERICAN SAIL TRAINING ASSOCIATION FOR ITS ADVANCEMENT OF CHARACTER BUILDING UNDER SAIL AND FOR ITS ADVANCEMENT OF INTERNATIONAL GOODWILL -- (Senate - September 18, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="9040">S9040</bill>]</narrative>
  <narrative>Mr. KERRY submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="sr" number="668">S. Res. 668</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas the American Sail Training Association (ASTA) is an educational nonprofit corporation whose declared mission is "to encourage character building through sail training, promote sail training to the North American public and support education under sail";</narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas, since its founding in 1973, ASTA has promoted these goals through--(1) support of character building experiences aboard traditionally-rigged sail training vessels; (2) a program of scholarship funds supporting such experiences; (3) a long history of tall ship races, rallies, and maritime festivals dating back as far as 1976; (4) the Tall Ships Challenge series of races and maritime festivals which have been conducted each year since 2001, have reached an aggregate audience to date of  some 8,000,000 spectators, have had a cumulative economic impact of over $400,000,000 for over 30 host communities, and involve sail training vessels, trainees, and crews from all the coasts of the United States and around the world; (5) support of its membership of more than 200 sail training vessels, embracing barks, barques, barkentines, brigantines, brigs, schooners, sloops, and full-rigged ships, which carry the flags of the United States, Canada, and many other nations and have brought life changing adventures to thousands and thousands of young trainees; (6)</narrative>
  <narrative> (3) encourages all citizens of the United States and of nations around the world to join in the celebration of Tall Ships Atlantic Challenge 2009 and in the character building and educational experience that it represents for the youth of all nations.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300060" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today it is my great pleasure to honor the incredible achievement, tradition, and performance of the American Sail Training Association, ASTA. This educational nonprofit corporation has allowed young participants from across the country to build character through sail training and to represent the United States around the world with distinction and good spirit. I am proud of the dedicated trainers who have taught young sailors to persevere in international adventures  on brigantines, schooners, slops, and other vessels. I commend the efforts of the ASTA to provide such exciting and educational opportunities for youth, and I look forward to the coming Tall Ships Atlantic Challenge 2009.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
