<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1189526401" ordinal="33" title="STATEMENTS ON INTRODUCED BILLS AND JOINT RESOLUTIONS">
  <narrative>STATEMENTS ON INTRODUCED BILLS AND JOINT RESOLUTIONS -- (Senate - September 11, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="11416">S11416</bill>]</narrative>
  <narrative>By Mr. HATCH (for himself and Mr. BENNETT): <bill type="s" number="2039">S. 2039</bill>. A bill to require an assessment of the plans for the modernization and sustainment of the land-based, Minuteman III intercontinental ballistic missile strategic deterrent force, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Armed Services.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300052" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today I rise to introduce the Strategic Deterrent Sustainment Act of 2007, which is cosponsored by Senator Bennett. Currently, our land-based strategic forces are in the process of completing a vital and important modernization program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, I am unaware of any Department of Defense plan to maintain our land-based strategic missile industrial base once this modernization is completed in the next 2 to 3 years. Therefore, this legislation would require the Secretary of Defense to prepare a report detailing how our Nation will maintain an industrial base to replace the Minuteman III missile with a follow-on land-based strategic deterrent after 2030. 2030, is of course, the date in which the Minuteman III system is scheduled  to be replaced. The Secretary, under this legislation, will also be required to outline how our Nation will maintain, modernize and sustain the Minuteman III intercontinental ballistic missile system until at least 2030.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To put this in context, in 2002, the administration wisely committed the U.S. to a policy of modernizing our land-based intercontinental ballistic missile force. Under this policy, the Peacemaker ICBM has been retired and that system's warheads are being retrofitted and placed into the Minuteman III fleet. In addition to the new warheads, 500 Minuteman III systems are being completely rebuilt and thoroughly modernized.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, after this work is completed, no other work on land-based strategic missile systems is planned. As we all know, building an intercontinental ballistic missile is extremely complex and a great feat of engineering. It requires engineers with years of experience and highly trained and professional manufacturing specialists to successfully and safely build a missile system. Clearly, if there are not any additional systems to build, then these sought after engineers and specialists  will merely find employment elsewhere. In addition, if a replacement system will not be built  until 2030, it is very likely that much of our Nation's knowledge on how to design and build a land-based strategic missile system will be lost.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As an example, one can point to the British who recently decided to modernize their nuclear deterrent. Since the British nuclear warhead industrial base all but ceased to exist years ago, that nation will now have to allocate billions of additional pounds to reconstitute their design and production capability.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What would be the cost of our Nation to maintain our land-based strategic missile industrial base? Well I understand, the propulsion portion of the industrial base can be maintained for the relatively modest sum of under $50 million a year. In fact, such a program already exists for our submarine launched ballistic missile systems. Under this industrial base sustainment plan, 12 Trident missiles are manufactured each year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Should a plan to maintain our land-based strategic missile industrial base closely follow our submarine launched strategic missile industrial plans? Well under this legislation, the Secretary of Defense will have the opportunity to make that determination.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In conclusion, during this period of uncertainty we must keep our Nation's defense industrial options open in order to meet the threats of the future. The Strategic Deterrent Sustainment Act of 2007 affords us that opportunity and I hope that it will receive from my colleagues the support it deserves.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There being no objection the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>
      <bill type="s" number="2039">S. 2039</bill>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "Strategic Deterrent Sustainment Act of 2007".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. FINDINGS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Congress makes the following findings:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) The strategic forces of the United States remain a cornerstone of United States national security.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) The 2001 Nuclear Posture Review states that it is the current policy of the United States that intercontinental ballistic missiles (ICBMs), submarine-launched ballistic missiles, and long-range nuclear-armed bombers play a critical role in the defense capabilities of the United States, its allies, and friends.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) The dispersed and alert Minuteman III intercontinental ballistic missile system provides the most responsive, stabilizing, and cost-effective strategic force.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) Section 139 of the John Warner National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2007 (Public Law 109-364; 120 Stat. 2114) requires the Secretary of the Air Force to modernize Minuteman III intercontinental ballistic missiles in the United States inventory so as to maintain a sufficient supply of launch test assets and spares to sustain the deployed force of such missiles through 2030.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) The modernization program for the Minuteman III intercontinental ballistic missile is nearing completion. Once that program is complete, there will be no program to sustain the capability of the United States industrial base to modernize or replace the intercontinental ballistic missiles that constitute the sole land-based strategic deterrent system of the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph> (6) As an example, motor production for the Minuteman III Propulsion Replacement Program (PRP) is currently scheduled to end in fiscal year 2009. Once the PRP program ends, the capacity of the United States industrial base to respond to matters arising from the aging and obsolescence of Minuteman III intercontinental ballistic missiles will be extremely diminished, decades-worth of critical program knowledge may be lost, and the current design of the Minuteman III intercontinental ballistic  missile is likely to no longer be reproducible.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 3. REPORT ON CAPABILITIES FOR SUSTAINMENT OF THE MINUTEMAN III INTERCONTINENTAL BALLISTIC MISSILE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Report Required.--Not later than March 1, 2008, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the capability of the United States industrial base to achieve each of the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) To maintain, modernize, and sustain the Minuteman III intercontinental ballistic missile (ICBM) system until at least 2030.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) To replace the Minuteman III intercontinental ballistic missile with a follow-on land-based strategic deterrent system after 2030.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Elements.--The report required by paragraph (1) shall include the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) A description of any current plans for extending the Minuteman III intercontinental ballistic missile system after the period from 2020 to 2030, including plans for testing sufficient to account for any aging and obsolescence found in the Minuteman III intercontinental ballistic missile during the remaining life of the system, and an assessment of the risks associated with such plans after the shutdown of associated production lines.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) A description of any current plans to maintain the Minuteman III intercontinental ballistic missile system after 2030, including an assessment of any risks associated with such plans after the shutdown of associated production lines.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) An explanation why the Minuteman III intercontinental ballistic missile system, the only United States land-based strategic deterrent system, is no longer considered to be of the highest national defense urgency, as indicated by inclusion of the system on the so-called "DX-Rated Program List" while the sea-based strategic deterrent system, the Trident II D5 missile system, is still on the so-called "DX-list".</paragraph>
    <paragraph> (4) An analysis of existing commonalities between the service life extension program for the Trident II D5 missile system and any equivalent planned service life extension program for the Minuteman III intercontinental ballistic missile system, including an analysis of the impact on materials, the supplier base, production facilities, and the production workforce of extending all or part of the service life extension program for the Trident II D5 missile system to a service life extension program  for the Minuteman III intercontinental ballistic missile system.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) An assessment of the adequacy of current and anticipated programs, such as missile defense, space launch, and prompt global strike programs, to support the industrial base for the Minuteman III intercontinental ballistic missile system, including an analysis of the impact on materials, the supplier base, production facilities, and the production workforce of extending all or part of any such program to the program for the Minuteman III intercontinental ballistic missile system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph> (c) Comptroller General Review.--Not later than 60 days after submittal under subsection (a) of the report required by that subsection, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report setting forth the Comptroller General's assessment of the matters contained in the report under subsection (a), including an assessment of the consistency of the budget of the President for fiscal year 2009, as submitted to Congress pursuant to  section 1105 of title 31, United States Code, with the matters contained in the report under subsection (a).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (d) Congressional Defense Committees Defined.--In this section, the term "congressional defense committees" means--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="Introducing S.J. Res. 18. A joint resolution providing for congressional disapproval under chapter 8 of title 5, United States Code, of the rule submitted by the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services within the Department of Health and Human Services relating to a cost limit for providers operated by units of government and other provisions under the Medicaid program; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="sj" number="18">S.J. Res. 18</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today with Senators Rockefeller, Obama, Brown, Kerry, Byrd, Feinstein, Bill Nelson, Feingold, Murray, Bayh, Lincoln, Pryor, Whitehouse, Sanders, Cantwell, Tester, Clinton, Landrieu, and Salazar to offer a Joint Resolution that provides for Congressional disapproval of the rule submitted by the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services, CMS, relating to a cost limit for providers operated by units of government and other provisions under the  Medicaid program, 72 Fed. Reg. 29748, May 29, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This rule is a very blunt and sweeping instrument. It is purportedly intended to stamp out certain categories of Medicaid fraud, which by CMS's own admission may only be an issue in 3 States. As a result of the sweeping nature of this rule, many States like New Mexico will lose hundreds of millions of dollars in Federal Medicaid dollars. This would occur despite that fact that New Mexico and other States have worked hard to ensure the integrity of their Medicaid programs and have consistently  received approval from CMS for the design and operation of their programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress has reacted strongly to the proposed regulation with 65 Senators and 263 House Members publicly criticizing the rule. Ultimately, Congress temporarily prevented CMS from implementing the regulation. A 1-year moratorium of the rule was adopted in the recent supplemental appropriations bill, P.L. 110-28, Section 7002. This moratorium blocks CMS from implementing the Medicaid regulation before May 25, 2008.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In spite of clear Congressional disapproval, CMS published a final rule in the Federal Register the very day the President signed the 1-year moratorium provision into law. The final regulation retains the most damaging components of the proposed regulation, including limiting Medicaid payments to safety-net hospitals. In addition, we have been contacted by State Medicaid agencies that have been asked to certify in State Plan Amendments being considered this year that they will be in compliance  with rule as soon as the moratorium is lifted in 2008.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Major Medicaid reforms require a Congressional role; by rushing to publish a final regulation, CMS has disregarded Congressional opposition and attempted to usurp our role. CMS's action requires States to prepare for implementation of the regulation and expend administrative resources to do so, all of this before Congress has the opportunity to address the key policy issues contained in the regulation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This Resolution of Disapproval will permanently halt the damaging CMS regulation. At this time, it is the appropriate response given CMS's issuance of the final Medicaid rule and its devastating effect on State Medicaid programs, safety-net providers, and, ultimately, the ability of low-income Americans to receive the life-saving medical care to which they are entitled under Federal law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Therefore, I rise today to offer joint resolution with my colleagues and urge others to join in cosponsoring this important resolution. Together we can work to ensure its passage before the devastating Medicaid rule takes effect and jeopardizes our States' Medicaid programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of joint resolution be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the joint resolution was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="sj" number="18">S.J. Res. 18</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled, That Congress disapproves the rule submitted by the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services within the Department of Health and Human Services relating to a cost limit for providers operated by units of government and other provisions under the Medicaid program (published at 72 Fed. Reg. 29748 (May 29, 2007)), and such rule shall have no force or effect.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</narrative>
</record>
