<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1191513602" ordinal="70" title="COMMENDING THE GOVERNMENT OF GERMANY FOR PREVENTING A LARGE-SCALE TERRORIST ATTACK">
  <narrative>COMMENDING THE GOVERNMENT OF GERMANY FOR PREVENTING A LARGE-SCALE TERRORIST ATTACK -- (Senate - October 04, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="12826">S12826</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the consideration of <bill type="sr" number="344">S. Res. 344</bill>, which was submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="344">S. Res. 344</bill>) commending the government of Germany for preventing a large-scale terrorist attack in September 2007, and supporting future cooperation to prevent terrorism.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="344">S. Res. 344</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="344">S. Res. 344</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas, on September 4, 2007, police in Germany arrested 3 individuals for planning large-scale terrorist attacks against locations in Germany, including sites frequented by United States citizens;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas possible targets included Ramstein Air Base, which serves as headquarters for United States Air Forces in Europe and is also a North Atlantic Treaty Organization installation, and Frankfurt Airport, one of the largest airports in Europe;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, according to German authorities, the 3 suspects belonged to a German cell of Islamic Jihad Union, a radical Sunni group based in Central Asia with links to Al Qaeda;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas 300 police and other law enforcement officials were involved in the investigation and 41 homes across Germany were raided in a highly successful operation;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas United States intelligence agencies reportedly provided critical information that alerted their counterparts in Germany as to the travels of the suspects between Germany and Pakistan and the suspects' affiliation with the Islamic Jihad Union;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas German authorities acted swiftly and decisively to prevent an attack that could have come within days of the arrests;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the successful collaborative action by United States and German authorities prevented the possible deaths of many innocent people;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Germany and the United States have been close allies in the fight against terrorism;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the law enforcement, intelligence, diplomatic, and military organizations in Germany and the United States continue to work together to combat the terrorist threat and prevent future attacks; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas victory in the fight against terrorism is critical to preserve the liberty and ensure the safety of all people: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) commends the efforts of law enforcement authorities in Germany in preventing a large-scale terrorist attack on numerous targets in Germany, including sites frequented by United States citizens;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) recognizes the role of United States intelligence agencies in providing critical information to German authorities in their investigation and apprehension of the suspected terrorists and notes the continuing importance of such United States intelligence cooperation with Germany;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) commends the intelligence community of Germany for its outstanding work in identifying the individuals suspected of seeking to carry out this terrorist plot;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) condemns those individuals who would use acts of violence against innocent civilians to spread a message of hate and intolerance;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) urges the allies of the United States to remain steadfast in their efforts to defeat international terrorism; and</chair>
  <chair> (6) expresses its readiness to provide necessary assistance to the Government of Germany in its counterterrorism effort to bring to justice those individuals involved in this terrorist plot.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
