<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1184644800" ordinal="14" title="UNANIMOUS-CONSENT REQUEST--S. RES. 123, S. RES. 260, AND H.R. 2316">
  <narrative>UNANIMOUS-CONSENT REQUEST--S. RES. 123, <bill type="sr" number="260">S. RES. 260</bill>, AND <bill type="h" number="2316">H.R. 2316</bill> -- (Senate - July 17, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="9296">S9296</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="">
    <paragraph>With that, I will now propound a unanimous-consent request that would enact the earmark transparency rules and request that we go to conference with the House on the total ethics bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the Rules Committee be discharged from further consideration and the Senate now proceed to <bill type="sr" number="123">S. Res. 123</bill> and <bill type="sr" number="260">S. Res. 260</bill>, the earmark disclosure resolutions, all en bloc; that the resolutions be agreed to and the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I further ask that the Senate then proceed to the immediate consideration of <bill type="h" number="2316">H.R. 2316</bill>, the House-passed ethics and lobbying reform bill; that all after the enacting clause be stricken and the text of <bill type="s" number="1">S. 1</bill>, as passed by the Senate, be inserted in lieu thereof; that the bill be read the third time, passed, and the Senate insist on its amendment, request a conference with the House, and the Chair be authorized to appoint conferees at a ratio of 4 to 3.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300060" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, on behalf of the leadership, I do object.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, obviously, I am very disappointed that we continue to obstruct ethics reform and earmark reform.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With that, I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Massachusetts is recognized.</chair>
</record>
