<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1210176002" ordinal="17" title="PUBLIC SAFETY EMPLOYER-EMPLOYEE COOPERATION ACT--MOTION TO PROCEED">
  <narrative>PUBLIC SAFETY EMPLOYER-EMPLOYEE COOPERATION ACT--MOTION TO PROCEED -- (Senate - May 07, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="3883">S3883</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300034" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that upon the disposition of <bill type="h" number="3121">H.R. 3121</bill>, the House-passed Flood Insurance Act, the Senate proceed to the consideration of Calendar No. 275, <bill type="h" number="980">H.R. 980</bill>, an act to provide collective bargaining rights for public safety officers employed by States and political subdivisions.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, on behalf of several of my colleagues, I object.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300034" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I wonder if consent would be granted to proceed to <bill type="h" number="980">H.R. 980</bill> at a time to be determined by the majority leader following consultation with the Republican leader.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, on behalf of several of my colleagues, I object.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300034" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, in light of these objections, I now move to proceed to Calendar No. 275, <bill type="h" number="980">H.R. 980</bill>, and I send a cloture motion to the desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The cloture motion having been presented under rule XXII, the Chair directs the clerk to read the motion.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>Cloture Motion</narrative>
  <narrative>We, the undersigned Senators, in accordance with the provisions of rule XXII of the Standing Rules of the Senate, hereby move to bring to a close debate on the motion to proceed to Calendar No. 275, <bill type="h" number="980">H.R. 980</bill>, the Public Safety Employer-Employee Cooperation Act.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300034" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I now ask unanimous consent that the cloture vote occur on Monday, May 12, upon disposition of <bill type="h" number="3121">H.R. 3121</bill>; and that on Monday, May 12, all time after the Senate convenes until 5:30 p.m. be equally divided and controlled between the two leaders or their designees, with the mandatory quorum waived, and I withdraw the motion.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <chair>Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The Senator from South Dakota is recognized.</chair>
</record>
