<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1174665652" ordinal="8" title="SPRINGTIME ARTISTRY">
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, once again, we welcome in the Spring.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>&lt;center&gt;--&lt;em&gt;Christina Rossetti. &lt;/em&gt;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>March 21 is the vernal equinox, when the day and night are, briefly, in perfect balance. It is the first day of spring. This year, of course, the early switch to daylight savings time has created the illusion of an earlier spring with the artificial and arbitrary establishment of darker mornings and longer evenings. I, for one, am happy to welcome an early spring. It is my favorite season, full of new hope and untarnished promise.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>West Virginia has seen some snow this winter. The snow was welcomed by skiers and farmers, but those of us who neither ski nor plow view snow more as a nuisance--something to be moved out of the way, something that complicates our commutes and closes the schools. Snow makes the world monochromatic, a palette that ranges along a single line from blinding white through the shades of gray to the tired black of grime-crusted snow along the roadways. We are ready for spring, ready for some light and  for lots of vibrant color around us.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This year, the March winds again worked their artistry, blowing away the flotsam and jetsam of winter to uncover a clean canvas with just the sweeping curves of earth and the angular armature of tree limbs sketched in charcoal, awaiting the Master's hand to apply delicate springtime washes of color. Over the past weeks, we have seen the Master's skill at work in the first creeping stain of green across the lawns and fields, the soft blush of blossoms in the wild plum trees, the deepening blue  of the sky. Each day, the colors have grown darker, richer, and more vibrant, as if the warm breezes carried them to us from some distant sunny clime. Bright details have begun to take shape in the scattered spangles of violet and yellow crocus and the bright accents of hardy daffodils amid their grass green leaves. Oh, daffodils--the poets write of you! The Boston poet Amy Lowell (1874-1925) wrote of you:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, spring would not be spring without the daffodils. Their delicate beauty and seemingly fragile petals belie their toughness. Year after year, the daffodils spread, competing with the grass and the tree roots to expand their beds. They manage to deter the onslaught of determined squirrels and other wild creatures who unearth and consume dainty and expensive spring bulbs like so many canap&amp;#233;s at a reception. They push their way up into the sun through frozen ground and choking  mats of fallen leaves. They defy howling winds and frigid nighttime temperatures. They survive people and houses to bloom on around the decaying foundations of long ago farmsteads. And they do it all with effortless beauty, inspiring us and filling us with joy. The first daffodil, like the first robin, is akin to the dove that brought the olive branch back to Noah--a reassurance to worried man  from God that the spring, like the land, will return.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I do not want to take up too much of the Senate's time. We have important matters before us, matters of war and peace, matters of spending and accounting. But even in the heat of debate, we can each find joy in those first spring days. We can each feel peace in the steady warmth of the springtime sun, calm in the soft breeze that carries the scent of hyacinths, and delight in springtime flowers. The first day of spring is truly a time to stop and smell the flowers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>&lt;center&gt;--&lt;em&gt;Christina Rossetti. &lt;/em&gt;</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
