<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1211299202" ordinal="64" title="EXECUTIVE REPORTS OF COMMITTEES">
  <narrative>EXECUTIVE REPORTS OF COMMITTEES -- (Senate - May 20, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="4485">S4485</bill>]</narrative>
  <narrative>The following executive reports of nominations were submitted:</narrative>
  <narrative>By Mr. BIDEN for the Committee on Foreign Relations.</narrative>
  <narrative>*Marcia Stephens Bloom Bernicat, of New Jersey, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Senegal, and to serve concurrently and without additional compensation as Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Guinea-Bissau.</narrative>
  <narrative>Nominee: Marcia Stephens Bloom Bernicat.</narrative>
  <narrative>Post: Senegal.</narrative>
  <narrative>(The following is a list of all members of my immediate family and their spouses. I have asked each of these persons to inform me of the pertinent contributions made by them. To the best of my knowledge, the information contained in this report is complete and accurate.)</narrative>
  <narrative>Contributions, amount, date, and donee:</narrative>
  <narrative>1. Self: N/A.</narrative>
  <narrative>2. Spouse: Olivier Bernicat: N/A.</narrative>
  <narrative>3. Children and Spouses: Sunil Christopher Bernicat (minor); Sumit Nicolaus Bernicat (minor).</narrative>
  <narrative>4. Parents: Both deceased.</narrative>
  <narrative>5. Grandparents: All four deceased.</narrative>
  <narrative>6. Brothers and Spouses: Rodney &amp;amp; Cindy Bloom.</narrative>
  <narrative>7. Sisters and Spouses: Kathryn Bloom &amp;amp; Luther White, Jr.: N/A.</narrative>
  <narrative>&lt;pre&gt;--&lt;/pre&gt;</narrative>
  <narrative>*Marianne Matuzic Myles, of New York, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Cape Verde.</narrative>
  <narrative>Nominee: Marianne M. Myles.</narrative>
  <narrative>Post: Praia, Cape Verde.</narrative>
  <narrative>(The following is a list of all members of my immediate family and their spouses. I have asked each of these persons to inform me of the pertinent contributions made by them. To the best of my knowledge, the information contained in this report is complete and accurate.)</narrative>
  <narrative>Contributions, amount, date, and donee:</narrative>
  <narrative>1. Self: none.</narrative>
  <narrative>2. Spouse: $100.00, 11/7/06, Democratic Senatorial Campaign Committee; $50.00, 2/4/04, Democratic National Committee Services Corp.; $100.00, 5/3/06, Democrats.Org.</narrative>
  <narrative>3. Children and Spouses: Lee-Ellen Myles: none.</narrative>
  <narrative>4. Parents: J. Philip Matuzic (deceased), Eleanor Matuzic (deceased).</narrative>
  <narrative>5. Grandparents: Louis Mancheff (deceased), Mary Mancheff (deceased), Joseph Matuzic (deceased), Anna Matuzic (deceased).</narrative>
  <narrative>6. Brothers and Spouses: Philip J. Matuzic: none.</narrative>
  <narrative>7. Sisters and Spouses: Nancy Edwards, John Edwards: none.</narrative>
  <narrative>&lt;pre&gt;--&lt;/pre&gt;</narrative>
  <narrative>*Linda Thomas-Greenfield, of Louisiana, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Liberia.</narrative>
  <narrative>Nominee: Linda Thomas-Greenfield.</narrative>
  <narrative>Post: Monrovia.</narrative>
  <narrative>(The following is a list of all members of my immediate family and their spouses. I have asked each of these persons to inform me of the pertinent contributions made by them. To the best of my knowledge, the information contained in this report is complete and accurate.)</narrative>
  <narrative>Contributions, amount, date, and donee:</narrative>
  <narrative>1. Self: None.</narrative>
  <narrative>2. Spouse: Lafayette Greenfield: None.</narrative>
  <narrative>3. Children and Spouses: Lindsay Greenfield: None.</narrative>
  <narrative>Lafayette Greenfield: None.</narrative>
  <narrative>4. Parents' Names: Oliver Thomas, Jr.: None.</narrative>
  <narrative>Doretha Thomas: None.</narrative>
  <narrative>5. Grandparents' Names: All deceased: Maggie and Buck Peterson, Elnora and Oliver Thomas.</narrative>
  <narrative>6. Brothers and Spouses Names: Elvin Thomas (divorced): None.</narrative>
  <narrative>Ronald Thomas (Glenda): None.</narrative>
  <narrative>Oliver Thomas III (Renita): None.</narrative>
  <narrative>Cleveland (Deborah): None.</narrative>
  <narrative>7. Sisters and Spouses Names: Patricia Noble (Bertel): None.</narrative>
  <narrative>Kathy Thomas-Grover (James): None.</narrative>
  <narrative>Maxine Caldwell (Lawrence): None.</narrative>
  <narrative>&lt;pre&gt;--&lt;/pre&gt;</narrative>
  <narrative>* Joseph Evan LeBaron, of Oregon, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the State of Qatar.</narrative>
  <narrative>Nominee: Joseph Evan LeBaron.</narrative>
  <narrative>Post: Qatar.</narrative>
  <narrative>(The following is a list of all members of my immediate family and their spouses. I have asked each of these persons to inform me of the pertinent contributions made by them. To the best of my knowledge, the information contained in this report is complete and accurate.)</narrative>
  <narrative>Contributions, amount, date, and donee:</narrative>
  <narrative>1. Self: none</narrative>
  <narrative>2. Spouse: Elinor R. LeBaron, none.</narrative>
  <narrative>3. Children and Spouses: Petra Drake LeBaron, none.</narrative>
  <narrative>4. Parents: Carlos S. LeBaron, deceased; Truellen LeBaron McCracken, deceased.</narrative>
  <narrative>Grandparents: Edgar M. LeBaron, deceased; Zenobia H. LeBaron, deceased.</narrative>
  <narrative>6. Brothers and Spouses: Charles S. LeBaron, deceased.</narrative>
  <narrative>7. Sisters and Spouses: Joyce I. LeBaron, none; Veida Wissler, none; Steve Wissler (spouse), none.</narrative>
  <narrative>&lt;pre&gt;--&lt;/pre&gt;</narrative>
  <narrative>4. (Step) Parents: Lawrence McCracken, none.</narrative>
  <narrative>5. Grandparents (cont'd): Hyrum J. Davis, deceased, Berta B. Davis, deceased.</narrative>
  <narrative>6. Brothers and Spouses (cont'd): Daniel McCracken, none. Cindy McCracken (spouse), none.</narrative>
  <narrative>7. Sisters and Spouses (cont'd): Elma M. Witty, none; Ben Witty (spouse), none; Phyllis McCracken, none.</narrative>
  <narrative>&lt;pre&gt;--&lt;/pre&gt;</narrative>
  <narrative>*Stephen James Nolan, of Virginia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Botswana.</narrative>
  <narrative>Nominee: Stephen J. Nolan.</narrative>
  <narrative>Post: Gabarone, Botswana.</narrative>
  <narrative>(The following is a list of all members of my immediate family and their spouses. I have asked each of these persons to inform me of the pertinent contributions made by them. To the best of my knowledge, the information contained in this report is complete and accurate.)</narrative>
  <narrative>Contributions, amount, date, and donee:</narrative>
  <narrative>1. Self: none.</narrative>
  <narrative>2. Spouse: Judith F. Nolan: $25.00, 2004, Kerry Campaign.</narrative>
  <narrative>3. Children and Spouses:</narrative>
  <narrative>4. Parents: Mary P. Nolan, none; Bernard Nolan (deceased).</narrative>
  <narrative>5. Grandparents (all deceased).</narrative>
  <narrative>6. Brothers and Spouses: Robert B. Nolan (brother) none; Nancy W. Nolan (brother's spouse) none.</narrative>
  <narrative>7. Sisters and Spouses: Monica F. Kowalski (sister) none; Robert J. Kowalski (deceased). Bernadette Hoffman (sister) none; Joseph Hoffman (husband) none.</narrative>
  <narrative>&lt;pre&gt;--&lt;/pre&gt;</narrative>
  <narrative>*Donald E. Booth, of Virginia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Zambia.</narrative>
  <narrative>Nominee: Donald E. Booth.</narrative>
  <narrative>Post: Ambassador to Zambia.</narrative>
  <narrative>(The following is a list of all members of my immediate family and their spouses. I have asked each of these persons to inform me of the pertinent contributions made by them. To the best of my knowledge, the information contained in this report is complete and accurate.)</narrative>
  <narrative>Contributions, amount, date, and donee:</narrative>
  <narrative>1. Self: none.</narrative>
  <narrative>2. Spouse: Anita S. Booth, none.</narrative>
  <narrative>3. Children and Spouses: Alison L. Booth, none; Peter R. Booth, none; David I. Booth, none.</narrative>
  <narrative>4. Parents: John E. Booth, deceased; Eileen R. Booth, deceased.</narrative>
  <narrative>5. Grandparents: Ernest Ford, deceased; Lena Ford, deceased; Edward Booth, deceased; Margaret Booth, deceased.</narrative>
  <narrative>6. Brothers and Spouses: John L. Booth (step-brother) none; Tibby Booth, none.</narrative>
  <narrative>7. Sisters and Spouses: Camilla Noyes (step-sister) none; George Noyes, none.</narrative>
  <narrative>&lt;pre&gt;--&lt;/pre&gt;</narrative>
  <narrative>*Gillian Arlette Milovanovic, of Pennsylvania, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Mali.</narrative>
  <narrative>Nominee: Gillian Arlette Milovanovic.</narrative>
  <narrative>POST: Ambassador to Mali.</narrative>
  <narrative>(The following is a list of all members of my immediate family and their spouses. I have asked each of these persons to inform me of the pertinent contributions made by them. To the best of my knowledge, the information contained in this report is complete and accurate.)</narrative>
  <narrative>Contributions, amount, date, and donee:</narrative>
  <narrative>1. Self: None.</narrative>
  <narrative>2. Spouse: Zlatibor Radmilo Milovanovic: None other than IRS form one dollar check off.</narrative>
  <narrative>3. Children and Spouses: Alexandra Helene Milovanovic, none; Anna Michele Milovanovic, none.</narrative>
  <narrative>4. Parents: Andre Pesche--deceased; Annette Roussel-Pesche--deceased.</narrative>
  <narrative>5. Grandparents: Mary and Meyer Rosenson--deceased; Germaine and Robert Pesche--deceased.</narrative>
  <narrative>6. Brothers and Spouses: No brothers.</narrative>
  <narrative>6. Sisters and Spouses: No sisters.</narrative>
  <narrative>&lt;pre&gt;--&lt;/pre&gt;</narrative>
  <narrative>*James B. Cunningham, of New York, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Career Minister, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to Israel.</narrative>
  <narrative>Nominee: James B. Cunningham.</narrative>
  <narrative>POST: Tel Aviv.</narrative>
  <narrative>(The following is a list of all members of my immediate family and their spouses. I have asked each of these persons to inform me of the pertinent contributions made by them. To the best of my knowledge, the information contained in this report is complete and accurate.)</narrative>
  <narrative>Contributions, amount, date, and donee:</narrative>
  <narrative>1. Self: None.</narrative>
  <narrative>2. Spouse: None.</narrative>
  <narrative>3. Children and Spouses: Emma, none; Abigail, none.</narrative>
  <narrative>4. Parents: Blair--deceased; Julia--deceased.</narrative>
  <narrative>5. Grandparents: Grandparents Knowles--deceased; Grandparents Cunningham--deceased.</narrative>
  <narrative>6. Brothers and Spouses: Thomas, none; William--estranged, believe none.</narrative>
  <narrative>7. Sisters and Spouses: Carol, none; Kathleen--deceased.</narrative>
  <narrative>&lt;pre&gt;--&lt;/pre&gt;</narrative>
  <narrative>*Donald Gene Teitelbaum, of Texas, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Ghana.</narrative>
  <narrative>Nominee: Donald Gene Teitelbaum.</narrative>
  <narrative>POST: Ambassador.</narrative>
  <narrative>(The following is a list of all members of my immediate family and their spouses. I have asked each of these persons to inform me of the pertinent contributions made by them. To the best of my knowledge, the information contained in this report is complete and accurate.)</narrative>
  <narrative>Contributions, amount, date, and donee:</narrative>
  <narrative>1. Self: None.</narrative>
  <narrative>2. Spouse: Julianna Lindsey: none.</narrative>
  <narrative>3. Children and Spouses: none.</narrative>
  <narrative>4. Parents: Robert Teitelbaum, none; Fumie Teitelbaum, none.</narrative>
  <narrative>5. Grandparents: Deceased.</narrative>
  <narrative>6. Brothers and Spouses: Alex Teitelbaum, none; Cathy Teitelbaum, none.</narrative>
  <narrative>7. Sisters and Spouses: Romie Heidt, none; Rick Heidt, none.</narrative>
  <narrative>&lt;pre&gt;--&lt;/pre&gt;</narrative>
  <narrative>Robert Stephen Beecroft, of California, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan.</narrative>
  <narrative>Nominee: Robert Stephen Beecroft.</narrative>
  <narrative>Post: Ambassador to Jordan.</narrative>
  <narrative>(The following is a list of all members of my immediate family and their spouses. I have asked each of these persons to inform me of the pertinent contributions made by them. To the best of my knowledge, the information contained in this report is complete and accurate.)</narrative>
  <narrative>Contributions, amount, date, and donee:</narrative>
  <narrative>1. Self: none.</narrative>
  <narrative>2. Spouse: Anne T. Beecroft, none.</narrative>
  <narrative>3. Children: Blythe A. Beecroft, none; Robert Warren N. Beecroft, none; Sterling S. Beecroft, none; Grace A. Beecroft, none; Children's Spouses, N/A.</narrative>
  <narrative>4. Parents: Robert L. Beecroft (Deceased); Emma L. Beecroft, none.</narrative>
  <narrative>5. Grandparents: Irl R. Beecroft (Deceased); Ruth V. Beecroft (Deceased); John E. Warren (Deceased); Emma W. Warren (Deceased).</narrative>
  <narrative>6. Brothers and Spouses: Warren E. Beecroft, none; Frances Beecroft (spouse), none.</narrative>
  <narrative>Edward Regan Beecroft, none; JoAn Stopa-Beecroft (spouse), none.</narrative>
  <narrative>Collin J. Beecroft, none; Melinda Beecroft (spouse), $500, 3/31/07, Mitt Romney.</narrative>
  <narrative>7. Sisters and Spouses: Robyn R. Ryskamp, none; Barry Ryskamp (spouse), none.</narrative>
  <narrative>&lt;pre&gt;--&lt;/pre&gt;</narrative>
  <narrative>*Richard E. Hoagland, of the District of Columbia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Kazakhstan.</narrative>
  <narrative>Nominee: Richard Eugene Hoagland.</narrative>
  <narrative>Post: Ambassador to Kazakhstan.</narrative>
  <narrative>(The following is a list of all members of my immediate family and their spouses. I have asked each of these persons to inform me of the pertinent contributions made by them. To the best of my knowledge, the information contained in this report is complete and accurate.)</narrative>
  <narrative>Contributions, amount, date, and donee:</narrative>
  <narrative>1. Self: none.</narrative>
  <narrative>2. Spouse: N/A.</narrative>
  <narrative>3. Children and Spouses' Names: N/A.</narrative>
  <narrative>4. Parents' Names: Robert Hoagland (deceased); Thelma Hoagland, none.</narrative>
  <narrative>5. Grandparents' Names: Earl Hoagland (deceased); Nellie Hoagland (deceased); Charles Van Scoik (deceased); Faustina Van Scoik (deceased).</narrative>
  <narrative>6. Brothers' and Spouses' Names: Donald Hoagland, none; Helen Hoagland, none; David Hoagland, none; Kathy Hoagland, none; Daniel Hoagland, none; Karen Hoagland, none.</narrative>
  <narrative>7. Sisters' and Spouses' Names: Deborah Hoagland, none.</narrative>
  <narrative/>
  <narrative>* Peter William Bodde, of Maryland, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Malawi. </narrative>
  <narrative>Nominee: Peter W Bodde.</narrative>
  <narrative>Post: Ambassador to Malawi.</narrative>
  <narrative>(The following is a list of all members of my immediate family and their spouses. I have asked each of these persons to inform me of the pertinent contributions made by them. To the best of my knowledge, the information contained in this report is complete and accurate.)</narrative>
  <narrative>Contributions, amount, date, and donee:</narrative>
  <narrative>1. Self: none.</narrative>
  <narrative>2. Spouse: none.</narrative>
  <narrative>3. Children's and Spouses' Names: none.</narrative>
  <narrative>4. Parents' Names: Amb. William Bodde, Jr., $1,000.00, 2007, Senator Hillary Clinton, Rep. Chris Van Hollen.</narrative>
  <narrative>5. Grandparents' Names: deceased.</narrative>
  <narrative>6. Brothers' and Spouses': none.</narrative>
  <narrative>7. Sisters' and Spouses' Names: none.</narrative>
  <narrative>&lt;pre&gt;--&lt;/pre&gt;</narrative>
  <narrative>*Patricia McMahon Hawkins, of Virginia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Togolese Republic.</narrative>
  <narrative>Nominee: Patricia McMahon Hawkins.</narrative>
  <narrative>Post: Togo.</narrative>
  <narrative>(The following is a list of all members of my immediate family and their spouses. I have asked each of these persons to inform me of the pertinent contributions made by them. To the best of my knowledge, the information contained in this report is complete and accurate.)</narrative>
  <narrative>Contributions, Amount, Date, and Donee:</narrative>
  <narrative>1. Self: None.</narrative>
  <narrative>2. Spouse: None.</narrative>
  <narrative>3. Children and Spouses: Frederic Charles Game, None; and Jessica C. Hawkins, None.</narrative>
  <narrative>4. Parents: Charles J. McMahon, Deceased; and Rosemary V. McMahon, Deceased.</narrative>
  <narrative>5. Grandparents: George Graff, Deceased; Virginia M. Graff, Deceased; Charles J, McMahon, Deceased; and Lillian Whiting, Deceased.</narrative>
  <narrative>6. Brothers and Spouses: N/A.</narrative>
  <narrative>7. Sisters and Spouses: Barbara Ellen McMahon, None.</narrative>
  <narrative>&lt;pre&gt;--&lt;/pre&gt;</narrative>
  <narrative>*Richard A. Boucher, of Maryland, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Career Minister, for the personal rank of Career Ambassador in recognition of especially distinguished service over a sustained period.</narrative>
  <narrative>*William J. Burns, of the District of Columbia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Career Minister, for the personal rank of Career Ambassador in recognition of especially distinguished service over a sustained period.</narrative>
  <narrative>*Anne Woods Patterson, of Virginia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Career Minister, for the personal rank of Career Ambassador in recognition of especially distinguished service over a sustained period.</narrative>
  <narrative>*C. David Welch, of Virginia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Career Minister, for the personal rank of Career Ambassador in recognition of especially distinguished service over a sustained period.</narrative>
  <narrative>*T. Vance McMahan, of Texas, to be Representative of the United States of America on the Economic and Social Council of the United Nations, with the rank of Ambassador.</narrative>
  <narrative>*Janice L. Jacobs, of Virginia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be an Assistant Secretary of State (Bureau of Consular Affairs).</narrative>
  <narrative>*T. Vance McMahan, of Texas, to be an Alternate Representative of the United States of America to the Sessions of the General Assembly of the United Nations, during his tenure of service as Representative of the United States of America on the Economic and Social Council of the United Nations.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300008" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, for the Committee on Foreign Relations I report favorably the following nomination lists which were printed in the RECORD on the dates indicated, and ask unanimous consent, to save the expense of reprinting on the Executive Calendar that these nominations lie at the Secretary's desk for the information of Senators.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>Foreign Service nominations beginning with Craig Lewis Cloud and ending with Kimberly K. Ottwell, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record on April 15, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>Foreign Service nominations beginning with Carmine G. D'Aloisio and ending with Judy R. Reinke, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record on April 23, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>*Nomination was reported with recommendation that it be confirmed subject to the nominee's commitment to respond to requests to appear and testify before any duly constituted committee of the Senate.</chair>
  <narrative>(Nominations without an asterisk were reported with the recommendation that they be confirmed.)</narrative>
</record>
