<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1169571615" ordinal="16" title="FAIR MINIMUM WAGE ACT OF 2007">
  <chair> Under the previous order, the Senate will resume consideration of <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill>, which the clerk will report.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, if I can have the attention of the Senator from Maine, what I would like to do now is to ask that the amendment be modified with the modification that is at the desk, if that is agreeable with the Senator.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300091" topic="">
    <paragraph>It certainly is.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the amendment is modified.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I will take a moment or two to thank the Senator from Maine and thank the Senator from Wyoming. If one will take a few moments and look through this amendment and the modification, they will understand what the good Senators have been talking about. It talks about posting to make sure the information is going to be available to small businesses. It talks about distribution, to make sure there is going to be a generous distribution. It talks about a timely distribution,  so we are not going to have a final date, and then the Agency is going to delay in terms of posting and distribution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It explains what is necessary for small businesses to be able to comply with the rules and the regulations. It doesn't affect those regulations that have been set and established. And it makes the requirement that it be put in plain English language so that any person is able to understand what is intended and what the rule is covering, and then it has the provision to inform Congress, the appropriate committees, as to what they have done over previous years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This makes a lot of good sense. I commend the Senator from Maine and the Senator from Wyoming, and my colleague, Senator Kerry, who has been involved in this effort, and Senator Landrieu as well. I am very grateful to all of them for working with us. This is a very useful and extremely important and valuable addition to the legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I know the Senator from Pennsylvania is desirous to address the overall issue. Mr. President, as I understand it, under the previous order, at noontime, we are going to vote on this amendment; is that correct?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> There is no order to that effect.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>As I understand, shortly, there will be, I expect. At the appropriate time, we will ask for the yeas and nays. We intend to have the vote, for the information of offices, at that time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I see both the Senator from New Hampshire and the Senator from Pennsylvania are here.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from New Hampshire.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300095" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the pending amendment be set aside, and I call up amendment No. 112 and ask for its immediate consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection? Without objection, the clerk will report.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300095" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the reading of the amendment be dispensed with.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300095" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, this is an important debate and important discussion, especially in regard to the points made by Senator Snowe of Maine; that is, if we raise the minimum wage, we need to understand both the potential impact on small businesses and recognize those small businesses are creating most of the job opportunities in our country. They fuel our economy. Over the long term, as those smaller entrepreneurial firms grow, they provide support for a growing wage base, for  benefits, and for support of the families who depend on those small businesses for their jobs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I welcome her amendment that deals with small business regulation. It is an important step in the right direction, and I certainly hope it continues to receive bipartisan support in the Senate. I think many of the provisions that are in the substitute that deal with support for small business will receive bipartisan support.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator Snowe also mentioned the importance of tax treatment for small business investments and capital spending, and that they be allowed to expense that, in turn, allowing them to find additional resources to continue that pattern of investment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The amendment I have called up also deals with the issue of small business, entrepreneurship and job creation and a small, but important, program in our Government called the Women's Business Centers. There are about 100 Women's Business Centers across the country. There is one in Portsmouth, NH, that was among the very first created in the United States, and it deals with a range of issues from providing an incubator for women entrepreneurs just starting out a firm, to providing training and  counseling, support for marketing services, information about Government procurement, so many of the issues that have already been addressed on the floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What this amendment does is to simply ensure that those high-performing Women's Business Centers that have continued to serve a strong, important  clientele and have supported entrepreneurship and investment in their community continue to be eligible for funding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under the current restrictions, some of those centers, after 5 years of sustainability grants, lose the opportunity for additional funding. My amendment would create a new program within the WBC program that allows those centers to apply for a 3-year continuation of Federal funding, provided they continue to meet high standards, serve their clients effectively, and attract sources of funding from the community.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think it is a reasonable approach, one that makes sense. Look at the great example that has been set in Portsmouth. With the limited amount of Federal funding and other community resources, in the past year, it has served over 1,300 individual entrepreneurs. That, as we like to say in Washington, is real leverage, real performance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This does not require additional funding. It is a straightforward way to ensure that an important need continues to be met and that this bill has the appropriate balance and support for the small business community.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I commend the work of the Senator from Maine, for her work on small business generally within the Small Business Committee. This is something they have tried to address before and the Senate has supported in the past. I hope it is something that will continue to receive bipartisan support.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Massachusetts.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, with regard to the amendment of the Senator from New Hampshire, it seems by both the explanation and a first look, this is something that will be very useful and valuable. If the Senator will work with us--I am not prepared, at this time, to recommend the amendment, but we will work on it with him and indicate what our position is in the very near future. But it certainly seems, trying to give some focus and attention to small businesses that are initiated by women,  to make a good deal of sense, and it is subject to an authorization, so there is no point of order.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from New Hampshire.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300095" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I thank the chairman for his comments. Obviously, I just called up the amendment. I don't expect him to endorse it wholeheartedly. I think he will find he has supported it in the past and many in the Chamber have supported it in the past and it is worthy of our consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Arizona.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300062" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I seek recognition for the purpose of laying down an amendment and not speaking to it. I ask unanimous consent that the pending amendment be laid aside for that purpose.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300062" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I send to the desk an amendment that deals with extending some current provisions and adding additional provisions to assist small businesses to pay for a minimum wage increase, should one be adopted. I will speak to this later. I appreciate others allowing me to lay it down.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300062" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the reading of the amendment be dispensed with.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412246" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today in support of <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill> which, as we know, will increase the minimum wage from $5.15 an hour to $7.25 an hour. I thank my colleague, Senator Kennedy, and the bipartisan work that went into developing this issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I speak today of an issue which I believe is one of economic justice. Those earning the minimum wage have not had an increase in 10 years. We should ask ourselves today not only about the information in the bill and the data, as important as that is, we should ask ourselves who are these Americans who have not had an increase in 10 long years?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Most, of course, we know are adults working full time. In fact, in my home State of Pennsylvania, 71 percent of the workers whose wages would be raised directly by an increase in the minimum wage are adults ages 20 and older.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Also, these Americans in many cases are women. Sixty percent of those who would be affected by an increase in the minimum wage are women, working every day to make ends meet, to support their children. In fact, if the minimum wage is raised, 6 million children will benefit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Recently, the Children's Defense Fund reported that a single parent working full time at the current minimum wage of $5.15 an hour earns enough to cover only 40 percent--just 40 percent--of the cost of raising children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Those who earn the minimum wage are not people who are connected to the wealthy and the powerful. They don't have high-paid lobbyists in Washington advocating for them. No, these people are Americans who lead quiet, triumphant lives of struggle and sacrifice, overcoming hardships and setbacks every day. They do hard work, very hard work, such as the waitresses we see every day carrying heavy trays, on their feet hour after hour, as they dream of a better life for themselves and for their children.  And at the end of a long day, these Americans return to work and go home at the end of a long day often exhausted, often working not one job but two jobs or three, and the dignity of their labor gives meaning to their lives. We know, and they would tell us that if they were standing here today next to me. So that work they do gives meaning to their lives without a doubt.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But no one, no matter how hard they work, can keep pace with the avalanche of cost increases we have seen over the last 10 years. Let me take my colleagues through a couple of those cost increases.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since 1997, congressional pay has increased 24 percent, about $31,000.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This has occurred while the value of the minimum wage has been eroded by 20 percent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me say that again: Congressional pay up 24 percent, the value of the minimum wage down 20 percent. We cannot say that enough. The cost of living is up 26 percent, the cost of food up 23 percent, the cost of housing up 29 percent, the cost of gasoline up over 130 percent, the cost of health care up 43 percent. Families who are listening to this today know this. The average premium for a family of four costs over $10,000, almost $11,000, which is more than a minimum wage worker earns in a year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The cost of raising a child since 1997 has increased 52 percent; the cost of educating those children has risen 61 percent; the cost of heating a home has increased by 120 percent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What we are talking about here is an issue, indeed, of economic justice. Raising the Federal minimum wage will give our workers more than $4,000 per year. Let's consider what that could buy for a family in America. You can buy almost 2 years of childcare with over $4,000, full tuition at a community college, 2 years of health care, 1 year of groceries, 1 1/2  years of heat and electricity, and 8 months of rent. That is how we affect, in a positive way, people's lives, the lives of hard-working  men and women in America today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Those who argue against an increase in the minimum wage will say that an increase will hurt small business and/or the economy. I do not agree with that because if you look at the data, when the minimum wage was increased in 1997, what happened in the aftermath? Millions and millions of jobs were created and raising the minimum wage did not slow that down one iota.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Recently, over 650 economists issued a statement calling for an increase in  the minimum wage. We do not have time today to go through that, but it is an important statement from leading economists in America. With an increase in minimum wage, employers will get a lot in return: higher productivity they will get with an increase in the minimum wage; lower turnover; and, of course, increased worker morale.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, you know as well as I do that more than 28 States now have increased the minimum wage, including my home State of Pennsylvania. In July of this year it will increase to $7.15 an hour, as a result of State legislation. That should not have had to take place. The Federal Government long ago--we are years overdue on this--should have taken the responsibility for increasing the minimum wage, but that did not happen here in Washington. There were other priorities, other interests, more  powerful interests that took precedence.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>More than 400,000 Pennsylvanians will be affected positively by an increase in the minimum wage. I am thinking of them today as I am of families across America who will be affected positively by an increase in the minimum wage. Yes, I do believe that small businesses across Pennsylvania and America do need help. However, in my judgment, based upon the people to whom I have spoken in my State, the No. 1 priority or the No. 1 burden faced by small business owners, men or women, is the cost, the  crushing cost of health care. We need to deliver health care relief to those small businesses, and that as well is long overdue, because those small business owners and their workers deserve the same kind of economic justice I talked about today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I fervently urge support for this legislation, and I appreciate this time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Massachusetts.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I thank my friend from Pennsylvania for speaking in favor of this minimum wage amendment. This was an issue, I know, out in the State of Pennsylvania during the course of the campaign. Senator Casey was resolute in his commitment to the working families in his State and I am very grateful for his comments and strong support for this issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As I understand it, we expect Senator Grassley is going to speak to the Senate, and my friend and colleague from Hawaii, Senator Akaka, is going to address the Senate. We are working out the consent agreement for the time for the vote. It had initially been set tentatively for noontime. Now, I want to tell our colleagues, it is going to be after the caucuses. We are working out the final time and we will make that announcement in a very few moments. But for the information of  our colleagues, and their schedules, we will not be voting prior to the caucuses. We will be voting after the caucuses and we will be more precise in a very short period of time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Iowa.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I want to address two aspects of this legislation because they are necessarily connected. One is, obviously, the increase in the minimum wage. The other one is the small business tax provisions that have come out of the committee Senator Baucus chairs and on which I am the ranking member, the Finance Committee. I want to deal with the minimum wage part of this issue first.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Popular support for raising the minimum wage is based on a number of widely held beliefs: First, that no one can support a family at $5.15 an hour; second, minimum wage earners will not get a pay raise unless Congress gives them one; and third, raising the minimum wage helps millions of poor workers and hurts no one.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, these popular beliefs are in some cases misleading and in some cases outright wrong. First, minimum wage earners are not trying to support a family--or you might argue a small percentage of them are trying to support a family, but I want to say why most are not. Those who are, of course, can get additional benefits through Government programs to supplement family income; thus, no one has to rely solely on the minimum wage to support a family.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second, minimum wage jobs are generally entry level jobs. Most workers who start at the minimum wage quickly earn more. Few workers remain stuck at the minimum wage for very long and, unfortunately, those who do are most at risk of losing their jobs from a minimum wage increase.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Third, the benefits of a minimum wage increase do not go exclusively to poor families. Only 15 percent of the proposed minimum wage increase would go to those living below the poverty level, as an example. Increasing the minimum wage would result in higher prices for consumers of minimum wage products, higher unemployment among the least skilled minimum wage workers--and that particularly affects minority groups within our country--increased poverty among minimum wage families, and in some cases  it could be a combination of these three things I mentioned.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Much of the popular support for the minimum wage is based on a fallacy, that the Government can help the poor without hurting anyone else. But if the Government can increase wages with no ill effects, then why stop at $7.25, as is currently proposed? Why not make it $10.25? Why not make it $20.25, or even more? The fact is, this does have limited impact and it does have some negative consequences, so that is why these occasional increases are justified.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Popular support for increasing the minimum wage is tempered by the fact that virtually everyone agrees that there is some level at which the minimum wage would produce obvious negative effects. In the past, policymakers have attempted to mitigate any negative effects by limiting the size of the minimum wage increase, providing tax credits to employers who hire at-risk workers, and providing tax or regulatory relief to business generally, particularly small businesses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, additional research in recent years has cast some doubt on the effectiveness of these previous efforts. First, research suggests raising the minimum wage does not reduce poverty among minimum wage earners. Instead, it most likely increases poverty.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second, legislative action by various States to adopt their own higher minimum wage has led to significant differences within our 50 States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Third, research shows that the earned income tax credit could provide a cost-effective way to help poorest workers and be more effective than even increasing the minimum wage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am pleased that over the last few years we have enhanced the earned income credit for many families by making the child tax credit refundable. That is through the work of the Senate Finance Committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Before I go on to my next point I would say parenthetically there are studies that have been updated quite frequently over the last 20 or 25 years, where economists have followed people in quintiles: the lowest, the second, you know, for five quintiles from the lowest income up to the highest income. Following people over a period of years, they have been able to study the mobility of the American worker. In other words, once you are in the workforce, most people work themselves up the economic  ladder--some way up, some part way up. But we find that only about 2 percent of our population seems to be stuck in the lowest quintile of income for long periods of time--a very small percentage. But other people go from the second quintile--from the first to the second to the third, and we also find that there is a larger percentage of our population</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Despite some serious policy concerns, public support for increasing the minimum wage remains strong. That is why the Senate is taking up a minimum wage increase. The political reality is a majority of Senators support a minimum wage increase.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So a lot of economists would make an argument that you should not have any increase in the minimum wage at all and that the mistakes, going back to the 1930s, were mistakes; that you should not interfere with the marketplace. But Congress has decided for 70 years to do that. We are in the process for doing it. Regardless of the economic arguments, as long as this is a  political issue, without a doubt, from time to time it is going to be raised and I suppose  you could make an argument that, as long as it is political it ought to be raised, or else you should not even have a minimum wage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now I would go to the tax incentive portions we hope stay in this bill when it goes to the other body. Tax incentives targeted to small business and other businesses impacted by a minimum wage increase have been linked to the minimum wage legislation. We have done this in the past decade. Democrats have at times joined Republicans supporting this language.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would quote from two former chairmen on this committee in their opening remarks on the conference agreement on the last piece of legislation that went through this body to raise the minimum wage. Senator Roth, then the chairman of the committee, described taxes as the sand that grinds the gears of small business. So he saw merit in small business tax relief as a separate matter. Senator Roth went on to say:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>[We will] proceed to the legislation on the minimum wage and small business taxes. We're anxious to move ahead on the small business tax legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator Moynihan, who at times was chairman of the committee and at times the ranking Democrat, said, at the same time Senator Roth was speaking:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My distinguished chairman, as always, has so stated the facts. But there is a small semantic issue here. Some call this a small business relief act; others on this side call it the minimum wage bill. But we will not resolve that tonight, nor need we.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, the next time the Senate deals with this, about 8 or 9 years since we last dealt with it, it is still the same issue. Senators Roth and Moynihan were right then, and if they were still living today, I would tell them they are right now.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To different groups of Senators, these topics carry their own benefits or burdens. Many on my side don't like the idea of second-guessing the labor market with a federally mandated minimum wage. I pointed out some of the related issues that should give us pause, arguments put forth by economists when considering this legislation, that it is not all positive.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many on the Democratic side want a straight minimum wage hike and refuse to consider the burden that policy puts on employers and workers. Those Members do not want any linkage between the minimum wage policy and small business tax relief. As Senator Moynihan said, however, we don't have to agree now whether the upcoming legislation will be a minimum wage or a small business tax relief bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Some, mostly Democrats, will call it a minimum wage bill. Some, mostly Republicans, will call it a small business tax relief bill. Still others will call it both a minimum wage and small business tax relief bill. President Bush, like President Clinton, the last President who signed an increase in the minimum wage bill years ago, will recognize both parts of the package. If my friends on the other side review the statement made by President Clinton, they will see that he saw merit in small business  tax relief.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our Committee on Finance chairman, Senator Baucus, recognizes the linkage. I told him Republicans will insist on a small business tax relief package. He, in his cooperative way, as I hope I have been cooperative with him in the past, has heard us. Some in his caucus, their labor union friends and sympathetic ears of the east coast media, attacked Senator Baucus--which I don't understand--for recognizing a basic reality, as Senator Moynihan and Senator Roth worked together a  decade ago to do, to see that there is some negative impact on small business from an increase in the minimum wage so you ought to offset that with some benefit to small business through the tax portions of the legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Those folks who are criticizing Senator Baucus don't have the responsibility to find the middle ground and evidently think we can get a bill through the Senate that can get the votes without finding the middle ground. It can't be done.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, if I were chairman--and I am not chairman, and I am not crying about that--I would have tilted this package a little bit more toward the depreciation incentive and less toward the work opportunity tax credits. The reality is, Republicans don't have a majority on the Committee on Finance or in the full Senate, so chairman Baucus has struck a balance between majority Democrats and minority Republicans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I will assist Senator Baucus in defending the tax relief package that goes for the offsets and the revenue-losing provisions. We should not disturb the core structure of this package. I am hopeful, however, that we will improve the package by enhancing the package on the depreciation side, as Senator Kyl has suggested. It is important these incentives coincide with the time when the minimum wage increase will take effect. In seeking this objective we will need to find appropriate  offsets, obviously. There may be other improvements.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bottom line is the Committee on Finance package is a well-known set of small business tax relief measures, things we have done before--extending, mostly. These proposals have merit by themselves, but a minimum wage increase is not likely to pass the Senate without them. I hope everyone understands that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As many know, I am a working family farmer. For farmers, fields look familiar because we work our fields every year. This linkage, then, to put a commonsense touch on it, is that the linkage between minimum wage and small business relief is a familiar feel. I can quote Roth and Moynihan ad infinitum to prove it. It is not something new that is coming up with Baucus and Grassley. We have plowed this ground before. This is well-known common ground.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I referred to President Clinton in a signing ceremony about 10 years ago. That legislation was founded on a small business tax relief package twice this size. I emphasize it was twice the size of what people are complaining about now that we are presenting to the Senate. It was supported at that time by many seeking cloture on the bill that is before the Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>President Clinton singled out the work opportunity tax credit and the depreciation proposals in his remarks. My friend, Senator Kennedy, attended the signing ceremony and was recognized by President Clinton for the great product they brought to President Clinton. And John Sweeney was recognized, the head of the AFL-CIO.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent the remarks be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="">
    <paragraph>President Clinton said in the signing ceremony:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank all the Members of Congress who are here, especially Senator Kennedy who, himself, probably broke the wage in hour laws by working so hard to pass this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And then in another place:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are a lot of people who worked hard on this bill who aren't here--Senator Daschle, Congressman Gephardt--</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He went on to name other Members--</paragraph>
    <paragraph>led by truly tireless John Sweeney. &lt;p&gt;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And there was applause. Now, some of the same people are objecting to what we are doing now.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Another quote:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would also like a very special word of thanks to the business owners, especially the small business owners who supported this bill. Many of the minimum wage employers I talked to wanted to pay their employees more than $4.25 an hour and would be happy to do so as long as they can do it without hurting their businesses, and that means their competitors have to do the same thing. This bill will allow them to compete and win, to have happier, more productive employees, and to know they are doing  the right thing. For all those small businesses, I am very, very appreciative.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Continuing:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would also say that this bill does a remarkable number of things for small businesses. .....[a]nd we know that most of the new jobs in America are being created by small- and medium-sized businesses. In 1993 I--</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Meaning President Clinton--</paragraph>
    <paragraph>proposed a $15,000 increase in the amount of capital a small business can expense, to spark the kind of investment that they need to create jobs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As the Vice President said--</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Meaning at that time Mr. Gore--</paragraph>
    <paragraph>this bill also includes a Work Opportunity Tax Credit to provide jobs for the most economically disadvantaged working Americans, including people who want to move from welfare to work. Now, there will be a tightly drawn economic incentive for people to hire those folks and give them a chance to enter the workforce, as well. &lt;p&gt;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Well, if Senators who were on the stage at that time thought that the work opportunity tax credit was a good thing to have, why isn't it a good thing to have it here, to extend it? Why not?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a win-win situation. There is a win for the workers, a win for small business. Why should we chortle over a little thing such as increasing the minimum wage or having a tax provision in it?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Massachusetts.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that at 2:45 today the Senate proceed to a vote on or in relation to Snowe amendment No. 103, as modified, with time from 2:15 to 2:45 equally divided and controlled in the usual form, with no second-degree amendments in order prior to the vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="APPOINTMENT OF COMMITTEE TO ESCORT THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the Presiding Officer of the Senate be authorized to appoint a committee on the part of the Senate to join with a like committee on the part of the House to escort the President of the United States into the House Chamber for the joint session to be held at 9 p.m. Tuesday.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="APPOINTMENT OF COMMITTEE TO ESCORT THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I see my friend and colleague from Hawaii wishes to address the Senate on morning business time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Hawaii.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="APPOINTMENT OF COMMITTEE TO ESCORT THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent to speak for 10 minutes as if in morning business.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <narrative>(The remarks of Mr. AKAKA and Mr. KENNEDY are printed in today's RECORD under "Morning Business.")</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="APPOINTMENT OF COMMITTEE TO ESCORT THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, we are going to go into a recess in a moment. We will come out of the party caucuses at 2:15. We are working on some additional amendments. The amendments of the Senator from Alabama, the Sessions amendments, we will try to include, if necessary, votes on those issues as well around the 2:45 hour. We are making some progress. We have a shorter evening tonight because of the President's State of the Union, but we want to move this legislation. It is not complicated.  Everyone in this body, new Members who have arrived here, understands what the increase in the minimum wage is all about. It is not complex. Is it not difficult. It is not hard to understand. There is no reason we can't move this process quickly. If it is necessary to have votes, we are prepared to move along on those issues.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have listened this morning to those who believe that raw economic arguments ought to control the question of the minimum wage. We as a country have moved away from that. We have accepted the great traditions of Judeo-Christian teachings as well as the underlying teachings of all the religions that talk about responsibilities we all have for the least among us. In the Constitution of the United States, they have what is called the general welfare clause. The general welfare clause was written  into the Constitution for those very purposes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The fact is, this country has rejected the law of the jungle as it applies to economic conditions for workers. In my State of Massachusetts, we had individuals at the turn of the last century, children, 10, 11, 12 years old, who were working 12, 15 hours a day, 6 1/2  days a week. We had the exploitation of children, of women, the exploitation of workers. We, as a country and a society, have recognized that we can be the strongest economy in the world and treat people with respect and dignity.  That is why the members of Let Justice Roll, an extraordinary number of religious leaders representing a wide group of churches, talk about what the Scriptures say about poverty in their letter.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent to print the letter in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="APPOINTMENT OF COMMITTEE TO ESCORT THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES">
    <paragraph>They mention Matthew's great teachings. The questioner says: When did I fail to treat you well? And the Lord says: When you failed to treat the least of these among us.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are talking about a minimum wage, not an optimum wage. As the charts show, it has declined dramatically over a period of years, now at $5.15, far away from what it was in the 1960s and 1970s, right through the 1980s. We believe that in this country, with the strongest economy in the world, people who work hard 40 hours a week, 52 weeks of the year, should not have to live in poverty. An increase in the minimum wage is long overdue. Hopefully, we will have an opportunity in this body to express  our views on this in the near future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If there are no further speakers, I suggest that we recess, according to the leadership's earlier request.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
