<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1207670402" ordinal="55" title="COMMENDING THE UNIVERSITY OF KANSAS MEN'S BASKETBALL TEAM FOR WINNING THE 2008 NATIONAL COLLEGIATE ATHLETIC ASSOCIATION (NCAA) DIVISION I BASKETBALL CHAMPIONSHIP">
  <narrative>COMMENDING THE UNIVERSITY OF KANSAS MEN'S BASKETBALL TEAM FOR WINNING THE 2008 NATIONAL COLLEGIATE ATHLETIC ASSOCIATION (NCAA) DIVISION I BASKETBALL CHAMPIONSHIP -- (Senate - April 08, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="2764">S2764</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300034" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate now proceed to the consideration of <bill type="sr" number="505">S. Res. 505</bill>, which was submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <chair>The assistant legislative clerk read as follows:</chair>
  <chair>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="505">S. Res. 505</bill>) commending the University of Kansas men's basketball team for winning the 2008 National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA) Division I basketball championship.</chair>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300083" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, it is my privilege today to submit <bill type="sr" number="505">S. Res. 505</bill>, along with Mr. Brownback. It is my hope it will be considered hot-lined on both sides and passed later this afternoon.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This resolution is a commendation resolution on behalf of the University of Kansas Men's Basketball Team for winning the 2008 National Collegiate Athletic Association, NCAA, Division I, basketball championship as of last night.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This might be a little unique in that I am a graduate of Kansas State University, home of the ever-optimistic and fighting Wildcats. Sometimes we are rivals. In this particular case, all of Kansas, including every K State fan, stands in salute of the Jayhawks. It is clearly "Rock Chalk, Jayhawk" time in Kansas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I will skip to the bottom line of the resolution, where it says:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Whereas, the families of the players, students, alumni, and faculty of the University of Kansas, and all the supporters of the University of Kansas, are to be congratulated for their commitment to, and pride in, the basketball program at the university: Now, therefore be it resolved the Senate commends the University of Kansas men's basketball team for winning the 2008 NCAA Division I Basketball Championship.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Secretary of the Senate will transmit enrolled copies of this resolution to the University of Kansas so they can display it; the chancellor of the university, Bob Hemenway, a great friend; the athletic director of the university, Lew Perkins; and the head coach of the team, Bill Self, who should remain at the University of Kansas. Those remarks were not prepared, but that is my advice.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For those of you who did not see the game last night--and it started at 9 p.m. and I know most Senators are probably asleep at 9 o'clock at night--trailing 60 to 51, with 2:12 seconds left in regulation, Kansas closed the second half with a 12-3 run, capped off by a Mario Chalmers' three-point basket, with 2.1 seconds remaining to force overtime. Kansas then outscored Memphis 12 to 5 in overtime to claim its third national championship.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As General Petraeus is here testifying before four committees in regard to national security and the war with Iraq, and when this Senate is considering a housing bill and stimulus package to help the economy, let us hope the example of the University of Kansas men's basketball team, in regard to their perseverance and dedication, will enable us to achieve our goals as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If you listen hard, from the mountains from which our acting Presiding Officer is so familiar, from Montana and further west, on to the high plains, to the Midwest, across the Appalachians, and clear to the east coast and our Nation's capital--if you listen hard, you can hear that chant, "Rock Chalk, Jayhawk, KU-U-U." If we listen hard, maybe we can work together, follow their example of perseverance and unbelievable heroics to win the NCAA championship. Thus, sayeth this champion of Kansas  State athletics on behalf of the University of Kansas and their basketball team.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300034" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="505">S. Res. 505</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="505">S. Res. 505</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas, on April 7th, 2008, the University of Kansas men's basketball team won its third NCAA Division I Basketball Championship and fifth national title with its 75-68 overtime win over the University of Memphis--on the twentieth anniversary of the historic win by the team led by Danny Manning known as "Danny and the Miracles";</chair>
  <chair>Whereas, with this win the Jayhawks achieved a school record for all-time season wins, posting a 37-3 win-loss record during their run for the title, and finished the season with a thirteen-game winning streak, securing the Big XII Conference Championship title after starting the season with a twenty-game undefeated record, in addition to the 2008 NCAA Division I men's basketball crown;</chair>
  <chair>Whereas, Head Coach Bill Self improved his all-time record at Kansas to 142-32 and 12-4 in the tournament assisted by a miraculous last-minute three-point shot by guard Mario Chalmers;</chair>
  <chair>Whereas, Kansas guard Mario Chalmers was chosen as the Most Outstanding Player of the Final Four and was named to the all-tournament team along with guards Brandon Rush and Sherron Collins;</chair>
  <chair>Whereas, each player, coach, trainer, and manager dedicated his or her time and effort  to ensuring that the Kansas Jayhawks reached their goal of capturing a national championship; and</chair>
  <chair>Whereas, the families of the players, students, alumni, and faculty of the University of Kansas, and all the supporters of the University of Kansas, are to be congratulated for their commitment to, and pride in, the basketball program at the University: Now, therefore, be it</chair>
  <chair>Resolved, That the Senate--</chair>
  <chair>(1) commends the University of Kansas men's basketball team for winning the 2008 NCAA Division I Basketball Championship;</chair>
  <chair>(2) recognizes the achievements of all of the players, coaches, and support staff who were instrumental in helping the University of Kansas men's basketball team win its third NCAA Division I Basketball Championship and fifth national championship;</chair>
  <chair>(3) respectfully requests the Secretary of the Senate to transmit enrolled copies of this resolution to--</chair>
  <chair>(A) the University of Kansas for appropriate display;</chair>
  <chair>(B) the Chancellor of the University of Kansas, Robert Hemenway;</chair>
  <chair>(C) the Athletic Director of the University of Kansas, Lew Perkins;</chair>
  <chair>(D) the Head Coach of the University of Kansas men's basketball team, Bill Self.</chair>
</record>
