<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1173200403" ordinal="43" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="COMMITTEE ON AGRICULTURE, NUTRITION, AND FORESTRY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry be authorized to conduct a hearing during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, March 6, 2007, at 9:30 a.m. in SH-216, Senate Hart Office Building. The subject of this committee hearing will be "Child Nutrition and the School Setting."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="COMMITTEE ON ARMED SERVICES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, March 6, at 9:30 a.m., in open session to receive testimony on care, living conditions, and administration of outpatients at Walter Reed Army Medical Center.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, March 6, 2007, at 10:30 a.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building. The purpose of the hearing is to review the Corporate Average Fuel Economy Program.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, March 6, 2007, at 2:15 p.m. to hold a business meeting.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="COMMITTEE ON HEALTH, EDUCATION, LABOR, AND PENSIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, March 6, 2007 at 10 a.m. in SD-430.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet to conduct a hearing on "Preserving Prosecutorial Independence: Is the Department of Justice Politicizing the Hiring and Firing of U.S. Attorneys?--Part II" on Tuesday, March 6, 2007 at 10 a.m. in Dirksen Senate Office Building Room 226.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Witness List:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>H.E. "Bud" Cummins, III, Former U.S. Attorney, Eastern District of Arkansas, Little Rock, AR.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>David C. Iglesias, Former U.S. Attorney, District of New Mexico, Albuquerque, NM.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Carol Lam, Former U.S. Attorney, Southern District of California, San Diego, CA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>John McKay, Former U.S. Attorney, Western District of Washington, Seattle, WA.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="COMMITTEE ON VETERANS' AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent the Committee on Veterans' Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, March 6, 2007 at 9:30 a.m. in the Cannon Caucus Room, to hear the legislative presentation of the Veterans of Foreign Wars.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="SELECT COMMITTEE ON INTELLIGENCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Select Committee on Intelligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on March 6, 2007 at 2:30 p.m. to hold a closed hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
