<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1185940800" ordinal="51" title="NATIONALLY HISTORICALLY BLACK COLLEGES AND UNIVERSITIES WEEK">
  <narrative>NATIONALLY HISTORICALLY BLACK COLLEGES AND UNIVERSITIES WEEK -- (Senate - August 01, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="10679">S10679</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412246" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate now proceed to the consideration of <bill type="sr" number="291">S. Res. 291</bill> which was submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="291">S. Res. 291</bill>) designating the week beginning September 9, 2007, as "National Historically Black Colleges and Universities Week."</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412246" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="291">S. Res. 291</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="291">S. Res. 291</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas there are 103 historically Black colleges and universities in the United States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas historically Black colleges and universities provide the quality education essential to full participation in a complex, highly technological society;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas historically Black colleges and universities have a rich heritage and have played a prominent role in the history of the United States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas historically Black colleges and universities have allowed many underprivileged students to attain their full potential through higher education; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the achievements and goals of historically Black colleges and universities are deserving of national recognition: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, that the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) designates the week beginning September 9, 2007, as "National Historically Black Colleges and Universities Week"; and</chair>
  <chair> (2) calls on the people of the United States and interested groups to observe the week  with appropriate ceremonies, activities, and programs to demonstrate support for historically Black colleges and universities in the United States.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
