<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1196960402" ordinal="64" title="EXPRESSING THE CONDOLENCES OF THE SENATE TO THOSE AFFECTED BY THE TRAGIC EVENTS OF DECEMBER 5, 2007, AT WESTROADS MALL IN OMAHA, NEBRASKA">
  <narrative>EXPRESSING THE CONDOLENCES OF THE SENATE TO THOSE AFFECTED BY THE TRAGIC EVENTS OF DECEMBER 5, 2007, AT WESTROADS MALL IN OMAHA, NEBRASKA -- (Senate - December 06, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="14999">S14999</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of <bill type="sr" number="393">S. Res. 393</bill>, submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="393">S. Res. 393</bill>), expressing the condolences of the Senate to those affected by the tragic events of December 5, 2007, at Westroads Mall in Omaha, NE.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300077" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today to honor and remember the victims of yesterday's tragic shooting in Omaha, NE. I know every one of my colleagues joins me in extending our prayers and deepest sympathies to the families and friends of the victims and the entire Omaha community.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On Wednesday, December 5, 2007, the worst mass slaying in Nebraska history occurred at the Westroads Mall in Omaha, claiming the lives of eight victims. The names of those victims are: shoppers Gary Sharf of Lincoln, NE, and John McDonald of Council Bluffs, IA; and store employees Angie Schuster, Maggie Webb, Janet Jorgensen, Diane Trent, Gary Joy, and Beverly Flynn, all of Omaha. We must never forget these individuals or the horrible tragedy which took them from us.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, five people were wounded. Nebraska stands with each of them on their road to recovery.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I concur with the words of Omaha Mayor Mike Fahey, who said, "We are a community who will grieve this loss. Omaha is a good city with wonderful people."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At Westroads Mall, this time of year is especially lovely with holiday decorations and music. That peace and tranquility were forever shattered by this senseless act of violence. Today, many Nebraskans are asking, "Why?" but there are no answers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are shocked, grief-stricken and in complete disbelief. Things like this should not happen anywhere, but headlines like these are unexpected in places such as Omaha. Our community has been altered forever--a sentiment reflected in today's headline in the state's largest newspaper, which declared: "It Happened To Us."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, now as we are celebrating what should be the most joyous season of the year, Nebraskans are preparing to bury our dead. And we are praying. We ask the nation to continue to pray with us; and on behalf of my fellow Nebraskans, I thank you for all the prayers and expressions of sympathy we have received.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, the motions to reconsider be laid on the table, and any statements be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="393">S. Res. 393</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="393">S. Res. 393</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas, on Wednesday, December 5, 2007, the worst mass slaying in Nebraska history occurred at Westroads Mall in Omaha;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas lives were tragically lost, and others were wounded;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the brave men and women of the Omaha Police Department, Fire Department, and other emergency responders acted valiantly to save lives;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the people of Omaha have embraced those affected and will continue to offer support to their neighbors who have suffered from this tragedy; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the community of Omaha will endure the aftereffects of this tragedy to emerge stronger than it was before: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) expresses its heartfelt condolences to the friends and families of those who lost their lives in the tragic shooting on December 5, 2007, at Westroads Mall in Omaha, Nebraska: Gary Sharf of Lincoln, Nebraska, John McDonald of Council Bluffs, Iowa, and Angie Schuster, Maggie Webb, Janet Jorgensen, Diane Trent, Gary Joy, and Beverly Flynn, all of Omaha;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) shares its prayers and best wishes for recovery to those who were wounded;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) extends its thanks to the first responders, police, and medical personnel who responded so quickly and decisively to provide aid and comfort to the victims; and</chair>
  <chair> (4) stands with the people of Omaha as they begin the healing process in the aftermath of this terrible attack.  &lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
