<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1189180801" ordinal="9" title="TRIBUTE TO JOHN WARNER">
  <narrative>TRIBUTE TO JOHN WARNER -- (Senate - September 07, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="11263">S11263</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, it is with a touch of sadness that I speak about my friend, the senior Senator from Virginia, JOHN WARNER, who announced last week that he will not seek a sixth term and will return to the Commonwealth he loves so well following the conclusion of the 110th Congress. We will miss our friend, our colleague, and one of our finest and most respected members.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>JOHN WARNER is a true American patriot, who has spent his life serving the public good. From volunteering to serve in World War II at the age of 17, to his service as Secretary of the Navy and his years among us in the Senate, his life has been defined by a commitment of service to others.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First and foremost a Virginia gentleman, JOHN WARNER is also one of the greatest advocates our fighting men and women have ever had in the U.S. Senate, consistently supporting their interests regardless of the prevailing winds.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He was an extraordinary chairman of the Armed Services Committee, where he helped transform the Committee from a Cold War posture to a new focus on emerging threats, rapid technological changes, and asymmetric warfare. The changes he made helped usher the committee into the 21st Century. As his colleague on the committee for a quarter century, I can attest to the unrivalled depth of his understanding of our Nation's military, and was grateful to have the opportunity to call upon him innumerable  times over the years for his wise counsel.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to his commitment and dedication to our military and to a strong national defense, JOHN WARNER is also the embodiment of the finest traditions of the Senate. Deliberate, thoughtful, and principled, over the past 28 years he has shown us all that we can disagree without being disagreeable, and that the demands of party must yield to the demands of the American people that we do our very best to support our armed forces in their all-important missions for our country and our  future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Time after time, he has demonstrated his courage, decency and high principles in the Senate, whatever the partisan passions of the moment. That is who JOHN WARNER is--someone who thinks long and hard about important decisions, and then does what he feels is right.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am sure he and Jeanne thought long and hard about the decision to retire from the Senate, and I know it wasn't an easy call. He will leave enormous shoes to fill for the next person elected to serve the people of Virginia in this body.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I will miss serving side by side with JOHN WARNER in the next Congress, but I am grateful we will have him here in the Senate for the coming year, especially, as we work to find answers to the extraordinarily complex and dangerous situation we confront in the Middle East. I am sure that all of us admire him for his statesmanship and leadership.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And we are especially grateful for his friendship, which extended to my brothers Jack and Bobby as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We will miss him very much.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
