<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1211385602" ordinal="31" title="MATTHEW SHEPARD ACT OF 2007">
  <narrative>MATTHEW SHEPARD ACT OF 2007 -- (Senate - May 21, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="4614">S4614</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300090" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today to speak about the need for hate crimes legislation. Each Congress, Senator Kennedy and I introduce hate crimes legislation that would strengthen and add new categories to current hate crimes law, sending a signal that violence of any kind is unacceptable in our society. Likewise, each Congress I have come to the floor to highlight a separate hate crime that has occurred in our country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On Thursday evening, May 15, 2008, in Sacramento, CA, a 23-year-old man was sitting in his car at a gas station when he was approached by three men. According to police, one of the men asked him if he was gay and he responded that he was. When the man then exited the car, he was attacked by the three men as they yelled homophobic slurs. Micah Jontomo Tasaki, 21, Gregory Lee Winfield, 20, and Robert Lee Denor, 19, were arrested at the gas staion where the attack occurred in connection with the  assault. Luckily for the victim, he did not sustain injuries serious enough to necessitate a hospital visit. A Sacramento police officer investigating the crime has called it a "gay bashing" and a hate crime.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe that the Government's first duty is to defend its citizens, to defend them against the harms that come out of hate. Federal laws intended to protect individuals from heinous and violent crimes motivated by hate are woefully inadequate. This legislation would better equip the Government to fulfill its most important obligation by protecting new groups of people as well as better protecting citizens already covered under deficient laws. I believe that by passing this legislation and changing  current law, we can change hearts and minds as well.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
