<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1207238402" ordinal="50" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <narrative>AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET -- (Senate - April 03, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="2587">S2587</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON ARMED SERVICES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, April 3, 2008, at 9:30 a.m., in open session to consider pending nominations.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON BANKING, HOUSING, AND URBAN AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on April 3, 2008, at 10:00 A.M., to conduct a hearing entitled "turmoil in U.S. credit markets: examining the recent actions of Federal Financial Regulators."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, April 3, 2008, at 10 a.m., in Room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND NATIONAL RESOURCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate to conduct a hearing on Thursday, April 3, 2008, at 9:30 a.m., in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENVIRONMENT AND PUBLIC WORKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Environment and Public Works be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, April 3, 2008 at 10 a.m. in room 406 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building to hold a hearing entitled, "Examining Strategies to Reduce Greenhouse Gas Emissions at U.S. Colleges and Universities."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON FINANCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Finance be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, April 3, 2008, at 10 a.m., in room 215 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building, to conduct a hearing entitled "Outside the Box on Estate Tax Reform: Reviewing Ideas to Simplify Planning".</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the  Senate on Thursday, April 3, 2008, at 9:30 a.m. to hold a hearing on Iraq.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON HOMELAND SECURITY AND GOVERNMENTAL AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, April 3, 2008, at 10 a.m. to conduct a hearing entitled "The New FEMA: Is the Agency Better Prepared for a Catastrophe Now Than It Was in 2005?".</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate, to conduct an executive business meeting on Thursday, April 3, 2008, at 10 a.m. in room SD-226 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I. Bills: <bill type="s" number="2136">S.2136</bill>, Helping Families Save Their Homes in Bankruptcy Act of 2007, (Durbin, Schumer, Whitehouse, Biden, Feinstein); <bill type="s" number="2133">S.2133</bill>, Home Owners "Mortgage and Equity Savings Act", (Specter, Coleman); <bill type="s" number="2041">S.2041</bill>, False Claims Act Correction Act of 2007, (Grassley, Durbin, Leahy, Specter, Whitehouse); <bill type="s" number="2533">S.2533</bill>, State Secrets Protection Act, (Kennedy, Specter, Leahy, Feingold, Whitehouse); <bill type="s" number="702">S.702</bill>, State Court Interpreter Grant Program Act, (Kohl, Kennedy, Durbin, Biden, Cardin, Leahy, Specter).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>II. Resolution: <bill type="sr" number="468">S. Res. 468</bill>, designating April 2008 as "National 9-1-1 Education Month", (Clinton, Stevens).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>III. Nominations: Catharina Haynes to be United States Circuit Court Judge for the Fifth Circuit, Rebecca Ann Gregory to be United States Attorney for the Eastern District of Texas.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate, to conduct a hearing on Thursday, April 3, 2008, at 2:15 p.m., in room SD-226 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Witness list: Mark S. Davis to be United States District Judge for the Eastern District of Virginia; David Gregory Kays to be United States District Judge for the Western District of Missouri; David J. Novak to be United States District Judge for the Eastern District of Virginia; Stephen N. Limbaugh, Jr. to be United States District Judge for the Eastern District of Missouri; Elisebeth C. Cook to be Assistant Attorney General for the Office of Legal Policy, Department of Justice.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON VETERANS' AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent for the Committee on Veterans' Affairs to be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, April 3, 2008 to conduct a Joint Hearing with the House Veterans' Affairs Committee to hear the Legislative Presentations from the: AMVETS, Military Order of the Purple Heart, Gold Star Wives of America, Fleet Reserve Association, The Retired Enlisted Association, Military Officers Association of America, and National Association of State  Directors of Veterans Affairs. The Committee will meet in room 216 of the Hart Senate Office Building, at 9:30 a.m.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON AIRLAND">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on Airland of the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, April 3, 2008, at 3 p.m., in open session to receive testimony on Army modernization in review of the defense authorization request for fiscal year 2009 and the future years defense program.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON OVERSIGHT OF GOVERNMENT MANAGEMENT, THE FEDERAL WORKFORCE, AND THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Homeland Security and Government Affairs' Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, April 3, 2008 at 2 p.m. to conduct a hearing entitled, "Managing Diversity of Senior Leadership in the Federal Workforce an Postal Service."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="SPECIAL COMMITTEE ON AGING">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Special Committee on Aging be authorized to meet on Thursday, April 3, 2008, from 10:30 a.m. to 12:30 p.m. in Dirksen 608 for the purpose of conducting a hearing</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
