<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1211385602" ordinal="38" title="TRIBUTE TO BRIGADIER GENERAL NEIL SMART">
  <narrative>TRIBUTE TO BRIGADIER GENERAL NEIL SMART -- (Senate - May 21, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="4616">S4616</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300088" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I wish today to pay tribute to BG Neil Smart, former battalion commander in the Battle of the Bulge in World War II and Director of the Veterans Administration Regional Office in Montgomery, AL. General Smart's service to this nation was long and distinguished.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Smart was commissioned a second lieutenant in the ROTC department of the University of Alabama in 1938. He left Active Duty as a lieutenant colonel and continued to serve in the National Guard. After General Smart completed his military service, he continued to serve the Nation's veterans in his work with the Veterans' Administration. He led the VA in Alabama in an exemplary manner from 1958 to 1974.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>General Smart also loved to share stories of World War II. He felt this was a legacy his generation should leave younger generations. He really liked to tell the story about an unscheduled inspection he and his battalion had to undergo during World War II. The inspectors were GEN Dwight Eisenhower, GEN Omar Bradley, and British Prime Minister Winston Churchill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This 94-year-old was also a key fundraiser in the efforts to build a memorial honoring the American effort in World War II. He was scheduled to visit the World War II Memorial with an Honor Flight group from the Prattville and Montgomery area of Alabama this past Saturday. My wife and I were there at the memorial to meet this group of heroes. When the group arrived, we were told the sad news that General Smart had died just hours before their departure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, Mr. President it is my honor to pay tribute to this great Alabamian and American. He served his State and Nation well.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
