<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1191513602" ordinal="59" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <narrative>AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET -- (Senate - October 04, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="12811">S12811</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300073" topic="COMMITTEE ON ARMED SERVICES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on October 4, 2007, at 9:30 a.m., in open session to consider the following nominations: Honorable John J. Young, Jr. to be Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition, Technology, and Logistics; Douglas A. Brook to be Assistant Secretary of the Navy for Financial Management and Comptroller; and Robert L. Smolen to be Deputy Administrator for Defense  Programs, National Nuclear Security Administration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300073" topic="COMMITTEE ON BANKING, HOUSING, AND URBAN AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on October 4, 2007, at 10 a.m., in order to conduct a hearing entitled "Examining the Regulation and Supervision of Industrial Loan Companies."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300073" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Thursday, October 4, 2007, at 10 a.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The hearing will review the Department of Homeland Security's implementation and administration of several port and cargo security programs authorized in the SAFE Port Act, the Maritime and Transportation Security Act of 2002, and the Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation Act of 2004.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300073" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Thursday, October 4, 2007, at 2:30 p.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At this hearing, the Committee will explore the state of the Consumer Product Safety Commission, examine reforms that are necessary to make the agency more effective to protect children and other consumers from dangerous and defective products, and seek comments on <bill type="s" number="2045">S. 2045</bill>, the Consumer Product Safety Commission Reform Act of 2007.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300073" topic="COMMITTEE ON FINANCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Finance be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, October 4, 2007, at 2 p.m., in room 215 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building, to consider favorably reporting an original bill entitled, "The Heartland, Habitat, Harvest, and Horticulture Act of 2007" and legislation implementing the U.S.-Peru Trade Promotion Agreement.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300073" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, October 4, 2007, at 9:30 a.m. to hold a hearing on the Law of the Sea Convention.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300073" topic="COMMITTEE ON INDIAN AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Indian Affairs be authorized to meet on Thursday, October 4, 2007, at 9:30 a.m. in room 628 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building to conduct an oversight hearing on Backlogs at the Department of the Interior: Land into Trust Applications; Environmental Impact Statements; Probate; and Appraisals and Lease Approvals.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300073" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate in order to conduct an Executive Business Meeting on Thursday, October 4, 2007, at 10 a.m. in the Dirksen Senate Office Building room 226.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I. Bills: <bill type="s" number="2035">S. 2035</bill>, Free Flow of Information Act of 2007 (Specter, Schumer, Lugar, Dodd, Leahy, Graham) and <bill type="s" number="1640">S. 1640</bill>, Vessel Hull Design Protection Amendments of 2007 (Leahy, Cornyn, Kohl, Whitehouse).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>II. Resolutions: <bill type="sr" number="326">S. Res. 326</bill>, Supporting the goals and ideals of a National Day of Remembrance for Murder Victims (Cornyn, Feinstein, Kyl) and <bill type="hc" number="193">H. Con. Res. 193</bill>, Recognizing all hunters across the United States for their continued commitment to safety.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>III. Nominations: Thomas P. O'Brien to be United States Attorney for the Central District of California.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300073" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate to conduct a hearing entitled "Justice Denied? Implementation of  the Hometown Heroes Survivors Benefits Act" on Thursday, October 4, 2007 at 2:30 p.m. in the Dirksen Senate Office Building room 226.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300073" topic="JOINT ECONOMIC COMMITTEE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Joint Economic Committee he authorized to conduct a hearing entitled, "Mass Incarceration in the United States: At What Cost?", in room 216 of the Hart Senate Office Building, Thursday, October 4, 2007, from 10 a.m. to 1 p.m.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300073" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON OVERSIGHT OF GOVERNMENT MANAGEMENT, THE FEDERAL WORKFORCE, AND THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs' Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Managment, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, October 4, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. in order to conduct a hearing entit1ed, "Forestalling the Coming Pandemic: Infectious Disease Surveillance Overseas."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
