<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1204822801" ordinal="42" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <narrative>AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET -- (Senate - March 06, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="1716">S1716</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300080" topic="COMMITTEE ON ARMED SERVICES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, March 6, 2008, at 9:30 a.m., in open session in order to receive testimony on U.S. Southern Command and U.S. Northern Command in review of the Defense authorization request for fiscal year 2009 and the future years Defense program.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300080" topic="COMMITTEE ON BANKING, HOUSING, AND URBAN AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on March 6, 2008, at 10 a.m., in order to conduct a hearing entitled "Reforming the Regulation of Government Sponsored Enterprises."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300080" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, March 6, 2008, at 10:30 a.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building, in order to conduct a hearing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Committee will review the President's proposed U.S. Coast Guard budget for the 2009 fiscal year. It will also examine programs in the pending Coast Guard Reauthorization Act for fiscal year 2008.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300080" topic="COMMITTEE ON FINANCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Finance be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, March 6, 2008, at 10 a.m., in room 215 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building, in order to hear testimony on the administration's 2008 trade agenda.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300080" topic="COMMITTEE ON HEALTH, EDUCATION, LABOR, AND PENSIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions be authorized to meet, during the session of the Senate, in order to conduct a hearing entitled "Unemployment in a Volatile Economy: How to Secure Families and Build Opportunity" on Thursday, March 6, 2008. The hearing will commence at 10 a.m. in room 430 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300080" topic="COMMITTEE ON INDIAN AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Indian Affairs be authorized to meet on Thursday, March 6, at 10 a.m. in room 628 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building in order to conduct an oversight hearing on the State of Facilities in Indian Country--jails, schools, and health facilities.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300080" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate, in order to conduct an executive business meeting on Thursday, March 6, 2008, at 10 a.m. in room SD-226 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Agenda</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="2304">S.2304</bill>, Mentally III Offender Treatment and Crime Reduction Reauthorization and Improvement Act of 2007, (Domenici, Kennedy, Specter, Leahy); <bill type="s" number="2449">S.2449</bill>, Sunshine in Litigation Act of 2007, (Kohl, Leahy, Graham); <bill type="s" number="352">S.352</bill>, Sunshine in the Courtroom Act of 2007, (Grassley, Schumer, Leahy, Specter, Graham, Feingold, Cornyn, Durbin); <bill type="s" number="2136">S.2136</bill>, Helping Families Save Their Homes in Bankruptcy Act of 2007, (Durbin, Schumer, Whitehouse, Biden, Feinstein); <bill type="s" number="2133">S.2133</bill>, Home Owners "Mortgage and Equity Savings Act,"</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Kevin J. O'Connor to be Associate Attorney General, Department of Justice; Gregory G. Katsas to be Assistant Attorney General, Civil Division, Department of Justice; William Joseph Hawe to be United States Marshal for the Western District of Washington; Brian Stacy Miller to be United States District Judge for the Eastern District of Arkansas; James Randal Hall to be United States District Judge for the Southern District of Georgia; John A. Mendez to be United States District Judge for the Eastern  District of California; and Stanley Thomas Anderson to be United States District Judge for the Western District of Tennessee.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300080" topic="SELECT COMMITTEE ON INTELLIGENCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Select Committee on Intelligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on March 6, 2008, at 2:30 p.m. in order to hold a closed hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
