<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1217001603" ordinal="8" title="REMEMBERING JOHN Y. SIMON">
  <narrative>REMEMBERING JOHN Y. SIMON -- (Senate - July 25, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="7474">S7474</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, in 1887, 2 years after the death of Ulysses S. Grant, William Tecumseh Sherman wrote in a letter to his old Army Chief of Staff, "Grant's whole character was a mystery, even to himself."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, more than 120 years later, the world has a far better understanding of Ulysses Grant than did General Sherman, or maybe even General Grant himself. And for that, we are indebted to one man more than any other.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>John Y. Simon, a leading Civil War scholar and the preeminent authority on Ulysses Grant, died on July 8 in Carbondale, IL. Mr. Simon, an award-winning historian, spent more than four decades at Southern Illinois University, where he taught courses on the Civil War, Reconstruction and the history of Illinois. He also served as executive director of the Ulysses S. Grant Association, based at SIU, since 1962.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But his passion and his true vocation was the Ulysses Grant papers project. Mr. Simon collected, edited, and organized hundreds of thousands of documents connected with America's 18th President--then assembled them to form a vast and astounding collection, which he called the "Papers of Ulysses S. Grant."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He began the Grant papers project in 1962 and was close to completing it when he died. The 31st and final volume of the collection is in its final stages. The entire collection is published by Southern Illinois University Press.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Harriet Simon, Mr. Simon's wife of 51 years, told the New York Times that working on the Grant papers consumed her husband.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>"It was daily," she said. "It was weekends and it was most holidays. Some holidays, not all day."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>John Younker Simon was born in Highland Park, IL, in 1933. He graduated from Swarthmore College and received an M.A. and a Ph.D., both in history, from Harvard, where he met his future wife. He taught at Ohio State before finding his place at S.I.U. in 1964.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Just as President Grant's own autobiography raised the standard for Presidential memoirs, Mr. Simon's work raised the standard for Presidential papers collections.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Harold Holzer is senior vice president of the Metropolitan Museum of Art in New York. He is also a renowned Lincoln scholar and a cochairman, along with Representative Ray LaHood and me, of the Abraham Lincoln Bicentennial Committee. As he told the New York Times, Mr. Simon approached his work on the Grant papers as a biographer rather than simply a cataloger.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Holzer said:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He changed the whole ethos of presidential papers. He matched incoming correspondence with outgoing, so researchers would have a complete episode. He included editorial commentary that was more substantial than footnotes. He wrote introductions to each volume. ..... He is the father of this whole discipline.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 2004, Mr. Simon received a Lincoln Prize for outstanding achievement for the Grant papers. The awards jury wrote, "It is inconceivable that any historian would write on the Civil War without having these volumes at hand."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 2005, John Simon was honored with a lifetime achievement award from the Lincoln Forum. Frank J. Williams, chairman of the Lincoln Forum and president of the Ulysses S. Grant Association, praised him as "a brilliant scholar, a dazzling writer and an original, irreplaceable personality [who] has enriched the world of Civil War studies and enriched the lives of those who know him."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Upon receiving the Lincoln Prize, Mr. Simon said of his life's work:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have enjoyed it. It has been an opportunity for me to spend time with a spectacular figure in American history. Grant was a complex character--an unmilitary soldier, an unpolitical president and an unliterary author.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And Ulysses Grant was often misunderstood.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Alexander Stephens, the Vice President of the Confederacy, met General Grant toward the end of the Civil War. Years later, he wrote of their meeting:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We all form our preconceived ideas of men of whom we have heard a great deal ..... but I was never so completely surprised in all my life as when I met him and found him a different person, so entirely different from my idea of him. ..... He is one of the most remarkable men I have ever met.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He was an unlikely war hero. At the start of the Civil War, Grant was several years out of the Army and utterly broke. At one point, he had been reduced to selling firewood on the street in St. Louis.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But the cause of preserving the Union gave Grant a new purpose. He reentered the military in 1861, and rose quickly through the ranks, thanks to his fearlessness and brilliance as a military commander.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1864, he was promoted to the rank of Lieutenant General of the Armed Forces, a position only ever held by George Washington, and given overall command of all Union Forces.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The following year, he accepted the surrender of the Army of Northern Virginia from General Robert E. Lee at Appomattox Courthouse. His generous terms of surrender and his magnanimity stunned Lee and his men and helped a bloodied nation begin to heal.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As President during the Reconstruction era, Grant's policies moved America further toward reconciliation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Near the end of his life, broke again after being swindled in a business venture and in constant pain from throat cancer, Grant agreed to write his memoirs to earn money for his family. He wrote feverishly, racing against death, and died 5 days after putting down his pen.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>His friend, Mark Twain, called "The Personal Memoirs of Ulysses S. Grant" "a great, unique and unapproachable literary masterpiece." It is widely regarded as the finest U.S. Presidential memoir ever written.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Understanding the real Grant and helping others to understand this pivotal figure in our history was John Simon's life's work, and he did it with uncommon distinction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to the Grant papers, he wrote and edited a number of other books dealing with Grant, Lincoln and the Civil War and produced hundreds of journal articles. Along with the Lincoln Prize and the Lincoln Forum award, he received an Award of Merit from the Illinois State Historical Society and many other honors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After the Union victory at Vicksburg, President Lincoln wrote to General Grant:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My Dear General: I write this now as a grateful acknowledgement for the almost inestimable service you have done the country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By spending his entire career to give us a clearer picture of "The Hero of Appomattox," John Y. Simon also performed a great service for our country.  He brought honor to my State and a deeper understanding to us all. I offer my sincere condolences to his wife Harriet, his daughter Ellen, his grandchildren, friends and colleagues, and the many students he inspired.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
