<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1197306002" ordinal="12" title="REGULATIONS GOVERNING THE PUBLIC AVAILABILITY OF CONFERENCE REPORTS">
  <narrative>REGULATIONS GOVERNING THE PUBLIC AVAILABILITY OF CONFERENCE REPORTS -- (Senate - December 10, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="15059">S15059</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I wish to notify all Senators that the Committee on Rules and Administration adopted Regulations Governing the Public Availability of Conference Reports, effective December 7, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These regulations were promulgated pursuant to Public Law 110-81, the Honest Leadership and Open Government Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the regulations be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>Regulations Governing the Public Availability of Conference Reports</narrative>
  <narrative>(Adopted by the Committee on Rules and Administration, United States Senate, Effective December 7, 2007)</narrative>
  <narrative>1. Section 511 (b)(1) of Public Law 110-81, enacted on September 14, 2007, authorizes the Committee on Rules and Administration to promulgate regulations implementing the requirements of paragraph 9 of Rule XXVIII of the Standing Rules of the Senate.</narrative>
  <narrative>2. Under the direction of the Committee on Rules and Administration, the Government Printing Office shall create and maintain a publicly accessible website that shall make available conference committee reports.</narrative>
  <narrative>3. The Government Printing Office shall affix a time stamp to each conference report noting the date and time the report was made available to the public on the website. The Government Printing Office shall also notify, in writing or by e-mail, designated staff of the Secretary of the Senate and the Clerk of the House of the date and time the report was posted on the website. The 48-hour period of public availability of a conference report prior to a vote on the adoption of the report, required  by Section 511 (b)(1) of P.L. 110-81, shall commence on the date and time of the time stamp, unless there is an earlier public posting on a Congressionally authorized website.</narrative>
  <narrative>4. The Government Printing Office shall provide public notification of this website through communications with the Library of Congress and the Federal Depository Library system.</narrative>
</record>
