<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1179331205" ordinal="13" title="FISCAL YEAR 2008 BUDGET RESOLUTION">
  <speaking speaker="300036" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I believe that my service in the Senate has been highlighted by my interest in the budget process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As this year's budget negotiations continue, I would like to draw the attention of other Senators to a recent editorial in the Wall Street Journal concerning the single largest day of tax collection in U.S. history. The editorial is entitled "April Revenue Shower."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think this editorial raises some very interesting points that are particularly relevant as Congress debates the fiscal year 2008 budget resolution. The Wall Street Journal points out that in April alone the U.S. Government collected $70 billion in tax receipts above the same month last year and for the current fiscal year tax receipts are up 11.3 percent or $153 billion from last year. I am not sure if most  people are aware of the fact that on April  24, 2007, the United States collected a record setting $48.7 billion in tax receipts. I think these numbers are certainly worth our attention.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What I find so interesting about these record-breaking tax revenues is the fact they were achieved without raising taxes and without a Federal budget in place. Rather, the American economy is the driving force behind these windfalls. I would pose the question that maybe; just maybe, we should maintain the status quo instead of entering into the budget resolution that is being proposed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think Congress should think long and hard about these numbers before we consider making any change to current budget policy. Because of these record tax revenues the budget deficit could be slashed in more than half from this same time last year. The deficit could be reduced by $150 billion this year, which equates to approximately 1 percent of gross domestic product. I believe our current budget policy is paying off and in the next 18 to 24 months the deficit could completely disappear, if  we here in Congress do not veer off course.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am not surprised that we are collecting nearly 30 percent more from nonwithheld income. Moreover, I also do not find it surprising that individual income tax receipts are up by almost 17.5 percent. I believe that the tax relief that we instituted in 2001 and 2003 is paying large dividends and our economy is benefiting.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I hope my colleagues in the Senate will consider these facts and not attempt to fix something that is not broken. I am simply saying that maybe we should not be rushed into action.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Additionally, I ask unanimous consent that this editorial from the Wall Street Journal be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
</record>
