<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1196960402" ordinal="24" title="CHARLIE W. NORWOOD LIVING ORGAN DONATION ACT">
  <narrative>CHARLIE W. NORWOOD LIVING ORGAN DONATION ACT -- (Senate - December 06, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="14827">S14827</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask the Chair to lay before the Senate a message from the House of Representatives with respect to <bill type="h" number="710">H.R. 710</bill>, Charlie W. Norwood Living Organ Donation Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The PRESIDING OFFICER (Ms. KLOBUCHAR) laid before the Senate the following message from the House of Representatives:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>
      <bill type="h" number="710">H.R. 710</bill>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph> Resolved, That the House agree to the amendment of the Senate to the bill (<bill type="h" number="710">H.R. 710</bill>) entitled "An Act to amend the National Organ Transplant Act to provide that criminal penalties do not apply to paired donations of human kidneys, and for other purposes", with the following House amendments to Senate amendment:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In lieu of the matter proposed to be inserted by the amendment of the Senate to the text of the bill, insert the following:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "Charlie W. Norwood Living Organ Donation Act".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. AMENDMENTS TO THE NATIONAL ORGAN TRANSPLANT ACT.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Section 301 of the National Organ Transplant Act (42 U.S.C. 274e) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in subsection (a), by adding at the end the following: "The preceding sentence does not apply with respect to human organ paired donation."; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) in subsection (c), by adding at the end the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(4) The term `human organ paired donation' means the donation and receipt of human organs under the following circumstances:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(A) An individual (referred to in this paragraph as the `first donor') desires to make a living donation of a human organ specifically to a particular patient (referred to in this paragraph as the `first patient'), but such donor is biologically incompatible as a donor for such patient.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(B) A second individual (referred to in this paragraph as the `second donor') desires to make a living donation of a human organ specifically to a second particular patient (referred to in this paragraph as the `second patient'), but such donor is biologically incompatible as a donor for such patient.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(C) Subject to subparagraph (D), the first donor is biologically compatible as a donor of a human organ for the second patient, and the second donor is biologically compatible as a donor of a human organ for the first patient.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(D) If there is any additional donor-patient pair as described in subparagraph (A) or (B), each donor in the group of donor-patient pairs is biologically compatible as a donor of a human organ for a patient in such group.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(E) All donors and patients in the group of donor-patient pairs (whether 2 pairs or more than 2 pairs) enter into a single agreement to donate and receive such human organs, respectively, according to such biological compatibility in the group.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(F) Other than as described in subparagraph (E), no valuable consideration is knowingly acquired, received, or otherwise transferred with respect to the human organs referred to in such subparagraph.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 3. REPORT.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that details the progress made towards understanding the long-term health effects of living organ donation.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 4. NO IMPACT ON SOCIAL SECURITY TRUST FUND.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Nothing in this Act (or an amendment made by this Act) shall be construed to alter or amend the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 301 et seq.) (or any regulation promulgated under that Act).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Amend the title so as to read: "An Act to amend the National Organ Transplant Act to provide that criminal penalties do not apply to human organ paired donation, and for other purposes.".</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate concur in the House amendments and the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, this bipartisan legislation makes technical changes to legislation I previously introduced, <bill type="s" number="487">S. 487</bill>, along with Senators BOND, DORGAN, GRAHAM, DURBIN, MIKULSKI, PRYOR, CARDIN, ISAKSON, COLEMAN, BROWN, and CHAMBLISS and which passed the Senate on July 9, 2007. Companion legislation, <bill type="h" number="710">H.R. 710</bill>, was introduced in the House by Representatives CHARLES NORWOOD and JAY INSLEE,  &lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page:  <bill type="s" number="14828">S14828</bill>]&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/center&gt;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, the House has returned the bill passed by the Senate on July 9, 2007, with several technical changes and we are all pleased that with its adoption today and fast-track to the President for his signature, the saving of thousands of lives is on the horizon.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our legislation will save lives by increasing the number of kidneys and other organs available for transplantation through the process called paired organ donation. It addresses this relatively new procedure, which is supported by numerous medical organizations, including the United Network for Organ Sharing, UNOS, the American Society of Transplant Surgeons, the National Kidney Foundation, the Association of Organ Procurement Organizations, and the American Society of Pediatric Nephrology, as  well as many other organ donation and transplant organizations. Paired organ donation, which did not exist when the National Organ Transplant Act, NOTA, was enacted more than two decades ago, will make it possible for thousands of people who wish to donate a kidney or other organ to a spouse, family member or friend, but find that they are medically incompatible, to still become living kidney donors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the process of organ paired donation, a donor who is willing to give an organ to a family member or a friend, but is biologically incompatible, donates to another patient, who also has an incompatible donor. By cross-matching two or more incompatible living donor recipient pairs, more patients can receive organs and more donors can give an organ. Paired organ donation results in donor-recipient matching, that would not otherwise occur.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation is necessary because the National Organ Transplant Act, NOTA, which contains a prohibition intended by Congress to preclude purchasing organs, is unintentionally impeding the facilitation of matching incompatible pairs, as just described. Our legislation would simply add paired donation to the list of other living-related donation exemptions that Congress originally placed in NOTA. It removes an unintended impediment to paired donations by clarifying ambiguous language in section  301 of the National Organ Transplant Act, NOTA. That section has been interpreted by a number of transplant centers to prohibit such donations. In section 301 of NOTA, Congress prohibited the buying and selling of organs. Subsection (a), titled "Prohibition of organ purchases," says, "It shall be</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress surely never intended that the living donation arrangements that permit paired donation be impeded by NOTA. Our bill simply makes that clear. Some transplant professionals involved in these and other innovative living kidney donation arrangements have proceeded in the reasonable belief that these arrangements do not violate section of 301 of NOTA, but they  contend that they are doing so under a cloud.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>No Federal dollars are needed to implement this change. And, for each patient who receives a kidney, Medicare will save roughly $220,000 in the end-stage-renal disease program because of the significantly lower cost of transplantation compared to dialysis cost. It is essential that we make the intent of Congress explicit so that transplant centers which have hesitated to implement incompatible living kidney donation programs can feel free to do so.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Currently, over 97,000 people are waiting for an organ, including 72,000 who are waiting for a kidney transplant, over 2,600 of whom are in the State of Michigan, as they endure countless hours attached to a life-sustaining dialysis machine hoping that a organ donor will become available before they die. Because of the shortage of available organs, approximately 3,800 people die every year while on the waiting list for a kidney transplant. For them, time is of the essence.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last but certainly not least, the great success we have achieved here today would not have been possible without the support of my good friend and colleague in the House, Representative JOHN DINGELL chair of the House Energy and Commerce Committee and my distinguished and caring colleague in the Senate, Senator TED KENNEDY, chair of the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. In addition, there are those who energetically led the effort in educating Congress on the  need for paired donation and they have long been a progressive force in organ donation and transplantation. I thank Dr. Robert M. Merion, professor of surgery at the University of Michigan Transplant Center and secretary of the American Society of Transplant</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington University in St. Louis, MO, and president of the American Society of Transplantation, AST; Dr. David Briscoe, director of transplant research at Children's Hospital in Boston, Harvard University; Dr. David Cohen, director of kidney transplant, Columbia University; and Bill Lawrence of United Network of Organ Donor Sharing for his steadfast leadership in the cause of organ donor awareness and organ transplantation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senate passage and enactment of this legislation is a fitting tribute that honors the memory of six members of the University of Michigan Transplant Team, who died in a tragic plane crash while on an emergency mission to deliver life-saving organs to the University of Michigan Hospital to save the lives of transplant patients.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to share with my colleagues the sentiments expressed by Mary Sue Coleman, President of the University of Michigan, upon learning of the tragic loss of the six members of the University of Michigan Transplant Team. Her remarks, given on June 5, 2007, are as follows:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our hearts are broken by the devastating and irreplaceable loss of six members of the Survival Flight transplant team.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Every day, the doctors, nurses and flight personnel of Survival Flight do heroic work in saving the lives of others, and that is how we will remember those who perished in Monday's tragedy--as selfless heroes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is no greater act than that of saving a life, and through our grief, we take comfort in knowing these six men died in the service of a fellow human being.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Please hold in your hearts David Ashburn, M.D., a fellow (physician-in-training) in cardiothoracic surgery; Richard Chenault II, a transplant donation specialist with the U-M Transplant Program; Dennis Hoyes, a Marlin air pilot; Rick Lapensee, a transplant donation specialist with the U-M Transplant Program; Bill Serra, a Marlin air pilot; and Martinus (Martin) Spoor, M.D., a cardiac surgeon who had been on the U-M faculty since 2003.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our thoughts and prayers are with their families, friends and colleagues.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, I would also like to share an excerpt from a letter I received from Dr. Robert Merion regarding his cherished colleagues and friends who were members of the University of Michigan Transplant Team, as follows:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>All of my colleagues who perished in that horrible crash were committed to organ donation. In fact, the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services awarded one of them, Richard Chenault II, its Medal of Honor in 2006 for his successful efforts to increase organ donation at the University of Michigan. All six of these fine men would have been extraordinarily proud to know that their names were being invoked to stimulate final passage of a bill that will provide the gift of life to so many others.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I commend the Senate on the passage of this much-needed legislation and look forward to the President signing it in the days ahead.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <chair>The legislative clerk proceeded to call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412246" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
