<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1171515600" ordinal="61" title="STATEMENTS ON INTRODUCED BILLS AND JOINT RESOLUTIONS">
  <speaking speaker="300080" topic="Introducing S. 602. A bill to develop the next generation of parental control technology; to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="602">S. 602</bill>] Mr. President, I wish to introduce two communications bills. First, I am introducing the Child Safe Viewing Act, a bill to develop the next generation of parental control technology. Last year, following several hearings and forums on decency, I concluded that the V-Chip is not an adequate solution for parents to prevent their children from viewing adult content, especially in a world of 500 channels and video streaming.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>During the 1996 Telecommunications Act debate, President Clinton urged inclusion of a mandatory V-Chip device, and in collaboration with Congress, the FCC, and the entertainment industry, the V-Chip was born. The V-Chip was an important beginning to control child access to adult material. Over a decade has passed since the 1996 act, and the world of communications has changed. However, the issues that inspired the V-Chip continue to exist today for not only television but for the Internet and  other video streaming devices.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Child Safe Viewing Act is a pragmatic approach to addressing the pitfalls of video content not intended for kids, and it acts on current law. It simply directs the Federal Communications Commission to begin a proceeding on the requirements in section 551 of the V-Chip law. Section 551 states that the Commission shall take action on alternative blocking technology as it is developed. This mandate is clear and the time has come. We must engage in this issue now to ensure that families have  the tools to keep inappropriate and sometimes dangerous material out of their children's view.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am also introducing ED 1.0, a bill to advance online higher education opportunities for minorities. Last Congress, Senator Allen and I introduced a bill that would establish a digital and wireless network technology program for minority-serving institutions, and it was reported favorably by the Commerce Committee. Regrettably, I am concerned that the cost of the bill will prohibit it from moving in this Congress. But the needs to this Nation's minorities are not standing still.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>ED 1.0 would allow some of our goals to move forward now by creating a pilot online degree program at four minority-serving institutions. African-American, Hispanic, and tribal serving colleges and universities in socially and economically disadvantaged areas would be eligible to participate in this program to help define what works in ensuring that minorities are obtaining higher education degrees.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With the high costs of networks and limited availability of resources, the program would provide a national "lessons learned" about how to develop and implement flexible degree programs in fields such as health or education, which are currently underserved in the disadvantaged community. The goals of ED 1.0 will make education a reality for thousands of Americans, and I hope this bill will have the support of my colleagues.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300064" topic="Introducing S. 604. A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to limit increases in the certain costs of health care services under the heaalth care programs of the Department of Defense, and for the purposes; to the Committee on Armed Services.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="604">S. 604</bill>] Mr. President, I rise to introduce the Military Health  Care Protection Act along with my colleagues, Senators HAGEL, KERRY, and LINCOLN.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This important legislation will keep the Pentagon from dramatically raising health care fees on active duty military personnel, National Guard, Reserves, retirees and their families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our bill will limit increases to TRICARE military health insurance enrollment fees, deductibles, and pharmacy co-payments for those military retirees who are enrolled in TRICARE. Under this legislation, increases in these health care fees cannot exceed the rate of growth in uniformed services beneficiaries' military compensation, thereby protecting beneficiaries from an undue financial burden.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our bill will also cap increases to TRICARE military health insurance pharmacy co-payments at current levels for those active duty military personnel, National Guard, Reserves members, and their families. Under this legislation, increases in such fees also cannot exceed the rate of growth in uniformed services beneficiaries' military compensation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Just last week, the Department of Defense (DOD) submitted its Fiscal Year 2008 budget to Congress. Within that budget, a cut of $1.86 billion was made to TRICARE out of the Defense Health Program budget. Such a cut would require a doubling of fees on senior enlisted retirees and a tripling of such fees for officer retirees. This would mean increases of up to $1,000 annually for some military retirees. While the Department of Defense temporarily halted plans to raise fees last year at the direction  of Congress, we are again faced with this challenge. We must pass legislation now that limits the amount of any health care increase and protects beneficiaries from extreme health care fee increases in the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With this bill, Senator Hagel and I reiterate our commitment to our troops and future veterans by assuring them that just as they protected us, we will take care of them when their service ends.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last year, Congress rejected the same increases that the Pentagon is proposing again for this year. I ask the support of my colleagues to pass this legislation this year to prevent these significant increases permanently.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300018" topic="Introducing S. 605. A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to promote and improve the allied health professions; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="605">S. 605</bill>] Mr. President, early in the 109th Congress I introduced a bill to address the troubling shortage of allied health professionals in our country. Sadly, we were unable to act on this bill despite continuing deficiencies in the health care workforce. That is why, today, I am reintroducing the Allied Health Reinvestment Act, along with my good colleagues, Senators BINGAMAN, BOXER, KENNEDY, LANDRIEU, LIEBERMAN, LINCOLN, MIKULSKI, and MURRAY. </paragraph>
    <paragraph>Allied health professionals constitute roughly one third of the American healthcare workforce. These individuals take x-rays, perform lab tests, and provide emergency services. They help rehabilitate the injured, manage health records, and ensure patients are eating right. Allied health professionals are responsible for a critical and diverse array of functions, working with doctors and nurses to keep patients healthy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The allied health professions recognized in this bill include professionals in the areas of: dental hygiene, dietetics/nutrition, emergency medical services, health information management, clinical laboratory sciences/medical technology, cytotechnology, occupational therapy, physical therapy, radiologic technology, nuclear medical technology, rehabilitation counseling, respiratory therapy, and speech language-pathology/audiology. This is by no means a complete list of allied health professions,  which is why the Secretary of Health and Human Services will have the authority to determine additional professions that can benefit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, many allied health professions suffer from existing workforce shortages. The American Hospital Association (AHA) reports vacancy rates of 18 percent for radiology technicians, 15.3 percent for imaging technicians, and 12.7 percent for pharmacy technicians. In my State alone, the Washington State Hospital Association reports vacancy rates of 14.3 percent for ultrasound technologists, 11.3 percent for radiology technicians, and 10.9 percent for nuclear medicine technologists.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These shortages have real consequences for patients, often extending wait times for important test results or routine examinations. Every time I meet with hospital officials in my State, I always learn how patient care is hurt by the lack of available healthcare workers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enrollment figures in allied health education programs suggest we will not have the individuals available to meet the challenges created by existing shortages. The Association of Schools of Allied Health Professionals (ASAHP) reports in a 2006 survey of 87 member institutions that enrollment for a number of allied health programs have not reached capacity for the seventh straight year. The Institutional Profile Survey, which the ASAHP conducts every year, shows under-enrollment by 55 percent  in dietetics, 54 percent in health administration, 49 percent in rehabilitation counseling, 43 percent in health information management, 38 percent in speech language pathology/audiology, 33 percent in emergency medical sciences, 26 percent in nuclear medicine technology, 25 percent in clinical laboratory sciences/medical technology, and 20 percent in cytotechnology.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These rates cannot continue. On top of existing workforce shortages, our health system faces a growing senior population, a group that typically requires more care. The U.S. Census Bureau reports that the section of our population age 65 and over will begin to rapidly increase in 2011 when the first of the baby boom generation reaches age 65. This increase will create greater demand on all sectors of the healthcare workforce.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill my colleagues and I introduce today, like the Nurse Reinvestment Act in the 107th Congress, intends to provide incentives for individuals to seek and complete high-quality allied health education and training.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill offers allied health education, practice, and retention grants. Education grants will be used to expand enrollment in allied health education programs, especially by underrepresented racial and ethnic minority students, and provide educational opportunities through new technologies and methods, including distance-learning. Practice grants will establish or expand allied health practice arrangements in non-institutional settings to demonstrate methods that will improve access to primary  health care in rural areas and other medically underserved communities. Retention grants will promote career advancement for allied health personnel.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Grants will also be made available for health care facilities to enable them to carry out demonstrations of models and best practices in allied health for the purpose of developing innovative strategies or approaches for retention of allied health professionals. These grants will be awarded in a variety of geographic regions to a range of different types of facilities, including those in rural, urban, and suburban areas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Furthermore, this bill will give the Secretary of HHS, acting through the Administrator of HRSA, the authority to enter into an agreement with any institution that offers an eligible allied health education program to establish and operate a faculty loan fund to increase the number of qualified allied health faculty. Loans may be granted to faculty pursuing a full-time course of study or, at the discretion of the Secretary, a part-time course of study in an advanced degree program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, the Allied Health Reinvestment Act will establish a scholarship program modeled after the National Health Service Corps that provides scholarships to individuals seeking allied health education in exchange for service by those individuals in rural and other medically underserved areas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Allied Health Reinvestment Act represents a serious commitment on our part to confront a problem that will only grow more serious in the future. Our system of care cannot operate without the dedicated allied health professionals working today, and we must take the actions necessary to ensure that there is a strong workforce that can serve in the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="Introducing S. 606. A bill to improve Federal contracting and procurement by eliminating fraud and abuse and improving competition in contracting and procurement and by enhancing administration of Federal contracting personnel, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="606">S. 606</bill>] I am proud to cosponsor this bill, which will create new and better tools to combat fraud, waste, and abuse in government contracting. I commend our chief sponsor, Senator BYRON DORGAN, for his leadership on this.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Waste, fraud, and abuse in the name of defense is destructive and offensive, and it should never be tolerated. It saps critical resources needed by our troops, and it plays the taxpayers for fools, all the while hiding under the cover of national defense.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Within the last few weeks, the Special Inspector General for Iraq Reconstruction has reported that the problems of waste, fraud, and abuse continue to plague our reconstruction efforts in Iraq, and billions of dollars are unaccounted for, and possibly lost, to fraud and waste. So far, the Inspector General has initiated more than 100 investigations into this fraud and abuse, but to date the Department of Justice has prosecuted just a few individuals for wrongdoing. The Department has yet to prosecute  any of the contracting companies or their senior officials for fraud.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislative reform package establishes new criminal penalties for war profiteers and cheats who, for ill-gotten gain, would exploit the chaos of war. I recently introduced the War Profiteering Prevention Act of 2007, and I am pleased that Senator Dorgan has included this legislation in the Honest Leadership and Accountability in Contracting Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation also promotes openness and fairness in contracting, and it includes safeguards to end cronyism and eliminate conflicts of interest in contracting decisions. It also strengthens the Federal protections afforded to whistleblowers who alert the public to contract fraud and misconduct.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have introduced antiwar profiteering legislation in the past, but the Republican-led Congress has repeatedly refused to pass it. While Congress has waited to act, we have learned that private contractors have stolen and defrauded, by some estimates, hundreds of millions of dollars from money that should have supported our troops in Iraq and Afghanistan. The time to stop these shameful acts is now, and Congress should act swiftly to enact this vital legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I will continue my efforts on this issue as chairman of the Judiciary Committee. In particular, I plan to hold a hearing next month on the war profiteering bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Every penny of our taxpayers' money must be protected from waste, and Federal contracts--which are paid for with taxpayer funds--should be open and transparent. This is an accountability bill, and taxpayers deserve this to be one of our highest priorities.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="Introducing S. 608. A bill to improve the allocation of grants through the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="608">S. 608</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to introduce legislation that ensures our Nation's homeland security grant resources are allocated in the most effective manner possible. I am pleased to be joined by my colleague from Texas, Senator JOHN CORNYN, as well as Senators BOXER, HUTCHISON, LAUTENBERG, SCHUMER, CLINTON, MENENDEZ, and OBAMA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Simply put, the current system for allocating homeland security grants to States is fundamentally flawed. Proportionate funding is not allotted to regions which face the highest risk of a terrorist attack, and adequate assessment of threats is not calculated.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The "Risk-Based Homeland Security Grants Act of 2007" addresses these  concerns with a common-sense approach that responsibly directs taxpayer dollars to protect our Nation's vital interests.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The methodology is straightforward and spelled out in the language at the beginning of the bill:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure that homeland security grants are allocated based on an assessment of threat, vulnerability, and consequence to the maximum extent practicable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This direction would apply to the four major first-responder grant programs administered by the Department of Homeland Security: the State Homeland Security Grant Program; the Urban Area Security Initiative; the Law Enforcement Terrorism Prevention Program; and the Citizens Corps Program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The primary objective of the legislation is accomplished by reducing the amount of funding that each State is guaranteed. Current practice requires a "small state minimum," giving each State at least 0.75 percent of much of the grant funding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The result is that roughly 38 percent of the funds are marked for distribution before any substantive risk analysis has been performed. That sends disproportionate money to low-risk, rural areas and territories.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For most, this outcome is not acceptable. Funding to bolster the security of our country should go to where the threat is greatest--such as seaports, airports, and national landmarks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill lowers the "small state minimum" to 0.25 percent per State. A Homeland Security Grants Board, comprised of seven top Department of Homeland Security officials, including the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Undersecretary of Information Analysis and Infrastructure Protection, is established to rank grant applications based upon risk. Three factors guide this evaluation: threat, vulnerability, and consequence.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The current system, by contrast, allocates a significant amount of funding to states based upon their population.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To ensure that grant funds are properly accounted for, and utilized within an integrated framework to enhance domestic security, grants must be designed to meet "essential" capabilities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>"Essential capabilities" refers to the ability of regions to address risks by reducing vulnerability to attacks and diminishing the consequences of such attacks by effective response.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation assures that States must demonstrate that they have a detailed, prioritized plan for emergency preparedness and resource allocation, so that Federal funds are assigned to the most effective uses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>States must then quickly distribute the Federal funds to regions and localities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The notion of risk-based allocation of homeland security grants is not novel. This is a bipartisan approach advocated by both the Bush Administration and the 9/11 Commission.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The 9/11 Commission report said: "Homeland security assistance should be based strictly on an assessment of risks and vulnerabilities."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Four years ago, President Bush signed Homeland Security Presidential Directive 8, which required the Department of Homeland Security to allocate grant funding "based on national priorities."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In April 2005, Representatives Cox and TURNER, the Chair and Ranking Member of the House Homeland Security Committee at the time, offered similar legislation to reform the grant process by reducing State minimums and allocating funds based upon risk assessments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That effort, the "Faster and Smarter Funding for First Responders Act of 2005," passed the House of Representatives as part of the Intelligence Reform bill, but was dropped in conference. This bill is based on the House efforts, and closely tracks the previous bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, the House has acted, passing legislation last month, by an overwhelming vote of 299-128, to implement the recommendations of the 9/11 Committee. A key component is the risk-based allocation of homeland security resources.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill, though updated to reflect recent changes at the Department of Homeland Security, marks the continuation of a legislation effort we began last session, with the FORWARD Funding Act. That bill was unsuccessful. Hopefully, this time will be different.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the post-Cold War world, America needs the flexibility to defend against a different type of enemy. The amorphous nature of the threat and likelihood of asymmetric attacks demands a robust approach.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But our resources are limited, and difficult choices must be made.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We will never know exactly how, when or where the next major attack may occur. But we can refine our risk-assessment capabilities, and make objective analyses and predictions. It follows that our resources should be directed based upon our best estimate of where the next strike might take place.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Two guiding principles--the ability to predict future attacks, coupled with the necessity of utilizing finite resources effectively--form the backbone of a comprehensive strategy to make our Nation more secure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The approach is three-pronged: risks of potential terrorist attacks must be accurately assessed; the vulnerability of critical infrastructure and potential targets must be measured; and, resources should be dispersed based upon these assessments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Department of Homeland Security was created to accomplish these goals. Yet we find again and again that scarce resources are allocated based on factors unrelated to real security.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For example, last year California's Urban Area Security Initiative grants totaled only $6.81 per capita. Hawaii received $11.55 per capita, and Wyoming, $18.06 per capita.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I recognize the environment in which we are operating, and understand this bill is not a panacea. This bill is a first step towards reducing the threat of terrorist attacks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress should not act alone. The Department of Homeland Security must embrace the concept of risk-based allocation of resources. And it must act on these principles. Slow progress has been made, but the Department's intelligence analysis and vulnerability assessment capabilities must be improved.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We can do better. We must put aside pork-barrel politics and take action to protect all Americans. The security of our Nation hangs in the balance and we cannot afford to wait until it is too late.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill was conceived and put forth in the spirit of bipartisanship. I hope that Senators LIEBERMAN and COLLINS will accept this legislation, which is a reasoned alternative to their approach and a starting point for continued discussion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask my colleagues to join me in supporting this simple, straightforward approach to effectively distribute our Nation's resources and make America secure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300027" topic="Introducing S. 608. A bill to improve the allocation of grants through the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today to join with my colleague, Sen. Dianne Feinstein of California, and several of our distinguished colleagues in introducing The Risk-Based Homeland Security Grants Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator Feinstein, myself, and other Senators have been working now for several years on changing how our homeland security dollars are distributed throughout the country. Some have been talking about the need for a risk-based allocation of assistance as long as the Department of Homeland Security has been in existence. Throughout these debates, Senator Feinstein has been a tireless advocate in this effort, and I would like to thank her for her fine leadership and collaboration  in crafting this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The attacks on our country on September 11, 2001 were unprecedented in our history, and they brought with them the need for similarly unprecedented security measures. Our Nation needed to respond quickly to the devastation that day delivered to our country, so the Federal Government created a system that worked to raise overall national emergency preparedness to ensure we could better guard against another such terrorist attack.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And so, we embarked on the task of shoring up our airline, transportation, border, and port security. We worked to protect our critical infrastructure, to protect our cyber security, our agriculture and food-supply systems.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But taxpayer dollars are not limitless, and Congress must work to ensure every penny be directed where it will do the most good. It is imperative that we guard the places across our Nation where terrorists are most likely to strike, and where such strikes could do the most damage to our people, our government, and our national economy. We believe this is the most responsible way to prepare for any future attack.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We need to have a system that will protect our most vulnerable assets and populations--one that recognizes the need to protect the critical infrastructure and vital components of our national economy. I am reminded of this often when I travel around my home State of Texas. Recently, I met with officials and business leaders from Houston and Southeast Texas and discussed their homeland security needs. Their needs are enormous considering the vast amount of critical infrastructure and energy facilities  in and among large population centers. The potential consequences of a terrorist attack on any of these facilities would be devastating, not only to the local communities, but to the economic engine of the whole country. Unfortunately, we got a small taste of effects of a disaster along America's energy coast during the storms of 2005--hurricanes Katrina and Rita.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation that Senator Feinstein and I are proposing would require that Federal Homeland Security funds be allocated to States according to a risk-based assessment. It is vital that we better allocate our limited resources to the vulnerable places in the country we most need to protect, and that that these funds are distributed in an efficient and timely manner.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since we began this effort, I am pleased that there has been progress made. The considerations of threat, vulnerability, and consequence have been incorporated into more homeland security programs. But I'm concerned that we haven't done enough. And I'm concerned that our homeland security dollars are being treated as a pie in which all States get to claim a piece, regardless of risk.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This approach is inconsistent if we truly evaluate the 9/11 Commission recommendations. They clearly call for allocation of money based on an assessment of risks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our legislation provides for a distribution formula for homeland security grants based on risk, which considers three main criteria: threat, vulnerability, and consequence. It requires States to quickly pass on Federal funds to areas where they are most needed. It provides greater flexibility in using the funds, allowing a State to use them for other hazards consistent with federally established capability standards. And it allows States to retain authority to administer grant programs, but there  are penalties for states that do not pass funds to local governments within 45 days, and if a State fails to pass the funds through, local governments may petition the Department of Homeland Security to receive the funds directly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is our hope and intent that, by introducing this bill, we can positively contribute and enrich the public discourse on this critical issue, and help move the Nation toward a more rational and effective distribution of our homeland security resources.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Continuing to spread Homeland Security funds throughout the Nation--irrespective of the actual risk to particular states and communities--would be to ignore much of what we have learned as part of our effort to assess our vulnerabilities since the attacks of September 11. So I would urge that we swiftly work to pass this legislation, to better ensure the safety of our citizens.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300084" topic="Introducing S. 609. A bill to amend section 254 of the Communications Act of 1934 to provide that funds received as universal service contributions and the universal service support programs established pursuant to that section are not subject to certain provisions of title 31, United States Code, commonly known as the Antideficiency Act; to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="609">S. 609</bill>] Mr. President, today I join with my colleagues, Senator OLYMPIA SNOWE and Vice-Chairman TED STEVENS, to re-introduce the Antideficiency Act to protect the Universal Service Program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a bipartisan effort to ensure that all of the fundamental universal service program can continue to operate smoothly and effectively. Last year, this legislation garnered the support of 55 members, and I hope that it will gain additional support in the 110th Congress. It is also important to note that the House also has a similar bipartisan legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For many years, I have fought hard for universal service, including the E-Rate. It is essential for all of the universal service programs to operate in a timely manner.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Universal Service Fund is accomplishing its mission. Our country has a strong telecommunications network, and rural customers are getting service at affordable rates. Lifeline and Linkup programs help the poorest of customers keep basic telephone access which is essential in our modern world. Rural health care is helping connect our rural clinics to modern medicine and specialists.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over the past decade, the E-Rate discounts have helped to connect our classrooms and our libraries to the Internet and modern technology. In 1996, when the Telecommunications Act passed, only 14 percent of classrooms were connected, and just 5 percent of the poorest classrooms were connected. The latest data is encouraging with 93 percent of all classrooms connected and 89 percent of the poorest classrooms connected. Since 1998, West Virginia schools and libraries have received over $70 million  in E-Rate discounts. While this is extraordinary success, the need for E-Rate discounts remains because schools and libraries  face monthly telecommunication costs and Internet access fees. Every school and library will periodically need to upgrade its internal connections.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation gives the Universal Service Fund a permanent exemption from the Antideficiency Act. Over the last few years, we have done one year exemptions. It makes good sense to enact a long term solution for the Universal Service Fund.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="610">S. 610</bill>] Mr. President, today, I am introducing a bill to change an unfair administrative decision that hurts aging, retired VA nurses. This bill is designed to correct a problem from legislation enacted in 2001, to help VA nurses' retirement. That legislation improved nurses' pensions, and Congress intended it to be retroactive. Unfortunately, administrative officials took a very narrow view of that law. Currently VA nurses, who retired between 1986 and 2002, do not get the full pension  benefits as current retirees do.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the 1980s, VA aggressively recruited nurses to fill a huge need at VA medical centers by promising full retirement for part-time work. At the time, nurses joined the VA, and they believed in the promise.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sadly, the VA and the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) will not fulfill that promise. This legislation would explicitly require the Federal Government to honor its commitment to our retired VA nurses. Pension benefits are a vital promise. It is disturbing when we do not fulfill our obligations, and we simply must correct this error.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nurses play a critical role in our health care system, including the VA. Recruiting and retaining nurses is important, and this pension shortfall does not help. It is time to deliver full pension benefits to the retired nurses who cared for our veterans, but sadly retired in the wrong years, between 1986 and 2002.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300070" topic="Introducing S. 613. A bill to enhance the overseas stabilization and reconstruction capabilities of the United States Government, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Foreign Relations.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="613">S. 613</bill>] Mr. President, this legislation authorizes the creation of a civilian readiness corps to address post-conflict situations and other emergencies overseas. The Senate already embraced the creation of such a corps when it unanimously passed <bill type="s" number="3322">S. 3322</bill> last June. Unfortunately, that bill, introduced by Senator Biden and me and co-sponsored by Senators Hagel, Alexander and Warner languished in the House of Representatives. We have hopes that the 110th Congress  will now bring this idea to fruition.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In his State of the Union address last month, the President endorsed the need for such a corps:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>"A second task we can take on together is to design and establish a volunteer Civilian Reserve Corps. Such a corps would function much like our military reserve. It would ease the burden on the Armed Forces by allowing us to hire civilians with critical skills to serve on missions abroad when American needs them. It would give people across America who do not wear the uniform a chance to serve in the defining struggle of our time." President Bush, January 23, 2007, State of the Union speech,  Washington, DC.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation I am introducing today is an updated version of <bill type="s" number="3322">S. 3322</bill>. It is the result of a conversation begun in 2003 between Members of the Senate Foreign Relations Committee and the leadership of the State Department. The concept has gone through a number of evolutions and has passed the Committee unanimously both as a free-standing bill and as part of the State Department authorization bill. I am asking the Senate to pass it now again as a free-standing bill and send it to the House with  our unanimous approval.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>International crises are inevitable, and in most cases, U.S. national security interests will be threatened by sustained instability. The war on terrorism necessitates that we not leave nations crumbling and ungoverned. We have already seen how terrorists can exploit nations afflicted by lawlessness and desperate circumstances. They seek out such places to establish training camps, recruit new members, and tap into a global black market in weapons.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In this international atmosphere, the United States must have the right structures, personnel, and resources in place when an emergency occurs. A delay in our response of a few weeks, or even days, can mean the difference between success and failure. Clearly we need a full range of tools to prevail. Our Committee's focus has been on boosting the civilian side of our stabilization and reconstruction capabilities, while encouraging improved mechanisms for civilian and military agencies to work  together on these missions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Those who were once unconvinced of the need for such a corps have only to look at our experience in Iraq and Afghanistan to understand its value.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation continues to build on the original legislation, <bill type="s" number="2127">S. 2127</bill>, that Senators Biden and Hagel and I introduced in early 2004 to encourage and support a well-organized, sufficiently resourced and strongly led civilian counterpart to the military in post-conflict zones. It is our view that the civilian side needs both operational capability and a significant surge capacity. This legislation gives statutory status to the State Department's Office of the Coordinator of  Reconstruction and Stabilization and makes the position of Coordinator subject to the advice and consent of the Senate. The legislation authorizes the establishment of a federal response capability with both active and standby components, as well as a civilian reserve that draws upon the talent and willingness to serve that resides</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The State Department has made progress through the Office of the Coordinator of Reconstruction and Stabilization that was established in July of 2004. The Office has already done a great deal of the preliminary work needed to build an effective corps. But now it is time for the Office to recruit, train, and organize the corps so that we have deployable units.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We need to have a 250-person active duty component made up of State Department and USAID employees. We need a 2,000 person standby component drawn from both State and USAID, but also from other Federal agencies that have employees who are willing to volunteer and have the necessary skill sets. And we need to begin building a civilian reserve, recruiting at least 500 highly skilled persons and eventually many more.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The 250-person active duty personnel should include people with skills that are more technical than the broader diplomatic requirements--civil engineering, police expertise, agricultural knowledge, health, education, and political organization. They should have experience in difficult situations overseas and be trained and available for rapid deployment with the military for both initial assessments and programming purposes. They would be the first civilian team on the ground in post-conflict  situations, probably well in advance of the establishment of an embassy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Such a 250-person corps would be no larger than a typical army company. But it would be a force multiplier. It would be equipped with the authority and training to take broad operational responsibility for stabilization missions. Establishment of such a corps is a modest investment when seen as part of the overall national security budget. Even in peace time, we maintain active duty military forces of almost 1.4 million men and women who train and plan for the possibility of war. Given how critical  post conflict situations have been to American national security in the last decade, I believe it is reasonable to have a mere 250 civilians who are training for these situations and are capable of being deployed anywhere in the world, at any time they may be needed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress must now be willing to provide the funding to make this corps a reality. This legislation authorizes a $75 million crisis response fund to be made available as a contingency for stabilization and reconstruction crises. Of this amount, the administration is authorized to spend $25 million for the organization, training, and emergency deployment of the response corps. This legislation authorizes the crisis response fund and $80 million for the operations of the new State Department office  and the active duty component, including training, equipment, and travel.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have a long way to go in creating the kind of robust civilian capacity that we need. Both the State Department and the Defense Department are keenly aware of the importance of this legislation. If we cannot plan better as a government, the United States may come to depend even more on our military for tasks and functions far beyond its current role. But I remain optimistic that we can build on the progress already made to create a strong and reliable civilian component that boosts our stabilization  and reconstruction capabilities. Passing this legislation once again will demonstrate that there is a keen understanding in the Senate that we need to move forward. It will support executive branch actions already taken and encourage further progress. We hope that our friends in the House of Representatives, several of whom are considering introducing their own legislation, will move forward with the Senate in this endeavor. I urge adoption of this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300064" topic="Introducing S. 615. A bill to provide the nonimmigrant spouses and children of nonimmigrant aliens who perished in the September 11, 2001, terrorist attacks an opportunity to adjust their status to that of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence, and for other purposes; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="615">S. 615</bill>] Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the full text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="Introducing S. 616. A bill to promote health care coverage parity for individuals participating in legal recreational activities or legal transportation activities; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="616">S. 616</bill>] Mr. President, I am pleased to join with my colleague from Wisconsin, Senator FEINGOLD, in introducing legislation to prohibit health insurers from denying benefits to plan participants if they are injured while engaging in legal recreational activities like skiing, snowmobiling, or horseback riding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Among the many rules that were issued at the end of the Clinton administration was one that was intended to  ensure non-discrimination in health coverage in the group market. This rule was issued jointly on January 8, 2001, by the Department of Labor, the Internal Revenue Service and the Health Care Financing Administration--now the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services--in accordance with the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act,  HIPAA, of 1996.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While I was pleased that the rule prohibits health plans and issuers from denying coverage to individuals who engage in certain types of recreational activities, such as skiing, horseback riding, snowmobiling or motorcycling, I am concerned that it would allow insurers to deny health benefits for an otherwise covered injury that results from participation in these activities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The rule states that "While a person cannot be excluded from a plan for engaging in certain recreational activities, benefits for a particular injury can, in some cases, be excluded based on the source of the injury." A plan could, for example, include a general exclusion for injuries sustained while doing a specified list of recreational activities, even though treatment for those injuries--a broken arm, for instance--would have been covered under the plan if the individual had tripped and  fallen.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of this loophole, an individual who was injured while  skiing or running could be denied health care coverage, while someone who is injured while drinking and driving a car would be protected.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This clearly is contrary to Congressional intent. One of the purposes of HIPAA was to prohibit plans and issuers from establishing eligibility rules for health coverage based on certain health-related factors, including evidence of insurability. To underscore that point, the conference report language stated that "the inclusion of evidence of insurability in the definition of health status is intended to ensure, among other things, that individuals are not excluded from health care coverage  due to their participation in activities such as motorcycling, snowmobiling, all-terrain vehicle riding, horseback riding, skiing and other similar activities." The conference report also states that "this provision is meant to prohibit insurers or employers from excluding employees in a group from coverage or charging them higher premiums based on their health status and other related factors that could lead to higher health costs."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. PRESIDENT, millions of Americans participate in these legal and common recreational activities which, if practiced with appropriate precautions, do not significantly increase the likelihood of serious injury. Moreover, in enacting HIPAA, Congress simply did not intend that people would be allowed to purchase health insurance only to find out, after the fact, that they have no coverage for an injury resulting from a common recreational activity. If this rule is allowed to stand, millions of  Americans will be forced to forgo recreational activities that they currently enjoy lest they have an accident and find out that they are not covered for needed care resulting from that accident.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation that we are introducing today will clarify that individuals participating in activities routinely enjoyed by millions of Americans cannot be denied access to health care coverage or health benefits as a result of their activities. The bill should not be controversial. In fact, it passed the Senate by unanimous consent at the end of the 108th Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am therefore hopeful that we will be able to move quickly on this legislation this year, and I urge all of my colleagues to join us as cosponsors.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300090" topic="Introducing S. 617. A bill to make the National Parks and Federal Recreational Lands Pass available at a discount to certain veterans; to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="617">S. 617</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to introduce the Veterans Eagle Parks Pass Act. This legislation would provide admission to any Federal park that charges an admissions fee by creating a "Veterans Eagle Pass" for honorably discharged veterans. I am pleased to continue the efforts of my colleague Congressman THOMAS REYNOLDS, who performed yeoman's work to introduce and push forward this legislation in the House of Representatives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Currently, an annual America the Beautiful lands pass is available to anyone for eighty dollars. My legislation would allow honorably discharged veterans to buy an annual pass for only ten dollars. I feel very strongly that those who fought so hard to protect our great nation should have better and easier access to its public lands. It is only fitting to offer our veterans improved entrance to America's great public lands like Yosemite National Park in California, Fort Sumter National Monument  in South Carolina, Arthur R. Marshall Loxahatchee National Wildlife Refuge in Florida, and Crater Lake National Park in my home State of Oregon.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>America's terrain is diverse, from flat plains to high mountains, raging rivers to still lakes. Our country is truly bountiful. Many veterans are avid outdoorsmen and understand the value and quality of our land. In a time of such turmoil abroad, I see no more appropriate opportunity to reward our veterans for their commitment and service to our nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am pleased that this legislation has received the support of the American Legion, AMVETS, and Veterans of Foreign Wars. We owe it to our veterans to provide them with this service.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="Introducing S. 618. A bill to further competition in the insurance industry; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="618">S. 618</bill>] Mr. President, so people understand. I know the Senator from Pennsylvania has spoken briefly about this and had remarks on it printed in the Record.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our Nation's competition laws are powerful tools to ensure that consumer welfare is the benchmark of fair and accountable industry practices. These competition laws are what make businesses work in America. The vast majority of the companies doing business in the United States are subject to our antitrust laws. Consumers benefit from lower prices, more choices, better services.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are only a few industries that operate outside the Federal antitrust laws. The bipartisan measure I have introduced would end the insurance industry's exemption from the requirement of those laws. I am joined in this effort, as I said before, by the ranking member of the Senate Judiciary Committee. Senator Specter has a strong record of supporting effective competition in every industry through our antitrust laws. Of course, as I have also said, I am joined by the majority leader  and by Senator Lott, who is the deputy Republican leader.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator Lott probably wishes he was not in this position, but he represents many of the gulf coast residents who can speak personally and painfully to the abuses that insurers can wreak on their policyholders. The insurance industry's practices affect us all. Perhaps nowhere has the industry and its practices come under as much scrutiny as along the gulf coast in the wake of hurricanes Katrina and Rita. Insurers have been too often denying claims and delaying payments to residents along  the gulf coast instead of honoring their contractual commitments. The behavior of insurers in Mississippi has been so outrageous that the State's attorney general recently convened a grand jury to investigate some of the practices.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It seems to me, insurance companies are very eager to collect premiums when times are good but reluctant to compensate policyholders when tragedy strikes. Senator Lott knows all too well the difficulties his constituents have had with insurers. His State was hit hard by Hurricane Katrina. I commend the Senator from Mississippi for his tireless efforts in trying to ensure resources are in place to rebuild. I know he is joined in that effort by his colleague from Mississippi, Senator Cochran.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have worked with others to support efforts to rebuild the Gulf Coast. Most recently, I was pleased to assist Senator Landrieu in her successful efforts to convince the Attorney General to dispatch additional law enforcement to the New Orleans region.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>People in the gulf coast are Americans. They are our fellow citizens. They have been utterly failed by a woefully unprepared Government, and they should not also be bullied and neglected by insurance companies in their time of need.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The insurance industry has operated largely beyond the reach of Federal  antitrust laws for more than six decades. Assuming there ever was a justification to exempt insurers from Federal Government oversight, I find it hard to believe there is still a reason to exempt them--not in the age of instant communication, the age of the Internet, or the ability to compare not only risks but payments. In fact, we need real oversight, which can be brought about  by removing them from the antitrust exemption. We deserve confidence that the industry is not engaging in the most egregious forms of anticompetitive conduct, such as price-fixing, agreements not to pay, or market allocation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Antitrust laws are the beacon of good competition policy. Insurers may object to being subject to the same antitrust laws as everyone else, but why shouldn't they be subject to the same laws as every other company in this country? If they are operating in an honest and appropriate and open way, they have nothing to fear.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have more on this, but I ask unanimous consent that my full statement be placed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the Record as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="Introducing S. 618. A bill to further competition in the insurance industry; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, to reiterate, our Nation's competition laws are powerful tools to ensure that consumer welfare is the benchmark for fair and accountable industry practices. The vast majority of the companies doing business in the United States are subject to the strictures of the antitrust laws, and consumers benefit through lower prices, more choices, and better services. Only a few industries operate outside the federal antitrust laws, and I am pleased to introduce today a bipartisan  measure that will end the insurance industry's exemption from the requirements of those laws.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am joined in this effort by the ranking member of the Senate Judiciary Committee who has a strong record of supporting effective competition in every industry through our antitrust laws. I am joined as well by Senator Reid and Senator Lott. Senator Lott represents many of the gulf coast residents who can speak personally, and painfully, to the abuses that insurers can wreak on their policy holders.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Insurance industry practices affect all of us. They affect each of our constituents; they affect every business in every state. But perhaps nowhere has the industry and its practices come under as much scrutiny as along the gulf coast in the wake of Hurricanes Katrina and Rita. Insurers have been too often denying claims and delaying payouts to residents along the gulf coast instead of honoring their contractual commitments to their customers, and thereby contributing to the rebuilding and rejuvenation  of the area.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The behavior of insurers in Mississippi has been so outrageous that the state's attorney general recently convened a grand jury to investigate certain practices. Hundreds of policyholders had to go to court to force the insurance companies to fulfill their obligations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It seems some insurance companies are eager to collect premiums when times are good, but reluctant to aid policyholders when tragedy strikes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator Lott knows all too well the difficulties his constituents have had with insurers. His state was hit hard by Hurricane Katrina, and I commend him on his tireless efforts to ensure that resources are in place to rebuild. I have worked with them in other contexts to support efforts to rebuild the gulf coast. Most recently, I was honored to have assisted Senator Landrieu in her successful efforts to convince the attorney general to dispatch additional law enforcement to  the New Orleans region.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our fellow citizens on the gulf coast who have had to cope with the devastation and destruction of the 2005 hurricanes, and who were utterly failed by their woefully unprepared government, should not also be bullied or neglected by insurance companies in their time of need--insurance companies whose business is based on compensating people after a tragic loss.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, the insurance industry has operated largely beyond the reach of federal antitrust laws for more than six decades. If there ever was, there is no longer any justification to exempt the insurance industry from federal government oversight.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Such oversight could provide confidence that the industry is not engaging in the most egregious forms of anticompetitive conduct--price fixing, agreements not to pay, and market allocations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Insurance Industry Competition Act we introduce today will simply give the Department of Justice and the Federal Trade Commission the authority to apply the antitrust laws to anticompetitive behavior by insurance companies. Our antitrust laws are the beacon of good competition policy. Competition is good for consumers and good for our economy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Insurers may object to being subject to the same antitrust laws as everyone else, but if they are operating in an honest and appropriate way, they should have nothing to fear. American consumers and American businesses rely on insurance--it is a vital part of our economy--and they have the right to be confident that the cost of their insurance, and the decisions by their insurance carriers about which claims will be paid, reflect competitive market conditions, not collusive behavior.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank Senator Reid and Senator Specter for joining me in this important effort. And I thank Senator Lott for his support, and for using the lessons of his constituents' experiences to shed light on an industry that for too long, in too many ways, has been out of the reach of federal antitrust authorities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I see the Senator from Mississippi on the floor and the Senator from Pennsylvania. If they are seeking time, I would ask how much time they need.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300069" topic="Introducing S. 618. A bill to further competition in the insurance industry; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I wish to withhold until the Senator from Pennsylvania makes his brief remarks.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="Introducing S. 618. A bill to further competition in the insurance industry; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>How much time does the Senator from Pennsylvania want? Because this is coming out of time I had set aside for something else.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300092" topic="Introducing S. 618. A bill to further competition in the insurance industry; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>Less than 5 minutes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="Introducing S. 618. A bill to further competition in the insurance industry; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>I yield 5 minutes to the Senator from Pennsylvania.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300092" topic="Introducing S. 618. A bill to further competition in the insurance industry; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I thank my distinguished colleague from Vermont.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As noted earlier, legislation was introduced in the last Congress by Senator Leahy and myself and others to deal with the problem of the McCarran-Ferguson Act. We held hearings on this matter in the Judiciary Committee. On recent matters which have evolved from Hurricane Katrina, which will be amplified by the distinguished Senator from Mississippi, Mr. Lott, there is a more pressing need to enter into this arena.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There have been various attempts over the years to limit McCarran-Ferguson, and they have not succeeded because, as amplified in a more detailed statement which I will include for the Record, there were safe harbors proposed. They became very complicated. We have provided in this legislation that the Commission decide what is to be violative of the antitrust laws, a line which has been successful on the health industry.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The economy of the United States functions much better when the antitrust laws are available and enforceable. We see a great many problems at the present time with what is happening with the sports teams. The National Football League enjoys a limited antitrust exemption, and they are proposing the Sunday ticket to DIRECTV, which has a monopoly. Cable companies can't get the Sunday ticket. They now have the Thursday to Saturday ticket. It is only on the NFL channel. I had a talk with the commissioner  of the NFL recently, who was living in New York City, and he couldn't get the Sunday ticket because his highrise wouldn't allow him to put a dish on top of the building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>May I note for the record the distinguished junior Senator from Montana is nodding in the affirmative. He lives in an area--now he is smiling. He lives in an area where you need a satellite, and his constituents do, and some of mine in Pennsylvania do, and in my home State of Kansas. Now baseball is coming along with extra innings and exclusive to DIRECTV.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The impact of the antitrust exemption on the insurance industry has been even more profound. But it is noted when we have the Federal Trade Commission authorized to issue guidelines in identifying joint practices where the antitrust concerns ought to be addressed, that is the way to approach it, as the Federal Trade Commission did in the health care industry.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think this is a significant step forward, and I am glad to see that the majority leader, Senator Reid, is behind this legislation. We can pass it out of committee, we can take it up on the Senate floor, and I think we can provide better protection for the American consumers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the full text of my statement be included in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300092" topic="Introducing S. 618. A bill to further competition in the insurance industry; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, the Insurance Industry Antitrust Enforcement Act of 2007 would subject the insurance industry to the antitrust laws which apply to almost every other industry in America. Congress enacted the McCarran-Ferguson Act in 1945  in response to a controversial Supreme Court case in which the Court held that the business of insurance constituted interstate commerce. That ruling opened the door to federal regulation of insurance, a  business that had historically been regulated and taxed by the states. McCarran-Ferguson reaffirmed the power of the states to regulate and tax insurance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In doing so, Congress exempted the insurance industry practices from antitrust scrutiny to the extent that such practices are "regulated by state law." Since then, the courts have liberally interpreted the phrase "regulated by state law." They have held that insurance industry practices are exempt from the antitrust laws so long as regulators have been given jurisdiction over the challenged practices--regardless of whether the regulators ever exercise that jurisdiction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over the years, state regulators have either chosen not to regulate, or failed to regulate, practices that would have violated the antitrust laws absent McCarran-Ferguson. With McCarran-Ferguson, such practices escape both regulatory and federal antitrust oversight. The most notorious practices to come to light involved bid-rigging and customer allocation by insurance broker Marsh &amp; McClennan and several of the nation's largest insurers. Under the scheme, Marsh steered unsuspecting clients to  insurers with which it had lucrative payoff agreements. To make the scheme work, Marsh solicited fictitious bids from other complicit insurers to make the bid submitted by the selected insurer--the one that offered Marsh the highest payoff--seem competitive.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Even though the scheme eliminated competition among the insurance companies that were involved, those companies could not be prosecuted under federal antitrust law. Several states prosecuted the insurance companies under a variety of state laws, including antitrust laws, but federal prosecutors could not bring their significant resources to bear. There simply is no justification for that. Federal law enforcement should have the power to prosecute such blatant violations of the antitrust laws.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is not the first attempt to subject the insurance industry to federal antitrust law. In the wake of numerous insolvencies, mismanagement and other misconduct by insurers in the late 1980s, legislation was introduced repealing the exemption. That legislation, introduced by Congressman Brooks, faced opposition from insurers who claimed that many industry practices engaged in jointly by insurance companies were pro-competitive and necessary for smaller insurers. The legislation provided a safe  harbor, specifically listing the practices of insurance companies that would be exempt from the antitrust laws. However, it proved impossible to craft a list of safe harbors for all the information that competing insurers claimed they needed to share with one another. This bill has avoided that problem.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>More recently, some have argued that the answer to insurance industry ills is full federal regulation. I do not necessarily believe that stripping the states of their authority to regulate the insurance industry is the answer. This bill does not do that. It allows states to continue to regulate their insurance industries. However, the existence of state regulation is no reason to prevent federal prosecutors from going after antitrust violators. And, there is no reason to prevent federal prosecutors  from going after antitrust violators just because those violators happen to work for insurance companies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As I have said, allowing federal prosecutors to go after those who violate the antitrust laws will not prevent states from regulating the insurance industry. If a state is actively supervising practices by its insurance industry that might otherwise violate the antitrust laws, this legislation would exempt that practice from the antitrust laws. Antitrust law does not generally apply where a state is actively regulating an industry. This is as it should be and the legislation I introduce today,  the Insurance Industry Antitrust Act of 2007, incorporates that standard.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Judiciary Committee held a hearing on this issue in May. During the hearing, Marc Racicot, the President of the American Insurance Association, a trade association composed of the nation's largest insurers, acknowledged that "every state provides some form of antitrust regulation of insurers." In other words, many states already enforce their state antitrust laws with respect to insurers. So, I have to ask, why have we tied the hands of federal antitrust enforcers?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The insurers will argue that repealing the antitrust exemption for insurers will create uncertainty by  throwing into question the legality of every joint practice engaged in by insurers. They will argue that the legality of each joint practice will have to be litigated in court. However, this bill has been drafted to avoid such litigation. Rather than incorporating a laundry list of safe harbors, an approach that was taken in the past, the bill would allow the Federal Trade Commission to issue guidelines identifying joint practices that do not raise antitrust concerns and would therefore not face</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a job for which the Commission is well equipped. In the past, the Commission along with the Justice Department issued "Statements of Antitrust Enforcement Policy in Health Care." The Health Care Statements identified joint conduct by health care providers that did not raise antitrust concerns and therefore would likely escape scrutiny by antitrust enforcers. The Health Care Statements were designed to give health care providers certainty about the legality of their joint conduct under  the antitrust laws. Similar guidelines for the insurance industry would provide insurers with certainty, but at the same time, would ensure that joint practices that are anticompetitive receive scrutiny from the antitrust enforcement agencies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although many insurers oppose repeal of their antitrust exemption, others support a repeal. In particular, the Antitrust Section of the American Bar Association has long supported repeal. During the Judiciary Committee's hearing, the current head of the Antitrust Section, Donald Klawiter noted the Section's nearly 20-year history of supporting repeal. Klawiter testified that "the benefits of antitrust exemptions almost never outweigh the potential harm imposed on society by the loss of competition."  At the same hearing, Robert Hunter, testifying on behalf of the Consumer Federation of America, concluded that "application of the antitrust laws to the insurance industry could result in double-digit savings for America's insurance consumers."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is my hope that this legislation will bring the benefits of competition to the insurance industry and to consumers. Too many consumers are paying too much for insurance due to the collusive atmosphere that exists in the insurance industry. This has become a particular problem along the Gulf Coast, where insurers have shared hurricane loss projections, which may result in double-digit premium increases for Gulf Coast homeowners.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I strongly urge Members who are concerned about industry exemption from the antitrust laws and collusive insurance industry practices to support this important piece of legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300069" topic="Introducing S. 618. A bill to further competition in the insurance industry; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, may I get some time under the agreement?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="Introducing S. 618. A bill to further competition in the insurance industry; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>How much time would the distinguished Senator need?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300069" topic="Introducing S. 618. A bill to further competition in the insurance industry; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>Probably 5 or 6 minutes. How much would you have left then? I don't want to eat up all your time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="Introducing S. 618. A bill to further competition in the insurance industry; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>Again, we are using time that I--Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that my time be extended by 6 minutes, and that I be allowed to yield that 6 minutes to the Senator from Mississippi.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300069" topic="Introducing S. 618. A bill to further competition in the insurance industry; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, let me say at the beginning, I appreciate the courtesy of the Senator from Vermont and his comments on our effort here; also, my colleague from Pennsylvania, Senator Specter, whom I have discussed this issue with several times over the past year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me begin at the beginning of this effort. I thank my colleagues for this bipartisan effort. It shows what we can do when we work together. Now, we have a long road to go, but this is being introduced as a bipartisan measure with leaders from both sides and leaders of the Judiciary Committee joining in cosponsoring this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>How did I get interested in this area? Well, it is like so many things in my life that go back only until August 29, 2005, when Hurricane Katrina devastated my hometown and the area of my State that I love so much, Mississippi and the gulf coast area. I had been active in years gone by actually in the insurance area. I had done some law practice in that area. I had done some defense work. But I never had become steeped in the laws that apply to the industry because most of the time I was dealing  with an automobile accident case or something of that nature.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Well, after Hurricane Katrina we learned a lot of lessons, and we found a lot of new concerns in areas where we had to take action. One of the commitments I have made to the people--and to the Senate because the Senate has been so good in helping us in our recovery effort, in changing the laws where applicable, the Stafford Act, in providing funds. But one of the commitments I made as a result of that is to make sure we take a look at what happened to us. What did we learn from Katrina? What  can we do to have more laws and the right things in place after the next natural disaster--and there will be one--or any kind of catastrophic disaster? We learned that the laws were not what they should be. They needed to be changed. We have changed them some and we need to change them some more. We learned the Federal</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We need to ask ourselves: Do we need to give some additional thought to how  we deal on a national level with the coverage of people or how we help them recover? Do we need a national catastrophic insurance program? I don't know that I am satisfied I know the answer yet, but I think we need to ask that question in advance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also found, to my absolute horror, something I should have known, which is that the insurance industry is not covered by antitrust laws. They have a waiver. I said: How could that be? I remember hearing discussion over the years about the McCarran-Ferguson Act, but I never focused on it. When I realized that ratesetting and actually policy actions by the industry were not covered by antitrust laws, I was stunned. I understand you need a lot of information to decide on rates, but that information  can be used back and forth to in effect set rates as an industry without making sure that it is not done in an anticompetitive way. Do you mean that under this exemption, that companies could collude on what actions they take or, even worse, what actions they don't take, which is what we got into after Hurricane Katrina? We had companies basically saying: Oh, no, no, you are covered by Federal flood insurance. We don't have to pay under the household policies for wind damage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So as I got into it, I found that this happened back in 1944. At that point, there was regulation of the insurance industry, but there was a case styled the United States v. South Eastern Underwriters Association which caused a change in how insurers were regulated. Then the Congress immediately acted and said: Oh, no, we are going to say that federal antitrust laws do not apply to this industry.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Soon the courts got into this issue and took a look at what happened. They looked at the record. There were no hearings in the Senate. It was passed quickly on a voice vote, and it went quickly through the House. The conference report was debated for 2 days by the Senate, and most of the debate, as I have looked at it, looks as though everybody thought this was going to be a temporary moratorium. However, that is not the way the courts have interpreted the laws.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under the McCarran-Ferguson Act, insurers are exempt from antitrust scrutiny, so long as they are regulated by State law. Then you get into a patchwork of State laws: Do the States actively regulate them? Is there a process for antitrust activities to be considered?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over the years, many have advocated the repeal of this antitrust exemption. The Judiciary Committee had hearings on this last summer. The American Bar Association's antitrust section noted that the organization for nearly 20 years has supported repeal of this exemption. Look, there is a unique role for States to deal with insurance questions and needs in those States, but my question beyond that is: Should the Federal Government have the right to make sure there are not anticompetitive activities,  to make sure there is no colluding? I think we need to take a serious look at that. This legislation would do that. It would take away that exemption. It would make the insurance industry subject to the same coverage of almost every other corporation in America: antitrust legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I know my time has expired. I thank the Chair for his leniency. I thank Senator Leahy for doing this. I look forward to having the hearings and testifying. This is wrong, Mr. President, and the Senate in a bipartisan way should, and I believe will, correct it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="Introducing S. 618. A bill to further competition in the insurance industry; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I thank my friend from Mississippi, and I am proud to be joining with him on this. He and I have discussed this several times over the past several months. I told him last fall I would join with him on such legislation, and I am proud to do so.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="Introducing S. 618. A bill to further competition in the insurance industry; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I want to express my support for the "Insurance Industry Competition Act of 2007," which repeals the well-known McCarran-Ferguson Act. McCarran-Ferguson gave States the authority to regulate the business of insurance and exempted insurance from the Federal antitrust laws. Unfortunately, McCarran-Ferguson came about as a result of a Senator from my State of Nevada, McCarran, and a Senator from Michigan, Ferguson. It was passed to give a few years of relief to the insurance  industry. In 1944, the United States Supreme Court ruled against the industry-wide practice of cooperating to set premium prices in United States v. Southeastern Underwriters Association. Insurers argued that most companies were too small to rely solely on their own</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, some 60 plus years later, insurance companies are the only businesses--other than Major League Baseball--not subject to antitrust laws. Congress began investigating the effectiveness of State insurance regulation in 1958, under the oversight of Senator O'Mahoney, who had been a principal architect of the McCarran-Ferguson Act, and found State regulation lacking, incapable of dealing with interstate and international issues, and unwilling or unable to "bring the blessings of competition"  to insurance rate-making. The same thing is true today, and its time we take action to remedy this situation. The rationale for this exemption has long since passed. Insurance should be like any other business--subject to antitrust laws.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator Leahy's bill would accomplish this. "The Insurance Industry Competition Act of 2007" would repeal the exemption and simply give the Department of Justice and the Federal Trade Commission the authority to apply the antitrust laws to anticompetitive behavior by insurance companies. Such oversight could ensure that the industry is not engaging in the most egregious forms of anticompetitive conduct--price fixing, agreements not to pay, and market allocations. This Act would not  affect the ability of each State to regulate the business of insurance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If insurers around the country are operating in an honest and appropriate way, they should not object to being answerable under the same Federal antitrust laws as virtually all other businesses. American consumers should be confident that the cost of their insurance reflects competitive market conditions, not collusive behavior, and they should benefit through lower prices, more choices, and better services.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Perhaps nowhere has the insurance industry and its practices come under as much scrutiny as along the Gulf Coast in the wake of Hurricanes Katrina and Rita. Just yesterday, the AP reported that "State Farm Insurance Cos. is suspending sales of any new commercial or homeowner policies in Mississippi starting Friday." I ask Unanimous Consent that a news article dated February 14, 2007, from the Associated Press be printed in the Record. Insurers have been too often denying claims and  delaying payouts to residents of New Orleans and all along the Gulf Coast instead of honoring their contractual commitments to their customers, and thereby contributing to the rebuilding and rejuvenation of the area. We need to act now to end this practice. I thank Senators LEAHY, SPECTER, and LOTT for their work on this important legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the article was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300042" topic="Introducing S. 620. A bill to establish a demonstration project to train unemployed workers for employment as health care professionals, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="620">S. 620</bill>] Mr. President, today I am introducing the third in a series of bills intended to support American companies and American workers. Earlier this week, I introduced a resolution which would set some minimum standards for future trade agreements into which our country enters, and legislation which would strengthen the Buy American Act. Today I am introducing legislation that would help workers who have lost their manufacturing or service sector jobs to be retrained for jobs in high-demand  health care fields. I am pleased that my colleague, Senator Mikulski, is cosponsoring this important legislation and I look forward to working with her to advance it during the 110th Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>According to statistics from the Department of Labor, Wisconsin has lost over 90,000 manufacturing jobs between January 2000 and November 2006. Nationally, the country has lost around 3 million manufacturing jobs since January 2001, yet the administration has continued to support policies that lead to the outsourcing of American jobs. I continue to be deeply troubled by the Bush Administration's contention that the outsourcing of American service sector and other jobs is good for the economy.  I am concerned about the message that this policy sends to Wisconsinites and all Americans who are currently employed in these sectors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is something of a silver lining to the looming cloud of manufacturing and other jobs loss: the country's workforce development system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In spite of stretched resources and long waiting lists for services, our workforce development boards are making a tremendous effort to retrain laid-off workers and other job seekers for new jobs. And this effort is clearly evident in Wisconsin, where my State's workforce development boards--despite shoestring budgets--are leading the way in finding innovative solutions to retraining workers for new careers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I strongly support the work of these agencies, and have urged the Administration and Senate appropriators to provide adequate funding for the job training programs authorized by the Workforce Investment Act. I look forward to the reauthorization of the Workforce Investment Act this year and I will continue to work to ensure that the workforce development boards in my state and across our country receive the resources that they need to help job seekers get the training they need to be successful.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am committed to finding resources to retrain those who have been laid off from the manufacturing and service sectors and who wish to find new jobs in high-demand fields such as health care.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As most of my colleagues know all too well, we are facing a significant shortage of health care workers. Congress has made some progress in addressing the nursing shortage, but we need to expand our efforts. Shortages of health professionals pose a real threat to the health of our communities by impacting access to timely, high-quality health care. Studies have shown that shortages of nurses in our hospitals and health facilities increase medical errors, which directly affects patient health.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As our population ages, and the baby-boomers need more health care, our need for all types of health professionals is only going to increase. This is particularly true for the field of long-term care. According to the Bureau of Labor Statistics, we are going to need an additional 1.4 million nursing aides, home health aides, and other health professionals in long-term care before the year 2014. In total, there will be almost 1.7 million job openings in health care support occupations through  2012.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As our demand for health care workers grows, so does the number of jobs available within this sector. According to the Wisconsin Department of Workforce Development, the surging job growth in health care will translate into a real need for workers, and real opportunity. In Wisconsin alone, there will be an additional 61,910 health care positions by 2014. This represents a 27 percent increase in jobs in health care by 2014.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Workforce development agencies in my home State of Wisconsin are already working to support displaced workers in their communities by training them for health care jobs, since there is a real need for workers in these fields. These agencies are helping communities get and maintain access to high-quality health care by ensuring that there are enough health care workers to care for their communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As the executive director of one of the workforce development boards in my State put it, "[t]here are simply not many good quality jobs to replace manufacturing jobs lost to rural communities. The medical professions, by offering a `living wage' and good benefits, provide an excellent alternative to manufacturing for sustaining a higher, family-oriented standard of living."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe we should support our communities in these efforts by providing them with the resources they need to establish, sustain, or expand these important programs. For that reason, today I am introducing the Community-Based Health Care Retraining Act. This bill would amend the Workforce Investment Act to authorize a demonstration project to provide grants to community-based coalitions, led by local workforce development boards, to create programs to retrain unemployed workers who wish to obtain  new jobs in the health care professions. My bill would authorize a total of $25 million for grants between $100,000 and $500,000, and, in the interest of fiscal responsibility, my legislation is fully offset.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill will help provide communities with the resources they need to run retraining programs for the health professions. The funds could be used for a variety of purposes, from increasing the capacity of our schools and training facilities, to providing financial and social support for workers who are in retraining programs. This bill allows for flexibility in the use of grant funds because I believe that communities know best about the resources they need to run an efficient program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill represents a nexus in my efforts to support workers whose jobs have been shipped overseas and to ensure that all Americans have access to the high-quality health care that they deserve. By providing targeted assistance to train laid-off workers who wish to obtain new jobs in the health care sector, we can both help unemployed Americans and improve the availability and quality of health care that is available in our communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am pleased that this bill is supported by a variety of organizations that are committed to providing high-quality job training and health care services, including: the Wisconsin Association of Job Training Executives, the Wisconsin Hospital Association, Madison Area Technical College, the Northwest Wisconsin Concentrated Employment Program, the Workforce Development Board of South Central Wisconsin, the Bay Area Workforce Development Board, the Healthcare Workforce Network, the Southwest Wisconsin  Workforce Development Board, Sauk County Development Corporation, the American Osteopathic Society, Umos, the Fox Valley Workforce Development Board, and the West Central Wisconsin Workforce Development Board.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In order to ensure that our workers are able to compete in the new economy, we must ensure that they have the tools they need to be trained or retrained for high-demand jobs such as those in the health care field. My bill is a small step toward providing the resources necessary to achieve this goal. I will continue to work to strengthen the American manufacturing sector and to support those workers who have been displaced due to bad trade agreements and other policies that have led to the loss  of American jobs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of this bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300042" topic="Introducing S. 621. A bill to establish commissions to review the facts and circumstances surrounding injustices suffered by European Americans, European Latin Americans, and Jewish refugees during World War II; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="621">S. 621</bill>] Mr. President, today I introduce the Wartime Treatment Study Act. This bill would create two fact-finding commissions: one commission to review the U.S. government's treatment of German Americans, Italian Americans, and European Latin Americans during World War II, and another commission to review the U.S. government's treatment of Jewish refugees fleeing Nazi persecution during World War II. This bill is long overdue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am very pleased that my colleagues Senators GRASSLEY, KENNEDY, LIEBERMAN and INOUYE have joined me as cosponsors of this important bill. I thank them for their support. And I thank Congressman Wexler, who has been the unflagging champion of this legislation in the House of Representatives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The victory of America and its allies in the Second World War was a triumph for freedom, justice, and human rights. The courage displayed by so many Americans, of all ethnic origins, should be a source of great pride for all Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But, at the same time that so many brave Americans fought for freedom in  Europe and the Pacific, the U.S. government was curtailing the freedom of people here at home. While, it is, of course, the right of every nation to protect itself during wartime, the U.S. Government must respect the basic freedoms for which so many Americans have given their lives to defend. War tests our principles and our values. And as our Nation's recent experience has shown,  it is during times of war and conflict, when our fears are high and our principles are tested most, that we must be even more vigilant to guard against violations of the basic freedoms guaranteed by the Constitution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many Americans are aware that during World War II, under the authority of Executive Order 9066, our government forced more than 100,000 ethnic Japanese from their homes and ultimately into internment camps. Japanese Americans were forced to leave their homes, their livelihoods, and their communities and were held behind barbed wire and military guard by their own government. Through the work of the Commission on Wartime Relocation and Internment of Civilians, created by Congress in 1980, this  shameful event finally received the official acknowledgement and condemnation it deserved. Under the Civil Liberties Act of 1988, people of Japanese ancestry who were subjected to relocation or internment later received an apology and reparations on behalf of the people of the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>February 19, 2007, is the "Day of Remembrance," the 65th anniversary of the signing of Executive Order 9066. On this day, we should remember the freedoms all of these individuals were forced to give up, and resolve never to make these mistakes again.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While I commend our government for finally recognizing and apologizing for the mistreatment of Japanese Americans during World War II, I believe that it is time that the government also acknowledge the mistreatment experienced by many German Americans, Italian Americans, and European Latin Americans, as well as Jewish refugees.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Wartime Treatment Study Act would create two independent, fact-finding commissions to review this unfortunate history, so that Americans can understand why it happened and work to ensure that it never happens again. One commission will review the treatment by the U.S. government of German Americans, Italian Americans, and other European Americans, as well as European Latin Americans, during World War II.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe that most Americans are unaware that, as was the case with Japanese Americans, approximately 11,000 ethnic Germans, 3,200 ethnic Italians, and scores of Bulgarians, Hungarians, Romanians or other European Americans living in America were taken from their homes and placed in internment camps during World War II. We must learn from this history and explore why we turned on our fellow Americans and failed to protect their basic freedoms.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A second commission created by this bill will review the treatment by the U.S. government of Jewish refugees who were fleeing Nazi persecution and genocide. We must review the facts here as well and determine how restrictive immigration policies failed to provide adequate safe harbor to Jewish refugees fleeing the persecution of Nazi Germany. It is a horrible truth that the United States turned away thousands of refugees, delivering many refugees to their deaths at the hands of the Nazi regime.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As I mentioned earlier, there has been a measure of justice for Japanese Americans who were denied their liberty and property. It is now time for the U.S. government to complete the accounting of this period in our nation's history. It is time to create independent, fact-finding commissions to conduct a full and through review of the treatment of all European Americans, European Latin Americans, and Jewish refugees during World War II.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Up to this point, there has been no justice for the thousands of German Americans, Italian Americans, and other European Americans who were branded "enemy aliens" and then taken from their homes, subjected to curfews, limited in their travel, deprived of their personal property, and, in the worst cases, placed in internment camps.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There has been no justice for Latin Americans of European descent who were shipped to the United States and sometimes repatriated or deported to hostile, war-torn European Axis powers, often in exchange for Americans being held in those countries.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, there has been no justice for the thousands of Jews, like those aboard the German vessel the St. Louis, who sought refuge from hostile Nazi treatment but were callously turned away at America's shores.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The injustices to European Americans, European Latin Americans, and Jewish refugees occurred more than fifty years ago. Americans can learn from these tragedies now, while the people who survived these injustices are still with us, and are still here to teach us. We cannot put this off any longer. If we wait, the people who were affected will no longer be here to know that Congress has at last recognized their sacrifice and resolved to learn from the mistakes of the past.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We should never allow this part of our Nation's history to repeat itself. And, while we should be proud of our Nation's triumph in World War II, we should not let that justifiable pride blind us to the treatment of some Americans by their own government.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As the Day of Remembrance approaches, I urge my colleagues to join me in supporting the Wartime Treatment Study Act, and to allow this bill to become law as soon as possible. I have been seeking to enact this legislation for six years. It is time for a full accounting of this tragic chapter in our Nation's history.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the Wartime Treatment Study Act be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="Introducing S. 621. A bill to establish commissions to review the facts and circumstances surrounding injustices suffered by European Americans, European Latin Americans, and Jewish refugees during World War II; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today I am introducing the "Competitive and Fair Agricultural Markets Act of 2007." Cosponsors joining me in introducing this legislation are: Senators ENZI, FEINGOLD, THOMAS, DORGAN, BAUCUS and  MCCASKILL. This legislation seeks to level the playing field for agricultural producers by strengthening and clarifying the Packers and Stockyards Act of 1921 and the Agricultural Fair Practices Act of 1967 and strengthening enforcement of both laws by USDA.  I intend to use this legislation as the basis for developing a proposed competition title in the new farm bill this year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Consolidation is happening in all sectors of agriculture and having a negative effect on producers and consumers across the Nation. Consolidation in itself is not a violation of the Packers and Stockyards Act, but when some entities become larger and more powerful that makes enforcement of the Packers and Stockyards Act absolutely critical for independent livestock and poultry  producers. The statistics speak for themselves. For example, today, only four  firms control 84 percent of the procurement of cattle and 64 percent of the procurement of hogs. Economists have stated that when four firms control over 40 percent of the industry, marketplace competitiveness begins to decline. Taken together with fewer buyers of livestock, highly integrated firms can exert tremendous power over the industry.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Grain Inspection, Packers and Stockyards Administration, GIPSA, at USDA has the responsibility to enforce the Packers and Stockyards Act. This Act is critical, and protects livestock producers from unfair, unjustly discriminatory and anti-competitive practices in the marketplace. For years I have had my doubts about whether USDA was serious about enforcing the Packers and Stockyards Act. In 2005, I requested an audit by USDA's Inspector General to investigate USDA's oversight, and enforcement  of the law. Last year, the Inspector General confirmed the concerns I had and uncovered even more systemic problems. The report described widespread inaction, management of the agency actively blocking employees from conducting investigations into anti-competitive behavior and a scheme to cover up the lack of enforcement by inflating the reported number of investigations conducted.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is why today, the legislation I introduce will reorganize the structure in how USDA enforces the Packers and Stockyards Act and create an office of special counsel on competition matters. The special counsel would be appointed by the President with advice and consent from the U.S. Senate. Some would argue that Senate advice and consent is not needed. However, for over five years, GIPSA failed to move competition investigations forward and no one above the level of deputy administrator at  GIPSA seemed to have any idea that any problems were going on, despite the fact I was sending letters to the Secretary of Agriculture pointing out that USDA was failing to enforce the law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the past year, GIPSA has worked in good faith to improve its enforcement activities. However, GIPSA only investigates potential violations of the law, they do not litigate and follow-through with the investigation to the end. Litigating cases is reserved only for USDA's Office of General Counsel, OGC, unless they refer it to the Department of Justice.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>USDA's Office of General Counsel has not been active on cases involving anti-competitive  practices in recent years since GIPSA was not referring cases to them. To be sure, only two cases involving anti-competitive practices were referred to OGC in 5 years. But there are concerns that OGC is not as committed to enforcing competition investigations as they should be. This lack of commitment was clearly evident last year in testimony provided by OGC Assistant General Counsel in the Trade Practices Division at a hearing by the Senate Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Concerns about OGC's attitude toward enforcing the Packers and Stockyards Act are not new. USDA's Inspector General stated in its 1997 audit that Packers and Stockyards program officials were concerned that OGC did not want to litigate competition cases "because they are complicated and time consuming" and OGC had "limited expertise" with them. In 2000, the Government Accountability Office found "disagreements" between OGC and GIPSA regarding the interpretation of the Act's competition  provisions. By combining investigation and prosecution activities into the proposed special counsel office, designated to handle competition issues, it reduces the ability for investigations to be batted back and forth within USDA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation also makes many important clarifications to the Packers and Stockyards Act. The Packers and Stockyards Act prohibits unfair, unjustly discriminatory and anti-competitive practices, but some courts have ruled that producers need to prove an impact on competition in the market in order to prevail in such cases involving unfair or deceptive practices. For example, the United States Eleventh Circuit Court of Appeals ruled that a poultry grower operation failed to prove how its case  involving an unfair termination of its contract adversely affected competition. The court indicated that the grower had to prove that their unfair treatment affected competition in the relevant market. That is very difficult to prove and was never the intent of the Packers and Stockyards Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation also modifies the Packers and Stockyards Act so that poultry growers have the same enforcement protections by USDA as livestock. Currently, it is unlawful for a livestock packer or live poultry dealer to engage in any unfair, unjustly discriminatory or deceptive practice, but USDA does not have the authority to enforce violations because the enforcement section of the law is absent of any reference to poultry. This important statutory change is long overdue. In addition, to better  reflect the integrated nature of the poultry industry, this legislation also ensures that protections under the law extend to all poultry growers, such as breeder hen and pullet operations, not just those who raise broilers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Agricultural Fair Practices Act of 1967 was passed by Congress to ensure that producers are allowed to join together as an association to strengthen their position in the marketplace without being discriminated against by handlers. Unfortunately, this act was passed with a clause that essentially abolishes the actual intent of the law. The act states that "nothing in this Act shall prevent handlers and producers from selecting their customers" and it also states that it does not "require  a handler to deal with an association of producers." This clause in effect allows handlers to think of any reason possible to not do business with certain producers, as long as the stated reason is not because they belong to an association.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I propose to expand the Agricultural Fair Practices Act to provide new needed protections for agricultural contracts. As I have mentioned earlier, consolidation in all sectors of agriculture is reducing the number of buyers of commodities and for the very few who are left, many require contracts to conduct business. With so few buyers, it increases the chances that some firms will force unfair contracts upon producers. As a result, some producers have little or no choice but to contract with  a firm with questionable practices or face leaving the industry they have known for their whole lives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment to the Agricultural Fair Practices Act requires that the contract spell out in clear language what is required by the producer. This legislation prohibits confidentiality clauses, ensuring producers the ability to share the contract with family members or a lawyer to help them make an informed decision on whether or not to sign it. This legislation also prevents companies from prematurely terminating contracts without notice when producers have made large capital investments as  a condition of signing the contract. And it only allows mandatory arbitration after a dispute arises and both parties agree to it in writing. Producers should not be forced to sign contracts with arbitration clauses thereby preventing them from seeking legal remedy in the courts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, producers deserve to have a fair and evenhanded market in which to conduct business. This legislation won't be able to turn back the clock, but it will strengthen laws and enforcement of them so that markets operate more fairly.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300087" topic="Introducing S. 623. A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for the licensing of comparable and interchangeable biological products, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="623">S. 623</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to introduce the Access to Life-Saving Medicine Act with my colleague, Senator Clinton. Recognizing the promise of generic drugs as safe and effective treatments at greatly reduced prices, I have worked for years with my colleagues in the House and the Senate to increase generic drug availability and accessibility, most notably with Senator McCain on a 2003 law. This legislation represents the next step in the availability of generic  drugs for American consumers by creating a statutory pathway for generic  versions of biotech drugs to enter the market.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While generic drugs save American consumers an estimated eight to ten billion dollars each year, American consumers have not yet reaped the full potential savings from the generic drug market. Under current law, there is no generic approval process at the Food and Drug Administration, FDA, for an entire category of drugs, even once the patents have expired. These biologic drugs, which are an expensive and growing sector of the pharmaceutical market, will obtain monopoly pricing on the market  indefinitely without the possibility of generic competitors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Drug companies that invest in the research and development of life-saving drugs, whether biological or chemical in nature, deserve to be rewarded for their work. At the same time, patients need the ability to access affordable drugs. We have created a statutory framework for chemical drugs that balances incentives for continued innovations with access to affordable drugs for patients. But, this framework has not yet expanded to biotech drugs, which are on the cutting edge of science but for which  the laws are hopelessly out of date.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now is the time to ensure that American consumers have the same access to life-saving biotech drugs that consumers have to well-known, widely used chemical drugs. Patients need to be able to afford and access their medications, and they don't care what kind of drug they have. Patients rely on biotech drugs to treat a wide array of diseases, ranging from diabetes to cancer to AIDS, but with no generic versions of biotech drugs available, these drugs can cost tens of thousands of dollars a year--too  expensive for many patients to afford. Introducing fair competition for biotech drugs is essential to make life-saving biotech treatments affordable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Access to Life-Saving Medicine Act will allow the FDA to approve generic versions of biologic drugs that have been determined to be both safe and effective. The FDA is not required to approve any generic biologics, but if the data is there, they will now have the ability to do so.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A report released earlier this year by Pharmaceutical Care Management Association estimated that the introduction of generic biotech drugs into the market could save Medicare Part B $14 billion over the next ten years. We need to embrace those potential savings and provide American consumers access to affordable biotech drugs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Moving this legislation forward and creating a statutory pathway for generic versions of biotech drugs to enter the market is one of my highest priorities in the 110th Congress. I look forward to working with my colleagues, especially Senator CLINTON, to accomplish this goal.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300022" topic="Introducing S. 623. A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for the licensing of comparable and interchangeable biological products, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I am pleased today to join with Senator Schumer to introduce the Access of Life-Saving Medicine Act. This legislation will have a dramatic impact on the rising costs of prescription drugs, which puts the squeeze on employers trying to provide health coverage for employees while turning a profit, on families struggling to make ends meet, and on our economy. We spend 16 percent of our national income on health care and prescription drugs and that number is on  the climb.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 2005, the cost of biologics grew 17.5 percent compared to the cost of traditional drugs, which increased 10 percent. According to CMS, the top 2 anemia drugs--both biologics--accounted for 17 percent of all Medicare Part B carrier drug spending, while two other biologics for rheumatoid arthritis and cancer accounted for an additional 13 percent. In 2006, the Medicare Part B program spent more than $5 billion on biologic drugs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>More than $10 billion worth of biopharmaceuticals will come off patent in the next 5 years but will continue to cost on-patent prices unless we act. Our legislation creates a pipeline for approval of safe, cost effective generic versions of these biologic drugs. Without action, the manufacturers of these biotech drugs can continue to charge monopoly prices indefinitely.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a perfect example of skyrocketing costs in health care--and a perfect opportunity to put the brakes on this overspending, which is bad for patients, businesses, and our country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>According to a report released in January by Engel &amp; Novitt to the Pharmaceutical Care Management Association, passage of this bill could save, by conservative estimates, $14 billion over the next 10 years in Medicare Part B alone.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Scientific advances over the past 20 years have made the biotechnology industry an integral part of the pharmaceutical industry, but our health care system has not kept pace. Our laws need to be updated to reflect the critical role biologics now play in treatment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Access to Life-Saving Medicine Act amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the FDA to approve abbreviated applications for biological products that are "comparable" to and "interchangeable" with previously approved biological products. And because biological products are very diverse, the Secretary has discretion on a case-by-case basis to determine what studies are necessary to establish comparability and interchangeability, and may require a clinical study or studies if necessary.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To encourage the development of substitutable products, the legislation gives the first applicant to obtain approval of an interchangeable product a period of exclusive marketing during which no other interchangeable version of the product may be approved. In order to facilitate timely access to these products, an approval may, however, be granted for a comparable version of the brand name product if it is not interchangeable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, to encourage early resolution of patent disputes which might otherwise delay competition, a patent holder must disclose relevant patents in response to a request and bring a patent infringement suit within 45 days of notice of a challenge or lose the right to certain remedies in court.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Biotech drugs hold great promise, but we break that promise when costs push treatment out of reach for American families and employers. We should bring safe, effective and affordable generic versions of these medicines to patients through passage of the Access to Life-Saving Medicine Act, saving money and lives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This issue is part of a larger challenge. It is time to develop a health care system that reflects and responds to how people are living today, that addresses the critical problems in cost, quality, and coverage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We can use what is right in health care--incredible ingenuity, leaders at the forefront of medical research, advances in technology, the best medical professionals in the world--to fix what is wrong.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Smart solutions to the vexing problems plaguing our health care system will require evidence-based--not ideologically-based--decision making.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My wonderful predecessor, Senator Moynihan, memorably said, "Everyone is entitled to his own opinion, but no one is entitled to his own facts." Well, right now, we see a lot of people who have their own facts that are not based on the evidence.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The fact is, building a pipeline for generic biologics is long overdue. Achieving this goal is a top priority for me in the HELP Committee when we consider FDA-related legislation this spring and I look forward to working with Senator Schumer and my other colleagues to get it done.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="Introducing S. 625. A bill to protect the public health by providing the Food and Drug Administration with certain authority to regulate tobacco products; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="625">S. 625</bill>] Mr. President, today, we are introducing legislation to give the Food and Drug Administration broad authority to regulate tobacco products. Congress cannot in good conscience allow the Federal agency most responsible for protecting the public health to remain powerless to deal with the enormous risks of tobacco, the most deadly of all consumer products. Health experts believe this legislation is the most important action Congress could take to protect children from this deadly addiction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a bipartisan, bicameral initiative. The bill that Senator Cornyn and I are introducing already has over 25 cosponsors. Congressman Waxman and Davis will introduce identical legislation in the House. Our bill has the support of a broad coalition of public health organizations led by the Campaign for Tobacco-Free Kids, the American Cancer Society, the American Heart Association and the American Lung Association. They all recognize the importance of enacting this  bill this year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation we are introducing today is well known. It is the same bill that passed the Senate in 2004, and that we introduced in the last Congress. However, in this new Congress, the likelihood of passage is greatly enhanced. Last November's election swept away many of the barriers to passage from prior years. We believe 2007 is the year that legislation empowering the FDA to regulate tobacco products will finally become law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We intend to move forward on the legislation quickly. I have already scheduled a hearing in the HELP Committee for February 27, and a markup is planned soon thereafter.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The stakes are vast. Four thousand children have their first cigarette every day, and one thousand become daily smokers. More than one-third of them will die prematurely from tobacco-induced diseases. Cigarettes kill well over 400,000 Americans each year. That is more lives lost than from automobile accidents, alcohol abuse, illegal drugs, AIDS, murder, and suicide combined. Congress's response to a public health problem of this magnitude is long overdue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Regulating the conduct of tobacco companies is as necessary today as it has been in years past. The facts presented in the Federal Government's landmark lawsuit against the tobacco industry demonstrate that the misconduct is substantial and ongoing. The decision of the court states: "The evidence in this case clearly establishes that Defendants have not ceased engaging in unlawful activity ..... Defendants continue to engage in conduct that is materially indistinguishable from their previous  actions, activity that continues to this day."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We must deal firmly with tobacco company marketing practices that target children and mislead the public. The Food and Drug Administration needs broad authority to regulate the sale, distribution, and advertising of cigarettes and smokeless tobacco.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The tobacco industry currently spends over $15 billion a year to promote its products. Much of that money is spent in ways designed to tempt children to start smoking, before they are mature enough to appreciate the enormity of the health risk. The industry knows that nearly 90 percent of smokers begin as children and are addicted by the time they reach adulthood.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Documents obtained from tobacco companies prove, in the companies' own words, the magnitude of the industry's efforts to trap children into dependency on their deadly product. Studies by the Institute of Medicine and the Centers for Disease Control show the substantial role of industry  advertising in decisions by young people to use tobacco products.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If we are serious about reducing youth smoking, FDA must have the power to prevent industry advertising designed to appeal to children wherever it will be seen by children. This legislation will give FDA the authority to stop tobacco advertising that glamorizes smoking to kids. It grants FDA full authority to regulate tobacco advertising "consistent with and to the full extent permitted by the First Amendment."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>FDA authority must also extend to the sale of tobacco products. Nearly every State makes it illegal to sell cigarettes to children under 18, but surveys show that those laws are rarely enforced and frequently violated. FDA must have the power to limit the sale of cigarettes to face-to-face transactions in which the age of  the purchaser can be verified by identification. This means an end to self-service displays and vending machine sales. There must also be serious enforcement efforts with real penalties for those caught selling tobacco products to children. This is the only way to ensure that children under 18 are not able to buy cigarettes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The FDA conducted the longest rulemaking proceeding in its history, studying which regulations would most effectively reduce the number of children who smoke. Seven hundred thousand public comments were received in the course of that rulemaking. At the conclusion of its proceeding, the agency promulgated rules on the manner in which cigarettes are advertised and sold. Due to litigation, most of those regulations were never implemented. If we are serious about curbing youth smoking as much as  possible, as soon as possible; it makes no sense to require FDA to reinvent the wheel by conducting a new multi-year rulemaking process on the same issues. This legislation will give the youth access and advertising restrictions already developed by FDA the immediate force of law, as if they had been issued under the new statute.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation also provides for stronger warnings on all cigarette and smokeless tobacco packages, and in all print advertisements. These warnings will be more explicit in their description of the medical problems which can result from tobacco use. The FDA is given the authority to change the text of these warning labels periodically, to keep their impact strong.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The nicotine in cigarettes is highly addictive. Medical experts say that it is as addictive as heroin or cocaine. Yet for decades, tobacco companies vehemently denied the addictiveness of their products. No one can forget the parade of tobacco executives who testified under oath before Congress that smoking cigarettes is not addictive. Overwhelming evidence in industry documents obtained through the discovery process proves that the companies not only knew of this addictiveness for decades, but  actually relied on it as the basis for their marketing strategy. As we now know, cigarette manufacturers chemically manipulated the nicotine in their products to make it even more addictive.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A newly released analysis by the Harvard School of Public Health demonstrates that cigarette manufacturers are still manipulating nicotine levels. Between 1998 and 2005, they significantly increased the nicotine yield from major brand name cigarettes. The average increase in nicotine yield over the period was 11 percent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The tobacco industry has a long, dishonorable history of providing misleading information about the health consequences of smoking. These companies have repeatedly sought to characterize their products as far less hazardous than they are. They made minor innovations in product design seem far more significant for the health of the user than they actually were. It is essential that FDA have clear and unambiguous authority to prevent such misrepresentations in the future. The largest disinformation  campaign in the history of the corporate world must end.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Given the addictiveness of tobacco products, it is essential that the FDA regulate them for the protection of the public. Over 40 million Americans are currently addicted to cigarettes. No responsible public health official believes that cigarettes should be banned. A ban would leave 40 million people without a way to satisfy their drug dependency. FDA should be able to take the necessary steps to help addicted smokers overcome their addiction, and to make the product less toxic for smokers who  are unable or unwilling to stop. To do so, FDA must have the authority to reduce or remove hazardous ingredients from cigarettes, to the extent that it becomes scientifically feasible. The inherent risk in smoking should not be unnecessarily compounded.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Recent statements by several tobacco companies make clear that they plan to develop what they characterize as "reduced risk" cigarettes. Some are already on the market making unsubstantiated claims. This legislation will require manufacturers to submit such "reduced risk" products to the FDA for analysis before they can be marketed. No health-related claims will be permitted until they have been verified to the FDA's satisfaction. These safeguards are essential to prevent deceptive industry  marketing campaigns, which could lull the public into a false sense of health safety.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Smoking is the number one preventable cause of death in America. Congress must vest FDA not only with the responsibility for regulating tobacco products, but with full authority to do the job effectively.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation will give the FDA the legal authority it needs to reduce youth smoking by preventing tobacco advertising which targets children, to prevent the sale of tobacco products to minors, to help smokers overcome their addiction, to make tobacco products less toxic for those who continue to use them, and to prevent the tobacco industry from misleading the public about the dangers of smoking.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enacting this bill this year is the right thing to do for America's children. They are depending on us. By passing this legislation, we can help them live longer, healthier lives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="Introducing S. 626 A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for arthritis research and public health, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="626">S. 626</bill>] Mr. President, it is a privilege to join Senator Bond in introducing "The Arthritis Prevention, Control and Cure Act."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our goal in this important initiative is to provide a strong federal response to arthritis. Early diagnosis, treatment, and appropriate management of arthritis can control its symptoms, improve the quality of life of patients, and Federal action will improve the lives of the family members and caregivers of those affected by the disease.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Arthritis exits in more than a hundred different forms. It's one of the most devastating diseases impairing the health of the American people. It's second only to heart disease as a cause of work disability. It undermines everyday activities such as walking, dressing and bathing for more than seven million Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One out of very five adults in the United States suffers from some form of arthritis. The number of patients in the U.S. with arthritis will keep growing as the number of older Americans continues to increase dramatically in the next few decades. Today, 8.7 million adults, ages 18 through 44, have arthritis and millions of others are at risk of developing the disease.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In fact, arthritis is one of the most prevalent chronic illnesses and the  leading cause of disability among Americans over age 15. More than 40 percent of adults with arthritis are limited in their activities because of their arthritis. By 2030, nearly 25 percent of the projected United States adult population will have arthritis and these numbers don't account for the current trends in obesity, which may contribute to future cases of the disease.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is an illness that affects all types of people in the U.S., not just older Americans. Arthritis knows no boundaries. Men, women and children are all afflicted with the disease. According to the Arthritis Foundation, 24 million women and 17 million men have been diagnosed with arthritis by their doctors. Women are still disproportionately affected by the disease.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nearly 3 out of every 1,000 American children are affected by arthritis. The devastating effects of pediatric arthritis justifies greater investment by the federal government in research and to identify more effective treatments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Special concerns are raised by juvenile arthritis because of its impact on family relationships, school life, dating, sports and other aspects active, growing youths. Teens and young adults entering the workforce face even greater challenges.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Arthritis an other rheumatic diseases cost our economy $128 billion annually, according to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. In 2003, the cost was  equivalent to 1.2 percent of the nation's gross domestic product. $80 million of that amount were direct costs for medical care and $47 million were indirect costs for lost earnings. National medical costs attributed to arthritis grew by 24 percent between 1997 and 2003, with an increase attributed to the growing number of people affected with the disease.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1975, Congress enacted the National Arthritis Act to encourage basic and clinical research, establish Multipurpose Arthritis Centers and expand clinical knowledge of the illness. The act was successful in implementing and continued funding of research and has led to important advances in the control, treatment and prevention of the illness.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Early diagnosis, treatment and management can control symptoms and improve the quality of life. Weight control and exercise can help lower risks. Patient education, training and self-management also contribute to greater control of these diseases. Innovative and increasingly effective drug therapies, joint replacements, and other therapeutic alternatives are being developed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Despite much research identifying effective interventions, many of them are not being used well enough and the inevitable result is unnecessary loss of life, poorer health and poorer quality of life.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our legislation will expand the effort to find new ways to prevent, treat and care for patients with arthritis and related rheumatic diseases.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It will enhance the National Arthritis Action Plan by providing additional support to federal, state and private efforts to prevent and manage arthritis. It will establish a National Arthritis Education and Outreach Campaign to inform the health care profession and the public about the most successful self-management strategies for controlling the illness.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With greater coordination and intensification of federal research, this bill will organize a National Arthritis and Rheumatic Diseases Summit to look at the challenges and opportunities related to these efforts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, the bill will provide greater attention to juvenile arthritis research by offering planning grants for research specific to juveniles and by prioritizing the activities that create better understanding of the incidence and outcomes associated with juvenile arthritis.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally the bill contains incentives to encourage health professionals to enter the field of pediatric rheumatology by education loan repayment and career development awards.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this public health initiative to reduce the pain and disability of arthritis. Early diagnosis, effective treatment and greater investment in research and prevention can help us wage a stronger battle against one of the most widespread and devastating conditions affecting our Nation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="Introducing S. 627. A bill to amend the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 to improve the health and well-being of maltreated infants and toddlers through the creation of a National Court Teams Resource Center, to assist local Court Teams, and for other purposes; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="627">S. 627</bill>] Mr. President, I am honored to join with the distinguished senior Senator from Oregon, Senator Smith, to introduce the Safe Babies Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is a tragic fact that America's child welfare system is failing our most vulnerable. From birth to age five, children develop their social, emotional, cognitive and moral capacities more rapidly than at any other time in life. Early experiences and relationships are absolutely critical to future development; they set the stage for how well individuals learn, think, control their emotions, and relate to others.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This critical period is a time of tremendous promise, but also a time of great vulnerability. Unfortunately, infants and toddlers are disproportionately affected by child abuse and neglect. Children between birth and age three are twice as likely as older children to become victims of maltreatment, and are three times more likely to be placed in foster care. Abuse and neglect during this significant period can lead to perilous developmental outcomes, including school failure, delinquency and  crime, substance abuse, and mental health problems.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Yet the current child welfare system does a particularly poor job of serving infants and toddlers. Once in foster care, infants and toddlers are more likely to be abused. And they stay in foster care longer than older children. More than 40 percent of infants and toddlers involved in a maltreatment investigation are developmentally delayed, yet only 10 percent of these young people currently receive treatment for developmental problems.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A Federal review of 19 States' performance on child welfare outcomes found that all of the States received failing grades on outcomes related to providing adequate physical and mental health services.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Without intervention, we put our future generation at risk and perpetuate the cycle of maltreatment. But we can alter these developmental outcomes by ensuring that children are in safe, permanent homes and have access to necessary mental and physical health care. The Safe Babies Act authorizes funding for juvenile courts to create Court Teams for the integrated handling of infant and toddler abuse and neglect cases. By bringing together the legal, child welfare, and children's services communities,  we can promote the health and well-being of our babies and toddlers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, this bill establishes a National Court Teams Resource Center. This Resource Center would provide grants and technical assistance to juvenile courts for the creation of local Court Teams to better handle infant and toddler abuse and neglect cases. Few judges have all the necessary knowledge about early childhood development and they frequently lack resources in the community for services necessary for young children. They are often frustrated by the piecemeal provision of services and the  overburdened child welfare system. To adequately serve children, they need the expertise of child welfare workers, Guardians Ad Litem, Court Appointed Special Advocates, substance abuse treatment providers and mental health care providers. Court Teams bring together this expertise. Through monthly case reviews,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Court Teams work with families in an effort to reunite children with their parents. By bringing together multiple service providers, they can facilitate opportunities for parents to learn to create a safe and nurturing home environment. Court Teams ensure support for future reunification only when the  parent is ready and able to step up to provide an appropriate and safe environment. We know from research that each visit between a child and birth parent  triples the likelihood of achieving permanence. Through the Court Teams, judges are able to coordinate education and supervision so parents can visit their children and continue to nurture a loving bond.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although reunification with parents is the ultimate goal, when that is not possible, Court Teams are also focusing on Plan B. By conducting concurrent planning, Court Teams are more likely to find an appropriate placement that will lead to permanency and minimize disruptions. By supporting training for foster parents and newly reunified biological parents, we can prevent children from being bounced around in the foster care system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Court Teams are also able to coordinate services for children. Judges and child welfare services are able to collaborate to include necessary medical and developmental interventions. By improving access to mental health and substance abuse treatment for parents and children, Court Teams make sure children are able to access needed services and increase the chances of successful, healthy development.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, Court Teams provide services and supports for families to preserve and stabilize homes for children. Judges are able to use court oversight to ensure compliance, facilitate visits with caregivers to promote positive attachments, and make sure that children are in safe environments after placement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Safe Babies Act will make an important impact in the way we treat infants and toddlers in the court system. By facilitating involvement from all parties, Court Teams are better equipped to ensure that young children have the community support and services they need. Early evaluation research in the Miami/Dade County court project finds a high rate of permanency for children in the court and increased quality of parent-child interaction. By finding permanent homes, children were able to escape  the limbo of the foster care system. More importantly, the court was successful in preventing any future recurrence of abuse or neglect.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Together we can work to protect the safety and well-being of our infants and toddlers. With this legislation, we have the opportunity to ensure that children are placed quickly in safe and loving homes. I look forward to working with my colleagues to ensure that this legislation is passed and signed into law.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300090" topic="Introducing S. 627. A bill to amend the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 to improve the health and well-being of maltreated infants and toddlers through the creation of a National Court Teams Resource Center, to assist local Court Teams, and for other purposes; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today with my colleague from Iowa, Senator HARKIN, to introduce the Safe Babies Act of 2007. The safety and well-being of our nation's children, including its most vulnerable infants and toddlers, is very important and I am confident that this bill will take an important step forward in protecting them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, in our Nation millions of children are reported abused or neglected each year. Of these, more than 900,000 are confirmed maltreated by child protective service organizations and our court systems. Abuse and neglect of children causes about 1,500 deaths each year. Children who are under the age of four are at the greatest risk for injury or death--making up nearly 80 percent of child maltreatment fatalities. We also know that shaken-baby syndrome, SBS, is a form of abuse that affects  more than 1,200 babies each year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Studies also tell us that younger children who are abused or neglected are vulnerable to long-term challenges associated with their maltreatment. Their long-term outcomes show much higher rates for social, emotional and cognitive impairment. They also are more likely to adopt high risk behaviors and develop substance abuse and mental health problems than their peers who have not been abused.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These numbers tell us very loudly that there is a problem in America. Our most vulnerable and innocent are being abused and need our help.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Children who come through our Nation's court systems need more support. While the hardworking judges, attorneys, child welfare workers and volunteers do so much to help stop the child abuse and neglect they see every day, they too often see families returning to the courts generation after generation. They see their workloads expand. They see too many families in strife.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Safe Babies Act will help these most vulnerable children. This bill puts into motion a proven model for helping infants and toddlers to recover from their abuse, and for families to stop the cycle of abuse and reunite. This model is made up of a judicial and mental health partnership, or "court team," that provides the needed abuse and neglect prevention and early intervention services to children and their families. It is based on a model developed by the Honorable Cindy Lederman of the  Miami-Dade Juvenile Court in Miami. Seeing the success she has had with this model. It has been replicated in courts across the nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In my home State of Oregon, our Salem courts have developed the "Foster Attachment" program based on Judge Lederman's model. This program brings together the courts, local treatment providers, and child welfare agencies to provide substance abuse treatment and mental health treatment, as well as parenting intervention to help parents who have had their children removed due to methamphetamine use.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I look forward to the passage of this important legislation and to working with my colleague Senator HARKIN to ensure its passage. There is no issue of greater importance than the safety and welfare of our next generation. I urge my colleagues on both sides of the aisle to support this important bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300024" topic="Introducing S. 628: A bill to provide grants for rural health information technology development activities; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="628">S. 628</bill>] Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill I introduced today, the Critical Access to Health Information Technology Act of 2007, be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300024" topic="Introducing S. 629. A bill to amend the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to provide direct and guaranteed loans, loan guarantees, and grants to complete the construction and rehabilitation of rural critical access hospitals; to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="629">S. 629</bill>] Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill I introduce today, to amend the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to provide direct and guaranteed loans, loan guarantees, and grants to complete the construction and rehabilitation of critical access hospitals, be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300024" topic="Introducing S. 630. A bill to amend part C of title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for a minimum payment rate by Medicare Advantage organizations for services furnished by a critical access hospital and a rural health clinic under the Medicare program; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="630">S. 630</bill>] Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill I introduce today, the Rural Health Services Preservation Act of 2007, be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the bill the of the was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300024" topic="Introducing S. 630. A bill to amend part C of title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for a minimum payment rate by Medicare Advantage organizations for services furnished by a critical access hospital and a rural health clinic under the Medicare program; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill I introduce today, the Remote Monitoring Access Act of 2007, be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300024" topic="Introducing S. 632. A bill to provide for a hospital in Cass County, Minnesota; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="632">S. 632</bill>] Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill I introduce today, to provide for a hospital in Cass County, Minnesota, be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300024" topic="Introducing S. 633. A bill to provide assistance to rural schools, hospitals, and communities for the conduct of collaborative efforts to secure a progressive and innovative system to improve access to mental health care for youth, seniors and families; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="633">S. 633</bill>] Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill I introduce today, the Working Together for Rural Access to Mental Health and Wellness for Children and Seniors Act, be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300034" topic="Introducing S. 634. A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to establish grant programs to provide for education and outreach on newborn screening and coordinated followup care once newborn screening has been conducted, to reauthorize programs under part A of title XI of such Act, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="634">S. 634</bill>] Mr. President, I am pleased today to join with my colleague Senator Hatch to introduce legislation to protect the most vulnerable members of our society: newborn infants. Many people know the joy of parenthood. These parents know the sense of worry about whether their kids are doing well, are feeling well, and are safe. Nothing is of greater importance than the health and well-being of our children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thanks to incredible advances in medical technology, it is now possible to test newborns for more than 50 genetic and metabolic disorders. Many of these disorders, if undetected, would lead to severe disability or death. However, babies that are properly diagnosed and treated can, in many cases, go on to live healthy lives. So newborn screening can literally save lives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Frighteningly, the disorders that newborn screening tests for can come without warning. For most of these disorders, there is no medical history of the condition in the family and no way to predict the health of a baby based on the health of the parents. Although the disorders that are tested for are quite rare, there is a chance that any one newborn will be affected. In that sense, this is an issue that has a direct impact on the lives of all families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Fortunately, some screening has become common practice in every state. Each year, over four million infants have blood taken from their heel after birth to detect these disorders that could threaten their life and long-term health. As a result, about one in 4,000 babies is diagnosed with one of these disorders. That means that newborn screening could protect the health or save the life of approximately 1,000 newborns each year. That is 1,000 tragedies that can be averted families that can know  the joy of a new infant rather than absolute heartbreak.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 2004, the American College of Medical Genetics (ACMG) completed a report commissioned by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services which recommended that every baby born in the U.S. be screened for twenty-nine disorders, including certain metabolic conditions and hearing deficiency. Unfortunately, as of February 2007, only 11 States and the District of Columbia require infants to be screened for all twenty-nine of these recommended disorders. If diagnosed early, all of these conditions  can be successfully managed or treated to prevent or mitigate severe and often lifelong health problems.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For every baby saved, another two are estimated to be born with potentially detectable disorders that go undetected because they are not screened. These infants and their families face the prospect of disability or death from a preventable disorder. The survival of a newborn may very well come down to the state in which it is born, because not all states test for every detectable disorder.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Government Accountability Office, GAO, released a report in 2003 highlighting the need for this legislation. According to the report, most states do not educate parents and health care providers about the availability of tests beyond what is mandated by a State. States also reported that they do not have the resources to purchase the technology and train the staff needed to expand newborn screening programs. Finally, even when States do detect an abnormal screening result, the majority do  not inform parents directly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation that we are introducing today will give states an additional helping hand toward meeting the advisory's committee's recommendation by providing $25 million for states to expand and improve their newborn screening programs. In order to access these resources, states will be required to commit to screening for all 29 disorders.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our legislation will also authorize $15 million for two types of grants. The first seeks to address the lack of information available to health care professionals and parents about newborn screening. Every parent should have the knowledge necessary to protect their child. The tragedy of a newborn's death is only compounded by the frustration of learning that the death was preventable. This bill authorizes grants to provide education and training to health care professionals, state laboratory  personnel, families and consumer advocates.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The second type of grant will support States in providing follow-up care for those children diagnosed by a disorder detected through newborn screening. While these families are the fortunate ones, in many cases they are still faced with the prospect of extended and complex treatment and major lifestyle changes. We need to remember that care does not stop at diagnosis.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To ensure the quality of laboratories involved in newborn screening, so that tests are as accurate as possible and infants receive appropriate care, the legislation authorizes $5 million for the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, CDC, to carry out a number of functions such as quality assurance for newborn screening tests, performance evaluation services, and technical assistance and technology transfer to newborn screening labs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the event of a public health emergency, such as Hurricane Katrina, newborn screening may seem like a low priority. However, if babies aren't tested and, when necessary, treated within the first few days of life, they may suffer irreparable harm or even death. In the wake of a public health crisis, contingency planning for newborn screening is essential. Our legislation requires the CDC, in consultation with the Health Resources and Services Administration, HRSA, to develop a national contingency  plan for newborn screening in the event of a public health emergency within 180 days of enactment of the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, the bill directs the CDC, in consultation with HRSA, to establish a national surveillance program for newborn screening, and authorizes $15 million for that purpose. Such a program will help us conduct research to better understand these rare disorders, and will hopefully lead us toward more effective treatments and cures.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this important legislation so that every newborn child will have the best possible opportunity that America can offer to live a long, healthy and happy life. I look forward to working with the Chairman of the Health, Education, Labor and Pensions (HELP) Committee, Senator Kennedy, and Ranking Member Enzi to advance this legislation as early as possible.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300052" topic="Introducing S. 634. A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to establish grant programs to provide for education and outreach on newborn screening and coordinated followup care once newborn screening has been conducted, to reauthorize programs under part A of title XI of such Act, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>I am pleased to introduce today, along with my colleague Senator CHRISTOPHER DODD, the Newborn Screening Saves Lives Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Every State and U.S. territory routinely screens newborns for certain genetic, metabolic, hormonal and functional disorders. Most of these birth defects have no immediate visible effects on a baby but, unless detected and treated early, can cause physical problems, mental retardation and, in some cases, death.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Babies who have these diseases and babies who do not have these diseases look the same at birth. Fortunately, most babies are given a clean bill of health when tested. In cases where babies are found to have metabolic disorders or hearing impairment, early diagnosis and proper treatment can make the difference between healthy development and lifelong impairment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Except for hearing screening, all newborn screening tests are done using a few drops of blood from the newborn's heel. Newborn screening checks for diseases that can cause problems with the way the body gets energy, how the body makes hormones, or how the body makes blood cells.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Currently each state or region operates by law its own newborn screening program. Individual programs vary widely in the number and types of conditions for which they test. According to the National Newborn Screening and Genetics Resources Center, some States test for as few as four disorders, while others test for 30 or more.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Disparities among States in screening tests given at birth result in too many babies with serious birth defects not being diagnosed and treated in time to avoid death or long term disability. Many States offer only limited educational materials for parents and health care providers about the availability of newborn screening tests; therefore parents are often unaware of the importance of testing and may learn too late that their newborn has an abnormal metabolic condition which could have been  treated.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 2004, the American College of Medical Genetics completed a report commissioned by the Department of Health and Human Services which recommended that every baby born in the United States be screened for 29 disorders, including certain metabolic conditions and hearing deficiency. Currently, only 11 States and the District of Columbia require the recommended screening for all 29 disorders.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last year there was much success in improving newborn screening in my home State of Utah, which increased testing from 4 to 36 disorders. The expansion of newborn screening is a major advancement for children's healthcare in Utah, as the screening should identify an additional 15 to 20 Utah infants every year in time to help them get the treatment they need to live a fuller and healthier life.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enactment of the Newborn Screening Saves Lives Act would provide necessary resource materials to educate parents and health providers about newborn screening and help states expand and improve their newborn screening programs. Other important provisions of this legislation help ensure the quality of laboratories involved in newborn screening and call for establishing a system for collecting and analyzing data from newborn screening programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill will establish grant programs to provide for education and outreach on newborn screening and coordinated follow-up care once newborn screening has been conducted. It will help States expand and improve their newborn screening programs, educate parents and providers and improve follow-up care for infants. The bill also contains provisions for a contingency plan for newborn screening in the case of a national public health emergency, such as that which was witnessed in the wake of Hurricanes  Katrina and Rita.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Newborn Screening Saves Lives Act of 2007 is endorsed by the March of Dimes, the American Academy of Pediatrics, Easter Seals, and the American Public Health Labs. These groups recognize that expanded newborn screening will help pediatricians and other healthcare providers identify rare disorders than can be easily confused with common pediatric problems. Diagnosing and treating these conditions will help prevent irreversible brain damage, permanent disabilities, and possibly death. I urge  my colleagues to take a stand for newborn health and support this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300087" topic="Introducing S. 636. A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to extend the reporting period for certain statements  sent to taxpayers; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="636">S. 636</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to introduce the "Reduce Wasteful Tax Forms Act of 2007." This bill extends the deadline from January 31 to February 15 for certain types of 1099 forms to be sent to taxpayers. 1099 forms are used to report non-wage income, such as income from dividends and capital gains. These forms are distributed by brokerage firms and financial institutions to their investors, who must report the information on their income tax returns.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Due to recent changes in tax laws that govern income from interest and dividends, there has been a significant increase in the number of inaccurate forms sent out by firms in order to meet the January 31 deadline. The problem is that much of the tax data for certain types of investment income cannot be calculated until after the first of the year, resulting in a compressed window for calculating data in compliance with the new laws and mailing the forms. Once accurate data becomes available,  financial institutions must send taxpayers an amended form with the correct information.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These amended forms create confusion for taxpayers, and in some cases, those who receive an amended 1099 may have to re-file their taxes. If taxpayers underpaid in their initial return, they could face interest charges and penalties if they do not file again before the April 15 deadline. The January 31 deadline results in tons of wasted paper, confusion for taxpayers, and wasted expenses incurred in sending the amended forms.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This problem affects an increasing number of taxpayers. According to recent press reports in the Wall Street Journal and USA Today, prior to 2003, an average of 5 to 8 percent of 1099 forms required correcting. That number has since jumped to an average of 13 percent, translating into millions of amended 1099s being sent to taxpayers each year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My legislation would extend the deadline for sending 1099 forms to taxpayers to February 15, by which time the vast majority of required data will be available to ensure the accuracy of the forms. The bill extends the deadline only for certain types of 1099 forms used to report investment income; it would not extend the deadline for 1099 forms sent to independent contractors or for statements that only report interest earned on bank deposits. Accordingly, this extension will not delay filing  for the vast majority of taxpayers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This year, the IRS granted several brokerage firms an extension to the January 31 deadline. However, this bill would provide a permanent extension for all firms and financial institutions to remove the uncertainty for taxpayers that arises due to this unnecessarily early deadline. My bill will help taxpayers by reducing confusion, the financial industry by cutting costs and waste, and the environment by eliminating millions of unnecessary mailings.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I hope that my colleagues will join me in supporting this legislation, and I look forward to working with other Finance Committee members to have it considered during the 110th Congress. Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="Introducing S. 642. A bill to codify Executive Order 12898, relating to environmental justice, to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to fully implement the recommendations of the Inspector General of the Agency and the Comptroller General of the United States, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="642">S. 642</bill>] Mr. President, today I introduce, with Senators KERRY and MENENDEZ, an environmental justice bill that will help protect the well-being of minority and low-income communities throughout the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1994, President Clinton issued an Executive Order instructing Government agencies to develop strategies to identify and address environmental inequities that might be created through agency programs. The Executive Order recognized that low-income and minority communities often end up with more than their fair share of pollution, associated health risks and environmental degradation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>More advantaged communities--with strong advocates, more resources, and better access to information--are less likely to have landfills, petrochemical plants, or waste incinerators built in their neighborhoods.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency has not honored the 1994 Executive Order and the goal of environmental justice has not been met. In a March 2004 report, the EPA Inspector General concluded that the agency "has not fully implemented Executive Order 12898 nor consistently integrated environmental justice into its day-to-day operations. EPA has not identified minority and low-income [populations] ..... and has neither defined nor developed criteria for determining [who is]  disproportionately impacted. Moreover, in 2001, the Agency restated its commitment to environmental justice in a manner that does not emphasize minority and low-income populations, the intent of the Executive Order."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, with the introduction of the Environmental Justice Act of 2007, we ask Congress to codify the Executive Order. The legislation also directs the EPA to implement recommendations in this area from both the EPA Inspector General and the Government Accountability Office. The recommendations include creating offices to review programs and policies for environmental justice implications, training staff to address environmental justice concerns in the rule making process and specifically assessing  the impacts of future regulation and enforcement on the communities most at risk to human and environmental health problems. Finally, the bill establishes reporting requirements for the implementation of the recommendations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am pleased that our legislation currently has the support of 18 organizations, including: Earthjustice; Lawyers' Committee for Civil Rights Under  Law; Center for Health, Environment and Justice; Natural Resources Defense Council; Advocates for Environmental Human Rights and Labor Council for Latin American Advancement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill we are introducing today is an important step toward shifting the balance of environmental hazards, so the burden is not shouldered unfairly by low-income and minority communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="Introducing S. 642. A bill to codify Executive Order 12898, relating to environmental justice, to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to fully implement the recommendations of the Inspector General of the Agency and the Comptroller General of the United States, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today I introduce the Disabled Veterans Insurance Improvement Act of 2007. The legislation would increase the amount of supplemental life insurance available to totally disabled veterans from $20,000 to $40,000. Many totally disabled veterans find it difficult to obtain commercial life insurance. These are the veterans we are trying to help with this legislation by providing them with a reasonable amount of life insurance coverage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>VA's Service-Disabled Veterans' Insurance, commonly known as S-DVI, was established during the Korean War to provide life insurance for veterans with service-connected disabilities. This $10,000 benefit has never been increased.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In comparison, the Servicemembers' Group Life Insurance and Veterans' Group Life Insurance benefits, which were $10,000 and $20,000 respectively at their inception, have been increased over time to $400,000. The most recent increases to these programs have been in response to public sentiment and the determination by Congress that the amount provided to the beneficiaries of servicemembers who die while fighting in Operations Enduring Freedom and Iraqi Freedom is insufficient.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1992, Congress increased the amount of life insurance available to S-DVI policyholders by offering $20,000 worth of supplemental coverage to those who are considered totally disabled. Forty percent of the veterans enrolled in the S-DVI program are considered totally disabled and are eligible for a premium waiver for their basic coverage. In fiscal year 2006, thirty-two percent of veterans granted new policy waivers also opted to pay for this supplemental coverage. Even with $30,000 in coverage,  the amount of life insurance available to disabled veterans falls well short of the death benefits available to servicemembers and veterans enrolled in the Servicemembers' Group Life Insurance and Veterans' Group Life Insurance programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The 2001 Congressionally mandated study entitled Program Evaluation of Benefits for Survivors of Veterans with  Service-Connected Disabilities found the lowest area of veteran satisfaction to be the maximum amount of coverage that veterans were authorized to purchase. My bill would allow totally disabled veterans to purchase an additional $20,000 in insurance coverage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask my colleagues to support the Disabled Veterans Insurance Improvement Act of 2007. This is a modest and affordable way of increasing the life insurance coverage for those veterans with the greatest need. I realize that there are paygo implications associated with this legislation and I am actively looking for ways to pay for this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I request unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300024" topic="Introducing S. 646: A bill to increase the nursing workforce; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="646">S. 646</bill>] Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300100" topic="Introducing S. 647. A bill to designate certain land in the State of Oregon as wilderness, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="647">S. 647</bill>] Mr. President, it has been more than 200 years since Lewis and Clark first laid eyes on Mount Hood. Today, I propose, with Senator Smith, that the spectacular mountain, seen first by our pioneers, should be preserved for all time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Lewis and Clark Mount Hood Wilderness Act of 2007, which we introduce today, is similar to the bill Senator Smith and I introduced in the last Congress. It does include several improvements that came about from comments and constructive suggestions  from a variety of groups at home in Oregon.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation also includes input from the Energy and Natural Resources Committee. We appreciate their input and believe their views can help speed the bill's passage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In tribute to the great river-dependent journey of Lewis and Clark, our legislation adds nine free-flowing stretches of rivers to the National Wild and Scenic River System. This reflects the views of Oregonians, but, frankly, I hear it from folks in the Midwest, where the Presiding Officer lives, and from people from every nook and cranny in this country who have all come to treasure our spectacular mountain.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation contains a number of provisions of the original Mount Hood legislation I introduced in 2004. The bill protects the lower elevation forests surrounding Mount Hood and the Columbia River Gorge as Lewis and Clark saw them. These forests embody the natural beauty of our home State. They provide the clean water necessary for the survival of threatened steelhead, Coho, and Chinook salmon. They provide critical habitat and diverse ecosystems for elk, deer, lynx, and the majestic bald  eagle. These are the forests that provide unparalleled recreational opportunities for Oregonians and the scores and scores of visitors we get from Minnesota and every other part of the country as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But the legislation I offer today with Senator Smith differs from the bill I introduced several years ago because it responds to the many comments we have heard. We have received thousands of comments on our proposed legislation. Some comments came as a result of the general public meetings I held at home in Oregon. Many of the meetings lasted over 3 hours. Everybody who wanted to speak was given the opportunity to do so. Other comments came from the second Mount Hood summit that was  held at Timberline Lodge, hosted by Congressmen WALDEN and BLUMENAUER. My staff and I met with over 100 community groups and local governments, the members of the Oregon congressional delegation, the Governor, and the Bush administration. More comments came from calls and letters from Oregonians who are saying that now, now, now is the time to preserve Mount Hood.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Overwhelmingly, these comments have urged that we build on Oregon's wilderness system. This goal is as important today as it was in 1804, when Lewis and Clark first viewed Mount Hood; in 1964, when the Wilderness Act was passed; or in 1984, when wilderness protections were last designated on Mount Hood. It is time to plan now to protect this treasure for future generations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Mount Hood National Forest is the seventh most visited national forest in our country. In the 22 years that have elapsed since any new wilderness has been designated on Mount Hood, the population in the local counties has increased significantly--25 percent in Multnomah County, 24 percent in Hood River County, and 28 percent in Clackamas County.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The predominant public use of this urban forest is nonmechanized activities such as hiking, camping, and fishing. With increasing emphasis on wild scenery, unspoiled wildlife habitats, free-flowing rivers, wilderness, and the need for opportunities for diverse outdoor recreation, sometimes it seems we are in jeopardy of loving our wild places to death. We all see Americans coming together to make sure the most special places are protected for future generations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A few years ago, the Forest Service made a proposal to limit the number of people who could hike on the south side of Mount Hood. Suffice it to say, the public outcry in opposition was enormous. It seems to me, rather than tell people they are going to be restricted from using our public lands, part of the solution for Mount Hood lies in providing more opportunities for them to enjoy the mountain's great places. We ought to ensure that the Mount Hood National Forest can meet the increased demand  for outdoor experiences, and the legislation I offer today with Senator Smith provides these opportunities. Hundreds of people spoke at the public meetings I held throughout the State. I have received 2,500 written comments urging additional wilderness on Mount Hood. There are a few key areas the citizens continually come back and refer to:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, by astonishing numbers, they want to see additional wilderness on Mount Hood. A large number of Oregonians didn't think enough wilderness had been included, for example, in the legislation that was considered by the other body.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A second area is mountain biking. Some mountain bikers expressed concern that their recreation opportunities not be unfairly curtailed. Senator Smith and I had many discussions with them to ensure that would not be the case.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Third, fire protection and forest health was something referred to by many Oregonians. Citizens were concerned about the health of the forest. Those living in towns on the mountain and the gorge were concerned about fire protection in their communities, and we sought to address those issues as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An additional concern was developed recreation, with some citizens worried about maintaining a role for developed recreation, such as skiing, on Mount Hood.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In each of these areas, Senator Smith and I tried to follow up and be responsive to what citizens at home were saying.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With respect to additional wilderness, there are currently 189,200 acres of designated wilderness in the Mount Hood National Forest. This bill increases wilderness on Mount Hood by designating approximately 128,000 acres of new wilderness.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill adds the areas surrounding the oldest Mount Hood wilderness--the mountain itself--which was designated in the original Wilderness Act of 1964. These additions include cathedral old growth forests, special trails, lava beds that were created during the Mount Hood eruptions, and much of the legendary route that Oregon's pioneers used when they came to our great State.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To the north and west of the mountain, we add the viewshed of the Columbia Gorge to the current Mark O. Hatfield Wilderness. These areas encompass the spectacular ridges that frame the gorge that we marvel at from I-84 and include perhaps the greatest concentration of waterfalls in all of North America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To the southwest of the mountain, we add lands to the current Salmon Huckleberry Wilderness to conserve their diverse wildlife and protect unique recreational areas such as those around the extremely popular Mirror Lake. These lands include Alder Creek, the source of drinking water for the city of Sandy, and that city unanimously endorsed the draft proposal.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over to the east are proposed additions to the Badger Creek Wilderness area. These areas provide a critical link between westside forests and eastside ecosystems. This area is known for its spectacular colors in the fall and the best deer and elk hunting in our entire Mount Hood National Forest.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Among the areas we are protecting is the newly designated Richard L. Kohnstamm Memorial area. It is dedicated in honor of Mr. Kohnstamm who restored the historic Timberline Lodge built originally by the Works Progress Administration in 1937. Our new 2007 bill adds 2,730 acres of Marion County lands in the Bull of the Woods Wilderness Additions, while removing lands where users identified potential conflicts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second, in the area of wild and scenic rivers, we protect over 79 miles of wild and scenic rivers on nine free-flowing rivers. This protects some of the most pristine rivers in our State. Among those proposed rivers are the picturesque waterfalls and glacial outwash of the East Fork of the Hood River, and the ancestral hunting and fishing grounds of Fish Creek. Over 17 miles of extraordinary salmon and steelhead habitat on the Collowash River have also been added for protection under our legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mountain biking is an area where there has been a lot of debate. We believed the local riders raised valid concerns, and we took two steps. First, we proposed the Mount Hood National Recreation Area. This area was so popular in our last bill that Senator Smith and I decided to greatly expand it to include 34,640 acres, an increase of over 16,000 additional acres. It is going to offer permanent environmental protection to those beautiful areas, while  providing  mountain bikers, recreational users, and others an opportunity to enjoy recreation on the mountain.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Additionally, I made boundary adjustments to ensure that all open mountain biking trails were not included in this proposed legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With respect to fire protection and forest health, we tried to make clear that where there are healthy, older trees, they should not be harvested on Mount Hood or in the gorge. Older healthy stands are most resistant to fire and disease. However, there is an enormous backlog of overcrowded plantation, second growth that really ought to be thinned. The legislation includes provisions that would give the Forest Service a mandate to prepare an assessment for promoting forests resilient to fire,  insects, and disease. This also includes provisions to study and encourage the development of biomass in conjunction with forest health work.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We happen to think that biomass is one of the most exciting new fields for Oregonians to get into. The opportunity to generate clean energy, help small rural communities, create family wage jobs, is something that we should not miss out on. This legislation tries to tap the potential for progress in the biomass field as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, we add fire-safe community zones so that the Secretary of Agriculture will construct a system of fire-safe buffer zones around the communities of Cascade Locks and Government Camp.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With respect to developed recreation, we wanted to facilitate recreational opportunities in this area and thus adopted a provision that came from the other body known as "fee retention" that would establish a special account for the Mount Hood National Forest.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, in order to help address growth while ensuring access to recreational opportunities, we have adopted provisions originally coming, again, from language from the other body directing the Secretary of Agriculture and the State of Oregon to develop an integrated transportation plan for the Mount Hood region.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I commend particularly my colleague in the other body, Congressman Blumenauer, one of the real pioneers in thinking about transportation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, with respect to key relationships with our tribes and our local governmental bodies, we have incorporated provisions on local and tribal relationships, emphasizing the rich history of the Mount Hood area and affirming the rights of Native peoples to access the mountains as they have for generations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The protections of these important Oregon places is going to depend on the hard work and dedication of all Oregonians. I am very pleased--I am summing up, and the Senate has been patient in giving me this extra time--to say that this has been a bipartisan effort by the Oregon congressional delegation. Senator Smith joins me in introducing this legislation. We believe this brings together our county commissioners, entrepreneurs, environmentalists, Chamber of Commerce, State-elected officials,  the Governor. All of those who feel so strongly about protecting Mount Hood rolled up their sleeves, went to work, and joined myself and Senator Smith to try to find common ground to make sure that Mount Hood would be protected for all time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are looking forward to perfecting the legislation together in the coming weeks and looking forward to seeing a swift adoption by Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The grandeur of Mount Hood and our special treasures is pretty much in the chromosomes of Oregonians. Protecting our treasures is something about which we feel so strongly. Today is a special day for us because, once again, the citizens of our State have come together and have worked with myself and Senator Smith to take action to protect our treasures.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, Oregon's Mount Hood is a cherished State treasure. This wild place is often photographed, visited and enjoyed by scores of Oregonians and non-Oregonians. Today, I am introducing, along with my colleague Senator Smith, a bi-partisan Oregon Wilderness bill: the "Lewis and Clark Mount Hood Wilderness Act of 2007." This bill is similar to the one Senator Smith and I introduced in the last Congress, but it includes several improvements that resulted from comments  received from stakeholders. The bill also includes input from the Energy and Natural Resources Committee, which we hope will help speed the bill's passage. In tribute to the great riverdependent journey of Lewis and Clark, our legislation adds nine free-flowing stretches of rivers to the National Wild and Scenic River System. This reflects the Oregonian wish to protect but also actively experience our State's treasures.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill contains many elements of the Mount Hood bill I introduced in 2004, while also incorporating many new provisions to protect and improve the Mount Hood region. This bill protects the lower elevation forests surrounding Mount Hood and the Columbia River Gorge as Lewis and Clark saw them. These forests embody the natural beauty of Oregon. They provide the clean water necessary for the survival of threatened steelhead, Coho and Chinook salmon. These forests provide critical habitat and  diverse ecosystems for elk, deer, lynx and the majestic bald eagle. And these are the forests that provide unparalleled recreational opportunities for Oregonians and our visitors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But the bill I introduce today differs from the bill I introduced 2 years ago because it responds to the many comments I heard in the ensuing years. I received thousands of comments on proposed Mount Hood legislation. Some comments came as a result of the general public meetings I held in Oregon. Many of the meetings lasted over 3 hours, and everyone who wanted to speak was given an opportunity to do so. Other comments came from the second Mount Hood Summit held at Timberline Lodge hosted by  Representatives Walden and Blumenauer. I and my staff met with over 100 community groups and local governments, the members of the Oregon congressional delegation, the Governor, and the Bush administration. And still more comments came from letters and phone calls from Oregonians.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Overwhelmingly, these comments urged me to protect and build on Oregon's Wilderness system. This goal is as important today as it was in 1804, when Lewis and Clark first viewed Mount Hood, 1964, when the Wilderness Act was passed, or 1984, when wilderness protections were last designated on Mount Hood--if not more so. To succeed, we must provide the tools that help us create a planned future on Mount Hood. This bill does both.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Mount Hood National Forest is the seventh most visited National Forest in the United States. In the 22 years that have elapsed since any new wilderness has been designated in the Mount Hood area, the population in local counties has increased significantly--25 percent in Multnomah County, 24 percent in Hood River County, and 28 percent in Clackamas County.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The predominant public use of this urban forest is non-mechanized activity like hiking, camping, and fishing. With increasing emphasis on wild scenery, unspoiled wildlife habitats, free flowing rivers, wilderness and the need for opportunities for diverse outdoor recreation, sometimes it seems we are in jeopardy of "loving our wild places to death."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A few years ago, the Forest Service made a proposal to limit the number of people that could hike the south side of Mount Hood and the public outcry was enormous. Seems to me, rather than tell people that they are going to be restricted from using our public lands, part of the solution for the future of the Mountain lies in providing more opportunities for them to enjoy the Mountain's great places. We should ensure the Mount Hood National Forest can meet the increased use and demand for outdoor  experiences--my bill will provide those opportunities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Of the hundreds of people who attended the meetings I held throughout the State of Oregon, the vast majority spoke in favor of more wilderness. Additionally, I have received more than 2,500 written comments supporting additional wilderness for Mount Hood.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is what I have heard: First and foremost, I heard that Oregonians in astonishing numbers support protecting Mount Hood and the Columbia River Gorge with additional wilderness. A large number of Oregonians didn't think that enough wilderness areas had been included in the House proposal.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Some mountain bikers expressed concerns that their recreation opportunities not be unfairly curtailed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Some people were worried about forest health, and those living in towns on the mountain and in the gorge were concerned about fire protection for their communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Some people were worried about maintaining a role for developed recreation, like skiing, on Mt. Hood.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is what my bill does to address those concerns: There are currently l89,200 acres of designated wilderness in the Mount Hood National Forest. This bill increases wilderness on Mount Hood by designating approximately 128,600 new acres of wilderness.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill adds the areas surrounding the oldest Mt. Hood Wilderness--the mountain itself--which was designated in the original Wilderness Act of 1964. These additions include cathedral old growth forests, the historic Tilly Jane trail, lava beds that were created during the Mt. Hood eruptions, and much of the legendary route that Oregon's pioneers used when they were settling our great State. To the north and west of the mountain, I would add the viewshed of the Columbia Gorge to the current  Mark O. Hatfield wilderness. These areas encompass the spectacular ridges framing the Gorge that we all marvel at from 1-84 and include perhaps the</paragraph>
    <paragraph>greatest concentration of waterfalls in North America. To the southwest of the mountain I add lands to the current Salmon Huckleberry Wilderness to conserve their diverse wildlife and protect unique recreational areas like those around popular Mirror Lake. These lands include Alder Creek, the source of drinking water for the City of Sandy, which unanimously endorsed the draft proposal. Over to the east are proposed additions to the Badger Creek Wilderness. These areas provide a critical link  between Westside forests and Eastside ecosystems. This area is known for beautiful fall color and the best deer and elk hunting in the entire Mount Hood National Forest. Among the areas we are protecting is the newly designated Richard L. Kohnstamm Memorial Area. It is dedicated in honor of Mr. Kohnstamm</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My proposal seeks to protect over 79.6 miles of wild and scenic rivers on nine free flowing rivers. This includes some of the most pristine and beautiful rivers in Oregon. Among those proposed rivers are the picturesque waterfalls and glacial outwash of the East Fork of the Hood River, and the ancestral hunting and fishing grounds of Fish Creek. Over 17 miles of superb salmon and steelhead habitat on the Collowash River have also been proposed for protection.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe that local riders raised some valid concerns, so I did two things. I have proposed Mount Hood National Recreation Area. This area was so popular in our last bill that Senator Smith and I decided to greatly expand it to include 34,640 acres--an increase of over 16,700 acres. It will offer greater, permanent environmental protections to those beautiful areas, while providing mountain bikers and other recreational users an opportunity to continue to recreate in these areas. Additionally,  I made boundary adjustments to ensure all open mountain biking trails were not included in my proposed wilderness.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I protect wilderness, where there are healthy, older trees that should never be harvested on Mount Hood or in the Gorge. Older, healthy stands are the most resistant to fire and disease. However, there is an enormous backlog of over-crowded, plantation, second-growth that should be thinned. My bill includes provisions that would give the Forest Service a mandate to prepare an assessment for promoting forests resilient to fire, insects and disease. This also includes provisions to study and encourage  the development of biomass in conjunction with forest health work. In addition, I added fire safe community zones so that the Secretary will construct a system of fire safe buffer zones around the communities of Cascade Locks and Government Camp.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In order to facilitate developed recreation opportunities, I have adopted the House provisions establishing a "feeretention" provision that will establish an account for the Mount Hood National Forest. In addition, in order to help address growth while ensuring access to recreational opportunities, I have adopted provisions, originally coming from the language passed in the House last Congress, directing the Secretary and the State of Oregon to develop an integrated transportation plan for  the Mount Hood region.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have also incorporated provisions on local and tribal relationships emphasizing the rich history of the Mount Hood region and affirming the rights of Native peoples to access the mountain's resources, as they have for generations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The protection of these important Oregon places will depend on the hard work and dedication of all Oregonians and particularly that of my Oregon colleagues here in the Congress. I am especially pleased that Senator Smith has joined me in developing this bipartisan legislation and putting forth our proposal for wilderness. I am hopeful everyone will pull together: county Commissioners, environmentalists, entrepreneurs, chambers of commerce, State elected officials, the Governor, and the  Oregon delegation here in the Capitol. I look forward to perfecting legislation together in the coming weeks, and seeing its swift adoption by Congress thereafter. Then the grandeur of Mount Hood and other Oregon treasures can be assured for future generations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="Introducing S. 650. A bill to amend the Energy Employees Occupational Illness Compensation Program Act of 2000 to provide for certain nuclear weapons program workers to be included in the Special Exposure Cohort under the compensation program established by that Act; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="650">S. 650</bill>] Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="Introducing S. 651. A bill to help promote the national recommendation of physical activity to kids, families, and communities across the United States; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="651">S. 651</bill>] Mr. President, as you may have heard, today we are launching the Partnership for Play Every Day and it has been spearheaded by three terrific organizations: the YMCA, the National Recreation and Park Association, and the National Association for Sport and Physical Education. Together, they have 350 years of experience in helping our kids to be physically active or, to use the old-fashioned word, "to play."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>More than a century ago, these groups came together to support the Playground Movement, which took kids out of factories and coal mines, and gave them parks and playgrounds where they could be children again.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Well, today we face a different challenge. As we confront an epidemic of childhood obesity, as many new elementary schools are built without playgrounds, as recess and PE are phased out of so many of our schools, we need a 21st century Playground Movement. And that's what we are launching this morning.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On a personal note, I have been a lifelong admirer of the YMCA. When I was in my early 20s and aspiring to join the Navy as a fighter pilot, they told me: First you've got to learn how to swim. So what did I do? I signed up at the Y in downtown Des Moines for swimming lessons.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Well, the Y was there for me, just as the Y is there for millions of American families, giving them the facilities and tools to stay fit and healthy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>You know, there is something fundamentally wrong when kids spend their free time parked in front of the TV instead of playing in parks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I mentioned the childhood obesity epidemic. "Epidemic" is not my word. That's what the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention call it. Today, nearly 15 percent of American children and teenagers are obese. A quarter of the children between the ages of 5 and 10 already show the early warning signs of heart disease. Cases of adult-onset diabetes in children--which used to be almost unheard of--have exploded tenfold in the last two decades.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Add it all up, and experts say there is a very real prospect that today's kids could be the first generation in American history to have a shorter lifespan than their parent's generation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And that is unacceptable. We are not going to let that happen. And that is why we have set the goal of ensuring that every child in America gets 60 minutes of play and physical activity every day.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Hand in hand with this important new initiative, today I am honored to introduce with Senator HILLARY CLINTON a bill called the PLAY Every Day Act. That first word, PLAY, is an acronym for "Promoting Lifelong Active Communities."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The PLAY Every Day Act will help to promote the national physical-activity standards for both children and adults.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To that end, the legislation will do two things:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One, it will mandate the development of a well-validated assessment tool called the "community play index," to identify barriers preventing young people from being physically active in a given community.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And two, it will help local coalitions to use this "community play index" as they craft plans to promote physical activity and wellness in their communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My vision is to have every community in America focused on promoting  health and preventing disease--instead of just dealing with the bad consequences of obesity, diabetes, and heart disease.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By the way, I am grateful to the good corporate citizens that are joining in the Partnership for Play Every Day, including PepsiCo, Toyota, Kellogg Company, General Mills, PlayCore, and Landscape Structures. Your support of this legislation and new initiative is going to be critical to the Partnership's success.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, again, I salute all the players in this new Partnership. Together, we can build a better, healthier future for America's children.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="Introducing S. 654. A bill to establish the Food Safety Administration to protect the public health by preventing food-borne illness, ensuring the safety of food, improving research on contaminants leading to food-borne illness, and improving security of food from intentional contamination, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="654">S. 654</bill>] Mr. President, years ago, a friend from Chicago went out and bought hamburger meat at a local grocery store. She took it home, cooked it, and gave it to her five-year-old boy. That poor boy was exposed to E. coli and died a few days later, a gruesome, horrible death.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1992, four children died and 700 people were sickened by an E. coli outbreak that was traced to hamburgers served at Jack in the Box restaurants. That outbreak proved to be a pivotal moment in the history of the beef industry. The Federal Government revamped the meat inspection program which has led a decline in the number of illnesses from beef since 2000.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The E. coli outbreaks from fresh produce that occurred at the end of 2006 may prove to be the critical events for the produce industry as the Jack in the Box outbreak was for the meat industry. Three people died and nearly 200 were sickened in 26 States due to E. coli that was traced back to packaged spinach.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The breadth of the problem of foodborne illness is stunning. The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention estimate that as many as 76 million people suffer from food poisoning each year. Of those individuals, approximately 325,000 will be hospitalized and more than 5,000 will die. Children and the elderly are especially vulnerable to foodborne pathogens. Despite these statistics, our food supply is still the safest in the world; however, there are widening gaps in our food safety system due  to the fact that food safety oversight has evolved over time and is spread across several agencies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As the number of foods imported from outside the United States continues to increase so do concerns that terrorists could easily attack our food supply and distribute a harmful product widely. It is more important now then ever to reinforce any potential weak spots in our food safety system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last month, the Government Accountability Office (GAO) designated the Federal oversight of food safety as a high-risk area. In order to achieve greater effectiveness and accountability, there needs to be a broad-based transformation of our federal food safety oversight. GAO concluded that the fragmented federal system, with 15 agencies collectively administering at least 30 laws, has caused inconsistent oversight and an inefficient use of resources. An accidental or deliberate contamination of  the food supply could undermine consumer confidence and cause severe economic consequences. It is not a surprise that GAO placed food safety oversight on its high-risk list this year. GAO has been calling for a single food safety agency for the past 30 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Here is one example of where our current food safety system doesn't make sense. Take a pre-packaged ham and cheese sandwich that's available at your local convenience store. The way the sandwich is regulated depends on how it is presented. USDA has jurisdiction if the sandwich is a packaged open-face meat or poultry sandwich that contains one slice of bread. If the sandwich is a closed-face meat or poultry sandwich, meaning it has two slices of bread, FDA inspects it. USDA inspects the open-face  sandwiches that are sold in interstate commerce on a daily basis while FDA inspects closed-face sandwiches an average of once every five years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Here's another example that illustrates the inefficient use of resources. The U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) and the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) both inspect shipments of imported food at 18 U.S. ports-of-entry; however the two agencies do not share inspection resources at these ports. USDA import inspectors are assigned to USDA-approved import inspection facilities at these ports and some of the ports also handle FDA-regulated products. USDA does not have jurisdiction over the  FDA-regulated products. USDA has inspectors assigned to these facilities every day while the FDA-regulated products may remain at the facilities for some time awaiting FDA inspection. In fiscal year 2003, USDA spent nearly $16 million on imported food inspections and FDA spent over $115 million. This is just one example of where millions of dollars could have been saved if one agency oversaw the inspection process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Please join me in sponsoring the Safe Food Act of 2007, which addresses our Nation's fractured food safety system. The Safe Food Act of 2007 would create a single, independent Federal food safety agency to administer all aspects of Federal food safety efforts, including inspections, enforcement, standards-setting and research, in order to protect public health. The agencies and sub-agencies now charged with protecting the food supply, primarily housed at the Food and Drug Administration and the  Department of Agriculture, would be transferred to this new agency.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A single food safety agency with authority based on sound scientific principles would provide this country with the greatest hope of reducing foodborne illness, and would also prevent or minimize the harm of a bioterrorist attack on our food supply. The Safe Food Act of 2007 would put authority for imported and domestic food in the hands of one Food Safety Administrator. The Administrator would oversee one science-based food safety law that would harmonize the various authorities that currently  govern food safety regulation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our food distribution system has undergone many changes over the years. For example, in the past, it was likely that produce that ended up in a local grocery store came from a farm not too far from the retailer. Fast forward to today produce grown on a single farm in one state could end up on dinner tables in many states across the country. We cannot continue trying to use a 1950s food safety model to oversee a 21st Century food distribution system. That's like asking a propeller plane to keep  up with an F-18. We need to change, to shed the old bureaucratic shackles that have tied us to the overlapping and inefficient ad hoc food safety system of the past and create a system fit for the 21st Century.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
</record>
