<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1197910803" ordinal="36" title="CONGRATULATING THE VALDOSTA STATE UNIVERSITY FOOTBALL TEAM">
  <narrative>CONGRATULATING THE VALDOSTA STATE UNIVERSITY FOOTBALL TEAM -- (Senate - December 17, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="15791">S15791</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300034" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate now proceed to the consideration of <bill type="sr" number="408">S. Res. 408</bill> which was submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="408">S. Res. 408</bill>) congratulating the Valdosta State University football team on winning the 2007 Division II national championship.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300034" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="408">S. Res. 408</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, is as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="408">S. Res. 408</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas, on December 15, 2007, the Valdosta State University Blazers football team defeated Northwest Missouri State University by a score of 25-20 in Florence, Alabama, to win the 2007 National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA) Division II National Championship;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas this victory gave Valdosta State University its 2nd football national championship title in 4 years;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Coach David Dean became only the 2nd 1st-year head coach in NCAA history to lead a team to the Division II title;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Blazers finished the season with an impressive 13-1 record, including victories over Catawba College, the University of North Alabama, and California University of Pennsylvania in the playoffs to advance to the championship game against Northwest Missouri State University; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas 7 Valdosta State University players were named to the All-Gulf Conference team, including wide receiver Cedric Jones and safety Sherard Reynolds, who were also named to the All-American team: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) congratulates and honors the Valdosta State University Blazers football team on winning the 2007 National Collegiate Athletic Association Division II National Championship;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) recognizes and commends the courage, hard work, and dedication displayed by the Valdosta State University football team and staff throughout the season in order to obtain this great honor; and</chair>
  <chair> (3) commends Valdosta State University, the city of Valdosta, and all of the fans of the Blazers football team throughout the State of Georgia for their endless support of this special team throughout the 2007 championship season.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
