<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1189526401" ordinal="45" title="NATIONAL CHILDHOOD LEAD POISONING PREVENTION WEEK">
  <narrative>NATIONAL CHILDHOOD LEAD POISONING PREVENTION WEEK -- (Senate - September 11, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="11459">S11459</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of <bill type="sr" number="316">S. Res. 316</bill>, submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="316">S. Res. 316</bill>) designating the week of October 21 through October 27, 2007, as "National Childhood Lead Poisoning Prevention Week."</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table, and that any statements relating thereto be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="316">S. Res. 316</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair> <bill type="sr" number="316">S. Res. 316</bill></chair>
  <chair>Whereas lead poisoning is a leading environmental health hazard to children in the United States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas according to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, 240,000 preschool children in the United States have harmful levels of lead in their blood;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas lead poisoning may cause serious, long-term harm to children, including reduced intelligence and attention span, behavior problems, learning disabilities, and impaired growth;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas children from low-income families are significantly more likely to be poisoned by lead than are children from high-income families;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas children may be poisoned by lead in water, soil, or consumable products;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas children most often are poisoned in their homes through exposure to lead particles when lead-based paint deteriorates or is disturbed during home renovation and repainting; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas lead poisoning crosses all barriers of race, income, and geography: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) designates the week of October 21 through October 27, 2007, as "National Childhood Lead Poisoning Prevention Week"; and</chair>
  <chair> (2) calls upon the people of the United States to observe National Childhood Lead Poisoning Prevention Week with appropriate programs and activities. &lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
