<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1172682003" ordinal="37" title="SENATE CONCURRENT RESOLUTION 14--COMMEMORATING THE 85TH ANNIVERSARY OF THE FOUNDING OF THE AMERICAN HELLENIC EDUCATIONAL PROGRESSIVE ASSOCIATION, A LEADING ASSOCIATION FOR THE 1,300,000 UNITED STATES CITIZENS OF GREEK ANCESTRY AND PHILHELLENES IN THE UNITED STATES">
  <speaking speaker="300091" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, this year marks the 85th anniversary of the founding of the American Hellenic Educational Progressive Association, AHEPA. I rise today to submit with my colleague, Senator MENENDEZ, a concurrent resolution honoring AHEPA's history of service, not only to Americans of Greek descent, but to Americans of all backgrounds and to the United States itself.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>AHEPA was founded in 1922 to combat the bigotry encountered by Greek immigrants to this country, and to assist these new Americans with building and protecting their livelihoods in our great Nation. Eighty-five years later--decades in which generations of Greek-Americans worked tirelessly in commerce and fought patriotically on the battlefield to make the United States the prosperous and peaceful land it is today--AHEPA continues its mission to promote the shared Hellenic and American values  of education, philanthropy, civic responsibility, and family and individual excellence.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is more than a mission statement, it is a commitment to action that has been fulfilled time and again. AHEPA today awards more than half a million dollars in academic scholarships annually. Its philanthropic efforts have contributed to the restoration of the Statue of Liberty and Ellis Island. It has enhanced the civic participation of its members and other U.S. citizens through seminars and conferences on key domestic and international policy issues. And, together with three affiliated  organizations--the Daughters of Penelope, the Sons of Pericles and the Maids of Athena--AHEPA has contributed to over a billion dollars in funding for youth- and family-focused projects across the country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As the first Greek-American woman elected to both the House and Senate, I am often reminded that the connection between the U.S. Congress and the Greek people is not limited to the Greek Americans who have served as members, or the foreign policy issues debated in its halls. Rather, the very inspiration for the Congress as a legislative body are the democratic chambers of ancient Greece.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The myriad ties between our two countries--be they cultural, economic or geopolitical--comprise a bond that can and should only strengthen. AHEPA's long record of service to Greek-Americans and their countrymen are both a testament and critical component of that historical bond. It is accordingly an honor and a pleasure to submit this concurrent resolution recognizing the accomplishments of AHEPA's first 85 years. May there be many, many more.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
