<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1177344482" ordinal="32" title="NOTICES OF HEARINGS/MEETINGS">
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON ENERGY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to announce for the information of the Senate and the public that a hearing has been scheduled before the Subcommittee on Energy of the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. The hearing will be held on May 1, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. in room 366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building in Washington, DC.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the hearing is to receive testimony on <bill type="s" number="129">S. 129</bill>, a bill to study and promote the use of energy- efficient computer servers in the United States; <bill type="s" number="838">S. 838</bill>, a bill to authorize funding joint ventures between United States and Israeli businesses and academic persons; <bill type="h" number="85">H.R. 85</bill>, a bill to provide for the establishment of centers to encourage demonstration and commercial application of advanced energy methods and technologies; and <bill type="h" number="1126">H.R. 1126</bill>, a bill  to reauthorize the Steel and Aluminum Energy Conservation and Technology Competitiveness Act of 1988.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of the limited time available for the hearing, witnesses may testify by invitation only. However, those wishing to submit written testimony for the hearing record should send it to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, United States Senate, Washington, DC 20510-6150, or by email to Amanda</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For further information, please contact Jonathan Epstein at (202) 224-3357 or Amanda Kelly at (202) 224-6836.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to announce for the information of the Senate and the public that a hearing has been scheduled before the Subcommittee on Water and Power of the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. The hearing will be held on May 2, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. in room 366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building in Washington, DC.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the hearing is to receive testimony on <bill type="s" number="27">S. 27</bill>, a bill to authorize the implementation of the San Joaquin River Restoration Settlement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of the limited time available for the hearing, witnesses may testify by invitation only. However, those wishing to submit written testimony for the hearing record should send it to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, United States Senate, Washington, DC 20510-6150, or by email to Gina</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For further information, please contact Michael Connor at (202) 224-5479 or Gina Weinstock at (202) 224-5684.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to announce for the information of the Senate and the public that a hearing has been scheduled before Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The hearing will be held on May 3, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the hearing is to receive testimony on the following bills: <bill type="s" number="205">S. 205</bill> and <bill type="h" number="865">H.R. 865</bill>, to grant rights-of-way for electric transmission lines over certain Native allotments in the State of Alaska; <bill type="s" number="390">S. 390</bill>, to direct the exchange of certain land in Grand, San Juan, and Uintah Counties, Utah; <bill type="s" number="647">S. 647</bill>, to designate certain land in the State of Oregon as wilderness; <bill type="s" number="1139">S. 1139</bill>, to establish the National Landscape Conservation System; <bill type="h" number="276">H.R. 276</bill>, to designate the Piedras Blancas Light Station and  the surrounding public land as an Outstanding Natural Area to be administered as a part of the National Landscape Conservation System; and <bill type="h" number="356">H.R. 356</bill>, to remove certain restrictions on the Mammoth Community Water District's ability to use certain property acquired by that District from the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of the limited time available for the hearing, witnesses may testify by invitation only. However, those wishing to submit written testimony for the hearing record should send it to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, United States Senate, Washington, DC 20510-6150, or by email to rachel</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For further information, please contact David Brooks at (202) 224-9863 or Rachel Pasternack at (202) 224-0883.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
