<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1207152003" ordinal="42" title="NATIONAL CUSHING'S SYNDROME AWARENESS DAY">
  <narrative>NATIONAL CUSHING'S SYNDROME AWARENESS DAY -- (Senate - April 02, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="2364">S2364</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate now proceed to the consideration of <bill type="sr" number="498">S. Res. 498</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <chair>The assistant legislative clerk read as follows:</chair>
  <chair>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="498">S. Res. 498</bill>) designating April 8, 2008, as "National Cushing's Syndrome Awareness Day."</chair>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="498">S. Res. 498</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="498">S. Res. 498</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas Cushing's Syndrome affects an estimated 10 to 15 people per 1,000,000 people annually, most of those affected are between the ages of 20 and 50;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Cushing's Syndrome is an endocrine or hormonal disorder caused by the prolonged exposure of the body's tissue to high levels of the hormone cortisol;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas exposure to cortisol can occur by overproduction of cortisol in the body or by taking glucocorticoid hormones, which are routinely prescribed for asthma, rheumatoid arthritis, and lupus, or as an immunosuppressant following organ transplants;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Cushing's Syndrome may also result from pituitary adenomas, ectopic  adrenocorticotropic hormone (ACTH) syndrome, adrenal tumors, and Familial Cushing's Syndrome;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Cushing's Syndrome can cause abnormal weight gain, skin changes, and fatigue and can ultimately lead to diabetes, high blood pressure, depression, osteoporosis, or death;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Cushing's Syndrome is diagnosed through a series of tests, often requiring x-ray examinations of adrenal or pituitary glands to locate tumors;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas many people who suffer from Cushing's Syndrome are misdiagnosed or go undiagnosed for years because many of the symptoms of Cushing's Syndrom are also indications of milder diseases, and those errors in diagnoses delay the implementation of important treatment options;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas treatments for Cushing's Syndrome include surgery, radiation, chemotherapy, the use of cortisol-inhibiting drugs, and reducing the dosage of glucocorticoid hormones;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Cushing's Syndrome was discovered by Dr. Harvey Williams Cushing, who was born on April 8, 1869;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Dr. Harvey Cushing stamp was part of the United States Postal Service's "Great American" series of stamps, initiated in 1980 to recognize individuals for making significant contributions to the heritage and culture of the United States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas President Ronald Reagan spoke on April 8, 1987, in the Rose Garden at a White House ceremony to unveil the commemorative stamp honoring Dr. Harvey Cushing;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, following the ceremony, President Reagan hosted a reception in the State Dining Room for Mrs. John Hay Whitney, Dr. Cushing's daughter, and representatives of the American Association of Neurological Surgeons; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Senate is an institution that can raise awareness of Cushing's Syndrome in the general public and the medical community: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) designates April 8, 2008, as "National Cushing's Syndrome Awareness Day";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) recognizes that all people in the United States should become more informed and aware of Cushing's Syndrome;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) calls upon the people of the United States to observe the date with appropriate ceremonies and activities; and</chair>
  <chair> (4) directs the Secretary of the Senate to transmit a copy of this resolution to the Cushing's Understanding, Support, and Help Organization. &lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
