<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1183046405" ordinal="59" title="NOTICE OF HEARINGS">
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND NATURAL RESOURCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to announce for the information of the Senate and the public that an oversight hearing has been scheduled before the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The hearing will be held on Thursday, July 12, 2007, at 9:30 a.m. in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of this hearing is to consider the nominations of Clarence H. Albright, of South Carolina, to be Under Secretary of Energy; Lisa E. Epifani, of Texas, to be an Assistant Secretary of Energy for Congressional and Intergovernmental Affairs; and, James L. Caswell, of Idaho, to be Director of the Bureau of Land Management.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of the limited time available for the hearing, witnesses may testify by invitation only. However, those wishing to submit written testimony for the hearing record should send two copies of their testimony to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, United States Senate, Washington, DC 20510-6150, or by e-mail to amanda Xkelly@energy.senate.gov.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For further information, please contact Sam Fowler at (202) 224-7571 or Amanda Kelly at (202) 224-6836.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to announce for the information of the Senate and the public that a hearing has been scheduled before Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The hearing will be held on July 12, 2007, at 2:30 p.m., in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the hearing is to receive testimony on the following bills: <bill type="s" number="488">S. 488</bill> and <bill type="h" number="1100">H.R. 1100</bill>, to revise the boundary of the Carl Sandburg Home National Historic Site in the State of North Carolina; <bill type="s" number="617">S. 617</bill>, to make the National Parks and Federal Recreational Lands Pass available at a discount to certain veterans; <bill type="s" number="824">S. 824</bill> and <bill type="h" number="995">H.R. 995</bill>, to amend Public Law 106-348 to extend the authorization for establishing a memorial in the District of Columbia or its environs to honor veterans who became disabled  while serving in the Armed Forces of the United States; <bill type="s" number="955">S. 955</bill>, to establish the Abraham Lincoln National Heritage Area; <bill type="s" number="1148">S. 1148</bill>, to establish the Champlain Quadricentennial Commemoration Commission and the Hudson-Fulton 400th Commemoration Commission; <bill type="s" number="1182">S. 1182</bill>, to amend the Quinebaug and Shetucket Rivers Valley National Heritage Corridor Act of 1994 to increase the authorization of appropriations and modify the date on which the authority of the Secretary</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of the limited time available for the hearing, witnesses may testify by invitation only. However, those wishing to submit written testimony for the hearing record should send it to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, United States Senate, Washington, DC 20510-6150, or by e-mail to rachel Xpasternack@energy.senate.&#xD0;gov.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For further information, please contact David Brooks at (202) 224-9863 or Rachel Pasternack at (202) 224-0883.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
