<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1228842003" ordinal="34" title="PANCREATIC CANCER AWARENESS MONTH">
  <narrative>PANCREATIC CANCER AWARENESS MONTH -- (Senate - December 09, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="10835">S10835</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the HELP Committee be discharged from further consideration of <bill type="sr" number="720">S. Res. 720</bill> and the Senate proceed to its immediate consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will report the resolution by title.</narrative>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="720">S. Res. 720</bill>) supporting the goals and ideals of Pancreatic Cancer Awareness Month.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="720">S. Res. 720</bill>) was agreed to.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The preamble was agreed to.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>
      <bill type="sr" number="720">S. Res. 720</bill>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>Whereas approximately 37,680 people will be diagnosed with pancreatic cancer this year in the United States;  &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas pancreatic cancer is the 4th most common cause of cancer death in the United States;  &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Randolph ("Randy") Frederick Pausch, who was diagnosed with pancreatic cancer in 2006, delivered his "Last Lecture" on September 18, 2007, which gave a voice to victims of pancreatic cancer, and inspired people to live life to the fullest;   &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the lecture by and advocacy of Randy Pausch have brought, and will continue to bring, renewed advocacy and commitment to the field of pancreatic cancer research and treatment;  &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the lecture by and advocacy of Randy Pausch have touched countless people throughout the United States and the world and encouraged them to change their lives for the better;  &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas 75 percent of pancreatic cancer patients die within the first year of their diagnosis and only 5 percent survive more than 5 years, making pancreatic cancer the deadliest of any cancer;  &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas there has been no significant improvement in survival rates in the last 30 years and pancreatic cancer research is still in the earliest scientific stages;  &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas there are no early detection methods and minimal treatment options for pancreatic cancer;  &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas when symptoms of pancreatic cancer present themselves, it is generally too late for an optimistic prognosis, and the average survival rate of those diagnosed with metastasis of the disease is only 3 to 6 months;  &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the incidence rate of pancreatic cancer is 40 to 50 percent higher in African-Americans than in other ethnic groups; and  &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas it would be appropriate to observe November as Pancreatic Cancer Awareness Month to educate communities across the Nation about pancreatic cancer and the need for research funding, early detection methods, effective treatments, and treatment programs: Now, therefore, be it</paragraph>
    <paragraph> Resolved, That the Senate supports the goals and ideals of Pancreatic Cancer Awareness Month.  &lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
