<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1185940800" ordinal="54" title="EXECUTIVE SESSION">
  <narrative>EXECUTIVE SESSION -- (Senate - August 01, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="10680">S10680</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412246" topic="EXECUTIVE CALENDAR">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to executive session to consider Executive Calendar Nos. 162, 230, 231, 243, 244, 250, 251, 252, 253, 254, 257 through 272, and all nominations placed on the Secretary's desk; further, that the Senate Foreign Relations Committee be discharged from the following nominations: PN 579, Eric G. John to be Ambassador to Thailand, and PN 604, Michael Michalak to be Ambassador to Vietnam; that the Agriculture Committee be discharged  from the following nominations: PN 479, Jill Sommers, and PN 480, Bartholomew Chilton, to be Commissioners of the Commodity Futures Trading Commission; that the nominations be confirmed, the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table, that any statements thereon be printed in the Record, the President be immediately notified of the Senate's action, and the Senate then return to legislative session.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The nominations, considered and confirmed, are as follows:</chair>
  <chair>Thomas P. D'Agostino, of Maryland, to be Under Secretary for Nuclear Security, Department of Energy.</chair>
  <chair>Bijan Rafiekian, of California, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the Export-Import Bank of the United States for a term expiring January 20, 2011. (Reappointment).</chair>
  <chair>Diane G. Farrell, of Connecticut, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the Export-Import Bank of the United States for a term expiring January 20, 2011.</chair>
  <chair>Joe W. Stecher, of Nebraska, to be United States Attorney for the District of Nebraska for the term of four years.</chair>
  <chair>Charles L. Hopkins, of Massachusetts, to be an Assistant Secretary of Veterans Affairs (Operations, Preparedness, Security and Law Enforcement).</chair>
  <chair>David C. Geary, of Missouri, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the National Board for Education Sciences for a term expiring November 28, 2010.</chair>
  <chair>Miguel Campaneria, of Puerto Rico, to be a Member of the National Council on the Arts for a term expiring September 3, 2012.</chair>
  <chair>Diane Auer Jones, of Maryland, to be Assistant Secretary for Postsecondary Education, Department of Education.</chair>
  <chair>Peter B. McCarthy, of Wisconsin, to be an Assistant Secretary of the Treasury.</chair>
  <chair>David H. McCormick, of Pennsylvania, to be an Under Secretary of the Treasury.</chair>
  <chair>The following named officer for appointment in the United States Air Force to the grade indicated while assigned to a position of importance and responsibility under title 10, U.S.C., section 601:</chair>
  <chair>To be lieutenant general &lt;br&gt;Maj. Gen. Daniel J. Darnell, 0600</chair>
  <chair>The following named officer for appointment in the United States Air Force to the grade indicated under title 10, U.S.C., section 624:</chair>
  <chair>To be brigadier general &lt;br&gt;Col. Lyn D. Sherlock, 8452</chair>
  <chair>The following named officer for appointment in the United States Air Force to the grade indicated while assigned to a position of importance and responsibility under title 10, U.S.C., section 601:</chair>
  <chair>To be lieutenant general &lt;br&gt;Maj. Gen. Donald C. Wurster, 1815</chair>
  <chair>The following named officer for appointment as the Vice Chief of Staff, United States Air Force, and appointment to the grade indicated while assigned to a position of importance and responsibility under title 10, U.S.C., sections 8034 and 601:</chair>
  <chair>To be general &lt;br&gt;Gen. Duncan J. McNabb, 2295</chair>
  <chair>The following named officer for appointment in the United States Air Force to the grade indicated while assigned to a position of importance and responsibility under title 10, U.S.C., section 601:</chair>
  <chair>To be general &lt;br&gt;Lt. Gen. Arthur J. Lichte, 5483</chair>
  <chair>The following named officer for appointment in the United States Air Force to the grade indicated while assigned to a position of importance and responsibility under title 10, U.S.C., section 601:</chair>
  <chair>To be general &lt;br&gt;Gen. John D. W. Corley, 9553</chair>
  <chair>The following named officer for appointment in the United States Air Force to the grade indicated while assigned to a position of importance and responsibility under title 10, U.S.C., section 601:</chair>
  <chair>To be lieutenant general &lt;br&gt;Lt. Gen. Frank G. Klotz, 6089</chair>
  <chair>The following named officers for appointment in the United States Air Force to the grade indicated under title 10, U.S.C., section 624:</chair>
  <chair>To be major general &lt;br&gt;Brigadier General Robert R. Allardice, 0051</chair>
  <chair>The following Army National Guard of the United States officer for appointment in the Reserve of the Army to the grade indicated under title 10, U.S.C., section 12203:</chair>
  <chair>To be brigadier general &lt;br&gt;Col. Bradly S. MacNealy, 4551</chair>
  <chair>The following named officer for appointment in the Reserve of the Army to the grade indicated under title 10, U.S.C., section 12203:</chair>
  <chair>To be brigadier general &lt;br&gt;Col. Michael J. Trombetta, 2104</chair>
  <chair>The following named officers for appointment in the United States Army to the grade indicated under title 10, U.S.C., section 624:</chair>
  <chair>To be major general &lt;br&gt;Brigadier General Charles A. Anderson, 4562</chair>
  <chair>The following named officers for appointment in the United States Navy to the grade indicated under title 10, U.S.C., section 624:</chair>
  <chair>To be rear admiral &lt;br&gt;Rear Adm. (lh) Victor G. Guillory, 1980</chair>
  <chair>The following named officer for appointment in the United States Navy to the grade indicated under title 10, U.S.C., section 624:</chair>
  <chair>To be rear admiral (lower half) &lt;br&gt;Capt. David J. Mercer, 7160</chair>
  <chair>The following named officer for appointment in the United States Navy to the grade indicated while assigned to a position of importance and responsibility under title 10, U.S.C., section 601:</chair>
  <chair>To be vice admiral &lt;br&gt;Rear Adm. David Architzel, 0741</chair>
  <chair>The following named officer for appointment in the United States Navy to the grade indicated while assigned to a position of importance and responsibility under title 10, U.S.C., section 601:</chair>
  <chair>To be vice admiral &lt;br&gt;Vice Adm. John D. Stufflebeem, 4012</chair>
  <chair>The following named officer for appointment as Chief of the Bureau of Medicine and Surgery and Surgeon General and for appointment to the grade indicated under title 10, D.S.C., sections 601 and 5137:</chair>
  <chair>To be vice admiral &lt;br&gt;Rear Adm. (Selectee) Adam M. Robinson, Jr.,</chair>
  <chair>Nominations Placed on the Scretary's Desk</chair>
  <chair>PN368 AIR FORCE nominations (27) beginning MARIA M. ALSINA, and ending LE THI ZIMMERMAN, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of March 19, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN741 AIR FORCE nomination of Jonathan L. Huggins, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of July 12, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN742 AIR FORCE nomination of Nelson L. Reynolds, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of July 12, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN743 AIR FORCE nomination of Bryan M. Boyles, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of July 12, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN744 AIR FORCE nomination of Michael S. Agabegi, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of July 12, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN745 AIR FORCE nomination of Freddie M. Goldwire, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of July 12, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN746 AIR FORCE nominations (4) beginning VAL C. HAGANS, and ending RUJING HAN, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of July 12, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN747 AIR FORCE nominations (3) beginning KENT S. THOMPSON, and ending JAVIER SANTIAGO, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of July 12, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN748 AIR FORCE nominations (4) beginning THOMAS S. BUTLER, and ending ADAM W. SCHNICKER, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of July 12, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN628 ARMY nominations (32) beginning JAMES E. CARAWAY JR., and ending WILLIAM S. WEICHL, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of June 4, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN749 ARMY nomination of Stephen T. Sauter, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of July 12, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN750 ARMY nomination of Terry D. Bonner, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of July 12, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN751 ARMY nomination of Mark Trawinski, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of July 12, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN752 ARMY nomination of Francisco C. Dominicci, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of July 12, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN753 ARMY nomination of Joseph E. Jones, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of July 12, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN754 ARMY nomination of Colin S. McKenzie, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of July 12, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN755 ARMY nominations (2) beginning LOZAY FOOTS, and ending JOSEPH L. KARHAN, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of July 12, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN756 ARMY nominations (2) beginning LOUIS R. KUBALA, and ending THOMAS K. SPEARS, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of July 12, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN757 ARMY nominations (2) beginning WILLIAM A. MCNAUGHTON, and ending MICHAEL B. VITT, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of July 12, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN758 ARMY nominations (3) beginning JAMES E. COLE, and ending MICHAEL F. TRAVER, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of July 12, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN759 ARMY nominations (2) beginning DANIEL L. DUECKER, and ending DOUGLAS L. WEEKS, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of July 12, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN760 ARMY nominations (44) beginning JOSEPH A. BERNIERRODRIGUEZ, and ending EDWARD M. WISE JR., which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of July 12, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN770 ARMY nominations (342) beginning MAZEN ABBAS, and ending TAMATHA F. ZEMZARS, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of July 17, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN567 NAVY nominations (206) beginning NICHOLAS J. ALAGA JR., and ending MARK H. ZUHONE, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of May 15, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN702 NAVY nomination of PETER J. OLDMIXON, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of June 28, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN703 NAVY nominations (43) beginning DAN L. AMMONS, and ending ROBERT D. WOODS, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of June 28, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN704 NAVY nominations (19) beginning GILBERT AYAN, and ending COLIN D. XANDER, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of June 28, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN705 NAVY nominations (16) beginning SIMONIA R. BLASSINGAME, and ending JASON L. WEBB, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of June 28, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN706 NAVY nominations (20) beginning JEFFREY A. BAYLESS, and ending WARREN YU, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of June 28, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN707 NAVY nominations (26) beginning CHRIS D. AGAR, and ending TYRONE L. WARD, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of June 28, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN708 NAVY nominations (27) beginning PAUL B. ANDERSON, and ending DARREN S. WILLIAMS, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of June 28, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN709 NAVY nominations (5) beginning CHRISTINA S. HAGEN, and ending RON A. STEINER, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of June 28, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN710 NAVY nominations (14) beginning CHRISTOPHER J. ARENDS, and ending KEITH E. WILLIAMS, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of June 28, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN711 NAVY nominations (10) beginning SARAH A. DACHOS, and ending CLAY G. WILLIAMS, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of June 28, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN712 NAVY nomination (26) beginning BENITO E. BAYLOSIS, and ending JON E. WITHEE, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of June 28, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN713 NAVY nominations (18) beginning DOUGLAS S. BELVIN, and ending KYLE T. TURCO, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of June 28, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN714 NAVY nominations (9) beginning FITZGERALD BRITTON, and ending JOHN F. ZREMBSKI, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of June 28, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN715 NAVY nominations (56) beginning WILLIAM L. ABBOTT, and ending ALLEN W. WOOTEN, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of June 28, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN716 NAVY nominations (538) beginning KEVIN T. AANESTAD, and ending WILLIAM A. ZIEGLER, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of June 28, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN761 NAVY nomination of BRUCE S. LAVIN, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of July 12, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN762 NAVY nominations (2) beginning CHRISTOPHER R. DAVIS, and ending ALAN J. FERGUSON, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of July 12, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN763 NAVY nominations (3) beginning ROBERT D. CLERY, and ending GARFIELD M. SICARD, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of July 12, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN771 NAVY nominations (56) beginning MICHAEL J. ALLANSON, and ending JANINE Y. WOOD, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of July 17, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN772 NAVY nominations (36) beginning MARIA L. AGUAYO, and ending STEVEN T. ZIMMERMAN, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of July 17, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN773 NAVY nominations (27) beginning ANTONY BERCHMANZ, and ending GLEN WOOD, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of July 17, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN774 NAVY nominations (58) beginning ERIC J. BACH, and ending WILLIAM B. ZABICKI JR., which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of July 17, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN775 NAVY nominations (116) beginning ELIZABETH M. ADRIANO, and ending SCOT A. YOUNGBLOOD, which nominations were received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of July 17, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>Eric G. John, of Indiana, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Kingdom of Thailand.</chair>
  <chair>Michael W. Michalak, of Michigan, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Socialist Republic of Vietnam.</chair>
  <chair>Jill E. Sommers, of Kansas, to be a Commissioner of the Commodity Futures Trading Commission for the remainder of the term expiring April 13, 2009, vice Sharon Brown-Hruska, resigned.</chair>
  <chair>Bartholomew H. Chilton, of Delaware, to be a Commissioner of the Commodity Futures Trading Commission for the remainder of the term expiring April 13, 2008, vice Frederick William Hatfield, resigned.</chair>
</record>
