<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1170262802" ordinal="16" title="SEC INVESTIGATION FINDINGS">
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I am very happy to be on the floor with my colleague Senator Specter on something we have worked on together over a long period of time, and it falls very much into the category of congressional oversight. I am not going to go into the details now because I have a statement I want to use as a basis for our cooperation, and then you will hear from Senator Specter. I want to say how great it was to work with Senator Specter.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are here to update the Senate on the interim Finance Committee findings of the joint investigation into the Securities and Exchange Commission that was conducted by the Finance Committee on the one hand, and the Judiciary Committee on the other, during the 109th Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Before I go into details, there is another person I would thank for his cooperation. I want to take this opportunity to thank Securities and Exchange Commission Chairman Christopher Cox for his cooperation in providing access to thousands of pages of documents, as well as interviews with the staff at the Securities and Exchange Commission. Chairman Cox's cooperation was very essential to our ability to conduct our constitutionally mandated oversight of Federal agencies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That said, I hope Chairman Cox takes today's findings to heart and will work to implement recommendations Senator Specter and I plan to put forth into the forthcoming final report.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, we want to update the Senate on some of the details of our investigation, which began early last year when allegations were presented to our staffs by former Securities and Exchange Commission attorney Gary Aguirre. Mr. Aguirre described the roadblocks he faced in pursuing an insider trading investigation while he was employed as a senior enforcement attorney at the Securities and Exchange Commission. Specifically, he alleged his supervisor prevented him from taking the testimony of a  prominent Wall Street figure because of his "political clout," which obviously should not be ignored if an agency is doing the job they should be doing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Well, after Mr. Aguirre complained about that sort of preferential treatment given to somebody with "political clout," his supervisors terminated him from the SEC while he was on vacation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The interim findings we released today outlined the three primary concerns shared by Senator Specter and me. First, the SEC's investigation into Pequot Capital Management was plagued with problems from its beginning to its abrupt conclusion. Second, the termination of Mr. Aguirre by the SEC was highly suspect given the timing and the circumstances. Thirdly, the original investigation conducted by the SEC Office of Inspector General was both seriously and fatally flawed. The inspector  general's failure required our committees to take a more thorough look at Mr. Aguirre's allegations and examine this matter closely. Taken together, these findings paint a picture of a troubled agency that faces serious questions about public confidence, the integrity of its investigations, and its ability to protect all investors, large and small, with an even hand.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The SEC should have taken Mr. Aguirre's allegations more seriously and very seriously. Instead, it does like too many agencies do when under fire: it circled the wagons and it shot a whistleblower--an all too familiar practice in Washington, DC. As we know, whistleblowers are about as welcome as a skunk at a picnic.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is more information to follow and more details that need to come to light. Senator Specter and I together plan on releasing a comprehensive report in the near future. For now, I hope these interim findings will spur the SEC to consider meaningful reforms. I urge all my colleagues to read these important interim findings and to read the final report when it is made available.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Pennsylvania.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300092" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to begin by thanking my distinguished colleague, Senator Grassley, for his outstanding work on the issues which he has just addressed. Senator Grassley and I have a long record of working together. We were elected together in November 1980 with the election of Ronald Reagan. There were 16 members of the incoming class of Republican Senators at that time. Two Democrats were elected.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the intervening years, Senator Grassley and I have become the sole survivors, and we have done a great deal of work together.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We sit together on the Judiciary Committee, and Senator Grassley has had a very distinguished record as chairman of the Senate Finance Committee during the 109th Congress, and I chaired the Judiciary Committee during the 109th Congress. We are making a presentation today of interim findings on the investigation into potential abuse of authority at the Securities and Exchange Commission.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I join Senator Grassley in commending the Chairman of the SEC, Christopher Cox, for his cooperation, and I also join Senator Grassley in urging Chairman Cox and the SEC to do more. The oversight which our two committees undertook constituted a review of over 9,000 pages of documents and the interviewing of 19 witnesses over the course of 24 interviews.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Judiciary Committee, on which we both serve, held a series of three public hearings regarding this matter, most recently on December 5, 2006, when the committee heard detailed sworn testimony from current and former SEC employees involved in the so-called Pequot investigation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Based upon our review of the evidence, we have serious concerns, which are documented in a lengthy report, which we will make a part of the record, plus supplemental documents. Our investigation has raised concerns about, first, the SEC's mishandling of the Pequot investigation before, during, and after the firing of Mr. Gary Aguirre; secondly, the circumstances under which Mr. Aguirre was terminated; and third, the manner in which the SEC's Inspector General's Office handled Mr. Aguirre's allegations  after he was fired.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Viewing these concerns as a whole, we believe a very troubling picture evolves. At best, the picture shows extraordinarily lax enforcement by the SEC, and it may even indicate a coverup by the SEC. We are concerned, first of all, as detailed in this report, that the SEC failed to act on the GE/Heller trades for years. We are concerned about the suggestions of political power which was present in the investigation, which has all of the earmarks of a possible obstruction of justice.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is sworn testimony by Mr. Gary Aguirre that he was told in a face-to-face meeting with his immediate supervisor, Branch Chief Robert Hanson, that he could not take the testimony of Mr. John Mack, who was thought to have leaked confidential information. Mr. Aguirre testified that Mr. Hanson refused to allow the taking of testimony, as Mr. Aguirre pointed out, because of Mr. Mack's "powerful political contacts."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, Mr. Hanson denied to the SEC inspector general and to the committee that he ever said that, but we have contemporaneous e-mails, for example, where Mr. Hanson admitted to a very similar statement when he wrote to Mr. Aguirre on August 24, 2005, "Most importantly, the political clout I mentioned to you was a reason to keep Paul," referring to a man named Paul Berger, "and possibly Linda," referring to a woman named Linda Thomsen, "in the loop on the testimony." Now, that is conclusive  proof of the political clout or at least what Mr. Hanson thought was political clout when the SEC made a decision not to permit the taking of key testimony, the testimony</paragraph>
    <paragraph>of Mr. Mack.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Hanson submitted a written statement to the committee concluding that it was "highly suspect and illogical" to link Mr. Mack as the tipper, but in his prior writings he said, in written form, "Mack is another bad guy."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The rationale used by the SEC officials who denied Mr. Aguirre's request to take the testimony of Mr. Mack was that they wanted to get "their ducks in a row." But the overwhelming evidence in the matter showed that the testimony should have been taken at a much earlier stage. There is no problem with taking testimony again if necessary at a later stage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A key SEC investigator, Mr. Hilton Foster, with knowledge of the Pequot matter, said, "As the SEC expert on insider trading, if people had asked me, `When do you take his testimony,' I would have said take it yesterday."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Joseph Cella, Chief of the SEC's Market Surveillance Commission, told committee investigators, "it seemed to me that it was a reasonable thing to do to bring Mack in and have him testify," and "in my mind there was no down side."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Mack's testimony was taken 5 days after the statute of limitations expired. But let me point out at this juncture that even though the statute of limitations has expired, there is injunctive relief and other action that can yet be taken by the SEC.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The problems with the Pequot investigation are amplified by the suspect termination of Mr. Aguirre. On June 1, 2005, in a performance plan and evaluation, Mr. Aguirre was given an acceptable rating, and Mr. Hanson, on June 29, 2005, noted Mr. Aguirre's "unmatched dedication" to the Pequot investigation and "contributions of high quality." These evaluations were submitted to the SEC's Compensation Committee, which later approved Mr. Hanson's recommendation on July 18. Despite these favorable  reviews, Aguirre's supervisors wrote a so-called supplemental evaluation on August 1, and this reevaluation on August 1 occurred 5 days after Mr. Aguirre sent supervisor Berger an e-mail saying that he believed the Pequot investigation was being halted because of Mr. Mack's political power.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There was an investigation by the inspector general of the SEC, and in my years in the Senate and hearing many inspectors general testify, I can't recall hearing an inspector general who said less, did less, and was more thoroughly inadequate in the investigation. For example, the inspector general's staff said, "we don't second guess management's decisions. We don't second guess why employees are terminated." Well, that is precisely the purpose of having an inspector general. The purpose of  having an inspector general is to review those kinds of decisions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The inspector general testified that he was given advice by the Department of Justice, which made absolutely no sense. This appears in some detail in the record.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Then the inspector general initiated an attempt to take what was really punitive action against Mr. Aguirre by seeking enforcement of a subpoena for documents which were involving Mr. Aguirre's communications with Congress. Now, how can an individual communicate, talk to an oversight committee, such as the Judiciary Committee or the Finance Committee, if those communications are going to be subject to a subpoena by the SEC, by the inspector general? It is just preposterous. We have constitutional  oversight responsibilities, and we obviously cannot conduct those responsibilities if the information we glean is going to be subject to somebody else's review.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The subpoena wasn't pursued, but the lack of judgment--and it is hard to find a strong enough word which is not insensitive to describe the inspector general's conduct in trying to subpoena the records of the Senate Judiciary Committee and the Senate Finance Committee. It just made absolutely no sense.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We hope that the SEC will reopen its investigation even though the statute of limitations has run on criminal penalties. It has run because of the inaction of the SEC waiting so long to start the investigation, then not taking Mr. Mack's testimony until 5 days after the statute of limitations had expired. Notwithstanding that, there are other remedies, such as disgorgement, which still may be pursued.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The oversight function of Congress, as we all know, is very important. Pursuing an investigation of this sort is highly technical, but we have done so, so far, in a preliminary manner. We believe this matter is of sufficient importance so that Senator Grassley and I have come to the floor jointly today to make a statement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On behalf of Senator Grassley and myself, I ask unanimous consent that the full text of the interim findings on the investigation of potential abuse of authority of the Securities and Exchange Commission be printed in the Record, together with extensive documentation which supports the findings.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, we acknowledge the cooperation of Chairman Cox and the SEC, and we ask that further investigation be undertaken there. It is a matter of continuing oversight concern to Senator Grassley and myself and the respective committees where we now serve as ranking members.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask Senator Grassley, what did I leave out?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="">
    <paragraph>You didn't leave anything out, but we did ask unanimous consent that this be put in.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300092" topic="THERE DO NOT APPEAR TO BE OTHER LEADS IN THE SAMBERG E-MAILS">
    <paragraph>In the absence of any Senator on the floor seeking recognition, I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300092" topic="THERE DO NOT APPEAR TO BE OTHER LEADS IN THE SAMBERG E-MAILS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300092" topic="THERE DO NOT APPEAR TO BE OTHER LEADS IN THE SAMBERG E-MAILS">
    <paragraph>Madam President, a personal comment or two. On the Senate floor, some years ago, I compared Senator Grassley to Senator Harry Truman, later President Harry Truman. I did so after observing Senator Grassley's work over a long period of time. Senator Grassley prides himself on being a farmer--on being a farmer Senator. May the record show that Senator Grassley is nodding in the affirmative. It may be--Senator Grassley would have to speak  for himself--he prides himself more on his status as a farmer than as a Senator. But if he were to do that, I would disagree with him, even not knowing his prowess as a farmer because of his prowess as a Senator.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator Grassley is very direct and very plain spoken. I know of his career when he became a member of the Iowa legislature, the lower house. I have only a recollection, Senator Grassley can correct me, that he earned $6 a day in the Iowa legislature at that time?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="THERE DO NOT APPEAR TO BE OTHER LEADS IN THE SAMBERG E-MAILS">
    <paragraph>It was $30 a day but no expenses.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300092" topic="THERE DO NOT APPEAR TO BE OTHER LEADS IN THE SAMBERG E-MAILS">
    <paragraph>It was $30 a day but no expenses. As I recollect, Senator Grassley told me it was an increase in pay from what he earned as a farmer.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="THERE DO NOT APPEAR TO BE OTHER LEADS IN THE SAMBERG E-MAILS">
    <paragraph>It was.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300092" topic="THERE DO NOT APPEAR TO BE OTHER LEADS IN THE SAMBERG E-MAILS">
    <paragraph>It was. Senator Grassley corroborates that. But I have seen Senator Grassley take on the giants in the Senate. They say people in glass houses should not throw stones. Senator Grassley has thrown a lot of stones in the 26 years he has been here and he doesn't live in a glass house, but he has taken on the giants in the Federal executive branch. He believes thoroughly in oversight, as I do. The work we are submitting today is an example of that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think it is a good analogy, between Chuck Grassley and Harry Truman. I may search the Congressional Record to see how long ago it was that I said it, but it is time it is said again.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="THERE DO NOT APPEAR TO BE OTHER LEADS IN THE SAMBERG E-MAILS">
    <paragraph>Thank you, I appreciate that.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300092" topic="THERE DO NOT APPEAR TO BE OTHER LEADS IN THE SAMBERG E-MAILS">
    <paragraph>May the record show Senator Grassley said thank you, and he appreciates it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I may make one addendum, and that is that I say this notwithstanding the 26-years-plus ribbing I have taken from Senator Grassley for being a Philadelphia lawyer.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="THERE DO NOT APPEAR TO BE OTHER LEADS IN THE SAMBERG E-MAILS">
    <paragraph>I have always said: Thank God we only have to have one Philadelphia lawyer in the Senate.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300092" topic="THERE DO NOT APPEAR TO BE OTHER LEADS IN THE SAMBERG E-MAILS">
    <paragraph>The Senator said off-camera: Thank God we only have one Philadelphia lawyer in the Senate.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="THERE DO NOT APPEAR TO BE OTHER LEADS IN THE SAMBERG E-MAILS">
    <paragraph>But I say that complimentary.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300092" topic="THERE DO NOT APPEAR TO BE OTHER LEADS IN THE SAMBERG E-MAILS">
    <paragraph>But says it complimentary. I don't know. The tone of his voice was usually derisive. There was one time the Senate had two Philadelphia lawyers, Senator Hugh Scott and Senator Joe Clark, they were lawyers together. Senator Clark was elected to the Senate in 1956 for two terms and Senator Scott in 1958 for three terms. So there was an overlapping period of time where there were two Philadelphia lawyers in the Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But notwithstanding the questioning tone, sometimes, of Senator Grassley about a Philadelphia lawyer, I maintain my view of him at the highest level of comparison to President Truman.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="THERE DO NOT APPEAR TO BE OTHER LEADS IN THE SAMBERG E-MAILS">
    <paragraph>Thank you.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300092" topic="THERE DO NOT APPEAR TO BE OTHER LEADS IN THE SAMBERG E-MAILS">
    <paragraph>I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300099" topic="THERE DO NOT APPEAR TO BE OTHER LEADS IN THE SAMBERG E-MAILS">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered. The Senator from Virginia is recognized.</chair>
</record>
