<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1216828802" ordinal="18" title="STOP EXCESSIVE ENERGY SPECULATION ACT OF 2008">
  <narrative>STOP EXCESSIVE ENERGY SPECULATION ACT OF 2008 -- (Senate - July 23, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="7129">S7129</bill>]</narrative>
  <chair> All time has expired.</chair>
  <chair>The question is on agreeing to the motion to proceed.</chair>
  <chair>The motion was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair> The clerk will report the bill.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A bill (<bill type="s" number="3268">S. 3268</bill>) to amend the Commodity Exchange Act, to prevent excessive price speculation with respect to energy commodities, and for other purposes.</narrative>
  <chair> The majority leader.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I have an amendment at the desk, and I ask for its consideration at this time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the amendment.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>The Senator from Nevada [Mr. Reid] proposes an amendment numbered 5098.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that further reading of the amendment be waived.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The amendment is as follows:</chair>
  <chair>The provisions of this bill shall become effective 5 days after enactment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask for the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there a sufficient second? There appears to be a sufficient second.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I have a second-degree amendment at the desk, and I ask that it be reported.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the amendment.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>The Senator from Nevada [Mr. Reid] proposes an amendment numbered 5099 to amendment No. 5098.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that further reading of the amendment be waived.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The amendment is as follows:</chair>
  <chair>In the amendment, strike "5" and insert "4".</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, it seems that the Republicans have two tools in their obstruction and delay kit. It is a tool kit that has worked quite well for them. First, they prevent the Senate from getting to bills. The Republican leader uses this tool when he can convince enough of his caucus to kill legislation before the Senate debate even begins.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second, when a bill is so popular that the Republican leader is unable to convince enough of his colleagues to kill it before debate can begin, he switches to his second tool--claiming the process is unfair. That is what we have before us today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Republican leader requests an unlimited or virtually unlimited number of amendments on which he is unable or unwilling to provide specifics. When these requests are not accepted in their entirety, as the Republican leader knows they cannot be, he then turns to his caucus and asks them to oppose any further action on the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Regardless of which tool the minority leader uses, the result is the same. The Republicans refuse to let us address the most critical priorities of the American people.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This situation reminds me of a story I learned as a young lawyer that has now become somewhat legendary, which says: If you have the facts, you pound the facts. If you have the law, you pound the law. If you have neither, you pound the table.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is exactly what is happening today and has happened on many other occasions. Unfortunately, it has happened, Mr. President, a record number of times this session--84 filibusters. That is obstruction at its zenith.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Republicans would love to muddy the issue by claiming that the Democratic majority won't let them be heard, but that is simply not the truth. Democrats have proposed a comprehensive plan to address our energy crisis, starting with speculation. The Republicans, if they do not like our speculation legislation, let them offer something to the contrary. The Republicans have been talking about their plan for weeks and weeks now. That plan is to drill, to drill, and to drill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, both parties want more drilling. It is not something that simply the Republicans want. We Democrats believe that increasing domestic production is certainly a big part of the problem, and we should do something about it. But, Mr. President, realistically--and we all know this--realistically we have a situation where we have, counting ANWR and all the offshore oil, less than 3 percent of the oil in the world. We use more than 25 percent of the world's oil every day. So we can't produce our  way out of the problem. We can certainly increase domestic production, and we should do that, and we have a comprehensive plan to do that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our approach is different from theirs on drilling. We believe our approach is more responsible because we basically force the oil companies to take a look at the land and do an inventory of it and tell us why they are not using certain pieces of land. That is 68 million acres in addition to about 25 million acres in Alaska that are available with the signing of the President's pen. That increases it up to, as you know, about 90 million acres.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have offered our plan to the Republicans. They say they want to drill. They have talked about what their drilling plan is, and we have said: Let's have a vote on it. But they have said no. They can't take yes for an answer. So it is very clear. The only conclusion the American people can reach from this is that the Republicans would rather talk than act. They would rather score, in their own minds, some kind of political points with the oil companies than accomplish something for the American  people.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Republican leadership has refused our offer of votes on drilling, so I am going to now, Mr. President, file cloture on this piece of legislation before us--the speculation legislation. I think it is very important that we do that, and it is important for a number of reasons.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I should mention that one of the things they refuse to take yes for an answer on is their drilling proposal. But I am confident the American people are seeing what the Republicans are doing, and have been doing, for 18 months--talking and talking about drilling and then running for the exits when we give them a vote on what they have asked to do.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am equally confident, when given a choice of who to send to Congress, the American people will choose to send people who want to get things done and not those who seek delay, obstruction, and the failed ways of the past.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <chair>The legislative clerk proceeded to call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I apologize to everyone. I wanted to make sure I hadn't missed anything in my script.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I now send a cloture motion to the desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The cloture motion having been presented under rule XXII, the Chair directs the clerk to read the cloture motion.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>Cloture Motion</narrative>
  <narrative>We, the undersigned Senators, in accordance with the provisions of rule XXII of the Standing Rules of the Senate, hereby move to bring to a close debate on <bill type="s" number="3268">S. 3268</bill>, the Stop Excessive Energy Speculation Act of 2008.</narrative>
  <chair> By unanimous consent, the mandatory quorum call has been waived.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="MOTION TO COMMIT">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I move to commit the bill to agricultural committee with instructions to report back forthwith, with an amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the motion.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>The Senator from Nevada [Mr. Reid] moves to commit the bill (<bill type="s" number="3268">S. 3268</bill>) to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition and Forestry with instructions to report back forthwith, with an amendment numbered 5100.</narrative>
  <narrative>The amendment is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>At the end, insert the following:</narrative>
  <narrative>This title shall become effective 3 days after enactment of the bill.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="MOTION TO COMMIT">
    <paragraph>I ask for the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there a sufficient second?</chair>
  <chair>There appears to be a sufficient second.</chair>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I have an amendment to the instruction at the desk. I ask now for its consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>The Senator from Nevada [Mr. Reid] proposes an amendment numbered 5101, to the instructions of the motion to commit.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent the reading of the amendment be dispensed with.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The amendment is as follows:</chair>
  <chair>In the amendment, strike "3" and insert "2".</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask for the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there a sufficient second? There appears to be a sufficient second.</chair>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I now have a seconddegree amendment at the desk. I ask the clerk to report the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>The Senator from Nevada [Mr. Reid] proposes an amendment numbered 5102 to amendment No. 5101.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent the reading of the amendment be dispensed with.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The amendment is as follows:</chair>
  <chair>In the amendment, strike "2" and insert "1".</chair>
</record>
