<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1197478803" ordinal="17" title="ENERGY INDEPENDENCE AND SECURITY ACT OF 2007">
  <narrative>ENERGY INDEPENDENCE AND SECURITY ACT OF 2007 -- (Senate - December 12, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="15218">S15218</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask that the Chair lay before the Senate the message from the House on <bill type="h" number="6">H.R. 6</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The PRESIDING OFFICER laid before the Senate the following message from the House of Representatives:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Resolved, That the House agree to the amendments of the Senate to the bill (<bill type="h" number="6">H.R. 6</bill>) entitled "An Act to reduce our Nation's dependency on foreign oil by investing in clean, renewable, and alternative energy resources, promoting new emerging energy technologies, developing greater efficiency, and creating a Strategic Energy Efficiency and Renewables Reserve to invest in alternative energy, and for other purposes," with amendments.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(Purpose: In the nature of a substitute.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="MOTION TO CONCUR WITH AMENDMENT NO. 3841">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I move to concur in the House amendment to the Senate amendment to the text with the amendment that is at the desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report.</chair>
  <chair>The assistant legislative clerk read as follows:</chair>
  <chair>The Senator from Nevada [Mr. Reid] moves to concur in the House amendment to the Senate amendment to the text of <bill type="h" number="6">H.R. 6</bill>, with an amendment numbered 3841.</chair>
  <narrative>(The amendment is printed in today's Record under "Text of Amendments.")</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="MOTION TO CONCUR WITH AMENDMENT NO. 3841">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask for the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there a sufficient second?</chair>
  <chair>There appears to be a sufficient second.</chair>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I have a second-degree amendment at the desk I wish to have reported.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report.</chair>
  <chair>The assistant legislative clerk read as follows:</chair>
  <chair>The Senator from Nevada [Mr. Reid] proposes an amendment numbered 3842 to amendment No. 3841.</chair>
  <chair>The amendment is as follows:</chair>
  <chair>At the end of the amendment add the following:</chair>
  <chair>This section shall take effect one day after the date of this bill's enactment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I send to the desk a cloture motion.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The cloture motion having been presented under rule XXII, the Chair directs the clerk to read the motion.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>Cloture Motion</narrative>
  <narrative>We, the undersigned Senators, in accordance with the provisions of rule XXII of the Standing Rules of the Senate, hereby move to bring to a close debate on the Reid motion to concur in the House amendment to the Senate amendment to the text with an amendment, with reference to <bill type="h" number="6">H.R. 6</bill>, Energy.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the live quorum under rule XXII be waived and that the Senate resume consideration of the farm bill, <bill type="h" number="2419">H.R. 2419</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
