<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1204045202" ordinal="43" title="NOTICES OF HEARINGS">
  <narrative>NOTICES OF HEARINGS -- (Senate - February 26, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="1204">S1204</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND NATURAL RESOURCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to announce for the information of the Senate and the public that an oversight hearing has been  scheduled before the Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. The hearing will be held on Tuesday, March 4, 2008, at 10 a.m., in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of this oversight hearing is to receive testimony on the Energy Information Administration's revised Annual Energy Outlook.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of the limited time available for the hearing, witnesses may testify by invitation only. However, those wishing to submit written testimony for the hearing record may do</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For further information, please contact Tara Billingsley at (202) 224-4756 or Rosemarie Calabro at (202) 224-5039.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to announce for the information of the Senate and the p ublic that an oversight hearing has been scheduled before the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The hearing will be held on Wednesday, March 12, 2008 at 2:15 p.m., in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of this oversight hearing is to receive testimony on Hardrock Mining: Issues Relating to Abandoned Mine Lands and Uranium Mining.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of the limited time available for the hearing, witnesses may testify by invitation only. However, those wishing to submit</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For further information, please contact Patty Beneke at 202-224-5451 or Gina Weinstock at 202-224-5684.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
