<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1227200405" ordinal="97" title="SENATE NATIONAL SECURITY WORKING GROUP">
  <narrative>SENATE NATIONAL SECURITY WORKING GROUP -- (Senate - November 20, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="10775">S10775</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300037" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of <bill type="sr" number="715">S. Res. 715</bill>, submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="715">S. Res. 715</bill>) extending the authority for the Senate National Security Working Group.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300037" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table, and that any statements relating to the resolutione be printed in the Record, without further intervening action or debate.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="715">S. Res. 715</bill>) was agreed to, as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="715">S. Res. 715</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair> Resolved, That Senate Resolution 105 of the One Hundred First Congress, 1st session (agreed to on April 13, 1989), as amended by Senate Resolution 149 of the One Hundred Third Congress, 1st session (agreed to on October 5, 1993), as further amended by Senate Resolution 75 of the One Hundred Sixth Congress, 1st session (agreed to on March 25, 1999), as further amended by Senate Resolution 383 of the One Hundred Sixth Congress, 2d session (agreed to on October 27, 2000), as further amended  by Senate Resolution 355 of the One Hundred Seventh Congress, 2d session (agreed to on November 13, 2002), as further amended by Senate Resolution 480 of the One Hundred Eighth Congress, 2d session (agreed to November 20, 2004), and as further amended by Senate Resolution 625 of the One Hundred Ninth Congress, 2d Session (agreed to on December 6, 2006), is further amended in section 4 by striking "2008" and inserting "2010".&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
