<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1174406404" ordinal="39" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <speaking speaker="400619" topic="COMMITTEE ON ARMED SERVICES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, March 20, 2007, at 9:30 a.m., in open session to receive testimony on the Air Force in review of the defense authorization request for fiscal year 2008 and the future years defense program.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400619" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, March 20, 2007, at 10 a.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building. The purpose of this hearing is to promote travel to America, and to examine economic and security concerns.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400619" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, March 20, 2007, at 2:30 p.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building. The purpose of this hearing is to discuss innovation in energy technology.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400619" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND NATURAL RESOURCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, March 20, 2007, at 10 a.m. in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building. The purpose of the hearing is to consider the nomination of Stephen Jeffrey Isakowitz, of Virginia, to be Chief Financial Officer of the Department of Energy.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400619" topic="COMMITTEE ON FINANCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Finance be authorized to meet during the session on Tuesday, March 20, 2007, at 10 a.m., in 215 Dirksen Senate Office Building, to hear testimony on "Realizing a Competitive Education: Identifying Needs, Partnerships and Resources."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400619" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, March 20, 2007, at 10 a.m. to hold a hearing on Chad.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400619" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet to conduct a hearing on "Combating War Profiteering: Are We Doing Enough to Investigate and Prosecute Contracting Fraud and Abuse in Iraq?" on Tuesday, March 20, 2007 at 9:30 a.m. in Dirksen Senate Office Building Room 226.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Honorable Stuart W. Bowen, Jr., Special Inspector General for Iraq Reconstruction, Arlington, VA; Thomas F. Gimble, Acting Inspector General, U.S. Department of Defense, Arlington, VA; Barry Sabin, Deputy Assistant Attorney General, Criminal Division, U.S. Department of Justice, Washington, DC.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400619" topic="PERMANENT SUBCOMMITTEE ON INVESTIGATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations be authorized to meet on Tuesday, March 20, 2007, at 2:30 p.m., for a hearing entitled "Medicare Doctors Who Cheat on Their Taxes and What Should Be Done About It."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400619" topic="SELECT COMMITTEE ON INTELLIGENCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Select Committee on Intelligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on March 20, 2007 at 2:30 p.m. to hold a closed hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400619" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON ANTITRUST, COMPETITION POLICY AND CONSUMER RIGHTS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on Antitrust, Competition Policy and Consumer Rights be authorized to meet on Tuesday, March 20, 2006, at 2:15 p.m., to conduct a hearing on "The OX-Sirius Merger: Monopoly or Competition from New Technologies" in room 226 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Witness List: Mel Karmazin, Chief Executive Officer, Sirius Satellite Radio, New York, NY; Mary Quass, President and CEO, NRG Media, LLC, Cedar Rapids, IA; David Balto, Attorney at Law, Law Office of David Balto, Washington, DC; and Gigi B. Sohn, President, Public Knowledge, Washington, DC.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400619" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON NATIONAL PARKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on National Parks be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, March 20, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the hearing is to receive testimony on the following bills: <bill type="s" number="126">S. 126</bill>, to modify the boundary of Mesa Verde National Park, and for other purposes; <bill type="s" number="257">S. 257</bill>, to direct the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a study to determine the feasibility of establishing the Columbia-Pacific National Heritage Area in the States of Washington and Oregon, and for other purposes; <bill type="s" number="289">S. 289</bill>, to establish the Journey Through Hallowed Ground National Heritage Area, and for other purposes; <bill type="s" number="443">S. 443</bill>, to establish  the Sangre de Cristo National Heritage Area in the State of Colorado, and for other purposes; <bill type="s" number="444">S. 444</bill>, to establish the South Park National Heritage Area in the State of Colorado, and for other purposes; <bill type="s" number="500">S. 500</bill> and <bill type="h" number="512">H.R. 512</bill>, to establish the Commission to Study the Potential Creation of the National Museum of the American Latino, to develop a plan of action for the establishment and maintenance of a National Museum of the American Latino in Washington, DC, and for other purposes; <bill type="s" number="637">S. 637</bill>, to direct the Secretary of the Interior to</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400619" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON RETIREMENT AND AGING">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on Retirement and Aging be authorized to hold a hearing on Alzheimer's research during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, March 20, 2007 at 10 a.m. in SH-216.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
