<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1183046405" ordinal="24" title="NOMINATION OF JOSEPH S. VAN BOKKELEN TO BE UNITED STATES DISTRICT JUDGE FOR THE NORTHERN DISTRICT OF INDIANA">
  <chair> The clerk will report the next nomination.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300070" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I appreciate this opportunity to support the President's nomination of Joseph S. Van Bokkelen to serve as a U.S. district judge for the Northern District of Indiana.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would first like to thank Senate Judiciary chairman, Pat Leahy; ranking member, Arlen Specter; and the respective leaders for their important work to facilitate timely consideration of this nomination.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In July of last year, Judge Rudy Lozano informed me of his decision to assume senior status after a distinguished career of public service. He was a remarkable leader on the Federal bench, and I applaud his leadership to Indiana and to the legal community.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Given this upcoming vacancy and the need for strong leadership, I was pleased to commend to President Bush Joe Van Bokkelen to serve on the Federal court in the Northern District of Indiana.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have known Joe for many years, and I have always been impressed with his high energy, resolute integrity, and remarkable dedication to public service.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Joe Van Bokkelen attended Indiana University where he received both his undergraduate and law degrees. He then served in the Indiana Attorney General's Office followed by his first experience in the United States Attorney's Office in the Northern District.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After many years of private practice, Joe assumed his current position of United States Attorney for the Northern District of Indiana on September 21, 2001. His performance in this position has been nothing short of remarkable. He has undertaken the most aggressive public corruption initiative in the history of the office. Since 2002, over 30 public officials have been indicted and convicted. Joe has also used his office to target the use and possession of illegal firearms, combat gang activity,  implement drug demand reduction programs, and cultivate community partnerships.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Likewise, Joe has demonstrated leadership in the Justice Department where he serves on several of the Attorney General's advisory committees, including Violent and Organized Crime, White Collar Crime, Sentencing Guidelines, and the Regional Information Sharing Working Group.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Newspapers across northern Indiana contain articles and editorials applauding his determination to bring about effective law enforcement. The Northwest Indiana Times recently commented that Joe Van Bokkelen "has an excellent track record for the five years he has led the U.S. Attorney's office in Northern Indiana."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Joe has received a number of high performance ratings, including the A.V. rating from Martindale-Hubbell and the highest judicial rating from the American Bar Association.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Outside of his public service, Joe is involved with a number of community activities and civic organizations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would again like to thank Chairman Leahy and Ranking Member Specter for their leadership in facilitating consideration of Joe Van Bokkelen's nomination to serve as a Federal judge. I believe that he will demonstrate remarkable leadership to northern Indiana and will appropriately uphold and defend our laws under the Constitution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is, Will the Senate advise and consent to the nomination of Joseph S. Van Bokkelen, of Indiana, to be United States District Judge for the Northern District of Indiana.</chair>
</record>
