<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1207238402" ordinal="53" title="RECOGNIZING AND HONORING 40TH ANNIVERSARY OF FAIR HOUSING ACT AND 20TH ANNIVERSARY OF FAIR HOUSING AMENDMENTS ACT OF 1988">
  <narrative>RECOGNIZING AND HONORING 40TH ANNIVERSARY OF FAIR HOUSING ACT AND 20TH ANNIVERSARY OF FAIR HOUSING AMENDMENTS ACT OF 1988 -- (Senate - April 03, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="2589">S2589</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300034" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of <bill type="sr" number="503">S. Res. 503</bill>, submitted earlier today by Senator Durbin.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="503">S. Res. 503</bill>) recognizing and honoring the 40th anniversary of the Fair Housing Act and the 20th anniversary of the Fair Housing Amendments Act of 1988.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today I rise to support this resolution honoring the 40th anniversary of the Fair Housing Act and the 20th anniversary of the Fair Housing Amendments Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But first I want to honor a man whose work helped pave the way for this landmark civil rights legislation. Forty years ago, the Reverend Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. lost his life to a sniper's bullet. Today, we remember him as one of the greatest civil rights leaders of our country. We know his dream. We are intimately familiar with it. It is a dream conceived in the founding of our country and enshrined in the words of the Declaration of Independence and in the Constitution, a dream that lives  today in our values, our identities, our highest ideals as Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is the dream: that all men are created equal, and that in a just society all are afforded the same opportunities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A week after Dr. King's assassination, and in a step closer to the fulfillment of this dream, Congress passed the Fair Housing Act as part of the Civil Rights Act of 1968. The Fair Housing Act prohibits discrimination in housing on the basis of race, color, national origin, and religion. In 1974, Congress added protection on the basis of sex. In 1988, thanks to the leadership of Senator Kennedy and Senator Specter, Congress included protection on the basis of familial status  and disability.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have made a lot of progress since the summer of 1966, when Dr. King led a movement to protest housing discrimination and slum conditions for African Americans in Chicago. But if he were alive today, he would be the first to say--we aren't there yet. Segregation persists in our schools and neighborhoods. We are in the middle of a housing crisis that is hitting African-American and Hispanic families and communities particularly hard. In Chicago, African-American borrowers were 14 times more  likely to have a higher cost loan from Wells Fargo than were White borrowers. This is a pattern that repeats all across the country. African-American and Latino families were dramatically more likely to have subprime loans than White families. Right now, millions</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For too many Americans, the dream is still just that--a dream, with little chance of becoming reality. We may have all been created equal, but since then we have been treated very differently. We are treated differently because of the color of our skin, the faith we practice, whether we are a man or a woman, single or with children, or use a wheelchair and a ramp to enter our apartment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The irony is that we have fair housing laws that make this kind of treatment not only unfair but illegal--and we have had them for 40 years. Yet 3.7 million violations of these laws occur each year against African Americans, Latinos, Asian Americans, and Indian Americans. This doesn't even include the number of violations that occur on the basis of other protected classes. Only 1 percent of people who believe they are victims of fair housing violations report it to the Government. Testing on  the enforcement of fair housing laws shows a high rate of discrimination in the rental, sales, mortgage lending, and insurance markets. More than four decades after Dr. King and his supporters marched through the streets of Chicago to fight housing discrimination, African Americans and Latinos in Cook County report substantial levels of unfair--and illegal--treatment in the housing industry.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The intent of the Fair Housing Act was broad and inclusive: to advance equal opportunity in housing and achieve racial integration for the benefit of all Americans. But enforcement of this law has been narrow and incomplete. Where you live profoundly affects where you work, what you do, where you send your kids to school, whether they grow up healthy and safe. As long as our commitment to fair housing laws--to civil rights--remains timid, we will never end segregation. We will never declare victory  over poverty. We will never build a truly just society.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As we honor Dr. King, former Senator Walter Mondale and former Senator Edward Brooke, who cosponsored the original Fair Housing Act, and others who made possible fair housing laws, we need to remember that it is not enough to pass laws. We have to enforce them. The dream of equality is our Nation's moral compass. Our duty as legislators and as citizens is to make sure the needle points in the right direction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank Senators SPECTER, KENNEDY, DODD, BROWN, and VOINOVICH for joining me today in honoring the 40th anniversary of the Fair Housing Act and the 20th anniversary of the Fair Housing Amendments Act, and I urge my colleagues in Congress to renew their dedication to upholding these laws. These laws may be 40 years old, but the dream they seek to make real is as old as our country.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300034" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table, with no intervening action or debate, and any statements related to the resolution be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="503">S. Res. 503</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="503">S. Res. 503</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas 2008 marks the 40th anniversary of the enactment of the Fair Housing Act (42 U.S.C. 3601 et seq.);&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas 2008 also marks the 20th anniversary of the enactment of the Fair Housing Amendments Act of 1988 (Public Law 100-430; 102 Stat. 1619);&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Chicago Freedom Movement, which took place from 1965 to 1967 and was led by the Reverend Doctor Martin Luther King, Jr., raised the national consciousness about housing discrimination and shaped the debate that led to landmark fair housing legislation;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the National Advisory Commission on Civil Disorders, appointed by President Lyndon B. Johnson and commonly  known as the Kerner Commission, found in 1968 that "[o]ur nation is moving toward two societies, one black, one white--separate and unequal";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Congress passed the Fair Housing Act as part of the Civil Rights Act of 1968 (Public Law 90-284; 82 Stat. 73), and President Johnson signed the Act into law on April 11, 1968, one week after the assassination of Dr. King;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Fair Housing Act prohibits discrimination in housing and housing-related transactions on the basis of race, color, national origin, and religion;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, in section 808 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (Public Law 93-383; 88 Stat. 728), Congress amended the Fair Housing Act to include protection on the basis of sex;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Fair Housing Amendments Act of 1988 (Public Law 100-430; 102 Stat. 1619), passed by overwhelming margins in Congress, included protection on the basis of familial status and disability and expanded the definition of "discriminatory housing practices" to include interference and intimidation;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Congress's intent in passing the Fair Housing Act was broad and inclusive, to advance equal opportunity in housing and achieve racial integration for the benefit of all people in the United States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas housing integration affects other dimensions of life, including educational attainment, employment opportunities, access to health care, and home equity;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the majority of people in the United States support neighborhood integration and numerous studies have shown the universal benefits of residential integration;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the National Fair Housing Alliance estimates that 3,700,000 violations of fair housing laws still occur each year against African Americans, Latinos, Asian Americans, and American Indians, and that number does not include violations that occur on the basis of other national origins, religion, sex, or familial status or against persons with disabilities;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Department of Housing and Urban Development estimates that only 1 percent of individuals who believe they are victims of housing discrimination report those violations of fair housing laws to the government, and this underreporting is a major obstacle to achieving equal opportunity in housing;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas testing of the enforcement of fair housing laws continues to uncover a high rate of discrimination in the rental, sales, mortgage lending, and insurance markets; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Fair Housing Act is an essential component of our Nation's civil rights legislation: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) recognizes and honors the 40th anniversary of the enactment of the Fair Housing Act (42 U.S.C. 3601 et seq.) and the 20th anniversary of the enactment of the Fair Housing Amendments Act of 1988 (Public Law 100-430; 102 Stat. 1619);&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) supports activities to recognize and celebrate the historical milestone represented by the anniversaries of the enactment of the Fair Housing Act and the enactment of the Fair Housing Amendments Act of 1988; and</chair>
  <chair> (3) encourages all levels of government to rededicate themselves to the enforcement and the ideals of fair housing laws. &lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
