<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1190649602" ordinal="24" title="THE DEATH OF DR. ALVIN SMITH">
  <narrative>THE DEATH OF DR. ALVIN SMITH -- (Senate - September 24, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="12001">S12001</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask to have printed in the RECORD an article on the death of Dr. Alvin Smith, who passed away last week at the age of 75. The son of sharecroppers, he went on to become a noted physician who worked throughout his life to increase access to the health care system, an issue that is near and dear to my heart. My condolences go out to his wife Ann, his three son, and his six grandchildren.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The article follows.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>[From newsjournalonline.com, Sept. 19, 2007]</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Noted Area Physician Dies With Family at Side</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(By Anne Geggis)</narrative>
  <narrative>Dr. Alvin Smith devoted his life to saving the lives of his patients and curing the ills of the health-care system.</narrative>
  <narrative>Smith, 75, died Tuesday morning at his Ormond Beach home. His family was at his side.</narrative>
  <narrative>The son of Alabama sharecroppers overcame meager beginnings to become one of the most respected physicians in the area.</narrative>
  <narrative>The 1952 Mainland High School graduate was perhaps best known to the community as the director of the Herbert D. Kerman Regional Oncology Center at Halifax Health Medical Center and as the owner of Angell &amp; Phelps Chocolate Factory that his son, Alvin Jr., now runs.</narrative>
  <narrative>In addition, he felt a strong pull toward changing the system so more people had access to medical care, serving as president of the Volusia County Medical Society and the Florida Medical Association.</narrative>
  <narrative>Smith was a self-confessed truant who went to fifth grade for only one day and didn't come back to school for a year. He quit high school in 10th grade and finally graduated from Mainland at the age of 21. But then he went on to become the first college graduate in his family, earning a biology degree from the University of Florida before getting his doctorate from the University of Miami.</narrative>
  <narrative>It was as president of the Florida Medical Association in the 1990s, however, that Smith achieved one of his most enduring accomplishments: convincing then-Gov. Lawton Chiles to form an autonomous state Department of Health. During that time, he also lobbied for legislation allowing the state of Florida to sue the tobacco industry to recover Medicaid costs.</narrative>
  <narrative>"He wanted to make sure that no patient in Florida went without the best health care they needed, regardless of their ability to pay," said Dr. Carl "Rick" Lentz, also a past president of the Florida Medical Association and a Daytona Beach surgeon.</narrative>
  <narrative>His voice choking, Lentz recalled how Smith recently handed him his Florida Medical Association president's pin because Lentz never got one during his term as president.</narrative>
  <narrative>"He's a wonderful human being who's been a blessing to the whole world," Lentz said. "There's not a patient who has been with him that doesn't love him. Anytime you call on Al, he's there for you."</narrative>
  <narrative>Former County Councilman, local talk show radio host and gadfly Big John recalled meeting Smith as an "intern" at Halifax Health Medical Center in which community members were invited to spend time with doctors to learn about the hospital's functions.</narrative>
  <narrative>"He was a great guy--great personality," John said.</narrative>
  <narrative>Smith's boyhood longing for chocolates he couldn't afford in the window at Angell &amp; Phelps gave way to occasional indulgence. When the chocolate factory came up for sale, he bought it to make sure all his favorite recipes stayed the same.</narrative>
  <narrative>Daytona Beach Mayor Glenn Ritchey served with him on the Halifax Community Health System Board.</narrative>
  <narrative>"I have known him to be a great community servant, as well as a wonderful doctor who has meant so much to our area," Ritchey said. "He'll be greatly missed."</narrative>
  <narrative>Smith served in the U.S. Army, retiring as a major, and from the U.S. Army Reserves as a lieutenant colonel. He was active in civic organizations, ranging from the Boy Scouts to the People to Prevent Nuclear War. He served on boards including the United Way, Hospice of Volusia/Flagler and A Child's Place.</narrative>
  <narrative>"Alvin's one of the really good guys," said John E. Evans, a former TV personality and spokesman for what was then called Halifax Community Health System.</narrative>
  <narrative>Survivors include his wife of 50 years, Ann; three sons, Alvin Jr., Ormond Beach, and Chuck and Mike, both of Palm Coast; a sister, Ginny Little, Ormond Beach; and six grandchildren.</narrative>
  <narrative>Viewing will be from 5 to 7 p.m., Friday at the social hall at Central Baptist Church, 142 Fairview Ave., Daytona Beach. Services will be at 11 a.m. Saturday at Central Baptist Church. A private military burial will be next week.</narrative>
</record>
