<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1180022410" ordinal="19" title="SUPPLEMENTAL APPROPRIATIONS">
  <chair> There is 3 minutes 20 seconds.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, before yielding so we can have a vote on the amendment of the Senator from Vermont, I would like to respond to my friend from Alabama regarding the earned-income tax credit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The earned-income tax credit is to help children--help children. Of all the industrialized nations of the world, we have more children living in poverty than any other Nation in the world. The earned-income tax credit is to help the children. They are not the lawbreakers; the parents are the lawbreakers. Yet this amendment will take it out on the children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We don't do it for those who have committed murder and gone to prison. We don't do it for those who have committed aggravated assault. We don't do it for those who commit burglary, but we are going to do it for those who have been adjusted in terms of their status of being illegal. That is what the  Sessions amendment does. We don't do it for murderers, we don't do it for burglars, we don't do it for those who have committed the most egregious crimes,  but we are going to do it in terms of those whose positions we are changing and altering in terms of their adjustment of status.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The people who are affected by it are the children. It doesn't seem to be the way we ought to go. But we will have a longer period of time to debate this at another time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe now we are prepared to vote, and I suggest that we get to it as quickly as we can so that we don't have other interference.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Vermont is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400357" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I will be very brief. I thank Senator Durbin and Senator Kennedy for their support. This amendment has been modified. The H-1B program would increase from $1,500 to $5,000, a $3,500 increase. The new revenue, as I mentioned earlier, would be used to establish a scholarship program so we can begin to see young Americans get the education they need for these professions so that we do not have to go abroad to bring people in to do the jobs that American  workers should be doing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would appreciate support for this amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent for 1 more minute.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>I want to commend the Senator from Vermont for this amendment. I intend to support it. Years ago I thought we ought to have it at $3,000. It went down to $1,000, and it has come back up to $1,500. The Senator has brought this up to a much more reasonable amount. I think he has made a very strong case for it. These funds will be used to make sure we get Americans being able to do those jobs. That is what the purpose is: to see we have Americans able to do those jobs, those H-1B jobs.  It makes a great deal of sense. I commend the Senator.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is one provision in here on the public hospitals, and I know he will work with us to try to address that in the conference, and I thank him for it. I hope the Senate will support his amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think we are prepared to vote on this amendment. I ask for the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there a sufficient second?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300092" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, just a word or two. I think it is a good amendment. I commend the Senator from Vermont. I urge my colleagues to support it.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on agreeing to the amendment.</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will call the roll.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>I announce that the Senator from South Dakota (Mr. Johnson) and the Senator from New York (Mr. Schumer) are necessarily absent.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300069" topic="">
    <paragraph>The following Senators are necessarily absent: the Senator from Kansas (Mr. Brownback), the Senator from Utah (Mr. Hatch), the Senator from Arizona (Mr. McCain), and the Senator from Wyoming (Mr. Thomas).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Further, if present and voting, the Senator form Utah (Mr. Hatch) would have voted: "nay."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Are there any other Senators in the Chamber desiring to vote?</chair>
  <narrative>The result was announced--yeas 59, nays 35, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>I move to reconsider the vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="">
    <paragraph>I move to lay that motion on the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The motion to lay on the table was agreed to.</narrative>
  <chair> The Senator from Massachusetts.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, we are anticipating a vote in the next 2 or 3 minutes. We will inform the Members about that decision. We are checking with the leadership at the present time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, the Senator from Connecticut wishes to propound a unanimous consent request, and then I will propound a unanimous consent request that we will have 2 minutes evenly divided between the Senator from Louisiana and myself, and then I expect we will have a rollcall vote up or down on the Vitter amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent to set aside the pending amendment so I might call up an amendment and then set it aside.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I call up amendment No. 1191.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the reading of the amendment be dispensed with.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <narrative>(The amendment is printed in today's Record under "Text of Amendments.")</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I have come to the floor to speak about my amendment to improve our Nation's treatment of asylum seekers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment would implement the key recommendations of the congressionally established U.S. Commission on International Religious Freedom, which 2 years ago issued a report raising serious concerns about the protections offered asylum seekers arriving in this country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think it is worth noting that the Commission that issued this report was established by Congress in 1998 as a result of legislation first introduced by Senator SPECTER, in concert with the efforts of Senators NICKLES, BROWNBACK, myself, and several others. Senator SPECTER should be proud of that work and accomplishment. I hope we can see this amendment as one of the fruits of that labor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Commission reported an unacceptable risk that genuine asylum seekers were being turned away because their fears--and the real dangers--of being returned to their home countries were not fully considered.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Commission also found that while asylum seekers are having their applications considered, they are often detained for months in maximum security prisons and jails, without ever having been fairly considered for release on bond. The Commission described conditions of detention that are completely unacceptable for a just nation to impose on people who are trying to escape war, oppression, religious persecution, even torture.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since the Commission's report was issued, I have routinely asked officials from the Department of Homeland Security what is being done about the problems the Commission identified. I have been assured that the Department was reviewing the report's findings. The time for review is over. The time for Congress to act is now.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My amendment will implement the Commission's most important recommendations. It calls for sensible reforms that will safeguard the Nation's security, improve the efficiency of our immigration detention system, and ensure that people fleeing persecution are treated in accordance with this Nation's most basic values.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My amendment would implement quality assurance procedures to ensure that DHS officers carefully and accurately record the statements of people who may have a legitimate fear of returning to their countries.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Asylum seekers not subject to mandatory detention would be entitled to a hearing to determine if they could be released. Providing bond hearings for those asylum seekers who are low-risk will free up detention beds.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At an average cost of $90 per person per day, often much higher, detention beds have always been scarce. Provisions in the Senate legislation before us would vastly increase the numbers of aliens being held in detention. Our immigration system should prioritize available space for aliens who pose a risk of flight, a threat to public safety or are subject to mandatory detention.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The amendment also promotes secure alternatives to detention of the type DHS has already begun to implement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For those who must remain detained, we are obliged as a compassionate society to provide humane conditions at immigration facilities and jails used by DHS. My amendment includes modest requirements to ensure decent conditions, especially for asylum seekers, families with children, and other vulnerable populations. It requires improvements in key areas, such as access to medical care and limitations on the use of solitary confinement. And it creates a more effective system within DHS for overseeing  and inspecting facilities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The origin of the United States is that of a land of refuge. Many of our Nation's founders fled here to escape persecution for their political opinions, their ethnicity, and their religion. Since that time, the United States has honored its history and founding values by standing against persecution around the world, offering refuge to those who flee from oppression, and welcoming them as contributors to a democratic society.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I hope this amendment will be viewed as a noncontroversial way the Nation can continue to honor that history.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that my amendment be set aside and that the Senate return to the previous order.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, we have 1 minute each side. This will be the final vote on the immigration bill this week. We have had great cooperation. We are enormously grateful to all the Members.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Louisiana.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400418" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, my amendment is very simple, it is very straightforward, and it is very important. It strikes title VI from the bill, which is the very controversial Z visa provision.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In my opinion, and the opinion of many people, many Americans, this is amnesty purely and simply, and that conclusion is important not because of a brand, not because of the word but because of what it means and what it will create.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It will create a magnet to increase illegal activity into the country, to encourage more of the same, more of the problem and not solve the problem. That is why we must remove this title from the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The key question in this debate is will this bill fundamentally repeat the horrible mistakes of 1986 when we did amnesty but not nearly enough enforcement. I believe this bill, as it stands now, repeats that horrible mistake.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator's time has expired.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, legalization is good for national security. We need to know the names of everyone living here. That is why the Department of Homeland Security supports earned legalization. All of title VI was written with the close cooperation of Secretary Chertoff and his staff.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Legalization is good for our economic prosperity. We need every worker in this country to join the formal economy and pay their taxes. That's why the Department of Commerce supports earned legalization. All of title VI was written with the close cooperation of Secretary Gutierrez and his staff.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Legalization is consistent with American family values. Would opponents of legalization deport children and divide families?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>More than 1.6 million undocumented children live in the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>More than 3.1 million U.S.-citizen children have at least one undocumented parent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Legalization supports our broader reform effort. We must break America's cycle of illegality. Enforcement at the worksite and elsewhere will fail if 12 million Americans and 5 percent of U.S. workers remain in the shadows.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The American people support earned legalization. Poll after poll find that large majorities of Americans want undocumented immigrants who have lived and worked in the United States to have a chance to keep their jobs and earn legal status.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This support spans political parties and crosses demographics.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Americans understand that this is a complex problem that requires a comprehensive solution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, this is not 1986; 1986 was amnesty. This is not amnesty. Let's be very clear about it. Not only do you have to have a background check, but you pay fees of $5,500, you have to learn English, you have to demonstrate you paid your taxes, you have to work for the next 8 years and demonstrate that you have worked in the past if you are ever going to get a green card. You have to return home in order to get your application for a green card, and you have to go to the back of the line.  None of that was 1986.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Legalization is important for our national security. We have to know who is in the United States of America. Legalization is important in terms of our economic prosperity so our economy can function well, and legalization is important for the families. Do we think we are going to deport 3.5 million American children who have parents who are undocumented? Are we going to send those people overseas?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment will undermine the legislation. I hope it will be rejected by the Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask for the yeas and nays, Mr. President.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there a sufficient second?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>I announce that the Senator from South Dakota (Mr. JOHNSON) and the Senator from New York (Mr. SCHUMER) are necessarily absent.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300069" topic="">
    <paragraph>The following Senators are necessarily absent: the Senator from Kansas (Mr. BROWNBACK), the Senator from Utah (Mr. HATCH), and the Senator from Wyoming (Mr. THOMAS).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Are there any other Senators in the Chamber desiring to vote?</chair>
  <narrative>The result was announced--yeas 29, nays 66, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I move to reconsider the vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="">
    <paragraph>I move to lay that motion on the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The motion to lay on the table was agreed to.</narrative>
</record>
