<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1197910803" ordinal="30" title="DO-NOT-CALL IMPROVEMENT ACT OF 2007">
  <narrative>DO-NOT-CALL IMPROVEMENT ACT OF 2007 -- (Senate - December 17, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="15788">S15788</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300034" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of Calendar No. 539, <bill type="s" number="2096">S. 2096</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the bill by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A bill (<bill type="s" number="2096">S. 2096</bill>) to amend the Do-Not-Call Implementation Act to eliminate the automatic removal of telephone numbers registered on the Federal "do-not-call" registry.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the bill which had been reported from the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation with an amendment to strike all after the enacting clause and insert in lieu thereof the following:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="s" number="2096">S. 2096</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "Do-Not-Call Improvement Act of 2007".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. PROHIBITION OF EXPIRATION DATE FOR REGISTERED TELEPHONE NUMBERS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) IN GENERAL.--The registration of a telephone number on the do-not-call registry of the  Telemarketing Sales Rule (16 C.F.R. 310.4(b)(1)(iii)) shall not expire at the end of any specified time period.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) REINSTATEMENT.--The Federal Trade Commission shall reinstate the registration of any telephone number that has been removed from the registry before the date of enactment of this Act under a Federal Trade Commission rule or practice requiring the removal of a telephone number from the registry 5 years after its registration.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) REGISTRY MAINTENANCE.--The Federal Trade Commission may check telephone numbers listed on the do-not-call registry against national databases periodically and purge those numbers that have been disconnected and reassigned.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300034" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the amendment at the desk be considered and agreed to; the committee-reported amendment, as amended, be agreed to; the bill, as amended, be read a third time, passed, the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table, and that any statements related thereto be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The amendment (No. 3867) was agreed to, as follows:</chair>
  <narrative>(Purpose: To require the FTC to report to the Congress on its efforts to improve the accuracy of the Do-Not-Call Registry)</narrative>
  <narrative> At the end of the bill, add the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 3. REPORT ON ACCURACY.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Not later than 9 months after the enactment of this Act, the Federal Trade Commission shall report to the Congress on efforts taken by the Commission, after the date of enactment of this Act, to improve the accuracy of the "do-not-call" Registry.</narrative>
  <narrative>The committee amendment in the nature of a substitute, as amended, was agreed to.</narrative>
  <narrative>The bill, as amended, was ordered to be engrossed for a third reading, read the third time and passed, as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="s" number="2096">S. 2096</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "Do-Not-Call Improvement Act of 2007".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. PROHIBITION OF EXPIRATION DATE FOR REGISTERED TELEPHONE NUMBERS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) IN GENERAL.--The registration of a telephone number on the do-not-call registry of the Telemarketing Sales Rule (16 C.F.R. 310.4(b)(1)(iii)) shall not expire at the end of any specified time period.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) REINSTATEMENT.--The Federal Trade Commission shall reinstate the registration of any telephone number that has been removed from the registry before the date of enactment of this Act under a Federal Trade Commission rule or practice requiring the removal of a telephone number from the registry 5 years after its registration.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) REGISTRY MAINTENANCE.--The Federal Trade Commission may check telephone numbers listed on the do-not-call registry against national databases periodically and purge those numbers that have been disconnected and reassigned.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 3. REPORT ON ACCURACY.</narrative>
  <narrative> Not later than 9 months after the enactment of this Act, the Federal Trade Commission shall report to the Congress on efforts taken by the Commission, after the date of enactment of this Act, to improve the accuracy of the "do-not-call" Registry.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</narrative>
</record>
