<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1211385602" ordinal="57" title="UNANIMOUS-CONSENT AGREEMENT--HOUSE MESSAGE ON H.R. 2642">
  <narrative>UNANIMOUS-CONSENT AGREEMENT--HOUSE MESSAGE ON <bill type="h" number="2642">H.R. 2642</bill> -- (Senate - May 21, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="4705">S4705</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that following any leader time on Thursday, May 22, the Senate then resume consideration of the House message on <bill type="h" number="2642">H.R. 2642</bill>, and there be 2 hours of debate equally divided and controlled between the leaders or their designees; that upon the use or yielding back of time, the cloture motion with respect to the Reid motion to concur in House amendment No. 2 with an amendment be withdrawn, and the Reid second-degree amendment be withdrawn; that the  Senate then proceed to vote on adoption of the motion to concur in House amendment No. 2 with an amendment; that the motion to concur be subject to an affirmative 60-vote threshold, that if the motion achieves that threshold, it be agreed to, and the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table; that if the motion to concur fails to achieve 60 votes, it be withdrawn, and Senator Reid be recognized to move to concur in House amendment No. 2 with an amendment which is the Webb GI bill; that the motion be subject to an affirmative 60-vote threshold; and that if it achieves that threshold, the motion to concur be agreed to, and the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table: that if it fails to achieve 60 affirmative votes, it be withdrawn, and the Senate disagree to House amendment No. 2; that upon disposition of House amendment No. 2, Senator Reid be recognized to move to concur in House amendment No. 1 with an amendment which is the text of the committee-reported amendments Nos. 2 and 3 on funding and Iraq policy; that Senator Sanders then be</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <chair>Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Thank you, Mr. President, very much.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
