<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1222444802" ordinal="16" title="TO EXTEND FOR 5 YEARS THE PROGRAM RELATING TO WAIVER OF THE FOREIGN COUNTRY RESIDENCE REQUIREMENT WITH RESPECT TO INTERNATIONAL MEDICAL GRADUATES">
  <narrative>TO EXTEND FOR 5 YEARS THE PROGRAM RELATING TO WAIVER OF THE FOREIGN COUNTRY RESIDENCE REQUIREMENT WITH RESPECT TO INTERNATIONAL MEDICAL GRADUATES -- (Senate - September 26, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="9573">S9573</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent the Judiciary Committee be discharged from further consideration of <bill type="h" number="5571">H.R. 5571</bill> and we now proceed to its consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will report the bill by title.</narrative>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A bill (<bill type="h" number="5571">H.R. 5571</bill>) to extend for 5 years the program relating to waiver of the foreign country residence requirement with respect to international medical graduates and for other purposes.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the bill.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent a Conrad amendment which is at the desk be agreed to, the bill, as amended, be read a third time, passed, the motion to reconsider be laid on the table, with no intervening action or debate, and any statements be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300003" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I wanted to make sure we had an opportunity to speak for 2 1/2  minutes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The amendment (No. 5654) was agreed to, as follows:</chair>
  <narrative>(Purpose: To reduce the length of the waiver program extension)</narrative>
  <narrative>On page 2, line 5, strike "June 1, 2013" and insert "March 6, 2009".</narrative>
  <narrative>The amendment was ordered to be engrossed and the bill read a third time.</narrative>
  <narrative>The bill (<bill type="h" number="5571">H.R. 5571</bill>), as amended, was read the third time and passed.</narrative>
</record>
