<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1176393602" ordinal="49" title="RAYMOND G. MURPHY DEPARTMENT OF VETERANS AFFAIRS MEDICAL CENTER">
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Veterans' Affairs be discharged from further consideration of <bill type="s" number="229">S. 229</bill> and the Senate proceed to its immediate consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered. The clerk will report the bill by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300036" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I am very pleased today that we will have renamed the Albuquerque VA facility as the Raymond G. Murphy Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Center. I thank my colleague Senator Bingaman for his support on this issue, as well as Senator Akaka and Senator Craig and the staff on the Committee of Veterans' Affairs for their help.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Raymond "Jerry" Murphy died last Friday at the age of 77. His obituary described him as "one of the softest-spoken, most modest men to ever wear the Medal of Honor." Jerry Murphy was a true American hero who in war and peace dedicated himself to others. CPT Jerry Murphy was the 39th U.S. Marine to be awarded the Medal of Honor for heroism in the Korean war. When he returned from war he dedicated his entire life to taking care of other veterans. He spent 23 years working in the Albuquerque  VA regional office. Upon his retirement, he continued to serve veterans as a volunteer until he became too sick to do so. I think it is only right that the medical center in Albuquerque bear his name in recognition of his great service to veterans and to the Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I came to the floor earlier in the week and spoke about my good friend after he died. I stand by that statement and again send my condolences to Jerry's wife Maryann, his sons John, Michael, and Tim, his daughter Eleanor, as well as his eight grandchildren. It is never easy to lose a loved one, but at these trying moments, we can take solace in the fact that Jerry lived a long and fulfilling life. He helped many people and touched many lives. His service is a shining example to civilians and  veterans alike of a life dedicated to service.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am very proud to have known Jerry Murphy and to have been able to call him my friend. It is a privilege to play a part in bestowing this deserving honor on a great man and a great American, Raymond Gerald Murphy.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the bill be read a third time, passed, the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table, and that any statements relating to this bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
