<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1209052802" ordinal="14" title="NATIONAL SMALL BUSINESS WEEK">
  <narrative>NATIONAL SMALL BUSINESS WEEK -- (Senate - April 24, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="3342">S3342</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300060" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, this is National Small Business Week. This country has nearly 27 million small businesses in total, and their contributions to the country are remarkable. They create the majority--the vast majority--of jobs, they drive the economy, and they are part of the solution to lead us out of economic downturns. But if we are going to really pay appropriate tribute to small business during Small Business Week, we frankly need to do more than simply provide lip service; we need  to promote policies that work for small businesses, not policies that favor large businesses under the guise of helping small ones.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship, we have worked on behalf of small business on a bipartisan basis. Senator Snowe, the ranking member, and I and the entire committee passed unanimously three bills to improve small business services that help America's job creators expand their payrolls.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, these bills have been blocked for a full year by some in the Senate: <bill type="s" number="1256">S. 1256</bill>, the Small Business Lending Reauthorization and Improvements Act of 2007; <bill type="s" number="1662">S. 1662</bill>, the Small Business Venture Capital Act of 2007; and <bill type="s" number="1671">S. 1671</bill>, the Entrepreneurial Development Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="1256">S. 1256</bill>, the Small Business Lending Reauthorization Improvements Act, passed the Small Business Committee 19 to 0 on May 16, 2007, almost a year ago. This legislation authorizes the Small Business Administration's major lending programs which are the largest source of long-term capital for small businesses in the country. The bill also strengthens the microloan program, a concept that has proven unbelievably effective around the world in helping men and women lift themselves and their families  out of poverty by accumulating assets, building wealth, and creating jobs. That is very important because the income gap, the economic gap, is growing year by year. When an  average White family's net worth is $67,000 but an average African-American family's income is only $6,100, we have a long way to go</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="1662">S. 1662</bill>, the Small Business Venture Capital Act of 2007, passed the Small Business Committee 19 to 0 on June 26, 2007, 10 months ago. This bill would simplify the Small Business Investment Company Debenture Program so it is more attractive to investors and allow the SBA to stabilize losses in the SBIC Participating Securities Program. The version of the bill we are trying to pass does not reauthorize the SBIC Participating Securities Program, as some in the past have suggested in public debate.  They used that as one of the justifications for opposing efforts to pass the bill last December. The bill focuses on improving the SBIC debenture program, which is an initiative that has actually given us extraordinary job creators, such as FedEx, Intel, Calaway Golf. They have more than repaid the cost of anything to the Federal Government through taxes paid and jobs created.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, <bill type="s" number="1662">S. 1662</bill> reauthorizes the New Markets Venture Capital Program. This program addresses the market gap in venture capital for companies located in low- and moderate-income, rural, and urban areas--i.e., high unemployment areas--as well as the need for smaller deals that neither traditional venture funds nor the SBIC Program will make. It has proven successful so far, and we need more community development venture capital to create sustainable, high-quality, local jobs. This bill would  allow the SBA to start anywhere from 10 to 20 more funds. Without this Government partnership, these investments are not going to be done. So at a time when our economy is pressured and hurting, when we need to create jobs, it doesn't make sense for the Senate to be blocking something that came out of committee 19 to 0, in a totally bipartisan effort. The bill also aligns the New Markets Venture Capital Program with the New Markets Tax Credit Program, which is exactly what Congress intended.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="1671">S. 1671</bill>, the Entrepreneurial Development Act, passed the Small Business Committee 19 to 0 on June 26, 2007, also 10 months ago. This act reauthorizes and improves the Small Business Administration's entrepreneurial development programs such as small business development centers, women's business centers, and SCORE. Poor management decisions are the No. 1 reason businesses declare bankruptcy. In a shaky economy, the topnotch counseling provided by these services is critical to ensuring that small  businesses survive the economic downturn and continue to provide jobs and income to families and communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill also increases assistance for small businesses wishing to conduct trade. Small businesses are 97 percent of all exporters, and for each additional $70,000 in exports generated, one additional U.S. job is created. These jobs pay 18 percent more on average than nontrade-related jobs. So small business success helps the economy and creates jobs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Lastly, this bill creates a number of pilot programs to help small businesses deal with rising health care costs and regulatory burdens, all of which hinder small business success. It creates new programs in support of Native American entrepreneurship and takes steps to improve small business ownership by minorities in highly skilled fields such as engineering, manufacturing, science, and technology, and it guides them toward entrepreneurship as a career option.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These bills I have described have the ability to help more than 1 million small businesses. They would help with credit, with venture capital or with counseling. It makes no sense at all to have one or two folks in the Senate holding up the ability to move forward on these when our economy needs innovation and, frankly, the job creation these businesses create. With 80,000 jobs lost in March alone and almost 300,000 jobs lost since January, there is no time to waste.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I hope we can get these bills done and do so shortly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Virginia.</chair>
</record>
