<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1194973204" ordinal="62" title="RECOGNIZING AND CELEBRATING THE CENTENNIAL OF OKLAHOMA STATEHOOD">
  <narrative>RECOGNIZING AND CELEBRATING THE CENTENNIAL OF OKLAHOMA STATEHOOD -- (Senate - November 13, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="14349">S14349</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate now proceed to the consideration of <bill type="sr" number="377">S. Res. 377</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="377">S. Res. 377</bill>) recognizing and celebrating the centennial of Oklahoma statehood.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="377">S. Res. 377</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="377">S. Res. 377</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas, on November 16, 1907, Oklahoma officially became the 46th State of the Union;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the State of Oklahoma is known as the Sooner State;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the State of Oklahoma has become a national leader in agriculture, natural resource industries, technology, and manufacturing;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the people of Oklahoma have harvested the natural abundance of the State to produce a wealth which has enabled the building of cities, educational institutions, an unhurried pace of life, and a rich culture, while maintaining the pristine ecology;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the beautiful mountains, rivers, lakes, trees, plains, and fields of the State of Oklahoma are appreciated and preserved, and the quality of life is unsurpassed; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, on November 16, 2007, the State of Oklahoma will begin a new century of statehood: Now, therefore, be it</chair>
  <chair> Resolved, That the Senate recognizes and celebrates the centennial of Oklahoma statehood.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
