<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1197565202" ordinal="61" title="LIEUTENANT COLONEL CLEMENT C. VAN WAGONER DEPARTMENT OF VETERANS AFFAIRS CLINIC">
  <narrative>LIEUTENANT COLONEL CLEMENT C. VAN WAGONER DEPARTMENT OF VETERANS AFFAIRS CLINIC -- (Senate - December 13, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="15572">S15572</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Veterans' Affairs Committee be discharged from further consideration of <bill type="s" number="2339">S. 2339</bill>, and that the Senate then proceed to its immediate consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered. The clerk will report the bill by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A bill (<bill type="s" number="2339">S. 2339</bill>) to designate the Department of Veterans Affairs clinic in Alpena, Michigan, as the "Lieutenant Colonel Clement C. Van Wagoner Department of Veterans Affairs Clinic."</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the bill.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the bill be read a third time, passed, the motions to reconsider be laid on the table, and any statements be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The bill (<bill type="s" number="2339">S. 2339</bill>) was ordered to be engrossed for a third reading, was read the third time and passed, as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="s" number="2339">S. 2339</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. DESIGNATION OF LIEUTENANT COLONEL CLEMENT C. VAN WAGONER DEPARTMENT OF VETERANS AFFAIRS CLINIC.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Designation.--The Department of Veterans Affairs clinic located in Alpena, Michigan, shall after the date of the enactment of this Act be known and designated as the "Lieutenant Colonel Clement C. Van Wagoner Department of Veterans Affairs Clinic".</chair>
  <chair> (b) References.--Any reference in any law, regulation, map, document, record, or other paper of the United States to the clinic referred to in subsection (a) shall be considered to be a reference to the Lieutenant Colonel Clement C. Van Wagoner Department of Veterans Affairs Clinic.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
