<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1210262403" ordinal="20" title="NOTICE OF PROPOSED RULEMAKING">
  <narrative>NOTICE OF PROPOSED RULEMAKING -- (Senate - May 08, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="3970">S3970</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the attached from the Office of Compliance be printed in the Record today pursuant to section 304(b)(1) of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (2 U.S.C. 1384(b)(1)).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>U.S. CONGRESS,</narrative>
  <narrative>OFFICE OF COMPLIANCE,</narrative>
  <narrative>Washington, DC, April 16, 2008.</narrative>
  <narrative>DEAR SENATOR BYRD: Section 304(b)(l) of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (CAA), 2 U.S.C. 1384(b)(l), requires that, with regard to the initial proposal of substantive regulations under the CAA, the Board "shall publish a general notice of proposed rulemaking" and "shall transmit such notice to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President Pro Tempore of the Senate for publication in the Congressional Record on the first day on which both Houses are in session  following such transmittal."</narrative>
  <narrative>The Board of Directors of the Office of Compliance is transmitting herewith the enclosed Notice of Proposed Rulemaking. The Board requests that the accompanying Notice be published in both the House and Senate versions of the Congressional Record on the first day on which both Houses are in session following receipt of this transmittal.</narrative>
  <narrative>Any inquiries regarding the accompanying Notice should be addressed to Tamara E. Chrisler, Executive Director of the Office of Compliance, 110 2nd Street, S.E., Room LA-200, Washington, D.C. 20540; 202-724-9250, TDD 202-426-1912, tchr@loc.gov.</narrative>
  <narrative>Sincerely,</narrative>
  <narrative>Susan S. Robfogel,</narrative>
  <narrative>(Editor's note: The notice of Proposed Rulemaking is printed in the RECORD dated April 21, 2008, at page <bill type="s" number="3188">S3188</bill>)</narrative>
</record>
