<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1220976002" ordinal="54" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <narrative>AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET -- (Senate - September 09, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="8216">S8216</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="COMMITTEE ON ARMED SERVICES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, September 9, 2008, at 9:30 a.m.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="COMMITTEE ON BANKING, HOUSING, AND URBAN AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on September 9, 2008, at 10 a.m., to conduct a hearing entitled "Strengthening the Ability of Public Transportation To Reduce Our Dependence on Foreign Oil."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="COMMITTEE ON FINANCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Finance be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, September 9, 2008, at 10 a.m., in room 215 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building, to conduct a hearing entitled "Improving Health Care Quality: An Integral Step Toward Health Reform".</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="COMMITTEEE ON HOMELAND SECURITY AND GOVERNMENTAL AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, September 9, 2008, at 3:15 p.m.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="COMMITTEEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate to conduct a hearing entitled "Nominations" on Tuesday, September 9, 2008, at 10 a.m., in room SD-562 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate, to conduct a hearing entitled "Protecting the Right to Vote: Oversight of the Department of Justice's Preparation for the 2008 General Election" on Tuesday, September 9, 2008, at 2:15 p.m., in room SD-562 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The PRESIDING OPPICER. Without objection, it is so ordered.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on Transportation and Infrastructure, Committee on Environment and Public Works, be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, September 9, 2008 at 10 a.m. in room 406 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building to hold a hearing entitled, "Economic Development Administration Oversight."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
