<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1207843202" ordinal="35" title="TRIBUTE TO DICK HALLIBURTON">
  <narrative>TRIBUTE TO DICK HALLIBURTON -- (Senate - April 10, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="2940">S2940</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412243" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask the Senate to join me today in honoring Dick Halliburton, an accomplished advocate at Legal Aid of Western Missouri. He has fought tirelessly for 38 years for the rights of low-income Missourians, first as a Legal Aid of Western Missouri, LAWMO, attorney and for the last 20 years as LAWMO's executive director. During his time as executive director, LAWMO's staff has represented clients in more than 250,000 cases--obtaining thousands of protective  orders for victims of domestic violence, preventing thousands of unlawful evictions, obtaining safe and affordable public and federally subsidized housing for thousands of families; and obtaining Medicaid, SSI and other public benefits for thousands of Missourians.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>His work has empowered low-income people throughout western Missouri, by giving them the means to assert and protect their legal rights in court. Without his leadership, many low-income people throughout Western Missouri would not have had meaningful access to the civil justice system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dick has worked for years as a governor of the Missouri bar to advocate for the interest of low-income people. This work has encouraged the bar to provide direct funding for Missouri's legal services programs and to advocate for State funding for legal services, which the programs now receive.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He has led LAWMO through many difficult challenges. Through it all, he has maintained the integrity of the program and made sure that LAWMO continues to provide high quality legal services that meet its clients' needs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dick has greatly increased private donations, grants and other non-LSC funding for the program. When he began as executive director, LSC funding accounted for well over half of LAWMO's budget. Now it is barely a quarter of the organization's budget.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dick has trained and nurtured one of the most experienced and well-respected groups of case handlers in any legal services program in the country, and those case handlers have achieved consistently high-quality results for their clients.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dick's work takes into account the words and commitment to public service of Reginald Heber Smith, who in his book, "Justice and the Poor," stated:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Without equal access to the law, the system not only robs the poor of their only protection, but it places it in the hands of their oppressors the most powerful and ruthless weapon ever created.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In short, Dick Halliburton has made Missouri's justice system more accessible for low-income people and, in doing so, he has improved the lives of all Missourians. We are sincerely grateful for his work.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
