<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1207756802" ordinal="45" title="CONGRATULATING THE UNIVERSITY OF TENNESSEE WOMEN'S BASKETBALL TEAM">
  <narrative>CONGRATULATING THE UNIVERSITY OF TENNESSEE WOMEN'S BASKETBALL TEAM -- (Senate - April 09, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="2827">S2827</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent the Senate now proceed to consideration of <bill type="sr" number="508">S. Res. 508</bill>, which was submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="508">S. Res. 508</bill>) congratulating the University of Tennessee women's basketball team for winning the 2008 National Collegiate Athletic Association Division I Women's Basketball Championship.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motions to reconsider be laid on the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="508">S. Res. 508</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="508">S. Res. 508</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas, on April 8, 2008, before a crowd of over 21,000 fans, the University of Tennessee women's basketball team (referred to in this preamble as the "Lady Vols") defeated the Cardinal of Stanford by a score of 64-48 to win the 2008 National Collegiate Athletic Association Division I Women's Basketball Championship;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas that victory marked the second national title for the Lady Vols in 2 years, and the 8th national title of the Lady Vols in the last 20 years;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the University of Tennessee became the first school to accomplish back-to-back national titles twice, having previously achieved that feat during its 3-peat from 1996 through 1998;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Lady Vols were successful due to the leadership of Head Coach Pat Summitt, the Nation's all-time winningest National Collegiate Athletic Association basketball coach among men's and women's teams, with 983 wins over 34 seasons at the University of Tennessee;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Joan Cronan, the Women's Athletics Director of the University of Tennessee, has--</chair>
  <chair>(1) shown vision and leadership throughout her 25-year career at the University of Tennessee; and</chair>
  <chair>(2) created 1 of the most visible and respected athletic programs in the country;</chair>
  <chair>Whereas the Lady Vols compiled an impressive overall record of 36 wins and 2 losses, avenging 1 of those losses against Stanford in the championship game;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Lady Vols were guided all season long by--</chair>
  <chair>(1) the leadership of the seniors on the team, including--</chair>
  <chair>&#xCC; (A) Nicky Anosike;</chair>
  <chair>&#xCC; (B) Alberta Auguste;</chair>
  <chair>&#xCC; (C) Shannon Bobbitt; and</chair>
  <chair>&#xCC; (D) Alexis Hornbuckle; and</chair>
  <chair>(2) the outstanding play of the 2008 Naismith Trophy winner, Candace Parker;</chair>
  <chair>Whereas Candace Parker, while playing with an injured shoulder, tallied 17 points, 9 rebounds, and 4 steals, and was selected as the Most Outstanding Player for the 2008 tournament, becoming--</chair>
  <chair>(1) the 4th player in history to achieve that honor 2 years in a row; and</chair>
  <chair>(2) the 5th member of the University of Tennessee women's basketball team to be so honored, following in the footsteps of--</chair>
  <chair>&#xCC; (A) Chamique Holdsclaw, who was honored in 1997 and 1998;</chair>
  <chair>&#xCC; (B) Michelle Marciniak, who was honored in 1996;</chair>
  <chair>&#xCC; (C) Bridgette Gordon, who was honored in 1989; and</chair>
  <chair>&#xCC; (D) Tonya Edwards, who was honored in 1987;</chair>
  <chair>Whereas Shannon Bobbitt, who at only 5 feet, 2 inches, is the shortest player ever to play on the University of Tennessee women's basketball team, and whose 3 first half 3-pointers and transition defense helped establish an early lead, finished the game with 13 points, and was named to the 2008 All-Tournament Team;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Nicky Anosike, who finished the game with 12 points, 8 rebounds, and a game-high 6 steals, was named to the 2008 All-Tournament Team;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Alberta Auguste scored 7 points to go along with 7 rebounds;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Alexis Hornbuckle, whose dogged defense helped hold the Stanford team to a season-low 48 points and a season-high 25 turnovers, finished with 6 points and 3 assists; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas freshman Vicki Baugh provided a nice boost off the bench with 8 points and 4 rebounds; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Head Coach Pat Summitt's Lady Vols set an example off the court as well, by continuing to sustain a remarkable graduation rate, with every student athlete who has completed her eligibility at the University of Tennessee graduating or working toward all of the requirements for graduation: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) congratulates the University of Tennessee women's basketball team for--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) being champions on and off the court; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) the victory of the team in the 2008 National Collegiate Athletic Association Division I Women's Basketball Championship (referred to in this resolution as the "NCAA women's basketball championship");&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) recognizes the significant achievements of the players, coaches, students, alumni, and support staff whose dedication and hard work helped the University of Tennessee Lady Volunteers win the NCAA women's basketball championship; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) respectfully requests the Secretary of the Senate to transmit for appropriate display an enrolled copy of this resolution to--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) Dr. John D. Petersen, President of the University of Tennessee;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) Joan Cronan, Women's Athletics Director of the University of Tennessee; and</chair>
  <chair> (C) Pat Summitt, Women's Basketball Head Coach of the University of Tennessee.  &lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
