<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1168621202" ordinal="21" title="JUDICIAL NOMINEES">
  <speaking speaker="300062" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today to express my regret that nominations to the U.S. Courts of Appeals will not be resubmitted for William G. Myers, Judge Terrence Boyle, William J. Haynes, and Michael B. Wallace. All four of these nominees were eminently qualified to serve on the U.S. Court of Appeals and no reasonable question has been raised as to their integrity. Each of them very likely would have been confirmed had they been afforded to the courtesy of a vote by the U.S. Senate. It is  generally understood that the Senate did not vote on these nominations because of Democratic threats of obstruction and filibuster, and that the President chose not to resubmit these nominations as a result of a hard political calculation that the new Democratic majority in the Senate would not allow a vote on these nominations during the remainder of his Presidency. These nominees were not treated fairly by this institution. This week's action reflects poorly on the Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Much could be said about each of these nominees, their qualifications, and the way that they were treated throughout the judicial nominations process. I would like today to simply submit for the RECORD a column published by Edward Whelan in National  Review Online. Mr. Whelan's column raises some disturbing questions about the American Bar Association's actions with regard to Michael B. Wallace, whom the President had nominated to the U.S. Court  of Appeals for the Fifth Circuit. Mr. Wallace is a graduate of Harvard University and received his law degree from the University of Virginia, where he served on the law review and was elected to the Order of the Coif. He clerked for Justice William Rehnquist on the United States Supreme Court. He became an associate and later a partner at a major</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is generally understood that the ultimate reason why Mr. Wallace's nomination has not been resubmitted is that he was rated "not qualified" by the ABA. on account of his "temperament." Mr. Whelan's column paints a disturbing picture of the process by which the ABA. came to rate Mr. Wallace. Mr. Whelan presents persuasive evidence that the ABA not only allowed its evaluations process to be corrupted by individuals who used it to carry out personal and political vendettas against Mr. Wallace,  but that the chairwoman of the ABA's judicial evaluations committee perjured herself in her testimony before the Senate Judiciary Committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To Mr. Whelan's column, I would simply add that I found the ABA's written justification for its rating of Mr. Wallace to be stunningly unpersuasive. The grounds cited in the ABA's written testimony, to the extent that they provided any verifiable basis at all for the ABA's rating of Mr. Wallace, do not stand up to even the most cursory scrutiny. To cite just one example: the ABA found that Mr. Wallace lacked the "temperament" to be a judge in part because "positions taken by Mr. Wallace  related to the Voting Rights Act" in the course of the Jordan v. Winter litigation were "not well-founded and [were] contrary ..... to existing interpretations of the Voting Rights Act." Mr. Wallace had argued in the Jordan case that the 1982 amendments to the Voting Rights Act did not invalidate a State's redistricting plan absent some evidence that the plan was the product of racial discrimination. At the time that Mr. Wallace made this argument, the 1982 amendments were less than a year old.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thus the ABA has rated Mr. Wallace as "not qualified" on the basis that he argued for a particular interpretation of a statute when the statute was new and was not yet subject to an authoritative interpretation, when Mr. Wallace's position was later adopted by two members of the U.S. Supreme Court, and when those same Supreme Court Justices characterized the statute as "unclear." I find the ABA's analysis to be wholly unreasonable. It is a lawyer's duty to make good-faith arguments on behalf  of his client. Yet in the case of Mr. Wallace, the ABA has effectively taken the position that if a lawyer argues for an interpretation of a statute that is ultimately rejected by the courts, then even if the statute is new and unclear and the lawyer's interpretation is even endorsed by some members of the</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the following column be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
</record>
