<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1197997209" ordinal="36" title="CHANGES TO S. CON. RES. 21">
  <narrative>CHANGES TO <bill type="sc" number="21">S. CON. RES. 21</bill> -- (Senate - December 18, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="15893">S15893</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300026" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, section 301(a) of <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>, the 2008 budget resolution, permits the chairman of the Senate Budget Committee to revise the allocations, aggregates, and other appropriate levels for legislation that reauthorizes the State Children's Health Insurance Program, SCHIP. Section 301 authorizes the revisions provided that certain conditions are met, including that such legislation maintains coverage for those currently enrolled in SCHIP and that it not worsen the deficit  over the period of the total of fiscal years 2007 through 2012 or the period of the total of fiscal years 2007 through 2017.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, section 304(b)(2) of <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill> permits the chairman of the Senate Budget Committee to revise the allocations, aggregates, and other appropriate levels for legislation that both increases the reimbursement rate for physician services under section  1848(d) of the Social Security Act and includes financial incentives for physicians to improve the quality and efficiency of items and services furnished to Medicare beneficiaries through  the use of consensus-based quality measures. Section 304(b)(2) authorizes the revisions provided that such legislation not worsen the deficit over the period of the total of fiscal years 2007 through 2012 or the period of the total of fiscal years 2007 through 2017.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Further, section 320(a) of <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill> permits the chairman of the Senate Budget Committee to revise the allocations, aggregates, and other appropriate levels for legislation that provides for a delay in the implementation of the proposed rule published on January 18, 2007, on pages 2236 through 2248 of volume 72, Federal Register, or any other rule that would affect the Medicaid program or SCHIP in a similar manner, or place restrictions on coverage of or payment for graduate medical education,  rehabilitation services, or school-based administration, transportation, or medical services under title XIX of the Social Security Act. The adjustment is contingent on such legislation not worsening the deficit over the period of the total of fiscal years 2007 through 2012 or the period of the total of fiscal years 2007 through 2017.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, section 320(c) of <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill> permits the chairman of the Senate Budget Committee to revise the allocations, aggregates, and other appropriate levels for legislation that extends the Transitional Medical Assistance program, provided that such legislation not worsen the deficit over the period of the total of fiscal years 2007 through 2012 or the period of the total of fiscal years 2007 through 2017.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I find that the Medicare, Medicaid, and SCHIP Extension Act of 2007, which was introduced today by Senators BAUCUS and GRASSLEY, satisfies the conditions of the four deficit-neutral reserve funds mentioned above. Therefore, pursuant to sections 301(a), 304(b)(2), 320(a), and 320(c) of <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>, I am adjusting the aggregates in the 2008 budget resolution, as well as the allocation provided to the Senate Finance Committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the following revisions to <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill> be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>[In billions of dolla rs]</narrative>
  <narrative>Section 101</narrative>
  <narrative>(1)(A) Federal Revenues:</narrative>
  <narrative>1,900.340</narrative>
  <narrative>2,025.853</narrative>
  <narrative>2,121.872</narrative>
  <narrative>2,175.881</narrative>
  <narrative>2,357.045</narrative>
  <narrative>2,499.046</narrative>
  <narrative>(1)(B) Change in Federal Revenues:</narrative>
  <narrative>-4.366</narrative>
  <narrative>-24.943</narrative>
  <narrative>14.946</narrative>
  <narrative>12.160</narrative>
  <narrative>-37.505</narrative>
  <narrative>-98.050</narrative>
  <narrative>(2) New Budget Authority:</narrative>
  <narrative>2,371.470</narrative>
  <narrative>2,512.349</narrative>
  <narrative>2,526.893</narrative>
  <narrative>2,580.802</narrative>
  <narrative>2,695.912</narrative>
  <narrative>2,735.561</narrative>
  <narrative>(3) Budget Outlays:</narrative>
  <narrative>2,294.862</narrative>
  <narrative>2,476.144</narrative>
  <narrative>2,573.701</narrative>
  <narrative>2,608.687</narrative>
  <narrative>2,701.268</narrative>
  <narrative>2,714.335&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <narrative>[In millions of dollars]</narrative>
  <narrative>Current Allocation to Senate Finance Committee</narrative>
  <narrative>FY 2007 Budget Authority</narrative>
  <narrative>1,011,527</narrative>
  <narrative>FY 2007 Outlays</narrative>
  <narrative>1,017,808</narrative>
  <narrative>FY 2008 Budget Authority</narrative>
  <narrative>1,088,237</narrative>
  <narrative>FY 2008 Outlays</narrative>
  <narrative>1,082,300</narrative>
  <narrative>FY 2008-2012 Budget Authority</narrative>
  <narrative>6,067,090</narrative>
  <narrative>FY 2008-2012 Outlays</narrative>
  <narrative>6,057,094</narrative>
  <narrative>Adjustments</narrative>
  <narrative>FY 2007 Budget Authority</narrative>
  <narrative>0</narrative>
  <narrative>FY 2007 Outlays</narrative>
  <narrative>0</narrative>
  <narrative>FY 2008 Budget Authority</narrative>
  <narrative>3,465</narrative>
  <narrative>FY 2008 Outlays</narrative>
  <narrative>4,644</narrative>
  <narrative>FY 2008-2012 Budget Authority</narrative>
  <narrative>-71</narrative>
  <narrative>FY 2008-2012 Outlays</narrative>
  <narrative>-80</narrative>
  <narrative>Revised Allocation to Senate Finance Committee</narrative>
  <narrative>FY 2007 Budget Authority</narrative>
  <narrative>1,011,527</narrative>
  <narrative>FY 2007 Outlays</narrative>
  <narrative>1,017,808</narrative>
  <narrative>FY 2008 Budget Authority</narrative>
  <narrative>1,091,702</narrative>
  <narrative>FY 2008 Outlays</narrative>
  <narrative>1,086,944</narrative>
  <narrative>FY 2008-2012 Budget Authority</narrative>
  <narrative>6,067,019</narrative>
  <narrative>FY 2008-2012 Outlays</narrative>
  <narrative>6,057,014 &lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</narrative>
</record>
