<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1211299202" ordinal="23" title="FAIR CREDIT REPORTING ACT AMENDMENTS">
  <narrative>FAIR CREDIT REPORTING ACT AMENDMENTS -- (Senate - May 20, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="4439">S4439</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300087" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of <bill type="h" number="4008">H.R. 4008</bill>, which was received from the House.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will state the bill by title.</chair>
  <chair>The assistant legislative clerk read as follows:</chair>
  <chair>A bill (<bill type="h" number="4008">H.R. 4008</bill>) to amend the Fair Credit Reporting Act to make technical corrections to the definition of willful noncompliance with respect to violations involving the printing of an expiration date on certain credit and debit card receipts before the date of the enactment of this Act.</chair>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the bill.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300087" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the bill be  read the third time and passed, the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table, and that any statements relating to the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The bill (<bill type="h" number="4008">H.R. 4008</bill>) was ordered to a third reading, was read the third time, and passed.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300087" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I am glad we have just passed <bill type="h" number="4008">H.R. 4008</bill>. I thank all of my colleagues and Representative Mahoney in the House, who authored the Credit and Debt Card Receipt Clarification Act. I introduced an identical bill on the Senate side, which was <bill type="s" number="2978">S. 2978</bill>. The House passed this bill last week by the unanimous vote of 407 to 0.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="4008">H.R. 4008</bill> is a narrow, commonsense bill that will smooth the transition to new rules for printing credit card receipts under the Fair and Accurate Credit Transaction Act, or FACTA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>FACTA says the credit card receipts can only display one of two things: either the last five digits of the credit card account number or the expiration date.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, the law was not as clear as it could have been, and many companies misunderstood this requirement. They redacted account numbers in order to comply with FACTA but mistakenly left expiration dates in place.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But unlike the State laws after which it is modeled, FACTA is tied to a statutory damages provision that sparked the filing of hundreds of class action lawsuits against companies whose sole error was printing expiration dates on receipts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let's be clear. These lawsuits are not alleging that consumers were harmed in any way. I will repeat that. The lawsuits are not alleging that consumers were harmed in any way. In fact, experts on identity theft will tell you that printing the expiration date doesn't present any risk of fraud or identity theft, as long as the account number is truncated.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Yet companies are facing sky-high liability of up to $1,000 per receipt. Some of them are large retail businesses; most of them are small mom-and-pop stores. The damages in these cases are so huge that judges have refused to certify class actions because the lawsuits could actually destroy the companies--small and large.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The long list of defendants in these cases includes many major corporations--we have all heard of the hotels, restaurant chains, et cetera--as well as little mom-and-pop stores.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is fair to say that these lawsuits will actually hurt consumers because companies will be forced to raise prices, or even close stores, in order to cover the cost of legal fees and expensive settlements. This is at a time when our economy and businesses--particularly those dealing with retail--are already struggling to rebound from tough times.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So the bill is a win-win proposition for everyone. It stops destructive lawsuits against companies that made a harmless error in the past, but it also ensures that consumers can still sue in any case where they were actually harmed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Going forward, companies will still have to meet the same strict rules Congress originally passed in fact. I am glad the Senate was able to take quick action on this important bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
