<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1179763212" ordinal="46" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="COMMITTEE ON HOMELAND SECURITY AND GOVERNMENTAL AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs be authorized to hold an off-the- floor markup during the session of the Senate on Monday, May 21, 2007, at 5:30 p.m., in S-216 of the Capitol, to consider pending committee business.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Agenda</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Howard C. Weizmann to be Deputy Director, Office of Personnel Management.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>(1) <bill type="s" number="1352">S. 1352</bill>, a bill to designate the facility of the U.S. Postal Service located at 127 East Locust Street In Fairbury, llilinois, as the "Dr. Francis Townsend Post Office Building";</paragraph>
    <paragraph>(2) <bill type="h" number="1402">H.R. 1402</bill>, a bill to designate the facility of the U.S. Postal Service located at 320 South Lecanto Highway in Lecanto, Florida, as the "Sergeant Dennis J. Flanagan Lecanto Post Office Building";</paragraph>
    <paragraph>(3) <bill type="h" number="625">H.R. 625</bill>, a bill to designate the facility of the U.S. Postal Service located at 4230 Maine Avenue in Baldwin Park, California, as the "Atanacio Haro-Marin Post Office";</paragraph>
    <paragraph>(4) <bill type="h" number="988">H.R. 988</bill>, a bill to designate the facility of the U.S. Postal Service located at 5757 Tilton Avenue in Riverside, California, as the "Lieutenant Todd Jason Bryant Post Office";</paragraph>
    <paragraph>(5) <bill type="h" number="437">H.R. 437</bill>, a bill to designate the facility of the U.S. Postal Service located at 500 West Eisenhower Street in Rio Grande City, Texas, as the "Lino Perez Jr. Post Office";</paragraph>
    <paragraph>(6) <bill type="h" number="414">H.R. 414</bill>, a bill to designate the facility of the U.S. Postal Service located at 60 Calle McKinley West in Mayaguez, Puerto Rico, as the "Miguel Angel Garcia Mendez Post Office Building."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
