<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1190131202" ordinal="51" title="NOTICE OF HEARING">
  <narrative>NOTICE OF HEARING -- (Senate - September 18, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="11678">S11678</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON NATIONAL PARKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to announce for the information of the Senate and the public that a hearing has been scheduled before the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, Subcommittee on National Parks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The hearing will be held on September 27, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of this hearing will be to receive testimony on the following bills: <bill type="s" number="128">S. 128</bill>, to amend the Cache La Poudre River Corridor Act to designate a new management entity, make certain technical and conforming amendments, enhance private property protections, and for other purposes; <bill type="s" number="148">S. 148</bill>, to establish the Paterson Great Falls National Park in the State of New Jersey, and for other purposes; <bill type="s" number="189">S. 189</bill>, to decrease the matching funds requirement and authorize additional appropriations for Keweenaw  National Historical Park in the State of Michigan; <bill type="s" number="697">S. 697</bill>, to establish the Steel Industry National Historic Site in the State of Pennsylvania; <bill type="s" number="867">S. 867</bill>, to adjust the boundary of Lowell National Historical Park, and for other purposes; <bill type="s" number="1341">S. 1341</bill>, to provide for the exchange of certain Bureau of Land Management land in Pima County, Arizona, and for other purposes; <bill type="s" number="1476">S. 1476</bill>, to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a special resources study of the Tule Lake Segregation Center in Modoc County, California, to determine the suitability and feasibility of establishing a unit of the National Park System; <bill type="s" number="1709">S. 1709</bill></paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of the limited time available for the hearing, witnesses may testify by invitation only. However, those wishing to submit written testimony for the hearing record should send it to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, United States Senate, Washington, DC 20510-6150, or by e-mail to rachel</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For further information, please contact David Brooks at (202) 224-9863 or Rachel Pasternack at (202) 224-0883.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
