<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1204045202" ordinal="44" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <narrative>AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET -- (Senate - February 26, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="1204">S1204</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300042" topic="COMMITTEE ON ARMED SERVICES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, February 26, 2008, at 9:30 a.m., in open session in order to receive testimony on the Department of the Army in review of the defense authorization request for fiscal year  2009 and the future years defense program.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300042" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND NATURAL RESOURCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources be authorized to me et during the session of the Senate in order to conduct a hearing on Tuesday, February 26, 2008, at 10 a.m., in room SD366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building. At this hearing, the Committee will hear testimony regarding U.S. oil inventory policies, including the Strategic Petroleum Reserve policies.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300042" topic="COMMITTEE ON FINANCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent  that the Committee on Finance be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, February 26, 2008, at 10 a.m., in room 215 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building, in order to hear testimony on "Economic and Fiscal Conditions of the States."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300042" topic="SELECT COMMITTEE ON INTELLIGENCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Select Committee on Intel ligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on February 26, 2008, at 2:30 p.m. in order to hold a closed hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
