<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1168275603" ordinal="31" title="ADDITIONAL STATEMENTS">
  <speaking speaker="300030" topic="A TRAGIC LOSS FOR IDAHOANS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, with sadness I recognize the passing of Dan Harpole, former executive director of the Idaho Commission on the Arts, president of the National Assembly of State Arts Agencies, and dedicated father and friend. I had the pleasure of working with Dan in recent years as he promoted arts in Idaho and truly changed the face of the Idaho Commission on the Arts. Dan successfully worked to integrate art appreciation and education into Idaho communities through local, State and  Federal collaboration efforts. Dan's spirit has transformed the arts in Idaho, bringing them to a place of cultural and community preeminence. I respectfully submit a portion of his obituary, written by his good friend and fellow Idaho artist, Cort Conley, that describes, in detail, Dan's remarkable achievements in Idaho.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In November 2000, Dan was unanimously singled out from a field of 36 distinguished candidates as the new executive director of the Idaho Commission on the Arts. Although chosen for his reputation and recognition earned elsewhere, he was also selected for his optimistic, companionable disposition and pragmatic views, his ability to build bridges and get things done. Chair Marilyn Beck's estimate that he was the perfect person for the job proved astute. He came to inhabit Idaho arts the way paint  does a painting. Dan thrived on the lives and challenges around him on what is now called networking. His attitude and leadership led to a legacy of accomplishments on behalf of the arts in Idaho. Not a little of it was his talent for consensus or accord, which he once attributed to being the seventh of ten children: When you're in a big family, you learn to negotiate for your life, he quipped. While in Idaho, Dan served on the executive committee of the board of directors for the National Assembly of State Arts Agencies and was elected president in 2005. He also served as trustee for the Western States Arts Federation. Among the exceptional achievements of his legacy: uniting the Idaho Congressional</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I was glad to hear of the NEA Chairman's Medal that Dan's family will receive on his behalf this month, but not the least bit surprised. I had the opportunity to recognize Dan's remarkable abilities and accomplishments in this Chamber almost a year ago when he was chosen to be president of the National Assembly of State Arts Agencies. Dan fully deserved this and all accolades that he received over the years. His love of the arts, his work promoting their appreciation in Idaho and his ability  to provide leadership, vision, insight, and compassion lives on unmistakably in his legacy. Cort Conley concludes his tribute to Dan's life by stating:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In summary, then: love, laughter, courage. All estimable indeed. Still, as a tombstone in County Kerry reads, "Death leaves a heartache no one can heal/Love leaves a memory no one can steal." Nothing more appropriate can be said.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My wife Susan and I offer our condolences to his family and especially to his young children, Hunter and Fiona, at this difficult time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
