<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1185163200" ordinal="36" title="EXECUTIVE SESSION">
  <narrative>EXECUTIVE SESSION -- (Senate - July 23, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="9792">S9792</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="EXECUTIVE CALENDAR">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to executive session to consider Executive Calendar Nos. 161, 232, 233, 234, 235, 236, 237, and the nominations placed on the Secretary's desk; that the nominations be confirmed, the motions to reconsider be laid on the table; that any statements thereon be printed in the Record, the President be immediately notified of the Senate's action, and the Senate then return to legislative session.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The nominations considered and confirmed are as follows:</chair>
  <chair>Michael G. Vickers, of California, to be an Assistant Secretary of Defense.</chair>
  <chair>William Herbert Heyman, of New York, to be a Director of the Securities Investor Protection Corporation for a term expiring December 31, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>Mark S. Shelton, of Kansas, to be a Director of the Securities Investor Protection Corporation for a term expiring December 31, 2008.</chair>
  <chair>William S. Jasien, of Virginia, to be a Director of the Securities Investor Protection Corporation for a term expiring December 31, 2009.</chair>
  <chair>Subject to qualifications provided by law, the following for temporary appointment to the grade indicated in the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</chair>
  <chair>To be rear admiral&lt;br&gt;Jonathan W. Bailey</chair>
  <chair>Subject to qualifications provided by law, the following for temporary appointment to the grade indicated in the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</chair>
  <chair>To be rear admiral (lower half)&lt;br&gt;Philip M. Kenul</chair>
  <chair>William Herbert Heyman, of New York, to be a Director of the Securities Investor Protection Corporation for a term expiring December 31, 2010.</chair>
  <chair>PN581 COAST GUARD nomination of Jason D. Rimington, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of May 21, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>PN582 COAST GUARD nomination of Jeffery J. Rasnake, which was received by the Senate and appeared in the Congressional Record of May 21, 2007</chair>
</record>
