<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1173974406" ordinal="56" title="CONGRATULATING THE UNIVERSITY OF ALASKA FAIRBANKS RIFLE TEAM">
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate now proceed to <bill type="sr" number="109">S. Res. 109</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300075" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise to recognize the University of Alaska Fairbanks rifle team for winning the 2007 National Collegiate Athletic Association Rifle Championship on March 10, 2007 in Fairbanks, AK.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With a total score of 4,662 points for their performance in the smallbore and air rifle competitions, the undefeated and defending champion University of Alaska Fairbanks "Nanooks" posted an 18-point win over the U.S. Military Academy and a 23-point win over Jacksonville State University to claim their ninth national championship title.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This was the first time the Nanooks have hosted an NCAA Championship. More than 900 spectators, a record crowd for an NCAA Rifle Championship, were present to help support the local team.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nanooks head coach Dan Jordan, along with each member of the 2007 University of Alaska Fairbanks rifle team, which includes six National Rifle Association All-Americans, should be recognized for their achievements during this past season. I congratulate the team and wish them continued success in future years.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
