<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1192723202" ordinal="6" title="MEASURES PLACED ON THE CALENDAR--S. 2179, S. 2180, S. 2184, S. 2185, H.R. 2102, AND H.R. 3678">
  <narrative>MEASURES PLACED ON THE CALENDAR--S. 2179, <bill type="s" number="2180">S. 2180</bill>, <bill type="s" number="2184">S. 2184</bill>, <bill type="s" number="2185">S. 2185</bill>, <bill type="h" number="2102">H.R. 2102</bill>, AND <bill type="h" number="3678">H.R. 3678</bill> -- (Senate - October 18, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="13029">S13029</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, it is my understanding we have six bills at the desk due for a second reading.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will read the titles of the bills for the second time.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A bill (<bill type="s" number="2179">S. 2179</bill>) to authorize certain programs and activities in the Forest Service, the Department of the Interior, and the Department of Energy, and for other purposes.</narrative>
  <narrative>A bill (<bill type="s" number="2180">S. 2180</bill>) to authorize certain programs and activities in the Department of the Interior, the Forest Service, and the Department of Energy, and to amend the Compact of Free Association Amendments Act of 2003, and for other purposes.</narrative>
  <narrative>A bill (<bill type="s" number="2184">S. 2184</bill>) to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to permanently allow penalty-free withdrawals from retirement plans for individuals called to active duty for at least 179 days.</narrative>
  <narrative>A bill (<bill type="s" number="2185">S. 2185</bill>) to permanently extend the current marginal tax rates.</narrative>
  <narrative>A bill (<bill type="h" number="2102">H.R. 2102</bill>) to maintain the free flow of information to the public by providing conditions for the federally compelled disclosure of information by certain persons connected with the news media.</narrative>
  <narrative>A bill (<bill type="h" number="3678">H.R. 3678</bill>) to amend the Internet Tax Freedom Act to extend the moratorium on certain taxes relating to the Internet and to electronic commerce.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I object to further proceedings with respect to these bills en bloc.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <chair>The bills will be placed on the calendar.</chair>
  <chair>The Senator from Wisconsin.</chair>
</record>
