<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1216742408" ordinal="44" title="RECOGNIZING THE 60TH ANNIVERSARY OF INTEGRATION OF THE U.S. ARMED FORCES">
  <narrative>RECOGNIZING THE 60TH ANNIVERSARY OF INTEGRATION OF THE U.S. ARMED FORCES -- (Senate - July 22, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="7078">S7078</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300087" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of <bill type="sc" number="94">S. Con. Res. 94</bill> submitted earlier today by Senator Brown.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A concurrent resolution (<bill type="sc" number="94">S. Con. Res. 94</bill>) recognizing the 60th anniversary of the integration of the U.S. Armed Forces.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the concurrent resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300087" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the concurrent resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table, with no intervening action or debate, and that any statements relating to the measure be printed in the Record at the appropriate place, as if read.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The concurrent resolution (<bill type="sc" number="94">S. Con. Res. 94</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The concurrent resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sc" number="94">S. Con. Res. 94</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas service members representing a wide diversity of races and nationalities have fought in every war in the history of the United States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, on July 26, 1948, President Harry Truman signed Executive Order 9981, ordering the racial integration of the Armed Forces;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas President Truman declared that there should be equality of treatment and opportunity for all persons in the Armed Forces, without regard to race, color, religion, or national origin;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the United States could not maintain an all-volunteer force without the service of, and critical role played by, service members representing a wide diversity of races and nationalities;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas service member diversity brings a unique perspective and experience to the Armed Forces;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Armed Forces led the way in social integration prior to the signal achievement of the legal victory in the Supreme Court decision of Brown v. Board of Education, 347 U.S. 483 (1954), which rejected separate white and colored schools;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Armed Forces led the way in social integration prior to the passage of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, which banned discrimination in employment practices and public accommodations, the Voting Rights Act of 1965, which restored and protected voting rights, and the Civil Rights Act of 1968, which banned discrimination in the sale or rental of housing;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the integration of the Armed Forces enhanced the combat effectiveness of the military 60 years ago, and that still holds true to the current day;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the efforts of the Armed Forces to ensure equality of treatment and opportunity for their personnel significantly assisted in the advancement of that goal for all Americans; and &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, in 2008, members representing a wide diversity of races and nationalities serve in senior leadership positions throughout the Armed Forces, as commissioned and warrant officers, as senior noncommissioned officers, and as civilian leaders: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved by the Senate (the House of Representatives concurring), That Congress--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) recognizes the historic significance of the 60th anniversary of the integration of the Armed Forces of the United States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) reaffirms the commitment of the Federal Government to ensuring diversity in the military; and</chair>
  <chair> (3) commends African-Americans, Hispanics, Asian-Americans, Native Americans, and service members of all races and nationalities for their remarkable achievements, sacrifices, and contributions to our Armed Forces in all conflicts in United States history in the face of discrimination, hostility, and other obstacles. &lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
