<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1188956525" ordinal="56" title="NOTICES OF HEARINGS">
  <narrative>NOTICES OF HEARINGS -- (Senate - September 04, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="11065">S11065</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND NATURAL RESOURCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to announce for the information of the Senate and the public that a hearing has been scheduled before Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The hearing will be held on September 11, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the hearing is to receive testimony on the following bills: <bill type="s" number="127">S. 127</bill>, to amend the Great Sand Dunes National Park and Preserve Act of 2000 to explain the purpose and provide for the administration of the Baca National Wildlife Refuge; <bill type="s" number="327">S. 327</bill> and <bill type="h" number="359">H.R. 359</bill>, to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a special resource study of sites associated with the life of Cesar Estrada Chavez and the farm labor movement; <bill type="s" number="868">S. 868</bill>, to amend the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate segments  of the Taunton River in the Commonwealth of Massachusetts as a component of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System; <bill type="s" number="1051">S. 1051</bill>, to authorize National Mall Liberty Fund D.C. to establish a memorial on Federal land in the District of Columbia at Constitution Gardens previously approved to honor free persons and slaves who fought for independence, liberty, and justice for all during the American Revolution; <bill type="s" number="1184">S. 1184</bill> and <bill type="h" number="1021">H.R. 1021</bill>, to direct the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a special resources study regarding the suitability and feasibility of designating certain historic buildings and areas in Taunton, Massachusetts, as a unit of the National Park System, and for other purposes; <bill type="s" number="1247">S. 1247</bill>, to amend the Weir Farm National Historic Site Establishment Act of 1990 to limit the development of any property acquired by the Secretary of the Interior for the</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of the limited time available for the hearing, witnesses may testify by invitation only. However, those wishing to submit written testimony for the hearing record should send it to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, United States Senate, Washington DC 20510-6150, or by email to rachel Xpasternack@energy.senate.gov.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For further information, please contact David Brooks at (202) 224-9863 or Rachel Pasternack at (202) Q24-0883.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="COMMITTEE ON RULES AND ADMINISTRATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I wish to announce that the Committee on Rules and Administration will meet on Wednesday, September 12, 2007, at 10 a.m., to conduct a hearing on the Nomination of Robert C. Tapella of Virginia, to be Public Printer, Government Printing Office.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For further information regarding this hearing, please contact Howard Gantman at the Rules and Administration Committee, 224-6352.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
