<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1180022410" ordinal="17" title="CALLING UPON THE GOVERNMENT OF THE ISLAMIC REPUBLIC OF IRAN TO IMMEDIATELY RELEASE DR. HALEH ESFANDIARI">
  <speaking speaker="400064" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent to proceed to the immediate consideration of <bill type="sr" number="214">S. Res. 214</bill> submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400064" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, this resolution brings to the Senate's attention the ongoing plight of Dr. Haleh Esfandiari. Dr. Esfandiari is the director of the Middle East Program at the Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars here in Washington, DC. She holds dual citizenship with the United States and Iran and visits her ailing 93-year-old mother twice a year in Iran.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>During her return to the United States on her last visit, Dr. Esfandiari's vehicle was robbed by three knife-wielding men. She lost her luggage and her travel documents. Later, when she requested the replacement documents, agents of Iran's Ministry of Intelligence began to question her for hours over the course of several days. The Ministry of Intelligence asked Dr. Esfandiari questions about her work and her work at the Woodrow Wilson International Center. The Woodrow Wilson International Center  supplied exhaustive material about her education and information about her mission.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dr. Esfandiari was essentially kept under house arrest for 10 weeks. On May 7 she was informed she must return to the Intelligence Ministry on May 8. Upon honoring the summons, Dr. Esfandiari was immediately taken into custody and jailed. She has been denied contact with her family, her attorneys, and the outside world. Earlier this week, news reports stated that Dr. Esfandiari is suspected of espionage and supporting the "soft revolution" against the regime in Iran.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dr. Esfandiari is well known and well respected as a Middle East scholar. She has dedicated her professional career to bringing people together from the West to gain greater understanding of the Middle East and to gain common ground.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Increasingly, Iran has begun to stifle debate among different people and international exchanges.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Department of State has called upon the Iranians to release Dr. Esfandiari. I am joined in this resolution by Senators Mikulski, Biden, Lieberman, Smith, Clinton, and Dodd, which encourages the State Department to keep up the pressure on the Iranians to do the right thing and release Dr. Esfandiari.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also wish to recognize the solid effort of the Woodrow Wilson International Center and its staff, led by our former colleague in the House of Representatives, Lee Hamilton, for its steadfast support of Dr. Esfandiari.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, I wish to express my support for Dr. Esfandiari's family during this trying time. She has a strong family and dozens of caring friends who refuse to give up her plight and refuse to let the Iranians suppress a beacon of peace and understanding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is outrageous. The Iranians need to do the right thing and allow her to return home here in the United States.  I can tell my colleagues that this body needs to stand in strong opposition to what the Iranians are doing, urging them to release this U.S. citizen so she can return here to her home.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table, and that any statements relating there to be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
