<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1222444802" ordinal="137" title="ALCOHOL AND DRUG ADDICTION RECOVERY DAY">
  <narrative>ALCOHOL AND DRUG ADDICTION RECOVERY DAY -- (Senate - September 26, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="9876">S9876</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412247" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of calendar No. 1084, <bill type="sr" number="659">S. Res. 659</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="659">S. Res. 659</bill>) designating September 27, 2008, as Alcohol and Drug Addiction Recovery Day.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412247" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table, with no intervening action or debate, and that any statements relating to the resolution be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="659">S. Res. 659</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="659">S. Res. 659</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas treatment and long-term recovery from substance use disorders can offer a renewed outlook on life for those who are addicted and their family members;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas more than 23,000,000 people in the United States struggle with substance use disorders;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas people who receive treatment for substance use disorders can lead more productive and fulfilling lives, personally and professionally;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas studies have consistently found that treatment is essential for people to be successful in their paths of recovery;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas real stories of long-term recovery can inspire others to ask for help and improve their own lives, the lives of their families, and the entire community;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas it is critical that we educate our community members that substance use disorders are treatable chronic diseases, and that by reaching out to those who suffer from these disorders we can improve the quality of life for the entire community;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, to help achieve this goal, the Department of Health and Human Services, the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, the National Council on Alcoholism and Drug Dependency, the Partnership for a Drug-Free America, and A&amp;E Television Networks, along with thousands of people from across the country, will hold a Recovery Rally on the Brooklyn Bridge and in City Hall Park in New York City on September 27, 2008; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Recovery Rally will be part of National Alcohol and Drug Addiction Recovery Month: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) designates September 27, 2008, as Alcohol and Drug Addiction Recovery Day; and</chair>
  <chair> (2) calls upon the people of the United States to observe this day with appropriate programs, activities, and ceremonies.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
