<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1191513602" ordinal="35" title="EARMARKS DISCLOSURE">
  <narrative>EARMARKS DISCLOSURE -- (Senate - October 04, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="12768">S12768</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300056" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, yesterday, the Senate adopted several amendments to the Defense appropriations bill. It is my understanding that <bill type="s" number="1">S. 1</bill> requires that a Senator who offers any amendment is required to list the name of any Senator who submitted a request for each respective item in the CONGRESSIONAL RECORD.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In compliance with this, I note that on amendment 3117, Senators GREGG, MCCONNELL, VITTER, CORKER, KYL, DOMENICI, CHAMBLISS, CORNYN, SUNUNU, MCCAIN, SPECTER, and ISAKSON cosponsored the amendment regarding funding for border security. On amendment 3129, Senator MIKULSKI cosponsored the amendment regarding the Troops for Nurses program. On amendment 3131, Senator LEVIN submitted a request for the  Virtual Systems Integrated Laboratory. On amendment 3135, as modified, Senator KERRY submitted a request for High Temperature Superconductor Motors. On amendment 3141, Senators NELSON of Florida, KYL, LIEBERMAN, VITTER, INHOFE, NELSON of Nebraska, PRYOR, LAUTENBERG, BAYH, LINCOLN, and WEBB cosponsored the amendment regarding the Aegis Ballistic Missile System. On amendment 3152, Senators BROWN, SPECTER, WARNER, and WEBB submitted requests for the Minuteman Digitization Demonstration Program. On amendment 3153, as modified, Senator MIKULSKI cosponsored the amendment, and</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, in accordance with the requirements of paragraph 4.a of rule XLIV of the Standing Rules of the Senate, the following is a list of items included in amendments to the Fiscal Year 2008 National Defense Authorization Act at my request:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, in accordance with the requirements of paragraph 4.a of rule XLIV of the Standing Rules of the Senate, the following is a list of items included in amendments to the fiscal year 2008 Defense appropriations bill at my request:</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
