<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1212595202" ordinal="16" title="CONSUMER-FIRST ENERGY ACT OF 2008--MOTION TO PROCEED">
  <narrative>CONSUMER-FIRST ENERGY ACT OF 2008--MOTION TO PROCEED -- (Senate - June 04, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="5020">S5020</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to Calendar No. 743, <bill type="s" number="3044">S. 3044</bill>, the Consumer-First Energy Act of 2008, at a time to be determined by the majority leader, following consultation with the Republican leader.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300072" topic="">
    <paragraph>I object.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, in light of that objection, I now move to proceed to Calendar No. 743, <bill type="s" number="3044">S. 3044</bill>, and send a cloture motion to the desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The cloture motion having been presented under rule XXII, the Chair directs the clerk to read the motion.</chair>
  <chair>The assistant legislative clerk read as follows:</chair>
  <chair>Cloture Motion</chair>
  <chair>We, the undersigned Senators, in accordance with the provisions of rule XXII of the Standing Rules of the Senate, hereby move to bring to a close debate on the motion to proceed to <bill type="s" number="3044">S. 3044</bill>, the Consumer-First Energy Act of 2008.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the cloture vote occur on Tuesday, June 10, at 12 noon with 20 minutes immediately prior to the vote equally divided and controlled by the two leaders or their designees, with the majority leader controlling the final 10 minutes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300072" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>I object.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <chair>The legislative clerk proceeded to call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be dispensed with.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>I now ask that the cloture motion be withdrawn.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered. The cloture motion is withdrawn.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <chair>The legislative clerk proceeded to call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be dispensed with.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I have already expressed my appreciation to the staff for all their hard work. I have been informed by the minority that we need not be around here tonight having to vote on our ability to adjourn, so Senators, if they wish, can leave now and the two of us will terminate business. I thank everybody for their patience. I am sorry they had to come back tonight.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
