<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1196701202" ordinal="46" title="REMOVAL OF INJUNCTION OF SECRECY--TREATY DOCUMENT NO. 110-10">
  <narrative>REMOVAL OF INJUNCTION OF SECRECY--TREATY DOCUMENT NO. 110-10 -- (Senate - December 03, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="14706">S14706</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400619" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, as in executive session, I ask unanimous consent that the injunction of secrecy be removed from the following treaty transmitted to the Senate on December 3, 2007, by the President of the United States:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Treaty with Australia Concerning Defense Trade Cooperation (Treaty Document 110-10).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I further ask that the treaty be considered as having been read the first time; that it be referred with accompanying papers to the Committee on Foreign Relations and ordered to be printed; and that the President's message be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The message of the President is as follows:</chair>
  <chair>I transmit herewith for Senate advice and consent to ratification the Treaty Between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of Australia Concerning Defense Trade Cooperation, done at Sydney, September 5, 2007. I transmit also, for the information of the Senate, the report of the Department of State that includes an overview of this Treaty.</chair>
  <chair>My Administration is prepared to provide to the Senate for its information other relevant documents, including proposed implementing arrangements to be concluded pursuant to the Treaty, relevant correspondence with the Government of Australia, and proposed amendments to the International Traffic in Arms Regulations.</chair>
  <chair>This Treaty will allow for greater cooperation between the United States and Australia, enhancing the operational capabilities and interoperability of the armed forces of both countries. I recommend that the Senate give early and favorable consideration to this Treaty.</chair>
  <chair>George W. Bush.</chair>
  <chair> The White House, December 3, 2007.</chair>
</record>
