<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1205251202" ordinal="26" title="ADDITIONAL STATEMENTS">
  <narrative>ADDITIONAL STATEMENTS -- (Senate - March 11, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="1872">S1872</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="HONORING JERRY BUTKIEWICZ">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today I wish to honor Jerry Butkiewicz, a labor leader in San Diego who recently retired as secretary-treasurer of the San Diego Imperial Counties Labor Council. He has devoted the past 30 years to improving the quality of life for all people.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1975, Jerry Butkiewicz joined the American Postal Workers Union, APWU, in Phoenix, AZ. He became shop steward and within a few years rose to president of the local. Five years later, attracted by the beautiful weather in California, Jerry Butkiewicz and his family moved to Oceanside in San Diego where he continued to work for the U.S. Postal Service. Shortly after his arrival, he was elected president of the APWU in Oceanside. In 1981, the San Diego Imperial Counties Labor Council selected  him as their liaison between organized labor and the United Way of San Diego County.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Elected secretary-treasurer in 1996, Jerry Butkiewicz led the Labor Council with compassion, practicality, and a tireless work ethic until January 2008. Over his 12 years as secretary-treasurer, he worked to grow and strengthen the labor movement in San Diego. Through his efforts, the Labor Council has improved the lives of countless San Diegans. Jerry was active in the San Diego Greater Chamber of Commerce, the United Way of San Diego, the San Diego Workforce Partnership, the Environmental Health  Coalition, and the State Workforce Investment Board.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Jerry Butkiewicz has worked tirelessly to provide all Californians with a fair wage, affordable health care, and a safe working environment. His service to the working families of San Diego has been an invaluable contribution to all who live in San Diego and California.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I congratulate Jerry Butkiewicz on his retirement, and wish him continued success in his future endeavors.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
