<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1177603218" ordinal="63" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="COMMITTEE ON ARMED SERVICES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, April 26, 2007, at 9:30 a.m., in open session to receive testimony on legal issues regarding individuals detained by the Department of Defense as unlawful enemy combatants.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Thursday, April 26, 2007, at 10 a.m. in Room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building. The purpose of this hearing is to discuss clean coal technology.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="COMMITTEE ON FINANCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Finance be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Finance which will meet on Thursday, April 26, 2007, at 1 p.m., in 215 Dirksen Senate Office Building, to hear testimony on "Coal: A Clean Future".</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="COMMITTEE ON INDIAN AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Indian Affairs be authorized to meet on Thursday, April 26, 2007, at 10 a.m. in Room 485 of the Russell Senate Office Building to conduct a hearing on <bill type="s" number="462">S. 462</bill>, Shoshone-Paiute Tribes of Duck Valley Water Rights Settlement Act.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="SELECT COMMITTEE ON INTELLIGENCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Select Committee on Intelligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on April 26, 2007 at 2:30 p.m. to hold a closed business meeting.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON AIRLAND">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on Airland be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, April 26, 2007, at 3 p.m., in open session to receive testimony on Air Force  and Navy Aviation in review of the defense authorization request for fiscal year 2008 and the future years defense program.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON EMPLOYMENT AND WORKPLACE SAFETY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on Employment and Workplace Safety, be authorized to hold a hearing on OSHA during the session of the Senate on Thursday, April 26, 2007 at 10 a.m. in SD-628.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON NATIONAL PARKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on National Parks be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Thursday, April 26th, 2007 at 2:30 p.m. in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the hearing is to receive testimony on the following bills: <bill type="s" number="169">S. 169</bill>, to amend the National Trails System Act to clarify Federal authority relating to land acquisition from willing sellers for the majority of the trails in the System; <bill type="s" number="312">S. 312</bill>/H.R. 497, to authorize the Marion Park Project and Committee of the Palmetto Conservation Foundation to establish a commemorative work on Federal land in the District of Columbia and its environs to honor Brigadier General Francis Marion; S.  580, to amend the National Trails System Act to require the Secretary of the Interior to update the feasibility and suitability studies of four national historic trails; <bill type="s" number="686">S. 686</bill>, to amend the National Trails System Act to designate the Washington-Rochambeau Revolutionary Route National Historic Trail; <bill type="s" number="722">S. 722</bill>, to direct the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture to jointly conduct a study of certain land adjacent to the Walnut Canyon National Monument in the State of Arizona; S.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
