<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1170349202" ordinal="61" title="EXTENSION OF CERTAIN AUTHORITIES OF THE SMALL BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION">
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Small Business  and Entrepreneurship Committee be discharged from further consideration of <bill type="h" number="434">H.R. 434</bill> and the Senate then proceed to its consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered. The clerk will report the bill by title.</chair>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the bill.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I understand there is an amendment at the desk. I ask unanimous consent that the amendment be considered agreed to; the bill, as amended, be read three times, passed; the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table; the title amendment be agreed to; and any statements relating to the bill be printed in the Record, without intervening action or debate.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300072" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, reserving the right to object.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Republican leader.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300072" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, it is my understanding that the authorization of these small business programs expires tomorrow. The bill before us, <bill type="h" number="434">H.R. 434</bill>, was received in the Senate on January 18. I don't understand why the committee has waited until the day before the program expires to act. If we amend this bill and send it back to the House, they will not be able to act before these programs expire.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is my understanding that if we allow this authorization to lapse, it will result in the dissolution of the SBA's Advisory Committee on Veterans Business Affairs. This committee serves veteran entrepreneurs by formulating, executing, and promoting policies that assist veterans seeking to start and develop small businesses. I cannot imagine why we would want to dissolve the committee designed to assist veterans who want to start their own small businesses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Accordingly, I ask the Senator to modify the unanimous consent request to omit the Senate amendment and instead pass a bill clean so that it may go directly to the President for his signature.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, in responding to my friend, Senators Kerry and Snowe, who are the chairman and ranking member of the Committee on Small Business, have indicated there are a lot of matters relating to small business jurisdiction that need to be completed forthwith. They are going to work on this next week and hope to have something done very quickly, but this gives them an opportunity to deal with the House, which, I am told, basically did not confer with them at all  during the work they did over there, and they should have done that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I say again, Senators Kerry and Snowe understand the importance of this issue. They also know there are many other things depending on their raising this as an issue at this time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300072" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, if I may, I have been informed by Senator Snowe, with all due respect to the majority leader, that is not her view. It may well be the view of Senator Kerry, but it is not the view of Senator Snowe.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, we are checking at this time with Senator Kerry to see if we can work something out on this small business matter. In the meantime, we will move to another important issue that is before the Senate.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
