<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1175140800" ordinal="53" title="SENATE RESOLUTION 138--HONORING THE ACCOMPLISHMENTS AND LEGACY OF C&#xC9;SAR ESTRADA CH&#xC1;VEZ">
  <speaking speaker="400272" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, this week, our Nation comes together to honor one of our Nation's foremost civil rights and labor leader, C&#xE9;sar Estrada Ch&#xE1;vez. I rise today, along with my colleague Senator KEN SALAZAR, to submit a resolution honoring the accomplishments and legacy of C&#xE9;sar Ch&#xE1;vez.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>C&#xE9;sar Estrada Ch&#xE1;vez was born 80 years ago, on March 31, 1927, in Arizona to poor migrant farm workers. He and his family struggled to survive at a time when "Whites only" signs were still on display and when it was necessary to trade in his school books to support his family working full-time in the fields.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>"But rather than just survive those times, C&#xE9;sar Ch&#xE1;vez turned his experiences into ammunition to help fight for a better life for all Americans, becoming one of our Nation's most inspirational leaders.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Following the principles of Mahatma Gandhi and Martin Luther King Jr., in 1962 C&#xE9;sar Ch&#xE1;vez co-founded the first successful farm workers union in the United States--the United Farm Workers (UFW). Through the UFW, Ch&#xE1;vez brought many farm workers together, including Mexican- and Filipino-Americans, to fight for common goals. He also inspired hope in these workers through his great rallying catchphrase, "S&#xED; Se Puede."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In one of their major victories, after 5 years of boycotting table grapes, the United Farm Workers gained the first-ever collective bargaining agreement between farm workers and growers in the history of our country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As the son of poor, working-class parents who were not afforded the benefits of a union, I am moved by C&#xE9;sar Ch&#xE1;vez's selfless work on behalf of others. Remembering his legacy reinforces my belief that all hard-working individuals deserve the right to bargain collectively to achieve better wages, better health benefits and suitable working conditions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am happy that New Jersey has a proud labor tradition, which would not have been possible without people committed to fairness, social justice and equality. The legacy of C&#xE9;sar Ch&#xE1;vez still resonates today, from the rural agricultural fields to the urban centers all across this Nation, and his achievements are an inspiration to all hard-working Americans who want to achieve a better quality of life.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator Robert F. Kennedy rightly said that C&#xE9;sar Ch&#xE1;vez was "one of the heroic figures of our time," and I believe our resolution reinforces that statement. Therefore, I urge my colleagues to support this resolution, and by doing so, acknowledge that C&#xE9;sar Ch&#xE1;vez is truly an American hero.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
