<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1181145609" ordinal="43" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="COMMITTEE ON BANKING, HOUSING, AND URBAN AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on June 6, 2007, at     10 a.m., to conduct a hearing   entitled "Paying for College: The Role of Private Student Lending."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENVIRONMENT AND PUBLIC WORKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Environment and Public Works be authorized to meet in order to conduct a business meeting during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, June 6, 2007 at 10 a.m. in Room 406 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The business meeting will consider the following agenda:</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="506">S. 506</bill>, the High Performance Green Buildings Act of 2007;</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="1195">H.R. 1195</bill>, SAFETEA-LU Technical Corrections Act;</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="798">H.R. 798</bill>, a bill to direct the Administrator of General Services to install a photovoltaic system for the headquarters building of the Department of Energy;</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="635">S. 635</bill>, the Methamphetamine Remediation Research Act of 2007;</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="1523">S. 1523</bill>, the Capitol power plant carbon dioxide emissions reduction demonstration project bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="COMMITTEE ON FINANCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Finance be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, June 6, 2007, at 10 a.m., in 215 Dirksen Senate Office Building, to hear testimony on "Trade and Globalization: Adjustment for a 21st Century Workforce."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that Senate Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet to conduct a hearing entitled "Patent Reform: The Future of American Innovation" on Wednesday, June 6, 2007 at 10 a.m. in Dirksen Senate Office Building Room 226.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Panel I: The Honorable Jon W. Dudas, Undersecretary of Commerce for Intellectual Property Director of the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office, Department of Commerce, Alexandria, VA;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Panel II: Mr. Bruce G. Bernstein, Chief Intellectual Property and Licensing Officer, InterDigital Communications Corporation, King of Prussia, PA; Ms. Mary Doyle, Senior Vice President, General Counsel and Secretary, Palm, Inc., Sunnyvale, CA; Mr. John A. Squires, Chief Intellectual Property Counsel, Goldman, Sachs &amp; Co., New York, NY; Ms. Kathryn L. Biberstein, Senior Vice President, General Counsel and Secretary, and Chief Compliance Officer, Alkermes, Inc., Cambridge, MA.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON WATER AND POWER">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on Water and Power of the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, June 6, 2007 at 2:30 p.m. in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building. The purpose of the hearing is to receive testimony on the impacts of climate change on water supply and availability in the United States, and related issues from a water use perspective.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
