<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1204650002" ordinal="37" title="HONORING THE LIFE OF MYRON COPE">
  <narrative>HONORING THE LIFE OF MYRON COPE -- (Senate - March 04, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="1545">S1545</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300080" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Judiciary Committee be discharged from further consideration of <bill type="sr" number="467">S. Res. 467</bill> and the Senate proceed to its immediate consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered. The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <chair>The assistant legislative clerk read as follows:</chair>
  <chair>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="467">S. Res. 467</bill>) honoring the life of Myron Cope.</chair>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300080" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed, the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table, with no intervening action or debate, and that any statements relating to the resolution be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="467">S. Res. 467</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="467">S. Res. 467</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas Myron Cope was a legendary Pittsburgher and voice of the Pittsburgh Steelers for an unprecedented 35 seasons from 1970 to 2005;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Myron Cope died the morning of February 27th, 2008, at the age of 79;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas it is the intent of the Senate to recognize and pay tribute to the life of Myron Cope, his service to his community, and his legacy with the Pittsburgh Steelers, the game of football, and the city of Pittsburgh;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Myron Cope is best known for his quirky catch phrases and for creating the "terrible towel", which is twirled at Steelers games as a good luck charm and has since developed into an international symbol of Pittsburgh Steelers pride;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Myron Cope coined the phrase "Immaculate Reception", which became a household term to describe the game-winning play in the Steelers' 1972 American Football Conference Divisional playoff victory against the Oakland Raiders, one of the most notable plays in all of National Football League and sports history;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Myron Cope spent the first half of his professional career as one of the Nation's most widely read freelance sports writers, writing for Sports Illustrated and the Saturday Evening Post;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Myron Cope became the first professional football broadcaster to be elected to the National Radio Hall of Fame in 2005;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Myron Cope became so popular that the Steelers did not try to replace him when he retired in 2005, instead downsizing from a 3-man announcing team to 2;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Myron Cope served his community on the board of directors of the Pittsburgh Chapter of the Autism Society of America and the highly successful Pittsburgh Vintage Grand Prix charity auto races, of which he was a co-founder;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Myron Cope also served on the Tournament Committee of the Myron Cope/Foge Fazio Golf Tournament for Autistic Children;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, in 1996, Myron Cope contributed his ownership of "The Terrible Towel" trademarks to Allegheny Valley School, an institution for the profoundly mentally and physically disabled;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Myron Cope was born in Pittsburgh on January 23, 1929, and lived all but a few months of his life in Pittsburgh; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the passing of Myron Cope is a great loss to the city of Pittsburgh and the game of football, and his life should be honored with highest praise and respect for his heart of black and gold: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) recognizes Myron Cope as a familiar voice to every Pittsburgher and football fan alike, and his beloved persona which will live on in the hearts of Pittsburghers and Steelers fans for generations to come; and</chair>
  <chair> (2) recognizes the outstanding contributions of Myron Cope to the city of Pittsburgh, the game of football, and the Pittsburgh Steelers.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
