<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1194282001" ordinal="31" title="LYTTON RANCHERIA TRIBAL LANDS HELD IN TRUST">
  <narrative>LYTTON RANCHERIA TRIBAL LANDS HELD IN TRUST -- (Senate - November 05, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="13937">S13937</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412247" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of calendar No. 452, <bill type="s" number="1347">S. 1347</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the bill by title.</chair>
  <chair>The bill clerk read as follows:</chair>
  <chair>A bill (<bill type="s" number="1347">S. 1347</bill>) to amend the Omnibus Indian Advancement Act to modify the date as of which certain tribal land of the Lytton Rancheria of California is deemed to be held in trust and to provide for the conduct of certain activities on the land.</chair>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the bill.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412247" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the bill be read the third time and passed, the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table, and that any statements be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The bill (<bill type="s" number="1347">S. 1347</bill>) was ordered to be engrossed for a third reading, read the third time, and passed, as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="s" number="1347">S. 1347</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. LYTTON RANCHERIA OF CALIFORNIA.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Section 819 of the Omnibus Indian Advancement Act (Public Law 106-568; 114 Stat. 2919) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in the first sentence, by striking "Notwithstanding" and inserting the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(a) Acceptance of Land.--Notwithstanding";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) in the second sentence, by striking "The Secretary" and inserting the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(b) Declaration.--The Secretary"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) by striking the third sentence and inserting the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(c) Treatment of Land for Purposes of Class II Gaming.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(1) IN GENERAL.--Subject to paragraph (2), notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Lytton Rancheria of California may conduct activities for class II gaming (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act (25 U.S.C. 2703)) on the land taken into trust under this section.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(2) REQUIREMENT.--The Lytton Rancheria of California shall not expand the exterior physical measurements of any facility on the Lytton Rancheria in use for class II gaming activities on the date of enactment of this paragraph.</chair>
  <chair> "(d) Treatment of Land for Purposes of Class III Gaming.--Notwithstanding subsection (a), for purposes of class III gaming (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act (25 U.S.C. 2703)), the land taken into trust under this section shall be treated, for purposes of section 20 of the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act (25 U.S.C. 2719), as if the land was acquired on October 9, 2003, the date on which the Secretary took the land into trust.".&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
