<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1179158403" ordinal="25" title="SENATE RESOLUTION 197--HONORING THE ACCOMPLISHMENTS OF AMERICORPS">
  <speaking speaker="300073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise to introduce the AmeriCorps Week Resolution, which designates May 13-20, 2007, as a time to salute AmeriCorps members for their work, thank community partners who make the program possible, and encourage more people to join. I want to first say thank you to all the volunteers and service workers everywhere. They take time out of their lives to help their fellow Americans in their time of need, and they do it out of the goodness of their hearts. I love AmeriCorps.  I love what they do for communities, I love what they do for America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>AmeriCorps is stronger than ever. Since its creation in 1994, 500,000 people nationwide have joined the program and taken the AmeriCorps pledge to "get things done for America." AmeriCorps members have served more than 630 million hours nationwide. To date, 9,310 Maryland residents have earned education awards totaling over $30 million. These awards help volunteers pay for college, graduate school, vocational training, or to pay back student loans. The NCCC program, which has a campus in Perry  Point, MD, is a full-time residential program for 18- to 24-year-olds designed to strengthen communities and develop leaders through team-based service projects. Each year, approximately 1,100 participants reside in its 5 campuses nationwide. The Perry Point campus houses 200 AmeriCorps members every year, and since 1994 its residents have logged more than 400,000 service hours.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>AmeriCorps is the embodiment of the spirit of volunteerism and service to our country. They tackle the toughest problems in our communities: tutoring teens, starting neighborhood crime watches, turning vacant lots into neighborhoods, and helping communities clean up and rebuild after natural disasters. AmeriCorps volunteers are unflagging, unflinching and determined to make a difference. I know how important AmeriCorps is to communities across the country and to the  young  people who want to serve. We are so grateful for all the hard work that they do.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I fought to create AmeriCorps and I will continue to fight to strengthen AmeriCorps so it can continue to help local communities meet local needs. Today's Federal investment, like these fine volunteers, are needed now more than ever.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
