<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1168448402" ordinal="39" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="COMMITTEE ON AGRICULTURE, NUTRITION, AND FORESTRY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition and Forestry be authorized to conduct a hearing during the session of the Senate on Wednesday January 10, 2007 at 9:30 a.m. in 328a, Senate Russell Office Building. The purpose of this committee hearing will be to discuss agriculture and rural America's role in enhancing national energy security.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="COMMITTEE ON ARMED SERVICES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, January 10, 2007, at 2 p.m., in closed session to receive a briefing regarding U.S. military action in Somalia.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="COMMITTEE ON FINANCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Finance be authorized to meet during the session on Finance will meet on Wednesday, January 10, 2007, at 10 a.m., in 215 Dirksen Senate Office Building, to hear testimony on "Tax Incentives for Businesses in Response to a Minimum Wage Increase".</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, January 10, 2007, at 9:30 a.m. to hold a hearing on Iraq.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="COMMITTEE ON HEALTH, EDUCATION, LABOR, AND PENSIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, January 10, 2007 at 10 a.m. in SD-430.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet to conduct a hearing on "Balancing Privacy and Security: The Privacy Implications of Government Data Mining Programs" on Wednesday, January 10, 2007 at 9:30 a.m. in Dirksen Senate Office Building Room 226.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Witness List: The Honorable Robert Barr, Chief Executive Officer, Liberty Strategies, LLC, Atlanta, GA; James Jay Carafano, Ph.D., Heritage Foundation, Assistant Director, Kathryn and Shelby Cullom Davis Institute for International Studies, Senior Research Fellow, Douglas and Sarah Allison Center for Foreign Policy Studies, Washington, DC; Mr. Jim Harper, Director of Information Policy Studies, CATO Institute, Washington, DC; Ms. Leslie Harris, Executive Director, Center for  &lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page:  <bill type="s" number="401">S401</bill>]&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/center&gt;</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="SELECT COMMITTEE ON INTELLIGENCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Select Committee on Intelligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on January 10, 2007 at 2:30 p.m. to hold a business meeting.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
