<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1197997209" ordinal="62" title="TRIBUTE TO DR. DOUGLAS C. PATTERSON">
  <narrative>TRIBUTE TO DR. DOUGLAS C. PATTERSON -- (Senate - December 18, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="15905">S15905</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300088" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today I commend a distinguished resident of the State of Alabama, Dr. Douglas C. Patterson on the occasion of his retirement from Troy University. Upon receiving his bachelor's degree from Alabama College in 1967, Patterson was commissioned a lieutenant in the U.S. Marine Corps and served as a platoon commander for a Combat Engineer Platoon and as an intelligence officer for the First Engineer Battalion of the First Marine Division in the Republic of Vietnam.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Upon returning from Vietnam, Patterson received his masters from the University of Montevallo and his doctorate from the University of Alabama. Dr. Patterson's experience includes serving as a high school counselor, director of Counseling and Career Services at Jefferson State Junior College, vice president for instruction at the Alabama Institute for the Deaf and Blind and currently, he serves as the senior vice chancellor for administration for Troy University.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dr. Patterson has served Troy University with great honor and distinction as a senior administrator since 1989 and has provided exemplary service to the university and to the citizens of the State of Alabama. During his tenure as senior vice chancellor for administration, Dr. Patterson directed  the institution's finance and budgeting, information technology, institutional effectiveness, television and radio, strategic planning, athletics, and day-to-day  operations. Under his leadership, the University has enjoyed an unprecedented era of growth, doubling worldwide student enrollment to almost 30,000 students. Dr. Patterson has been instrumental in Troy University's glowing record of stewardship and financial stability, garnering praise and awards from the National Association of College and University Business Officers and earning TROY recognition as a "Best Value"</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I commend Dr. Douglas C. Patterson, on the occasion of his retirement from Troy University, for his leadership in Alabama higher education and for his outstanding service to Alabama and our country.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
