<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1204650002" ordinal="38" title="NATIONAL GLANZMANN'S THROMBASTHENIA AWARENESS DAY">
  <narrative>NATIONAL GLANZMANN'S THROMBASTHENIA AWARENESS DAY -- (Senate - March 04, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="1546">S1546</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300080" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate now proceed to the consideration of <bill type="sr" number="471">S. Res. 471</bill>, which was submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <chair>The assistant legislative clerk read as follows:</chair>
  <chair>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="471">S. Res. 471</bill>) designating March 1, 2008, as "National Glanzmann's Thrombasthenia Awareness Day".</chair>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300080" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="471">S. Res. 471</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="471">S. Res. 471</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas Glanzmann's Thrombasthenia affects men, women, and children of all ages;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Glanzmann's Thrombasthenia is a very distressing disorder to those who have it, causing great discomfort and severe emotional stress;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas children with Glanzmann's Thrombasthenia are unable to participate in many normal childhood activities including most sports and are often subject to social discomfort because of their disorder;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Glanzmann's Thrombasthenia includes a wide range of symptoms including life-threatening, uncontrollable bleeding and severe bruising;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Glanzmann's Thrombasthenia is frequently misdiagnosed or undiagnosed by medical professionals;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas currently there is no cure for Glanzmann's Thrombasthenia;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas it is essential to educate the public on the symptoms, treatments, and constant efforts to cure Glanzmann's Thrombasthenia to ensure early diagnosis and treatment of the condition;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Helen P. Smith established the Glanzmann's Thrombasthenia Research Foundation in Augusta, Georgia, in 2001; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Helen P. Smith and the Glanzmann's Thrombasthenia Research Foundation have worked tirelessly to promote awareness of Glanzmann's Thrombasthenia and help fund research on the disorder: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) designates March 1, 2008, as "National Glanzmann's Thrombasthenia Awareness Day";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) urges all people of the United States to become more informed and aware of Glanzmann's Thrombasthenia; and</chair>
  <chair> (3) respectfully requests the Secretary of the Senate to transmit a copy of this resolution to the Glanzmann's Thrombasthenia Research Foundation.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
