<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1184299200" ordinal="27" title="STATEMENTS ON INTRODUCED BILLS AND JOINT RESOLUTIONS">
  <narrative>STATEMENTS ON INTRODUCED BILLS AND JOINT RESOLUTIONS -- (Senate - July 13, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="9212">S9212</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300022" topic="Introducing S. 1787. A bill to conduct 1 or more higher education and career readiness demonstration projects for rural, low-income students; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1787">S. 1787</bill>] Mr. President, all students, regardless of where they live, need appropriate tools to compete in today's global economy. Today, I am pleased to introduce legislation that will ensure students in rural areas are equipped with the resources they need. If approved, the Rural Students College, Career, and Community Readiness Act of 2007 would improve the educational and career outcomes and build the leadership skills of students in rural communities. I am pleased to be working my colleague,  Senator Specter, on this important and timely legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Roughly one in four public schools is located in rural America, accounting for 14.5 percent of total public school enrollment. Unfortunately, studies have shown students attending these rural schools generally have lower educational aspirations than their urban and suburban peers. In addition, roughly half of rural high school students live and attend schools in counties that do not have colleges.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These facts are daunting and present a major hurdle in improving education for students in rural communities. However, if our country is to successfully compete for jobs in the marketplace of the 21st century, we must ensure all students have access to an excellent education. These are some of the many reasons why Senator Specter and I have joined together to introduce the Rural Students College, Career, and Community Readiness Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation will establish partnerships between nonprofit entities and rural school districts to improve the academic motivation and educational performance of rural, low-income students. Under these partnerships, students in grades 7-12 will receive 25 hours of program workshops during the school year to develop career awareness and build their leadership skills. Furthermore, these programs will provide information for students about the opportunities for and the importance of higher education  while increasing understanding of the future labor needs in their State.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation also calls for a rigorous evaluation of the program's impact. The results of this evaluation will not only tell us the rates of participation in dual enrollment courses, advanced placement courses, or other related programs of our rural students, but also provide models of best practices for partnerships so others can replicate their success.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Rural Students College, Career, and Community Readiness Act emphasizes the improvement of human capital through education as an important engine for economic development for rural communities. This legislation is needed to increase the number of rural students engaged in rigorous, college-preparatory coursework, improve their high school graduation rates, and prepare the next generation of leaders in rural communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am hopeful my Senate colleagues will join us to move this legislation to the floor without delay.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300083" topic="Introducing S. 1788. A bill to provide for the mandatory revocation of passports of individuals whose child support payments are more than $2,500 in arrears; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1788">S. 1788</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to offer legislation to ensure that noncustodial parents pay child support, instead of fleeing off to hide from their responsibilities. I commend my fellow Kansas colleagues, Congressman Dennis Moore and Congressman Jerry Moran, for introducing similar legislation in the House.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The problem is this: noncustodial parents could potentially avoid paying their responsible share of child support by leaving the country. State child support enforcement agencies must certify cases to the State Department for passport denial if the child support debt is over $2,500. The loophole that emerges is for those deadbeat parents who already have a passport. Under current implementation of the law, the next opportunity for enforcement is at the renewal of the passport, which could be  several years down the road. The legislation I offer today closes that loophole, and simply instructs the State Department to revoke, in addition to denying, a noncustodial parent's passport once the individual's child support debt exceeds $2,500. Studies show that the receipt of child support is a key factor that keeps a child and single parent family from living in or near poverty. Beyond the financial security that steady</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In Kansas alone, there are currently 131,000 child support cases open, including those receiving public assistance, and those above that income bracket. Last year, the Kansas Child Support Enforcement Program collected $156 million in child support.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, you might ask: What percentage of the population will this help? I would concede that, although this may not impact a high percentage of those children and families receiving child support, the impact on an individual family is very significant. According to my state's limited records on this issue, approximately 50 passport applications and renewals are denied on a yearly basis. That figure does not include those passports that should be revoked. The Kansas Child Support Enforcement Program  estimates that the number of deadbeat parents affected would increase to 250. The security afforded by the steady stream of child support could be the lone determinant of a family living in poverty or existing on adequate financial ground.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I encourage my colleagues to add their support to this important fix. We must ensure that the tools provided to the states have the teeth necessary to discourage deadbeat parents from running out on their financial responsibilities.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
