<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1201539602" ordinal="26" title="CURRENT ELECTORAL CRISIS IN KENYA">
  <narrative>CURRENT ELECTORAL CRISIS IN KENYA -- (Senate - January 28, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="389">S389</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300042" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, just over 1 month ago, in the days before the December 27 president election, I  noted that it had become the closest political contest in that country's history and that the two leading candidates were running robust, active campaigns. Although I also acknowledged the persistence of a deeply entrenched culture of corruption, I was encouraged by the growing engagement of Kenyan citizens and civil society organizations during  the relatively peaceful, well-run, and competitive campaign season. I joined many others in hoping that the presidential and parliamentary elections held on that day would confirm Kenya's place among the world's most promising emerging economies and young democracies. Instead, that hope turned to dismay as we watched a blatant disregard for democratic principles and</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With Somalia, Ethiopia, Sudan, and Uganda as neighbors in the volatile Horn of Africa, Kenya has long been regarded as a stable country making slow but persistent progress towards democracy. Kenya's press and courts seemed to be asserting their independence from the president-dominated government, and the mere fact that all pre-election opinion polls put the incumbent president neck-and-neck with his challenger from the main opposition party seemed to be an encouraging sign of a vibrant democracy.  But on December 27 and in the days that followed, this progress came to a grinding halt. The Kenyan election suffered a fate all too common in Africa, with the votes tallied behind closed doors and the results finally announced by Kenya's Electoral Commission suggesting significant rigging.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The resulting frustration and deadlock have sparked violence, looting, destruction of property, and disruption of normal activity, creating an economic and humanitarian emergency on top of the current political crisis. Hundreds have been killed--some of them because of disproportionate use of force by Kenyan police as they seek to quell protests</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The rival political leaders--incumbent President Mwai Kibaki and leader of the Orange Democratic Movement opposition party, Raila Odinga</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is early days yet, and it remains unclear how committed these leading candidates are to seeing the negotiation through to the finish line. Although he has agreed to participate in an internationally brokered meeting with Mr. Odinga, Mr. Kibaki has been less than cooperative by rushing to appoint his own cronies to top cabinet positions and declaring he will follow the recommendations only of the Kenyan courts, which are also packed with his supporters. A political settlement is a key element  in working through this electoral crisis but it must be part of a greater initiative that includes institutional reform. The road ahead is long, and I remain concerned that while both leading candidates have come to the table for negotiations, they could still decide to abandon the effort.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The past few weeks have shown how superficial Kenya's democratic gains may really have been. Now the international community</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Resolving Kenya's current political, humanitarian, and economic crisis will require a coordinated international effort to engage all players in identifying and addressing the deeper problems that allowed the election fraud to occur and to ignite such a wave of outrage. Although a power-sharing agreement will likely be part of the solution, serious underlying problems need to be addressed. The challenges facing Kenya include an over-concentration of power in the office of the president, insufficient  independence of the judiciary and electoral institutions, the need for professionalization of police and armed forces, and a persistent lack of transparency and inclusiveness throughout the political system. Only by addressing these root causes of the recent conflict will Kenya</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last week, along with my ranking member on the Senate Subcommittee on African Affairs, Senator Sununu, and Senators Cardin and Kerry, I introduced a resolution to encourage the United States and the wider international community to resist the temptation for a quick fix in Kenya and to instead pursue a more intensive, encompassing plan for political transition and transformation. I hope the Senate will pass this resolution shortly. The administration has played an active  role</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The U.S.-Kenya partnership is a longstanding and important one, but I can-not condone a continued relationship with a government that has apparently stolen an election and uses tactics of fear and intimidation to address dissent. This is not the Kenya I have come to know, and I am sure, not the Kenya its citizens want to know. We must close this devastating chapter by addressing the reasons for the electoral crisis and ensuing violence. Without such vital work, our historic partnership will deteriorate.  There is a window of opportunity to ensure this does not happen, and I encourage all key actors to seize upon this opening. Above all, I want to see violence end and hope restored in Kenya.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
