<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1179763212" ordinal="18" title="VOTE EXPLANATION">
  <speaking speaker="300013" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I regret that I was unable to vote the afternoon of May 9 on the confirmation of the nomination of Debra Ann Livingston, of New York, to be U.S. circuit judge for the Second Circuit of New York. I wish to address this confirmation so that the people of the great State of Kansas, who elected me to serve them as U.S. Senator, may know my position.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Regarding vote No. 158, I support the confirmation of Debra Ann Livingston. My vote would not have altered the outcome of this confirmation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I regret that on May 2, 3, 7, and 9 I was unable to vote on certain provisions and passage of <bill type="s" number="1082">S. 1082</bill>, the prescription drug user fee amendments of 2007. I wish to address these votes, so that the people of the great State of Kansas, who elected me to serve them as U.S. Senator, may know my position.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Regarding vote No. 148, on amendment No. 982, I would have voted in favor of this amendment. My vote would not have altered the final result of this vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Regarding vote No. 149, on amendment No. 1022, I would have voted in favor of this amendment. My vote would not have altered the final result of this vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Regarding vote No. 150, on amendment No. 990, I would not have voted in favor of this amendment. My vote would not have altered the final result of this vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Regarding vote No. 151, on amendment No. 1010, I would have voted in favor of this amendment. My vote would not have altered the final result of this vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Regarding vote No. 152, on the motion to invoke cloture on the committee substitute as modified and amended to <bill type="s" number="1082">S. 1082</bill>, I would have voted in favor of this motion. My vote would not have altered the result of this motion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Regarding vote No. 154, on amendment No. 1039, I would not have voted in favor of this amendment. My vote would not have altered the final result of this vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Regarding vote No. 155 on amendment No. 998, I would not have voted in favor of this amendment. My vote would not have altered the final result of this vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Regarding vote No. 156 on amendment No. 1034, I would not have voted in favor of this amendment. My vote would not have altered the final result of this vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Regarding vote No. 157, on passage of <bill type="s" number="1082">S. 1082</bill>, the prescription drug user fee amendments of 2007, I would have voted in favor of passage of this bill. My vote would not have altered the final result of this vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
