<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1174406404" ordinal="17" title="NORTHEAST PENNSYLVANIA MEDICARE WAGE INDEX">
  <speaking speaker="300092" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, for a considerable period of time, there have been a number of counties in Pennsylvania that have been suffering from low Medicare reimbursements, which has caused them great disadvantage in comparison to surrounding areas. I refer specifically to Luzerne, Lackawanna, Wyoming, Lycoming, and Columbia in northeastern Pennsylvania, and there are open disadvantaged counties elsewhere in Pennsylvania. Those counties are surrounded by MSAs, metropolitan statistical areas,  with higher Medicare reimbursements in Newark, and New York, to the east; in Allentown to the southeast; and in Harrisburg to the southwest. As a result, a flight of very necessary medical personnel has occurred as northeast Pennsylvania hospitals are not able to provide employees with adequate competitive wages.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Further complicating this issue are the exceptions to the Medicare wage index regulations. Since 1987, exceptions have been created to the wage index program for rural facilities, new facilities, and others. In fact, in 1999, Congress passed legislative reclassifications for specific hospitals to allow selected facilities to move to a new MSA and receive greater Medicare reimbursement. While these reclassifications have improved funding for those hospitals, hospitals that did not receive improved  funding are being further disadvantaged.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It has also come to my attention that inpatient rehabilitation facilities are not provided an opportunity to obtain equitable Medicare reimbursement. Inpatient rehabilitation facilities receive adjustments in their Medicare reimbursement due to geographic disadvantages within the Medicare inpatient prospective payment system. This is based on information gathered from other acute care facilities in the MSA, not from their own wage information. Thus, inpatient rehabilitation facilities cannot  apply for reclassification to another MSA that reflects their actual labor costs. As such, the facilities are prevented from being eligible for increased funding to assist with wages like acute care facilities, while being forced to compete for employees with those facilities that have had access to increased funding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have worked to find a solution to the Medicare wage index disparity in reimbursement for a number of years. During the conference for the fiscal year 2002 Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education Appropriations bill, the conferees agreed that there should be relief for these areas in Pennsylvania that were surrounded by areas with higher MSA ratings. However, at the last minute, there was an objection to including language in the conference report.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To correct this problem I, along with Representatives Sherwood and ENGLISH, brought the matter forward in the fiscal year 2002 supplemental appropriations bill. The language was included in the House version of the bill, and I filed an amendment to Senate bill. During conference negotiations my amendment was defeated and the provisions were not included.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As part of the fiscal year 2004 Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education appropriations bill, $7 million was provided for hospitals in northeast Pennsylvania that continued to be disadvantaged by the Medicare area wage index reclassification. The funding was provided as temporary assistance for those facilities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>During the consideration of the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003, I met with Finance Committee chairman, CHARLES GRASSLEY, and ranking member MAX BAUCUS about the bill provisions, including the need for a solution to the Medicare area wage index reclassification problem in Pennsylvania. Thereafter, section 508 was included in the bill, which provides $300 million per year for 3 years to increase funding for hospitals nationally to be reclassified  to locations with higher Medicare reimbursement rates. The temporary program, which began in April 2004 and  was scheduled to expire March 31, 2007, has and will provide Pennsylvania hospitals $69 million over that time, or $23 million per year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On September 29, 2006, I introduced the Hospital Payment Improvement and Equity Act to extend the section 508 Medicare wage index program for 3 more years until March 31, 2010. This legislation would have also expanded the eligibility of the program to include inpatient rehabilitation facilities and facilities that qualified for the program but did not receive assistance due to inadequate funding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As part of the Tax Relief and Health Care Act, which was signed into law on December 20, 2006, an extension of the section 508 Medicare wage index program was included. This will  provide 14 Pennsylvania hospitals an additional $18.4 million for 6 more months until September 30, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On February 21, 2007, I visited Moses Taylor Hospital in Scranton, PA, and met with representatives of northeast Pennsylvania hospitals affected by this issue. I went over with them the situation that had occurred and asked that they submit memoranda or letters outlining their hospitals' extreme plight, which I could then share with my colleagues in the Senate and have printed in the CONGRESSIONAL RECORD for everyone to see.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A letter prepared by Harold Anderson, president &amp; CEO of Moses Taylor Hospital, Scranton, PA, pointed out the following:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Health care facilities in our area are especially disadvantaged in that we must compete for specialized, skilled health care labor in a geographic market that includes easy access to Philadelphia, Allentown, and Stroudsburg, three geographic areas in which the Wage Index reimbursement for acute care hospitals is higher than that found in NEPA [Northeast Pennsylvania].</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He goes on to write:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Considering the relative scarcity and high demand for a highly skilled work force, such as nurses, pharmacists, imaging technologists, etc., the out-migration to the adjacent MSAs is further exacerbated in that NEPA hospitals are forced to pay higher salary and wage rates, which are not fully compensated by the Medicare reimbursements. As just one example, the starting salary for Registered Nurses has increased by more than 18% over the past three years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Regis Cabonor, president &amp; CEO of Bloomsburg Hospital, Bloomsburg, PA, wrote on February 26 as follows:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The significant volume of services provided to Medicare beneficiaries renders the Hospital largely dependant upon Medicare reimbursement to cover the cost of direct patient care.....</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He also states:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Without the additional reimbursement provided by this [508 wage index] reclassification, our hospital would not be able to attract and retain qualified clinical staff, forcing staff and our patients to travel to the next closest facility for work and care.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Similar concerns were expressed in a memorandum from Jim May, president &amp; CEO of Mercy Health Partners, Scranton, PA, pointing out that:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The 508 reclass funding has enhanced our ability to compete with our adjacent CBSA's [Core-Based Statistical Area] for registered nurses, technicians, and other medical professionals. Over a three year span we have reduced our registered nurse vacancy rate from 12.2% to 4.5%. Significantly, we have cut our spending for contract agency nurses in half. We believe that reducing those expenses has contributed toward improved care management and quality for our patients.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mary Theresa Vautrinot, President &amp; CEO of Marian Community Hospital, Carbondale, PA, noted that Marian Community Hospital is the largest employer in the Carbondale area. The hospital serves a large Medicare population who would have difficulty accessing health care if not for the hospital, which struggles to find physicians to staff the facility. She notes that, without the 508 wage index funding, the hospital may not be financially viable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Similar concerns were noted by the Community Medical Center Healthcare System of Scranton, PA. John Nillson, interim president and CEO, stated in his letter that:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The dramatic differential in Medicare payments between our MSA and the surrounding MSA's will continue to have a negative impact.....</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Further:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>..... the nursing shortage has intensified and when combined with other skilled labor shortages, has resulted in a highly competitive environment for these skilled caregivers. As a result, it remains difficult to recruit and retain healthcare professionals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>John Wiercinski, chief administrative officer, Geisinger South Wilkes-Barre, Wilkes-Barre, PA, and Lissa Bryan-Smith, chief administrative office, Geisinger Wyoming Valley, Wilkes-Barre, PA, noted that:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Due in large part to the Section 508 legislation, nurse vacancy rates have decreased significantly at both hospitals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>James Edwards, president &amp; CEO, of the Greater Hazelton Health Alliance, which is made up by Hazelton General Hospital and Hazelton--St. Joseph Medical Center, Hazelton, PA, submitted a memorandum that similarly states:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The monies received through the Section 508 reclassification played a major part in the successful turnaround of our health care system, assuring our community that quality health care services will be available to meet their health needs.&lt;p&gt;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Wyoming Valley Health Care System, in a letter from president and CEO, Dr. William Host, points out the problems in retaining registered nurses:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Prior to [the Section 508 wage index program], the discrepancy between our reimbursement by Medicare and that of surrounding MSA's was having disastrous effects. Nurses, technologists of all sorts, nurse anesthetists and pharmacists were abandoning northeastern Pennsylvania in droves. Vacancies in these areas were running 14% to 20% and this created a serious threat to quality of care and access.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Raoul Walsh, president &amp; CEO, Tyler Memorial Hospital in Tunkhannock, PA, sent a memorandum that shared this concern:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If the Section 508 was removed or reduced, the hospital would be forced to eliminate or reduce clinical services . . .</paragraph>
    <paragraph>James Brady, president of Allied Services, of Clarks Summit, PA, an inpatient rehabilitation facility which did not qualify under the section 508 wage index program, shared that as a result of not receiving funding they have been forced to employ international nurses to fill 13 of the 30 open nursing positions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Neal Bisno, secretary treasurer, Service Employees International Union, district 1199P, which has a number of northeast Pennsylvania hospital employees as members, addressed the issue from the workforce perspective, stating:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A permanent solution is needed [to the Medicare wage index program problems] in order to maintain a stable, well-trained health care work force in area hospitals and guarantee continued access to quality health care services in Wilkes Barre/Scranton region.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Denise Cesare, president &amp; CEO, Blue Cross of Northeastern Pennsylvania, in a memorandum dated February 26, 2007, notes:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Due to their current Medicare Wage Index classification, hospitals in the northeast and north central regions receive disproportionately lower reimbursements when compared to similar hospitals that compete with them for services and staff. This reimbursement imbalance drains trained clinical staff, primarily nurses, from the local delivery systems. Our system continues to suffer and decline as medical professionals move to hospitals in neighboring locales because higher Medicare Wage Indexes  allow these regions to pay higher salaries.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On February 24, 2007, the Scranton Times-Tribune published an editorial regarding this issue in northeast Pennsylvania. The editorial posited that northeast Pennsylvania hospitals are in critical need of reform to the Medicare wage index system to end this cycle and cogently captures the issue:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Wage rates at regional hospitals are lower than those for large metropolitan areas, resulting in lower Medicare reimbursements, resulting in the inability of many hospitals to significantly increase wages, resulting in lower reimbursements ..... and on it goes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congressional action is needed to reform the Mediare wage index system and provide a fair reimbursement for hospitals. MedPAC, the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission, is scheduled to release a report in late June, 2007 that will offer recommendations on reforming the wage index system. I encourage Finance Chairman Baucus and Ranking Member Grassley to examine these recommendations and move forward with improvements to this system in an expedited fashion. Northeast Pennsylvania  hospitals are in great financial distress. They deserve fair treatment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that these memoranda, letters, and editorial be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
</record>
