<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1190908802" ordinal="52" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <narrative>AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET -- (Senate - September 27, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="12312">S12312</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="COMMITTEE ON ARMED SERVICES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on September 27, 2007, at 9:30 a.m., in open session to consider the following nominations: Admiral Gary Roughead, USN for reappointment to the grade of Admiral and to be Chief of Naval Operations; General William E. Ward, USA for reappointment to the grade of General and to be Commander, United States Africa command; General Kevin P. Chilton, USAF for  reappointment to the grade of General and to be Commander, United States Strategic Command; and Lieutenant General James N. Mattis, USMC to be General and to be Commander, United States Joint Forces Command and Supreme Allied Commander for Transformation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Thursday, September 27, 2007, at 10:30 a.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The hearing will focus on modernization and efforts to address the needs of the air traffic system and to improve the movement of aircraft and passengers. Subcommittee members will be provided the opportunity to review problems encountered by travelers during the summer 2007 travel season and to consider steps that can be taken to improve the air traffic system.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold a business meeting during the session of the Senate on Thursday, September 27, 2007, at 2:30 p.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>During the Executive Session, Committee members will markup the following agenda items: <bill type="s" number="1578">S. 1578</bill>, Ballast Water Management Act of 2007; <bill type="s" number="1889">S. 1889</bill>, Railroad Safety Enhancement Act of 2007; <bill type="s" number="1453">S. 1453</bill>, Internet Tax Freedom Act (ITFA) Extension Act of 2007; <bill type="s" number="1965">S. 1965</bill>, Protecting Children in the 21st Century Act; <bill type="sj" number="17">S.J. Res. 17</bill>, a joint resolution directing the United States to initiate international discussions and take necessary steps with other Nations to negotiate an agreement for managing migratory and  transboundary fish stocks in the Arctic Ocean; <bill type="sc" number="39">S. Con. Res. 39</bill>, a concurrent resolution supporting the goals and ideals of a world day of remembrance for road crash victims; Nominations for Promotion in the United States Coast Guard (PN 878, PN 946, PN 947, and PN 948).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND NATURAL RESOURCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Thursday, September 27, 2007, at 9:30 a.m. in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the hearing is to receive testimony on hard rock mining on Federal lands.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="COMMITTEE ON FINANCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Finance be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, September 27, 2007, at 10 a.m., in room SD-215 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building, to hear testimony on the "Border Insecurity, Take Three: Open and Unmonitored".</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, September 27, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. to hold a hearing on the Convention on the Law of the Sea.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>Mr KENNEDY. Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Indian Affairs be authorized to meet on Thursday, September 27, 2007, at 9 a.m. in room 628 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building to conduct a business meeting to consider pending business, to be followed immediately by an oversight hearing on the prevalence of violence against Indian women.</chair>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>Committee on the Judiciary</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="COMMITTEE ON INDIAN AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate in order to conduct a markup on Thursday, September 27, 2007, at 10 a.m. in the Dirksen Senate Office Building room 226.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I. Bills: <bill type="s" number="1267">S. 1267</bill>, Free Flow of Information Act of 2007, (Lugar, Dodd, Graham), <bill type="s" number="2035">S. 2035</bill>, Free Flow of Information Act of 2007, (Specter, Schumer).</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="sj" number="13">S.J. Res. 13</bill>, Joint resolution granting consent to the International Emergency Management Assistance Memorandum of Understanding, (Leahy, Snowe, Kennedy, Whitehouse), <bill type="s" number="980">S. 980</bill>, Online Pharmacy Consumer Protection Act of 2007, (Feinstein, Sessions, Biden).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>II. Resolutions: <bill type="sc" number="45">S. Con. Res. 45</bill>, commending the Ed Block Courage Award Foundation for its work in aiding children and families affected by child abuse, and designating November 2007 as National Courage Month, (Cardin, Cornyn).</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="sr" number="258">S. Res. 258</bill>, recognizing the historical and educational significance of the Atlantic Freedom Tour of the Freedom Schooner Amistad, and expressing the sense of the Senate that preserving the legacy of the Amistad story is important in promoting multicultural dialogue, education, and cooperation, (Dodd).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>III. Nominations: James Russell Dedrick to be United States Attorney for the Eastern District of Tennessee.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="COMMITTEE ON VETERANS' AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent for the Committee on Veterans' Affairs to be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, September 27, 2007, in order to conduct a hearing on the Nomination of Paul J. Hutter to be General Counsel, Department of Veterans Affairs. The committee will meet in room 562 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building, at 9:30 a.m.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON ANTITRUST, COMPETITION POLICY AND CONSUMER RIGHTS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate Committee on the Judiciary, Subcommittee on Antitrust, Competition Policy and Consumer Rights, be authorized conduct a hearing entitled "An Examination of the Google-&#xD0;DoubleClick Merger and the Online Advertising Industry: What are the Risks for Competition and Privacy?" on Thursday, September 27, 2007, at 2 p.m. in the Dirksen Senate Office Building room 226.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON FEDERAL FINANCIAL MANAGEMENT, GOVERNMENT INFORMATION, FEDERAL SERVICES AND INTERNATIONAL SECURITY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs' Subcommittee on Federal Financial Management, Government Information, Federal Services and International Security be authorized to meet on Thursday, September 27, 2007, at 3:30 p.m. in order to conduct a hearing entitled "Cost Effective Airlift in the 21st Century".</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON NATIONAL PARKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on National Parks of the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Thursday, September 27, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the hearing is to receive testimony on the following bills: <bill type="s" number="128">S. 128</bill>, to amend the Cache La Poudre River Corridor Act to designate a new management entity, make certain technical and conforming amendments, enhance private property protections, and for other purposes; <bill type="s" number="148">S. 148</bill>, to establish the Paterson Great Falls National Park in the State of New Jersey, and for other purposes; <bill type="s" number="189">S. 189</bill>, to decrease the matching funds requirement and authorize additional appropriations for Keweenaw  National Historical Park in the State of Michigan; <bill type="s" number="697">S. 697</bill>, to establish the Steel Industry National Historic Site in the State of Pennsylvania; <bill type="s" number="867">S. 867</bill>, to adjust the boundary of Lowell National Historical Park, and for other purposes; <bill type="s" number="1039">S. 1039</bill>, a bill to extend the authorization for the Coastal Heritage Trail in the State of New Jersey; <bill type="s" number="1341">S. 1341</bill>, to provide for the exchange of certain Bureau of Land Management land in Pima County, Arizona, and for other purposes; <bill type="s" number="1476">S. 1476</bill>, to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a special resources study of the Tule Lake Segregation Center in Modoc County, California, to determine the suitability and feasibility of establishing a unit of the</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
