<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1214409602" ordinal="22" title="125TH ANNIVERSARY OF NEW SALEM, NORTH DAKOTA">
  <narrative>125TH ANNIVERSARY OF NEW SALEM, NORTH DAKOTA -- (Senate - June 25, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="6153">S6153</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300026" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I am pleased to honor a community in North Dakota that is celebrating its 125th anniversary. On July 18 through 20, the residents of New Salem, ND, will celebrate their community's history and founding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>New Salem began on an April day in 1882 when young John Christiansen hopped off a westbound freight train. The only sign of civilization he saw were the train tracks behind him and the belongings he brought. Soon after his arrival a Colonization Bureau out of Chicago sent settlers to the area and gave the colony its independence for $600. A church, land office, lumber yard, drugstore, and general store were soon built, and by the end of 1883, the town was ready for great plains living.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Known nationally as the home of the world's largest Holstein cow, New Salem is a community filled with pride and energy. "Salem Sue" stands 38 feet high, weighs over 6 tons, and was erected by the New Salem Lions Club in 1974 to honor the dairymen of North Dakota. New Salem also has a nine-hole golf course, public swimming pool, and numerous parks to entertain residents and tourists.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To celebrate its 125th anniversary, the community of New Salem is organizing a celebration that will include a parade, demolition derby, mixed golf scramble, pitchfork fondue, and numerous outdoor activities. A street dance down New Salem's Main Street will also be held. It promises to be a wonderful event.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask the U.S. Senate to join me in congratulating New Salem, ND, and its residents on their first 125 years and in wishing them well in the future. By honoring New Salem and all the other historic small towns of North Dakota, we keep the pioneering frontier spirit alive for future generations. It is places such as New Salem that have helped to shape this country into what it is today, which is why this fine community is deserving of our recognition.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>New Salem has a proud past and a bright future.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
