<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1228755603" ordinal="47" title="PERMITTING THE COLLECTION OF CLOTHING, TOYS, FOOD, AND HOUSEWARES">
  <narrative>PERMITTING THE COLLECTION OF CLOTHING, TOYS, FOOD, AND HOUSEWARES -- (Senate - December 08, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="10819">S10819</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400064" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate now proceed to the consideration of <bill type="sr" number="723">S. Res. 723</bill>, which was submitted earlier today by Senators McConnell and Reid. </paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="723">S. Res. 723</bill>) to permit the collection of clothing, toys, food, and housewares during the holiday season for charitable purposes in Senate buildings.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400064" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to and the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="723">S. Res. 723</bill>) was agreed to, as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="723">S. Res. 723</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair> Resolved,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. COLLECTION OF CLOTHING, TOYS, FOOD, AND HOUSEWARES DURING THE HOLIDAY SEASON FOR CHARITABLE PURPOSES IN SENATE BUILDINGS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) In General.--Notwithstanding any other provision of the rules or regulations of the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) a Senator, officer, or employee of the Senate may collect from another Senator, officer, or employee of the Senate within Senate buildings nonmonetary donations of clothing, toys, food, and housewares for charitable purposes related to serving those in need or members of the Armed Services and their families during the holiday season, if such purposes do not otherwise violate any rule or regulation of the Senate or of Federal law; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) a Senator, officer, or employee of the Senate may work with a nonprofit organization with respect to the delivery of donations described in paragraph (1).</chair>
  <chair> (b) Expiration.--The authority provided by this resolution shall expire at the end of the 110th Congress.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
