<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1190736002" ordinal="69" title="SUPPORTING EFFORTS TO INCREASE CHILDHOOD CANCER AWARENESS, TREATMENT, AND RESEARCH">
  <narrative>SUPPORTING EFFORTS TO INCREASE CHILDHOOD CANCER AWARENESS, TREATMENT, AND RESEARCH -- (Senate - September 25, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="12075">S12075</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412246" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the HELP Committee be discharged from further consideration, and the Senate now proceed to <bill type="sr" number="325">S. Res. 325</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will report the resolution by title.</narrative>
  <narrative>The assistant legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="325">S. Res. 325</bill>), supporting efforts to increase childhood cancer awareness, treatment, and research.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412246" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="325">S. Res. 325</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="325">S. Res. 325</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas an estimated 12,400 children are diagnosed with cancer each year;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas cancer is the leading cause of death by disease in children under age 15;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas an estimated 2,300 children die from cancer each year;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the incidence of cancer among children in the United States is rising by about 1 percent each year;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas 1 in every 330 people in the United States develops cancer before age 20;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas approximately 8 percent of deaths of individuals between 1 and 19 years old are caused by cancer;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, while some progress has been made, a number of opportunities for childhood cancer research still remain unfunded or underfunded;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas limited resources for childhood cancer research can hinder the recruitment of investigators and physicians to the field of pediatric oncology;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the results of peer-reviewed clinical trials have helped to raise the standard of care for pediatrics and have improved cancer survival rates among children;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the number of survivors of childhood cancers continues to increase, with about 1 in 640 adults between ages 20 to 39 having a history of cancer;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas up to  2/3  of childhood cancer survivors are likely to experience at least 1 late effect from treatment, which may be life-threatening;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas some late effects of cancer treatment are identified early in follow-up and are easily resolved, while others may become chronic problems in adulthood and have serious consequences; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas 89 percent of children with terminal cancer experience substantial suffering in the last month of life: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That it is the sense of the Senate that Congress should support--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) public and private sector efforts to promote awareness about--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) the incidence of cancer among children;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) the signs and symptoms of cancer in children; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) options for the treatment of, and long-term follow-up for, childhood cancers;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) increased public and private investment in childhood cancer research to improve prevention, diagnosis, treatment, rehabilitation, post-treatment monitoring, and long-term survival;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) policies that provide incentives to encourage medical trainees and investigators to enter the field of pediatric oncology;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) policies that provide incentives to encourage the development of drugs and biologics designed to treat pediatric cancers;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) policies that encourage participation in clinical trials;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (6) medical education curricula designed to improve pain management for cancer patients;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (7) policies that enhance education, services, and other resources related to late effects from treatment; and</chair>
  <chair> (8) grassroots efforts to promote awareness and support research for cures for childhood cancer.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
