<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1222444802" ordinal="66" title="OVARIAN CANCER">
  <narrative>OVARIAN CANCER -- (Senate - September 26, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="9636">S9636</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300019" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, ovarian cancer, the fifth most fatal cancer among women in the United States, is a serious and underrecognized threat to women's health.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This year alone, there will be an estimated 21,650 new cases of ovarian cancer in the United States and it will cause more than 15,000 deaths. In Delaware, there were 322 cases of ovarian cancer between 1999 and 2003--the most recent data--and 211 deaths during that time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, there is no screening test currently available for the early detection of ovarian cancer despite the fact that it is highly treatable when detected early.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Increased public awareness of this disease, its risk factors and its subtle symptoms can save the lives of women across Delaware. Moreover, women's doctors must learn to recognize the warning signs of ovarian cancer, which are often the only early indication of illness.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Throughout this past September, the Delaware Chapter of the National Ovarian Cancer Coalition has promoted ovarian cancer awareness activities and encouraged every Delaware woman to become educated about the symptoms and risk factors of ovarian cancer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>More ovarian cancer research will help to develop reliable diagnostics, better therapies and prevention strategies, offering women in Delaware and throughout the United States an opportunity to win their battle against this tragic gynecologic cancer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is time for all women and their doctors to become more aware of the warning signs of ovarian cancer and to become better educated about early treatment options, because lives depend on it.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
