<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1185854400" ordinal="53" title="PROVIDING FOR THE REAPPOINTMENT OF PATRICIA Q. STONESIFER">
  <narrative>PROVIDING FOR THE REAPPOINTMENT OF PATRICIA Q. STONESIFER -- (Senate - July 31, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="10525">S10525</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412244" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Rules Committee be discharged from further consideration of <bill type="sj" number="8">S.J. Res. 8</bill> and that the Senate then proceed to its consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered. The clerk will report the joint resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A joint resolution (<bill type="sj" number="8">S.J. Res. 8</bill>) providing for the reappointment of Patricia Q. Stonesifer as a citizen regent of the Board of Regents of the Smithsonian Institution.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the joint resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412244" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the joint resolution be read three times, passed, and the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table; that any statements relating to the joint resolution be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The joint resolution (<bill type="sj" number="8">S.J. Res. 8</bill>) was ordered to be engrossed for a third reading, was read the third time, and passed, as follows:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>
      <bill type="sj" number="8">S.J. Res. 8</bill>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph> Resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled, That, in accordance with section 5581 of the Revised Statutes (20 U.S.C. 43), the vacancy on the Board of Regents of the Smithsonian Institution, in the class other than Members of Congress, occurring because of the expiration of the term of Patricia Q. Stonesifer of Washington, is filled by the reappointment of Patricia Q. Stonesifer, for a term of 6 years, effective December  22, 2007.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;PEACEKEEPING MISSION IN DARFUR, SUDAN</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent the Foreign Relations Committee be discharged from further consideration of <bill type="sr" number="276">S. Res. 276</bill>, and that the Senate proceed to its immediate consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered. The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="276">S. Res. 276</bill>) calling for the urgent deployment of a robust and effective multinational peacekeeping mission with sufficient size, resources, leadership and mandate to protect civilians in Darfur, Sudan, and efforts to strengthen renewal of a just and conclusive peace process.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412244" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent the amendment to the resolution be agreed to, the resolution, as amended, be agreed to, the amendment to the preamble, which is at the desk, be considered and agreed to, the preamble, as amended, be agreed to, the motions to reconsider be laid on the table en bloc, and that any statements related thereto be printed in the Record, without intervening action or debate.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The amendment (No. 2591) was agreed to, as follows:</chair>
  <chair>On page 8, line 9, strike "and".</chair>
  <chair>On page 8, between lines 9 and 10, insert the following:</chair>
  <chair>(5) urges all participants in the conflict in Darfur, including the leaders of rebel movements that were not signatories to the Darfur Peace Agreement, to participate fully in all meetings, conferences, and discussions within a political process led by the United Nations and African Union in order to return peace and security to the people of Darfur;</chair>
  <chair>(6) regards failure to participate in such meetings, conferences, and discussions, as requested by the African Union and United Nations, as an obstruction of the political process and its goals that may be worthy of international sanctions; and</chair>
  <chair>On page 8, line 10, strike "(5)" and insert "(7)".</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="276">S. Res. 276</bill>), as amended, was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The amendment to the preamble (No. 2592) was agreed to, as follows:</chair>
  <chair>Purpose: (To urge all participants in the conflict in Darfur to engage in a political process led by the United Nations and African Union, to express disapproval of failure to participate in such political process, and for other purposes)</chair>
  <chair> In the twelfth whereas clause, insert "and members of his administration" after "al-Bashir".&lt;p&gt;</chair>
  <chair> Strike the seventeenth whereas clause and insert the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the United Nations and African Union have invited leaders of the rebel movements in Darfur to participate in a political process led by the United Nations and African Union to return peace and stability to the people of Darfur;</chair>
  <chair>Whereas deliberately targeting civilians and people providing humanitarian assistance during an armed conflict is a flagrant violation of international humanitarian law, and those who commit such violations must be held accountable; and&lt;p&gt;</chair>
  <chair>The preamble, as amended, was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, as amended, with its preamble, as amended, reads as follows:</chair>
  <narrative>(The resolution will be printed in a future edition of the RECORD.)</narrative>
</record>
