<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1173974406" ordinal="22" title="NOMINATIONS OF JOHN PRESTON BAILEY AND OTIS D. WRIGHT">
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="NOMINATION OF OTIS D. WRIGHT">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, it is my pleasure to support Judge Otis Wright, a distinguished nominee to the U.S. District Court for the Central District of California.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Judge Wright is nominated to a seat that has been designated as a judicial emergency. The Central District of California, based in Los Angeles, is the largest and busiest Federal judicial district in the Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When this Congress began, there were five vacancies on this court more than twice as many as in any other judicial district in the country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am pleased that the Senate has already confirmed two new judges for the Central District this year, and I thank Chairman Leahy for moving the California judicial nominees quickly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Judge Wright is a graduate of California State University at Los Angeles and of the Southwestern School of Law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After graduating from law school, Judge Wright was a deputy attorney general in the California Department of Justice for 3 years. During that time he specialized in criminal appeals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He went on to join the law firm of Wilson, Elser, Moskowitz, Edelman &amp; Dicker, where he became a partner during a career that spanned more than 20 years. He practiced civil litigation in many areas, with a particular focus on insurance coverage litigation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While in private practice, Judge Wright was a volunteer attorney with the HIV AIDS Legal Services Alliance. His work on behalf of those with HIV and AIDS included housing and employment discrimination cases, as well as preparing wills for the terminally ill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Judge Wright's public service has not been limited to his legal career: he was a deputy sheriff in the Los Angeles County Sheriff's Department while attending college and law school, and before that he served in the U.S. Marine Corps and the Marine Corps Reserves.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He is one of only 16 African Americans who have been nominated to be federal judges in the 6 years that President Bush has been in office. During the first 6 years of the Clinton presidency, by contrast, 53 African Americans were nominated. Judge Wright will be a welcome addition to the bench.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In California we have developed a bipartisan process known as the Parsky Commission for selecting Federal district court nominees. Under this system, a committee of lawyers, including Democrats and Republicans, recommends qualified applicants to the President.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am proud of this system and pleased to say that Judge Wright was recommended by the Parsky Commission. This gives me confidence that he comes to the bench without an ideological agenda and prepared to serve all the people of California.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to vote in favor of Judge Wright's nomination.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="NOMINATION OF JOHN PRESTON BAILEY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I am pleased to speak today in support of an esteemed colleague, a fine West Virginia lawyer named Mr. John Preston Bailey. Mr. Bailey hails from the beautiful city of Wheeling, WV. John Bailey has been nominated by the President for a seat on the Federal bench in the Northern District of West Virginia.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Bailey is a splendid choice for this judgeship. He is senior partner at the firm of Bailey, Riley, Buch and Harman. Not only is Mr. Bailey well-versed in administrative law, he is also a successful litigator, competent in both civil and criminal litigation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>John Bailey graduated from West Virginia University's College of Law in 1976, where he was a member of the West Virginia Law Review. He was admitted to the State Bar of West Virginia that same year and clerked for 2 years thereafter with the Honorable Charles H. Haden II, who, at that time, was the U.S. district judge for both the Northern and Southern Districts of West Virginia.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Bailey is extremely well qualified to be confirmed as a Federal judge. He worked as an assistant prosecuting attorney in the mid-1980s, and he served as chairman of the Workers' Compensation Appeals Board in West Virginia from 1985 to 1991. He sat on the executive council of the West Virginia Bar Association for 6 years and was elected to be president of that association in 1992. He was thereafter elected and served as president of the West Virginia State Bar from 2003 to 2004. Before that,  he served as vice president of the state bar and as a member of the bar's Board of Governors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>More recently--in fact, just last year--he was also bestowed the honor of "Fellow" by the West Virginia Bar Foundation. In bestowing that honor upon Mr. Bailey, Tom Tinder, the executive director of the West Virginia Bar Foundation, stated that Mr. Bailey is a "true leader" of his community. John Preston Bailey has been a member of the Order of the Coif, the Order of the Barristers, a member of the Moot Court Board, the Ohio County Bar Association, the West Virginia Trial Lawyer Association,  and a member of the National Association of Criminal Defense Attorneys.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I can attest to the fact that Mr. Bailey comes highly recommended by West Virginians of varying legal viewpoints. He is a smart, independent thinker. He is hard working. He has had over 30 years of experience as a licensed attorney. As a result, he recognizes the solemn responsibility with which a Federal judge is charged. He must interpret--impartially,</paragraph>
    <paragraph> and with proper contemplation of, and respect for, the three, separate branches of our Government--provisions that have been approved by the Congress and signed into law the President.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Bailey has an excellent reputation and a keen intellect. Based on my understanding of Mr. Bailey's character and impressive credentials, I believe that he will make a fine Federal judge. For all of the reasons that I have mentioned, I am pleased to urge my colleagues to support his nomination to be a U.S. district court judge for the Northern District of West Virginia.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300084" topic="NOMINATION OF JOHN PRESTON BAILEY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I thank the majority leader for moving expeditiously to move the confirmation for John Preston Bailey to be a judge on the U.S. District Court for the Northern District of West Virginia. I thank Judiciary Committee Chairman LEAHY and Ranking Member SPECTER for reporting this nomination to the full Senate, and I commend Mr. Bailey to my colleagues as exactly the type of nominee we should all support for seats on the Federal bench.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>John Bailey did something somewhat unusual after he earned his degree from Dartmouth College. He came back. He defied a longstanding trend of our best and brightest young men and women leaving to seek their fortunes and not returning. He went on to earn his law degree from the School of Law at West Virginia University and then served as a law clerk for the Honorable Charles Haden II. Judge Haden was a Republican and a Ford appointee but was also a good friend to this Senator. He was a fair and  decent man widely respected for his intellect and his diligent efforts to arrive at the correct outcome. I can only hope that John Bailey chooses to emulate his former mentor, Judge Haden. Knowing what I know of John Bailey, he will, and West Virginians will benefit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Lawyers in West Virginia have a great deal of respect for John Bailey. He has served the West Virginia legal community as president of the West Virginia State Bar and the West Virginia Bar Association and was a member of the Board of Governors of the West Virginia Trial Lawyers Association. Some West Virginia lawyers and judges I have known for many decades believe John Bailey will be a very capable judge because he is a great lawyer. He takes the facts as he finds them and does not come to the  table with preconceived notions as to what the outcome should be. Those traits, along with a first-rate intellect and solid educational and work credentials, make up the formula for the kind of judicial nominee we all hope to see come to the Senate from Presidents of both parties.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield back the remainder of my time and ask for the yeas and nays on the Hardiman nomination.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there a sufficient second?</chair>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300092" topic="NOMINATION OF JOHN PRESTON BAILEY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, a very brief supplemental comment: Judge Hardiman has been on this bench since 2003. He received a unanimous "well qualified" rating from the American Bar Association.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the following information be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="NOMINATION OF JOHN PRESTON BAILEY">
    <paragraph>We yield back all of our time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300092" topic="NOMINATION OF JOHN PRESTON BAILEY">
    <paragraph>I yield back my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> All time is yielded back.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="NOMINATION OF JOHN PRESTON BAILEY">
    <paragraph>I announce that the Senator from Illinois (Mr. Durbin) and the Senator from South Dakota (Mr. Johnson) are necessarily absent.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300069" topic="NOMINATION OF JOHN PRESTON BAILEY">
    <paragraph>The following Senators were necessarily absent: the Senator from Colorado (Mr. Allard), the Senator from Mississippi (Mr. Cochran), and the Senator from Arizona (Mr. McCain).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Are there any other Senators in the chamber desiring to vote?</chair>
  <narrative>The result was announced--yeas 95, nays 0, as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> The question is, Will the Senate advise and consent to the nomination of John Preston Bailey, of West Virginia, to be United States District Judge for the Northern District of West Virginia?</chair>
</record>
