<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1175097624" ordinal="38" title="SENATE RESOLUTION 132--RECOGNIZING THE CIVIL AIR PATROL FOR 65 YEARS OF SERVICE TO THE UNITED STATES">
  <speaking speaker="300094" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, last December, the Civil Air Patrol completed its 65th year of distinguished service to our Nation. I've come to the floor today to pay tribute to the brave men and women who helped this important organization reach this milestone.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the late 1930s, Gill Robb Wilson, General Henry "Hap" Arnold, and other American aviation leaders recognized the need for a civilian group which could complement air operations undertaken by our military. Their vision led to the establishment of the Civil Air Patrol on December 1, 1941.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Less than a week later, Pearl Harbor was attacked and the United States was drawn into World War II. The newly formed Civil Air Patrol played a vital role in keeping America safe during this dark period in our history. CAP members kept watch for enemy submarines, assisted the Army Air Corps with training exercises, and helped transport military personnel and cargo. They rescued hundreds of crash survivors and helped force the Nazis to withdraw U-boat operations from our East Coast. In total,  thousands of CAP volunteers flew more than 500,000 hours and 24 million miles during the war.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The tremendous accomplishments and potential of this organization did not go unnoticed. After World War II, President Truman signed a law designating the Civil Air Patrol as a nonprofit, benevolent corporation and an "instrumentality of the United States." Two years later, Congress passed legislation establishing CAP as a volunteer auxiliary of the United States Air Force.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, the three principal missions of the Civil Air Patrol are to administer cadet training programs, provide aerospace education, and perform operations related to homeland security and emergency services. This organization has exceeded all expectations in each of these areas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Approximately 750,000 American children have learned important life and leadership lessons from CAP's cadet programs. More than 300,000 teachers--and some eight million students--have received training and instructional materials through CAP's aerospace education program. CAP volunteers have now flown more than one million hours of search and rescue operations, and thousands of lives have been saved as a result. As an Alaskan, I am particularly appreciative of these efforts--since 2004, the Civil  Air Patrol has saved at least 57 lives in our State. And, I served as a Legal Officer for the Civil Air Patrol in Fairbanks, AK, in the 1950s.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, the Civil Air Patrol is a nationwide organization of nearly 57,000 volunteers. CAP wings can be found in all 50 States, the District of Columbia, and Puerto Rico. The organization's members--all volunteers--fly approximately 120,000 hours each year as they assist with border patrol, terrorism preparedness, the War on Drugs, and natural disaster responses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Civil Air Patrol also submits an annual report to Congress. In 2005, this report was titled "Everyday Heroes . . . The Faces of the Civil Air Patrol." In part, the word "hero" is defined as "a person noted for feats of courage or nobility of purpose, especially one who has risked or sacrificed his or her life."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I can think of no title more fitting for the members of the Civil Air Patrol. The men and women of this organization have volunteered their time and resources in the service of others for the past 65 years. Each is truly an "everyday hero" and worthy of our Nation's deepest gratitude.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In honor of the Civil Air Patrol's 65th anniversary, Senators Inouye, Domenici, Crapo, Murkowski, Wyden, Sanders, Snowe, Collins, Warner, Inhofe, and I have introduced S. Res. XX. I encourage each Member of the Senate to support this resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
