<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1182268804" ordinal="10" title="OUR NUCLEAR DETERRENT">
  <speaking speaker="300036" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, for more than six decades, the bedrock of American national security has been a strong, reliable, and cutting-edge nuclear deterrent. Literally thousands of the best scientists and engineers in the world have dedicated themselves to ending World War II, winning the Cold War, and protecting the free world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Each year, the Directors of the three national nuclear weapons laboratories must certify to the President, and through him to the rest of the United States, that our nuclear weapons systems are reliable. That certification process assures Americans, and warns our adversaries, that the Nation's nuclear stockpile will be able to continue to perform its basic mission--prevention of a nuclear weapons exchange.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>During these six decades, discussion of the nature and size of our nuclear deterrent has been literally constant. Each year, hundreds of scientists, engineers, and global strategists devote innumerable hours and days to intense discussions of the proper strategy for the Nation and the proper nuclear stockpile to implement that strategy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Each year, Presidents have recommendations based upon the work of specialists inside and outside the Federal Government. Since the end of physical testing of our nuclear weapons stockpile--a big event; and, in fact, a major event in American nuclear weapons evolution, the idea we would no longer test our weapons--America has relied on a concept called stockpile stewardship to try to keep our nuclear weapons resources certifiably reliable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This Nation has already embarked upon, and through three different Presidents has reaffirmed, a commitment to physical testing-free testing that has cost billions of dollars. Our strategy has been simple: the most reliable weapons without physical testing, upgraded as strategy dictates.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At the same time, the United States has embarked on a major reduction in the size of our stockpile and in the nuclear stores of other nations. We have done this through programs this Senator has supported and authored during the past 20 years. I salute Senator Richard Lugar, my colleague from Indiana, and former Senator Sam Nunn of Georgia, for their groundbreaking work in forging these programs, and I am proud I have been able to work with them in these critical efforts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of these initiatives--the Nunn-Lugar, Nunn-Lugar-Domenici, the Nuclear Cities Initiative, the Global Initiative for Proliferation Prevention, the Nuclear Nonproliferation Research and Development Program, and others--our world is safer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In total, under Nunn-Lugar, we have deactivated 6,982 warheads, 644 ICBMs, 485 ICBM silos, 100 mobile ICBM launchers, 155 bombers, 906 air-launched cruise missiles, 436 submarine-launched ballistic missile launchers, 611 submarine-launched ballistic missiles, 30 strategic missile submarines, and 194 nuclear test tunnels. Indeed, nine more warheads were deactivated in the last month.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have offered thousands of Russian nuclear scientists alternative pay and occupations, in hopes they will be less susceptible to blandishments from other parties. We are sharing nonproliferation efforts with other nations beyond the former Soviet Union states.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In more stark terms, under the Washington-Moscow Treaty, ratified by the Senate and signed by the President, we will have in our nuclear stockpile, by 2013, fewer weapons than at any time since the era of President Eisenhower. We will have fewer nuclear weapons than we had, in other words, before the Cold War began in earnest.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So this two-pronged approach--international cooperation against proliferation and for elimination of weapons, coupled with the inception of Science-Based Stockpile Stewardship--has been America's strong response to the need to reduce the danger of both nuclear  weapon stockpiles and physical nuclear testing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Almost a decade ago, in a speech at Harvard University, I outlined what I called a new nuclear paradigm. That paradigm envisioned, among other things, a cut in American nuclear weapons to what I then called a threat-based nuclear stockpile; that is, a stockpile commensurate with the anticipated international threat to our Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Critical to that concept was, and remains, the principle of reliability and the continuous battle against degradation of our present stockpile. No serious expert advocated simply keeping the very same physical weapons we had 20 or 25 years ago, with no upgrading or improvements. At some point, the degradation of components in those weapons would mean the certification necessary from the three weapons labs Directors to the President could not be honestly made.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In short, without upgrades and continuous nonphysical monitoring, our nuclear weapons deterrence could be put in serious doubt. Yet at this very time, the youngest nuclear weapons designs in our arsenal are 20 to 25 years old. Age-related component degradation could impact several different systems at the same time, calling into question reliability.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For the past several years, this Senate has supported, on a bipartisan basis, spending the money necessary to protect our stockpile from degradation. At the same time, we have recognized some of our systems are too complicated, pose risks to workers, and need substantial upgrading.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This background brings me to the present Energy and Water Development Appropriations bill for fiscal year 2008 proposed by the House Appropriations Committee and scheduled for House floor action this week.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That bill, if enacted without substantial change, would send American nuclear deterrence strategy in a new, unknown, direction. Think about that. More than 20 years of intensive study, by some of the best minds in the world, could begin to be overturned by enactment of a single appropriations bill. The new direction wouldn't be enacted as the result of 3 to 4 years of intensive study and hearings by all of the relevant committees of Congress. It wouldn't result from a convocation of the best  minds at our disposal. It wouldn't result from the kind of pain-staking analysis of future risks that any prudent American would demand from its government. No, that new path would begin by a single appropriations bill, devised by a small group with</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300036" topic="">
    <paragraph>Note an important point in this story. The funding cuts are proposed now; a new strategic direction will be forged later in this decade. Such an approach is absolutely backwards. We should forge the new direction, if one is believed appropriate in a world of increasing threats to our security, after great study. We should fund our present strategy, 20 years in the making, now.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The House Bill and the Post story focus on the so-called RRW, the Reliable Replacement Warhead. The RRW is a proposed new element of administration policy. The intent of the RRW, to enable increased reliability and design simplification in weapons of comparable explosive yield is, in my view, a very appropriate consideration, which may well result in the ability to maintain still smaller future stockpiles supported by a still smaller future weapons complex. But, as other legislators have suggested  and as I noted in the last paragraph, I agree that a study of the complete role of the RRW in the Nation's nuclear deterrent is appropriate. That study must involve far greater resources than those involved in the House report language. Furthermore, Congress will have</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But far beyond the RRW debate, with or without any RRW, stockpile stewardship is absolutely vital to our national security. As long as this Nation requires a nuclear deterrent in our defense or in support of our allies, we must maintain the skills and infrastructure that support the viability of that stockpile. That must include both trained people and the facilities to enable their work to proceed. Th House bill does harm to the Stockpile Stewardship Program. It cuts all funding for the new  CMRR facility, which would replace</paragraph>
    <paragraph>the present facility, which will be inoperable after 2010. Without a new facility, our Nation will not be able to support the pit mission, which is a single point failure in the complex. Without a viable pit capability, the U.S. nuclear deterrent is vulnerable. The House bill cuts the Nuclear Material Safeguard and Security Upgrade, required to meet the Design Basis Threat around the key nuclear facilities that contain special nuclear material; it would cut stockpile services, the foundation  of the production capability for our Nation; it would cut almost in half  our pit mission, the critical component of our nuclear deterrent systems; it would cut funding for the repair and elimination of old and unused facilities that now drain</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge all my colleagues to attend to this debate as it moves through the House and to markup in subcommittee next week on the Senate side. Implementing and funding a new strategic policy after extensive debate is intelligent; defunding critical parts of our present strategy without a clear new path in view poses serious risks to our national security.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The time controlled by the minority has expired.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I believe we are in a period of morning business.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> That is correct.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I yield myself 12 minutes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
