<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1185854400" ordinal="57" title="SUPPORTING THE GOALS AND IDEALS OF THE NATIONAL ANTHEM PROJECT">
  <narrative>SUPPORTING THE GOALS AND IDEALS OF THE NATIONAL ANTHEM PROJECT -- (Senate - July 31, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="10527">S10527</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412244" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the Senate now proceed to the immediate consideration of Calendar No. 276, <bill type="sr" number="236">S. Res. 236</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="236">S. Res. 236</bill>) supporting the goals and ideals of the National Anthem Project, which has worked to restore America's voice by re-teaching Americans to sing the national anthem.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412244" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, the motions to reconsider be laid on the table, en bloc, and any statements relating thereto be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="236">S. Res. 236</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="236">S. Res. 236</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas a Harris Interactive Survey discovered that of men and women 18 years of age and older, 61 percent of those surveyed did not know all the lyrics of the first stanza of the national anthem, and of those who answered the question affirmatively, 58 percent had received at least 5 years of music education while growing up;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas an ABC News poll revealed that more than 1 in 3 Americans (38 percent) do not know that the official name of the national anthem is "The Star-Spangled Banner", less than 35 percent of American teenagers can name Francis Scott Key as the author of the national anthem, and as few as 15 percent of American youth can sing the words to the anthem from memory;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the national anthem, "The Star-Spangled Banner", holds a special place in the hearts and minds of the American people as a symbol of national unity, resolve, and willingness to sacrifice in order to preserve the Nation's sacred heritage of freedom;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the National Anthem Project has inspired the American people to have a greater appreciation of their patriotic musical heritage while learning American history;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas music educators are the among the leading caretakers of this important piece of our Nation's heritage, in that many students learn the national anthem in music class;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas our Nation's future is enhanced by the quality of the historic knowledge and awareness provided to children of all ages through learning about the national anthem, and that high-quality music education represents a worthy commitment to our children and our Nation's future; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, the national anthem is the symbol of American ideals and freedom around the world: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) supports the goals and ideals of the National Anthem Project;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) commends the American citizens who have participated in this project; and</chair>
  <chair> (3) encourages the people of the United States to learn the national anthem, "The Star-Spangled Banner", and its proud history.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
