<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1208188802" ordinal="19" title="REAUTHORIZATION OF THE TRAUMATIC BRAIN INJURY PROGRAM">
  <narrative>REAUTHORIZATION OF THE TRAUMATIC BRAIN INJURY PROGRAM -- (Senate - April 14, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="2972">S2972</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300052" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I rise today to acknowledge the passage of <bill type="s" number="793">S. 793</bill>, the reauthorization of the Traumatic Brain Injury, TBI, Program. Both the Senate and House of Representatives have passed this bill and it will now be sent to the President's desk to be signed into law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank my colleague and coauthor of the Senate bill, Senator Kennedy, and his staff for their hard work over the past few years. I also extend my gratitude to Senator Enzi and his staff for their diligent efforts in helping to reauthorize this important program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also must thank the leaders of this effort in the House, Representatives Bill Pascrell, Jr., Frank Pallone, Jr., and their staffs who have been so dedicated to helping individuals with TBI.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Also, this bill would not have been possible without the cooperation and input from involved organizations, such as the Brain Injury Association of America, BIAA; the National Association of State Head Injury Administrators, NASHIA; the National Brain Injury Research, Treatment and Training Foundation, NBIRTT; and the National Disability Rights Network, NDRN; and I thank them all for their contributions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It means a lot to the 5.3 million Americans living with TBI, and their families, to reauthorize the only Federal program that helps them. The Federal TBI Program comprises prevention and surveillance activities at the Center for Disease Control, CDC, research at the National Institutes of Health, NIH, and grants to States from the Health Resources and Services Administrations, HRSA. This reauthorization bill expands and improves those activities, and includes provisions to look at the reintegration  of war vets returning to their communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Each year, 1.4 million people sustain a TBI and face long-term or lifelong need for help to perform activities of daily living as a result. Direct medical costs and indirect costs such as lost productivity of TBI totaled an estimated $60 billion in the United States in 2000. We can help truncate those costs and ensure that people are connected to the services they need by continuing this important program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It has been a labor of love to draft and enact legislation to reauthorize this important program. On behalf of individuals living with TBI, and their families, I thank my colleagues in Congress for passing this legislation and reaffirming our commitment to helping those with who suffer from traumatic brain injuries.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
