<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1197997209" ordinal="93" title="125TH ANNIVERSARY OF THE 1882 TREATY OF PEACE, AMITY, COMMERCE AND NAVIGATION">
  <narrative>125TH ANNIVERSARY OF THE 1882 TREATY OF PEACE, AMITY, COMMERCE AND NAVIGATION -- (Senate - December 18, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="15935">S15935</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300080" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Foreign Relations committee be discharged from further consideration of <bill type="sr" number="279">S. Res. 279</bill> and that the Senate then proceed to its immediate consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will report the resolution by title.</narrative>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="279">S. Res. 279</bill>) expressing the sense of the Senate regarding the 125th anniversary of the 1882 Treaty of Peace, Amity, Commerce and Navigation between the Kingdom of Chosun (Korea) and the United States.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300080" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the amendment at the desk be considered and agreed to, the resolution, as amended, be agreed to, the amendment to the preamble be agreed to, the preamble,  as amended, be agreed to, that the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table, en bloc, that any statements be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The amendment (No. 3880) was agreed to as follows:</chair>
  <narrative>(Purpose: To strike a reference to the 2007 Free Trade Agreement and to add environmental protection to the list of bilateral goals that should be addressed by the United States and the Republic of Korea)</narrative>
  <narrative> On page 4, strike lines 4 through 10 and insert the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(2) the economic relationship, highlighting the vibrancy and diversity of the common interests of the United States and the Republic of Korea, should be broadened and deepened;".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; On page 5, lines 4 and 5, strike "and support for peacekeeping" and insert ", support for peacekeeping, and protection of the environment".</narrative>
  <narrative>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="279">S. Res. 279</bill>), as amended, was agreed to.</narrative>
  <narrative>The amendment (No. 3883) was agreed to, as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>On page 3, strike "Whereas the Free Trade Agreement" and all that follows through "both countries;".</narrative>
  <narrative>The preamble, as amended, was agreed to.</narrative>
  <narrative>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="279">S. Res. 279</bill>), as amended, with its preamble, as amended, reads as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>(The resolution will be printed in a future edition of the RECORD.)</narrative>
</record>
