<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1212422402" ordinal="36" title="PRIVILEGES OF THE FLOOR">
  <narrative>PRIVILEGES OF THE FLOOR -- (Senate - June 02, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="4895">S4895</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, on behalf of Senator Lieberman, I ask unanimous consent that Alexander Barron, Ellen Cohen, and Sherry Gillespie, congressional fellows in his office, be granted the privileges of the floor for the duration of the debate on <bill type="s" number="3036">S. 3036</bill>. I also ask unanimous consent, on behalf of Senator Pryor, that Suzanne McGuire, a fellow in his office, be granted the privileges of the floor for the duration of debate on <bill type="s" number="3036">S. 3036</bill>. Further, I ask unanimous consent that  Rachel Radell, a fellow in the office of Senator Feinstein, be granted the privileges of the floor for the duration of debate on this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300055" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that T. J. Kim, a fellow with my committee office, be granted the privileges of the floor for the remainder of debate.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, on behalf of Senator Nelson of Florida, I ask unanimous consent that Maria Honeycutt be granted floor privileges for the duration of the Senate's consideration of this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, on behalf of Senator Carper, I ask unanimous consent that Khesha Jennings, a legislative fellow in his office, be allowed privileges of the floor during the climate change debate.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that Javier Gamboa, an intern with the EPW Committee, be allowed privileges of the floor for the duration of the debate on <bill type="s" number="3036">S. 3036</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
