<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1221235202" ordinal="10" title="BUDGET SCOREKEEPING REPORTS">
  <narrative>BUDGET SCOREKEEPING REPORTS -- (Senate - September 12, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="8472">S8472</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300026" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise to submit to the Senate the second set of budget scorekeeping reports for the 2009 budget resolution. The reports, which cover fiscal years 2008 and 2009, were prepared by the Congressional Budget Office pursuant to section 308(b) and in aid of section 311 of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974, as amended.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The reports show the effects of congressional action through September 8, 2008, and include legislation that was enacted since I filed my last reports in July. The new legislation includes: Public Law 110-275, the Medicare Improvements for Patients and Providers Act of 2008; Public Law 110-287, a joint resolution approving the renewal of import restrictions contained in the Burmese Freedom and Democracy Act of 2003; Public Law 110-289, the Housing and Economic Recovery Act of 2008; and Public  Law 110-315, the Higher Education Opportunity Act. The estimates of budget authority, outlays, and revenues are consistent with the technical and economic assumptions of <bill type="sc" number="70">S. Con. Res. 70</bill>, the 2009 budget resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For 2008, the estimates show that current level spending is below the budget resolution by $5.2 billion for budget authority and $2.4 billion for outlays while current level revenues are above the budget resolution by $3 billion. For 2009, the estimates show that current level spending is below the budget resolution by $958 billion for budget authority and $591.1 billion for outlays while current level revenues are above the budget resolution level by $56.7 billion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the letters and accompanying tables from CBO be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>U.S. CONGRESS,</narrative>
  <narrative>CONGRESSIONAL BUDGET OFFICE,</narrative>
  <narrative>Washington, DC, September 11, 2008.</narrative>
  <narrative>DEAR MR. CHAIRMAN: The enclosed report shows the effects of Congressional action on the fiscal year 2008 budget and is current through September 8, 2008. This report is submitted under section 308(b) and in aid of section 311 of the Congressional Budget Act, as amended.</narrative>
  <narrative>The estimates of budget authority, outlays, and revenues are consistent with the technical and economic assumptions of <bill type="sc" number="70">S. Con. Res. 70</bill>, the Concurrent Resolution on the Budget for Fiscal Year 2009, as approved by the Senate and the House of Representatives.</narrative>
  <narrative>Pursuant to section 204(a) of <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>, provisions designated as emergency requirements are exempt from enforcement of the budget resolution. As a result, the enclosed current level report excludes these amounts (see footnote 2 of Table 2 of the report).</narrative>
  <narrative>Since my last letter, dated July 9, 2008, the Congress has cleared and the President has signed the following acts that affect budget authority, outlays, or revenues for fiscal year 2008:</narrative>
  <narrative>Medicare Improvements for Patients and Providers Act of 2008 (Public Law 110-275);</narrative>
  <narrative>Housing and Economic Recovery Act of 2008 (Public Law 110-289); and</narrative>
  <narrative>Higher Education Opportunity Act (Public Law 110-315).</narrative>
  <narrative>Sincerely,</narrative>
  <narrative>Robert A. Sunshine</narrative>
  <narrative>Enclosure.</narrative>
  <narrative>U.S. CONGRESS,</narrative>
  <narrative>CONGRESSIONAL BUDGET OFFICE,</narrative>
  <narrative>Washington, DC, September 11, 2008.</narrative>
  <narrative>DEAR MR. CHAIRMAN: The enclosed report shows the effects of Congressional action on the fiscal year 2009 budget and is current through September 8, 2008. This report is submitted under section 308(b) and in aid of section 311 of the Congressional Budget Act, as amended.</narrative>
  <narrative>The estimates of budget authority, outlays, and revenues are consistent with the technical and economic assumptions of <bill type="sc" number="70">S. Con. Res. 70</bill>, the Concurrent Resolution on the Budget for Fiscal Year 2009, as approved by the Senate and the House of Representatives.</narrative>
  <narrative>Pursuant to section 204(a) of <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>, provisions designated as emergency requirements are exempt from enforcement of the budget resolution. As a result, the enclosed current level report excludes these amounts (see footnote 2 of Table 2 of the report).</narrative>
  <narrative>Since my last letter, dated July 9, 2008, the Congress has cleared and the President has signed the following acts that affect budget authority, outlays, or revenues for fiscal year 2009:</narrative>
  <narrative>Medicare Improvements for Patients and Providers Act of 2008 (Public Law 110-275);</narrative>
  <narrative>A joint resolution approving the renewal of import restrictions contained in the Burmese Freedom and Democracy Act of 2003 (Public Law 110-287):</narrative>
  <narrative>Housing and Economic Recovery Act of 2008 (Public Law 110-289); and</narrative>
  <narrative>Higher Education Opportunity Act (Public Law 110-315).</narrative>
  <narrative>Sincerely,</narrative>
  <narrative>Enclosure.</narrative>
  <narrative> HONORING OUR ARMED FORCES</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400619" topic="STAFF SERGEANT KENNETH W. MAYNE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, it is with a heavy heart that I rise today to honor the life and heroic service of SSG Kenneth W. Mayne. Staff Sergeant Mayne, a member of the 4th Infantry Division, was killed in a neighborhood outside of Baghdad on September 4, 2008, when a roadside bomb struck his vehicle. He was 29 years old.</paragraph>
    <paragraph> A graduate of Arvada West High School in Colorado, Staff Sergeant Mayne enlisted in the Army in 1997 at the age of 18. According to his mother, Michelle, he immediately took to the discipline and dedication to duty that defines the life of an American soldier. He chose to make service to country his career.</paragraph>
    <paragraph> He was first deployed to Iraq in 2003 with the 101st Airborne, and spent a year there in support of Operation Iraqi Freedom.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Later, Staff Sergeant Mayne transferred to the 4th Infantry Division in Fort Hood, TX, because the division was scheduled to be moved to Fort Carson, CO, following its deployment to Iraq in March 2008. He loved Colorado and wanted to go home to be close to his family. Following his discharge, he intended to become a history teacher.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Those who knew Kenneth described him as brave, as dedicated to his men, and as possessing a great empathy for the children of Iraq. During his patrols in Sadr City, one of the poorest and most volatile neighborhoods in the country, Kenneth distributed toys, soccer balls, and coloring books to Iraqi children that his mother had sent from home. Concerned about their health, he worked with his men to get fresh water into local schools and to clean up sewage so that children had a clean place to  play. He believed in the work he was doing because he could see the difference he was making in people's lives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ralph Waldo Emerson wrote that, "to share often and much ..... to know even one life has breathed easier because you have lived. This is to have succeeded."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For all the Iraqi children who are better off, for all the neighborhoods that are safer, for all those whose image of America has been transformed, Staff Sergeant Mayne has succeeded. Staff Sergeant Mayne embodied an America that reaches out to those in need, an America brimming with kindness and compassion, an America that "shares often and much."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For all this, and for his tireless service to his country, Sergeant Mayne has the eternal gratitude of his nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To Kenneth's mother Michelle, his father, his stepfather Dan, his sisters Christina and Jennifer, his brother Danny, and all his friends and family, I cannot imagine the sorrow you must be feeling. I hope that, in time, the pain of your loss is assuaged by your pride in Kenneth's service to his country and by your knowledge that his country will never forget him. We are humbled by his service and his sacrifice.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
