<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1195146001" ordinal="30" title="ADDITIONAL STATEMENTS">
  <narrative>ADDITIONAL STATEMENTS -- (Senate - November 15, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="14480">S14480</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300003" topic="IN RECOGNITION OF PROFESSORS OF THE YEAR">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I wish to congratulate the four national winners of the U.S. Professors of the Year Award. Since 1981, this program has saluted outstanding undergraduate instructors throughout the country. This year, a State Professor of the Year was also recognized in 40 States and the District of Columbia.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This award is recognized as one of the most prestigious honors bestowed upon a professor. To be nominated for this award requires dedication to the art of education and excellence in every aspect of the profession. Professors personally vested in each student shape the leaders of tomorrow. These individuals should be proud of their accomplishment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I commend and thank all the winners for your leadership and passion for educating. No doubt you have inspired an untold number of students. I wish you the very best in all your endeavors. Congratulations and best regards.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The four national award winners are:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Outstanding Baccalaureate Colleges Professor of the Year: Glenn W. Ellis, associate professor of engineering, Smith College, Northampton, MA;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Outstanding Community Colleges Professor of the Year: Rosemary M. Karr, professor of mathematics, Collin County Community College, Plano, TX;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Outstanding Doctoral and Research Universities Professor of the Year: Christopher M. Sorensen, University Distinguished Professor of Physics, Kansas State University, Manhattan, KS;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Outstanding Master's Universities and Colleges Professor of the Year: Carlos G. Spaht, professor of mathematics, Louisiana State University in Shreveport, Shreveport, LA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>State winners are:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Alabama: Lawrence Davenport, professor of biology, Samford University;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Arizona: John M. Lynch, honors faculty fellow, Arizona State University;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Arkansas: Jay Barth, associate professor of politics, Hendrix College;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>California: Andrew Fraknoi, professor of astronomy, Foothill College;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Colorado: Thomas G. McGuire, associate professor of English and fine arts, U.S. Air Force Academy;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Connecticut: Marc Zimmer, Kohn professor of chemistry, Connecticut College;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>District of Columbia: Richard P. Tollo, associate professor of geology, the George Washington University;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Florida: Patrick K. Moore, public history program director and associate professor, University of West Florida;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Georgia: Linda Stallworth Williams, associate professor of English, North Georgia College &amp; State University;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Idaho: Heidi Reeder, associate professor of communication, Boise State University;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Illinois: Steven A. Meyers, professor of psychology, Roosevelt University;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Indiana: Kristen L. Mauk, Kreft professor of nursing, Valparaiso University;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Iowa: Gail Romberger Nonnecke, professor of horticulture, Iowa State University;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Kansas: David Littrell, university distinguished professor of music, Kansas State University;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Kentucky: Carol Holzhausen Hunt, professor of English and women's studies, Bluegrass Community and Technical College;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Louisiana: Carol E. O'Neil, Peltier professor of dietetics, Louisiana State University and A&amp;M College;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Maine: Robert A. Strong, university foundation professor of investment education, University of Maine;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Maryland: Ernest Bond, associate professor of education, Salisbury University;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Massachusetts: Robert L. Norton, professor of mechanical engineering, Worcester Polytechnic Institute;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Michigan: Norma J. Bailey, professor of middle level education, Central Michigan University;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Minnesota: Ellen Brisch, professor of biology, Minnesota State University Moorhead;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mississippi: George J. Bey, professor of anthropology, Millsaps College;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Missouri: Mark Richter, professor of chemistry, Missouri State University;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Montana: Marisa Pedulla, assistant professor of biological science, Montana Tech of The University of Montana;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nebraska: Isabelle D. Cherney, associate professor of psychology, Creighton University;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>New Jersey: Osama M. Eljabiri, senior university lecturer of managament information systems, New Jersey Institute of Technology;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>New York: T. Michael Duncan, associate professor of chemical engineering, Cornell University;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>North Carolina: Reed M. Perkins, McMahon professor of environmental science, Queens University of Charlotte;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ohio: Linda Morrow, professor of education, Muskingum College;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Oklahoma: Mickey Hepner, associate professor of economics, University of Central Oklahoma;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Oregon: Dawn J. Wright, professor of geography and oceanography, Oregon State University;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Pennsylvania: John A. Commito, professor of environmental studies, Gettysburg College;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>South Carolina: Melissa Walker, Johnson associate professor of history, Converse College;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>South Dakota: Ahrar Ahmad, professor of political science, Black Hills State University;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Tennessee: Peter Giordano, professor and chair of psychology, Belmont University;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Texas: Frank Jones, Harding professor of mathematics, Rice University;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Utah: Lyle G. McNeal, professor of animal, dairy and veterinary science, Utah State University;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Virginia: Joe Hoyle, associate professor of accounting, University of Richmond;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington: Nancy K. Bristow, professor of history, University of Puget Sound;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>West Virginia: Kenneth C. Martis, professor of geography, West Virginia University;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Wisconsin: Kristina M. Ropella, professor of biomedical engineering, Marquette University.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
