<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1178553612" ordinal="14" title="ORDER OF PROCEDURE">
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, we will speak as in morning business for 10 minutes and if the Chair would let me know when I have a minute left.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300037" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, reserving the right to object, and I certainly would not object, but I want to understand the time. We have a vote at 4 o'clock, I believe, which is already ordered. Would the President tell me what the time is between the two parties, how it is divided and who controls time at this point?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The time for morning business has been equally divided until 4 o'clock. The Republicans have no time remaining, and the majority has 33 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300037" topic="">
    <paragraph>Senator Kennedy is asking for 10 minutes in morning business?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Senators are permitted to speak for 10 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300037" topic="">
    <paragraph>Might I ask to follow Senator Kennedy in morning business for 10 minutes?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300083" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, reserving the right to object, if that is where we are.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, could I have the attention of Members. I understand the good Senator from Kansas wanted to make a brief statement about the terrible tragedies that have affected his State, and I see my friend from Vermont is here, so if he were to take 10 minutes, we would still have 10 minutes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400357" topic="">
    <paragraph>Ten minutes would be fine.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>I am wondering if Senator Sanders would be willing to take 6 minutes and let Senator Roberts have 4 to talk about the tragedies in his State. He mentioned this earlier to me, and I didn't think we would have this time dilemma. Would that be acceptable?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400357" topic="">
    <paragraph>Yes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300083" topic="">
    <paragraph>I could not hear the amount of time I might be permitted.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>We have the whole 30 minutes, but the Senator from Vermont has said that, of his 10 minutes, he would be glad to yield to you 4 minutes, and then he will take 6 minutes. Would that be agreeable?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300083" topic="">
    <paragraph>If I could plead with the Senator for 5 minutes?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400357" topic="">
    <paragraph>Yes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300083" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the Senator from Vermont.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I will yield 1 minute of my time to Senator Sanders.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400357" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the Senator.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Massachusetts is recognized.</chair>
</record>
