<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1169053202" ordinal="37" title="SENATE CONCURRENT RESOLUTION 2--EXPRESSING THE BIPARTISAN RESOLUTION ON IRAQ">
  <speaking speaker="300008" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today, Senator Hagel, Senator Levin, and I are submitting a bipartisan resolution that opposes the President's plan to escalate the war in Iraq.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This resolution says what we and many of our colleagues, Democrats and Republicans, are against: deepening America's military involvement in Iraq by escalating our troop presence.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Just as important, it says what we and many of our colleagues are for: a strategy that can produce a political settlement in Iraq.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That's the only way to stop Shiites and Sunnis from killing each other and allow our troops to leave Iraq without leaving chaos behind.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last week, when Secretary of State Rice presented the President's plan to escalate our troop presence in Iraq to the Foreign Relations Committee, the reaction from Democrats and Republicans alike ranged from profound skepticism to outright opposition.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This resolution will give every Senator a chance to say where he or she stands on the President's plan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe that when a President goes way off course on something as important as Iraq, the single most effective way to get him to change course is to demonstrate that his policy has waning or no support--from both parties.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The more we make Iraq a partisan issue, the more the President is likely to dig in. The more we show that Americans across the board don't want to go down the path of escalation, the better our chance to stop it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Iraq is not a partisan issue. It's a challenge we must meet as Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The very first sentence of our resolution says something the three of us believe profoundly: "U.S. strategy and presence on the ground in Iraq can only be sustained with the support of the American people and the bipartisan support of Congress."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This resolution will demonstrate that, right now, the support is not there for the President's policy in Iraq. The sooner he recognizes that reality and acts on it, the better off all of us will be.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300050" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, we have before us one of the most important issues that has ever faced our country, certainly in modern times. The future of Iraq will affect the United States, the Middle East, and the world for decades to come.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>No one in Congress and no one in the United States wants to see America humiliated, defeated, or in any way lose its purpose. The issue of Iraq involves all of us. The Congress of the United States must have a role to play.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our responsibility is to join together in a bipartisan effort to work to develop a consensus to deal with the great challenges of our time. I know of no challenge that is greater today, before this country, than Iraq. When a Nation commits its men and women to war, it is the greatest challenge that any of us will ever deal with in our time in the Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We owe it to the American people to help find a bipartisan consensus of purpose, to help develop a policy worthy of our men and women in uniform. The American people not only deserve but they expect a consensus. This resolution is not about trying to assign blame on the Administration. It is not about replaying past mistakes. This resolution is about moving forward. It is difficult but it is our responsibility.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Some of us believe that the course that the President announced Wednesday was not the appropriate course. I do not believe that the United States should be sending more American troops into the middle of the tribal, sectarian civil war that is occurring in Iraq.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senators BIDEN, LEVIN, and I have focused personally on writing this resolution because we felt it must reflect a responsible, forward-looking, and constructive approach. We must remain focused on a strategy which seeks to advance America's national interests and allow America to leave Iraq honorably.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The American people look to its government for responsible policy. A policy that can be sustained. A policy that reflects a clear consensus of purpose regarding our objectives, our strategy and our policies. This is what our resolution seeks to achieve.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, the primary objective of the bipartisan resolution my colleagues and I are introducing today is to convince a bipartisan majority of Senators to oppose deeper military involvement in Iraq by the United States and to get the Iraqis to reach a political settlement among themselves as the only way to end the violence in Iraq.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The resolution would send a clear message that Congress does not support the plan to increase the number of U.S. troops in Iraq because it is based on the false premise that there is a  military solution to the violence and instability in Iraq, when what is needed is a political solution among the Iraqi leaders and factions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Iraq's own Prime Minister Maliki acknowledged recently that "The crisis is political, and the ones who can stop the cycle of aggravation and bloodletting of innocents are the politicians."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The resolution states that it is not in the national security interests of the United States to deepen our military involvement in Iraq by increasing the number of U.S. troops.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The resolution calls for the transition of our military mission in Iraq to a more limited one of training, counterterrorism, and protecting the territorial integrity of Iraq. It also calls for greater engagement of other countries in the region in the stabilization and reconstruction of Iraq.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last week the President said that he had made clear to Iraq's leaders that America's commitment is not open-ended. I welcome these words. But the reality behind the President's new rhetoric is that the open-ended commitment continues--more American military men and women would be sent into the chaos of Iraq's sectarian violence without condition or limitation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>President Bush also indicated that the Iraqi government needs "breathing space" to make political progress. The opposite is true. The Iraqi leaders don't need breathing space--they must feel real pressure to reach a political settlement. Increasing our military presence in Iraq takes more pressure off. The Iraq Study Group put it this way last month: "An open-ended commitment of American forces would not provide the Iraqi government the incentive it needs to take the political actions that  give Iraq its best chance of quelling sectarian violence."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>President Bush also said that the Iraqis have set benchmarks for themselves. But look at the track record of the Iraqi government in meeting some of its past benchmarks and promises: Iraqi President Talibani said in August 2006 that Iraqi forces would "take over security in all Iraqi provinces by the end of 2006." That pledge has not been kept. Prime Minister Maliki said last June that he would disband the militias and illegal armed groups as part of his national reconciliation plan, and in  October he set the timetable for disbanding the militias as the end of 2006. That commitment has not been kept. The Iraqi Constitutional Review Commission was to present its recommendations for changes in the Constitution to the Council of Representatives within four months of the formation of the Government last May. The Commission has yet to formulate any recommendations. Prime Minister Maliki put forward a series</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is not a track record that inspires confidence in Iraqi pledges and commitments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The President said that "America will hold the Iraqi government to the benchmarks it has announced." How did the President say we are going to do that? What will the consequences be if the Iraqis continue to fail to meet these benchmarks, particularly since some of them have been established and missed in the past? The President said "If the Iraqi government does not follow through on its promises, it will lose the support of the American people ..... " That is an empty threat given the fact  that the Iraqi Government has already lost the support of the American people, and it hasn't affected their behavior. The President's most recent plan, like previous ones, includes no mechanism to hold the Iraqis to their commitments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Just two months ago General Abizaid testified before our Committee against increasing the number of U.S. troops in Iraq. He told us: "I met with every divisional commander, General Casey, the corps commander, General Dempsey. We all talked together. And I said, in your professional opinion, if we were to bring in more American troops now, does it add considerably to our ability to achieve success in Iraq? And they all said no. And the reason is, because we want the Iraqis to do more. It's easy  for the Iraqis to rely upon us do this work. I believe that more American forces prevent the Iraqis from doing more, from taking more responsibility for their own future."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Deepening our involvement in Iraq would be a mistake. Deepening our involvement in Iraq on the assumption that the Iraqis will meet future benchmarks and commitments given their track record would compound the mistake.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For America to supply more troops while the Iraqi leaders simply supply more promises is not a recipe for success in Iraq. Telling the Iraqis that we will increase our troops to give them yet more breathing space will only postpone the day when Iraqis take their future into their own hands and decide whether they want to continue to fight a civil war or make peace among themselves.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This resolution does not limit any future course of action that Congress may decide to take. What it would do is send a powerful message to the President and the Iraqis that Congress does not support an escalation of our military presence in Iraq.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
