<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1169744418" ordinal="35" title="HONORING THE 150TH ANNIVERSARY OF THE PHILADELPHIA ACADEMY OF MUSIC">
  <speaking speaker="300078" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate now proceed to the consideration of <bill type="sr" number="43">S. Res. 43</bill> which was submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300092" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I have sought recognition to support legislation with my distinguished colleague, Senator CASEY, that will honor the 150th Anniversary of the Academy of Music of Philadelphia, PA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Academy of Music has served as a venue for the performing arts, ceremonial events, Presidential conventions and historical occasions since its opening in 1857. The Academy is the oldest grand opera house in the United States still used for its original purpose, and was designated as a National Historic Landmark in 1963.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Academy served as the main concert hall for the Philadelphia Orchestra for more than a century. The Orchestra purchased the Academy in 1957, and continues to perform there each year for the Academy's anniversary. Additionally, a host of legendary artists including Maria Callas, Joan Sutherland, George Gershwin, Anna Pavlova, Igor Stravinsky and Luciano Pavarotti have performed at this important venue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Academy of Music has also been the site of several significant and historic cultural events. Alexander Graham Bell conducted a demonstration of the telephone in 1877, Leopold Stokowski and the Philadelphia Orchestra performed the first ever concert in stereophonic sound there in 1933, and in 1939, the Philadelphia Orchestra recorded the soundtrack to Walt Disney's classic film, Fantasia, at the Academy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Academy's history extends further than the opulent interior of the main hall and the magnificent performances that have graced its stage. An elegant restaurant was constructed in the basement in 1857 for opera-goers and arts patrons. During World War II, the restaurant was converted into a canteen that hosted 2.5 million service men and women between the years of 1942 and 1945 who enjoyed performances by Abbott and Costello, Duke Ellington, Lynn Fontanne and Frank Sinatra.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Academy of Music continues to be the Philadelphia area's primary venue for the performing arts, hosting major Broadway productions, operatic performances and traveling dance and theater companies. It is with great pleasure that Senator CASEY and I present this resolution honoring the Academy of Music's 150th Anniversary, and pay homage to an institution that has played a significant role in Philadelphia's vibrant arts community. I ask my colleagues to join me in recognizing the Academy  of Music.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300078" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <narrative>(The resolution will be printed in a future edition of the RECORD.)</narrative>
</record>
