<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1228928403" ordinal="34" title="GENERIC MEDICINES">
  <narrative>GENERIC MEDICINES -- (Senate - December 10, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="10862">S10862</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I rise today to bring to my colleagues' attention a recent article in the respected Journal of American Medicine on generic medicines. The article comes at a critical time as we begin to tackle the important issue of health care reform.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is no doubt that health care reform must include offering solutions that reduce skyrocketing health care costs. One solution to reducing costs is to increase access to generic medicines, which offer savings of up to 80 percent over brand drug costs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The new JAMA article provides specific evidence on the benefits of generic medicines. The analysis, which included U.S. scientists reviewing more than 20 years of research on generic versus brand name drugs, found that there is no clinical evidence showing that brand name cardiovascular drugs were superior to their generic versions. Moreover, the lead author of the report noted that generics can lead to better outcomes because they cost less, which means patients can afford to take them and stay  on them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As our economy continues to struggle, Americans across the country are looking for ways to make ends meet. We hear too often about older Americans rationing their medicines and even mothers watering down infant formula to make it last longer, not knowing of the dangerous health impact this can have. A recent survey conducted by BearingPoint, Inc., and Zogby found that an alarming number of consumers admitted that they would consider denying themselves or their children health care to save money  during this difficult economic time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As we consider the critical and interrelated issues regarding the economic crisis and reform of national health care, the new JAMA study supports every effort we can make now to increase the use of generic medicines. We should remove the numerous barriers to getting generic medicines to consumers sooner rather than later, and we must prevent the creation of new barriers that will impede greater use of generics. We also should consider how to create a workable pathway for biogenerics, a pathway  that actually gets these safe and affordable lifesaving medicines to patients in a timely manner.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Generic medicines save consumers and State and Federal governments billions of dollars annually. At the same time, generic medicines are FDA approved, guaranteeing their safety and effectiveness.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When the new Congress tackles the important health care initiatives that lie ahead, the safety and effectiveness of prescription drugs must remain a top priority. As the medical evidence concludes, Congress can have confidence in the fact that increasing access to generic medicines will provide high-quality care at significant cost savings for consumers and the government.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent to have the article to which I referred printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
</record>
