<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1193760002" ordinal="57" title="CONDOLENCES REGARDING THE TRAGIC FIRE IN OCEAN ISLE BEACH, NORTH CAROLINA">
  <narrative>CONDOLENCES REGARDING THE TRAGIC FIRE IN OCEAN ISLE BEACH, NORTH CAROLINA -- (Senate - October 30, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="13587">S13587</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent the Senate now proceed to consideration of <bill type="sr" number="360">S. Res. 360</bill>, which was submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="360">S. Res. 360</bill>) offering condolences regarding the tragic fire in Ocean Isle Beach, North Carolina which killed 6 University of South Carolina students and 1 student from Clemson University on October 28, 2007.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent the resolution be agreed to, the motion to reconsider be laid on the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="360">S. Res. 360</bill>) was agreed to, as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="360">S. Res. 360</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair> Resolved, That the Senate offers its heartfelt condolences to the victims and their families regarding the tragic fire on October 28, 2007, in Ocean Isle Beach, North Carolina, which killed 6 University of South Carolina students and 1 student from Clemson University, and to the students, faculty, administration, and staff and their families who have been deeply affected by these tragic events.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
