<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1217260803" ordinal="49" title="TEMPORARY EXTENSION OF PROGRAMS UNDER HIGHER EDUCATION ACT OF 1965">
  <narrative>TEMPORARY EXTENSION OF PROGRAMS UNDER HIGHER EDUCATION ACT OF 1965 -- (Senate - July 28, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="7578">S7578</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of <bill type="s" number="3352">S. 3352</bill>, introduced earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the bill by title.</chair>
  <chair>The bill clerk read as follows:</chair>
  <chair>A bill (<bill type="s" number="3352">S. 3352</bill>) to temporarily extend the programs under the Higher Education Act of 1965.</chair>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the bill.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the bill be read three times, passed, the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table, with no intervening action or debate, and any statements related to the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The bill (<bill type="s" number="3352">S. 3352</bill>) was ordered to a third reading, was read the third time, and passed.</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="s" number="3352">S. 3352</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,</chair>
  <chair>(a) EXTENSION OF PROGRAMS.--Section 2(a) of the Higher Education Extension Act of 2005 (Public Law 109-81; 20 U.S.C. 1001 note) is amended by striking "July 31, 2008" and inserting "August 15, 2008".</chair>
  <chair>(b) RULE OF CONSTRUCTION.--Nothing in this section, or in the Higher Education Extension Act of 2005 as amended by this Act, shall be construed to limit or otherwise alter the authorizations of appropriations for, or the durations of, programs contained in the amendments made by the Higher Education Reconciliation Act of 2005 (Public Law 109-171), by the College Cost Reduction and Access Act (Public Law 110-84), or by the Ensuring Continued Access to Student Loans Act of 2008 (Public Law  110-227) to the provisions of the Higher Education Act of 1965 and the Taxpayer-Teacher Protection Act of 2004.</chair>
  <chair>(c) EFFECTIVE DATE.--The amendment made by subsection (a) shall take effect as if enacted on July 31, 2008.</chair>
</record>
