<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1168448402" ordinal="34" title="STATEMENTS ON INTRODUCED BILLS AND JOINT RESOLUTIONS">
  <speaking speaker="300042" topic="Introducing S. 236. A bill to require reports to Congress on Federal agency use of data mining; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="236">S. 236</bill>] Mr. President, I am pleased today to introduce the Federal Agency Data Mining Reporting Act of 2007. I want to thank Senator Sununu for once again cosponsoring this bill, which we also introduced in the last Congress. Senator Sununu has consistently been a leader on privacy issues, and I am pleased to work with him on this effort. I also want to thank Senators Leahy, Akaka, and Wyden, for their continuing support of the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The controversial data analysis technology known as data mining is capable of reviewing millions of both public and private records on each and every American. The possibility of government law enforcement or intelligence agencies fishing for patterns of criminal or terrorist activity in these vast quantities of digital data raises serious privacy and civil liberties issues--not to mention serious questions about the effectiveness of these types of searches. But four years after Congress first  learned about and defunded the Defense Department's program called Total Information Awareness, there is still much Congress does not know about the Federal Government's work on data mining.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have made some progress. We know from reviews conducted by the Government Accountability Office that as of May 2004 there were nearly 200 Federal data mining programs, more than one hundred of which relied on personal information and 29 of which were for the purpose of investigating terrorists or criminals. And we have learned a few more details on five of those programs from a follow-up report that GAO issued in August 2005. We also have a brief report from the DHS Inspector General published  in August 2006, and as a result of my amendment to the DHS appropriations bill we have a July 2006 report from the Privacy Office at the Department of Homeland Security that provides some interesting policy suggestions relating to data mining.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But this information has come to us haphazardly, and lacks detail about the precise nature of the data mining programs being utilized or developed, their efficacy, and the consequences Americans could face as a result. Furthermore, much of the reporting thus far has focused on the Department of Homeland Security. It also appears there has been little if any government-wide consideration of privacy policies for these types of programs. Indeed, public debate on government data mining has been generated  more by press stories than as a result of congressional oversight.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My bill would require all Federal agencies to report to Congress within 180 days and every year thereafter on data mining programs developed or used to find a pattern or anomaly indicating terrorist or other criminal activity on the part of individuals, and how these programs implicate the civil liberties and privacy of all Americans. If necessary, specific information in the various reports could be classified.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is information we need to have. Congress should not be learning the details about data mining programs after millions of dollars are spent testing or using data mining against unsuspecting Americans. The possibility of unchecked, secret use of data mining technology threatens one of the most important values that we are fighting for in the war against terrorism--freedom.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Data mining could rely on a combination of intelligence data and personal information like individuals' traffic violations, credit card purchases, travel records, medical records, and virtually any information contained in commercial or public databases. Congress must conduct oversight to make sure that all government agencies engaged in fighting terrorism and other criminal enterprises--not just the Department of Homeland Security, but also the Department of Justice, the Department of Defense  and others--use these types of sensitive personal information effectively and appropriately.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me clarify what this bill does not do. It does not have any effect on the government's use of commercial data to conduct individualized searches on people who are already suspects, nor does it require that the government report on these types of searches. It does not end funding for any program, determine the rules for use of data mining technology, or threaten any ongoing investigation that might use data mining technology.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My bill would simply provide Congress with information about the nature of the technology and the data that will be used. The Federal Agency Data Mining Reporting Act would require all government agencies to assess  the efficacy of the data mining technology they are using or developing--that is, whether the technology can deliver on the promises of each program. In addition, my bill would make sure that Congress knows whether the Federal agencies using  data mining technology have considered and developed policies or guidelines to protect the privacy and due process rights of individuals, such as privacy technologies and redress procedures. With complete information about the current data mining plans and practices of the Federal Government,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, Congress must look closely at the government's activities because data mining is unproven in this area. Some argue that data mining can help locate potential terrorists before they strike. But we do not, today, have evidence that pattern-based data mining will prevent terrorism. In fact, some technology experts have warned that this type of data mining is not the right approach for the terrorism problem. Just last month, the Cato Institute released a report--coauthored by a scientist  specializing in data analytics and an information privacy expert--concluding that "[t]he only thing predictable about predictive data mining for terrorism is that it would be consistently wrong."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Some commercial uses of data mining have been successful, but have arisen in a very different context than counterterrorism efforts. For example, the financial world has successfully used data mining to identify people committing fraud because it has data on literally millions, if not billions, of historical financial transactions. And the banks and credit card companies know, in large part, which of those past transactions have turned out to be fraudulent. So when they apply sophisticated  statistical algorithms to that massive amount of historical data, they are able to make a pretty good guess about what a fraudulent transaction might look like in the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We do not have that kind of historical data about terrorists and sleeper cells. We have just a handful of individuals whose past actions can be analyzed, which makes it virtually impossible to apply the kind of advanced statistical analysis required to use data mining in this way. That raises serious questions about whether data mining will ever be able to locate an actual terrorist. Before the government starts reviewing personal information about every man, woman and child in this country,  we should learn what data mining can and can't do--and what limits and protections are needed if data mining programs do go forward.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We must also bear in mind that there will inevitably be errors in the underlying data. Everyone knows people who have had errors on their credit reports--and that is the one area of commercial data where the law already imposes strict accuracy requirements. Other types of commercial data are likely to be even more inaccurate. Even if the technology itself were effective, I am very concerned that innocent people could be ensnared because of mistakes in the data that make them look suspicious.  The recent rise in identity theft, which creates even more data accuracy problems, makes it even more important that we address this issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also want to touch on one issue that has proved difficult in many debates about data mining: how to define the term. What is data mining? From policy debates to government reports, many people have wrestled with this question. While it can be defined more broadly, for the purpose of this reporting requirement, data mining is limited to the process of attempting to predict future events or actions by discovering or locating patterns or anomalies in data. However, for purposes of the reporting  requirement in this bill, which seeks information on those data mining programs most likely to threaten the privacy and civil liberties of Americans, I have limited the definition in a couple of other ways. First, the bill's core definition of data mining is to conduct a query, search or other analysis of one or more electronic databases to "discover a predictive pattern or an anomaly indicative of terrorist or criminal activity on the part of any individual or individuals." Data mining has a number of applications at various government</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second, as I alluded to earlier, the definition explicitly excludes queries to retrieve information from a database that is based on information--such as address, passport number or license plate number--that is associated with a particular individual or individuals. This type of query is a traditional investigative technique. Although government agencies must be careful in their use of commercial databases, simply querying a Choicepoint database for information about someone who is already a  suspect is not data mining.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Most Americans believe that their private lives should remain private. Data mining programs run the risk of intruding into the lives of individuals who have nothing to do with terrorism or other criminal activity and understandably do not want their credit reports, shopping habits and doctor visits to become a part of a gigantic computerized search engine operating without any controls or oversight, and without much promise of locating terrorists. As the Cato report put it, "[t]he possible benefits  of predictive data mining for finding planning or preparation for terrorism are minimal. The financial costs, wasted effort, and threats to privacy and civil liberties are potentially vast."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At a minimum, the administration should be required to report to Congress about the various data mining programs now underway or being studied, and the impact those programs may have on our privacy and civil liberties, so that Congress can determine whether any benefits of this practice come at too high a price to our privacy and personal liberties. As Senator Wyden and I have told the Director of National Intelligence, we must have a public discussion about the efficacy and privacy  implications of data mining. We wrote a letter to him on November 15, 2006, that included the following:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>[W]e believe there needs to be a public discussion before the implementation of any government data mining program that would rely on domestic commercial data and other information about Americans. There are serious questions about whether pattern analysis of such data can effectively identify terrorists, given the relative lack of historical data about terrorist activities. And as the furor over the Total Information Awareness program demonstrated, the American public has serious--and legitimate--concerns  about the privacy ramifications of programs designed to fish for patterns of criminal or terrorist activity in vast quantities of digital data, collected by other entities for entirely different reasons. Pattern analysis runs the risk of generating a large number of false positives, meaning that innocent Americans could become the subject of investigation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Of course, the Intelligence Community should be taking advantage of new technologies in its critical responsibility to protect our country from terrorists, and much of its work must remain classified to protect national security. But we can have a public debate about what privacy rules should constrain data mining programs deployed domestically, without revealing sensitive information like the precise algorithms that the government has developed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill is the first step in this process--a way for Congress and, to the degree appropriate, the public to finally understand what is going on behind the closed doors of the executive branch so that we can start to have a policy discussion about data mining that is long overdue. I urge my colleagues to support this bill. All it asks for is information to which Congress and the American people are entitled.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the text of this bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="Introducing S. 236. A bill to require reports to Congress on Federal agency use of data mining; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I am pleased today to join with Senators FEINGOLD, SUNUNU and others to introduce the Federal Agency Data Mining Reporting Act of 2007. This important privacy legislation would begin to restore key checks and balances by requiring Federal agencies to report to Congress on their datamining programs and activities. We joined together to introduce a similar bill last Congress. Regrettably, it received no attention. This year, I intend to make sure that we do a better  job in considering Americans' privacy, checks and balances, and the proper balance to protect Americans' privacy rights while fighting smarter and more effectively against security threats.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In recent years, the Federal Government's use of data mining technology has exploded. According to a May 2004 report by the General Accounting Office, there are at least 199 different government data mining programs operating or planned throughout the Federal Government, with at least 52 different Federal agencies currently using data mining technology. And, more and more, these data mining programs are being used with little or no notice to ordinary citizens, or to Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Advances in technologies make data banks and data mining more powerful and more useful than at any other time in our history. These can be useful tools in our national security arsenal, but we should use them appropriately so that they can be most effective. A mistake can cost Americans their jobs and wreak havoc in their lives and reputations that can take years to repair. Without adequate safeguards, oversight and checks and balances, these powerful technologies also become an invitation to  government abuse. The government must take steps to ensure that it is properly using this technology. Too often, government data mining programs lack adequate safeguards to protect the privacy rights and civil liberties of ordinary Americans, whose data is collected and analyzed by these programs. Without these safeguards, government data mining programs are prone to produce inaccurate results and are ripe for abuse, error and unintended consequences.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation takes an important first step in addressing these concerns by pulling back the curtain on how this Administration is using this technology. It does not by its terms prohibit the use of this technology, but rather provides an oversight mechanism to begin to ensure it is being used appropriately and effectively. This bill would require Federal agencies to report to Congress about its data mining programs. The legislation provides a much-needed check on federal agencies to disclose  the steps that they are taking to protect the privacy and due process rights of American citizens when they use these programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We need checks and balances to keep government data bases from being misused against the American people. That is what the Constitution and our laws should provide. We in Congress must make sure that when our government uses technology to detect and deter illegal activity that it does so in a manner that also protects our most basic rights and liberties. This bill advances this important goal, and I urge all Senators to support this important privacy legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="Introducing S. 237. A bill to improve agricultural job opportunities, benefits, and security for aliens in the United States and for other purposes; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="237">S. 237</bill>] Mr. President, Senators CRAIG, KENNEDY, MARTINEZ, BOXER, VOINOVICH and I are once again introducing legislation that will address the chronic labor shortage in our Nation's agricultural industry. This bill is a priority for me--and for the tens of thousands of farmers who are currently suffering--and I hope we will move it forward early in this Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Agricultural Job Opportunities, Benefits, and Security Act, or AgJOBS, is the product of more than ten years of work. It is a bipartisan bill supported by growers, farmers, and farm workers alike. It passed the Senate last year as part of the comprehensive immigration reform bill last spring in the 109th Congress. It is time to move this bill forward.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The agricultural industry is in crisis. Farmers across the Nation report a 20 percent decline in labor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The result is that there are simply not enough farm workers to harvest the crops.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Nation's agricultural industry has suffered. If we do not enact a workable solution to the agricultural labor crisis, we risk a national production loss of $5 billion to $9 billion each year,  according to the American Farm Bureau.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>California, in particular, will suffer. California is the single largest agricultural state in the nation. California agriculture accounts for $34 billion in annual revenue. There 76,500 farms that produce half of the nation's fruits, vegetables, and nuts from only 3 percent of the Nation's farmland.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>California farms produce approximately 350 different crops: pears, walnuts, raisins, lettuce, onions, cotton, just to name a few.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many of the farmers who grow these crops have been in the business for generations. They farm the land that their parents and their grandparents farmed before them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The sad consequence of the labor shortage is that many of these farmers are giving up their farms. Some are leaving the business entirely. Others are bulldozing their fruit trees--literally pulling out trees that have been in the family for generations--because they do not have the labor they need to harvest their fruit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Once the trees are gone, they are replaced by crops that do not require manual labor. And our pears, our apples, our oranges will come from foreign sources.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The trend is quite clear. If there is not a means to grow and harvest our produce here, we will import produce from China, from Mexico, from other countries who have the labor they need.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We will put American farmers out of business. And there will be a ripple effect felt throughout the economy: in farm equipment, inputs, packaging, processing, transportation, marketing, lending and insurance. Jobs will be lost and our economy will suffer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The reality is that Americans have come to rely on undocumented workers to harvest their crops for them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In California alone, we rely on approximately one million undocumented workers to harvest the crops. The United Farm Workers estimate that undocumented workers make up as much as 90 percent the farm labor payroll.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Americans simply will not do the work. It is hard, stooped labor, requiring long and unpredictable hours. Farm workers must leave home and travel from farm to farm to plant, prune, and harvest crops according to the season.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We must come to terms with the fact that we rely on an undocumented migrant work force. We must bring those workers out of the shadows and create a legal and enforceable means to provide labor for agriculture. That realization is what led to the long and careful negotiations creating AgJOBS.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The AgJOBS bill is a two part bill. Part one identifies and deals with those undocumented agricultural workers who have been working in the United States for the past 2 years or more. Part two creates a more usable H-2A Program, to implement a realistic and effective guest worker program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The first step requires undocumented agricultural workers to apply for a "blue card" if they can demonstrate that they have worked in American agriculture for at least 150 workdays over the past 2 years. The blue card entitles the worker to a temporary legal resident status.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The blue card itself is encrypted and machine readable; it is tamper and counterfeit resistant, and contains biometric identifiers unique to the farm worker.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The second step requires that a blue card holder work in American agriculture for an additional 5 years for at least 100 workdays a year, or 3 years at 150 workdays a year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Blue card workers would have to pay a $500 fine. The workers can travel abroad and reenter the United States and they may work in other, non-agricultural jobs, as long as they meet the agricultural work requirements.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The blue card worker's spouse and minor children, who already live in the United States, may also apply for a temporary legal status and identification card, which would permit them to work and travel.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The total number of blue cards is capped at 1.5 million over a five year period and the program sunsets after 5 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At the end of the required work period, the blue card worker may apply for a green card to become a legal permanent resident.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are also a number of safeguards. If a blue card worker does not apply for a green card, or does not fulfill the work requirements, that individual can be deported.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Likewise, a blue card holder who commits a felony, three misdemeanors, or any crime that involves bodily injury, the threat of serious bodily injury, or harm to property in excess of $500, cannot get a green card and can be deported.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This program, for the first time, allows us to identify those hundreds of thousands of farm workers who now work in the shadows. It requires the farm workers to come forward and to be identified in exchange for the right to work and live legally in the United States. And it gives farmers the legal certainty they need to hire the workers they need.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The program also modifies the H-2A guest worker program so that it realistically responds to our agricultural needs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Currently, the H-2A program is bureaucratic, unresponsive, expensive, and prone to litigation. Farmers cannot get the labor when they need it. AgJOBS offers a much-needed reform of the outdated system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The labor certification process, which often takes 60 days or more, is replaced by an "attestation" process. The employer can file a fax-back application form agreeing to abide by the requirements of the H-2A program. Approval should occur in 48 to 72 hours.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The interstate clearance order to determine whether there are U.S. workers who can qualify for the jobs is replaced by a requirement that the employer file a job notification with the local office of the state Employment Security Agency. Advertising and positive recruitment must take place in the local labor market area.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Agricultural associations can continue to file applications on behalf of members.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The statutory prohibition against "adversely affecting" U.S. workers is eliminated. The Adverse Effect Wage Rate is instead frozen for 3 years, and thereafter indexed by a methodology that will lead to its gradual replacement with a prevailing wage standard.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Employers may elect to provide a housing allowance in lieu of housing if the governor determines that there is adequate rental housing available in the area of employment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Inbound and return transportation and subsistence are required on the same basis as under the current program, except that trips of less than 100 miles are excluded, and workers whom an employer is not required to provide housing are excluded.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The motor vehicle safety standards for U.S. workers are extended to H-2A workers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Petitions for admission of H-2A workers must be processed and the consulate or port of entry notified within 7 days of receipt. Requirements are the same as current law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Petitions extending aliens' stay or changing employers are valid upon filing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Employers may apply for the admission of new H-2A workers to replace those who abandoned their work or are terminated for cause, and the Department of Homeland Security is required to remove H-2A aliens who abandoned their work.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>H-2A visas will be secure and counterfeit resistant.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A new limited federal right of action is available to foreign workers to enforce the economic benefits required under the H-2A program, and any benefits expressly offered by the employer in writing. A statute of limitations of three years is imposed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, lawsuits in State court under State contract law alleging violations of the H-2A program requirements and obligations are expressly preempted. Such State court lawsuits have been the venue of choice for litigation against H-2A employers in recent years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>AgJOBS is the one part of the immigration bill about which there is uniform agreement. Everyone knows that agriculture in America is supported by undocumented workers. As immigration enforcement tightens up, and increasing numbers of people are prevented from crossing the borders or are being deported, the result is our crops go unharvested.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are faced today with a very practical dilemma and one that is easy to solve. The legislation has been vetted over and over again. Senator CRAIG, I,  and a multitude of other Senators have sat down with the growers, with the farm bureaus, with the chambers, with everybody who knows agriculture, and they have all signed off on the AgJOBS bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is our opportunity to solve a real problem.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask my colleagues to join Senator CRAIG, Senator KENNEDY, Senator MARTINEZ, Senator BOXER, Senator VOINOVICH and me in supporting this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also ask by unanimous consent that the text of this bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="TITLE III--MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, It's a privilege to join Senator Feinstein and Senator Craig and my other colleagues today as we reintroduce the Agricultural Jobs, Opportunity, Benefits, and Security Act. I commend them and Representatives Howard Berman and Chris Cannon for their bipartisan leadership and I'm honored to be part of this landmark legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill reflects a far-reaching and welcome agreement between the United Farm Workers and the agricultural industry on one of the most difficult immigration' challenges we face, and we in Congress should make the most of this unique opportunity for progress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>America has a proud tradition as a Nation of immigrants and a Nation of laws. But our current immigration laws fail us on both counts. Much of the Nation's economy today depends on the hard work and the many contributions of immigrants. The agricultural industry would grind to a halt without immigrant farm workers. Yet, the overwhelming majority of these workers lack legal status, and can be easily exploited by unscrupulous employers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation we are introducing, called the "AgJOBS Act," is an opportunity to correct these long-festering problems. It will give farm workers and their families the dignity and justice they deserve, and it will give agricultural employers a legal workforce.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is a realistic compromise that now has broad support in Congress, and from business and labor, civic and faith-based organizations, liberals and conservatives, trade associations and immigrant rights groups.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Act is a needed reform in our immigration law to reflect current economic realities and meet our national security needs more effectively, and do so in a way that respects America's immigrant heritage. It provides a fair and reasonable means for illegal agricultural workers to earn legal status, and it also reforms the current visa program, so that employers unable to obtain American workers can hire needed foreign workers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The AgJOBS Act is good for both labor and business. The Nation can no longer ignore the fact that more than half of our agricultural workers are undocumented. Growers need an immediate, reliable and legal workforce at harvest time. Farm workers need legal statues to improve their wages and working conditions. Everyone suffers when crops rot in the fields because of the lack of an adequate labor force.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The AgJOBS Act provides a fair and reasonable process for undocumented agricultural workers to earn legal status. Undocumented farm workers are clearly vulnerable to abuse by unscrupulous labor contractors and growers. Their illegal status deprives them of bargaining power and depresses the wages of all farm workers. Our bill provides fair solutions for undocumented workers who have been toiling in our fields and harvesting our fruits and vegetables.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill is not an amnesty. To earn the right to remain in this country, workers would not only have to demonstrate past work contributions to the U.S. economy, but also make a substantial future work commitment. These workers will be able to come forward, identify themselves, provide evidence that they have been employed in agriculture and will continue to work hard, and will play by the rules in the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation will modify the current temporary foreign agricultural worker program, while preserving and enhancing key labor protections. It achieves a fair balance. It streamlines the H-2A visa application process by reducing paperwork for employers and accelerating processing. But individuals participating in the program receive strong labor protections.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our legislation will unify families. When temporary residence is granted a farm worker's spouse and minor children will be able to remain legally in the U.S. but they will not be authorized to work. When the worker becomes a permanent resident, the spouse and minor children will also gain such status.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>AgJOBS will also enhance national security and reduce illegal immigration. It will reduce the chaotic, illegal, and all-too-deadly flows of immigrants at our borders by providing safe and legal avenues for farm workers and their families. Future temporary workers will be carefully screened to meet security concerns. Enforcement resources will be more effectively focused on the highest risks. By bringing undocumented farm workers out of the shadows and requiring them to pass through security checks,  it will enable officials to concentrate more effectively on terrorists and criminals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last year, Senators came together--Democrats and Republicans--to pass a far-reaching immigration reform bill that included the AgJOBS bill. The American people are calling on us to come together again. They know there is a crisis, and they want action now.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>President Bush has been a leader on immigration reform, and I'm hopeful that he will renew his efforts with members of his party, so that we can continue action quickly this year on comprehensive reform legislation and end this festering crisis once and for all. The House of Representatives is now ready to be a genuine partner in this effort.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By heritage and history, America is a Nation of immigrants. Our legislation proposes necessary changes in the law while preserving this tradition. This bill will ensure that immigrant farm workers can live the American dream and contribute to our prosperity, our security, and our values, and I hope very much that it can be enacted as soon as possible in this new Congress.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="Introducing S. 238. A bill to amend title 18, United States Code, to limit the misuse of Social Security numbers, to establish criminal penalties for such misuse, and for other purposes; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="238">S. 238</bill>] Mr. President, I rise to introduce legislation to protect one of Americans' most valuable but vulnerable assets: social security numbers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill I propose is identical to legislation that I introduced last year. This is the fifth Congress in which I have proposed legislation to protect social security numbers. I stand before you again today because I believe that this issue is too important to ignore.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We all know that once a person's social security number is compromised, the path to identity theft is a short one. The Federal Trade Commission estimates that as many as 10 million Americans have their identities stolen each year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The crime takes many forms. Thieves can obtain social security numbers through public records--marriage licenses, professional licenses, and countless other public documents--many of which are available on the internet.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These stolen social security numbers then act like virtual keys, allowing the thieves to unlock an individual's identity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thieves open credit cards and charge them to the max. Often, the victim does not even realize what has happened until they are denied credit in the future because of the unpaid debt on the fraudulent credit cards.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thieves open bank accounts in the victim's name and write bad checks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thieves get driver's licenses or identification cards, and even apply for government benefits in the victim's name.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Identity theft is serious. A person whose identity is stolen can lose thousands of dollars and take months or even years to regain their good name and credit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The damage, loss, and stress of identity theft are considerable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Victims may lose job opportunities, or be denied loans for education, housing, or cars because of negative information on their credit reports. They may even be arrested for crimes they did not commit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The ease with which social security numbers can be accessed is distressing, but also, unnecessary.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Social Security Number Misuse Prevention Act would require government agencies and businesses to do more to protect Americans' social security numbers. The bill would: stop the sale or display of a person's social security number without his or her express consent; prevent Federal, State and local governments from displaying social security numbers on public records posted on the Internet; end the printing of social security numbers on government checks; prohibit the employing of inmates  for tasks that give them access to the social security numbers of other individuals; limit the circumstances in which businesses could ask a customer for his or her social security number; commission a study of the current uses of social security numbers and the impact on privacy and data security; and institute criminal and civil penalties for misuse of social security numbers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation is simple and necessary to stop the growing epidemic of identity theft that has been plaguing America and its citizens.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As we move further into the information age and rely more on information sharing, this problem will only get worse, unless we take action. I urge my colleagues to support the Social Security Number Misuse Prevention Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD. </paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="Introducing S. 239. A bill to require Federal agencies, and persons engaged in interstate commerce, in possession of data containing sensitive personally identifiable information, to disclose any breach of such information; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="239">S. 239</bill>] Mr. President, I rise to introduce the Notification of Risk to Personal Data Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is vitally important that Congress take immediate action to ensure that individuals are notified when companies, Federal agencies, and other institutions suffer security breaches that could jeopardize their personal information.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Notification of Risk to Personal Data Act is a simple, straightforward bill that would require that notice be sent to individuals in the event of a data breach which compromises their personal information.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Providing individuals with knowledge that their personal information has been accessed by a hacker will allow them to take action to prevent or limit the damage caused by these security breaches.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The need for such legislation is, unfortunately, self-evident given the spate of data breaches we have all read and heard about. Unfortunately, almost every week we learn of a new breach.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For example, there have been major data breaches in just the last few months at Boeing, UCLA, the Colorado Department of Human Services, Starbucks, the Chicago Voters' Database, and Akron Children's Hospital.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Given this ongoing problem, it is not surprising that Americans have made it clear that they want Congress to act. A September 2005 CBS News/New York Times national poll on privacy and identity theft found that 89 percent of Americans are "concerned" about the theft of their personal identity information and 68 percent of Americans feel that Congress should do more to regulate personal data and its collection.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>According to the Federal Trade Commission identity theft affects approximately 10 million Americans each year. In 2004, there were 635,173 identity theft and fraud complaints made to the Federal Trade Commission's Consumer Sentinel. In 2004, identity fraud cost Americans $52.6 billion dollars. Over the past 2 years, approximately 18 million individuals in this country have been exposed or affected by identity theft.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Data breaches threaten individual's economic and emotional well being. A person whose identity is stolen can lose thousands of dollars and it can take months or even years for a person to regain their good name and credit. So when a data breach occurs, people have a right to find out as soon as possible.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is why I have introduced and tried to pass legislation that would: require that the Federal Government and business entities notify individuals when there has been a security breach involving their personal data; ensure that the notice is provided without unreasonable delay; create very limited exceptions to notification for national security and law enforcement purposes, as well as instances in which law enforcement certifies that there is no threat of harm to the individual; provide civil  remedies against those who do not notify individuals and the provisions of the bill would be enforced by State attorney generals; and pre-empt all state laws so that there is a single, nationwide notification requirement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I strongly believe that individuals have a right to be notified when their most sensitive information is compromised--because it is truly their information.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The instant legislation will give all Americans more control and confidence about the safety of their sensitive personal information. They will know when their data has been compromised so that they take the appropriate steps to protect themselves.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In November 2005, the Judiciary Committee approved the Personal Data Privacy and Security Act. That bill included similar notification legislation. Unfortunately, the Senate took no further action and the bill expired at the end of the 109th Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since then, the problem of identity theft has worsened--there have been numerous large scale data security breaches involving companies, federal agencies, and universities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We cannot afford to keep waiting to act. I urge the Senate to pass the Notification of Risk to Personal Data Act to give Americans the information they need to protect themselves from identity theft.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300029" topic="Introducing S. 239. A bill to require Federal agencies, and persons engaged in interstate commerce, in possession of data containing sensitive personally identifiable information, to disclose any breach of such information; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I am today introducing, along with Senators DOMENICI, BINGAMAN, ENZI, STEVENS, BENNETT, MURKOWSKI, and BUNNING, the National Geologic Maping Reauthorization Act of 2007. This is an act that has been very beneficial to the Nation and deserves to be reauthorized.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The National Geologic Mapping Act was originally signed into law in 1992, creating the National Cooperative Geologic Mapping Program (NCGMP). This program exists as a partnership between the USGS and the State geological surveys, whose purpose is to provide the Nation with urgently-needed geologic maps that can be and are used by a diverse clientele. These maps are vital to understanding groundwater regimes, mineral resources, geologic hazards such as landslides and earthquakes, and geology essential  for all types of land use planning; as well as providing basic scientific data. The NCGMP contains three parts; FedMap--the U.S. Geological Survey's geologic mapping program, StateMap--the State geological survey's part of the act, and EdMap--a program to encourage the training of future geologic mappers at our colleges and universities. All three components are reviewed annually by a Federal Advisory Committee to ensure program effectiveness and to provide future guidance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>FedMap geologic mapping priorities are determined by the needs of Federal land-management agencies, regional customer forums, and cooperatively with the State geological surveys. FedMap also coordinates national geologic mapping standards. StateMap is a competitive program wherein the States submit proposals for geologic mapping that are critiqued by a peer review panel. A requirement of this section of the legislation is that each Federal dollar be matched one-for-one with State funds. Each  participating State has a State Advisory Committee to ensure that its proposal addresses priority areas and needs as determined in the NGMA. The success of this program ensured reauthorization of similar legislation in 1997 and in 1999 with widespread bipartisan support in both the House and Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To date, millions of dollars been awarded to State geological surveys through StateMap, and these Federal dollars have been more than matched by State dollars. The high quality geologic maps produced will be used by a very broad base of customers including geotechnical consultants, Federal, State and local land managers, and mineral and energy exploration companies. Information on how to obtain all of these maps is provided on the Internet by the National Geologic Map Database, allowing ease  of access for all users.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>EdMap has trained over 550 university students at 118 universities across the Nation. The best testament to the quality of this training are its beneficiaries--an unusually high percentage of these students go on to careers in Earth Science, becoming university professors, energy company exploration scientists, or mapping specialists themselves. Their EdMap program experience provides them with a remarkable self-confidence, having completed a difficult and independent field mapping experience.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The National Geologic Mapping Reauthorization Act benefits numerous citizens every day by assuring there is accurate, usable geologic information available to communities and individuals so that safe, educated resource use decisions can be made. I encourage my colleagues to support this legislation and am committed to its timely consideration.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300100" topic="Introducing S. 241. A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to enter into cooperative agreements to protect natural resources of units of the National Park System through collaborative efforts on land inside and outside of units of the National Park System; to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="241">S. 241</bill>] Mr. President, today I introduce legislation to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to enter into cooperative agreements to protect National Parks through collaborative efforts on lands inside and outside of National Park System units. My bill passed the Senate in the 109th Congress, but unfortunately did not have an opportunity to pass in the House before the end of the Congress. Today, I reintroduce the bill hoping that it can expeditiously pass again in the Senate and continue  on to pass in the House.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation is based on very successful watershed protection legislation enacted for the Forest Service and the Bureau of Land Management, now commonly referred to as the Wyden amendment. The Wyden amendment, first enacted in 1998 for Fiscal Year 1999, has resulted in countless Forest Service and Bureau of Land Management cooperative agreements with neighboring state and local land owners to accomplish high priority restoration, protection and enhancement work on public and private lands.  It has not required additional funding, but has allowed the agencies to leverage their scarce restoration dollars thereby allowing the Federal dollars to stretch farther.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation I introduce today will allow the Park Service to use a similar authority to attack natural threats to National Parks, such as invasive weeds, before they cross onto Parks' land. The National Park Service tells me that if they have to wait until the weeds hit the Parks before treating them the costs for treatment rise exponentially and the probability of beating the weeds back drops exponentially.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Examples of projects the National Park Service would pursue with this authority, as well as the groups with which they would partner, are attached. I am pleased that Senator AKAKA is joining me as an original co-sponsor of this legislation and I hope my other colleagues will join me as co-sponsors of this legislation and in ensuring its swift passage. I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill and a list of projects be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300037" topic="STATE: WYOMING">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I have come to the floor for just a couple of minutes to describe a piece of legislation that I and Senator OLYMPIA SNOWE have introduced today with 30 of our colleagues in the Senate dealing with the issue of drug reimportation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent to show on the floor of the Senate a couple of bottles.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300037" topic="STATE: WYOMING">
    <paragraph>I would like to show two bottles that contained Lipitor, a drug that most of us know is a cholesterol-lowering drug. Lipitor is made by a company in a plant--in this case in Ireland--and in Ireland they put Lipitor in these two bottles, and they send the Lipitor in this bottle to Canada, and they send the Lipitor in this bottle to the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The difference? Well, there is no difference. It is the same pill, put in the same bottle, made by the same company, an FDA-approved drug. The difference is the United States consumer pays 65 percent more for this drug than the consumer in Canada.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But it is not just Lipitor. And it is not just a plant in Ireland by this company that produces it and sends it to here and then to Canada, and charges the American consumer the highest prices. It is virtually all of the brand drugs. And in virtually every case, the American consumer is paying the highest prices for prescription drugs--the highest prices in the world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My colleague, Senator Snowe and I and many others in this Chamber--Senator Stabenow, Senator Kennedy, Senator McCain, and so many others--30 Senators have introduced this legislation that allows the reimportation of FDA-approved drugs--produced in FDA-inspected plants--allows the reimportation of those lower priced prescription drugs into this country. It allows American consumers to take advantage of the global economy by buying that FDA-approved drug where  it is sold for a fraction of the price.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One day, some while ago, on a beautiful summer day, outside of Oakes, ND, I was meeting with a group of farmers. At this farmyard, we were sitting on bales of straw and having a long discussion, and there was one older fellow there in his eighties, early eighties. He said to me: My wife has been suffering from breast cancer for 3 years. She is an elderly woman battling breast cancer now for 3 years. For 3 years, we have driven from the southern part of North Dakota into Canada to buy Tamoxifen  for my wife to treat this breast cancer. She needs this medicine to fight the breast cancer, and the only way we can afford it is for us to get in the car and drive to Canada and buy Tamoxifen at 20 percent of the price we would have to pay in this country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>American consumers should not have to do that. They ought to be allowed to reimport prescription drugs that are made in FDA-approved plants and are FDA-approved drugs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation we have introduced today is necessary. I do not want American consumers to have to purchase prescription drugs elsewhere. I want them to be able to purchase them in this country at a fair price. The problem is, we are now paying the highest prices in the world. If we allow the reimportation, it will put downward pressure on prices in this country. That is our real goal.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now the Congressional Budget Office has done a study. They tell us that brandname drugs cost 35 to 55 percent less in most other countries than they do in the United States. The AARP, American Association of Retired Persons, has done a study showing the drugs most frequently used by senior citizens in our country have increased by a 6.3-percent price increase from June 2005 to June 2006--double the rate of inflation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Congressional Budget Office estimates that if we pas the legislation we have now introduced today, there will be a savings of about $50 billion in direct savings over the next decade for American consumers, with $6.1 billion of that savings to the Federal budget.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So we believe this is important. We have been blocked from getting this legislation through the Congress for some long while. The leadership of this institution supports it. The legislation is bipartisan--broadly bipartisan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now let me say one other thing. Some people say, and particularly the pharmaceutical industry says, this cannot be done safely, it will jeopardize safety for American consumers. Well, let me say that the consumers in the European countries have been doing this for 20, 25 years. There is something called parallel trading. They have been doing it for 20, 25 years without any issues of safety. If you want to buy a drug in Spain, and you live in France, no problem. If you want to buy a drug in Italy,  and you live in Germany, no problem. They have been doing that--called parallel trading--for 25 years. Surely, we can accomplish that in this country as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me show a couple of charts, briefly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, Americans are charged the highest prices in the world. This one chart compares it to Canada: Lipitor, Prevacid, Zocor, Zoloft, Celebrex. I will not go through the entire list.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dr. Peter Rost, vice president of marketing for Pfizer, came to Washington, and here is what he said:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The biggest argument against reimportation is safety. What everyone has conveniently forgotten to tell you is that in Europe reimportation of drugs has been in place for 20 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He went on to say there is not any issue of safety.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And, finally, the American Association of Retired Persons endorses the legislation we have introduced today. I will not read all of that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But the final chart shows what is happening with respect to spending on prescription drugs, and where it is heading, and why we ought to do something to give consumers the opportunity to see fair prices on prescription drugs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Miracle drugs offer no miracles to those who cannot afford to buy them. I have no brief against the pharmaceutical industry. I want them to keep producing lifesaving, miracle drugs for this country. In fact, we produce a great deal of public spending in the NIH and elsewhere that gives them the research base for which a good number of those drugs is produced.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But let me also say that the pharmaceutical industry owes the American consumer a fair deal. We should not be paying the highest prices in the world for prescription drugs. It is not fair. And if the pharmaceutical industry is going to use a global economy in order to move its commodities and its various ingredients for prescription drugs around the world to produce in Ireland or to produce here or in Puerto Rico, then the American people ought to be able to use the global economy to get a better  price on FDA-approved drugs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have waited a long while. I have worked on this I guess 6 or 8 years. We have been blocked repeatedly from getting a vote in the Congress, both in the House and the Senate. Now we have introduced, with broad, bipartisan support, an identical piece of legislation in the House and in the Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe we will get a vote in both bodies and pass legislation and send it to the President of the United States. It will save $50 billion over the next decade on prescription drug bills for the American people, save the Federal Government $5 billion or $6 billion in spending, and give a fair deal to the American people that they will be able to buy prescription drugs at a fair price.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I look forward to consideration of this measure in the Senate. I am pleased on behalf of my colleague Senator Snowe and myself and a broad group of Republicans and Democrats in the Senate to push this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I see Senator Sanders is here, and I know she has worked on this issue for a long while as well. We have a broad, bipartisan group. We are going to push this and get this done in this session of Congress.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300091" topic="Introducing S. 246. A bill to enhance compliance assistance for small business; to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="246">S. 246</bill>] Mr. President, I have long worked to reduce the burden that Federal regulations bear on small businesses. Over the past twenty years, the number and complexity of Federal regulations have multiplied at an alarming rate. These regulations impose a much more significant impact on small businesses than larger businesses. A recent report prepared for the Small Business Administration's Office of Advocacy found that in 2004, the per-employee cost of Federal regulations for firms with fewer  than 20 employees was $7,647. That was 44.8 percent more than the $5,282 per-employee cost faced by businesses with 500 or more workers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is why today, I rise with Senators Kerry, Enzi, and Landrieu to introduce the Small Business Compliance Assistance Enhancement Act of 2007. Our bill would clarify requirements that exist under Federal law to ensure that agencies produce useful small business compliance guides that explain, in a readable format, the compliance requirements of complex rules. This "small," targeted reform, which would not create any new rules or requirements, would have a major  benefit for small businesses across the country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1996, the Senate passed without opposition the Small Business Regulatory Enforcement Fairness Act (SBREFA) to make the Regulatory Flexibility Act more effective in curtailing the impact of regulations on small businesses. One of the most important provisions of SBREFA is a requirement that agencies produce compliance assistance materials to help small businesses satisfy regulatory obligations. Unfortunately, over the years, agencies have done a poor job of meeting this requirement. The Government  Accountability Office (GAO) has found that agencies have ignored this requirement or failed miserably in their attempts to satisfy it. The GAO has also found that the language of SBREFA is unclear in some places about what is actually required. Consequently, small businesses have been forced to figure out on their own how to comply with these regulations. This makes compliance that much more difficult to achieve, and therefore reduces the effectiveness of the regulation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Small Business Compliance Assistance Enhancement Act of 2007 would close those loopholes and requires agencies to produce quality compliance assistance materials for small businesses. Our bill is drawn directly from the GAO's recommendations and is intended only to clarify an already existing requirement. Similarly, the compliance guides that the agencies will produce are merely suggestions about how to satisfy a regulation's requirements without imposing further requirements or additional  enforcement measures. Nor does this bill, in any way, interfere or undercut an agency's ability to enforce its regulations to the full extent they currently enjoy. Furthermore, our bill was included as part of the Small Business Reauthorization and Improvements Act that was unanimously reported out of the Senate Small Business Committee in the 109th Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>All too often, small businesses do not maintain the staff, or possess the financial resources to comply with complex Federal regulations. This puts them at a disadvantage compared to larger businesses, and reduces the effectiveness of the agency's regulations. If an agency cannot describe how to comply with its regulation, how can we expect a small business to figure it out? This was the reason the requirement to provide compliance assistance was originally included in SBREFA, and this rationale  is just as valid today as it was in 1996.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Specifically, our bill would clarify that a small business compliance guide  is required whenever an agency determines that a rule will have "a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities". This would avoid confusion about whether the agency should produce a compliance guide.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second, our bill would also clarify how a guide shall be designated. Under current law, agencies must "designate" the publications prepared under the section as small business compliance guides. However, the form in which those designations should occur is unclear. This term would be changed to "entitle." Consistent use of the phrase "Small Entity Compliance Guide" in the title could make it easier for small entities to locate the guides that the agencies develop. This would also aid in  using on line searches--a technology that was not widely used when SBREFA was passed. Thus, agencies would be directed to publish guides entitled "Small Entity Compliance Guide."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Third, our bill would clarify how a guide shall be published. SBREFA currently requires that agencies "shall publish" the guides, but it does not indicate where or how they should be published. At least one agency has published the guides as part of the preamble to the subject rule, thereby requiring affected small entities to read the Federal Register to obtain the guides. Under our bill, agencies would be directed, at a minimum, to make their compliance guides easily accessible and available  through their websites. In addition, agencies would be directed to forward their compliance guides to known industry contacts such as small businesses or associations with small business members that will be affected by the regulation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Fourth, our bill also clarifies when a guide shall be published. Section 212 of SBREFA currently does not indicate when compliance guides should be published. This means that even if an agency was required to produce a compliance guide, the agency may claim that they have not violated that requirement since there is no deadline established for when they had to produce that guide. Under our bill, agencies would be instructed to publish the compliance guides coincident with, or as soon as possible  after, the final rule is published, provided that the guides must be published no later than the effective date of the rule's compliance requirements.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, our bill would clarify the phrase "compliance requirements." At a minimum, this term means what a small business has to do to satisfy the regulation, and when they will know they have met the requirements. This should include a description of the procedures a small business might employ. If, as is the case with many OSHA and EPA regulations, testing is required, the agency should explain how that testing should be conducted. Our bill makes clear that the procedural description should  be merely suggestive--an agency would not be able to enforce this procedure if a small business was able to satisfy the requirements through a different approach.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300010" topic="Introducing S. 247. A bill to designate the United States courthouse located at 555 Independence Street, Cape Girardeau, Missouri, as the &quot;Rush Hudson Limbaugh, Sr. United States Courthouse&quot;; to the  Committee on Environment and Public Works.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="247">S. 247</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to introduce legislation designating the new Federal Courthouse in Cape Girardeau, MO. as the Rush Hudson Limbaugh, Sr. United States Courthouse.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When people talk about the American Dream, the "Spirit of America" and the people who helped make this country great, all one really has to do is mention the name of the late Rush Hudson Limbaugh Sr.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Limbaugh led an extraordinary life in which he practiced law for almost 80 years until his death at age 104 in 1996. At the time of his death, Mr. Limbaugh was the Nation's oldest practicing lawyer and still came into work about twice a week at the law firm he founded over 50 years before in Cape Girardeau, MO.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Known by his peers as a superb trial lawyer with impeccable character and integrity, he was a beloved icon of the Missouri legal community, especially in Southeast Missouri where he lived all his life.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Born in 1891, on a small farm in rural Bollinger County, he was the youngest of eight children and attended school in a one room primary school house. It is said that a passion for the law first developed in Rush as a 10-year-old boy when a Daniel Webster Oration that he memorized inspired him to become a lawyer. Fourteen years later, he began a legal career that lasted eight decades. Throughout those 80 years, his interest in the law and his dedication to his clients never wavered.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rush paid his way through college at the University of Missouri at Columbia by working on the university farm and doing odd jobs such as carpentry, firing up furnaces, caring for animals and waiting tables. While in college, his oratory skills won him awards which he later utilized with great success in the courtroom.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1914, he entered law school, and after two years, he skipped the third year and passed the Missouri Bar examination. In 1916, he was admitted into the Missouri Bar and his long distinguished legal career began in Cape Girardeau.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over his career, Rush argued more than 60 cases in front of the Missouri Supreme Court along with many prominent civil cases. He was a specialist in probate law and helped draft the 1955 Probate Code of Missouri. He also tried cases before the Interstate Commerce Commission, the U.S. Labor Board and the Internal Revenue Appellate Division.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>From 1955 through 1956, he was President of the Missouri Bar and later served as President of the State Historical Society of Missouri. In addition to this, Mr. Limbaugh was a leading member of numerous legal and civic organizations including the American Bar Association, the Missouri Bar Foundation, the Missouri Human Rights Commission, the Cape Girardeau Board of Education and the Salvation Army Advisory Board</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, Rush's contributions were not just limited to Missouri. In the late 1950's, Rush served as a U.S. State Department special envoy to India where he promoted American jurisprudence and constitutional government among lawyers, judges and university students in that newly formed country. And in the 1960's, he served as Chairman of the American Bar Association's special committee on the Bill of Rights.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rush was truly an inspiration and mentor to many aspiring lawyers, especially the ones in his own family. His two sons, Rush Jr. and Steven, both practiced law with him for many years. His son, Steven N. Limbaugh, currently serves as a Senior Federal Judge in St. Louis. Four of his grandsons followed in his footsteps and pursued legal careers including his grandson Steven Jr. who is now a Missouri Supreme Court Justice.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Perhaps the best measure of Rush Hudson Limbaugh' legacy as a lawyer and as a human being comes from the praise and admiration of his peers in the legal community. "A top notch all-around lawyer; the epitome of what a lawyer ought to be said one colleague. "A legend in his time," said another.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, his grandson Steven may have offered the best possible description of this great citizen: "He was an extraordinary man, exemplary in every way, yet very humble. He was a lawyer's lawyer, a community servant and a gentle and kind man whose family was the very center of his life."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is only fitting that the new Federal courthouse in Cape Girardeau, Missouri be named after this great hero of American Jurisprudence.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of this bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="Introducing S. 248. A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to permanently extend and modify the work opportunity credit, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="248">S. 248</bill>] President, I am pleased to join my Colleague, Senator Snowe, in introducing legislation to improve and permanently extend the Work Opportunity and the Welfare-to-Work tax credits. Last year, I was pleased to help enact legislation that consolidated, streamlined, and extended these credits through the end of 2007. Now it is time to make these tax credits permanent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The current extension expires at the end of this year. So immediate action is needed to make these credits permanent and make several improvements to the programs to improve their effectiveness. Recurring lapses and extensions make administration of this credit burdensome both for the taxpaying employer, who cannot keep track of who is or is not qualified, and for the IRS, which needs to ensure that taxpayers are complying with the ever-shifting law. Last year, the program lapsed until late December,  when Congress finally passed a retroactive extension.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over the past decade, the Work Opportunity Tax Credit, WOTC, and the Welfare-to-Work credits have helped more than 2.2 million public assistance dependent individuals to enter the workforce. These hiring tax incentives have demonstrated their effectiveness. They help to level the job selection playing field for low-skilled individuals. They provide employers with additional resources to help recruit, select, train and retain individuals with significant barriers to work. Many vulnerable individuals  still need a boost in finding employment. And this is particularly important during periods of high unemployment. Without an extension of these programs, the task of transitioning from welfare-to-work will become even harder for individuals who reach their welfare eligibility ceiling.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of the costs involved in setting up and administering a WOTC and Welfare-to-Work program, employers have established massive outreach programs to maximize the number of eligible persons in their hiring pool. The States, in turn, have steadily improved the programs through improved administration. WOTC has become an example of a true public-private partnership design to assist the most needy applicants. Without the additional resources provided by these hiring tax incentives, few employers  would actively seek out this hard-to-employ population.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The new combined WOTC and Welfare-to-Work credits provide employers with a graduated tax credit equal to 25 percent of the first $6,000 in wages for eligible individuals working between 120 hours and 399 hours and a 40-percent tax credit on the first $6,000 in wages for those working more than 400 hours. In the category of longterm welfare recipients, employers receive a maximum credit of $4,000, or 40 percent of qualified first year wages up to $10,000. Employers receive a maximum credit of</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In my home State of Montana, many businesses take advantage of this program, including large multinational firms and smaller family-owned businesses. Those who truly benefit from the WOTC and Welfare-to-Work program, however, are low-income families under the Food Stamp Program, the Aid to Families with Dependent Children, AFDC, and Temporary Assistance for Needy Families, TANF, programs, and also low income U.S. Veterans. In Montana, more than 1,000 people were certified as eligible under the  WOTC program during an 18-month period, October 2001 through March 2003, including 476 Food Stamp recipients, 475 AFDC or TANF recipients, and 52 U.S. veterans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill that we are introducing today provides for a permanent program extension of the combined credits. After a decade of experience with WOTC and Welfare-to- Work, we know that employers do respond to these important hiring tax incentives. Permanent extension would provide these programs with greater stability, thereby encouraging more employers to participate, make investments in expanding outreach to identify potential workers from the targeted groups, and avoid the wasteful disruption  of termination and renewal. A permanent extension would also encourage the state job services to invest the resources needed to make the certification process more efficient and employer-friendly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, there are other changes in the bill that would extend these benefits to more people and help them find work. One change would increase the age of eligibility for those individuals seeking work who reside in enterprise zones or empowerment communities. Another change would include referrals from the Ticket to Work program in the Vocational Rehabilitation category. These two changes are modest improvements to the program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Further, this bill adds a new subcategory with an enhanced credit for employers who hire veterans with service-connected disabilities occurring on or after September 11, 2001. As of July 2006, nearly 20,000 members of our Armed Forces were wounded in action in Operation Iraqi Freedom and Operation Enduring Freedom. Many of these veterans are now permanently disabled. Of these brave men and women who have been wounded, nearly 5,000 are members of the National Guard and Reserves. Our National Guard  and Reserves are carrying a huge burden in our current conflicts abroad.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many of these wounded veterans come from rural States such as my home State of Montana. In Montana, we have the highest proportion of veterans per capita of any state. According to the most recent census, veterans account for nearly one out of every six people in Montana. And veterans and families of veterans constitute a significant portion of the population in rural states throughout the country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When not deployed, many National Guardsmen and reservists in Montana support their families with second and even third jobs. At any time, they can be deployed overseas, to our borders, or even to aid with national disasters such as hurricanes or forest fires. If they are injured or disabled, however, many become unable to perform the jobs that they did before deployment. They will need to transition into a new job or career. It is our duty to provide the proper means for veterans to make that  transition. It is our duty to help them to live as independent citizens.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since August 2002, the share of veterans collecting unemployment insurance has nearly doubled. During any given year, half a million veterans across the Nation experience homelessness. We are not providing enough resources for veterans looking for work. We are too often failing our injured and our disabled veterans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many seriously injured and disabled veterans simply do not know what they are going to do once they return home. We need to help these young men and women. And a modest tax incentive to get them back into the workforce is one place to start.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I look forward to working with Senator Snowe to get a permanent work incentive for these individuals. And I encourage our Colleagues to join us in this effort.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="Introducing S. 249. A bill to permit the National Football League to restrict the movement of its franchises, and for other purposes; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="249">S. 249</bill>] Mr. President, last November, John York, the owner of the San Francisco 49ers, announced his intention to move the team to Santa Clara.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The 49ers have been an integral part of San Francisco for the past 60 years. The team was founded in 1946 as part of the All-American Football Conference and joined the National Football League in 1950, when the two leagues merged.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The team's name is derived from the city's history, celebrating the miners who rushed to San Francisco in search of gold in 1849 and helped build the city.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The team has been a part of San Francisco for so long, and is such a central part of its culture, that the prospect of the team leaving concerns many of the people of San Francisco.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In response, I am introducing the Football Fairness Act that provides a new and limited antitrust exemption that is designed to slow the frequent movement of National Football League teams and prevent communities from suffering the financial and intangible costs of these moves.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As Mayor of San Francisco, I had the pleasure of witnessing several 49ers' Super Bowl victory parades.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What I remember most about those victories is the way the team's success brought the city together. I've also seen other cities unite in celebration of their teams' championships.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our football teams are more than just businesses. They are a common denominator that cut across class, race, and gender to bond the people of a city. They are a key component of a city's culture and identity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are instances where a city cannot support a team, but it is disheartening when a city that can--and does--support a team is nevertheless abandoned and the loyalty of the fans discarded.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1985, then 49ers owner Eddie DeBartolo explored the possibility of moving the team to San Jose. As Mayor of San Francisco, I worked with the 49ers and we were able to reach an agreement to keep the team in San Francisco.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, I remain hopeful that an agreement to keep the team will be reached that will benefit the people of San Francisco and the 49ers' organization.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, this situation highlights a broader trend of NFL teams abandoning cities after those communities invested substantial funds and good will into a team.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This persistent movement is bad for our cities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the last 25 years, National Football League teams have moved 7 times: Oakland Raiders to Los Angeles in 1982, Baltimore Colts to Indianapolis in 1984, St. Louis Cardinals to Tempe in 1988, Los Angeles Rams to St. Louis in 1994, Los Angeles Raiders to Oakland in 1994, Cleveland Browns to Baltimore in 1996, and Houston Oilers to Nashville in 1997.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, during that same time period only 1 Major League Baseball franchise moved. In 2004, with the approval of Major League Baseball, the Montreal Expos became the Washington Nationals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Why has there been stability in baseball, while National Football League teams have moved so frequently?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unlike the NFL, Major League Baseball has an antitrust exemption which gives the league and its owners control over the movement of its teams.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When the Oakland Raiders sought to relocate to Los Angeles in 1982, the National Football League's owners voted to prevent the move. However, the courts found that the NFL's intervention was a violation of antitrust laws, and the League could do nothing to prevent the Raiders from moving.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Just 12 years later, the Raiders left Los Angeles to return to the same city and stadium it had abandoned.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If a city is incapable of supporting a team, it is understandable that a franchise would move. However, of the six cities that have seen National Football League teams leave in the last 25 years, five of those cities later received another NFL franchise.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is clear that NFL teams are not moving because cities cannot support teams.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To address the real costs imposed on communities by the persistent and unnecessary franchise movement that we  have witnessed, I am introducing the Football Fairness Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Football Fairness Act is straightforward and it is limited.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It would permit the National Football League to review and restrict its teams' movement. This should help keep the fans who support the NFL from being left out of the equation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Act is targeted. It limits the exemption from antitrust laws solely to the National Football League's ability to prevent the movement of its franchises. Consequently, the Act will not diminish competition.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleague to support the Football Fairness Act and help prevent the damage done to fans and communities by frequent NFL franchise movement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300091" topic="Introducing S. 250. A bill to reduce the costs of prescription drugs for Medicare beneficiaries and to guarantee access to comprehensive prescription drug coverage under part D of the Medicare program, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="250">S. 250</bill>] Mr. President, today I join with my colleague and friend Senator RON WYDEN, to introduce legislation which we have sponsored since 2004 to ensure the sound fiscal management of our Medicare prescription drug benefit. Together we both supported the enactment of the Medicare Modernization Act in 2003 (MMA), and we remain committed to seeing our seniors able to rely on a high quality, affordable benefit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today millions of American seniors are at last receiving assistance with the high cost of prescription drugs. For so many, that will make a difference between choosing whether to take needed medications and the other necessities of life. We have indeed come a very long way. We look forward to realizing all the incredible benefits of this coverage as we see the results of more affordable access to prescription drugs--better health for our seniors, and substantial health care savings.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This new benefit marks a milestone for Medicare. And that is an apt analogy because today Part D represents a landmark, not a destination. There is no doubt that this benefit is not all it could or should be, but it is a giant step forward in helping millions of seniors to afford medications which are so essential to health care today. For modem drugs not only treat disease, but actually can prevent its development.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While we have seen this landmark progress, it has not come without difficulty. Yet today seniors are saving substantially on their prescription drugs and we see reports that four of five enrollees are pleased with the assistance they are receiving.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is undoubtedly the help they are getting which has resulted in such satisfaction. Because the confusion, the complexity, and often a lack of oversight on the plans has created some serious consumer issues which we will continue to address. But today the first issue before us is the cost of prescription drugs in the plans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over 3 years ago the Congress was given a price tag for this benefit that was simply unrealistic. Recognizing an absence of cost management, I joined with Senator WYDEN to address the escalating cost projections we were seeing. Today, some say all is well, as we hear that the estimated cost of the benefit declined somewhat from a peak estimate of about $720 billion over 10 years. Yet I must note that some of the reasons for that reduction are too quickly glossed over. Enrollment is lower  than it was estimated to be as more Americans chose to stay in private coverage. We also saw this past year that we failed to reach many of those low income seniors who most needed help. Today as seniors enter their first full year of coverage, we will see a more realistic year--particularly in terms of more beneficiaries facing the donut hole.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have heard estimates that the average senior is saving an average of $1,000 per year, but we should ask how that savings is being achieved. The discovery by many seniors--when they reached the donut hole--that their cost of medications was the same  or even higher than what they paid prior to enrolling in Part D--that should be a red flag that we may not be seeing the purchasing power of seniors harnessed for the savings they deserve.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Back in 2005 the Medicare Actuary had estimated that drug plans would negotiate a discount of about 15 percent off undiscounted retail prices. So last year we were curious--just how were they doing in Maine? My staff compared prices for the top 24 medications used by seniors and found that our plan prices for those medications averaged less than 12 percent below the price any senior could already obtain, by simply walking into a retail pharmacy. That is not even using membership or association  discounts, or using an on-line pharmacy like Drugstore.com--where seniors could obtain better prices. That result--finding a single senior could do better than a plan--is certainly disappointing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That points to a system that is working well in terms of subsidy, but certainly needs to improve in terms of negotiating substantial discounts. But we are told that the cost of the benefit is lower, and that premiums were stable this year. Yet if you ask what stand-alone drug coverage actually costs this  year, CMS will tell you that those premiums have gone up about 10 percent. Not unlike increases in the deductible, the size of the donut hole, and out-of-pocket  expense. As Senator WYDEN and I learned from GAO reports we have received, the prices of drugs used by seniors have inexorably increased since 2000 at two to three times the inflation rate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So the costs of this program will remain a concern. Most of us envisioned that not only would the taxpayer contribute to helping seniors with drug expenses, but we would realize substantial savings from lower prices on prescription drugs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is why Senator WYDEN and I proposed to achieve some balance in the public private partnership which is Part D today, and it is why today we are again introducing the Medicare Enhancements for Needed Drugs Act--the MEND Act. In this drug benefit the HHS Secretary should have a proper role in negotiation. Negotiation, not price setting.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is clear that what the Congress intended to do was to create a true public-private partnership, utilizing competitive forces to bring more choices to seniors--in drugs, benefit plan designs, pharmacies, and more. So seniors can vote with their pocketbooks, and we can see their choices in the market influence the kind of benefit they receive. That is not the same as a system in which the government sets prices, and that is why our legislation specifically bans such a practice. Under our legislation,  the Federal Government cannot set either prices or formularies--that is absolutely clear.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What I believe most of us desire to do is give the present system the best tools to achieve success. That means that the Secretary must have an oversight role. He should be examining performance and pointing out where plans need to improve. But today if he noticed a product on which poor discounts were being achieved, and he attempted to discuss that publicly, he would likely be accused of interference. Further, if a plan reported intransigence in trying to negotiate with a manufacturer, the  Secretary could not respond. That makes no sense. It is a disservice taxpayers, beneficiaries, and the plans as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our legislation rescinds the "non-interference" clause and directs the Secretary to negotiate for any necessary fallback plan, and in addition, to respond to requests for help from plans which cannot obtain reasonable negotiation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have also added two additional areas in which the Secretary must negotiate. First, as the CBO has stated that negotiation of single-source drugs could yield savings, our legislation directs the Secretary to engage in negotiation regarding those unique products. We also know that some drugs exist because the taxpayer provides substantial support to see them developed. The public deserves a fair price on those products it made possible, so the Secretary should weigh in those cases.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, our bill protects beneficiaries by assuring that seniors will have access to a comprehensive coverage option--at least one plan in each region must provide the option to avoid the coverage gap, dreaded "donut hole". Today seniors in 11 States simply cannot obtain such coverage and they must at least have the option of protecting themselves.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These are reasonable ways to help plans succeed, and to protect both beneficiaries and taxpayers within the public-private partnership on which this benefit rests.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I call on my colleagues to join us in this effort, so that we may improve the partnership between private enterprise and the Federal Government in serving our seniors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask consent that the bill's text be printed in the CONGRESSIONAL RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300100" topic="Introducing S. 250. A bill to reduce the costs of prescription drugs for Medicare beneficiaries and to guarantee access to comprehensive prescription drug coverage under part D of the Medicare program, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, Senator Snowe and I said we would work to improve the Medicare Part D benefit ever since we voted for its passage. Senator Snowe and I think one of the most egregious errors in the Medicare drug benefit was to write into law that the Secretary cannot have bargaining power under any circumstances. That is why today we are introducing the Medicare Enhancements for Needed Drugs Act of 2007. This legislation lifts the prohibition on bargaining power and  requires the Secretary to negotiate on behalf of seniors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We believed that one of the most important things missing from the Part D benefit was cost containment--and allowing Medicare to negotiate for drug prices would be an important cost containment measure. Our legislation clearly prohibits price setting or the creation of a uniform formulary. What our legislation allows Medicare to do is to be a smart shopper--just as any consumer would be--by allowing Medicare to go in the market and use its clout just like any other big purchaser.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under our proposal, the Secretary could negotiate in any circumstance, but must negotiate in several instances: for single source drugs for which there is no therapeutic equivalent; drugs for which taxpayer funding was substantial in its research and development; and for any fallback plan the Secretary must provide. In addition, our legislation requires the Secretary to provide a fallback plan if there is not comprehensive coverage, including coverage for the so-called donut hole, available in  a region.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Congressional Budget Office has stated there might be savings achieved if the Secretary could negotiate for single source drugs for which there is no therapeutic equivalent. To be good stewards of taxpayer dollars, to be able to strengthen the program and to help seniors truly save, we must look toward using every logical tool to lower costs. Not to try to achieve lower prices in areas identified as potentially saving the program, taxpayers and seniors would be foolish.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I don't know of a single private entity, whether it's a timber company in my home State of Oregon, or a big auto company, who when they're buying something in bulk doesn't say, hey pal, how about a discount? So why shouldn't Medicare, if it needs to negotiate, have that authority just in case? Why wouldn't we want to assure that Medicare can be a smart shopper?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I look forward to working with my colleagues as the Senate Finance Committee works on this issue.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300042" topic="Introducing S. 252. A bill to repeal the provision of law that provides automatic pay adjustments for Members of Congress; to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="252">S. 252</bill>] Mr. President, I am pleased to reintroduce legislation that would put an end to automatic pay raises for Members of Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As I have noted when I raised this issue in past years, Congress has the authority to raise its own pay, something that most of our constituents cannot do. Because this is such a singular power, Congress ought to exercise it openly, and subject to regular procedures including debate, amendment, and a vote on the record.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But current law allows Congress to avoid that public debate and vote. All that is necessary for Congress to get a pay raise is that nothing be done to stop it. The annual pay raise takes effect unless Congress acts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This stealth pay raise mechanism began with a change Congress enacted in the Ethics Reform Act of 1989. In section 704 of that Act, Members of Congress voted to make themselves entitled to an annual raise equal to half a percentage point less than the employment cost index, one measure of inflation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On occasion, Congress has voted to deny itself the raise, and the traditional vehicle for the pay raise vote is the Treasury appropriations bill. But that vehicle is not always made available to those who want a public debate and vote on the matter. Just last year, for example, the Senate did not consider the Treasury appropriations bill. Instead, we passed a series of continuing resolutions to fund government operations usually addressed in that bill and other appropriations bills that were  not taken up. Because of that, Senators were effectively prevented from offering an amendment to force an up or down vote on the annual pay raise. And that situation was not unique.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As I have noted in the past, getting a vote on the annual congressional pay raise is a haphazard affair at best, and it should not be that way. The burden should not be on those who seek a public debate and recorded vote on the Member pay raise. On the contrary, Congress should have to act if it decides to award itself a hike in pay. This process of pay raises without accountability must end.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This issue is not a new question. It was something that our Founders considered from the beginning of our Nation. In August of 1789, as part of the package of 12 amendments advocated by James Madison that included what has become our Bill of Rights, the House of Representatives passed an amendment to the Constitution providing that Congress could not raise its pay without an intervening election. On September 9, 1789, the Senate passed that amendment. In late September of 1789, Congress submitted  the amendments to the States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although the amendment on pay raises languished for two centuries, in the 1980s, a campaign began to ratify it. While I was a member of the Wisconsin State Senate, I was proud to help ratify the amendment. Its approval by the Michigan legislature on May 7, 1992, gave it the needed approval by three-fourths of the States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The 27th Amendment to the Constitution now states: "No law, varying the compensation for the services of the senators and representatives, shall take effect, until an election of representatives shall have intervened."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I honor that limitation. Throughout my 6-year term, I accept only the rate of pay that Senators receive on the date on which I was sworn in as a Senator. And I return to the Treasury any additional income Senators get, whether from a cost-of-living adjustment or a pay raise we vote for ourselves. I don't take a raise until my bosses, the people of Wisconsin, give me one at the ballot box. That is the spirit of the 27th Amendment. The stealth pay raises like the one that Congress allowed for 2006  certainly violate the spirit of that amendment at the very least.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This practice must end and this bill will end it. Senators and Congressmen should have to vote up-or-down to raise Congressional pay, and my bill would require just that. We owe our constituents nothing less.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300063" topic="Introducing S. 253. A bill to permit the cancellation of certain loans under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="253">S. 253</bill>] Mr. President, it gives me great pleasure to introduce the Disaster Loan Fairness Act of 2007. This legislation strikes provisions contained in the Community Disaster Loan Act of 2005 and the Emergency Supplemental spending bill for hurricane relief, which prohibited forgiveness of Special Community Disaster Loans authorized in those measures.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Section 417 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act requires forgiveness of a loan if an independent audit determines that its recipient cannot sustain its repayment obligations after a 3-year grace period. The statute recognizes the very real possibility that hard-hit communities may need to be excused from repayment. For the first time in the history of the program though, forgiveness was specifically prohibited by the Community Disaster Loan Act of 2005. These  were the strictest terms ever required. Clamping down in the wake of the worst disaster in history did not make sense at the time, and it does not make sense now.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the last Congress, I introduced <bill type="s" number="1872">S. 1872</bill>, which eliminated this provision governing the first round of loans authorized in October of 2005. Louisiana applicants received about $739 million in this first round. This bill accomplishes that same objective, and also strikes forgiveness restrictions attached to a second  round of loans authorized in June of 2006, through which Louisianans received about $261 million in Orleans, St. Bernard, and St. Tammany Parishes. These recipients in the second round included sheriffs, fire districts, levee districts, school boards, sewage and water boards, port harbor and terminal authorities, regional transit authorities and parish governments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Essential operational expenditures must be made to facilitate recovery in the wake of a disaster, including services like police, fire protection, transit and sanitation. One of the great ironies of the Community Disaster Loan Program is the fact that it exists largely to supplement shortcomings in the Stafford Act. Between 1970 and 1974, the program was administered as a grant program before the Stafford Act converted it to a loan program. FEMA will not reimburse emergency responders for their  straight-time salaries, and a large portion of these loans were needed for payroll expenses to essential employees.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill does not necessarily forgive all loans made to hurricane-affected communities. Communities must apply for cancellation, and forgiveness is only permitted when an independent review of a city's fiscal health finds justification to cancel the debt. Even then, communities must still repay loan funds used for capital improvements, debt servicing, assessments, intragovernmental services, cost-sharing and otherwise reimbursable activities. It is also important to remember that the size of  the loans has been limited to a proportion of the community's operating budget since these programs were first authorized.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The majority of disaster loans have been repaid, and the program is used only by areas that have suffered a major disaster. In 29 years, the program has only received 64 applications associated with 21 disasters. Compared to 1,104 disasters declared in total, that is a very small proportion. There were no loans issued under this authority for 6 years prior to FY 2005. These figures indicate that this program has not been abused by jurisdictions that could do without the funds. Program administrators  and independent auditors have found cause to cancel 93 percent of loan funding distributed to hard-hit areas over the years, but this represents the inevitable fact that disasters can be catastrophic, and areas requiring significant help are less likely to be whole again after only 3 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The City of New Orleans was forced to lay off 3,000 people--over 80 percent of its workforce. Let us act now to ensure that other cities are not forced to follow, by giving a break to disaster loan recipients who prove unable to repay their debt. They will still have 3 years to try, and some may succeed, but we must adjust to the reality of the situation. It is time we relieve Gulf Coast communities of the burdens they were forced to shoulder in order to keep police cars, fire trucks and sanitation  trucks rolling, reopen schools and bring cities back to life by getting things working.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300036" topic="Introducing S. 255. A bill to provide assistance to the State of New Mexico for the development of comprehensive State water plans, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="255">S. 255</bill>] Mr. President, water is the life's blood for New Mexico. When the water dries up in New Mexico, so will many of its communities. As such, the scarcity of water in New Mexico is a dire situation. Unfortunately, the New Mexico Office of the State Engineer (NM OSE) lacks the tools necessary to undertake the Herculean task of effectively managing New Mexico's water resources.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, I introduce legislation that would allow New Mexico to make informed decisions about its limited water resources.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In order to effectively perform water rights administration, as well as comply with New Mexico's compact deliveries, the State Engineer is statutorily required to perform assessments and investigations of the numerous stream systems and ground water basins located within New Mexico. However, the NM OSE is ill equipped to vigorously and comprehensively undertake the daunting but critically important task of water resource planning. At present, the NM OSE lacks adequate resources to perform necessary  hydrographic surveys and data collection. As such, ensuring a future water supply for my home state requires that Congress provide the NM OSE with the resources necessary to fulfill its statutory mandate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill I introduce today would create a standing authority for the State of New Mexico to seek and receive technical assistance from the Bureau of Rec1amation and the United States Geological Survey. It would also provide the NM OSE the sum of $12.5 million in federal assistance to perform hydrologic models of New Mexico's most important water systems. This bill would provide the NM OSE with the best resources available when making crucial decisions about how best preserve our limited water  stores.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ever decreasing water supplies in New Mexico have reached critical leve1s and require immediate action. The Congress cannot sit idly by as water shortages cause death to New  Mexico's communities. I hope the Senate will give this legislation its every consideration. I thank Senator Bingaman, Chairman of the Energy and Natural Resources Committee for cosponsoring this important legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
</record>
