<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1204909201" ordinal="26" title="NATIONAL SLEEP AWARENESS WEEK">
  <narrative>NATIONAL SLEEP AWARENESS WEEK -- (Senate - March 07, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="1736">S1736</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300058" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today I wish to recognize March 8, 2008, as Suddenly Sleepy Saturday--A Day of Narcolepsy Awareness, part of National Sleep Awareness Week. Sleep is an integral part of health and overall well-being, and its importance cannot be stressed enough. Sleep disorders present a chronic health threat that can compromise normal physical, mental, and emotional functioning. There are an estimated 135,000 Americans suffering from narcolepsy, and half of that total remains undiagnosed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Narcolepsy is a chronic disorder, which causes excessive daytime sleepiness, irresistible sleep attacks, and cataplexy--a loss of muscle tone, hypnagogic hallucinations, sleep paralysis, and disrupted nighttime sleep in women, men, and children of all ethnic backgrounds. Symptoms often begin in the teen years and increase over time. Undiagnosed narcolepsy can impair educational goals, relationships, career success, and even one's independence.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Suddenly Sleepy Saturday is an effort to lead the estimated 65,000 Americans who are living with undiagnosed narcolepsy to a proper diagnosis and treatment. This day of awareness will allow for expanding knowledge of life with narcolepsy and will allow participating communities to better support people who struggle with the challenges of this chronic neurological disorder. I am pleased that many South Dakotans, including those in Aberdeen, SD, will be commemorating Suddenly Sleepy Saturday and  raising awareness of narcolepsy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge all citizens to support the search for the cause, cure, and prevention of narcolepsy and assist those individuals and families who deal with this devastating disorder on a daily basis.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
