<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1192723202" ordinal="23" title="SHERIDAN CONSERVATION EASEMENT DEDICATION">
  <narrative>SHERIDAN CONSERVATION EASEMENT DEDICATION -- (Senate - October 18, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="13074">S13074</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, recently I got to participate in the dedication of the first conservation easement in Sheridan County, WY. I attended grade school in Sheridan and graduated from high school there. I earned the Boy Scout merit badges I needed to become an Eagle Scout while I lived there. One of the badges was bicycling. It required several 25-mile rides. My first ride of that length went from Sheridan to Big Horn and beyond. That ride was on the highway. Today it would be much more dangerous  as the area has developed and more people drive. So I am glad for this new conservation easement--what I hope will be the first of many conservation easements--that will make it possible to go from Sheridan to Big Horn on a scenic path by the river that will provide safety and great views.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to congratulate the Volunteers of America for their great role in this achievement and "first." I want to thank and congratulate the Sheridan County Commission and the city of Sheridan, mayor and council for their great cooperation. I especially want to thank the members of the Sheridan Land Trust for their effort and vision. This is the kind of community, the kind of people, I remember growing up in Sheridan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I was glad to play a small role in getting the 501c(3) certification for nonprofit status pushed through the system. I also did some work for conservation easements in, of all places, the pension bill last year. I got to chair the conference committee for the pension bill last year. At the end of the process, leadership from both sides of the aisle brought me a small tax package to include. I mentioned that I had a couple of small provisions I wanted included. One was a provision to get Wyoming  abandoned mine land money released back to Wyoming. I found the power of a chairmanship. The abandoned mine land money will amount to $1.6 billion for Wyoming. Another provision included was for conservation easements--conservation easements that would make it possible for the average person to participate as</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is very important that I share with the Nation the words of Mayor Kinsky at the dedication of this first conservation easement in Sheridan County. It is the finest description of what we are trying to do that I have heard. Here is what he said:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Look about you--the mountains, the creek, the wildlife. It is as God made it. This is how it was before we came. Because of what we do here today--preserving this place as it is, unspoiled--it will be here for those who follow us.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are those who say we inherited this place from our grandparents. I believe we are borrowing it from our grandchildren.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As such, we have a duty to preserve--for them--the beauty that had drawn us here, and holds us here.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Fifty years from now, the town will have changed. Coffeen Avenue will look different, our downtown will look different. But this area will look as we see it today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Future generations will not recall who we are, or what we say. But they will recap the benefit of what we do here today. We may hope that they will look out on what we have left them and say, "These were people of vision. These were people who cared about the future."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is proper that this be done in a manner fitting of the character of our people. This easement comes about not as a mandate of government, but as a gift--given with love--to the community and future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the Sheridan Community Land Trust is to hold such gifts, preserving them for our heirs. It is our hope that many more in the community may be moved to make similar gifts to generations to come.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With history the final judge or our deeds, we ask God's blessing and help, but knowing here on earth God's work must truly be our own.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mayor Kinsky, thank you for those words. May they serve as a challenge and example to everyone to do what you and the greater Sheridan community have done.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
