<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1207152003" ordinal="40" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <narrative>AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET -- (Senate - April 02, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="2364">S2364</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, April 2, 2008, at 2:30 p.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENVIRONMENT AND PUBLIC WORKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Environment and Public Works be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, April 2, 2008, at 10 a.m. in room 406 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building to hold a hearing entitled, "Oversight on the Listing Decision for the Polar Bear Under Endangered Species Act."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, April 2, 2008, at 9:30 a.m. to hold a hearing on Iraq.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, April 2, 2008, at 2:30 p.m. to hold a hearing on Iraq.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="COMMITTEE ON HOMELAND SECURITY AND GOVERNMENTAL AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, April 2, 2008, at 11 a.m. to conduct a hearing entitled "Nuclear Terrorism: Assessing the Threat to the Homeland."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate, to conduct a hearing entitled "Oversight of the Department of Homeland Security" on Wednesday, April 2, 2008, at 9:30 a.m., in room SH-216 of the Hart Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Honorable Michael Chertoff, Secretary, United States Department of Homeland Security, Washington, D.C.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="READINESS AND MANAGEMENT SUPPORT SUBCOMMITTEE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Readiness and Management Support Subcommittee of the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, April 2, 2008, at 2:30 p.m., in open session to receive testimony on Department of Defense contracting in Iraq and Afghanistan.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON EMERGING THREATS AND CAPABILITIES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on Emerging Threats and Capabilities of the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, April 2, 2008, at 10 a.m., in open session to receive testimony on the Cooperative Threat Reduction Program; and the proliferation security initiative at the Department of Defense and Nuclear Nonproliferation Programs at the National Nuclear Security Administration in review of the  Defense authorization request for fiscal year 2009 and the future years Defense program.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
