<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1168621202" ordinal="15" title="LEGISLATIVE TRANSPARENCY AND ACCOUNTABILITY ACT OF 2007--Continued">
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that on Tuesday, January 16, at 5:30 p.m., the Senate proceed to a vote on or in relation to the Durbin amendment No. 44, to be followed by a vote on or in relation to the DeMint amendment No. 11, as amended, if amended, and then without further intervening action or debate, the Senate proceed to a vote on the motion to invoke cloture on amendment No. 14; that if the Durbin amendment is not modified to Senator DeMint's satisfaction, then  the agreement with respect to a vote with respect to the two amendments be vitiated.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to spread on the RECORD the fact that we have had long conversations with Senator DeMint and Senator Durbin. I have spoken personally with Senator DeMint on several occasions. We appreciate his cooperation. I believe what we have done here preserves what he wanted to do and more. So this should make everyone happy on Tuesday. We hope this will be an overwhelmingly positive vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also note that staff, during this evening and during Tuesday, is also going to continue to work on other matters to see if there are other items on which we can vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that my amendment No. 4 be the pending business.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I send a cloture motion to the desk with respect to this amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The cloture motion having been presented under rule XXII, the Chair directs the clerk to read the motion.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I now send to the desk a cloture motion on the substitute amendment, amendment No. 3.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The cloture motion having been presented under rule XXII, the Chair directs the clerk to read the motion.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, finally, I send to the desk a cloture motion on the bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The cloture motion having been presented under rule XXII, the Chair directs the clerk to read the motion.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the live quorum with respect to each cloture motion be waived and that Monday, January 15, count as the intervening day with respect to the cloture motion on amendment No. 4.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the pending amendment be set aside, and I ask that it be in order to call up amendments on behalf of other Senators en bloc, and that after reporting they be laid aside:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Amendment No. 54 to amendment No. 3 for Senator Feingold; amendment No. 43 to amendment No. 3 for Senator Lieberman; and amendment No. 56 to amendment No. 3 for Mr. Casey.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered. The clerk will report.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
</record>
