<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1172682003" ordinal="41" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="COMMITTEE ON BANKING, HOUSING, AND URBAN AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President,    I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, February 28, 2007, at 10:30 a.m. to conduct a hearing on "Examining the Terrorism Risk Insurance Program."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold a hearing during the sessions of the Senate on Wednesday, February 28, 2007, at 10 a.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building. The purpose of the  hearing is to evaluate vehicle safety for children.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science and Transportation be authorized to hold a hearing during the sessions of the Senate on Wednesday, February 28, 2007, at 2:30 p.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building. The purpose of the hearing is to discuss and evaluate the Fiscal Year 2008 budget for the National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND NATURAL RESOURCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, February 28, 2007, at 9:45 a.m. in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building. The purpose of the hearing is to consider the President's fiscal year 2008 budget request for the USDA Forest Service.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to conduct a hearing on "Comprehensive Immigration Reform" on Wednesday, February 28, 2007 at 10 a.m. in Hart Senate Office Building Room 216.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Witness List: The Honorable Carlos M. Gutierrez, Secretary, U.S. Department of Commerce, Washington, DC; The Honorable Michael Chertoff, Secretary, U.S. Department of Homeland Security, Washington, DC.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="COMMITTEE ON RULES AND ADMINISTRATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Rules and Administration be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, February 28, 2007, at 9:30 a.m., to conduct a markup on the Omnibus Budget for Senate Committees.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="COMMITTEE ON SMALL BUSINESS AND ENTREPRENEURSHIP">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate for a hearing entitled "The President's Fiscal Year 2008 Budget Request for the Small Business Administration," on Wednesday, February 28, 2007, beginning at 10 a.m. in Room 428A of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="JOINT ECONOMIC COMMITTEE">
    <paragraph>Mr President, I ask unanimous consent that the Joint Economic Committee be authorized to conduct a hearing in Room 562 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building, Wednesday, February 28, 2007, from 9:30 a.m. to 12:30 p.m.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="SPECIAL COMMITTEE ON AGING">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Special Committee on Aging be authorized to meet Wednesday, February 28, 2007, from 10:30 a.m.-12:30 p.m. in Dirksen 628 for the purpose of conducting a hearing. Re: The Aging Workforce: What Does It Mean for Businesses and the Economy.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
