<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1195232402" ordinal="90" title="THE JOHN &quot;MARTY&quot; THIELS SOUTHPARK STATION">
  <narrative>THE JOHN "MARTY" THIELS SOUTHPARK STATION -- (Senate - November 16, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="14657">S14657</bill>]</narrative>
  <narrative>The bill (<bill type="s" number="2272">S. 2272</bill>) to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service known as the Southpark Station in Alexandria, Louisiana, as the John "Marty" Thiels Southpark Station, in honor and memory of Thiels, a Louisiana postal worker who was killed in the line of duty on October 4, 2007, was considered, ordered to be engrossed for a third reading, read the third time, and passed, as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="s" number="2272">S. 2272</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. JOHN "MARTY" THIELS SOUTHPARK STATION.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Designation.--The facility of the United States Postal Service known as the Southpark Station in Alexandria, Louisiana, shall be known and designated as the "John `Marty' Thiels Southpark Station".</narrative>
  <narrative> (b) References.--Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the facility referred to in subsection (a) shall be deemed to be a reference to the "John `Marty' Thiels Southpark Station".&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412249" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed en bloc to the consideration of the following calendar items: Calendar Nos. 509 and 510.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412249" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolutions be agreed to; that the preambles be agreed to; that the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table, en bloc; that the consideration of these items appear separately in the Record; and that any statements relating to the resolutions be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
