<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1217088004" ordinal="10" title="UNANIMOUS-CONSENT REQUEST--S. 294">
  <narrative>UNANIMOUS-CONSENT REQUEST--S. 294 -- (Senate - July 26, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="7511">S7511</bill>]</narrative>
  <chair> The majority leader is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Chair lay before the Senate a message from the House on <bill type="s" number="294">S. 294</bill>, the Passenger Rail Investment Improvement Act; further, that the Senate disagree to the House amendment, agree to the request for a conference on the disagreeing votes of the two Houses, and the Chair be authorized to authorize conferees on the part of the Senate with a ratio 4 to 3.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400576" topic="">
    <paragraph>I object.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, there are a number of individuals who want to speak. I ask consent that the following be the order of the Chair: that Senator Brown be recognized for 10 minutes, Senator Cantwell for 1 minute--Senators Brown and Cantwell for 1 minute and Senator Enzi for 1 minute. How many minutes is that?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Where I made my mistake is Senator Cantwell needs 4 minutes. So Senator Brown, 10 minutes; Senator Cantwell, 4 minutes; Senator Enzi, 1 minute; Senator Carper, 1 minute; and then the Senator from Alaska would be given 30 minutes to distribute however she feels appropriate. This is all as in morning business.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection? Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The Senator from Ohio is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400050" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, would the Presiding Officer let me know when I have 1 minute left, please?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator will be notified.</chair>
</record>
