<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1169139604" ordinal="31" title="ART BUCHWALD--THE MARK TWAIN OF OUR TIME">
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President it is with a heavy heart that I rise to pay tribute to Art Buchwald. Art finally said good-bye to all of us last night. It was far too soon.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Art is survived by his son Joel and his wife Tamara--who he lived with for so many wonderful years--his daughters Jennifer and Connie, his two sisters and five grandchildren. We are fortunate to have had him for so long, and he will be missed very much.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Art was an incredible friend to my wife Vicki and me and to the entire Kennedy family. We all enjoyed Art's company and columns, and President Kennedy was known to read Art's column regularly while he was in the White House.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We enjoyed so many delightful times together. Whether here in Washington or on Martha's Vineyard, Art brought tons of laughter into our lives. We'll continue to remember him and his wife, Ann McGarry Buchwald, as they will now be laid to rest together on the Vineyard.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Art was the Mark Twain of our time. He will forever live on in our hearts and minds for his brilliant wit and observations. For decades there was no better way to start the day than to open the morning paper to Art's column, laugh out loud and learn all over again to take the issues seriously in the world of politics, but not take yourself too seriously.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As Art said, "Whether it's the best of times or the worst of times, it's the only time we've got." The special art of Art Buchwald was to make even the worst of times better. We are fortunate to have had him for so long, and I will miss him very much.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Art was born in 1925 in Mount Vernon, New York, and made his own way in the world becoming a renowned political humorist and highly regarded columnist. In 1982, he received a Pulitzer Prize. Art never stopped working--writing and making us laugh right up until the very end.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Just last November, he published his final book, "Too Soon To Say Goodbye." He even had the foresight to write one final column--published today. Among his final words were these:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I don't know how well I've done while I was here, but I'd like to think that some of my printed works will persevere at least for three years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In fact, Art, they'll persevere forever.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Vicki and I remember fondly celebrating Art's 80th birthday just over a year ago with The Brady Center to Prevent Gun Violence, together with my sister Eunice and her husband Sargent Shriver. Like every gathering with Art, it was an evening full of joy, humor and passion. Art was a great friend to the Brady Center and an inspiring advocate for sensible gun laws. He was a true leader for the cause and we are closer to our goal of rational gun control today because of him.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Art was also an outspoken and powerful advocate on the importance of mental health care, speaking openly about his own experiences and providing hope to some many others.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When we lost President Kennedy, Art honored him with his column, "We Weep." He wrote:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We weep for our president who died for his country. We weep for his wife and his children, brothers and sisters. We weep for the millions of people who are weeping for him. We weep for Americans that this could happen in our country. We weep for the Europeans and the Africans and the Asians and people in every corner of the globe who saw in him a hope for the future and a chance for mankind.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, Art, the world weeps for you.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that Art Buchwald's final column, published today, be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
</record>
