<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1217088004" ordinal="16" title="HOUSING">
  <narrative>HOUSING -- (Senate - July 26, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="7513">S7513</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300019" topic="">
    <paragraph>The Nation has gone through a housing bubble over the last year or two. Housing values have gone up in a way that are unsustainable. We have now seen the collapse of the bubble. As we eventually move our way toward a stabilizing of housing prices, with this housing legislation to make sure that when we do reach the bottom, prices stabilize, and there is enough confidence on the part of people who are renting houses today, people who would like to be homeowners, that they can move  in, they will have a mortgage mechanism that still works, they will have a housing finance operation that still works, and we will be able to get this economy moving again.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation we have adopted provides for stabilizing Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac, makes sure we have a strong independent regulator for them, brings the FHA into the 21st century and streamlines it, provides for housing counselors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It does a whole lot of good things.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I commend everyone who has had a hand in working in that, including the Presiding Officer, and say that I am delighted it has passed and the President is going to sign it into law.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Alaska.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300075" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, under the previous unanimous consent order, I believe the Republicans have 30 minutes under our control.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield to the Senator from Tennessee.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300002" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I thank the Senator from Alaska.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent, if it has not been asked already, that we conduct the next 30 minutes as in a colloquy.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
