<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1228928403" ordinal="56" title="ENSURING COMPENSATION AND OTHER EMOLUMENTS ATTACHED TO THE OFFICE OF SECRETARY OF STATE">
  <narrative>ENSURING COMPENSATION AND OTHER EMOLUMENTS ATTACHED TO THE OFFICE OF SECRETARY OF STATE -- (Senate - December 10, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="10885">S10885</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the consideration of <bill type="sj" number="46">S.J. Res. 46</bill> introduced earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the joint resolution by title.</chair>
  <chair>The assistant legislative clerk read as follows:</chair>
  <chair>A joint resolution (<bill type="sj" number="46">S.J. Res. 46</bill>) ensuring that the compensation and other emoluments attached to the Office of Secretary of State are those which were in effect on January 1, 2007.</chair>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the joint resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that the joint resolution be read three times and passed, the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table; and that any statements related thereto be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The joint resolution was ordered to be engrossed for a third reading, was read the third time, and passed, as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sj" number="46">S.J. Res. 46</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair> Resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. COMPENSATION AND OTHER EMOLUMENTS ATTACHED TO THE OFFICE OF SECRETARY OF STATE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) In General.--The compensation and other emoluments attached to the office of Secretary of State shall be those in effect January 1, 2007, notwithstanding any increase in such compensation or emoluments after that date under any provision of law, or provision which has the force and effect of law, that is enacted or becomes effective during the period beginning at noon of January 3, 2007, and ending at noon of January 3, 2013.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Civil Action and Appeal.--</chair>
  <chair> (1) JURISDICTION.--Any person aggrieved by an action of the Secretary of State may bring a civil action in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia to contest the constitutionality of the appointment and continuance in office of the Secretary of State on the ground that such appointment and continuance in office is in violation of article I, section 6, clause 2, of the Constitution. The United States District Court for the District of Columbia shall have exclusive  jurisdiction over such a civil action, without regard to the sum or value of the matter in controversy.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) THREE JUDGE PANEL.--Any claim challenging the constitutionality of the appointment and continuance in office of the Secretary of State on the ground that such appointment and continuance in office is in violation of article I, section 6, clause 2, of  the Constitution, in an action brought under paragraph (1) shall be heard and determined by a panel of three judges in accordance with section 2284 of title 28, United States Code. It shall  be the duty of the district court to advance on the docket and to expedite the disposition of any matter brought under this subsection.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) APPEAL.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) DIRECT APPEAL TO SUPREME COURT.--An appeal may be taken directly to the Supreme Court of the United States from any interlocutory or final judgment, decree, or order upon the validity of the appointment and continuance in office of the Secretary of State under article I, section 6, clause 2, of the Constitution, entered in any action brought under this subsection. Any such appeal shall be taken by a notice of appeal filed within 20 days after such judgment, decree, or order is entered.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) JURISDICTION.--The Supreme Court shall, if it has not previously ruled on the question presented by an appeal taken under subparagraph (A), accept jurisdiction over the appeal, advance the appeal on the docket, and expedite the appeal.</chair>
  <chair> (c) Effective Date.--This joint resolution shall take effect at 12:00 p.m. on January 20, 2009. &lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
