<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1209657603" ordinal="61" title="NATIONAL PHYSICAL FITNESS AND SPORTS MONTH AND NATIONAL PHYSICAL EDUCATION AND SPORTS WEEK">
  <narrative>NATIONAL PHYSICAL FITNESS AND SPORTS MONTH AND NATIONAL PHYSICAL EDUCATION AND SPORTS WEEK -- (Senate - May 01, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="3729">S3729</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300018" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the consideration of <bill type="sr" number="546">S. Res. 546</bill>, which was submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report.</chair>
  <chair>The assistant legislative clerk read as follows:</chair>
  <chair>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="546">S. Res. 546</bill>) designating May 2008 as "National Physical Fitness and Sports Month," and the week of May 1 through May 7, 2008, as "National Physical Education and Sports Week."</chair>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400546" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I am pleased to submit a resolution today with my colleague, Senator WYDEN OR, designating the month of May as "National Physical Fitness and Sports Month" and the first week of May as "National Physical Education and Sports Week."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Developing healthy habits is important for all of us, as children, young  adults, and as we grow older. Current and past Presidents have recognized the month of May, the beginning of spring, as "Physical Fitness and Sports Month" for over 20 years. Around South Dakota and across the country, local YMCAs, afterschool programs, and other organizations take time during the month of May to recognize the need to get fit, stay active, and look at new ways  to promote physical activity. This year, I am pleased we are able to recognize the importance of physical fitness through the Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As we talk more about health care reform and the uninsured, it is important to remember that each of us has a responsibility concerning our own care and to educate our children on the importance of staying healthy. Too often I hear from constituencies, such as school groups and health care providers, that childhood obesity and diabetes are on the rise--and it is not just affecting our health, but also our pocketbooks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>According to my State and the Centers for Disease Control, more than 50,000 South Dakotans have diabetes and projections show that number will continue to increase. Diabetes of course can cause severe complications and takes a tremendous toll on our society. The disease is associated with significant personal and social costs due to impaired health and quality of life.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Heart disease is another significant and often related illness to diabetes that effects millions of Americans and costs Medicare and Medicaid, and therefore taxpayers, millions each year. In South Dakota, approximately 1,743 deaths--24.8 percent of all deaths--in 2006 were caused by cardiovascular diseases, including stroke.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now much of the burden of heart disease is due to smoking--and that is another problem we will continue to tackle through education at the state and local levels. But it is also helpful to know that both heart disease and type 2 diabetes are largely preventable. Also, obesity and inactivity are two of the major risk factors associated with these diseases---which means a healthy diet and regular physical activity at all ages can go a long way toward improving our quality of life and reducing our  health care bills.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For adults, it is recommended that minimum physical activity consist of moderate activity for 30 minutes, 5 days a week, or more vigorous activity for 20 minutes, 3 days a week. My daughters and I happen to have a passion for running, which is particularly popular this time of year in South Dakota.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The month of May is also a time to recognize the importance of sports to our State and to our schools. Getting involved in your local school team--high school or college--or in other local teams is a great way to stay motivated and focused through school and to develop healthy habits that will last for many years. It is also a tremendously important part of community life in South Dakota.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am proud that this resolution has been endorsed by YMCA of the USA, AAHPERD--American Alliance for Health, Physical Education, Recreation &amp; Dance--the American Heart Association, American Diabetes Association, and the National Coalition for Promoting Physical Activity.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300018" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="546">S. Res. 546</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="546">S. Res. 546</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas regular physical activity helps increase endurance, strengthen bones and muscles, control weight, and reduce anxiety and stress, and may improve blood pressure and cholesterol levels;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas about  2/3  of young people in the ninth through 12th grades do not engage in recommended levels of physical activity, and daily participation in high school physical education classes has declined over the last 7 years;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas 39 percent of adults report they are not physically active, and only 3 in 10 adults engage in the recommended amount of physical activity;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, in 2004, more than 9,000,000 children and adolescents in the United States between the ages of 6 and 19 were considered overweight;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas obesity and inactivity are 2 major risk factors for developing type 2 diabetes, a disease that affects millions of people in the United States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas many chronic diseases may be prevented by living a healthy lifestyle that includes regular physical activity and a balanced diet;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, according to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the American Heart Association, and the American College of Sports Medicine, minimum physical activity for adults consists of moderate activity for 30 minutes 5 days a week or vigorous activity for 20 minutes 3 days a week;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, according to a 1996 report by the Surgeon General, positive experiences with physical activity at a young age help to lay the foundation for being active throughout life;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the President's Council on Physical Fitness and Sports promotes regular physical activity to achieve and maintain good health and to prevent chronic disease and offers motivational tools through the President's Challenge program for people of all ages to track physical activity; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the month of May has been recognized since 1983 as National Physical Fitness and Sports Month to encourage physical fitness and activity and to promote health in children and adults of all ages: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) designates--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) May 2008 as "National Physical Fitness and Sports Month"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) the week of May 1 through May 7, 2008, as "National Physical Education and Sports Week"; and</chair>
  <chair> (2) encourages the people of the United States to observe the month and the week with appropriate ceremonies and activities.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
