<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1221062403" ordinal="21" title="MORNING BUSINESS">
  <narrative>MORNING BUSINESS -- (Senate - September 10, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="8266">S8266</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="">
    <paragraph>In that case, Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that we now move off the bill, move to morning business, and that Senators Graham and Lieberman be recognized and then Senator Sanders be recognized.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Virginia.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300099" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, if I might say to my colleague, Senator Graham has an airplane he is trying to catch.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I wonder if Senator Graham could speak for just a few minutes, and then we could turn to Senator Sanders and then to Senator Lieberman.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask Senator Graham, how many minutes does he wish?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300047" topic="">
    <paragraph>Three minutes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that we now move off the bill and go to morning business and that Senator Graham be recognized for 3 minutes and then Senator Sanders be recognized for up to 20 minutes. I want Senator Lieberman to hear that request.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400357" topic="">
    <paragraph>I say to the Senator, I listened to your speech.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="">
    <paragraph>That Senator Sanders be recognized for up to 20 minutes and Senator Lieberman be recognized for up to 20 minutes. That is my unanimous consent request.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300099" topic="">
    <paragraph>No objection.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The Senator from South Carolina is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300047" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the Chair.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
