<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1197651602" ordinal="49" title="OPENNESS PROMOTES EFFECTIVENESS IN OUR NATIONAL GOVERNMENT ACT OF 2007">
  <narrative>OPENNESS PROMOTES EFFECTIVENESS IN OUR NATIONAL GOVERNMENT ACT OF 2007 -- (Senate - December 14, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="15701">S15701</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the consideration <bill type="s" number="2488">S. 2488</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the bill by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A bill (<bill type="s" number="2488">S. 2488</bill>) to promote accessibility, accountability, and openness in Government by strengthening section 552 of title 5, United States Code (commonly referred to as the Freedom of Information Act), and for other purposes.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the bill.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that the bill be read three times, passed, the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table, with no intervening action or debate, and that any statements relating to this bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The bill (<bill type="s" number="2488">S. 2488</bill>) was ordered to be engrossed for a third reading, was read the third time, and passed, as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="s" number="248">S. 248</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "Openness Promotes Effectiveness in our National Government Act of 2007" or the "OPEN Government Act of 2007".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. FINDINGS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Congress finds that--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) the Freedom of Information Act was signed into law on July 4, 1966, because the American people believe that--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) our constitutional democracy, our system of self-government, and our commitment to popular sovereignty depends upon the consent of the governed;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) such consent is not meaningful unless it is informed consent; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) as Justice Black noted in his concurring opinion in Barr v. Matteo (360 U.S. 564 (1959)), "The effective functioning of a free government like ours depends largely on the force of an informed public opinion. This calls for the widest possible understanding of the quality of government service rendered by all elective or appointed public officials or employees.";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) the American people firmly believe that our system of government must itself be governed by a presumption of openness;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) the Freedom of Information Act establishes a "strong presumption in favor of disclosure" as noted by the United States Supreme Court in United States Department of State v. Ray (502 U.S. 164 (1991)), a presumption that applies to all agencies governed by that Act;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) "disclosure, not secrecy, is the dominant objective of the Act," as noted by the United States Supreme Court in Department of Air Force v. Rose (425 U.S. 352 (1976));&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) in practice, the Freedom of Information Act has not always lived up to the ideals of that Act; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (6) Congress should regularly review section 552 of title 5, United States Code (commonly referred to as the Freedom of Information Act), in order to determine whether further changes and improvements are necessary to ensure that the Government remains open and accessible to the American people and is always based not upon the  "need to know" but upon the fundamental "right to know".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 3. PROTECTION OF FEE STATUS FOR NEWS MEDIA.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Section 552(a)(4)(A)(ii) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</chair>
  <chair> "In this clause, the term `a representative of the news media' means any person or entity that gathers information of potential interest to a segment of the public, uses its editorial skills to turn the raw materials into a distinct work, and distributes that work to an audience. In this clause, the term `news' means information that is about current events or that would be of current interest to the public. Examples of news-media entities are television or radio stations broadcasting to the  public at large and publishers of periodicals (but only if such entities qualify as disseminators of `news') who make their products available for purchase by or subscription by or free distribution to the general public. These examples are not all-inclusive. Moreover, as methods of news delivery evolve (for example, the adoption of the electronic dissemination of newspapers through telecommunications services), such alternative media shall be considered</chair>
  <chair> "(l) FOIA Public Liaisons shall report to the agency Chief FOIA Officer and shall serve as supervisory officials to whom a requester under this section can raise concerns about the service the requester has received from the FOIA Requester Center, following an initial response from the FOIA Requester Center Staff. FOIA Public Liaisons shall be responsible for assisting in reducing delays, increasing transparency and understanding of the status of requests, and assisting in the resolution of  disputes.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Effective Date.--The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 11. REPORT ON PERSONNEL POLICIES RELATED TO FOIA.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Office of Personnel Management shall submit to Congress a report that examines--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) whether changes to executive branch personnel policies could be made that would--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) provide greater encouragement to all Federal employees to fulfill their duties under section 552 of title 5, United States Code; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) enhance the stature of officials administering that section within the executive branch;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) whether performance of compliance with section 552 of title 5, United States Code, should be included as a factor in personnel performance evaluations for any or all categories of Federal employees and officers;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) whether an employment classification series specific to compliance with sections 552 and 552a of title 5, United States Code, should be established;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) whether the highest level officials in particular agencies administering such sections should be paid at a rate of pay equal to or greater than a particular minimum rate; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) whether other changes to personnel policies can be made to ensure that there is a clear career advancement track for individuals interested in devoting themselves to a career in compliance with such sections; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (6) whether the executive branch should require any or all categories of Federal employees to undertake awareness training of such sections.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 12. REQUIREMENT TO DESCRIBE EXEMPTIONS AUTHORIZING DELETIONS OF MATERIAL PROVIDED UNDER FOIA.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Section 552(b) of title 5, United States Code, is amended in the matter after paragraph (9)--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in the second sentence, by inserting after "amount of information deleted" the following: ", and the exemption under which the deletion is made,"; and</chair>
  <chair> (2) in the third sentence, by inserting after "amount of the information deleted" the following: ", and the exemption under which the deletion is made,".  &lt;p&gt;</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I am pleased that, once again, the Senate has reaffirmed its bipartisan commitment to open and transparent government by unanimously passing the Openness Promotes Effectiveness in our National Government Act, the "OPEN Government Act--the first major reform to the Freedom of Information Act, "FOIA", in more than a decade. I commend the bill's chief Republican cosponsor, Senator John Cornyn, for his commitment and dedication to passing FOIA reform legislation  this year. I am also appreciative of the efforts of Senator Jon Kyl for cosponsoring this bill and helping us to reach a compromise on this legislation, so that the Senate could consider and pass meaningful FOIA reform legislation this year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Earlier this year, the Senate passed this historic FOIA reform legislation, <bill type="s" number="849">S. 849</bill>, before adjourning for the August recess. Now that the Senate has unanimously passed a modified bill, to ensure that "pay/go" and other concerns of the House are adequately addressed, I hope that the House will promptly enact this bill and send it to the President without further delay.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have worked very hard to address the concerns of the House Oversight and Government Reform Committee, to ensure that the Congress can enact meaningful FOIA reform legislation this year. I commend Congressman Waxman, the distinguished Chairman of that Committee, for his commitment to FOIA reform and I thank him and his staff for all of their hard work on this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill that the Senate passed today includes "pay/go" language that has been requested by the House and it also eliminates a provision on citations to FOIA exemptions in legislation that was in the previous bill. To accommodate other concerns of the House, the bill also includes a new provision that requires Federal agencies to disclose the FOIA exemptions that they rely upon when redacting information from documents released under FOIA. In addition, the bill adds FOIA duplication fees for  noncommercial requesters, including the media, to the fee waiver penalty that will be imposed when an agency fails to meet the 20-day statutory clock under FOIA. While I will continue to work with the House and others to further strengthen this critical open government law, I hope that the House will promptly take up the bipartisan FOIA compromise bill that we have been able to pass so that it may be signed into law before the end of the year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As the first major reform to FOIA in more than a decade, the OPEN Government Act will help to reverse the troubling trends of excessive delays and lax FOIA compliance in our government and help to restore the public's trust in their government. This bill will also improve transparency in the Federal Government's FOIA process by restoring meaningful deadlines for agency action under FOIA; imposing real consequences on federal agencies for missing FOIA's 20-day statutory deadline; clarifying that  FOIA applies to Government records held by outside private  contractors; establishing a FOIA hotline service for all Federal agencies; and creating a FOIA Ombudsman to provide FOIA requestors and, federal agencies with a meaningful alternative to costly litigation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Specifically, the OPEN Government Act will protect the public's right to know, by ensuring that anyone who gathers information to inform the public, including freelance journalists and bloggers, may seek a fee waiver when they request information under FOIA. The bill ensures that Federal agencies will not automatically exclude Internet blogs and other Web-based forms of media when deciding whether to waive FOIA fees. In addition, the bill also clarifies that the definition of news media, for  purposes of FOIA fee waivers, includes free newspapers and individuals performing a media function who do not necessarily have a prior history of publication.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also restores meaningful deadlines for agency action, by ensuring that the 20-day statutory clock under FOIA starts when a request is received by the appropriate component of the agency and requiring that agency FOIA offices get FOIA requests to the appropriate agency component within 10 days of the receipt of such requests. To ensure accuracy in FOIA responses, the bill allows federal agencies to toll the 20-day clock while they are awaiting a response to a reasonable request for information  from a FOIA requester on one occasion, or while the agency is awaiting clarification regarding a FOIA fee assessment. In addition, to encourage agencies to meet the 20-day time limit the bill requires that an agency refund FOIA search fees--and duplication fees for noncommercial requestors--if it fails to meet the 20-day deadline, except in the case of exceptional circumstances as defined by the FOIA statute.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also addresses a relatively new concern that, under current law, Federal agencies have an incentive to delay compliance with FOIA requests until just before a court decision is made that is favorable to a FOIA requestor. The Supreme Court's decision in Buckhannon Board and Care Home, Inc. v. West Virginia Dep't of Health and Human</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Resources, 532 U.S. 598, 2001, eliminated the "catalyst theory" for attorneys' fees recovery under certain federal civil rights laws. When applied to FOIA cases, Buckhannon precludes FOIA requesters from ever being eligible to recover attorneys fees under circumstances where an agency provides the records requested in the litigation just prior to a court decision that would have been favorable to the FOIA requestor. The bill clarifies that Buckhannon does not apply to FOIA cases. Under the  bill, a FOIA requester can obtain attorneys' fees when he or she files a lawsuit to obtain records from the Government and the Government releases those records before the court orders them to do so. But, this provision would not allow the requester to recover attorneys' fees if the requester's claim is wholly insubstantial. To address House "pay/go" concerns, the bill also requires that any attorneys" fees assessed under this provision be paid from any annually appropriated agency funds.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To address concerns about the growing costs of FOIA litigation, the bill also creates an Office of Government Information Services in the National Archives and creates an ombudsman to mediate agency-level FOIA disputes. In addition the bill ensures that each federal agency will appoint a Chief FOIA Officer, who will monitor the agency's compliance with FOIA requests, and a FOIA Public Liaison who will be available to resolve FOIA related disputes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, the bill does several things to enhance the agency reporting and tracking requirements under FOIA. The bill creates a tracking system for FOIA requests to assist members of the public and the media. The bill also establishes a FOIA hotline service for all Federal agencies, either by telephone or on the Internet, to enable requestors to track the status of their FOIA requests. The bill also clarifies that FOIA applies to agency records that are held by outside private contractors, no  matter where these records are located.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Freedom of Information Act is an essential tool to ensure that all Americans can access information about the workings of their government. But, after four decades, this open government law needs to be strengthened. I am pleased that the reforms contained in the OPEN Government Act will ensure that FOIA is reinvigorated--so that it works more effectively for the American people.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, I commend Senators Cornyn and Kyl and the many other cosponsors of this legislation for their dedication to open government. But, most importantly, I especially want to thank the many concerned citizens who, knowing the importance of this measure to the American people's right to know, have demanded action on this bill. This bill is endorsed by more than 115 business, public interest, and news organizations from across the political and ideological spectrum, including  the American Library Association, the U.S. Chamber of Commerce, OpenTheGovemment.org, Public Citizen, the Republican Liberty Caucus, the Sunshine in Government Initiative and the Vermont Press Association. The invaluable support of these and many other organizations is what led the opponents of this bill to come around and support this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By passing this important FOIA reform legislation, the Senate has reaffirmed the principle that open government is not a Democratic issue or a Republican issue. But, rather, it is an American issue and an American value. I strongly encourage the House of Representatives, which overwhelmingly passed a similar measure earlier this year, to promptly take up and enact this bill before adjourning for the year.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
