<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1207324801" ordinal="24" title="NOTICE OF HEARING">
  <narrative>NOTICE OF HEARING -- (Senate - April 04, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="2617">S2617</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON PUBLIC LANDS AND FORESTS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to announce for the information of the Senate and the public that a hearing has been scheduled before the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The hearing will be held on Tuesday, April 15, 2008, at 2:30 p.m. in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the hearing is to receive testimony on the following bills: <bill type="s" number="570">S. 570</bill> and <bill type="h" number="1011">H.R. 1011</bill>, to designate additional National Forest System lands in the State of Virginia as wilderness or a wilderness study area, to designate the Kimberling Creek Potential Wilderness Area for eventual incorporation in the Kimberling Creek Wilderness, to establish the Seng Mountain and Bear Creek Scenic Areas, to provide for the development of trail plans for the wilderness areas and scenic areas, and for  other purposes; <bill type="s" number="758">S. 758</bill> and <bill type="h" number="1311">H.R. 1311</bill>, to direct the Secretary of the Interior to convey the Alta-Hualapai Site to the city of Las Vegas, Nevada, for the development of a cancer treatment facility; <bill type="s" number="1680">S. 1680</bill>, to provide for the inclusion of certain non-Federal land in the Izembek National Wildlife Refuge and the Alaska Peninsula National Wildlife Refuge in the State of Alaska, and for other purposes; <bill type="s" number="2109">S. 2109</bill>, to designate certain Federal lands in Riverside County, California, as wilderness, to designate certain river segments</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of the limited time available for the hearing, witnesses may testify by invitation only. However, those wishing to submit written testimony for the hearing record should send it to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, United States Senate, Washington, DC 20510-6150, or by email to rachel</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
