<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1181059208" ordinal="39" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <speaking speaker="300037" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND NATURAL RESOURCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, June 5, 2007, at 10 a.m. in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building. The purpose of the hearing is to consider the preparedness of Federal land management agencies for the 2007 wildfire season and to consider recent reports on the agencies' efforts to contain the costs of wildfire management activities.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300037" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet to conduct a hearing entitled "Examining the Federal Role to Work with Communities to Prevent and Respond to Gang Violence: The Gang Abatement and Prevention Act of 2007" on Tuesday, June 5, 2007, at 10 a.m. in Dirksen Senate Office Building Room 226.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Panel I: The Honorable Barbara Boxer, United States Senator [D-CA].</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Panel II: The Honorable Antonio R. Villaraigosa, Mayor, City of Los Angeles, Los Angeles, CA; William J. Bratton, Chief of Police, Los Angeles Police Department, Los Angeles, CA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Panel III: Ms. Boni Gayle Driskill, Wings of Protection, Modesto, CA.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300037" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet to conduct a hearing entitled "Preserving Prosecutorial Independence: Is the Department of Justice Politicizing the Hiring and Firing of U.S. Attorneys?--Part V" on Tuesday, June 5, 2007, at 2 p.m. in Dirksen Senate Office Building Room 226.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Panel I: Bradley J. Schlozman, Associate Counsel to the Director, Executive Office for United States Attorneys, Former Interim U.S. Attorney for the Western District of Missouri, Former Principal Deputy Assistant Attorney General and, Acting Assistant Attorney General for the Civil Rights Division, U.S. Department of Justice, Washington, DC</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Panel II: Todd Graves, Former U.S. Attorney, Western District of Missouri, Kansas City, MO.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300037" topic="PERMANENT SUBCOMMITTEE ON INVESTIGATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations of the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs be authorized to meet on Tuesday, June 5, 2007, at 9 a.m. for a hearing entitled "Executive Stock Options: Should the IRS and Stockholders Be Given Different Information?"</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300037" topic="SELECT COMMITTEE ON INTELLIGENCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Select Committee on Intelligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on June 5, 2007 at 2:30 p.m. to hold a closed hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
