<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1179331205" ordinal="44" title="NATIONAL INTERNET SAFETY MONTH">
  <speaking speaker="300018" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate now proceed to the consideration of <bill type="sr" number="205">S. Res. 205</bill>, which was submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300075" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today I introduced a resolution designating June 2007 as National Internet Safety Month.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Internet has become one of the most significant advances in the twentieth century and, as a result, it affects people's lives in a positive manner each day. However, this technology presents dangers that need to be brought to the attention of all Americans. Consider the pervasiveness of Internet access by children and the rapid increase in Internet crime and predatory behavior. Never before have powerful educational solutions--such as Internet safety curricula for grades kindergarten through  12--been more critical and readily at hand.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, i-SAFE America is one nonprofit organization that has worked tirelessly to educate our youth and our community on these important issues. Formed in 1998, i-SAFE America educates youth in all 50 states, Washington, DC, and Department of Defense schools worldwide to ensure that they have a safe experience online.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is imperative that all Americans learn about the Internet safety strategies which will help keep their children safe from victimization. Consider the facts: In the United States, about 35 million school-aged children have Internet access. Eighty percent of middle and high school students are online for at least one hour per week.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An alarming statistic is that 61 percent of middle and high school youths admit to using the Internet unsafely or inappropriately. Furthermore, at least 20 percent of these students have met face-to-face with someone they first met online and 23 percent of these students know of someone who has been bullied online.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now is the time for America to focus its attention on supporting Internet safety, especially bearing in mind that children will soon be on summer vacation and will spend more time online.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300018" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
