<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1177603218" ordinal="62" title="SENATE CONCURRENT RESOLUTION 29--ENCOURAGING THE RECOGNITION OF THE NEGRO BASEBALL LEAGUES AND THEIR PLAYERS ON MAY 20TH OF EACH YEAR">
  <speaking speaker="300078" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I, along with Senators Reid, Leahy, Specter, Obama, Clinton, Brownback, and Martinez, have proudly submitted a concurrent resolution honoring the Negro Baseball Leagues and their players by encouraging the recognition of Negro Leaguers Recognition Day May 20 of each year. My relationship with the Negro Leagues players began when I successfully worked to persuade Major League Baseball to give pension benefits to former players. In 2004, Major  League Baseball agreed to put up $1 million for monthly payments to 27 former Negro Leaguers. Last year, I worked with the families of several of the most notable Negro Leaguers to pass a Senate resolution designating May 20, 2006--the date on which the Negro National League played its first game--as Negro Leaguers Recognition Day.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am submitting a resolution honoring the Negro Leaguers again this year--in cooperation with Representative Cohen in the House--to demonstrate the support in both Chambers for recognizing Negro Leaguers Recognition Day on May 20 of each year. I hope that this will be a day when Negro Leaguers and their families will return to the ballpark to be honored for their historic contributions to the game of baseball and to bridging racial divisions in our country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since 1885, long before Major League Baseball was integrated in 1947, African-Americans organized their own professional leagues. These leagues did not succeed because of racial prejudice and lack of adequate financial backing. However, this changed dramatically with the inception of the first successful Negro league--the Negro National League. Its creation was the result of the efforts of an African-American player and manager named Andrew "Rube" Foster. Mr. Foster's success inspired the formation  of other leagues.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a result, on October 3, 1924, the first Negro League World Series game was played between the Kansas City Monarchs of the Negro National League and Hilldale of Philadelphia of the Eastern Colored League. This historic and exhaustive first series lasted 10 games, covered a span of almost 3 weeks, and was played in four different cities. In the end, Kansas City claimed the championship.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Some of the names we know and some we don't. Among them are Jackie Robinson, the first African-American to break the baseball color barrier; Satchel Paige, who was considered one of the greatest pitchers of all time; Josh Gibson, who was a prolific home-run hitter; Larry Doby, the first African-American to play in the American League in July 1947; Buck O'Neil, who was the first African-American coach in the Major Leagues and who went on to head the Negro Leagues Baseball Museum; Cool Papa Bell,  who was known as the fastest man in baseball; and Minnie Minoso; the "Cuban Comet," who played on the New York Cubans when they won the Negro League World Series, and broke the color barrier on the Chicago White Sox when he joined the team in 1951.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is important that we remember and honor these players and their teammates in the Negro Leagues. In breaking down baseball's color barrier, these pioneers dealt a blow to hatred and prejudice across America. Today, we can honor them by recognizing May 20 each year as Negro Leaguers Recognition Day.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
