<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1197478803" ordinal="62" title="REFORMING MUTUAL AID AGREEMENTS FOR THE NATIONAL CAPITOL REGION">
  <narrative>REFORMING MUTUAL AID AGREEMENTS FOR THE NATIONAL CAPITOL REGION -- (Senate - December 12, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="15373">S15373</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of Calendar No. 525, <bill type="s" number="1245">S. 1245</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the bill by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A bill (<bill type="s" number="1245">S. 1245</bill>) to reform mutual aid agreements for the National Capitol Region.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the bill.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I further ask unanimous consent that the bill be read the third time and passed, the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table with no intervening action or debate, and that any statements relating to the measure be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The bill (<bill type="s" number="1245">S. 1245</bill>) was ordered to be engrossed for a third reading, was read the third time, and passed, as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="s" number="1245">S. 1245</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. REFORM OF MUTUAL AID AGREEMENTS FOR THE NATIONAL CAPITAL REGION.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Section 7302 of the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 (42 U.S.C. 5196 note) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in subsection (a)--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) in paragraph (4), by striking ", including its agents or authorized volunteers,"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) in paragraph (5), by striking "or town" and all that follows and inserting "town, or other governmental agency, governmental authority, or governmental institution with the power to sue or be sued in its own name, within the National Capital Region.";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) in subsection (b)(1), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking ", the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority, the Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority, and any other governmental agency or authority"; and</chair>
  <chair> (3) in subsection (d), by striking "or employees" each place that term appears and inserting ", employees, or agents".&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
