<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1183953600" ordinal="55" title="CHARLES W. NORWOOD LIVING ORGAN DONATION ACT">
  <narrative>CHARLES W. NORWOOD LIVING ORGAN DONATION ACT -- (Senate - July 09, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="8879">S8879</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the consideration of Calendar No. 77, <bill type="h" number="710">H.R. 710</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the bill by title.</chair>
  <chair>The assistant legislative clerk read as follows:</chair>
  <chair>A bill (<bill type="h" number="710">H.R. 710</bill>) to amend the National Organ Transplant Act to provide that criminal penalties do not apply to paired donation of human kidneys, and for other purposes.</chair>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the bill.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, this bipartisan substitute is nearly identical to <bill type="s" number="487">S.487</bill>, which I introduced along with Senators BOND, DORGAN, GRAHAM, DURBIN, MIKULSKI, PRYOR, CARDIN, ISAKSON, COLEMAN, BROWN, and CHAMBLISS, and which passed the Senate on February 15, 2007. Companion legislation was introduced in the House where it was renamed in honor of our House colleague, the late Representative Charles Norwood, a longtime advocate of organ donation, who sponsored the legislation earlier  this year along with Representative JAY INSLEE.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our legislation, the Living Kidney Organ Donation Clarification Act, will save lives by increasing the number of kidneys available for transplantation through a process called paired organ donation. It addresses this relatively new procedure, which is supported by numerous medical organizations, including the United Network for Organ Sharing, the American Society of Transplant Surgeons, the American Society of Transplantation, the National Kidney Foundation and the American Society of Pediatric  Nephrology. Paired organ donation, which did not exist when the National Organ Transplant Act, NOTA, was enacted more than two decades ago, will make it possible for thousands of people who wish to donate a kidney to a spouse, family member or friend, but find that they are medically incompatible, to still become living kidney donors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation is necessary because the National Organ Transplant Act, NOTA, which contains a prohibition intended by Congress to preclude purchasing organs, is unintentionally impeding the facilitation of matching incompatible pairs. Our legislation would simply add kidney paired donation to the list of other living-related donation exemptions that Congress originally placed in NOTA. It removes an unintended impediment to kidney paired donations by clarifying ambiguous language in section 301  of the National Organ Transplant Act, NOTA. That section has been interpreted by a number of transplant centers to prohibit such donations. In section 301 of NOTA, Congress prohibited the buying and selling of organs. Subsection (a), titled "Prohibition of organ purchases," says: "It shall</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress surely never intended that the living donation arrangements that permit kidney paired donation be impeded by NOTA. Our bill simply makes that clear. Some transplant professionals involved in these and other innovative living kidney donation arrangements have proceeded in the reasonable belief that these arrangements do not violate section of 301 of NOTA, but they contend that they are doing so under a cloud.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the process of kidney paired donor transplants, a pair consisting of a kidney transplant candidate and a biologically incompatible living donor is matched with another such pair to enable two transplants that otherwise would not occur. In other words, the intended recipient of each donor is incompatible with the intended donor but compatible with the other donor in the arrangement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>No Federal dollars are needed to implement this change. And, for each patient who receives a kidney, Medicare will save roughly $220,000 in dialysis costs. It is essential that we make the intent of Congress explicit so that transplant centers which have hesitated to implement incompatible living kidney donation programs can feel free to do so.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Levin amendment at the desk be considered and agreed to, the bill, as amended, be read three times, passed, the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table, and that any statements relating to the bill be printed in the Record, the above occurring with no intervening action or debate.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The amendment (No. 2025) was agreed to, as follows:</chair>
  <narrative>(Purpose: To provide a complete substitute)</narrative>
  <narrative> Strike all after the enacting clause and insert the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "Charlie W. Norwood Living Organ Donation Act".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. AMENDMENTS TO THE NATIONAL ORGAN TRANSPLANT ACT.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Section 301 of the National Organ Transplant Act (42 U.S.C. 274e) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in subsection (a), by adding at the end the following: "For purposes of this section, human organ paired donation and similar practices, as defined by the Secretary, shall not be considered to involve the transfer of a human organ for valuable consideration."; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) in subsection (c), by adding at the end the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(4) The term `human organ paired donation' means the donation and receipt of human organs in a circumstance in which each of the following applies:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(A) An individual (referred to in this paragraph as the `first donor') desires to make a living donation of a human organ specifically to a particular patient (referred to in this paragraph as the `first patient'), but such donor is biologically incompatible as a donor for such patient.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(B) A second individual (referred to in this paragraph as the `second donor') desires to make a living donation of a human organ specifically to a second particular patient (referred to in this paragraph as the `second patient'), but such donor is biologically incompatible as a donor for such patient.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(C) Subject to subparagraph (D), the first donor is biologically compatible as a donor of a human donor for the second patient, and the second donor is biologically compatible as a donor of a human organ for the first patient.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(D) If there is any additional donor-patient pair as described in subparagraph (A) or (B), each donor in the group of donor-patient pairs is biologically compatible as a donor of a human organ for a patient in such group.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(E) All donors and patients in the group of donor-patient pairs (whether 2 pairs or more than 2 pairs) enter into a single agreement to donate and receive such human organs, respectively, according to such biological compatibility in the group.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(F) Other than as described in subparagraph (E), no valuable consideration is knowingly acquired, received, or otherwise transferred with respect to the human organs referred to in such subparagraph.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 3. REPORT.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that details the progress made towards understanding the long-term health effects of living organ donation.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 4. NO IMPACT ON SOCIAL SECURITY TRUST FUND.</narrative>
  <narrative> Nothing in this Act (or an amendment made by this Act) shall be construed to alter or amend the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 301 et seq.) (or any regulation promulgated under that Act).&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <narrative>The amendment was ordered to be engrossed and the bill to be read a third time.</narrative>
  <narrative>The bill (<bill type="h" number="710">H.R. 710</bill>), as amended, was read the third time and passed.</narrative>
</record>
