<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1202835603" ordinal="14" title="UNANIMOUS-CONSENT REQUEST--S. 2615">
  <narrative>UNANIMOUS-CONSENT REQUEST--S. 2615 -- (Senate - February 12, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="913">S913</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, as I indicated I would earlier today, I will ask unanimous consent to extend the law that is now in effect. I wish to extend that 15 days to see if we can work out something more with the House.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of Calendar No. 571, <bill type="s" number="2615">S. 2615</bill>; the bill be read a third time and passed; and the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table with no intervening action or debate.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Republican leader.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300072" topic="">
    <paragraph>Reserving the right to object, let me just make the point once again that we just passed this bill 68 to 29 in its initial form, which was preserved on the Senate floor. It came out of the Intelligence Committee 13 to 2. This is the Rockefeller-Bond bipartisan, overwhelmingly supported bill coming out of the Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The current law does not expire until Saturday. It is still my hope that the House, and particularly when you consider the fact that 21 House Democrats, so-called Blue Dog Democrats, have indicated to the Speaker in writing that they would like to see the Senate bill passed--the Rockefeller-Bond bill taken up and passed by the House--I think it is just premature for an extension, Madam President. I think there is  still at least a chance the House might  conclude that we have done a terrific piece of work, and they could very well consider the option, as the Blue Dogs have suggested, of taking up the measure and sending it on down to the President for signature.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So for the moment, Madam President, I object.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <chair>The legislative clerk proceeded to call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400050" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400050" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent to speak as in morning business.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
