<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1201626002" ordinal="47" title="ADDITIONAL STATEMENTS">
  <narrative>ADDITIONAL STATEMENTS -- (Senate - January 29, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="442">S442</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="CELEBRATING THE 75TH ANNIVERSARY OF THE PORT OF STOCKTON">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask my colleagues to join me in celebrating the 75th anniversary of the Port of Stockton, the second busiest inland port on the west coast.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>During the Gold Rush, the city of Stockton was an important seaport because it was the farthest point upriver ships could travel. In the early 20th century, Stockton became a vital hub for farm equipment that transformed the San Joaquin Valley from a primarily wheat-growing region to the Nation's most diverse and productive agricultural region.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When it became apparent that the San Joaquin River was too shallow to accommodate the increasingly large ships that supplied the region's growing demand for farm equipment, the first dredging contracts for the Stockton Deep Water Channel were awarded in 1930. The port of Stockton officially opened in 1933.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, the Port of Stockton processes more than 6 million tons of cargo annually. The port trades with more than 55 countries, from Canada to New Zealand, and from Thailand to Trinidad. It supports over 4,500 jobs in the region, accounting for more than $170 million in annual income.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In recent years, the Port of Stockton has made a commitment to implement a program for environmentally friendly port operations. Through its Delta Environmental Enhancement Program, the port has planted the seeds for sustained, long-term changes that will help protect the air, water, soil, and wildlife that are part of the precious Delta waterways.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The success of the Port of Stockton is made possible by the dedication of scores of hard-working people who work together to make sure that its operations go smoothly. Every person who has lent a helping hand over the years can take great pride in knowing that their support and hard work has resulted in the continued growth and success of the Port of Stockton.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I congratulate the Port of Stockton on its 75th anniversary and wish its  staff and supporters a bright future and continued success.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
