<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1175184011" ordinal="57" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="COMMITTEE ON ARMED SERVICES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, March 29, 2007, AT 9:30 a.m., to receive testimony on the posture of the Department of the Navy in review of the defense authorization request for fiscal year 2008 and the future years defense program.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Thursday, March 29, 2007, at 10 a.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building. The hearing is on the nomination of David James Gribbin IV to be the General Counsel for the U.S. Department of Transportation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENVIRONMENT AND PUBLIC WORKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Environment and Public Works be authorized to meet for a business meeting on Thursday, March 29, 2007, at 10:00 a.m. in S-211. The Business Meeting will consider the following agenda:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nomination of Bradley Udall to be a member of the Board of Trustees of the Morris K. Udall Scholarship and Excellence in National Environmental Policy Foundation, reappointment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nomination of Roger Romulus Martella, Jr. to be an Assistant Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, General Counsel.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="801">S. 801</bill>, a bill to designate a United States courthouse in Fresno, CA, as the Robert E. Coyle United States Courthouse.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="521">S. 521</bill>, a bill to designate the Federal building and courthouse in Duluth, MN, as the Gerald W. Heaney Federal Building and United States Courthouse and Customhouse.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="992">S. 992</bill>, The Public Buildings Cost Reduction Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>S.  __X, The Water Resources Development Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="496">S. 496</bill>, The Appalachian Regional Development Act Amendments of 2007 as revised.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="COMMITTEE ON FINANCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Finance be authorized to meet during the Session of the Senate on Thursday, March 29, 2007, at 10 a.m., in 215 Dirksen Senate Office Building, to hear testimony on "Clean Energy: From the Margins to the Mainstream."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, March 29, 2007, at 9:30 a.m. to hold a hearing on Iran.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="COMMITTEE ON INDIAN AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Indian Affairs be authorized to meet on Thursday, March 29, 2007, at 9:15 a.m. in room 485 of the Russell Senate Office Building to conduct an oversight hearing on Indian trust fund litigation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Those wishing additional information may contact the Indian Affairs Committee at 224-2251.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet to conduct a hearing on "Preserving Prosecutorial Independence: Is the Department of Justice Politicizing the Hiring and Firing of U.S. Attorneys?--Part III" on Thursday, March 29, 2007 at 10 a.m. in Dirksen Senate Office Building Room 226.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>D. Kyle Sampson, Former Chief of Staff to the Attorney General of the United States.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet to conduct a markup on Thursday, March 29, 2007, at 2 p.m. in Dirksen Room 226.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Agenda</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I. Committee Authorization: Authorization of Subpoenas in Connection with Investigation into Replacement of U.S. Attorneys.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>II. Bills: <bill type="s" number="236">S. 236</bill>. Federal Agency Data Mining Reporting Act of 2007, Feingold, Sununu, Leahy, Kennedy, Cardin; <bill type="s" number="376">S. 376</bill>. Law Enforcement Officers Safety Act of 2007, Leahy, Specter, Grassley, Kyl, Sessions, Cornyn; <bill type="s" number="849">S. 849</bill>. OPEN Government Act, Leahy, Cornyn, Specter, Feingold; <bill type="s" number="119">S. 119</bill>. War Profiteering Prevention Act of 2007, Leahy, Feinstein, Feingold, Schumer, Durbin; <bill type="s" number="621">S. 621</bill>. Wartime Treatment Study Act of 2007, Feingold, Grassley, Kennedy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>III. Resolutions: <bill type="sr" number="108">S. Res. 108</bill>. Designating the first week of April 2007 as "National Asbestos Awareness Week," Baucus, Leahy, Kennedy, Feinstein, Durbin.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="COMMITTEE ON SMALL BUSINESS AND ENTREPRENEURSHIP">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate for a markup entitled, "Small Business Disaster Response and Loan Improvements Act of 2007"on Thursday, March 29, 2007, beginning at 9:30 a.m. in room 428A of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="COMMITTEE ON VETERANS' AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Veterans' Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, March 29, 2007 at 9:30 a.m. in room 226 of the Dirksen Senate Office  Building, to hear the legislative presentation of the AMVETS, American Ex-Prisoners of War, Military Order of the Purple Heart, Gold Star Wives of America, Fleet Reserve Association, The Retired Enlisted Association, Military Officers  Association of America, and the National Association of State Directors of Veterans Affairs.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="SELECT COMMITTEE ON INTELLIGENCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Select Committee on Intelligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on March 29, 2007 at 2:30 p.m. to hold a closed hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON FEDERAL FINANCIAL MANAGEMENT, GOVERNMENT INFORMATION, FEDERAL SERVICES, AND INTERNATIONAL SECURITY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on Federal Financial Management, Government Information, Federal Services and International Security be authorized to meet on Thursday, March 29, 2007 at 10 a.m. for a hearing entitled, Eliminating and Recovering Improper Payments.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON FEDERAL FINANCIAL MANAGEMENT, GOVERNMENT INFORMATION, FEDERAL SERVICES, AND INTERNATIONAL SECURITY">
    <paragraph>It is my understanding a quorum call is not in progress.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> It is not. The leader is correct.</chair>
</record>
