<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1221753612" ordinal="39" title="PROTECTION FROM CHILD PREDATORS">
  <narrative>PROTECTION FROM CHILD PREDATORS -- (Senate - September 18, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="9015">S9015</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300002" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today I joined as a cosponsor of two bills to protect children: <bill type="s" number="1738">S. 1738</bill>, the Combating Child Exploitation Act; and <bill type="s" number="519">S. 519</bill>, the Securing Adolescents from Exploitation-Online--SAFE--Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am cosponsoring <bill type="s" number="1738">S. 1738</bill> to signal my support for this bipartisan effort to create a nationwide network of highly trained law enforcement experts to track down and prosecute child predators who exploit children, but it is my hope that Congress would enact the modified version of this legislation that was included in bills separately introduced by the majority leader--S. 3297--and Senator Coburn--S. 3344.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, both bills have been held up by partisan gridlock despite widespread support on both sides of the aisle. In fact, the House version of the SAFE Act--H.R. 3791--passed the House of Representatives by a vote of 409-2 in December 2007. That is why I believe that both bills <bill type="h" number="3791">H.R. 3791</bill> and the modified version of <bill type="s" number="1738">S. 1738</bill> could pass by unanimous consent if they were called up and passed together.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is time to stop playing politics, bring these bills to the Senate floor and let the Senate approve them. Child exploitation is too important a problem to get caught up in partisan politics. I urge the majority leader to call up and pass these two bills without delay, and without either being attached to other legislation that could prevent them from becoming law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I can't think of a more bipartisan step for the Senate to take this month than ending this impasse and passing these two worthwhile bills to protect children.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
