<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1179763212" ordinal="9" title="COMPREHENSIVE IMMIGRATION REFORM ACT OF 2007">
  <chair> Under the previous order the motion to proceed is agreed to.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> The Senator from West Virginia is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I thank the chair for the effort he has taken. I hesitate very much to impose on the time of the Senate. But there ought to be a time now and then when one might impose on the time of the Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me read from the Standing Orders of the Senate, Standing Order 105.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Hear this: "Resolved, That it is a standing order of the Senate that during yea and nay votes in the Senate, each Senator shall vote from the assigned desk of the Senator."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I always try to do that, Mr. President.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That was by <bill type="sr" number="480">S. Res. 480</bill>, 90th Congress, second session. October 11, 1984. I will tell you who authored that resolution. That was my former colleague, my former late colleague Jennings Randolph. I have never forgotten it. Once in a while, I vote from the well of the Senate, and sometimes I cast my vote from here. But that is what this book says: "Resolved, that it is a standing order of the Senate that during yea and nay votes in the Senate, each Senator shall vote from the assigned desk of the  Senator."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There was a reason for that. I won't take the time of the Senate this evening to talk about this further, but I will have something to say one day about that. "[E]ach Senator shall vote from the assigned desk of the Senator. <bill type="sr" number="480">S. Res. 480</bill>, 90th Congress, second session, October 11, 1984.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>May God bless his name, Jennings Randolph.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank the Senate, and I thank the Chair.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Massachusetts.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, as always, we thank the Senator from West Virginia for insisting that Senate decorum be enforced. All of us understand his devotion to this institution and to its ability to function in an effective and efficient way. He reminds us, and we need to be reminded at times. We thank him. I remember Jennings Randolph making those points time and time again about standing at one's desk. That was back at another time, but I certainly remember his service to the country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So we have some idea of the way we are going to proceed, I have been notified, although I haven't had an opportunity to talk either to Senator Specter or Senator Kyl or others on the other side, that we have two amendments at least that are going to deal with the temporary worker provision, one which would effectively strike all of the temporary worker provisions that will be probably offered by the Senator from North Dakota, and another amendment which will be the amendment  to reduce the number of temporary workers from 400,000 to 200,000. Those were amendments similar to the ones we had the last time we had the immigration bill. We had a good discussion, and we will have that debate, but we don't expect, obviously, that we will be voting this evening. We are prepared to involve or engage in the debate or discussion, if those Members want to, but it will be our hope that those amendments would be done in a timely way for tomorrow. It is a good way</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I hope that will be the beginning of the debate. We will talk to those Members to try to give the membership as much notice as possible to address those issues in a timely way. They have indicated their desire to start with those. We would expect that to be done.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
