<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1207670402" ordinal="25" title="HOUSING">
  <narrative>HOUSING -- (Senate - April 08, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="2720">S2720</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300002" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, yesterday I made a few remarks about an amendment Senator Kyl and I have offered to an Ensign-Cantwell amendment, and today I wish to place in the  Congressional Record a couple of documents.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In May 2007, I requested that the Energy Information Administration conduct a study of Federal subsidies of electricity, including a comparison of subsidies for different fuel types. Last week, I received a 250-page study in response to my request.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent to have printed in the Record the following: a copy of my May 17, 2007, letter to the EIA Administrator, Guy Caruso; a copy of the April 2, 2008, cover letter from Mr. Caruso that arrived with the EIA's 250-page study; and finally, a table titled "Federal Subsidies of Electric Power" that is based on information that was included in the executive summary of EIA's study.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>U.S. SENATE,</narrative>
  <narrative>Washington, DC, May 17, 2007.</narrative>
  <narrative>Dear Mr. Caruso: I am writing to request that the Energy Information Administration (ETA) conduct an analysis of federal subsidies of the electricity industry, including a comparison of subsidies for the different fuel types (e.g., coal, natural gas, petroleum, nuclear, wind, solar, etc.). I am interested in learning--for each fuel type--both (1) the overall annual cost of those subsidies, and (2) the annual cost per unit electricity generated (e.g., cost per kilowatt-hour). My staff  is familiar with the EIA report Federal Financial Interventions and Subsidies in Energy Markets 1999: Energy Transformation and End Use and understands that this new analysis will serve as an update of significant portions of this prior analysis with a focus on subsidies available to electricity and primary fuels used in electricity generation.</narrative>
  <narrative>To expedite its completion, the analysis should be limited to subsidies provided by the federal government, those that are energy-specific, and those that provide a financial benefit with an identifiable federal budget impact. Broad policies or programs that are applicable throughout the economy need not be considered. The analysis should include the following types of subsidies: tax expenditures (such as deductions, credits, and loan guarantees); direct expenditures (such as direct grant programs  and the Low Income Home Energy Assistance Program); federal research and development programs targeting electricity and its fuel inputs; and federal electricity programs (such as support for the Bonneville Power Administration).</narrative>
  <narrative>The report should include an estimate on the size of each subsidy over a recent, representative year. Where there has been a significant change in the amount or scope of a particular subsidy since the 2000 report, it would be useful for the report to provide an explanation for the change. If a valid methodology can be developed, a forecast of subsidy impacts would be very informative as well. To be most helpful, I would appreciate it if the report could be completed by November 30, 2007.</narrative>
  <narrative>Thank you for your assistance with this matter. If you have any questions, please contact Mr. Jack Wells of my staff.</narrative>
  <narrative>Sincerely,</narrative>
  <narrative>&lt;pre&gt;--&lt;/pre&gt;</narrative>
  <narrative>DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY,</narrative>
  <narrative>Dear Senator Alexander: In response to your letter of May 17, 2007, I am providing the enclosed analysis of Federal subsidies and support for energy markets, with emphasis on the electricity industry. The analysis includes a comparison of per unit subsidies for the different fuel types used to generate electricity. I hope you will find this analysis to be of assistance.</narrative>
  <narrative>Should you have any questions, please contact me, or your staff may contact Scott Sitzer, Director of the Office of Coal, Nuclear, Electric and Alternate Fuels.</narrative>
  <narrative>Sincerely,</narrative>
  <narrative>Administrator, </narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300002" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask through the Chair whether there is more time or whether the Chair would like to reclaim the time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Montana.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I am not managing this part of the bill. I think Senator Dodd is talking to Senators. They are working out some provisions, so if he wants to proceed until they work it out.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from California is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, perhaps I will proceed with my statement on morning business, and then, when we return to the bill, I wish to call up the amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Is that agreeable to the Senator from Tennessee?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask how much time the Senator from Tennessee would like to speak. If it is a short amount of time----</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300002" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, if it is agreeable with the other Senators, I ask unanimous consent for 4 minutes, to be followed by the Senator from California.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="">
    <paragraph>Reserving the right to object.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300034" topic="">
    <paragraph>Reserving the right to object, Mr. President.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Everybody is trying to extend morning business while we are waiting.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Tennessee has requested unanimous consent to speak for up to 4 minutes as in morning business.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300034" topic="">
    <paragraph>I have no objection.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
