<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1173974406" ordinal="44" title="STATEMENTS ON INTRODUCED BILLS AND JOINT RESOLUTIONS">
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="Introducing S. 888. A bill to amend section 1091 of title 18, United States Code, to allow the prosecution of genocide in appropriate circumstances; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="888">S. 888</bill>] Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400576" topic="Introducing S. 888. A bill to amend section 1091 of title 18, United States Code, to allow the prosecution of genocide in appropriate circumstances; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today as the lead Republican sponsor of the Genocide Accountability Act of 2007. I thank my colleague, Senator Durbin, for introducing this important piece of legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator Durbin serves as the chairman and I serve as the ranking member of the new Subcommittee on Human Rights and the Law in the Senate Judiciary Committee. We held our first hearing, entitled "Genocide and the Rule of Law," on February 5, 2007. There could not be a more appropriate way to begin examining the law as it relates to human rights than to determine what we can and must do to prevent and stop genocide. The United States is a signatory of the Convention on the Prevention  and Punishment of the Crime of Genocide. This convention provides that the contracting parties must "undertake to prevent and to punish" the crime of genocide. We have also passed a law implementing the Genocide Convention.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, our hearing demonstrated that there are changes that need to be made in law and foreign policy to respond to the ongoing genocide in Sudan and to any genocide that may occur elsewhere in the future. Fortunately, two of these changes can be accomplished right now.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The first change can be accomplished through a bill Senators Durbin and Cornyn introduced last week, of which I am a cosponsor. That bill, the Sudan Divestment Authorization Act of 2007, will allow State and local governments to prohibit the investment of State assets in the Government of Sudan or companies with certain business relationships with Sudan, while the Government of Sudan is subject to sanctions under U.S. law. The second change can be accomplished through the bill  we are introducing today, the Genocide Accountability Act of 2007. This act will ensure that our justice system has the authority to prosecute someone who has committed genocide if that person is found or brought into the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under current law, the United States can deny admission to and exclude aliens from the United States on human rights grounds. The Attorney General can also consider avenues for the prosecution of aliens who have committed certain crimes, including genocide. However, the Attorney General can only prosecute a perpetrator of genocide if he committed his crimes within the United States or is a U.S. national.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What does this mean? It means that if a person who plans or participates in the genocide occurring right now in Darfur travels to the United States on vacation, business, or even to live here for an extended period of time--as a refugee or student, for instance--a court in the United States cannot touch him. The best our justice system can do is deport him once his crime is discovered.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Without question, it may be more appropriate in some cases to extradite someone who commits genocide to his home country or turn him over to an international tribunal. However, there are also times when a person's home country may not be willing to prosecute him and there is no viable alternative for prosecution. In these cases, extraditing a criminal would be no different than setting him free. This bill will not force our justice system to prosecute those who commit genocide just because they  are found on our soil--it simply gives us the option. Nonetheless, in America we are blessed with great resources and the most effective and just legal system in the world. With these blessings comes great responsibility. It is contrary to our system of justice to allow perpetrators of genocide to go free without fear of prosecution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It simply makes no sense to withhold from our justice system the authority to prosecute someone who is found in the United States and who committed a crime as atrocious as genocide just because he is not American and did not commit the crime here. We have passed tough laws that ensure that we can prosecute anyone found in the United States who has committed terrorist acts or supports terrorism. We do not want to become a safe haven for terrorists, so I ask: Do we want to be a safe haven for those  who have committed genocide? The answer should be clear.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Fundamentally, we must decide if genocide is a bad enough crime, no matter where it happens, that it warrants the same treatment as terrorism-related crimes. I deeply believe that it is, and that is why I am proud to cosponsor this bill today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300056" topic="Introducing S. 890. A bill to provide for certain administrative and support services for the Dwight D. Eisenhower Memorial Commission, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="890">S. 890</bill>] Mr. President, the Eisenhower Memorial Commission was created by the U.S. Congress in 1999 as a bipartisan commission for the purpose of considering and formulating plans for the location, design and construction of a permanent memorial to President Dwight D. Eisenhower to perpetuate his memory and his contributions to the United States. Since being fully appointed in 2001, the Commission considered twenty-six different sites in the District of Columbia. In 2005, it selected a site  between the Department of Education and the National Air and Space Museum, two institutions resulting from and greatly influenced by President Eisenhower's leadership.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 2006, Congress approved the memorial's location within Area I, in compliance with the Commemorative Works Act. The Commission secured full approval for the selected site following extensive review by the National Park Service, the National Capital Memorial Advisory Commission, the National Capital Planning Commission, and the Commission of Fine Arts. Since its inception, the Commission has also taken great care to study and analyze President Eisenhower's legacy. It produced a report by leading  scholars and experts on President Eisenhower that provides a definitive statement on the transcending elements of President Eisenhower's enduring legacy. He ranks as one of the preeminent figures in the global history of the 20th century.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Eisenhower Memorial Commission now needs to move into the design phase. As design begins, the Commission's organization, specifically with regard to contracting and staffing, needs to be updated and revised to enable efficient management and responsible stewardship. The proposed legislation which I introduce today provides for the necessary reorganization. I am joined by Senators Stevens, Roberts, and Hagel as original cosponsors of the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation enables the Commission to retain the services of full, part-time, and volunteer staff as government employees, without the restrictions of the competitive service requirements. It also provides the authority for the Commission's Executive Architect to manage technical and administrative aspects of design and construction. It provides for staff to be released on the completion of the memorial and enables the Commission to work in collaboration with federal agencies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>President Eisenhower spent his entire life in public service. His extraordinary contributions include serving as Supreme Commander of the Allied Expeditionary Forces in World War II and as 34th President of the United States, but President Eisenhower also served as the first commander of NATO and as President of Columbia University. Dramatic changes occurred in America during his lifetime, many of which he participated in and influenced through his extraordinary leadership as President.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although President Eisenhower grew up before automobiles existed, he created the Interstate Highway System and took America into space. He created the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, and the Federal Aviation Administration. He added the State of Hawaii and the State of Alaska to the United States and ended the Korean War. President Eisenhower desegregated the District of Columbia and sent Federal troops into Little Rock, Arkansas,  to enforce school integration. He defused international crises and inaugurated the national security policies that guided the nation for the next three decades, leading to the peaceful end of the Cold War.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A career soldier, President Eisenhower championed peace, freedom, justice and security, and, as President, he stressed the interdependence of those goals. He spent a lifetime fulfilling his duty to his country, always remembering to ask: What is best for America?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>President Eisenhower once said, "I know that the American people share my belief that if a danger exists in the world, it is a danger shared by all; and equally, that if hope exists in the mind of one nation, that hope should be shared by all." President Eisenhower's legacy provides hope to all of us--like him, through education and public service, we, as a nation and individually, can rise to meet any challenge. Accordingly, I urge my colleagues to support this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of my bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300055" topic="Introducing S. 891. A bill to protect children and their parents from being coerced into administering a controlled substance in order to attend school, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="891">S. 891</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today, along with my colleague, TOM COBURN, to proudly reintroduce the Child Medication Safety Act, a bill to protect children and their parents from being coerced into administering a controlled substance or psychotropic drug in order to attend a school.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Parents today face many challenges when raising their children, one of which is ensuring that their children receive the best education possible. My views on education come from a somewhat unique perspective in that my wife, Kay, was a teacher at Edison High School in Tulsa for many years and now both of our daughters are teachers. I can assure you that I am one of the strongest supporters of quality education. However, it has come to my attention that schools have been acting as physicians or  psychologists by strongly suggesting that children with behavioral problems be put immediately on some form of psychotropic drugs. Schools and teachers are not equipped to make this diagnosis and should not make it mandatory for the student to continue attending the school. This is clearly beyond their area of expertise. Therefore, I am introducing this legislation to ensure that parents are not required by school personnel to medicate their children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Child Medication Safety Act requires, as a condition of receiving funds from the Department of Education, that States develop and implement polices and procedures prohibiting school personnel from requiring a child to obtain a prescription as a condition of attending the school. It should be noted that this bill does not prevent teachers or other school personnel from sharing with parents or guardians classroom-based observations regarding a student's academic performance or regarding the  need for evaluation for special education. Additionally, this bill calls for a study by the Comptroller General of the United States reviewing: (1) the variation among States in the definition of psychotropic medication as used in public education, (2) the prescription rates of medication used in public schools to treat children with attention deficit disorder</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe this is an extremely important bill that protects the rights of our children against improper intrusion regarding health issues by those not qualified. If a parent or guardian believes their child is in need of medication, then they have the right to make that decision and consult with a licensed medical practitioner who is qualified to prescribe an appropriate drug. Please join us in support of this legislation that protects the freedoms of our children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="892">S. 892</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to introduce the Capital Gains Inflation Relief Act of 2007. The taxation of inflation is one of the most unjust practices of the tax code. This simple improvement will not only enhance the basic fairness and efficiency of the tax code, but will also immediately increase the net return on capital investment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under current law, a taxable capital gain occurs whenever a capital asset is sold at a price higher than the original purchase price. However, the timing of capital gains taxation sets it apart from other types of income. While wages are generally taxed on a yearly basis, the taxation on capital assets occurs at the time the capital asset holder chooses to sell his asset and realize  his gains. The gains on capital assets accrue over the course of the  asset's life, which is usually many years. This is generally favorable to the capital asset holder, because he can defer taxation on his gains to a future year. This tax deferral is often cited as the primary reason for holding assets long term.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, the value of tax deferral is often times overstated because current tax policy taxes the capital asset holder not only on real gains, but also on gains due to inflation. This creates a situation that is patently unfair to the American taxpayer. For example, an American who purchased a share of stock for $10 in 1950 and sold it for twice that amount today would be subject to capital gains taxes on the nominal gain of $10, though the transaction was a clear loss when one accounts for inflation.  Why should an American taxpayer, who invested in a capital asset in his youth, be forced to pay capital gains taxes, on what can only be viewed as a loss, in his later years? In spite of all our efforts to curb inflation, it will remain a fact of life. This does not mean we should tax hard-working Americans with long-term goals on gains that are due to inflation, gains that they will never actually realize.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Without an inflation index, the tax code incentivizes short-term speculation and discourages long-term capital investment. The current turmoil in the subprime lending market is an example that demonstrates the perils of emphasizing short-term speculation over long-term capital investment. Though inflation has remained relatively modest recently, there is no guarantee of future stability. Inflation indexing would instantly increase the net return on capital investment and consequently encourage  more of it. Inflation indexing would also restore core principles of sound tax policy such as "horizontal equity," wherein two taxpayers in identical situations are treated identically by the tax system. Indexing capital gains would improve the basic fairness of the tax code with only a minor increase in administrative costs and a single step of simple multiplication for taxpayer compliance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The need for indexing is clear. It would help average Americans and improve tax policy by enhancing both the basic fairness and the pro-growth incentive of the tax code. The merits of the capital gains tax are themselves debatable, but if we are to tax capital gains let us make sure they are taxed fairly. Please join with me in supporting this legislation to free the American taxpayer from the unfairness of the current tax policy.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300022" topic="Introducing S. 895. A bill to amend titles XIX and XXI of the Social Security Act to ensure that every child in the United States has access to affordable, quality health insurance coverage, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="895">S. 895</bill>] Mr. President, I was proud to help create the State Children's Health Insurance Program during the Clinton Administration. It has provided health insurance for 6 million children, including more than 425,000 in New York. SCHIP was the biggest expansion in providing health insurance coverage in more than 30 years--a big first step to providing quality health care coverage for all children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And now it is time to take the next step. Today, I am introducing new legislation with my colleague from the House of Representatives, Chairman DINGELL: a plan to make quality affordable health care available to every child in America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Children's Health First Act will make quality, affordable health care available to all children, and will pave the way to cover the more than nine million children in our country without health coverage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our bill cuts red tape to allow States to provide affordable healthcare options for all families to cover their children. It gives States the financial incentives and resources to expand--existing State coverage and find and enroll the 6 million children who are currently eligible for health coverage but are not enrolled. And it provides incentives to expand employer sponsored coverage for children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As individuals and as a Nation, an ounce of prevention is truly worth a pound of cure. Health care accessible and affordable for all children will keep kids healthy, save lives, control costs, and end heartache and worry for so many parents. This plan is practical and fiscally responsible--it will honor our values and prevent kids from needing more costly healthcare in the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our bill will provide incentives for States to expand SCHIP to more children and provide health coverage for children up to 400 percent of poverty, about $70,000 for a family of three.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Parents whose incomes are above their State's SCHIP eligibility levels and employers who want to provide coverage to dependents will also have the option to buy-in to the SCHIP program. This will ensure that all families have access to affordable coverage and aren't forced into the private insurance market where affordable options for their children are often out of reach.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And while expanding coverage is critical, enrolling children who are already eligible must also be part of our efforts to ensure every child has health insurance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Currently, there are 6 million uninsured children who are eligible for public programs but not enrolled. In order to receive expanded Federal funding under our bill, States must undertake strategies designed to enhance outreach and enrollment of currently eligible children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, the Children's Health First Act would prevent funding shortfalls like those that 14 States are currently facing. Unlike the original SCHIP bill our legislation would determine funding based on State spending and indexed to medical inflation and child population growth so that states will get the funds they need.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Every child deserves a healthy start in life. This goes to the heart of our values, our responsibility to one another, the promise of our country. Far too many children in our Nation--more than 9 million--do not have health care. And, for the first time in nearly a decade, between 2004 and 2005, the number of uninsured children in New York increased by 61,000--part of a trend nationally.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It's simply wrong that there are working parents who worry about their children playing sports because they can't afford a doctor if their child gets hurt. I've met parents who when their children get sick fret and worry about their children's illness--but have the added anxiety of wondering how they are going to pay for the doctor visit. That just shouldn't happen.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>No child in America, the greatest, richest Nation on Earth home to so much promise, should lack for the care he or she needs to grow up to be a healthy, happy adult.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We can tackle this challenge--and provide access to quality, affordable health care for all children in America. It's the right thing to do, and it's the smart thing to do.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am proud to introduce this legislation. It will help us honor our values, protect our children. We can meet this challenge and that's what I'll be working with Chairman DINGELL and my Senate colleagues to achieve this year.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300075" topic="Introducing S. 896. A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act and the Social Security Act to increase the number of primary care physicians and medical residents serving health professional shortage areas, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="896">S. 896</bill>] Mr. President, I rise again this evening to speak about a growing crisis in rural America. This crisis is found in rural New England, throughout Appalachia, spans the Great Plains, crosses the Western deserts, and reaches the mountains of the great Northwest. It impacts the seniors, children, the women, and the men of rural America. What I am speaking about today is a lack of access to quality health care.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In rural America, patients have long gone without care. Despite the fact that one-fifth of the U.S. population lives in rural America, only 9 percent of the Nation's physicians are practicing in these areas. Over 50 million of these rural Americans live in areas that have a shortage of physicians to meet their basic needs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, physician recruitment to rural America is a big problem. Part of this problem comes about through high student debt, which often forces many students away from a rural practice and  into urban specialty medicine where they can probably command higher salaries.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I recently held a Senate HELP Committee field hearing in Alaska. This was during the February recess. I held this field committee hearing on the physician shortage crisis in rural America. At that hearing, I had a young woman come up and speak. She is a medical student who is currently part of the WAMI Program, the Western States medical program. This young woman, Melissa Howell, is 26 years old. She stated the student debt she has accumulated is a huge concern that hangs over the decisions she  makes as she decides where she is going to practice. Simply put, she said that the $100,000 student debt she faces is "kind of scary." I have to admit, that is kind of scary.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A dozen States already report severe physician shortages. These shortages exist in the areas of cardiology, radiology, neurology, to name a few. But the greatest shortages persistently have been in primary care. In fact, the shortage of primary care physicians in rural areas of the United States represents one of the most intractable health policy problems of the past century.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It will only worsen. In 20 years, 20 percent of the U.S. population will be 65 or older, and this is a percentage larger than at any other time in our Nation's history. Just as this aging population places the highest demand on our health care system, we have some experts who predict a national shortage of close to 200,000 physicians. If that becomes a reality, 84 million patients could be potentially left without a doctor's care.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So the question has to be asked, where are the doctors going? We are losing some of our doctors through attrition. One-third of physicians are 55 years old and older and are likely to retire as this baby boom generation moves into its time of greatest medical need. Additionally, for the last quarter of a century, medical schools have kept their student enrollments virtually flat.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are also losing a lot of our doctors, quite simply, through frustration. Low Medicare and Medicaid reimbursement rates, coupled with complex regulations and paperwork, leave physicians aggravated, leave them disappointed with the practice of medicine.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In Alaska, we have lived with provider shortages since statehood. I grew up in a part of the State down in the southeastern area where you did not have doctors who were available to deliver babies except on Tuesdays and Thursdays. You hoped you could give birth on a Tuesday or a Thursday. Still, in many parts of our State, we do not have providers who can deliver. If you are out in the Aleutian chain, you are told by your physician's attendant to come to Anchorage, some 600 miles away, to wait  out the remaining month of your pregnancy because they do not have the facilities, do not have the doctors available to take care of you in the event of an emergency.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So we have lived with provider shortages for a long time. Because our State is larger than Texas and California and Montana combined, "rural" brings on a new meaning and the physician shortage crisis is even more amplified, as I have given in my two examples. But we have had some recent events in the State that have created a situation far worse than Alaska has known in the past. Currently, in the State, we have the sixth lowest ratio of physicians to population in the United States. That is  when you take into account Anchorage, which is our largest population center. In rural Alaska, it is the worst physician-to-population situation in the Nation. Alaska needs nearly 400 more doctors to provide the same level of care as elsewhere in the country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One of our problems is we do not have a medical school, and we are not likely to be getting a medical school in the near future. We also have the lowest per capita number of medical school slots in the country and the lowest number of residency slots. We have two small but very successful programs; this is the University of Washington Medical School Partnership and the Alaska Family Residency Program. These two programs help train Alaskans as physicians and also help us bring doctors to Alaska.  But despite the success of these programs, each is far too small to meet our population's needs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Each week, without fail, I receive faxes, phone calls, letters, and e-mails from Alaskan seniors who simply cannot find a doctor to treat them. I wish to read a few excerpts from recent e-mails we have received. The first one is from a gentleman in Anchorage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Keep in mind, Anchorage is our largest population center; about half the population of the State is here.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He writes:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My mother ..... has had difficulty in the extreme in getting a doctor who will take her on as she is a medicare patient ..... doctors are telling potential patients that they are no longer taking medicaid. My mother has made in excess of 100 calls to physicians in Anchorage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Another constituent writes--and this is also from Anchorage:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>During the past year, I've tried to find a doctor that accepts Medicare. I used the Anchorage Yellow pages and called over 100 doctors, only to be told that they won't accept any more Medicare patients.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>She then writes to say:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I'll tell you ahead of time, we'll be going to the hospital emergency rooms, to receive, even the basic medical care, i.e.: colds, flu, and other basic medical care, that could have been treated through seeing a doctor, at their established practice. This doesn't sound like good fiscal management.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Another constituent--and this was actually in a letter to the editor in the Anchorage Daily News--says:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My friends telephoned more than 80 doctors recently, and not one was accepting new Medicare patients.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A third gentleman from Kenai, AK, writes:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My mom has Medicare and she had to wait 5 months to be seen by a Neurologist because she had been put on a waiting list to be seen due to the fact she was a Medicare patient.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Another woman from Anchorage says:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I just got through trying to find a physician for an elderly Medicare-dependent friend. At this time I have found no one who will take her. Most physicians take no Medicare patients or have a quota which is full. The Providence health care provider list has no one who takes Medicare.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The last e-mail was from Anchorage stating:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Almost no family practice office in Anchorage is accepting new Medicare patients.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is just a sample of what we get from constituents around the State of Alaska saying: I don't have anyone who can see my mother. I can't get in to see anyone myself.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I mentioned in my comments this is a crisis that is growing. In Alaska, we don't often think of it as being a State where we have a large senior population. We think of some of the Southern States as being the ones that attract our seniors. But the fact is Alaska has the second fastest-growing senior population in the Nation, second only to Nevada.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So again we ask the question: Why aren't Alaska's doctors able to provide care to our seniors? Why are they saying: No, we are not accepting any new Medicare patients? Well, a lot of it has to do with the reimbursement rates. Recent Federal reductions in Alaska Medicare reimbursement rates have been so severe that primary care physicians report that Medicare pays them only 37 cents--it is actually between 37 cents to 40 cents--for every dollar that it costs to treat a patient. So the doctor is  spending a dollar in the care provided but is getting reimbursed about 40 cents to every dollar. We had one physician testify at the field hearing, and he said that in order for him to basically break even with his medical practice, he would have to see one Medicare</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Losing money by seeing Medicare patients has meant that many of our physicians have stopped accepting Medicare patients entirely. They are making a decision not to accept any new Medicare patients. Or if you have been a patient of a particular physician and you turn 65, you may have had a good relationship with that physician, but if he tells you: I am sorry, I am not accepting any new Medicare patients, that date of your birthday comes and all of a sudden you don't have the care that you had  relied on for some period of time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>During this committee field hearing, we had testimony that revealed that  only one neighborhood health clinic in the entire city of Anchorage--and again, this is a city that has half the State's population--only one neighborhood health clinic is still accepting new Medicare patients.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So if you are lucky enough to find a physician, it often takes weeks or months for an appointment. So when you are faced with this kind of a delay, you have one of two options. You either go to the emergency room if the conditions are severe enough or you go without care entirely, putting it off until perhaps it becomes even more complicated down the road.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We had testify at the field hearing one gentleman who is from the city of Bethel. Bethel is in the western part of the State. He said he was willing to fly the 500-some-odd miles from Bethel to Anchorage if only he could find a primary care doctor who would accept him. He kind of joked because he said he counted himself lucky because he had a heart condition, and he was at least able to get in to see a specialist once in awhile.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The chairman of the Alaska Commission on Aging, Mr. Frank Appel, called the lack of access to health care for seniors "the most critical problem facing Alaska's seniors."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I know Alaska is not alone. The crisis is not just Alaska. It is nationwide. We as a body, as a Congress, should find this situation intolerable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I haven't been in the Senate for as long as many of my other colleagues, but I have been here long enough to know that we fight a lot about health care. We debate the solvency issues, the funding issues, the insurance, the benefit coverage, universal coverage, health savings accounts, the prescription drug benefit. We debate and argue about a lot of these issues as they relate to health care, and each and every one of these issues is certainly worthy of great debate. But I would submit that not  one of those very worthy debates matters in the least to one of the seniors I have mentioned in these letters who can't find a primary care doctor after making 100 phone calls.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So instead of this body debating how health care is delivered, it is time we focus on the fact that it is not delivered in much of America. We have a crisis that, simply put, cannot wait. We have to do two things. We have to help current physicians stay in the practice of medicine, and we must vastly increase our health care work force.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Earlier this year, Senator Stevens and I introduced the Rural Physician Relief Act, and this is a bill that provides tax incentives for physicians to practice in our most rural and frontier locations in the country. Today, along with my colleagues, Senator Schumer, Senator Stevens, and Senator Sanders, we are introducing legislation entitled the "Physician Shortage Elimination Act." This legislation will double the funding for the National Health Service  Corps, a program that is dedicated to meeting the needs of the underserved. Despite its success over the years, it has been vastly underfunded. We understand that 85 percent of the applicants to this worthy program have to be turned away each year because we don't fund it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation will also allow rural and underserved physician residency programs to expand by removing barriers that prevent programs from developing rural training programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We will also double certain title VII funding to create programs that target disadvantaged youth in rural and underserved areas and nurture them to create a pipeline to careers in health care. We need to get more people interested in the field.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, we must bolster the cornerstone of rural health care, which is the community health center, through additional grants and by allowing them to expand their residency programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would suggest that the prognosis for the quality of health care in America is poor. Fifteen million Americans in underserved areas across the Nation already do without care. Soon, with even greater physician shortages, it could mean that potentially another 84 million patients will be left without a physician's care.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The time for Congress to act is now. In fact, it is past time. I look forward to working with my colleagues on this issue that again is not just Alaska-specific. I think the facts on the ground up North perhaps make the arguments more accentuated, but I think it points to a situation in this Nation that we must deal with now before the crisis is felt throughout the country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I appreciate the attention of the Chair.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="Introducing S. 897. A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide more help to Alzheimer's disease caregivers; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="897">S. 897</bill>] Mr. President, I am pleased to join in cosponsoring the Alzheimer's Family Assistance Act of 2007 introduced by my colleague, Senator Mikulski.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As much as we all would like to think that we will remain healthy and strong throughout our lifetimes, many of us will need long-term care. The cost of that care, whether provided in a nursing home, assisted living facility, or in one's own home with the assistance of health aides, can quickly add up. That is why we should do everything we can to make people aware of long-term care insurance and to ensure that policies are affordable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We need to encourage people to include long-term care insurance in their planning, especially when people are younger and premiums would be lower. The Deficit Reduction Act of 2005, DRA, made good progress in that regard by expanding State long-term care partnership programs. In addition, the DRA established an information clearinghouse to help individuals learn about long-term care insurance options in their states.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We also need to encourage older individuals to purchase long-term care insurance. By establishing a deduction for long-term care insurance premiums, this legislation will help accomplish that goal. In order to qualify for the deduction, the policy must include several important consumer protections recommended by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners, NAIC. The DRA incorporated the same protections plus some additional NAIC consumer protections into the State long-term care partnership  policies. As this bill moves forward, I look forward to working with Senator Mikulski to ensure consistency in the application of these consumer protections to long-term care policies. Specifically, I hope we can expand the consumer protections in this bill so they are in line with those included in the DRA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, this legislation recognizes that individuals and their caregivers may need assistance in paying for medical supplies, nursing care, and other long-term care expenses. The tax credit called for in the bill, which increases from $1,000 to $3,000 in 2011 and beyond, will help defray these costs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I have long supported the policies included in this legislation and commend my colleague for her work on this important issue.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300034" topic="Introducing S. 899. A bill to amend section 401(b)(2) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 regarding the Federal Pell Grant maximum amount; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="899">S. 899</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today, joined by my colleagues Senators Mikulski, Murray, Sanders, Durbin, Lieberman, Cantwell, Akaka, and Levin, to introduce legislation to amend the Higher Education Act to improve access to college for low- and moderate-income students by raising the authorized maximum Pell grant to $11,600 within 5 years. This bill has the strong support of the American Association of Universities, American Jesuit Colleges and Universities, the American Association  of Community Colleges, the National Association of Independent Colleges and Universities, the American Council on Education, and The Higher Education Consortium for Special Education.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Pell grants were first established in the early 1970s by our former colleague, Senator Claiborne Pell. Pell grants are the largest source of Federal grant aid for college students and make it possible for millions of low- and moderate-income students to attend college. The benefits of Pell grant aid cannot be overstated. Pell grants are beneficial  to individual students as well as our society as a whole. Often, our Nation's great innovators and creative  minds sharpen their skills on college campuses. By increasing the Pell grant, we make a college education more affordable, and thus, make it more likely that qualified and hard working low- and moderate-income students will attend. It would be a significant loss to this great Nation if a generation of individuals were not able to earn a college degree simply because they could not afford to pay for it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1975, the maximum appropriated Pell grant covered 80 percent of the average student's tuition, fees, room, and board at 4-year public universities. In 2005-2006, the average Pell grant covered 33 percent of the total charges at 4-year public universities. That's not just a drop in aid, it's a free-fall. For low- and moderate-income families, the cost of college has also increased as a percentage of income. In 1999 it took 43 percent of a low-income family's income to pay for a college education.  In 1972, it only took 27 percent. The cornerstone of American democracy is providing all citizens with access and opportunities so that through hard work they can achieve the "American dream." We must keep that dream alive by providing students the financial opportunity to attend college.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In order to meet the cost of attending college, many low- and moderate-income students are forced to take out an exorbitant amount in student loans. Upon graduation these students are often faced with an unmanageable debt load. Surveys tell us that students with a significant amount of debt are postponing marriage and having children. Others are choosing their jobs based on where they think they can afford to work. Clearly, we do not want student loan debt to solely drive our young people's goals  and aspirations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over the past several years, the administration has not raised the maximum Pell grant. On top of leaving millions of children behind by underfunding K-12 education, they are also leaving students behind who have done well in school and want the chance to go on to college. If we are serious about leaving no student behind--if we are serious about having a society where equal opportunity for all is more than just rhetoric--then we must increase the Pell grant.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It has been said that investing in a student's future is investing in our Nation's future. We can start investing in our Nation's future by supporting this bill to increase the maximum appropriated Pell grant to $11,600. This bill won't bring the Pell grant's purchasing power back to where it was in 1975, but it is a critical first step. I hope that my colleagues will join me in taking this important step toward ensuring all that have the ability to excel in college are given that opportunity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name=".HATCH" of="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today to introduce the Boy Scouts of America Land Transfer Act of 2007. This important legislation will allow the exchange of two small parcels of land between the Utah Parks Council of the Boy Scouts of America and Brian Head Ski Resort.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1983, the Bureau of Land Management granted the Boy Scouts of America roughly 1,300 acres in Parowan, Utah. The land patent was granted with the stipulation that it be used exclusively for purposes of a Boy Scout camp. The Scout camp, known as Camp Thunder Ridge, is situated in the mountains adjacent to Brian Head Ski Resort and near Cedar Breaks National Monument.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When the land was given to the Scout Camp, a local rancher owned a parcel of land adjacent to the camp and another parcel in the middle of the camp. Upon his retirement, the rancher turned over his parcels, totaling 120 acres, to Brian Head Ski Resort. Thus, the ski resort now owns land in the middle of a Boy Scout Camp.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Boy Scouts and the Resort agree that the land previously owned by the rancher would best be used as part of Camp Thunder Ridge, while certain parcels of the Scout Camp would be of more use to the Ski Resort.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Boy Scouts of America Land Transfer Act would allow the Boy Scouts to exchange 120 acres of their land on the south end of the camp with Brian Head for 120 acres on the eastern side of the camp, including the 40 acres located in the middle of the camp. Because of the stipulations of the original BLM patent given to the Scout Camp, legislation is required to authorize this exchange.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While Camp Thunder Ridge is located in a steep, rough, mountainous area, much of the land the Boy Scouts seek is flat, making it particularly important for the camp. Obtaining the land would make it possible for the Scouts to make the camp shooting area and archery range safer and would allow them to improve and expand their camping facilities. It would also allow for the installation of much-needed septic tanks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am a strong supporter of the Boy Scouts of America. Scout camps, such as Camp Thunder Ridge, give young men the opportunity to learn vital skills, fulfill merit badge requirements, and otherwise improve themselves. This small land exchange will allow Camp Thunder Ridge to do a better job in helping these young men learn and grow.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For its part, Brian Head Ski Resort is seeking to expand their operations and have received preliminary approval from local officials. The local Planning Commission, however, has required them to build an emergency exit for their property. The only place to build such a road is through land owned by the Boy Scouts. The exchange will allow Brian Head to construct the access road and comply with county fire safety regulations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Boy Scouts have been working for more than 20 years to secure the lands in question, and Brian Head needs to build on lands currently owned by the Scouts. Therefore, it would be in the best interest of both parties to authorize this land exchange. In fact, the exchange is desperately needed by both parties, and I urge my colleagues to support this important legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="Introducing S. 901. A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to provide additional authorizations of appropriations for the health centers program under section 330 of such Act, tot he Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="901">S. 901</bill>] Mr. President, it's an honor to join Senator Hatch and my  HELP Committee colleagues today in introducing this bill to reauthorize the community health centers program. The Health Centers Renewal Act extends the program through 2012, it authorizes the funds needed to stabilize existing centers and enable them to increase their capacity and funds for new centers in underserved areas that have no existing center.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The community health centers program has been a success story by any measure over the past 40 years. It began as a two-site demonstration project for "neighborhood health centers" in 1965, with funds for Columbia Point in Massachusetts and Mound Bayou in Mississippi. The health center model was the brainchild of two young physicians and civil rights activists, Dr. H. Jack Geiger and Dr. Count Gibson. Their model was intended to address both health care and the roots of poverty, by giving communities  a voice in their health care through a patient-majority community board, by creating jobs and investments in local communities, and by focusing on primary care and reducing health disparities among income groups.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, more than 1,000 health centers provide good health care to 16 million patients each year. They provide safety nets in their communities for the most vulnerable Americans, and bring care to 1 of every 4 Americans living in poverty. Nearly 70 percent of health center patients have incomes below the poverty line, and two-thirds are members of racial and ethnic minorities. Health centers give those who are so often disenfranchised in our society a voice in their own health care and in the  care available in their community. Health centers are also an incentive for economic growth, providing 50,000 jobs across the country for residents in their communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As the number of uninsured and underinsured persons grows each year, the need for health center services increases. More than 40 percent of health center patients have no health insurance and their number is increasing. Another 36 percent of patients have coverage through Medicaid or CHIP, and cuts in these programs affect health centers as well. As the number of patients who rely on health centers continues to grow, we must provide the funds needed to open new centers in areas that are underserved  and to provide additional funds to enable existing centers to meet the growing demand for care.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The funding authorized in this bill will provide stability and expanded services in existing centers, and enable new centers to open in areas that have no centers today. The legislation will keep health centers on track to serve 20 million patients by 2010 and more than 23 million patients by 2012. It also provides the funds needed to expand existing health centers to reach more uninsured and underinsured patients, open new centers in underserved areas with no current centers, expand coverage  of mental health, dental, and pharmacy services to all centers, invest in information technology, and take other steps to improve health outcomes. Our goal in the bill is to make sure that health centers can provide high-quality care to their patients for years to come, and I look forward to its enactment into law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous request that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300052" topic="Introducing S. 901. A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to provide additional authorizations of appropriations for the health centers program under section 330 of such Act, tot he Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today I am introducing the Health Centers Renewal Act with my colleagues, Senators Kennedy, Roberts, Dodd, Bond, Harkin, Snowe, Mikulski, Domenici, Bingaman, Murkowski, Reed, Bennett, Clinton, Grassley, Obama, Burr and Brown.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Health Centers program, created over 40 years ago, has an outstanding record of providing quality health care services to many Americans who do not have adequate health insurance. This ranges from children to parents and grandparents, in virtually every comer of the United States. In fact, Health Centers are a necessary component of our nation's health care safety net--they supply health services to over 15 million people in our country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Health Centers include community health centers, which are local, not-for-profit 50l(c)(3) corporations that give community-oriented health care and are governed by Boards of Directors that are made up of at least 51 percent health centers patients, to ensure that the patients and their communities are well represented.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>From my work in Utah, I know how important Health Centers are. They have made a tremendous difference for Utah's citizens with insufficient health coverage--Utah community health centers serve close to 85,000 patients. Whenever I come home to Utah, I always hear wonderful things about the work of Community Health Centers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since 2001, Congress has consistently increased funding for Community Health Centers to meet President Bush's goal of having 1,200 new or expanded centers. The new dollars have provided services to four million new patients and have added facilities in over 750 communities across the country. By reauthorizing this program, Health Centers will give low-cost health care to many more deserving individuals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="901">S. 901</bill> I will reauthorize the Health Centers program for 5 more years; it includes funding levels of: $2,188,745,000  in fiscal year 2008; $2,451,394,400 in fiscal year 2009; $2,757,818,700 in fiscal year 2010; $3,116,335,131 in fiscal year 2011; and $3,537,040,374 in fiscal year 2012. These numbers are based on the National Association of Community Health Centers; NACHC, growth plan--NACHC's goal is for Community Health Centers to serve 20 million patients  a year by 2010 and 30 million patients a year by 2015.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe that Community Health Centers are worth every dime that our government invests in them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Utah Health Centers have made a tremendous difference in the lives of many Utahns--66 percent of patients come from Utah's urban areas and 27 percent are from the rural parts of the state. Ninety-six percent of Utah Health Center patients' incomes are below 200 percent of the Federal Poverty Level. Utah Health Centers have literally changed these patients' lives, serving as a link to the health care safety net system for the medically underserved and uninsured. In rural areas, Health Centers  are often the only health care provider.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Community Health Centers have made a huge impact on people's lives. I am pleased and proud to support them by introducing this legislation today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to cosponsor this important bill, which not only provides people with essential health care services, but also ensures that the Health Centers will continue to have the funding necessary to provide these services.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="Introducing S. 902. A bill to provide support and assistance for families of members of the National Guard and Reserve who are undergoing deployment, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Armed Services.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="902">S. 902</bill>] Mr President, Americans are divided over the Iraq war, but we are 100 percent united in our determination to support the troops in the field and their families back home.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But just as we have seen shortcomings in the treatment of wounded warriors at Walter Reed, it is clear to me that we are falling short in supporting the families of Guard and Reserve personnel who serve in Iraq and Afghanistan. These families are especially vulnerable because of their isolation, their distance from military bases, and their lack of access to the services that active-duty military families can draw upon.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a new era for our National Guard and for the Reserves. They are shouldering a huge share of the combat burden in Iraq and Afghanistan, plus a stepped-up role in homeland security. More than four times as many Guard members have been killed in Iraq as during the entire Vietnam war.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With many Guard and Reserve members on their third or even fourth deployment, and with some deployments being stretched out to 16 months, the stresses on their families are acute. Their children are at greater risk for depression, behavioral disorders, or academic problems. And long family separations often result in financial difficulties and troubled marriages.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To address this quiet crisis, today I am introducing legislation titled the Coming Together for Guard and Reserve Families Act. This bill does several things.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, it expands and strengthens the existing family assistance program. We need to ensure that there is adequate professional staff to work with Guard and Reserve families and meet their special needs at every point of the deployment cycle--as they prepare for deployment, during the long absence, and during reunification and readjustment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am especially concerned that there are few resources for the families of Guard and Reserve members who are wounded or experience mental illness. My bill expands the VA's Disabled Transition Assistance program to ensure that family members have access to family counseling and mental health services during this critical time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Children of deployed service members often react to parental separation with acting-out behaviors, anxiety, or depression. My bill calls for outreach to professionals who serve children--including school administrators and teachers--to alert them to the special needs of kids in military families, especially those with a parent deployed in a war zone.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Forty-one percent of Guard members and Reservists report symptoms of mental illness--including post-traumatic stress disorder--within 6 months of returning home from deployment. Currently, mental health information is distributed to service members when they return from deployment--and often that's it. But symptoms of PTSD may not appear for months after return. My bill will ensure that families receive mental health information 6 months post-deployment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, my bill creates a family-to-family mentoring program to enable military spouses to serve as peer counselors to other spouses and family members. It can be extremely valuable for a military spouse to consult with someone who has gone through a similar experience.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The role of our Guard and Reserve members in defending our national security abroad has significantly increased. In turn, we have an expanded obligation to care for their spouses and children, who are facing tremendous stresses, often alone and with no one to turn to.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The aim of my bill is to address the unmet needs of Guard and Reserve families before this becomes the kind of full-fledged crisis we witnessed at Walter Reed. I urge my colleagues to support this urgent and important legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="Introducing S. 903. A bill to award a Congressional Gold Medal to Dr. Muhammad Yunus, in recognition of his contributions to the fight against global poverty; to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="903">S. 903</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to honor Dr. Muhammad Yunus for his contributions to the fight against global poverty.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, joined by my colleague Senator Bennett of Utah as well as Senators Clinton, Kerry and Harkin, I introduced the Muhammad Yunus Congressional Gold Medal Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bipartisan bill would award Dr. Yunus a Congressional Gold Medal in recognition of his efforts to fight poverty and promote economic and social opportunity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Along with the Grameen Bank, which he founded, Dr. Yunus was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize in 2006 for developing the concept of microcredit. Through the Grameen system, Dr. Yunus created an economically sound model of extending very small loans, at competitive interest rates, to the very poor. Through this system, he has been transforming lives, one loan at a time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He began in 1976 with a loan of just $27, out of his own pocket, to 42 village craftspeople in Bangladesh. Over the past 30 years, his model has been emulated around the world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I met Dr. Yunus on my first trip to Bangladesh, and there I saw firsthand the economic miracle that microcredit can help create.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nearly half the world's population lives on less than $2 a day. We can not hope to achieve lasting global peace and stability until we find a means by which the world's poorest can begin to lift themselves out of poverty.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The microcredit movement that Dr. Yunus pioneered has made enormous strides towards that goal. Over 125 million households have already been transformed by microcredit loans, and more are joining them every day.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dr. Yunus' work has had a particularly strong impact on improving the economic prospects of women. Women disproportionately shoulder the burden of poverty. They also make up over 95 percent of microcredit borrowers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have long believed that if you want to predict the economic prospects of a country, ask how it treats its women. If a country sends its daughters to school, if its wives and mothers have economic and political rights and opportunities, then it is likely to prosper. But if it treats its women as second-class citizens, its chances for development diminish dramatically. Microcredit opens doors for women and in so doing it creates new opportunities for their sons and daughters alike.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Muhammad Yunus's work has also affected the lives of millions of Americans. Although Dr. Yunus launched his movement in 1976 in Bangladesh--a long time ago and a long way away--it  has come home to us here in America and is still relevant today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are now an estimated 21 million microentrepreneurs in the U.S., accounting for approximately 16 percent of private employment in the country. Over $318 million worth of microloans have been made to American entrepreneurs in the past 15 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Culminating with his Nobel Peace Prize, Dr. Yunus has been recognized around the world as a leading figure in the effort to fight poverty and promote economic and social opportunity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is time that we properly recognize him here in Congress with our most distinguished honor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dr. Yunus would join a long and illustrious line of Congressional Gold Medal recipients that stretches back to 1776, when the award was created. Although most of the recipients have been American, many have not: Prime Minister Tony Blair, Pope John Paul II, and His Holiness, the Fourteenth Dalai Lama, are just a few. We hope that Dr. Yunus will join them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank Senator Bennett and my other colleagues for joining me today in honoring Dr. Yunus. Dr. Muhammad Yunus is a great man who deserves our admiration and our thanks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300060" topic="Introducing S. 903. A bill to award a Congressional Gold Medal to Dr. Muhammad Yunus, in recognition of his contributions to the fight against global poverty; to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today to recognize Dr. Muhammad Yunus. For those who don't already know, Dr. Yunus is a modest man of great ideas, now revered around the world, as the father of microcredit and the founder of the Grameen Bank. His concept of microcredit has helped thousands of people work their way out of poverty. For his work to beat global poverty, I am very proud to join my colleagues, Senators DURBIN and BENNETT, in introducing a bill to honor Dr. Yunus with  a Congressional Gold Medal.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When I look at the success of Dr. Yunus's idea and the microenterprise programs it has inspired over the past 30 years, one thing that amazes me the most is that it all began with a loan of 27 U.S. dollars. The beauty of microcredit is that such a small amount of money can have such tremendous and lasting effects to foster entrepreneurship among those who would not qualify for typical bank loans. By offering loans at competitive interest rates, or no interest, Dr. Yunus's Grameen Bank has been  able to give individuals suffering from poverty the power to determine their own futures.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last year, Dr. Yunus and his Grameen Bank were honored with a Nobel Peace Prize for his economic imagination. Dr. Yunus's innovation and entrepreneurship are certainly commendable and worthy of such an honor, as well as the distinction of a Congressional Gold Medal. In accepting his Nobel Peace Prize, Dr. Yunus challenged the world to think of an entrepreneur as not only being motivated by profit, but also by "doing good to people and the world."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The effectiveness of microcredit programs is evident by the success stories they have inspired all around the world. As chairman of the Small Business and Entrepreneurship Committee, I have seen first hand the power of microcredit in this country, through the SBA's--Small Business Administration's--microloan programs. In my home State of Massachusetts, Thondup and Dolma Tsering, two Tibetan refugees in the United States, were able to start their own restaurant in 2005, with assistance from the  Massachusetts Small Business Development Center and financing from the Western Massachusetts Enterprise Fund. Through financing and support, otherwise not available to them from the banking community, they are now the successful owners of Lhasa Cafe in Northampton. As small business owners, the Tserings are socially responsible and support local farmers and their community.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>From Dr. Yunus's first microloans to 42 entrepreneurs in Bangladesh in 1976, the concept of microcredit has come a long way. Here in the United States, where SBA has had a similar program since 1992, more than $328 million in microloans have been made to deserving entrepreneurs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have long been a supporter of funding microloan programs, which offer current and potential small business owners the opportunity to achieve financial independence, financial security, and dignity through work. Sometimes they use it to work their way out of poverty, but sometimes they use it to patch together income when they need more money, lose a job, want to buy a house or car, or maybe pay for college or send a child to college. These entrepreneurs create jobs, provide services and products  to our communities, and generate tax revenue to benefit the economy. Funding microloan programs not only makes economic sense; it makes social sense as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In spite of growing support for microloan programs, and in spite of the  return on investment to our economy, microenterprise does not get the support in this country that it does in other countries. In 2005, the administration provided approximately $211 million for the development of foreign microenterprise programs through the Agency for International Development, USAID. In fiscal year 2006, we are told that the administration provided more than $54  million for microloans in Iraq:</paragraph>
    <paragraph> The efforts of the U.S. government in its assistance to Iraq have been broad based..... For example, over $54 million in micro-loans have been disbursed, resulting in 26,700 loans in twelve cities, and the program is set to expand to even more areas. Also, a Loan Guarantee Corporation is currently being established to encourage private banks to make loans to small businesses.--Ambassador Zalmay Khalilzad, U.S. Ambassador to Iraq, May 9, 2006.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And for fiscal year 2007, we are told that the administration is requesting supplemental funding for Iraq that includes at least $160 million for microloans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We will help local leaders improve their capacity to govern and deliver public services. Our economic efforts will be more targeted on specific local needs with proven records of success, like micro-credit programs. And we will engage with leading private sector enterprises and other local businesses, including the more promising state-owned firms, to break the obstacles to growth.--Secretary of State Condoleezza Rice, Foreign Relations Committee hearing on the administration's plan for Iraq,  January 11, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At the same time, the President has proposed for fiscal years 2005, 2006, 2007, and 2008 eliminating all funding for the SBA's microloan programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today I not only honor and recognize the genius of Dr. Yunus, but also call attention to President Bush's lack of support for U.S. microloans and call on the administration to reverse its policy. If we can support microloans in Baghdad, we should support microloans in Boston, and every other city that's home to a would-be entrepreneur.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am honored to add my name in support of Dr. Muhammad Yunus, and I am gratified to see the support he has received among my colleagues. But I also implore my colleagues to pay tribute to American entrepreneurs and to fund the SBA's microloan program. We must honor Dr. Yunus's ingenuity with more than words; we must honor him with our actions.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300091" topic="Introducing S. 904. A bill to provide additional relief for small business owners ordered to active duty as members of reserve components of the Armed Forces, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="904">S. 904</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to introduce the Veterans Small Business Opportunity Act of 2007. Senators Pryor, Craig, and I are introducing this legislation to assist veterans and small businesses that employ Guard and reservists. Our bill improves the Small Business Administration's, SBA's, Military Reservist Economic Injury Disaster Loan, MREIDL, program. Additionally, this bill increases procurement opportunities, capital access, and other types of business development  assistance for veterans and service-disabled veterans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We all know today's small business men and women play a vital role in the economic stability and prosperity of our Nation. Quite often, these same entrepreneurs are the veterans who have protected our Nation in years past, or who serve in the Armed Forces today. When our Nation's patriotic men and women are called to duty, they often leave behind thriving small businesses, and as a result, many of these businesses experience production slowdowns and lost sales, or incur additional expenses to  compensate for an employee's absence.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In recent years, the Department of Defense has placed a greater reliance on our country's Guard and Reserve Forces. In fact, since September 2001, nearly 600,000 Guard and Reserve members have been called up in support of current operations, comprising nearly one-third of deployed service members in Iraq and Afghanistan. Furthermore, Guard and Reserve members were charged with assisting recovery efforts in the gulf coast region in the aftermath of Hurricanes Katrina and Rita.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In my 4 years as chair of the Senate Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship, and now as ranking member, I have fought to support our patriotic small businesses affected by the Guard and Reserve call-ups. My home State of Maine has one of the highest Guard and Reserve deployment levels in the country--over 50 percent have been deployed to Iraq and Afghanistan. In response to this I commissioned a Congressional Budget Office, CBO, study which found that 35 percent of Guard and reservists  work for small busineses or are self-employed. In addition, the small businesses that employ them may be "paying" a disproportionate and unfair share of the burden of increased Guard and Reserve member call-ups. The burden is further magnified when it is the small business owner or a key employee who is deployed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our legislation will raise the maximum MREIDL amount from $1,500,000 to $2,000,000. A maximum military reservist loan amount of $2,000,000 is the same level as many of the SBA's other loan programs, including: 7(a) loans, international trade loans, and 504 Certified Development Corporation loans that serve a public policy goal.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Currently, some of the SBA's contracting and business development programs have defined time limits for participation. If the firm's time for participation expires prematurely, then competitive opportunities, investments, and jobs become lost. Today, small business owners  who get called-up to active duty in the National Guard or Reserve are effectively penalized because their active duty time is counted against the time limitation participation in the SBA's programs. The Veterans Small Business Opportunity Act amends the Small Business Act by allowing small businesses owned by veterans and service-disabled veterans to extend their SBA program participation time limitations by the duration of their owners' active duty service after September 11, 2001.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Additionally, this bill will allow the SBA Administrator, either directly or through banks, to offer loans up to $25,000 without requiring collateral from a loan applicant. Currently, the SBA offers military reservist loans up to $5,000 without collateral. This provision would increase that level to eligible small businesses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill will also require the Administrator to give military reservist loan applications priority for processing and ensure that Guard and Reserve members are adequately assisted with their loan application by incorporating the support and expertise of SBA entrepreneurial development partners, such as Small Business Development Centers and Veterans Business Outreach Centers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation increases the authorization of appropriations for the SBA's Office of Veteran Business Development to $2 million for fiscal year 2008, $2.1 million for fiscal year 2009 and $2.2 million for fiscal year 2010. Increased funding for SBA's Office of Veterans Business Development help them better assist our Nation's veterans and provide the business services they need.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation will also strengthen the access of veterans and service-disabled veterans to Federal contracts and subcontracts. Under the Small Business Act and the President's Executive Order 13360, Providing Opportunities for Service-Disabled Veteran Businesses To Increase Their Federal Contracting and Subcontracting, Federal agencies must award at least 3 percent of prime contracts and subcontracts to small businesses owned by service-disabled veterans. The order states that, to achieve  these goals, Federal agencies "shall more effectively" use the authorities in the Small Business Act to reserve and award contracts to service-disabled veterans. During the Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship Committee hearing held in January, it became very clear that Federal agencies have been short-changing</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, our legislation ensures that veterans and service-disabled veterans do not face confusing and duplicative red tape before they can be eligible to access the Federal procurement market. Currently, the Department of  Veterans Affairs and the SBA both operate registration databases for small businesses owned by veterans and service-disabled veterans. A veteran must often register in both databases to be properly considered for bidding. Surely,  in this information age, we can have a better process. Registration data can easily be made to migrate from one database to the other. Our legislation requires that a single registration point for both of these databases be established within a year. Such one-stop registration must be reliable and compliant with statutory provisions concerning veteran and service-disabled veteran status certifications for</paragraph>
    <paragraph>small businesses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To increase the capacity of service-disabled veteran-owned firms, my legislation permits the SBA, in cooperation with the Department of Veterans Affairs, to develop a business development assistance program, including mentor-prot&amp;#233;g&amp;#233; assistance, to be administered by the SBA. Our legislation contains a strict fairness requirement that any such program must be developed in such a way as to ensure success of other small business contracting programs. Within a year, the SBA is required  to submit a report to Congress on its proposals for this program. In 2004, I succeeded in amending the Department of Defense Mentor-Prot&amp;#233;g&amp;#233; Program statute by expanding it to service-disabled veterans. Since then, over $204 million in contracts and subcontracts have been awarded to service-disabled veteran-owned small businesses as a result of the $17 million in mentor-Prot&amp;#233;g&amp;#233; assistance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, our legislation creates an interagency task force among Federal agencies charged with improving procurement opportunities for service-disabled veterans. The scope of this task force will, in addition to procurement, include franchising, capital access, and other types of business development assistance. In examining the implementation of Executive Order 13360 and other veterans business development initiatives, our committee found that the responsible agencies were not talking to each  other on a regular basis, and that no overall "game plan" was in place to coordinate various Federal efforts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to thank Senators Pryor and Craig for working with me on this critical issue and I urge my colleagues to support this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300029" topic="Introducing S. 904. A bill to provide additional relief for small business owners ordered to active duty as members of reserve components of the Armed Forces, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise to comment on a bill that is being introduced by Senator Snowe today, the Veterans Small Business Opportunity Act of 2007. I am proud to join with Senator Snowe and Senator Pryor as an original cosponsor of this important bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation will benefit patriot "citizen-soldiers" who are called from their employment at America's small businesses to serve our country in uniform. In States across the Nation, small businesses are being affected by the mobilization of our Guard and Reserve personnel. In my home State, the Idaho National Guard's 116th Brigade Combat Team returned in 2005 from an 18-month deployment to Iraq. I visited members of the 116th while they were in Iraq and discovered that a good number had  left jobs at small businesses across Idaho. I also held a hearing in Idaho during the 109th Congress to examine the reemployment rights of returning Guard and Reserve members.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At that hearing, it was emphasized that, although legal rights to reemployment are critical, they do little for those who have no employer, or no small business, to return to. To me, it was clear that we should do more to help small businesses in coping with the financial hardships of frequent and lengthy mobilizations of its employees or owners during the war on terrorism. I believe we can provide some of that needed assistance with this legislation, which includes key provisions from The Patriot  Loan Act of 2006, a bill that Senator Snowe and I introduced last year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill would enhance the U.S. Small Business Administration's Military Reservist Economic Injury Disaster Loan, or MREIDL, Program. That program provides loan assistance to small businesses to help them meet ordinary and necessary operating expenses after essential employees are called to active duty in their roles as citizen-soldiers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill would raise the maximum military reservist loan amount from $1.5 million to $2 million. It would also allow the Small Business Administration, by direct loan or through banks, to offer unsecured loans of up to $25,000, an increase from the current $5,000 limit. In addition, this bill would ensure proactive outreach to Guard and Reserve members about the MREIDL Program and other small business programs by requiring SBA and the Department of Defense to develop a joint Web site and printed  materials with information about those programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For the brave men and women who serve our Nation in the Guard and Reserve, we must do what we can to ensure that their sacrifices do not place them in financial harm's way when they return home. I urge my colleagues to support these measures, and I thank Senator Snowe for her leadership in introducing this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300055" topic="Introducing S. 905. A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to eliminate the taxable income limit on percentage depletion for oil and natural gas produced from marginal properties; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="905">S. 905</bill>] Mr. President, the independent producers of oil and gas are the backbone of our domestic supply of energy. They have played and continue to play a critical role in meeting our domestic needs, especially as the big oil companies' focus mainly offshore. In fact, independents develop 90 percent of our Nation's wells. According to the Department of Energy, independent producers supply 68 percent of American oil production and 82 percent of overall American natural gas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Therefore, I rise today to introduce legislation that eliminates the taxable income limit on percentage depletion for oil and natural gas produced from marginal wells; wells producing 15 barrels of day and less than 90 thousand cubic feet of natural gas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under current law, the percentage depletion method is limited to only independent producers and royalty owners. It is a form of cost recovery for capital initially invested toward production of oil and gas wells. Generally, the percentage depletion rate is 15 percent of the taxpayer's gross income from an oil and gas producing property and is limited to a daily average of 1,000 barrels of oil or 6,000 thousand cubic feet of natural gas. However, under the net income limitation, percentage depletion  is limited to 100 percent of the net income from an individual property. In the case of marginal wells, where total deductions often do exceed this net-income, this limitation discourages producers from investing in the continued production from marginal wells.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a result Congress has suspended the net-income limitation for 1998 through 2005; and again for 2006 and 2007, with the passage of the Tax Relief and Health Care Act of 2006, <bill type="h" number="6111">H.R. 6111</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My bill would simply clarify the policy by doing away with the taxable net income limitation altogether.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In my own State of Oklahoma, it is the small independents, basically mom-and-pop operations, producing the majority of oil and natural gas, with 85 percent of Oklahoma's oil coming from marginal wells.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because marginal wells supply such a significant amount of our oil and gas, it is vital we keep them in operation. According to the Energy Department, between 1994 and 2003, we lost 110 million barrels of crude oil due to plugged marginal wells. Thus, when we lose marginal wells, we become more dependent upon foreign sources of energy, at a time when virtually all agree that U.S. policies should encourage reliance upon domestic sources. Furthermore, we lose domestic jobs to foreign nations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My bill would allow independents the necessary capital to continue to produce from these existing marginal wells--which is critical to the Nation's overall energy security. I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400629" topic="Introducing S. 906. A bill to prohibit the sale, distribution, transfer, and export of elemental mercury, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="906">S. 906</bill>] Mr. President, I am pleased to be joined today by my esteemed colleague from Alaska, Ms. Murkowski, in introducing the Mercury Market Minimization Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As most of us in this Chamber know, elemental mercury is a poisonous neurotoxin that can cause serious disability or death if ingested. Unfortunately, many people in the United States, and many millions more worldwide, do indeed ingest mercury--unintentionally, however, as a result of industrial emissions or practices, or poor waste management and storage techniques. When mercury enters into the environment, it often shows up in plants and animals, and that means a major source of mercury ingestion  for humans comes as a result of eating certain types of fish. That, in turn, causes serious developmental problems in half a million children in our country, and similar health problems in adults, especially women at childbearing age.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last year, an investigative report published in the Chicago Tribune outlined the extent of mercury contamination in fish. After concluding that the fish sampling efforts conducted by the Federal Government were limited and outdated, the Tribune conducted its own sampling, and the results showed surprisingly high levels of mercury concentrations in freshwater and saltwater fish purchased by consumers in the Chicago region--higher levels than had been documented by the Federal  Government. Mercury was found in both freshwater and saltwater species--tuna, swordfish, orange roughy, and walleye, to name a few examples. The Tribune also reported on how existing programs at the Food and Drug Administration and the Environmental Protection Agency have failed to adequately test and evaluate mercury levels in fish.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For those of us who like fish, it causes us to pause when we first learn of the range of species with high mercury levels. For pregnant women and other at-risk groups, however, this doesn't just cause pause, it creates serious concerns about health consequences. Meanwhile, experts tell us that fish is an excellent source of critical nutrients and other compounds indispensable for good health. More of us should eat more fish.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So the real long-term solution is not to eat less fish, or to criticize those who commercially provide us with fish as food. It's not about issuing advisories, or printing labels on tuna cans, or posting placards at the supermarket, or creating inspection bureaucracies, or collecting statistics. If we're serious about eliminating mercury from fish, we need to reduce mercury in the environment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Half of mercury settles where it is emitted, and the other half gets transported around the globe where we lose track of it, and it winds up in oceans, lakes, and rivers nowhere near mercury sources. From there, up it goes, through the food chain. If mercury is both local, and global, then the solution is not up to one state, or one nation, but up to all states and nations. The bill we introduce today was crafted based on that premise.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Mercury Market Minimization Act, or M3 Act, establishes a ban on U.S. exports of mercury by the year 2010. Such a ban, when coupled with goal of the European Union to ban mercury exports by 2011, and the insufficient capacity in the world's mercury mines to respond, will result in a tightening of the global supply of commercially available elemental mercury in sufficient quantities that developing nations that still use mercury will be compelled to switch to the affordable alternatives that  are already widespread in industrialized nations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The M3 Act also requires those Federal agencies that now hold mercury in stockpiles to keep that mercury. Right now, the Department of Energy, and the Department of Defense, possess tons of mercury left over from various operations over the years. While it is the policy of these agencies to keep this mercury--not to sell it, not to transfer it, not to release it from their possession--it is not the law. The M3 act codifies these policies. In December of 2006, it was widely understood that the  Department of Energy was considering the sale of its mercury stockpiles. After various inquiries into the matter, the Department of Energy ultimately announced that it would not sell its stockpiles. That underscores why a prohibition of stockpile sales must be enacted into law by the M3 act if we are to be assured that mercury remains safely stored, away from the environment, and not sold overseas to places where tracking and emissions and waste disposal laws may be inadequate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, the M3 Act calls for the creation of a committee to explore and make recommendations on the issues associated with the development of a permanent repository of mercury collected as a result of an export prohibition. Mercury is not like spent nuclear fuel, or other substances that may create community concerns, in that when mercury is stored in stainless steel containers in refrigeration, it remains benign. Every community must be provided the opportunity to evaluate for themselves if  and when mercury is stored nearby in secure and stable storage. I do believe, however, that when mercury is safely and permanently stored, it means less microscopic mercury on one's dinner plate, less mercury in our kids' tuna fish sandwiches, and less mercury in the air we breathe.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last month, a United States delegation, led by the State Department, participated in an international meeting in Kenya, sponsored by the United Nations Environmental Programme, where world representative discussed how to reduce mercury pollution. Two years ago, the U.S. Government could have taken a bolder stance, and did not. This time, with the decision of the E.U. to ban mercury exports, the United States had an opportunity to partner with its allies to eliminate a major part of worldwide  elemental mercury contamination. Again, the State Department did not.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is not often that policy options, such as this, might be considered "low-hanging fruit"--in that a small act of international leadership by the United States government could have far reaching benefits for the health of our kids, as well as millions of low-income hardworking artisanal gold miners whom we will never meet. But the United States, so far, has not acted. This bill, the M3 bill, is designed to change that course and the mark the beginning of the end of a global market of an outdated  and obsolete poison. I hope my colleagues will support this bill, and I ask unanimous consent that a copy of this legislation be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300022" topic="Introducing S. 907. A bill to establish an Advisory Committee on Gestational Diabetes, to provide grants to better understand and reduce gestational diabetes, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="907">S. 907</bill>] Mr. President, I am pleased to introduce the Gestational Diabetes Act of 2007 with my colleague Senator COLLINS, to bring attention to an important health issue facing women and children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I don't need to tell anyone that we have an obesity epidemic in the United States. Many of us realize that as parents, it is our responsibility to pass on good nutritional habits to our children. But many women may not realize that watching what you eat, exercising regularly, and having control of your blood sugar levels are serious health considerations during pregnancy. In fact, these factors are serious enough that they can affect both the health of the mother and the life of the child into  adulthood.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>More women than ever are entering their pregnancies overweight but without an understanding of how their own weight and nutritional habits can trigger gestational diabetes--a type of diabetes that only occurs during pregnancy. Women who are overweight before pregnancy are not only at greater risk of having gestational diabetes but are also more likely to have a c-section and are at an increased risk for other serious pregnancy complications.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In New York, gestational diabetes is on the rise. In New York City alone, gestational diabetes has risen by nearly 50 percent in about 10 years. This means that gestational diabetes affects 1 in 25 women, about 400 women per month. But across the Nation, between 4 and 8 percent of pregnant women in the United States are affected by gestational diabetes. Infants of women who have gestational diabetes are at increased risk for obesity and developing type 2 diabetes as adolescents or adults.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As women, we need to pay attention to our health. We are always worrying about the health of our children, our husbands, and our parents, but we often forget to take care of ourselves.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, I am introducing the Gestational Diabetes Act, also known as the GEDI Act. This legislation will increase our understanding of gestational diabetes by determining the factors that contribute to this condition and help mothers who had gestational diabetes reduce their risk of developing type 2 diabetes post-pregnancy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The GEDI Act will provide funding for projects to assist health care providers, as well as for communities to find ways to reach out to women so that they understand how their own good health during pregnancy can decrease serious health risks for their children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The GEDI Act would expand research to determine and develop interventions to lower the incidence of gestational diabetes. We need to alert women to the risk before this condition becomes an epidemic and, as we have seen so many times before, education is critical.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We should be doing everything we can to address the impact of obesity during pregnancy and to reduce the prevalence of gestational diabetes in pregnant women. The GEDI Act is an important step in assuring that women understand this critical issue and that we fully understand how to equip pregnant women to make the best choices for their health.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The GEDI Act is supported by the American Diabetes Association, American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists, National Research Center for Women &amp; Families, International Community Health Services, American Association of Diabetes Educators, and the American Association of Colleges of Pharmacy.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="Introducing S. 909. A bill to amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to permit States, at their option, to require certain individuals to present satisfactory documentary evidence of proof of citizenship or nationality for purposes of eligibility for Medicaid, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="909">S. 909</bill>] Mr. President, the legislation I am introducing today is designed to make several very important changes to current law to ensure that U.S. citizens receive the Medicaid to which they are entitled.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since July 1, 2006, most U.S. citizens and nationals applying for or renewing their Medicaid coverage face a new Federal requirement to provide documentation of their citizenship status. Recent reports indicate that tens-of-thousands of U.S. citizens, and in particular children, inappropriately are being denied Medicaid benefits simply because they don't have access to newly required documentation. The articles below and report by the Center on Budget and Policy Priorities highlight this very  serious problem. Hospitals, physicians, and pharmacies may not be willing to treat these individuals until they have a source of payment, but they cannot qualify for Medicaid until they produce a birth certificate and ID.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This new Federal requirement was added to Medicaid by the Deficit Reduction Act of 2005, DRA, enacted February 8, 2006. The Tax Relief and Health Care Act of 2006, TRHCA, signed into law December 20, 2006, included some amendments to the DRA citizenship documentation requirement, primarily to exempt certain groups. Prior to enactment of the DRA, States were permitted to use their discretion in requiring such citizenship documentation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under Section 6036 of the DRA, citizens applying for or renewing their Medicaid coverage must provide "satisfactory documentary evidence of citizenship or nationality." The DRA specifies documents that are acceptable for this purpose and authorizes the HHS Secretary to designate additional acceptable documents. No Federal matching funds are available for services provided to individuals who declare they are citizens or nationals unless the State obtains satisfactory evidence of their citizenship  or determines that they are subject to a statutory exemption.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is important to note that citizenship documentation requirements do not affect Medicaid rules relating to immigrants--they apply to individuals claiming to be citizens. Most new legal immigrants are excluded from Medicaid during their first 5 years in the U.S. and undocumented immigrants remain eligible for Medicaid emergency services only.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation I am introducing would make several very important changes to current law to ensure that U.S. citizens receive the Medicaid to which they are entitled.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, the legislation would restore citizenship verification to a State option. Specifically, States would be permitted to determine when and to what extent citizenship verification is required of U.S. Citizens. States would also be permitted to utilize the standards most appropriate to the their population as long as such standards were no more stringent than those currently used by the Social Security Administration and includes native American tribal documents when appropriate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second, the legislation would ensure that individuals are afforded a reasonable time period to provide citizenship documentation utilizing the same reasonable time period standard that is available to legal immigrants to provide satisfactory evidence of their immigration status.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Third the legislation protects children who are U.S. citizens by virtue of being born in the United States from being denied coverage after birth because of citizenship verification requirements.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Fourth, the legislation also clarifies ambiguities in federal law to ensure that these citizen children, regardless of the immigration status of their parents, are treated like all other low-income children born in the United States and are deemed eligible to receive Medicaid services for one year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, the legislation also ensures that the thousands of citizen children and adults, who were erroneously denied Medicaid coverage, may receive  retroactive Medicaid eligibility for coverage they were inappropriately denied because of citizenship verification requirements.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues in the Senate to support this critical legislation, which protects low-income U.S. citizens from being inappropriately denied Medicaid coverage because of lack of documentation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill and supporting documentation be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="Introducing S. 910. A bill to provide for paid sick leave to ensure that Americans can address their own health needs and the health needs of their families; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="910">S. 910</bill>] Mr. President day in and day out across America, millions of men and women go to work in jobs that are the backbone of our economy. They make our country great and prosperous. They work hard to provide for their families and care for them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Often, however, they have to miss days of work because of illness. Every parent knows what it's like to care for a sick child, and every child knows the importance of a parent taking care of them when they are ill. Yet, every day, countless Americans find their paychecks or even their jobs at risk when illness strikes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As Members of Congress, we don't lose our pay or risk our jobs if we stay home because of illness. But millions of our fellow citizens are not so fortunate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, 57 million Americans--nearly half of all private-sector workers in the United States--do not have paid sick days. Seventy percent don't have paid sick days they can use to care for family  members. They can't take a day off to recover from the flu. They can't leave work to care for a child who is running a fever.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Among workers in the lowest income quarter, the numbers are even worse--percent do not have the right to take time off for illness without losing their payor even their jobs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This lack of protection is especially difficult for working women with children. Women have moved into the workforce in record numbers, but they continue to have primary responsibility for their children's health. Nearly 80 percent of mothers say they are solely responsible for their children's medical care. Yet they can't take a day off to care for a sick child.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If we truly care about families, we have to change those facts. Americans want to be responsible employees and responsible parents. We need workplace laws that allow workers the time needed to care for themselves or family members when they are sick without losing payor risking their jobs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is why today I am introducing the Healthy Families Act, to give American workers up to seven paid days of sick leave a year. Now Congresswoman Rosa DeLauro is introducing the legislation in the House of Representatives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Earlier this week, she and I met with hundreds of workers and parents from around the country, representing tens of thousands of parents asking Congress to take action.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am talking about hard-working people such as Bertha Brown, who spoke to hundreds of us in front of the Capitol. Bertha is a home healthcare aide. She has spent her life caring for America's sick and elderly, yet she herself has no paid sick days to care for herself or her children. She told us how she had to leave her sick daughter at home when she went to work.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Paid sick days aren't just a family issue--they are also a public health issue. When sick people go to work, they are likely to infect their coworkers and the public. Every day, we hear reports of stomach illnesses breaking out in restaurants or on cruise ships. We learn of flu outbreaks leading to hospitalization of the elderly. Such illnesses are contagious, but their spread can be minimized if sick people stay at home.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, a high proportion of workers who have constant contact with the public have no paid sick days--85 percent of food service workers and 55 percent of workers in the retail industry are denied that benefit; 30 percent of health care workers can't take paid time off when they are ill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is why nurses and doctors support paid sick days. When our Health Committee held a hearing on this issue last month, we heard from pediatricians at Boston Children's Hospital and a public health expert in San Francisco about the significant health benefits and reduction of medical costs that result from paid sick days. We all know that preventive care helps reduce medical costs. Giving people the opportunity to obtain medical treatment for illnesses or chronic medical conditions before their  conditions worsen is common sense.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Paid sick days also are important to help children stay healthy and in school so that they can learn. When sick children go to school, they don't learn well, and they are likely to infect their fellow students.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We also heard this week from Carolyn Duff, a nurse in an elementary school in South Carolina. She treated a fifth grader she suspected had strep throat. His parents did not have paid sick days and could not take him to the doctor. After 4 days, his condition worsened. He developed scarlet fever and a rash covered his entire body--all because his parents, for fear of losing their jobs, weren't able to take time off to care for him. As Carolyn Duff said, the child not only suffered without the  care of his parents, he also lost 10 precious days of his studies at school.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Paid sick days will result in significant savings to our economy and our health care system. That is why employers support paid sick days too. Dancing Deer Bakery--a small business Boston--sent me a letter making this important point:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A national paid sick days law creates a level playing field for all businesses....... We hope that a bill will move through both Chambers and be on the President's desk. Paid sick days should be a non-partisan issue. A healthy nation is a productive nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Paid sick days are good for families, good for our public health, and good for our economy. Our people have waited long enough for this need to be met. It is time to pass the Healthy Families Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
</record>
