<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1228928403" ordinal="12" title="HONORING OUR ARMED FORCES">
  <narrative>HONORING OUR ARMED FORCES -- (Senate - December 10, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="10844">S10844</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412246" topic="FALLEN PENNSYLVANIANS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, yesterday, I came before the Senate to pay tribute to Pennsylvanians who gave, as Abraham Lincoln said, "the last full measure of devotion" to their country serving in Operation Iraqi Freedom.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Therefore, today, I would like to take this opportunity to honor the men and women of Pennsylvania who have served in Operation Enduring Freedom in Afghanistan. This struggle began in the weeks following the gravest attack on American soil; it was a direct response to eliminate the sanctuary of those who plotted the horrific events of 9/11.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The men and women who have served in Afghanistan have faced extreme danger but have persevered with a can-do spirit. Our men and women of the U.S. Armed Forces are indeed in a class of their own--all their own, I should say. And, like their brothers and sisters serving in Iraq, they mourn the sacrifices of their own.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So today in the Senate, I would also like to enter into the Congressional Record the names of those 25 Pennsylvanian heroes who may have fallen in the battles of Afghanistan but who have only risen in our appreciation for their service and sacrifice. I list them now:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To the families of these brave Americans, please know your son's or daughter's service will always be remembered and appreciated. Every time a child is able to go to school in America without fear, that service is appreciated. Every time a graduate looks positively toward their future, to live in a land of freedom and liberty, those who have served are appreciated and their sacrifice is appreciated.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The response of these men and women--whether it was in Afghanistan or anywhere in the world that they served--their response to the ultimate call to service ensures that each of us may live in freedom.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As Benjamin Disraeli once said:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legacy of heroes is the memory of a great name and the inheritance of a great example.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>During this holiday season, when thoughts of our families and loved ones are on our minds, I wish to express my condolences and gratitude to those families who have loved and lost someone dear to them and also to express gratitude to those whose loved ones are now serving in a war theater far from home. Please know you are in our prayers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I yield the floor and suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <chair>The assistant legislative clerk proceeded to call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412244" topic="FALLEN PENNSYLVANIANS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
