<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1179417651" ordinal="46" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <speaking speaker="300026" topic="COMMITTEE ON ARMED SERVICES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, May 17, 2007, at 10:15 a.m., in open session, to receive testimony on United States European Command in review of the Defense authorization request for fiscal year 2008 and the future years Defense Program.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300026" topic="COMMITTEE ON ARMED SERVICES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, May 17, 2007, at 3 p.m., in executive session, to consider a pending military nomination.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300026" topic="COMMITTEE ON INDIAN AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Indian Affairs be authorized to meet on Thursday, May 17, 2007, at 9:30 a.m. in Room 485 of the Russell Senate Office Building to conduct an oversight hearing on law enforcement in Indian Country.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300026" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet to conduct a markup on Thursday, May 17, 2007, at 10 a.m. in Dirksen Room 226.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Agenda</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Authorization of Subpoenas in Connection with Investigation into Replacement of U.S. Attorneys.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="221">S. 221</bill>, Fair Contracts for Growers Act of 2007 (Grassley, Feingold, Kohl, Leahy, Durbin).</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="376">S. 376</bill>, Law Enforcement Officers Safety Act of 2007 (Leahy, Specter, Grassley, Kyl, Sessions, Cornyn).</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="1079">S. 1079</bill>, Star-Spangled Banner and War of 1812 Bicentennial Commission Act (Cardin, Warner, Kennedy).</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="1327">S. 1327</bill>, A bill to create and extend certain temporary district court judgeships (Leahy, Brownback, Feinstein).</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="1027">S. 1027</bill>, Prevent All Cigarette Trafficking Act of 2007 (Kohl, Kyl, Leahy, Schumer, Specter).</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="sr" number="138">S. Res. 138</bill>, Honoring the accomplishments and legacy of Cesar Estrada Chavez (Salazar, Durbin).</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="sr" number="132">S. Res. 132</bill>, Recognizing the Civil Air Patrol (Stevens, Inouye).</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="sr" number="130">S. Res. 130</bill>, Resolution designating a National Day of the American Cowboy (Craig, Cornyn, Hatch).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300026" topic="SELECT COMMITTEE ON INTELLIGENCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Select Committee on Intelligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on May 17, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. to hold a closed mark-up.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300026" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON OVERSIGHT OF GOVERNMENT MANAGEMENT, THE FEDERAL WORKFORCE, AND THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs' Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia be authorized to meet on Thursday, May 17, 2007, at 9:30 a.m. for a hearing entitled, Evaluating the Progress and Identifying Obstacles in Improving the Federal Government's Security Clearance Program.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300026" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON SECURITIES, INSURANCE, AND INVESTMENT">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs Subcommittee on Securities, Insurance, and Investment be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on May 17, 2007, at 2:30 p.m., to conduct a hearing on "Consolidation of NASD and the Regulatory Functions of the NYSE: Working Towards Improved Regulation."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
