<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1216224002" ordinal="35" title="RECOGNIZING HEATH-HEADLEY AMERICAN LEGION AUXILIARY POST NO. 0199">
  <narrative>RECOGNIZING HEATH-HEADLEY AMERICAN LEGION AUXILIARY POST NO. 0199 -- (Senate - July 16, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="6867">S6867</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400546" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, today I recognize the Heath-Headley American Legion Auxiliary Post No. 0199 for their Veteran's Day program entitled "Honoring Those Who Served". This event took place on November 9, 2007, at the Henry School Gymnasium with the help of the school's students and staff.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The day's events were held to honor all veterans who have served their country. Local veterans were invited by the auxiliary which publicized the event, registered guests, decorated the school, helped serve lunch, and organized the event with school personnel.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Kampeska Marine Corps League presented and retired the colors. The Henry School Band, directed by Mrs. Deanna Martens, played patriotic music. Students sang "Proud of Our Veterans" and gave a "Living Flag" presentation. Superintendent Brian Sieh welcomed all and presented the guest speaker, Army National Guard Chaplain Joseph Holzhauser, who addressed the crowd on the topic, "Why All The Fighting?"</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Voice of Democracy winner, student Shantel Gassman, presented her winning essay and was awarded a plaque and a scholarship from Watertown Veterans of Foreign Wars Commander Duwayne Mack. Students Matthew Harms and Owen Redinger gave a proper flag folding demonstration and presented the flag to the guest speaker.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Henry High School choir sang "God Bless America" and students Randy Owen and Sarah Montgomery played echo taps. A flag retirement ceremony followed the program under the direction of Marine veteran Joel Montgomery.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The school technology committee took pictures of all veterans and gave prints to each as a thank you. The pictures were taken in front of a mural that senior students and auxiliary member Jane Green created. It depicts the American eagle with wings made of over 200 stars, each naming a local veteran.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Auxiliary members who helped with the activities include Donna Clyde, unit president; Veta Aker, unit treasurer; Jean Lian, unit chaplain; Wanda Clyde, membership chairman; Christy Clyde, junior auxiliary member; Jane Green, unit member and school coordinator for the program. Violet Wicks, district III president, was the auxiliary's guest for the day.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It gives me great pleasure to rise with the Heath-Headley American Legion Auxiliary Post No. 0199 and Henry School to thank our veterans for their dedication and service to our country.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
