<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1179331205" ordinal="10" title="PITTSBURGH HEALTHCARE SYSTEM">
  <speaking speaker="300092" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today I have sought recognition to comment on legislation to increase the authorized spending level for the ongoing consolidation project at the U.S. Department of Veterans Affairs, VA, Pittsburgh Healthcare System.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In May 2004, then-VA Secretary Anthony Principi announced the final results of the Capital Asset Realignment for Enhanced Services, CARES, plan, a nationwide effort to identify buildings and functions which do not merit continued operation and to create long-term budget efficiencies by getting rid of underutilized facilities while improving access to care. As a result of this process, the Highland Drive VA Medical Center, VAMC, in Pittsburgh was targeted for closure, and the facility's functions  are to be consolidated within Pittsburgh's University Drive VAMC and H.J. Heinz VAMC. However, in order for this consolidation to move forward and for the VA to realize the desired savings, significant construction is necessary at the University Drive and Heinz campuses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Initial estimates placed the total cost for construction at these two facilities at $189.2 million. I introduced legislation which authorized construction at this level and have helped secure $102.5 million in appropriations towards this effort--$20 million in fiscal year 2004 and $82.5 million in fiscal year 2006. I have pushed for Congress to fully fund this project in order to avoid cost overruns and to help the VA realize long-term savings which can be used to better serve our Nation's veterans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Despite the Pittsburgh project being ahead of schedule and ready for additional funding, I was disappointed to see that the administration did not seek funding for any component of the Pittsburgh project in its fiscal year 2007 budget request. On February 28, 2006, Senator Rick Santorum and I wrote VA Secretary Jim Nicholson a letter seeking clarification on VA's future plans for funding the project. According to his May 8, 2006, response, "Funding for construction of the mental health and research  facilities at the University Drive VAMC and the ambulatory care center at the Heinz VAMC will be incorporated into VA's fiscal year 2008 budget request." The response also stated, "..... closure of the Highland Drive Division will not be accomplished until all construction is completed." I will ask that this letter be printed in the RECORD. </paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, I was disappointed to learn that the VA's fiscal year 2008 Budget request indicates that the estimated total cost to complete these projects has risen dramatically to $248 million. Further, the VA has only requested $40 million for these projects in fiscal year 2008, which would leave $105.5 million remaining to be appropriated to complete construction. I believe Congress should fully fund this project now in order to avoid additional cost increases in the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill simply raises the authorization to the level indicated by the VA necessary to complete these construction projects. I urge my colleagues to support this technical legislation, which is intended to allow the VA to realize the savings envisioned by the 2004 CARES process on an expedited basis, making more money available for the care of our Nation's veterans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the February 28, 2006, letter Senator Santorum and I wrote to Secretary Nicholson and the Secretary's May 8, 2006 response be printed in the RECORD. </paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
</record>
