<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1190736002" ordinal="67" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <narrative>AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET -- (Senate - September 25, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="12075">S12075</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="COMMITTEE ON BANKING, HOUSING, AND URBAN AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on September 25, 2007, at 9:30 a.m., in order to conduct a hearing entitled "Two Years After the Storm: Housing Needs in the Gulf Coast."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND NATURAL RESOURSES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, September 25, 2007, at 10 a.m. in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purposes of the hearing are to receive testimony on <bill type="s" number="1756">S. 1756</bill>, a bill to provide supplemental ex gratia compensation to the Republic of the Marshall Islands for impacts of the nuclear testing program of the United States, and for other purposes; and to receive testimony on the implementation of the Compact of Free Association between the United States and the Marshall Islands.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENVIRONMENT AND PUBLIC WORKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Environment and Public Works be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, September 25, 2007 at 2 p.m. in room 406 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building in order to conduct a hearing entitled, "Green Jobs Created by Global Warming Initiatives."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="COMMITTEE ON FINANCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Finance be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, September 25, 2007, at 10 a.m., in room G-50 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building, to hear testimony on "Home and Community Based Care: Expanding Options for Long Term Care."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, September 25, 2007, at 2:30 p.m., in order to hold a nomination hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet in order to conduct a hearing entitled "Strengthening FISA: Does the Protect America Act Protect Americans' Civil Liberties and Enhance Security?" on Tuesday, September 25, 2007, at 9:30 a.m., in the Hart Senate Office Building Room 216.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Panel I: The Honorable J. Michael McConnell, Director of National Intelligence, Office of the Director of National Intelligence, Washington, DC.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Panel II: James A. Baker, Lecturer on Law, Harvard Law School, Formerly Counsel for Intelligence Policy, Department of Justice Washington, DC; James X. Dempsey, Policy Director, Center for Democracy and Technology, San Francisco, CA; Suzanne E. Spaulding, Principal Bingham Consulting Group, Washington, DC; Bryan Cunningham, Principal, Morgan &amp; Cunningham LLC, Greenwood Village, CO.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet in order to conduct a hearing entitled "Judicial Nominations" on Tuesday, September 25, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. in the Dirksen Senate Office Building Room 226.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Witness list: John Daniel Tinder to be United States Circuit Judge for the Seventh Circuit; Robert M. Dow, Jr., to be United States District Judge for the Northern District of Illinois.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="COMMITTEE ON VETERANS' AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent for the Committee on Veterans' Affairs to be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, September 25, 2007, in order to conduct an Oversight Hearing on Persian Gulf Research. The Committee will meet in 562 Dirksen Senate Office Building, at 9:30 a.m.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="SELECT COMMITTEE ON INTELLIGENCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Select Committee on Intelligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on September 25, 2007 at 2 p.m. to hold a closed hearing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The PRESIDING OFFICER: Without objection, it is so ordered.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
