<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1177948807" ordinal="22" title="HONORING MARGARET BLACKSHERE">
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today to honor Margaret Blackshere, a woman for whom I have great respect and admiration.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Margaret Blackshere has been involved in the labor movement for more than 40 years and remains deeply committed to helping the working families of Illinois. Until February, she served as president of the 1-million-member strong Illinois AFL-CIO, the third-largest state labor body in the country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over the years, she has never been afraid to roll up her sleeves and join the picket line or to lead the march.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Margaret always arrived first and left last.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>She knows that America's working men and women--those who perform some of the most demanding yet vital tasks in our society--are the real heroes. For her, her service has been a privilege an opportunity to fight for rights she believes should be guaranteed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Margaret didn't start out to be a labor leader; she began her career as a kindergarten teacher in Madison, IL. She became involved in the labor movement almost by accident, after she and her fellow teachers were repeatedly passed over for raises they had earned. In response, she and her colleagues mobilized to pass a referendum that would raise their wages. It wasn't just about the money. It was about having a voice.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This early effort led to a job with the local Illinois Federation of Teachers affiliate in Madison. Through hard work, Margaret rose to become statewide vice president of the IFT.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1993, she was elected secretary-treasurer of the Illinois AFL-CIO. At the time, there were only a handful of female officers in State labor federations, and Margaret stood out as the only female officer from an industrialized State. In 2000, she was elected president of the Illinois AFL-CIO--the first woman to serve as president in the State federation's 102-year history.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under Margaret Blackshere's leadership, the Illinois AFL-CIO helped lead the fight to raise Illinois' minimum wage--not once but twice.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Margaret also led passionate efforts to guarantee women equal pay for equal work, to expand health care, and to improve Illinois' workers' compensation system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>She has a gift for uniting people from diverse backgrounds, with very different viewpoints, under a common goal. This is no easy task, and one that many politicians regularly attempt but often fail.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Margaret recognized the importance of forming an alliance with the Illinois Manufacturers Association and helped to save and create Illinois manufacturing jobs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>She also helped to establish the Transportation for Illinois Coalition, which included groups as diverse as the Illinois Automobile Asphalt and Pavement Association and the Chicago Transit Authority, to speak with a unified voice for Illinois' transportation funding needs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As Margaret fought for Illinois' working families, she raised her own family and has two sons and four grandchildren.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>She also devotes a great deal of time to charitable organizations. She has served on the boards of a wide variety of institutions, including the Illinois branches of United Way and American Red Cross, Alliance for Retired Americans, Voices for Illinois Children, Unemployment Insurance Advisory Board, and the Federal Reserve Board of Chicago. She also is a board member of the Illinois Women's Institute for Leadership, which helps prepare women with progressive values run for political office.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over the years, Margaret has received many accolades and awards. In 2000, the Labor Council for Latin Advancement honored her with the Labor Leader Award, and the State of Israel presented her with the Israel Peace Medal. Margaret also received the Protector of Working People Award in 2002 from the Illinois State Crime Commission. Always proud of her Irish heritage, Margaret was delighted to be the Guest of Honor for Chicago's St. Patrick's Day Parade in 2003.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Margaret says that she doesn't really intend to retire--she will still be fighting the same fights but will do so as a volunteer. She believes her future efforts will involve reaching out to workers in countries across the globe.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to congratulate Margaret Blackshere on her retirement and thank her for her efforts to protect working families in Illinois and across the country. I wish her the very best in her future endeavors.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
