<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1170349202" ordinal="25" title="BIPARTISAN CONCURRENT RESOLUTION ON IRAQ--MOTION TO PROCEED">
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, first of all, I ask unanimous consent that the next cloture vote be vitiated.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300072" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I object.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, this next vote is not necessary. As a result of yesterday's breakthrough in negotiations, the base bill for the Iraq debate will be the Warner-Levin legislation and not <bill type="sc" number="2">S. Con. Res. 2</bill>. So I will vote against cloture and urge both sides of the aisle to do likewise.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The most important question that I have been asked, by popular demand, is when are we going to have a vote on Monday. I have conferred with the Republican leader on more than one occasion. We can still vote at 4:30 and complete the 30 hours prior to Wednesday, which would be our goal. So we are going to vote at 4:30 on Monday on cloture on the Levin-Warner measure, unless we work something out beforehand. Again, that is 4:30 Monday.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Under the previous order, the clerk will report the motion to invoke cloture.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, we yield back our time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300072" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, we yield back our time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> By unanimous consent, the mandatory quorum call has been waived.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>I announce that the Senator from South Dakota (Mr. JOHNSON) and the Senator from New York (Mr. SCHUMER) are necessarily absent.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300069" topic="">
    <paragraph>The following Senator was necessarily absent: the Senator from Oklahoma (Mr. INHOFE).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Further, if present and voting, the Senator from Oklahoma (Mr. INHOFE) would have voted "nay."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Are there any other Senators in the Chamber desiring to vote?</chair>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays resulted--yeas 0, nays 97, as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> On this vote, the yeas are 0, the nays are 97. Three-fifths of the Senators duly chosen and sworn not having voted in the affirmative, the motion is rejected.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="">
    <paragraph>I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400546" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400546" topic="SIOUX FALLS COUGARS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today I rise to recognize the University of Sioux Falls Cougars football team for winning the 2006 NAIA National Football Championship. I would also like to recognize their coach, Kalen DeBoer, for being named the NAIA Football Coach of the Year. The Cougars championship victory in December marked the second national football title for the school in the past 10 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This group of young men had an extraordinary season capped by a 23-to-19 victory over the previously unbeaten University of Saint Francis. That championship victory ensured the Cougars an undefeated season and the first football title since 1996. The University of Sioux Falls did not achieve a No. 1 ranking throughout the entirety of the 2006 season. Their championship was won on the field, not in the polls.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Coach DeBoer was able to achieve this victory in just his second year as head coach of the Cougars. He succeeded legendary coach Bob Young. Under the tutelage of Coach Young, and continued now by Coach DeBoer, the University of Sioux Falls has emerged as one of the premier football institutions in the country. Over the past 10 seasons, the Cougars have amassed a 103 to 19 record while capturing eight conference titles. Faith, loyalty, commitment, and teamwork have served as the foundation to  building this tradition of excellence.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The 2006 Cougars were led to the title thanks to the work of an explosive offense and a powerful defense. They averaged nearly 39 points per game while allowing only seven. Leading the way for the Cougars this season were Chad Cavender, Mike Dvoracek, Dusty Hovorka, and Trey Erickson. These four were selected to the first-team of the 2006 NAIA All-American football team. This marks the first time in University of Sioux Falls history that four players have represented the school on the first-team.  Also, five Cougars earned NAIA All-American honorable mention honors. These players were Zach Campbell, Josiah Fenceroy, Jason Glasco, Letarius Lee, and Adam Paulson.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many of the players from this year's team have spent the last 4 years as teammates. The sixteen current University of Sioux Falls seniors have compiled a remarkable 48 to 4 record, including three Great Plains Athletic Conference championships, four NAIA Championship Series appearances, and the 2006 NAIA Football Championship. This group of student-athletes should be very proud of their impressive accomplishments over the past years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The coaching staff, in alphabetical order, is as follows: Jon Anderson, Adam Breske, Al Christensen, Kalen DeBoer, Jeff Fitzgerald, Nick Fulton, Tom Grogan, Al Hansen, Chuck Morrell, Nate Moser, and Kurtiss Riggs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The team, in alphabetical order, is as follows: Blake Andersen, Alex Anderson, Drew Anderson, Kyle Anderson, Jeremy Barnes, Bret Beachner, Nick Benedetto, Trevor Bowers, Curtis Brown, Tyson Brown, Zach Campbell, Doug Carlson, Luke Castle, Chad Cavender, Max Chapman, Erik Cimpl, Ross Cimpl, Kyle Cummings, Josh Daniels, Drew DeGroot, Dan DeJong, Glen Dirksen, Kyle Dreckman, Michael Dvoracek, Ernest Eaton, Brett Elgersma, Trey Erickson, Nate Everett, Josiah Fenceroy, Clint Fischer, Jason Glasco,  Aaron Gunderson, Mike Hartley, Luke Hartman, Nick Haub, Adam Henglefelt, Trevor Holleman, Cameron Horton, Dusty Hovorka, Aaron Jensen, Gregg Jensen, James Johnikin, Matt Johnson, Joel Kelpe, Kyle Kidd, Blake Klinsing, Brandon Koolstra, Todd Kutter, Ty Larson, Letarius Lee, John Lentz, Matt Lindgren, Tyler Lodermeier, Ryan Lowmiller, Brad Maag, Lane Mellegaard, Matt Miller, Dan Moe, Joe Moen, Tyler Mousel, A.J. Munger, Scott Neu, Tyler Newman, Matt Norgaard, Jeff Nuzum, Chris Opitz,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I congratulate the men who won this National Championship and the coaches who led the way. The University of Sioux Falls football team has proven that they are strong competitors and dedicated athletes. On behalf of the city of Sioux Falls and the state of South Dakota, I am pleased to say congratulations, Cougars. You have made us all very proud.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor and suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="SIOUX FALLS COUGARS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
