<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1183953600" ordinal="28" title="INTELLIGENCE AUTHORIZATION">
  <narrative>INTELLIGENCE AUTHORIZATION -- (Senate - July 09, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="8789">S8789</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300084" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, in January the Senate took an important step toward improving congressional accountability by passing the Legislative Transparency and Accountability Act as part of <bill type="s" number="1">S. 1</bill>. One of the key provisions of this legislation attempts to shine light on the process by which Members request the inclusion of specific projects in legislation--in other words, earmarks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That provision includes a requirement that each Senate committee make public all congressional earmarks included in bills reported by the committee. We normally think of earmarks as part of the appropriations process, but the requirement in <bill type="s" number="1">S. 1</bill> applies to all bills and makes it clear that the term "congressional earmark" includes language authorizing funds, not just appropriations language. The legislation includes a specific requirement to disclose earmarks contained in classified portions  of reports "to the extent practicable, consistent with the need to protect national security."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With that in mind, I rise today to formally describe for the Senate the earmarks included in <bill type="s" number="1538">S. 1538</bill>, the Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008, a bill reported by the Senate Select Committee on Intelligence on May 31, 2007. This information was not included specifically in the bill or report because we were wrestling with what, if anything, in the bill and classified annex met the definition of an earmark. The definition included in <bill type="s" number="1">S. 1</bill> is subject to some interpretation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Taking an expansive view of the definition, Vice Chairman Bond and I identified three items that seem to fit. I ask to have a list of those earmarks printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>Congressional Earmarks Included in the Classified Annex Accompanying <bill type="s" number="1538">S. 1538</bill>, the Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008</narrative>
  <narrative>A provision adding $200,000 to the office of the Director of National Intelligence for an Intelligence Training Program run by the Kennedy School of Government. This program was started in fiscal year 2007 but the President did not request funding for it for fiscal year 2008. The provision was added at the request of Senator Rockefeller.</narrative>
  <narrative>A provision adding $4,500,000 to the Naval Oceanographic Command. This provision was added at the request of Senator Lott.</narrative>
  <narrative>A provision directing the expenditure of $5,000,000 for a classified effort with the National Reconnaissance Office's GEOINT/SIGINT Integrated Ground Development Engineering and Management Expenditure Center. This provision was added at the request of Senator Rockefeller.</narrative>
  <narrative><bill type="s" number="1538">S. 1538</bill> contains no limited tax benefits or limited tariff benefits, as defined in Section 103 of <bill type="s" number="1">S. 1</bill>.</narrative>
</record>
