<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1195059601" ordinal="5" title="MEASURES PLACED ON THE CALENDAR--S. 2334, S. 2340, S. 2346, S. 2348, and H.R. 3996">
  <narrative>MEASURES PLACED ON THE CALENDAR--S. 2334, <bill type="s" number="2340">S. 2340</bill>, <bill type="s" number="2346">S. 2346</bill>, <bill type="s" number="2348">S. 2348</bill>, and <bill type="h" number="3996">H.R. 3996</bill> -- (Senate - November 14, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="14353">S14353</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I understand there are five bills at the desk due for their second reading.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will read the titles of the bills, en bloc.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A bill (<bill type="s" number="2334">S. 2334</bill>) to withhold 10 percent of the Federal funding apportioned for highway construction and maintenance from States that issue driver's licenses to individuals without verifying the legal status of such individuals.</narrative>
  <narrative>A bill (<bill type="s" number="2340">S. 2340</bill>) making emergency supplemental appropriations for the Department of Defense for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2008, and for other purposes.</narrative>
  <narrative>A bill (<bill type="s" number="2346">S. 2346</bill>) to temporarily increase the portfolio caps applicable to Freddie Mac and Fannie Mae, to provide the necessary financing to curb foreclosures by facilitating the refinancing of at-risk subprime borrowers into safe, affordable loans, and for other purposes.</narrative>
  <narrative>A bill (<bill type="s" number="2348">S. 2348</bill>) to ensure control over the United States border and to strengthen enforcement of the immigration laws.</narrative>
  <narrative>A bill (<bill type="h" number="3996">H.R. 3996</bill>) to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to extend certain expiring provisions, and for other purposes.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I object to any further proceedings with regard to these bills en bloc.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Objection is heard. The bills will be placed on the calendar.</chair>
</record>
