<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1179417651" ordinal="44" title="SENATE RESOLUTION 210--HONORING THE ACCOMPLISHMENTS OF STEPHEN JOEL TRACHTENBERG AS PRESIDENT OF THE GEORGE WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY IN WASHINGTON, D.C., IN RECOGNITION OF HIS UPCOMING RETIREMENT IN JULY 2007">
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today to introduce a resolution, along with my colleague Senators ENZI and INOUYE, to honor the accomplishments of Stephen Joel Trachtenberg. This resolution honors a remarkable man. President Trachtenberg is about to retire in July 2007 as the third-longest serving President of George Washington University, one of this country's premier educational organizations; an institution that contributes deeply, year after year, to our understanding of  the world around us.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have known Steve Trachtenberg for a long time, since his service in Connecticut as the third President of the University of Hartford from 1977 to 1988. He is a proud native of Brooklyn, N.Y., and as an accomplished author, scholar, and educator, he has earned the respect and admiration of his colleagues, peers and students. I know he is also proud of his wife, Francine Zorn Trachtenberg, and his two sons, Adam and Ben.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>President Trachtenberg earned his bachelor's degree from Columbia University in 1959, and showed his skill at making sound decisions by going to Yale to get his law degree in 1962. A Master of Public Administration degree followed later from Harvard.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Prior to his illustrious career in academia, he served in government as a special assistant to the U.S. Education Commissioner at the Department of Health, Education and Welfare, as an attorney with the U.S. Atomic Energy Commission, and on the Hill as a legislative aide to former Indiana Congressman John Brademas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>President Trachtenberg's has won numerous well-deserved awards and  honorary degrees. I will only site a few examples here. In 1982 he was celebrated by the Connecticut Region of Hadassah with the Myrtle Wreath Award. In 1984 he was presented with The Mt. Scopus Award from Hebrew University in Jerusalem, and in 1987 received the Human Relations Award from the National Conference of Christians and Jews.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1988 he was honored with the Distinguished Public Service Award from the Connecticut Bar Association, and was proudly recognized by the Hartford NAACP for his contributions to the education of minority students. In 1992 he received the International Salute Award in honor of Martin Luther King, Jr.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He was even named "Washingtonian of the Year 2000" by Washingtonian Magazine, was decorated in 2000 with a medal by King Mohammed VI of Morocco, and was awarded the Order of St. John of Jerusalem, Knight Grand Cross for Distinguished Service to Freemasonry and Humanity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For all he has done, "Stephen Joel Trachtenberg Day" was declared by resolution of the Council of the District of Columbia, on January 22, 1998, in honor of his commitments to minority students, scholarship programs, public school partnerships and community service. Not to be outdone, "Stephen Joel Trachtenberg Day in San Francisco!" was declared by Proclamation of the City and County of San Francisco, on February 2, 1999.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He is also a respected author writing Reflections on Higher Education in 2002, Thinking Out Loud in 1998, and Speaking His Mind in 1994.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As President of George Washington University he opened new buildings for the School of Business and the Elliott School of International Affairs, a new hospital, and added the Mount Vernon Campus, formerly the Mount Vernon College for Women. He also created five new schools: Public Health and Health Services, Public Policy and Public Administration, College of Professional Studies, Graduate School of Political Management, and Media and Public Affairs. Importantly he "reinvented" the University's  position and positive reputation as Washington, D.C.'s center of scholarship.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After all of these accomplishments he is retiring as President of the George Washington University, but will continue as President Emeritus and as a University Professor of Public Service.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In this resolution, the Senate:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>1. honors and salutes the accomplishments of Stephen Joel Trachtenberg and recognizes his deeds throughout his 19 years of service as President of The George Washington University in Washington, D.C.;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>2. recognizes his accomplishments and achievements in higher education, as an author, as an attorney and as a public official; and</paragraph>
    <paragraph>3. based upon his service extends its appreciation to him in recognition of his retirement as President of The George Washington University in Washington, D.C.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I urge the Senate to act quickly on this resolution to honor the efforts of President Trachtenberg on behalf of so many who have benefited from his extraordinary service.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
