<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1196960402" ordinal="40" title="TRIBUTE TO JOSEPH ATKINS NICKERSON, JR.">
  <narrative>TRIBUTE TO JOSEPH ATKINS NICKERSON, JR. -- (Senate - December 06, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="14843">S14843</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I welcome this opportunity to pay tribute to the extraordinary life and work of Joseph Atkins Nickerson, Jr., of Chatham, MA, a retired builder and prominent local historian who passed away on November 23 at the age of 89. Joe lived his entire life in the town of Chatham. The only exception was during his service to the Navy during World War II.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Joe was a direct descendent of the founders of Chatham, and he will always be remembered for his leadership in preserving the town's history. He had an extraordinary ability to recall people, places, and dates, and his story-telling skill was legendary.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Joe was a member of numerous local sports teams in his youth, and at the age of 22 he pitched a no hit, no run, no walk, 22 strike-out perfect baseball game for the local Chatham team. He was also an original member of the Chatham Town Band, and played the clarinet beautifully in concerts and parades for over 50 years. His skills as a town musician were a great source of pride for all his family.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Joe served the town in many other ways as well. He was a volunteer fireman, a member of the School Building Committee, president and historian of the Chatham Historical Society, a founding member of the Conservation Association, president of the Boston Glass Club, and a member of the Retired Men's Club.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In recent years, Joe and his beloved wife Gerry worked together to write a book, "Chatham Sea Captains in The Age of Sail." Before he passed away he was delighted to learn that his long-awaited book would be published by History Press, Inc. of Charleston, SC, in February 2008. I am sure it will be a wonderful memorial to Joe and a delight to the people of Chatham and all of us who love Cape Cod. His remarkable life and his commitment to the community will continue to inspire us all for years  to come, and we mourn the passing of this amazing son of Chatham.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
