<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1207065602" ordinal="45" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <narrative>AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET -- (Senate - April 01, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="2305">S2305</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND NATURAL RESOURCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate to conduct a hearing on Tuesday, April 1, 2008, at 2:30 p.m., in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON FINANCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Finance be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, April 1, 2008, at 10 a.m., in room 215 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building, to hear testimony on "Anti-Terrorism Financing: Progress Made and the Challenges Ahead".</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, April 1, 2008, at 2:30 p.m., to hold a closed briefing on Iraq.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON HEALTH, EDUCATION, LABOR, AND PENSIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions be authorized to meet, during the session of the Senate, to conduct a hearing entitled "Serious OSHA Violations: Strategies for Breaking Dangerous Patterns" on Tuesday, April 1, 2008. The hearing will commence at 10 a.m. in room 430 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="READINESS AND MANAGEMENT SUPPORT SUBCOMMITTEE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Readiness and Management Support Subcommittee of the Committee on Armed  Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, April 1, 2008, at 2:30 p.m., in open session to receive testimony on the current readiness of the Armed Forces in review of the defense authorization request for fiscal year 2009 and the Future Years Defense Program.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection. it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="SELECT COMMITTEE ON INTELLIGENCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Select Committee on Intelligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on April 1, 2008, at 2:30 p.m. to hold a closed business meeting.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON AIRLAND">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on Airland of the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, April 1, 2008, at 9:30 a.m., in open session to receive testimony on the Army's new doctrine (field manual 3-0, operations) in review of the defense authorization request for fiscal year 2009 and the Future Years Defense Program.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON HUMAN RIGHTS AND THE LAW">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate Committee on the Judiciary, Subcommittee on Human Rights and the Law, be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate to conduct a hearing entitled "Rape as a Weapon of War: Accountability for Sexual Violence in Conflict" on Tuesday, April 1, 2008, at 10 a.m., in room SD-226 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Lisa F. Jackson, Documentary Maker and Director of "The Greatest Silence: Rape in the Congo", New York, NY; Karin Wachter, Acting Gender-Based Violence Senior Technical Advisor, International Rescue Committee, New York, NY; Dr. Kelly Dawn Askin, Senior Legal Officer, Open Society Justice Initiative, New York, NY; Dr. Denis Mukwege, Director, Panzi General Referral Hospital, Bukavu, South Kivu, Democratic Republic of the Congo.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON STRATEGIC FORCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on Strategic Forces of the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, April 1, 2008, at 2:30 p.m., in open session to receive testimony on ballistic missile defense programs in review of the Defense authorization request for fiscal year 2009 and the Future Years Defense Program.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
