<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1222876803" ordinal="36" title="PRIVACY PROTECTIONS--S. 2321">
  <narrative>PRIVACY PROTECTIONS--S. 2321 -- (Senate - October 01, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="10304">S10304</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I am pleased to announce that, today, after several discussions, the Bush administration and lead sponsors of the E-Government Reauthorization Act of 2008, <bill type="s" number="2321">S. 2321</bill>, have accepted an amendment I have drafted to ensure that Americans' privacy comes first when the Government purchases and uses their most sensitive personal information. My amendment requires that Federal agencies must conduct privacy impact assessments before employing outside contractors that use and market  Americans' sensitive personal data.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The addition of privacy protections to the E-Government Reauthorization Act will help to better protect all Americans from the growing threats of data breaches, identity theft, and other cyber crimes. I am particularly pleased about the compromise reached today because I am a proud supporter of this bill. In 2002, I was an original cosponsor of E-Government Act, and in the intervening years, I have worked to promote and strengthen this law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The E-Government Reauthorization Act is a good bill that will now be even better because of the privacy protections added by my amendment. Recently, the Government Accountability Office released a report on lessons learned about the Government data breaches at the Veterans' Administration and elsewhere. That report found that Government contractor responsibilities for preventing and responding to data breaches should be clearly defined. My amendment takes a small but important step toward addressing  the growing problem of lax data security by Government contractors by making sure that Americans' privacy rights are not compromised when they entrust their sensitive personal information to our Government.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank the lead sponsors of this bill for working with me on compromise privacy language for this bill. I also thank the many stakeholders who support this bill and my privacy amendment, including the Center for Democracy and Technology, Symantec, and the Cyber Security Industry Alliance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge all Senators to support and pass this important legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
