<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1222531203" ordinal="21" title="SENATOR JOHN WARNER">
  <narrative>SENATOR JOHN WARNER -- (Senate - September 27, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="9973">S9973</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400619" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I want to make a few comments about my good friend, Senator John Warner from Virginia. When you first come to this body, you get to know people. Soon I got to know him as a Senator's Senator, because he was one of those people who was always trying to bring people together and take on the major issues that confront our country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I had the distinct honor of traveling to Iraq and other countries with him and with the distinguished Presiding Officer. I admired the relationship between Senator Levin and Senator Warner as a template for how things should run in Washington, DC as we represent the 325 million people of America. There are two people from two different parties who work together to make sure that what we were doing was the very best job that we could to protect America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So you are, both the Presiding Officer as well as Senator Warner, two of my most significant role models in this Chamber. I admire you both for your service.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senator from Virginia was a member of pulling together the Gang of 14. It was now some 2 years ago when we were debating whether there would be a "nuclear option" and whether we would move forward in saving some of the procedures and the very functioning of the institution of the Senate. I remember working in awe with him as he and Senator Byrd and others worked on that historic document at that time, and on so many other occasions where he has been the person who has been the  glue to bring people together. So he is a Senator's Senator, because he is such a proud American and such a wonderful leader for Virginia and for the Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But he also is a wonderful Senator because he has a very unique ability of bringing people together. I would hope that all of us, the 100 Members of this Chamber, always continue to look to him for the kind of inspiration and great example he has been.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300099" topic="">
    <paragraph>I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <chair>The bill clerk proceeded to call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300063" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300063" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent to speak for up to 15 minutes as in morning business.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
