<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1196701202" ordinal="47" title="TO REPEAL A PROHIBITION ON THE USE OF CERTAIN FUNDS IN CALIFORNIA">
  <narrative>TO REPEAL A PROHIBITION ON THE USE OF CERTAIN FUNDS IN CALIFORNIA -- (Senate - December 03, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="14706">S14706</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400619" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Banking Committee be discharged from further consideration of <bill type="h" number="238">H.R. 238</bill> and that the Senate proceed to its immediate consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered. The clerk will report the bill by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A bill (<bill type="h" number="238">H.R. 238</bill>) to repeal a prohibition on the use of certain funds for tunneling in certain areas with respect to the Los Angeles to San Fernando Valley Metro Rail project, California.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the bill.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400619" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that a Dodd-Shelby amendment at the desk be agreed to, the bill as amended be read a third time and passed, the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table, with no intervening action or debate, and that any statements related to the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The amendment (No. 3802) was agreed to, as follows:</chair>
  <narrative>(Purpose: To amend section 5307 of title 49, United States Code, to extend the special rule for the allocation of urbanized area formula grants through fiscal year 2009)</narrative>
  <narrative> At the end of the bill, add the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. URBANIZED AREA FORMULA GRANTS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Section 5307(b)(2) of title 49, United States Code, is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in the heading, by striking "2007" and inserting "2009";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) in subparagraph (A), by striking "2007" and inserting "2009"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) by adding at the end the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(E) MAXIMUM AMOUNTS IN FISCAL YEARS 2008 AND 2009.--In fiscal years 2008 and 2009--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(i) amounts made available to any urbanized area under clause (i) or (ii) of subparagraph (A) shall be not more than 50 percent of the amount apportioned in fiscal year 2002 to the urbanized area with a population of less than 200,000, as determined in the 1990 decennial census of population;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(ii) amounts made available to any urbanized area under subparagraph (A)(iii) shall be not more than 50 percent of the amount apportioned to the urbanized area under this section for fiscal year 2003; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(iii) each portion of any area not designated as an urbanized area, as determined by the 1990 decennial census, and eligible to receive funds under subparagraph (A)(iv), shall receive an amount of funds to carry out this section that is not less than 50 percent of the amount the portion of the area received under section 5311 in fiscal year 2002.".</narrative>
  <narrative>The amendment was ordered to be engrossed and the bill to be read a third time.</narrative>
  <narrative>The bill (<bill type="h" number="238">H.R. 238</bill>), as amended, was read the third time and passed.</narrative>
</record>
