<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1229014804" ordinal="45" title="ADDITIONAL STATEMENTS">
  <narrative>ADDITIONAL STATEMENTS -- (Senate - December 11, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="10943">S10943</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300014" topic="CONGRATULATING BRONZE MEDAL SCHOOLS IN KENTUCKY">
    <paragraph>Madam President, today I congratulate the top public schools in the Commonwealth of Kentucky. I was pleased to learn that U.S. News and World Report awarded 26 high schools in Kentucky with a bronze medal for their outstanding performance on standardized exams and for providing college-level coursework.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These 26 Kentucky high schools have shown that they foster an environment that serves all students, no matter their academic goals, by demonstrating a commitment to excellence through quality education. These Bronze Medal Schools back this up with measurable academic outcomes that show improvement throughout a range of performance indicators.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have always been proud of Kentucky education because of its relentless effort to enhance and develop the lives of every student. This is a well deserved recognition for the excellent work that is done by all of these high schools, and I would like to congratulate each for its great success.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The following schools were commended with awards: Barbourville City School in Barbourville, KY; Bardstown High School in Bardstown, KY; Central High School in Louisville, KY; Corbin High School in Corbin, KY; Dawson Springs High School in Dawson Springs, KY; Eminence High School in Eminence, KY; Evarts High School in Evarts, KY; Frederick Fraize High School in Cloverport, KY; Graves County High School in Mayfield, KY; Hancock County High School in Lewisport,  KY;  Harlan High School in Harlan, KY; Hazard High School in Hazard, KY; Hickman County High School in Clinton, KY; Jackson City School in Jackson, KY; Johnson Central High School in Paintsville, KY; Magoffin County High School in Salyersville, KY; Owensboro High School in Owensboro, KY; Paintsville High School in Paintsville, KY; Paris</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, I commend these high schools for a job well done. I hope that their efforts will inspire other schools in Kentucky and around the country to strive for the best.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
