<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1170781203" ordinal="34" title="STATEMENTS ON INTRODUCED BILLS AND JOINT RESOLUTIONS">
  <speaking speaker="300070" topic="Introducing S. 494. A bill to endorse further enlargement of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) and to facilitate the timely admission of new members to NATO, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Foreign Relations.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="494">S. 494</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to introduce the "NATO Freedom Consolidation Act of 2007". Last year this legislation passed the Senate by unanimous consent. Unfortunately, the House was unable to act prior to adjournment last year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I was pleased that thirteen of my colleagues, including Senators BIDEN, CHAMBLISS, COLEMAN, DODD, HAGEL, HUTCHISON, MARTINEZ, MCCAIN, SMITH, and SUNUNU, joined me in proposing this important legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The goal of this bill is to reaffirm United States support for continued enlargement of NATO to democracies that are able and willing to meet the responsibilities of membership. In particular, the legislation calls for the timely admission of Albania, Croatia, Georgia, Macedonia, and Ukraine to NATO and authorizes security assistance for these countries in Fiscal Year 2008. Each of these countries has clearly stated its desire to join NATO and is working hard to meet the specified requirements  for membership.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe that eventual NATO membership for these five countries would be a success for Europe, NATO, and the United States by continuing to extend the zone of peace and security. Albania, Croatia, and Macedonia have been making progress on reforms through their participation in the NATO Membership Action Plan since 2002. Unfortunately, Georgia and Ukraine have not yet been granted a Membership Action Plan but nevertheless have made remarkable progress. This legislation will provide important  incentives and assistance to the countries to continue the implementation of democratic, defense, and economic reforms.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since the end of the Cold War, NATO has been evolving to meet the new security needs of the 21st century. In this era, the threats to NATO members are transnational and far from its geographic borders. There is strong support among members for NATO's operation in Afghanistan, and for its training mission in Iraq. NATO's viability as an effective defense and security alliance depends on flexible, creative leadership, as well as the willingness of members to improve capabilities and address common  threats.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If NATO is to continue to be the preeminent security Alliance and serve the defense interests of its membership, it must continue to evolve and that evolution must include enlargement. Potential NATO membership motivates emerging democracies to make important advances in areas such as the rule of law and civil society. A closer relationship with NATO will promote these values and contribute to our mutual security. Georgia is a young democracy that has made tremendous progress since the "Rose  Revolution." It is situated in a critical geo-strategic location and is host to a large portion of the Baku-Tbilisi-Ceyhan pipeline that carries important energy resources to the West from Azerbaijan and, in the future, Kazakhstan. Georgia is resisting</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Three years ago, the United States Senate unanimously voted to invite seven countries to join NATO. Today, Bulgaria, Estonia, Latvia, Lithuania, Romania, Slovakia, and Slovenia are making significant contributions to NATO and are among our closest allies in the global war on terrorism. It is time again for the United States to take the lead in urging its allies to bring in new members, and to offer timely admission of Albania, Croatia, Georgia, Macedonia, and Ukraine to NATO.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="Introducing S. 495. A bill to prevent and mitigate identity theft, to ensure privacy, to provide notice of security breaches, and to enhance criminal penalties, law enforcement assistance, and other protections against security breaches, fraudulent access, and misuse of personally identifiable information; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="495">S. 495</bill>] Mr. President, today I am pleased to join Senator Specter in reintroducing the Leahy-Specter Personal Data Privacy and Security Act. This is a comprehensive data privacy package aimed at better protecting Americans' privacy. Senator Specter has been a valuable partner on this, and I also thank Majority Leader Reid for his leadership and commitment to enacting data privacy legislation this year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When Senator Specter and I introduced this bill in 2005, we had high hopes of bringing urgently needed data privacy reforms to the American people. The Judiciary Committee reported this bill favorably in November of 2005, but with the last Congress, it simply sat on the calendar. The leadership would not bring it forward.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The irony is while they refused to bring it forward, the problems of data breaches remained a persistent and pernicious threat to Americans' privacy. Yesterday we learned that the Department of Veterans Affairs has lost a portable hard drive containing the sensitive personal information on as many as 48,000 veterans. I can imagine what the veterans in my State feel about that. I can imagine what the veterans in Montana feel about that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last week, there was a major data breach involving a State computer server in my home State of Vermont. It jeopardized the financial data of at least 69,000 Vermonters whose personal financial information had been stored on the computer used by the Vermont Agency of Human Services. Can you imagine 69,000 people, in a State of barely over 600,000 people.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is not unique to Vermont. Last month mega retailer TJX disclosed that it suffered a major computer breach involving credit and debt card purchases involving possibly hundreds of thousands of American consumers. And, even as disturbing as that is, while they knew about the breach in mid-December, none of those customers were told about it until a month later. It is as if a thief had gone to each one of their houses and stolen their data.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Of course, all of this comes on the heels of the theft of the personal data of 26.5 million of our veterans and active-duty personnel at the VA last year. Think about this: You are a man or a woman serving your country in Afghanistan or Iraq, and this information is stolen--with data about where you live and what family members are left at home while you are overseas. How do you think that makes you feel?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>According to the Privacy Rights Clearinghouse, more than 100 million records containing sensitive personal information have been involved in data security breaches since 2005. We need strong Federal data privacy and security laws to protect Americans' personal data, and to address the ills of lax data security.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our bill requires that data brokers let consumers know what sensitive personal information they have about them and to allow individuals to correct this. It is a simple matter of fairness. There is a clear precedent for our approach in the credit reporting context. Our bill also requires that companies who have databases with sensitive personal information about Americans establish and implement data privacy and security programs. In the information age, any company that wants to be trusted by  the public must earn that trust by vigilantly protecting the databases that they use and maintain. In addition, our bill requires notice when sensitive personal information has been compromised. The American people need to know when they may be exposed to a data breach. Whether it is a government agency or</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We also have tough criminal penalties for anyone who would intentionally or willfully conceal the fact that a data breach has occurred when that breach causes economic damage to consumers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Then finally, we address the important issue of the Government's use of personal data. This would require Federal agencies to notify affected individuals when Government data breaches occur.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We should never have to worry about our Government having this information on us and losing it, but certainly in the last 2 or 3 years, we have seen so many millions of files that have been lost or put in jeopardy. We live in a world in which our Government also is increasingly turning to the private sector to get personal data that they, in some instances, couldn't legally get on their own. To address this, our bill puts protecting Americans' privacy first and foremost: Government data has to  be protected and we have to know if the Government falls down on the job.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a comprehensive bill. It not only deals with the need to provide Americans notice when they have been victims of a data breach, it also deals with the underlying problems of lack of security and lack of accountability to prevent data breaches from occurring in the first place.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, Americans live in a world where their most sensitive personal information can be accessed and sold to the highest bidder with a few keystrokes on their computer. Our privacy laws greatly lag behind both the capabilities of our technology and the cunning of identity thieves. This legislation closes that gap. I commend the leadership for being willing to bring up our data privacy bill. I wish that the leadership in the last Congress had brought this bill up last year. But, I am glad that  the new leadership will do so this year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For the sake of all Americans, I urge all Senators to support this legislation and to act now to pass comprehensive data privacy and security legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300092" topic="TITLE IV--GOVERNMENT ACCESS TO AND USE OF COMMERCIAL DATA">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I seek recognition today to discuss the Personal Data Privacy and Security Act of 2007, which I am introducing with Senator LEAHY. Not long ago, personal information--Social Security numbers, birthdates, mothers' maiden names, addresses--all remained relatively private. Some information--for example,  whether you had a mortgage on your home--might have been publicly available, but finding that information required a  trip to the local courthouse. For the most part, the sheer difficulty of obtaining personal information kept it private. This privacy--what Justice Brandeis called the freedom to be left alone--has been a cherished value throughout American history.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As everyday transactions increasingly occur electronically, personal information can be stored, transmitted and accessed much more easily. Most Americans have benefited from this change. Because personal information is available electronically, Americans enjoy the convenience of purchasing goods over the phone or on the Internet. They can obtain a home mortgage in a matter of hours. They can apply for a credit card while they wait at the store. The availability of such information also helps  law enforcement agencies conduct investigations and apprehend criminals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In electronic form, personal information is both more valuable and more vulnerable. As the multitude of security breaches that have occurred over the past 2 years demonstrate, electronic information is more vulnerable because it can be accessed anonymously from afar and can be stolen in a split second. According to the Privacy Rights Clearing House, since February 2005, over 100 million records containing personal information have been subject to some sort of security breach. The first of these  incidents to come to light involved commercial data broker ChoicePoint, which in February 2005 reported that identity thieves had gained access to personal information of 163,000 people. The identity thieves had obtained the information by setting up sham accounts with ChoicePoint. ChoicePoint eventually settled with the FTC for $15 million, including $5 million for consumer redress. However, consumers might never have found out about the breach. The incident only</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After the ChoicePoint incident came a long series of security breaches involving major American companies. In March of 2005, Designer Shoe Warehouse reported that hackers had gained access to personal information, including credit card numbers, on over 100,000 of its customers. Weeks later, Lexis Nexis reported that hackers had gained access to the personal information of over 300,000 individuals. Other blue-chip companies where unauthorized persons have gained access to personal information  include Wal-Mart, General Motors, Wachovia Bank, H&amp;R Block, Honeywell, AT&amp;T, Lloyd's of London, ARCO, Visa, MasterCard, Bank of America, FedEx, OfficeMax, Blue Cross Blue Shield and Ralph Lauren. The largest incident came in June 2005, when Card Systems, which processes payments for the country's largest banks and credit card companies, reported that hackers had accessed 40 million records containing personal information. Most recently,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A large number of colleges and universities have also suffered significant breaches, including the University of Southern California, which in July of 2005 reported that hackers has accessed 270,000 records containing personal data. Other educational institutions that have been hacked include Boston College, Northwestern University, Tufts University, UCLA, Michigan State, Carnegie Mellon, Perdue, Stanford, Duke, the University of Iowa, the University of Colorado, and the University of Utah.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Governments also have not been immune from attempts by identity thieves to obtain personal information. Hackers have accessed personal data at the Department of Defense, Department of Energy, the Air Force and the Department of Agriculture. Hackers obtained over half a million records containing personal data from a State agency in Georgia. The San Diego County Employees Retirement Association, the California Department of Corrections, the Nebraska Treasurers office, the city of Lubbock, TX,  and a Women, Infants and Children (WIC) program in Hawaii have all been the victims of similar thefts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Electronic personal data is more valuable because identity thieves can steal a large volume of data and use it before anyone even knows their personal information has been compromised. For the last 5 years, identity theft has topped the FTC's list of consumer complaints. From 2002 to 2004, the number of complaints rose 52 percent, to 246,570. Put another way, that's one complaint every 2 minutes. But this is only the tip of the iceberg. Not all consumers report identity theft to the FTC. Not all victims report identity theft to their local police. Sixty percent of those who did file a report with the FTC did not call their local police department. It stands to reason that many did not call the FTC.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A recent study by the Better Business Bureau concluded that 8.9 million Americans were victims of identity fraud in 2006, and that each victim lost approximately $6,300. Ultimately, it has been predicted that nearly 20 percent of Americans will become victims of identity theft. Worse, according to the study, it took victims an average of 40 hours on the phone with creditors and credit bureaus to clear their names. I use the term "clear" loosely, because in many cases the damage caused by identity  theft is irreversible. Victims will have fraud alerts on their credit reports for years to come, making it more difficult for them to open new accounts or make major purchases. Some will be erroneously contacted by collection agencies. Many will not even know they have been victimized until they try to get a car loan or a mortgage on a home.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Individuals who have not yet been victims also suffer. Businesses lose nearly $50 billion a year from identity thieves posing as customers. These losses translate into increased prices for every consumer. All Americans are victims of identify theft, even if their own information remains secure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In some cases, the availability of electronic personal data can lead to tragedy. In 1999, a former high school classmate of Amy Lynn Boyer obtained her former work address and Social Security number from an on-line data broker. Using this information, he called Amy's mother and posed as the former employer, convincing Amy's mom to give him Amy's new work address. He then drove to Amy's workplace and fatally shot her.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In an effort to protect the privacy and security of our personal information, and prevent future tragedies, small and large, last Congress, Senator LEAHY and I introduced the Personal Data Privacy and Security Act. The problem is one of large proportions and many have views on how to go about tackling it. Six committees, three on the House side and three on the Senate side, introduced legislation last Congress addressing data security. At least two other Senate committees became involved  in the issue. It is my hope that the differences among committees and members can be bridged this Congress. The problem is simply too large to ignore.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In an effort to start that process, Senator LEAHY and I are again introducing the Personal Data Privacy and Security Act. We are reintroducing the bill in largely the same form that it was approved by the Judiciary Committee last Congress. The bill takes a comprehensive approach to the problem, an approach I believe is necessary. First, the legislation goes after identity thieves by increasing penalties for crimes involving electronic personal information. It also contains criminal penalties  for those who intentionally conceal a security breach involving personal data. Those who actively conceal breaches attempt to protect themselves by gambling with the reputations and finances of innocent Americans. They deserve to be punished.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also empowers Americans to look after the privacy of their own information. The bill will allow individuals to gain access to their personal information when it is in the hands of commercial data brokers. For individuals who believe their information is wrong--possibly because the activities of identity thieves--data brokers must provide assistance with correcting their information.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation also places some of the burden of protecting privacy on those that collect personal information. It will require the companies, government agencies, universities and others that deal with personal information to identify and remedy any weaknesses in their computer systems.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Such measures will not always be enough. As I've already noted, the nature of electronic information makes it vulnerable even when reasonable steps are taken to protect it. Currently, over 30 States have adopted legislation requiring companies, agencies, universities and others to give notice when they experience a security breach that involves personal information. However, no Federal law imposes such a requirement. As a result, companies are forced to comply with over 30 different State laws,  an expensive and time-consuming endeavor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Personal Data Privacy and Security Act requires that both affected individuals and law enforcement receive notice. Knowledge is power. Once individuals learn that their personal information is exposed, they can take steps to protect themselves. And, the company, school or agency that experienced the breach must help. They must provide individuals whose data was lost with credit monitoring. For large breaches, the media must be notified. Media reports over the 2 years have made Americans far  more aware of the problem of security breaches. Hopefully, we can raise awareness by continuing the practice of making public announcements. Notice will also give law enforcement a head start in catching those who steal personal information.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, this legislation will protect the privacy of all Americans by providing a check on the government's use of commercial databases. Federal law enforcement agencies use commercial databases to track criminals and criminal activity. Correctly used, these databases can be very useful tools in the fight against crime. However, there should be some check on their use. The bill makes it clear that protections similar to those provided by the Privacy Act are applied to the government's use of  commercial databases. The legislation also aims at making sure the government's use of such data is secure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill represents a comprehensive effort to protect the privacy and security of the personal information of all Americans. The lives of most Americans have been made easier because our personal information is readily available to those who have a legitimate need for it. This legislation aims to keep such information out of the hands of those who have no legitimate need for it. I want to take a moment to thank my colleague, Senator LEAHY, who has been tireless in his efforts to promote  individual privacy. He has long fought these issues on the Senate floor and has been a leader in securing the privacy rights of all Americans. I urge my colleagues to join us in supporting this important legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300042" topic="TITLE IV--GOVERNMENT ACCESS TO AND USE OF COMMERCIAL DATA">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I am proud to be an original cosponsor of the Personal Data Privacy and Security Act of 2007. This bill is a much-needed solution to the daunting problem of ensuring the privacy and the security of our personal data, which has become such a precious commodity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Several forces are converging to make our personal information more valuable--and more vulnerable--than ever. The world is digital and so is our personal data. In this day and age, almost everything we do results in a third party creating a digital record about us--digital records that we may not even realize exist. We seek the convenience of opening bank accounts, managing our credit cards, and making major purchases over the Internet. And we often complete these transactions without ever speaking  to another person face-to-face or over the telephone. Businesses, nonprofits, and political parties are personalizing their messages, products, and services to a degree we've never seen before, and they are willing to invest significant amounts of money in collecting personal</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a result, personal information has become a hot commodity that is bought, sold, and--as so often happens when something becomes valuable--stolen.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are at a crossroads. We all know about the security breaches that have been on the front pages of newspapers. They have placed the identities of hundreds of thousands of Americans at risk. The fear among the American public is so widespread that it has become the basis of an entire ad campaign by a credit card company.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But this is about much more than information security. Until California law required a company named ChoicePoint to notify individuals in 2005 that their information was compromised and that they might be vulnerable to identity theft, many Americans had never heard of ChoicePoint. As news stories focused on the data broker business, many Americans were surprised to discover that companies are creating digital dossiers about them that contain massive amounts of information, and that these companies  sell that information to commercial and government entities. The revelations about these security breaches highlighted the fact that Americans need a better understanding of what happens to their information in a digital world--and what kind of consequences they can face as a result.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When I am back home in Wisconsin, I hear from people who do not understand why companies have the right to sell their sensitive personal information. I hear from people who are shocked to discover that personal information about them is available for free on the Internet.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is no question that data aggregators facilitate societal benefits, allowing consumers to obtain instant credit and personalized services, and allowing police officers to locate suspects. But these companies also gather a great deal of potentially sensitive information about individuals, and in many instances they go largely unregulated.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Too many of my constituents feel that they have lost control over their own information. Congress must return some power to individual Americans so that we can all better understand and manage what happens to our own personal data.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Personal Data Privacy and Security Act takes a comprehensive approach to the privacy and security problems we face. It gives consumers back some control over their own information. The bill requires data brokers to allow consumers to access their own information and to investigate when consumers tell them that corrections are necessary. And it requires companies to give notice to affected consumers and to law enforcement if there is a serious security breach, so that individuals know their  identity may be at risk and can take steps to protect themselves.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, the bill extends existing criminal law to ensure that it covers unauthorized access of data broker systems, as well as concealment of security breaches. It requires companies that buy and sell information to have appropriate data security systems in place. These protections will help safeguard against future privacy violations and security breaches in the commercial data industry. But that is not all this bill accomplishes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also contains some critically important privacy and security provisions to govern the government's use of commercial data. This is an aspect of the data broker business that has not yet gotten as much attention in the wake of the security breaches over the past few years. The information gathered by these companies is not just sold to individuals and businesses; government agencies of all stripes also buy or subscribe to information from commercial sources. We all remember the discovery  in 2005 that the Pentagon had a contract with a marketing firm to analyze commercial and other data about high school and college students.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although the government should be able to access commercial databases in appropriate circumstances, there are few existing rules or guidelines to ensure this information is used responsibly. Nor are there restrictions on the use of commercial data for powerful, intrusive data mining programs. The Privacy Act, which governs when government agencies themselves are collecting data, likely does not apply because the information is held outside the government and is not gathered solely at government  direction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a result, there is a great deal we do not know about government use of commercial data, even in clearly appropriate circumstances such as when the agency's goal is simply to locate an individual already suspected of a crime.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We don't know under what circumstances government employees can obtain access to these databases or for what purposes. We don't know how government agencies evaluate the accuracy of the databases to which they subscribe. We don't know how the accuracy level of the data affects government use of the data. We don't know how employees are monitored to ensure they do not abuse their access to these databases. We don't know how those who misuse the information are punished. And we don't know how government  agencies, particularly those engaged in sensitive national security investigations, ensure that the data brokers cannot keep records of who the government is investigating, records which themselves could create a huge security risk in light of the vulnerabilities that have come to the forefront in recent months.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is why I am so pleased that this bill includes provisions to address the government's use of commercial data. A comprehensive approach to data privacy and security would be incomplete without taking on this piece of the puzzle. The bill recognizes there are many legitimate reasons for government agencies to obtain commercially available data, but that they need to be subject to privacy and security protections. It takes a common sense approach, pushing government agencies to take basic steps  to ensure that individuals' personal information is secure and only used for legitimate purposes, and that the commercial information the government is paying for and relying on is accurate and complete.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Specifically, the bill would require that federal agencies that subscribe to commercial data adopt standards governing its use. These standards would reflect long-standing basic privacy principles. The bill would ensure that government agencies consider and determine which personnel will be permitted to access the information and under what circumstances; develop retention policies for this personal data and get rid of data they no longer need, minimizing the opportunity for abuse or theft; rely  only on accurate and complete data, and penalize vendors who knowingly provide inaccurate information to the Federal Government; provide individuals who suffer adverse consequences as a result of the agency's reliance on commercial data with a redress mechanism; and establish enforcement mechanisms for those privacy policies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also directs the General Services Administration to review government contracts for commercial data to make sure that vendors have appropriate security programs in place, and that they do not provide information to the government that they know to be inaccurate. And it requires agencies to audit the information security practices of their vendors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These are basic good government measures. They guarantee that the Federal Government is not wasting money on inaccurate data and that vendors are undertaking the security programs that they have promised and for which the government is paying.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We live in a new digital world. The law may never fully keep up with technology, but we must make every effort we can. I am proud to be involved in this comprehensive, reasoned approach to privacy and security, and I hope it will move forward in this Congress. I congratulate Senators LEAHY and SPECTER for their excellent work on this bill. This bill is important and it deserves serious consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="Introducing S. 497. A bill to repeal a prohibition on the use of certain funds for tunneling in certain areas with respect to the Los Angeles to San Fernando Valley Metro Rail project, California; to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="497">S. 497</bill>] Mr. Pesident, today I rise to introduce a bill for myself and Senator FEINSTEIN to allow for subway tunneling in parts of Los Angeles.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1985, in response to a methane gas explosion that destroyed a Ross Dress for Less Store in Los Angeles, Representative WAXMAN worked to enact a law that prohibits subway tunneling in his district.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 2004, the Los Angeles City Council passed a motion in support of reversing the laws banning tunneling. In February 2005, the Los Angeles Metropolitan Transportation Authority board also voted to begin discussions of subway expansion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a result, a panel of scientific experts was created to conduct an independent safety review that determined that subway tunneling could move forward safely with new technology.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Representative WAXMAN introduced a bill to lift the Federal tunneling prohibition in the last Congress--where it passed the House--and again in this Congress. Senator FEINSTEIN and I are introducing the same bill in the Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation has the support of Los Angeles Mayor Antonio Villaraigosa and the Los Angeles Metropolitan Transportation Authority.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill is necessary to expand the subway, which is extremely important in Los Angeles--a city that ranks time and time again as the most congested region in the country. The Wilshire corridor is densely populated and is a large commercial area. The freeways and streets are filled--we need transit in this area.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300042" topic="Introducing S. 498. A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to improve the Medicare program for beneficiaries residing in rural areas; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="498">S. 498</bill>] Mr. President, today, along with my colleague Senator Collins from Maine, I am introducing legislation to address the needs of the nearly one-quarter of all Medicare beneficiaries who live in rural America. These beneficiaries are systematically disadvantaged in the Medicare program. The beauty of Medicare is its equity, its universality, and its accessibility. But we have compromised these values by stratifying payments, by under-representing rural voices on the Medicare  Payment Advisory Commission, and by continuing to use obsolete payment data that hurts rural America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, we must stop indexing physician payments for work based on geographic differences. Rural areas already have a hard enough time recruiting and retaining the Nation's top talent. Currently, even though 25 percent of Medicare beneficiaries live in rural areas, only 10 percent of the Nation's physicians serve them. Lower payments to doctors in these areas only perpetuate this dangerous shortage of medical expertise. We should not be discouraging medical school graduates from moving to underserved  rural areas by continuing to offer sub-par pay--in fact, we should be providing incentives to encourage them to work in underserved areas. My legislation proposes a project to help rural facilities to host educators and clinical practitioners in clinical rotations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Lack of dollars to rural health facilities has also prevented communities from investing in vital information technology. The Institute of Medicine published a report in 2005 detailing the ways in which health IT could assist isolated communities. For example, since rural physicians tend to be generalists rather than specialists, virtual libraries within physician offices would provide both doctors and patients with a wider and deeper source of information at their fingertips. Rural residents  can also be quite far from health facilities, so technology that allows emergency room physicians to communicate with EMS workers in an ambulance can help patients receive life-saving treatment before they physically reach the hospital. These kinds of technologies will improve</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Lastly, this legislation will end the disproportionately low representation of rural interests on the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission. This lack of representation has resulted in policies that hurt rural communities. Those policies have hurt--and continue to hurt--the people of my State of Wisconsin, and they hurt my colleague Senator Collins' constituents as well. For every dollar that Medicare spends on the average beneficiary in the average State in this country, Medicare spends  only 82 cents on a beneficiary in Wisconsin. In Maine, Medicare spends only 80 cents per dollar it spends on the average beneficiary.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>How is this the case, if beneficiaries in Wisconsin and in Maine pay the same payroll taxes as beneficiaries in other States? Because the distribution of Medicare dollars among the 50 States is grossly unfair to Wisconsin, and to much of the Upper Midwest. Wisconsinites pay payroll taxes just like every American taxpayer, but the Medicare funds we get in return are lower than those received in many other States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With the guidance and support of people across my State who are fighting for Medicare fairness, I am introducing this legislation to address Medicare's discrimination against Wisconsin's seniors and health care providers. My bill will decrease some of the inequitable payments that harm rural areas. It will provide rural areas the help they need to grow crucial health information technology infrastructure. It will offer the necessary incentives to help attract the Nation's top medical talent to  underserved rural areas. And it will mandate rural representation on the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission. Rural seniors are already underserved in their communities; they should not be underrepresented in Washington as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rural Americans have worked hard and paid into the Medicare program all their lives. In return, they deserve full access to the same benefits as seniors throughout the country: their choice of highly skilled physicians, use of the latest technologies, and a strong voice representing their needs in Medicare policy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of my bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400619" topic="Introducing S. 500. A bill to establish the Commission to Study the Potential Creation of the National Museum of the American Latino to develop a plan of action for the establishment and maintenance of a National Museum of the American Latino in Washington, DC, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="500">S. 500</bill>] Mr. President, I rise to speak about bi-partisan legislation I am introducing today. I am proud to be joined by Senator MEL MARTINEZ, Senator BOB MENENDEZ, and 20 additional Senators from both sides of the aisle.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The National Museum of the American Latino Community Commission Act will establish a Commission to study the potential creation of a National Museum of the American Latino Community. The Commission members, selected by the President and Members of Congress, will be tasked with studying the impact of such a Museum and the cost of constructing and maintaining a museum, developing a plan of action and a fundraising plan, and proposing recommendations to make the Museum a reality.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As we begin our efforts to pass this significant legislation, the U.S. House of Representatives is set to complete their consideration of <bill type="h" number="512">H.R. 512</bill>, the House companion bill, and will pass the bill on the House floor today. It has been a pleasure to working with Representative XAVIER BECERRA and Representative ILEANA ROS-LEHTINEN, who have championed this legislation for several years. I hope to work with the Senate Energy and Natural Resource Committee to quickly advance the Senate  bill, so that we can, at last, move forward.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If we are successful in our efforts, I believe we will have done our part to enhance the experience of the millions who visit our Nation's capital every year. By passing this legislation, we will contribute to the ongoing, deeply rewarding, and profoundly important process of national self-discovery.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Washington, DC is the symbolic heart of our country. When Americans travel to their capital, they expect the museums, monuments, and national parks they visit to reflect the complete American experience. I celebrate the opening of the National Museum of the America Indian and efforts underway to establish the National Museum of African American History and Culture because I believe we must celebrate our rich, diverse national heritage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Hispanics have long been a part of our country's history and my own family's story illustrates this truth.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over 400 years ago, in 1598, my family helped found the oldest city in what is now these United States. They named the city Santa Fe--the City of Holy Faith--because they knew the hand of God would guide them through the struggles of survival in the ages ahead. In Hispanic Pioneers in Colorado and New Mexico, a new book by Colorado Society of Hispanic Genealogy, their triumph over extreme adversity is documented. The time has come for the story of these pioneers to be told in our Nation's capital.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a proud American, I want to ensure that every individual who visits Washington has a chance to learn the full history of who we are as Americans. It is my hope that the Senate can work to pass this important bill. In doing so, we will preserve our shared America history.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300090" topic="Introducing S. 504. A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish long-term care trust accounts and allow a refundable tax credit for contributions to such accounts, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="504">S. 504</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to introduce the Long-Term Care Trust Account Act of 2007. I am pleased to be joined by my colleague Senator BLANCHE LINCOLN who has been a tireless leader on issues of importance to the health of our Nation. I look forward to continuing to work with Senator LINCOLN on this legislation as well as other opportunities to improve health care in America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are an aging Nation. With babyboomers rapidly retiring, the need for long-term care planning is becoming even more critical. However, we know all too well that planning for the likelihood of disability in young or old age is not done as actively as we would like it to be. Currently, only about 7 percent of all money spent on long-term care comes from private insurance. Too often, insurance is not being purchased, funds are not being saved and persons with disabilities are forced to rely on  Medicaid for their daily care.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a Nation, we need to do better. Senator LINCOLN and I believe that our bill will encourage Americans to invest in their futures and in their care, which is an important first step.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Specifically, our legislation will create a new type of savings mechanism for the purpose of preparing for the costs associated with long-term care services and purchasing long-term care insurance. An individual who establishes a long-term care trust account can contribute up to $5,000 per year to their account and receive a refundable 10 percent tax credit on that contribution. Interest accrued on these accounts will be tax free, and funds could be withdrawn for the purchase of long-term care  insurance or to pay for long-term care services. Our bill also will allow an individual to make contributions to another person's Long-Term Care Trust Account. This will allow relatives to help their parents or a loved one prepare for their future health care needs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services estimates that national spending for long-term care was more than $190 billion in 2004, representing about 12.5 percent of all personal health care expenditures. While those numbers already are staggering, we also know that the need for long-term care is expected to grow significantly in coming decades. Almost two-thirds of people receiving long-term care are over age 65, with this number expected to double by 2030. We also know that the population  over age 85, those most likely to need long-term services and supports, is expected to increase more than 250 percent by 2040 from 4.3 million to 15.4 million.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, millions of Americans are receiving or are in need of long-term care services and supports. Surprisingly, more than 40 percent of persons receiving long-term care are between the ages of 18 and 64. Some were born with disabilities; others came to be disabled through accident or illness. No one can predict their long-term health care needs. Therefore, everyone needs to be prepared.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Currently, long-term care insurance is the main way to prepare for possible future care and support needs. Long-term care insurance helps protect assets and income from the devastating financial consequences of long-term health care costs. Today's comprehensive long-term care insurance policies allow consumers to choose from a variety of benefits and offer a wide range of coverage choices. They allow individuals to receive care in a variety of settings including nursing homes, home care, assisted  living facilities and adult day care. Some of the most recent policies also provide a cash-benefit that a consumer can spend in the manner he or she chooses. When we buy long-term care insurance, we are also working to ensure that we can make more independent long-term care decisions and reduce the strain on state Medicaid budgets.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, for too many, the struggle to pay the immediate costs of long-term care insurance sometimes outweighs the security these products would provide. As Americans are spending more and saving less, I fear the American middle class is woefully unprepared to meet the coming challenges of their long-term care needs. Moving forward in our effort to help individuals prepare for life in their later years, we must encourage them to purchase long-term care insurance and save for long-term care  services. The Long-Term Care Trust Account Act of 2007 is designed to achieve both goals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is my hope that this legislation will help all Americans save for their future and their independence during times of vulnerability. I urge my colleagues on both sides of the aisle to support this important bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="Introducing S. 504. A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish long-term care trust accounts and allow a refundable tax credit for contributions to such accounts, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, the bill that I am introducing today, along with Senators WARNER, LANDRIEU, VITTER, COLEMAN, SMITH, and NELSON of Nebraska, would increase and expand the Teacher Tax deduction provided in current law. The Teacher Tax deduction is available to school teachers and other educators who incur out-of-pocket expenses in order to purchase classroom supplies for their students. The bill we are offering today would increase this above-the-line tax deduction to</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill builds upon a $250 tax deduction in current law authored by Senator WARNER and myself, which became law as part of the tax relief package in 2001. This tax relief was later extended through the end of this year, but we need to act to extend it further.</paragraph>
    <paragraph> I would suggest that there is no reason why we should not make the deduction permanent. Teachers who buy classroom supplies in order to improve the educational experience of their students deserve more than just our gratitude. They deserve this modest tax relief to thank them for their hard work.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So often teachers in my State, and throughout the country, spend their own money in order to improve the classroom experiences of their students. Many of us are familiar with a survey of the National Education Association that found that teachers spend, on average, $443 a year on classroom supplies. Other surveys show that they are spending even more than that. In fact, the National School Supply and Equipment Association found that educators spend an average of $826 to supplement classroom supplies,  plus $926 for instructional materials on top of that--for a total of over $1,700 out of their own pockets.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In most States, including mine, teachers are very modestly paid for their jobs. I think it is so  impressive that despite challenging jobs and modest salaries, teachers are willing to dig deep into their own pockets to enrich the classroom experience, because they care so deeply for their students.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Indeed, I have spoken to dozens of teachers in Maine who tell me they routinely spend far in excess of the $250 deduction limit that is in current law. I have made a practice of visiting schools all over Maine, and so far, I have had the opportunity to visit more than 160 schools in my State. At virtually every school I visit, I find teachers who are spending their own money to benefit their students. Year after year, these teachers spend hundreds of dollars on books, bulletin boards, computer  software, crayons, construction paper, stamps, inkpads--everything you can think of. Let me just give you a couple of examples. Anita Hopkins and Kathi Toothaker, who are elementary school teachers from Augusta, ME, purchase books for their students to have as a classroom library, as</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill would also expand the Teacher Tax deduction to make it available to teachers who incur expenses for professional development. Whenever the provisions of "No Child Left Behind" are being debated, we hear a lot of discussion about the need for highly-qualified teachers. One of the best ways for teachers to improve their qualifications is through professional development. Yet, in towns in my State, and I suspect throughout the country, school budgets are often very tight, and money for  professional development is either very limited or non-existent. For that reason, I believe we should allow this tax deduction to also apply when a teacher takes a course or attends a workshop and has to pay for it out of his or her own pocket.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In my view, students are the ultimate beneficiaries when teachers receive professional development to sharpen their skills or to learn a new approach to presenting material to their students. Studies have consistently shown that, other than involved parents, the single greatest determinant of classroom success is the presence of a well-qualified teacher. Educators themselves understand just how important professional development is to their ability to make a positive impact in the classroom.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Teacher Tax relief that we have made available since 2001 is certainly a positive step, and I was proud to have authored that law, along with Senator Warner. This bill would increase that deduction from $250 to $400, reflecting more accurately what teachers really spend, and would make the deduction permanent. The National Education Association has endorsed this bill, and I ask unanimous consent that a copy of the NEA's letter be printed in the RECORD at the end of my statement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill is a small but appropriate means of recognizing the many sacrifices that our teachers make every day to benefit the children of America. I urge my colleagues to support it.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the letter was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300099" topic="Introducing S. 504. A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish long-term care trust accounts and allow a refundable tax credit for contributions to such accounts, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today in support, once again, of America's teachers by joining with Senator Collins in introducing legislation regarding the Teacher Tax Relief Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator COLLINS and I have worked closely for some time now in support of legislation to provide our teachers with tax relief in recognition of the many out-of-pocket expenses they incur as part of their profession. In the 107th Congress, we were successful in providing much needed tax relief for our Nation's teachers with passage of <bill type="h" number="3090">H.R. 3090</bill>, the "Job Creation and Worker Assistance Act of 2002."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation, which was signed into law by President Bush, included the Collins/Warner "Teacher Tax Relief Act of 2001" provisions that provided a $250 above the line deduction for educators who incur out-of-pocket expenses for supplies they bring into the classroom to better the education of their students. These important provisions provided almost half a billion dollars worth of tax relief to teachers all across America in 2002 and 2003.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the 108th Congress we were able to successfully extend the provisions of the Teacher Tax Relief Act for 2004 and 2005. In the 109th Congress we were able to successfully extend the provisions for 2006 and 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While these provisions will provide substantial relief to America's teachers, our work is not yet complete.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is now estimated that the average teacher spends $826 out of their own pocket each year on classroom materials--materials such as pens, pencils and books. First year teachers spend even more.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Why do they do this? Simply because school budgets are not adequate to meet the costs of education. Our teachers dip into their own pocket to better the education of America's youth.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Moreover, in addition to spending substantial money on classroom supplies, many teachers spend even more money out of their own pocket on professional development. Such expenses include tuition, fees, books, and supplies associated with courses that help our teachers become even better instructors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The fact is that these out-of-pocket costs place lasting financial burdens on our teachers. This is one reason our teachers are leaving the profession. Little wonder that our country is in the midst of a teacher shortage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Without a doubt the Teacher Tax Relief Act of 2001 took a step forward in helping to alleviate the Nation's teaching shortage by providing a $250 above the line deduction for classroom expenses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, it is clear that our teachers are spending much more than $250 a year out of their own pocket to better the education of our children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Accordingly, Senator COLLINS and I have joined together to take another step forward by introducing this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This proposed legislation will build upon current law in three ways. The legislation will: One, increase the above-the-line deduction, as President Bush has called for, from $250 allowed under current law to $400; two, allow educators to include professional development costs within that $400 deduction. Under current law, up to $250 is deductible but only for classroom expenses; and three, make the Teacher Tax Relief provisions in the law permanent. Current law sunsets the Collins/Warner provisions  after 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our teachers have made a personal commitment to educate the next generation and to strengthen America. And, in my view, the Federal Government should recognize the many sacrifices our teachers make in their career.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This Teacher Tax Relief Act is another step forward in providing our educators with the recognition they deserve.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300064" topic="Introducing S. 506. A bill to improve efficiency in the Federal Government through the use of high-performance green buildings, and for other purposes; to the committee on Environment and Public Works.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="506">S. 506</bill>] Mr. President, I am pleased to be joined by my colleagues, Senators SNOWE and BOXER, to introduce the High Performance Green Buildings Act. This legislation encourages the government to improve the energy efficiency, indoor air quality, and environmental impacts of our Nation's Federal buildings, and will reenergize and focus the Federal Government's leadership and commitment on this issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Buildings in the United States have an enormous impact on the environment and also on our overall energy situation. According to the Department of Energy, buildings in the United States use almost 40 percent of the total energy consumed in this country. That figure is expected to rise to 53 percent by 2030, meaning that over half of the energy consumed in this country will be used by buildings alone. In addition, buildings are the source of 35 percent of national carbon dioxide emissions, 49  percent of sulfur dioxide emissions, and 25 percent of nitrogen oxide emissions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, the impact of buildings is even broader than that. Americans spend approximately 90 percent of their time indoors and the quality of the air they breathe can have an impact on their health, as well as work productivity and absenteeism. The U.S. Green Buildings Council, a national non-profit, indicates that on average, installing high performance lighting enhances worker productivity by 6.7 percent. There are also numerous sources of indoor air pollutants, ranging from mold to radon,  and strong building design that considers ventilation can help to remedy these potential health problems.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is important that we confront these issues, and our legislation does just that. High Performance Green Buildings are designed with the impact on occupants, surroundings and energy consumption in mind. Buildings designed or renovated on these merits save money, have healthier occupants, and have a more positive impact on their communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While the initial investment cost of green buildings may be higher than a traditional building, many of these costs are recouped over time. For instance, the Federal government spends about $170 million per year on the lighting of federal buildings; using new lighting technology can reduce energy use by 50 to 75 percent. Some estimates show that the payback time for energy efficient lighting is as little as four months.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The High Performance Green Buildings Act focuses the Federal Government's efforts on promoting sustainable design in federal buildings, and realizing the economic benefits associated with reduced energy use and increased occupant health. It creates an Office of High Performance Green Buildings within the General Services Administration (GSA), which manages buildings owned or leased by the Federal Government. GSA is the largest "landlord" in the country the government owns or leases nearly 500,000  buildings in the United States, covering 3.1 billion square feet. The new Office will promote public outreach, focus ongoing research and development, and create an Advisory Committee consisting of Agency representatives and experts from various sectors, to improve coordination across Federal Government agencies and bring best practices to the Federal government.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Additionally, the High Performance Green Buildings Act provides grants to schools, in consultation with the Environmental Protection Agency and the Department of Education, to provide technical assistance to address environmental and health concerns. The health of our children is our primary concern and this legislation takes important steps to ensure their well-being.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is clear that having sustainable design in our buildings is smart public policy and a wise financial investment, and this bill will allow the Federal Government to increase its leadership role on the promotion of green buildings. I urge my colleagues to support this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the full text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300026" topic="Introducing S. 507. A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for reimbursement of certified midwife services and to provide for more equitable reimbursement rates for certified nurse-midwife services; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="507">S. 507</bill>] Mr. President, today I am introducing the Midwifery Care Access and Reimbursement Equity (M-CARE) Act of 2007. For too many years, certified nurse midwives (CNMs) have not received adequate reimbursement under the Medicare program. My legislation takes steps to improve reimbursement for these important healthcare providers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since 1988, CNMs have been authorized to provide maternity-related services to Medicare-eligible women of child-bearing age. There are approximately three million disabled women of child-bearing age on Medicare; however, if they choose to utilize a CNM for "well women" services, the CNM is only reimbursed at 65 percent of the physician fee schedule. This is not right and does not come close to offsetting the costs incurred by these professionals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At this incredibly low rate of reimbursement, the Medicare Payment Advisory Committee (MedPAC) agrees that a CNM simply cannot afford to provide services to Medicare patients and has supported increasing reimbursement for CNMs. In fact, the Commission recommended in 2002 that CNMs' reimbursement be increased and acknowledged that the care provided by these individuals is at least comparable to similar providers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My legislation would make several changes to improve the ability of CNMs and certified midwives (CMs) to effectively serve the Medicare-eligible population. First, and most importantly, my bill recognizes the need to increase Medicare reimbursement for CNMs by raising the reimbursement level from 65 percent to 100 percent of the physician fee schedule. CNMs provide the same care as physicians; therefore, it is only fair to reimburse CNMs at the same level. Several states have recognized this  in their Medicaid programs--approximately 29 States reimburse at 100 percent of the physician fee schedule for out-of-hospital services.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, the M-CARE Act would establish recognition for a certified midwife (CM) to provide services under Medicare. Despite the fact that CNMs and CMs provide the same services, Medicare has yet to recognize CMs as eligible providers. My bill would change this.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill will enhance access to "well woman" care for thousands of women in underserved communities and make several needed changes to improve access to midwives. I urge my colleagues to support this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="Introducing S. 508. A bill to amend the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 to apply whistleblower protections available to certain executive branch employees to legislative branch employees, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="508">S. 508</bill>] Mr. President, I rise to reintroduce the Congressional Whistleblower Protection Act of 2007, which will extend whistleblower protections currently available to certain executive branch employees to legislative branch employees.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Presently, executive branch employees are shielded from retaliation for exposing waste, fraud, or abuse by the Whistleblower Protection Act. The bill I'm introducing today simply extends those same protections to legislative branch employees.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A theme that has dominated this new Congress, as well as the elections this past November, is accountability and responsibility in Washington. I have fought hard for whistleblowers over the years because they are key in our efforts to ensure government accountability to the people we are sent here to serve. In most instances, the only reason we discover waste or fraud is because employees are brave enough to stand up to the wrongdoers and expose their offenses. Without these whistleblowers, the  American taxpayer would continue to foot the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Office of Compliance has called for these changes on numerous occasions in recent years, and they are very supportive of this bill. We have already taken the steps to protect whistleblowers in the executive branch. It doesn't make sense not to extend these same protections to whistleblowers in our own backyard. My bill will, very simply, give congressional employees the same protections that workers in the other branches of government already possess.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I hope my colleagues will join me in supporting this bill to ensure that those who help us in the fight to hold government accountable are not punished for their efforts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of this bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300056" topic="Introducing S. 508. A bill to amend the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 to apply whistleblower protections available to certain executive branch employees to legislative branch employees, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today to introduce the Aviation Security Improvement Act with Senators STEVENS, ROCKEFELLER, LOTT, and LAUTENBERG, who are all original cosponsors of this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When the 9/11 Commission released its report in 2004, the Commission expressed continuing concern over the state of air cargo security, the screening of passengers and baggage, access controls at airports, and the security of general aviation. Congress responded then and enacted measures to address inefficiencies highlighted by the Commission. However, implementation through the rulemaking process was slow, and as a result, significant shortfalls in our security regime remain.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In fact, a little more than year ago, the 9/11 Public Discourse project issued a scorecard that gave inadequate grades in those key areas where the Commission had advocated for improvements in aviation security. Checked Baggage and Cargo Screening received a "D," Airline Passenger Explosive Screening received a "C," and Airline Passenger Prescreenig received an "F."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over the past year, the Transportation Security Administration, TSA, has continued working to significantly bolster air cargo security in the United States. While that is a good step in response to the report card, more must be done. The government must remain vigilant in its effort to provide security for our Nation, and the steps proposed in this bill will both improve our existing security system and give TSA the flexibility to combat new and emerging threats.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill we are introducing today would require the screening of all cargo going on passenger aircraft within 3 years. We expect TSA to develop a robust screening program that improves upon current measures and ensures the security of all cargo transported in commercial passenger air carriers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To improve our ability to detect explosives in checked baggage and at passenger screening checkpoints, the bill extends the Aviation Security Capital Fund and promotes the purchase and installation of advanced baggage screening systems that can be integrated into the daily workings of our Nation's air transportation system. This capital investment will improve security screening by permitting TSA employees to better focus on potential threats while reducing the high workplace injury rates.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill addresses airline passenger explosive screening in several ways:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>1. By promoting advanced research and development for checkpoint technology;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>2. By enhancing screener training to more clearly identify and address potential threats; and</paragraph>
    <paragraph>3. By requiring the Administration to complete and implement a plan over the next year that thoroughly addresses the threat of and response to carry-on explosives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Airline passenger prescreening also remains a primary concern of the Congress. Not enough progress has been made by the TSA to develop an advanced passenger prescreening system since it took on this task nearly 4 years ago. Too many passengers are inconvenienced each year by false positives when matched against passenger watchlists.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our bill would ensure a system is in place to coordinate passenger redress matters, and that the TSA moves rapidly to develop a strategic plan to test and implement an advanced passenger prescreening system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our bill also takes steps to improve general aviation security, airport access issues for airline employees, screener staffing issues, and other issues where there have been consistent shortcomings over the past several years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The 9/11 Commission's report and subsequent Public Discourse project helped keep Congress and the Administration focused on the need for aviation security. While they did not have all the answers for quick fixes, they did offer a vital blueprint, particularly in the areas of infrastructure and transportation system security.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My colleagues and I used that guideline in drafting the legislation we are introducing today. We believe that once this bill is enacted, it will significantly improve aviation security in the specific areas I have highlighted, and the aviation system as a whole. I look forward to working with my colleagues to move this bill quickly. We have had 5 years to consider what does and does not work. Now it is time to implement what we have learned.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that this bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
</record>
