<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1197565202" ordinal="22" title="FEDERAL ENERGY REGULATORY COMMISSION">
  <narrative>FEDERAL ENERGY REGULATORY COMMISSION -- (Senate - December 13, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="15456">S15456</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, FERC, is currently considering the renewal of the California Department of Water Resources, DWR, license for the Oroville Facilities hydroelectric project in Butte County, CA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DWR is exempt from paying State, local, or a Federal tax associated with the Oroville Project and has not compensated Butte County for the services it provides for the project and its visitors. Butte County believes the relicensing is an opportunity to mitigate the county's revenue losses, which are estimated at nearly $6.9 million per year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>FERC's Final Environmental Impact Statement also acknowledges that the Oroville Project has a negative fiscal impact on Butte County.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have sent a letter to FERC asking that they consider efforts to mitigate Butte County's revenue loss and treat all parties equitably during the Oroville Project relicensing proceedings, and I ask unanimous consent to have text of this letter printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>U.S. SENATE,</narrative>
  <narrative>Washington, DC, December 13, 2007.</narrative>
  <narrative>Dear Chairman Kelliher and Commissioners: I am writing in regards to the relicensing proceedings for the Oroville Facilities hydroelectric project (Project P-2100) currently before the Commission. As you know, Butte County is required to provide services associated with the Oroville Facilities Project and its visitors, including law enforcement, fire and rescue, and road maintenance services.</narrative>
  <narrative>The Commission's Final Environmental Impact Statement acknowledges the negative net fiscal impact the Oroville Facilities Project may impose on Butte County. As you prepare your final decision regarding the relicensing, I encourage you to consider efforts to mitigate the County's revenue loss. I am hopeful that all parties involved with the relicensing of the Oroville Facilities will be regarded equitably. Thank you for your attention to this matter.</narrative>
  <narrative>Sincerely,</narrative>
  <narrative>Dianne Feinstein,</narrative>
</record>
