<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1197565202" ordinal="59" title="TO MODERNIZE VETERANS AFFAIRS MEDICAL CENTER IN ATLANTA, GEORGIA">
  <narrative>TO MODERNIZE VETERANS AFFAIRS MEDICAL CENTER IN ATLANTA, GEORGIA -- (Senate - December 13, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="15571">S15571</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Veterans' Affairs be discharged from further consideration of <bill type="s" number="1396">S. 1396</bill> and the Senate proceed to its immediate consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered. The clerk will report the bill by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A bill (<bill type="s" number="1396">S. 1396</bill>) to authorize a major medical facility project to modernize inpatient wards at the Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Center in Atlanta, Georgia.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the bill.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the bill be read a third time, passed, and the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table; that any statements be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The bill (<bill type="s" number="1396">S. 1396</bill>) was ordered to be engrossed for a third reading, was read the third time, and passed, as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="s" number="1396">S. 1396</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,</chair>
  <chair>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs may carry out a major medical facility project for modernization of inpatient wards at the Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Center, Atlanta, Georgia, in an amount not to exceed $20,534,000.</chair>
</record>
