<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1197997209" ordinal="18" title="UNANIMOUS-CONSENT REQUEST--H.R. 2771">
  <narrative>UNANIMOUS-CONSENT REQUEST--H.R. 2771 -- (Senate - December 18, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="15827">S15827</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400357" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate now proceed to the immediate consideration of <bill type="h" number="2771">H.R. 2771</bill>, the legislative branch appropriations bill; that the only amendment in order be a substitute amendment at the desk which is cosponsored by Senators LEAHY, COLEMAN, KLOBUCHAR, SNOWE, OBAMA, DOLE, BAUCUS, SUNUNU, CANTWELL, COLLINS, CASEY, LIEBERMAN, LANDRIEU, KERRY, KENNEDY, and CLINTON--this amendment provides for $800 million in additional LIHEAP funding--that  there be a time limitation of 30 minutes for debate equally divided in the usual form on the amendment; that upon the use of that time, the amendment be agreed to, the bill be read a third time, and the Senate, without any intervening action or debate, vote on passage of the bill, as amended.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Reserving the right to object, I say to my friend from Vermont, I support this issue. All you have to do is look in the Washington Post today at their editorial. It says, among other things:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This could be the start of an epic winter. If the past few winters here in the northeast have taught us anything, it is to be prepared to do whatever winter allows at the moment it allows.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have to be prepared for a cold winter. We have some money in this bill that we hope to pass sometime in the next several hours to take care of some of the needs of the problems relating to the issue of LIHEAP; that is, money for people who are desperately poor and need help to keep their homes warm. That is what this is all about. I have told the Senator from Vermont that I am going to do everything within my power to get this issue before the Senate as soon as possible. Winter is not going  to end at Christmastime. Winter is going to be here. We can move to enlarge the funding for this bill. That is a commitment I have. I think with the list of cosponsors he has on this proposed unanimous-consent request, it is something we should be able to get done.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The problem the distinguished Senator finds himself in is, it is late in the year. This is the first year of this session of Congress. There are always a lot of reasons for not doing things this late in the year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have admired this fine Member of Congress for many years, being with the people he best represents, people who don't have any representation. I admire what the Senator has done. I hope we can move forward on this now.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300062" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, on behalf of several Republican Senators, I object.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would also note that I believe there may be one other unanimous-consent request, and I would be happy to suspend while that is made and then conclude my remarks in 3 minutes. I think the Senator from Rhode Island would like to speak, or I can go ahead and conclude, and then the Senator from Ohio could make his request--whatever the pleasure of the leader is.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Has there been objection?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <chair>The legislative clerk proceeded to call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senator from Arizona be recognized for up to 5 minutes to finish his statement, and then I would like to be recognized.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Arizona.</chair>
</record>
