<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1182873603" ordinal="10" title="UNANIMOUS CONSENT REQUEST--S. 4 AND H.R. 1">
  <speaking speaker="300062" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to propound a unanimous consent request, please.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that it not be in order for the Senate to consider any conference report on the 9/11 Commission legislation; that is, <bill type="h" number="1">H.R. 1</bill> and <bill type="s" number="4">S. 4</bill>, that compromises the security of America's transportation system by eliminating the flexibility given to the Transportation Security Administration to manage its employees to most effectively counter terrorist threats against Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Before the Chair responds, if I could just make a very brief statement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The President has clearly said he will veto any measure that makes collective bargaining rights for airport screeners a higher priority than protecting our national security and defeating terrorists. Passing a conference report that includes such a provision would be an exercise in futility and a waste of time, as the legislation would certainly be vetoed. We should be working to write a conference report that we know can be signed into law so we can enhance our national security and better protect  the American people from the terrorists we know are plotting every day to harm us.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I renew my request that it not be in order for the Senate to consider any conference report on the 9/11 Commission legislation that compromises our national security by eliminating the critical personnel management flexibility given to the Transportation Security Administration to enable it to respond to terrorist threats.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection? The majority leader is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I very much appreciate the minority coming forward and outlining their objections to the 9/11 bill. It seems pretty clear that the objection deals with collective bargaining, which is in the Senate-passed version of the bill. I appreciate very much that being on the record.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It seems, that being the case, we at least know what we are dealing with. It appears if that weren't in the bill--but it is in the bill--we could go to conference.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I object.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300062" topic="">
    <paragraph>I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
