<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1194019201" ordinal="15" title="APPROPRIATIONS SUBCOMMITTEE ASSIGNMENTS">
  <narrative>APPROPRIATIONS SUBCOMMITTEE ASSIGNMENTS -- (Senate - November 02, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="13723">S13723</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that the attached list of subcommittee assignments for the Committee on Appropriations be printed in the RECORD, to supplant the list printed in the RECORD on February 27, 2007.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>Senator Byrd, as chairman of the Committee, and Senator Cochran, as ranking minority member of the Committee, are ex officio members of all subcommittees of which they are not regular members.</narrative>
  <narrative>Senators Kohl,\1\ Harkin, Dorgan, Feinstein, Durbin, Johnson, Nelson, Reed, Bennett,\2\ Cochran, Specter, Bond, McConnell, Craig, Brownback. (8-7)</narrative>
  <narrative>Senators Mikulski,\1\ Inouye, Leahy, Kohl, Harkin, Dorgan, Feinstein, Reed, Lautenberg, Shelby,\2\ Gregg, Stevens, Domenici, McConnell, Hutchison, Brownback, Alexander. (9-8)</narrative>
  <narrative>Senators Inouye,\1\ Byrd, Leahy, Harkin, Dorgan, Durbin, Feinstein, Mikulski, Kohl, Murray, Stevens,\2\ Cochran, Specter, Domenici, Bond, McConnell, Shelby, Gregg, Hutchison. (10-9)</narrative>
  <narrative>Senators Dorgan,\1\ Byrd, Murray, Feinstein, Johnson, Landrieu, Inouye, Reed, Lautenberg, Domenici,\2\ Cochran, McConnell, Bennett, Craig, Bond, Hutchison, Allard. (9-8)</narrative>
  <narrative>Senators Durbin,\1\ Murray, Landrieu, Lautenberg, Nelson, Brownback,\2\ Bond, Shelby, Allard. (5-4)</narrative>
  <narrative>Senators Byrd,\1\ Inouye, Leahy, Mikulski, Kohl, Murray, Landrieu, Lautenberg, Nelson, Cochran,\2\ Gregg, Stevens, Specter, Domenici, Shelby, Craig, Alexander. (9-8)</narrative>
  <narrative>Senators Feinstein,\1\ Byrd, Leahy, Dorgan, Mikulski, Kohl, Johnson, Reed, Nelson, Allard,\2\ Craig, Stevens, Cochran, Domenici, Bennett, Gregg, Alexander. (9-8)</narrative>
  <narrative>Senators Harkin,\1\ Inouye, Kohl, Murray, Landrieu, Durbin, Reed, Lautenberg, Specter,\2\ Cochran, Gregg, Craig, Hutchison, Stevens, Shelby. (8-7)</narrative>
  <narrative>Senators Landrieu,\1\ Durbin, Nelson, Alexander,\2\ Allard. (3-2)</narrative>
  <narrative>Senators Johnson,\1\ Inouye, Landrieu, Byrd, Murray, Reed, Nelson, Hutchison,\2\ Craig, Brownback, Allard, McConnell, Bennett. (7-6)</narrative>
  <narrative>Senators Leahy,\1\ Inouye, Harkin, Mikulski, Durbin, Johnson, Landrieu, Reed, Gregg,\2\ McConnell, Specter, Bennett, Bond, Brownback, Alexander. (8-7)</narrative>
  <narrative>Senators Murray,\1\ Byrd, Mikulski, Kohl, Durbin, Dorgan, Leahy, Harkin, Feinstein, Johnson, Lautenberg, Bond,\2\ Shelby, Specter, Bennett, Hutchison, Brownback, Stevens, Domenici, Alexander, Allard. (11-10)</narrative>
</record>
