<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1226941203" ordinal="38" title="CONGRATULATING WILLIAM YUAN">
  <narrative>CONGRATULATING WILLIAM YUAN -- (Senate - November 17, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="10558">S10558</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300090" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I rise today to congratulate a young man who has not only achieved beyond his years but has also advanced the state of the art of solar power technology. William Yuan of Beaverton, OR, is a seventh grader at Meadow Park Middle School whose achievements are both jaw-dropping and important.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Recently, William earned a $25,000 scholarship from the Davidson Institute and became a Davidson Fellow for his work in renewable energy research. William's project, "A Highly-Efficient 3-Dimensional Nanotube Solar Cell for Visible and UV Light," featured a novel solar panel that enables light absorption from visible to ultraviolet light. The carbon nanotubes William designed can overcome the barriers of electron movement, doubling the light-electricity conversion efficiency. His optimized  design provides 500 times more light absorption than commercially available solar cells and nine times more than the cutting-edge, three-dimensional solar cell.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Given the current energy crisis, everyone must pitch in to reduce our dependence on oil consumption. In Congress and in the private sector, we are working to facilitate advancements in renewable energies. However, we cannot be successful without brilliant minds like William's.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Winning the Davidson scholarship is far from William's only achievement. This year alone, William won second place at the Northwest Science Expo, Best Engineering Project at the Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers, and second place at the Oregon Chess for Success State Tournament. The list goes on. Last year, William also received a junior black belt pum certification from the World Taekwondo Headquarters in Seoul, Korea. He has also received a number of awards from various Intel  Oregon competitions and First Place in Oregon in the Johns Hopkins Center for Talented Youth Talent Search in both quantitative and verbal sections.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At 12 years old, William is only just getting started. He intends to continue his research in renewable energy and eventually select a major for his college study toward a Ph.D. degree. John F. Kennedy once said:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our nation's first great leaders were also our first great scholars.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I look forward to watching William progress as a scholar and a leader.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
