<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1178035204" ordinal="16" title="PRESCRIPTION DRUG USER FEE AMENDMENTS OF 2007--Continued">
  <chair> The Senator from Oklahoma is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300055" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, on the bill under consideration at the present time, it is my intention to--and I have already placed at the desk two amendments, 987 and 988.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Briefly, what is the order right now?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator is recognized. The Senator has as much time as he may consume.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300055" topic="">
    <paragraph>Today I have submitted amendments to <bill type="s" number="1082">S. 1082</bill> requiring parental consent for intrusive physical exams administered under the Head Start Program. Young children attending Head Start Programs should not be subjected to these intrusive types of physical exams. We had an incident in my town of Tulsa, OK, where we felt that their rights, children's rights, were violated. They were subjected to different types of intrusive examinations. I will be bringing this up at an appropriate time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Secondly, briefly, as I see the manager of the bill is here, we will be introducing an amendment No. 988, having to do with protecting children from parents being coerced into administering a controlled substance or psychotropic drug in order to attend school.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I yield the floor, and I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300055" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300055" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent to withdraw my amendments, No. 988 and No. 987, with the intention to resubmit them when a substitute is made in a few minutes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300055" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Rhode Island.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300081" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I believe the Food and Drug Administration Revitalization Act before us today raises and addresses issues that are critically important to the public's health and well-being. Congress has a historic opportunity to strengthen and increase knowledge about drug safety and effectiveness, bring more transparency to the process of drug approval and surveillance, as well as reassess the goals of the prescription drug and medical device user fee programs, and fortify and expand  essential safety programs for children. The FDA Revitalization Act strikes a careful balance between these many important priorities and objectives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Recent serious adverse drug events related to several widely used drugs on the market underscore the urgency with which we should address and improve drug safety in this country. Moreover, as the population ages and science inevitably advances, more and more drugs will come to market, presenting potentially groundbreaking health benefits to the public, but simultaneously increasing the need for sophisticated mechanisms for monitoring and assuring drug safety.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The FDA Revitalization Act is an opportunity to improve our current system of drug approval and drug monitoring, but it also adeptly anticipates changes in the future of prescription drugs and consumer safety brought about by advances in science and an ever expanding market for prescription drugs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The primary mechanism this bill uses to strengthen drug safety is to strengthen and rearticulate the FDA's authority. The bill clarifies, and in some cases fortifies, the FDA's authority with regard to drug safety. Currently, if the FDA detects a problem, or a potential problem with a drug post approval, they have few options beyond what is often referred to as the "nuclear option." That is, pulling a drug from the market. While the FDA's authority to pull a drug from the marketplace is a powerful  tool, it is a blunt instrument. In order to prevent problems from spiraling into major public health crises, the FDA needs intermediary authority. The FDA's reluctance to pull a drug, potentially a drug upon which millions of Americans depend to manage an illness, unless it is overwhelmingly certain that the action is necessary, is understandable. However, prescription drug users suffer as a result since the "nuclear option" offers a forceful, but ultimately limited response. Pulling</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The risk evaluation and mitigation, REMS, system, the primary tool in the drug safety title of this bill, bolsters the FDA's intermediary authority to require drug manufacturers to monitor and provide important information regarding their products. By so doing, the FDA can actively require drug companies to provide information about the medications millions of Americans are taking and not just passively request drug companies to comply.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Most importantly, the REMS system focuses the FDA's efforts and resources on postmarket surveillance. Increased drug user fees would be used to review REMS as well as for general drug safety surveillance. User fee revenue will increase by $50 million to fund drug safety  activities, of which $30 million is authorized for the routine drug surveillance once they are marketed. Many of us would like to eliminate the need for industry paid user fees, but this arrangement, agreed on by industry and the FDA, offers the best workable solution in this strained budget environment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Another important objective of the FDA Revitalization Act is to improve the integrity of the agency and to enhance transparency on its actions. I am pleased that this bill improves the public's access to information about clinical trials and, more importantly, the results of those trials. The bill enhances patient enrollment in trials by requiring late phase II, as well as phase III and phase IV clinical trials on drugs are registered in a publicly available database. This will improve the public's  knowledge of important and potentially life saving clinical studies. The bill also creates a publicly available database of the results of those trials. This means, for instance, that a parent who wishes to understand why a much-talked about treatment for juvenile diabetes failed to advance past a clinical trial stage</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am also pleased to see efforts to increase research on pediatric drug safety, pediatric clinical trials, and pediatric medical devices in title IV of the FDA Revitalization Act. The bill includes reauthorizations of the Best Pharmaceuticals for Children Act, BPCA, championed by my colleague, Senator DODD, which I have cosponsored, and the Pediatric Research Improvement Act, PRIA, championed by my colleague, Senator CLINTON, which have been particularly successful at increasing  the availability of pediatric specific data on drug products, as well as greatly expanding the number of treatments that have been tested and labeled for use in pediatric populations. The bill also includes a new proposal to expand the collection and availability of pediatric data on medical devices, an area of the medical device market that remains seriously underdeveloped, and as a result places infants and</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, the FDA is responsible for overseeing the safety of a wide range of products consumed by millions of Americans each and every day. We can and must ensure that this critical agency has the tools and resources it needs to perform the myriad of tasks under its purview. We need to get this right for the millions of Americans who rely on the FDA to approve the drugs that they take to treat serious illnesses. The FDA Revitalization Act creates an opportunity to improve science at the  FDA, strengthen drug safety by devoting resources to postmarket surveillance, and "revitalize" the FDA's authority.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I yield the floor and suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="MODIFICATION TO REPORTED COMMITTEE SUBSTITUTE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, on behalf of the HELP Committee, I send to the desk a modification to the committee substitute.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The committee substitute is so modified.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="MODIFICATION TO REPORTED COMMITTEE SUBSTITUTE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, this basically incorporates a number of the adjustments and changes that we had indicated during the course of our markup. We had a number of amendments that were offered. We indicated to the members we would try to work through some of the points that were raised. I commend our staffs on both sides who have been diligent in doing so.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These are alterations, changes that are known to the majority and the minority and all the staff members. Later on in the discussion and debate we can go into some in greater detail. Most of them are clarifications. Some of them are simplifications. I think all of them are worthy and justified, and I think they help to strengthen the legislation. So we are very grateful to all of our colleagues on our committee who offered the amendments, and, most particularly, we are very grateful for their  willingness to work with us to try to work through these alterations and changes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, this legislation, as was pointed out in the excellent statement made by our friend and colleague from Rhode Island, Mr. Reed, and others, is complex, but it is incredibly important in terms of American families, most precisely with regard to drug safety. We have reviewed those provisions. Senator Enzi made an excellent presentation yesterday. We tried to go through those in some detail yesterday afternoon. I might go through some of those again this afternoon.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But we want our Members to know we are ready to consider amendments. We know there are several that are just about ready to be offered. We urge those who are considering bringing them to the floor, let's begin the debate and discussion. We have one or two that are still being worked on. So even though it does not appear like we are making progress on this legislation at the moment, progress is being made in making sure we are going to have strong FDA reauthorization legislation. But we do hope  we can get to the amendments very soon, and we expect to be able to do so.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Wyoming.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300041" topic="MODIFICATION TO REPORTED COMMITTEE SUBSTITUTE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise at this moment to support the substitute that has been put into <bill type="s" number="1082">S. 1082</bill>, the Food and Drug Administration Revitalization Act. I have said a lot about this important bill, and I do intend to say more. The most important thing I can say right now is this is the product of a lot of bipartisan work by members of the Senate Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. We have a great process that wound up with a work in progress, which wound up with this substitute  bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now we do have one major outstanding issue to figure out; that is, the direct consumer advertising for prescription drugs. I do believe we will work something out, but we are not quite there yet. So I would ask my colleagues' indulgence to work that out, and I hope I have the assurance of the  chairman that we will engage in a serious dialog about the various provisions that are included in that direct consumer issue. That will be a real key to finishing  up.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I congratulate the Senator from Massachusetts, Mr. Kennedy, for the outstanding way he and his staff have worked with all the Members on our side of the aisle to clear up. As he said, in some cases, clarifications were needed, and in some cases it was the expansion of wording; in some cases, a reduction in wording. But, at any rate, we got it to where I think both sides understand and agree on many of the issues that are included. I hope we can have other amendments brought to the floor  so we can debate them and get them worked out.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Of course, it would be nice if any Senator thinking about offering an amendment would share their idea with us prior to filing it. We might be able to save some time that way and make sure debate flows in an orderly process. We are trying to keep the bill to relevant amendments.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Massachusetts.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="MODIFICATION TO REPORTED COMMITTEE SUBSTITUTE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I am pleased to continue working with my colleague from Kansas, Senator Roberts, and my colleague from Iowa, Senator Harkin, on the important issue of direct-to-consumer advertising.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have to strike an important balance between seeing that consumers get accurate information on drug safety and seeing that we do not improperly restrain free speech.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator Harkin has a proposal to add safety information to drug ads. Senator Roberts has an idea to allow FDA to impose fines for inaccurate ads. Our bill includes a moratorium--only to be used in rare cases--on DTC ads. The IOM went further and recommended a moratorium on DTC for all new drugs. We rejected that recommendation due to the first amendment concerns but included more limited authority that we believe meets the constitutional test.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Still, some have raised concerns about our current proposal, and we take those concerns seriously. We will continue to work on this important issue with our colleagues and constitutional experts. I think we are making progress through the afternoon and, hopefully, by tomorrow we will have some recommendation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="MODIFICATION TO REPORTED COMMITTEE SUBSTITUTE">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="MODIFICATION TO REPORTED COMMITTEE SUBSTITUTE">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent to speak as in morning business and that my remarks be printed at the appropriate place in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
