<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1183046405" ordinal="55" title="STATEMENTS ON INTRODUCED BILLS AND JOINT RESOLUTIONS">
  <speaking speaker="412243" topic="Introducing S. 1723. A bill to amend the Inspector General Act of 1978 to enhance the independence of the Inspectors General, to create a Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1723">S. 1723</bill>] Mr. President, I rise to talk about something great Congress did 30 years ago. They passed the Inspector General Act. That act has provided a layer of accountability in our Government that is very important. Unfortunately, there are still times that the inspector generals in our Government are not given the respect and deference they deserve. That is why today I am introducing the Improving Government Accountability Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If one thinks about the inspector generals, what they are is a first line of defense on behalf of taxpayers and against Government waste and inefficiency. They are the first line of defense because they are inside Federal agencies. Let's be honest, inspector generals inside Federal agencies are facing mountains of waste and inefficiency. If they are to do their jobs the way Congress intended, they must be independent, and their work must be immediately accessible to the public.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have had some troubling incidents over the last several years as it relates to the independence, the qualifications and, frankly, the integrity of our inspector generals. That is why this legislation is necessary. That is why this legislation is so important.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation will do several things. First, all inspector generals will be appointed for terms of 7 years. That will make sure they cannot arbitrarily be removed from their position by a department head who is getting nervous about information they are providing to the public in terms of accountability.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second, Congress must be notified of the removal of any inspector general and, very importantly, the reasons for the removal before they can be removed from office.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Third, all inspector generals will have their own legal counsel to avoid using the agency counsel. This is important because if they are going to have independence, they must have independent legal advice about their ability to do their job.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Fourth, no inspector general can accept a bonus. The bonuses are given by the heads of the agencies. That is an inherent conflict. If you know that you please the head of your agency and you get more money, what kind of shortcuts are you going to take? What are you going to be willing to gloss over in order not to embarrass the head of that agency with information you have discovered about waste and inefficiency?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Fifth, in the event of a vacancy, the Council on Integrity and Efficiency will recommend to the appointing authority three possible replacements. They will not have the ability to dictate the replacement for the IG, but it will provide the appointing authority with three qualified people to take  over the important function of inspector general.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Also key in this legislation is that instead of making their annual budget requests to the agencies they oversee, the IG budget requests will go straight to the Office of Management and Budget, or OMB, that sends the President's budget request to Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Next, all inspector general Web sites must be directly accessible from the home page of the agency. I asked my staff to take a tour through Government agency Web sites to see how easy it was to find out what the IGs had been up to in those agencies. It was remarkably difficult. In many instances we couldn't even find the inspector general's information on the home page of that agency. The public ought to be able to go on the page of any Federal agency and immediately click on the last inspector  general report, find out what that inspector general found and, frankly, ought to be able to ask the question, what has been done about it. There will be a way for the public to anonymously send allegations of waste, fraud, and abuse directly to the IG offices.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our office found that only three of 27 sampled Federal agencies have an obvious direct link from their home page to the IG's Web site. Clearly, we are not focused on making this information available to the public. Frankly, all the auditors in the world, all the inspector generals in the world do no good if the public can't learn the information. Because if the public doesn't know about it, it isn't going to have the cleansing effect it should. Only six of the 27 sampled IGs have an obvious direct  link on their home page to report waste, fraud, and abuse. That is very important.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I give credit to Representative Jim Cooper of Tennessee who has been working on this legislation in the House. I am excited to join him in this effort. Senator Collins and Senator Lieberman have some of these provisions in their Accountability in Government Contracting Act, of which I am also proud to be a cosponsor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There have been specific examples that have occurred recently. I won't go into them other than to say, we had one Commerce IG who refused to resign after an investigation showed that he had committed malfeasance in office. However, after much pressure from Congress, he finally did step down. We have another inspector general who has been accused of trying to block the serving of a search warrant at NASA. Think about that, trying to block the serving of a search warrant that had been issued by  a court of law. We have another IG who was not reappointed by President Bush and said publicly it was because at the Department of Homeland Security, he was seen as a traitor, and he was intimidated about not issuing reports that might reflect badly on the agency.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Bottom line, we should protect inspector generals. They are precious. They are important to what we do. We can talk all we want about oversight, but if we can't get the information from inside these agencies, frankly, we are not going to be effective in Congress with any kind of oversight. The information the inspector generals provide is crucial to Congress and crucial to the public. This legislation would make sure that they are qualified, protected, independent, and the public knows what they  are up to.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to get excited about this legislation and maybe, uncharacteristically, move it quickly through the Senate.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300087" topic="Introducing S. 1726. A bill to regulate certain State taxation of interstate commerce, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1726">S. 1726</bill>] Mr. President, I want to speak about the bill I am introducing today with Senator Crapo, the Business Activity Tax Simplification Act of 2007. Our bill tries to address a very important question: How should States tax businesses that locate their operations in a few States, but have customers and earn income in many States? This issue has grown in importance in recent years, and the Supreme Court's decision last week not to get involved in the issue raises the stakes even  further.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The crux of the issue is this: A majority of States impose corporate income and other so-called "business activity taxes" only when companies have "physical presence," such as employees or property, in their States. However, some States contend that the mere presence of a business's customers, or an "economic presence," is all that is necessary to impose a business activity tax. These companies are facing a confusing and costly assortment of State and local tax rules, some enacted by legislatures  and others imposed upon them by State revenue authorities and upheld by State courts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator Crapo and I introduced similar legislation in the 109th Congress to try to address this problem of double taxation and tax practices that vary from State to State. That bill came close to passing the House, but some last-minute objections were raised. Now, the need for legislation and congressional action has taken on new urgency, and we have revised the bill to address many of the concerns expressed last year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Just last week, the U.S. Supreme Court denied certiorari in two cases that challenged the constitutionality of State taxation of out-of-State companies with no physical presence in a State. The States involved in these cases, West Virginia and New Jersey, asserted theories of economic nexus to tax out-of-State corporations. They claimed that because some customers of such corporations reside in the State, even though the corporation is not physically present, they are subject to business activity  taxes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The first case involves a credit card company headquartered in Delaware. The bank issued credit cards nationwide, including credit cards issued to West Virginia customers. The bank had no property or employees, no office or any other physical presence, in the State. The second case involves a Delaware holding company that licensed intellectual property trademarks and trade names to a customer that does business in New Jersey. The holding company itself had no offices, employees, or property in  New Jersey, and did not otherwise have a physical presence in the State. In both cases, the State courts ruled that the out-of-State corporation was taxable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What is so disappointing about the Supreme Court's silence on this issue is the fact that these State court decisions conflict with an earlier Supreme Court ruling. In 1992, in Quill Corp. v. North Dakota, the Supreme Court prohibited States from forcing out-of-State corporations from collecting sales and use tax, unless the corporation has a physical presence in the taxing State.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, some State courts have held that the physical presence test established by Quill creates no such limitations on the imposition of business activity taxes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Currently, 19 States take the position that a State has the right to tax a business merely because it has a customer within the State, even if the business has no physical presence in the State whatsoever.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These States' actions in pursuing these taxes have caused uncertainty and widespread litigation, so much so that it has created a chilling effect on foreign and interstate commerce. I have spoken out against double taxation on many issues in the past, and the double tax in these cases, while not as large, is just as wrong.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me be clear about this: I know that several Governors and State revenue commissioners have spoken out against the legislation because they don't like the Federal Government telling them what they can and cannot tax. They are also concerned about any revenue they might lose as a result. But if the States are collecting a tax they shouldn't be collecting in the first place, the fact that they might lose a small amount of revenue is not the most persuasive argument, in my view.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe Congress has a responsibility to create a uniform nexus standard for tax purposes so that goods and services can flow freely between the States. Firm guidance on what activities can be conducted within a State will provide certainty to tax administrators and businesses, reduce multiple taxation or the same income, and will reduce compliance and enforcement costs for States and businesses alike.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The last time Congress acted on this issue was in 1959, when Public Law 86-272 was enacted to prohibit States from imposing "income taxes" on sales of "tangible personal property" by a business whose sole activity within a State  was soliciting sales. No one can deny that in the almost 50 years since, interstate commerce has taken on a whole new character. New technologies allow companies headquartered in one State to provide services to consumers  across the country. The Internet is replacing bricks-and-mortar stores. Companies and consumers are increasingly linked across State lines.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Business Activity Tax Simplification Act of 2007 addresses these changes over the last 48 years both modernizing Public Law 86-272 and codifying the physical presence standard. Our bill extends the protections of the 1959 law to include solicitation activities performed in connection with all sales and transactions, not just sales of tangible personal property. The bill protects the free flow of information, including broadcast signals from outside the State, from becoming the basis for taxation  of out-of-State businesses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>BATSA also protects activities where the business is a consumer in the State. It makes little sense to impose tax on out-of-State businesses that purchases goods or services from an in-State company. Obviously, in this very common scenario, the out-of-State business is not using these goods or services to generate any revenue in the State. Why should they be subject to tax?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Most importantly, BATSA codifies the physical presence standard. States and localities can only impose business activity taxes on businesses within their jurisdiction that have employees in the State, or real or tangible personal property that is either leased or owned. It is consistent with current law and sound tax policy, which holds that a tax should not be imposed by a State unless that State provides benefits or protections to the taxpayer. Further, the physical presence standard is the  basis for each and every one of our treaties with foreign nations--adoption of a more nebulous standard by the States undermines these international treaties.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We need to act now. Already, State legislatures are interpreting the court's denial of cert as an affirmation of their position that they are free to enact whatever policies affecting interstate commerce that are beneficial to their particular State revenue needs, regardless of the national impact. Because the court will not review their nexus standard and Congress has not acted, States now have an ideal opportunity to raise revenues from out-of-State corporations regardless of the national impact.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Only 3 days after the Supreme Court denied cert, the New Hampshire Assembly added an amendment to the State budget at 3:40 a.m. to allow the State to collect revenue from out-of-State businesses. The denial of cert thereby resulted almost immediately in a $10 million to $100 million windfall for New Hampshire. No one can deny that this was an extremely aggressive action; why else would the legislature have taken such drastic measures to tack on this amendment it? the wee hours of the morning?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>States are clearly overreaching in their efforts to collect these taxes, and it creates a difficult situation for businesses. It is laughable to think that a company would decide to cut off all transactions with individuals within a certain State to avoid similar laws. And so they will have to start paying taxes to States where they start generating no revenue, hiring no employees, and contributing nothing to the State's economy from their phantom presence aside from these taxes. But these companies  are not going to stand idly by and be double-taxed; they will simply declare less income in their home States as a result.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I know that my legislation with Senator Crapo has raised concerns in the past. The States have argued that BAT legislation represents an intrusion into their authority to govern. But I believe the contrary: A fundamental aspect of American federalism is that Congress has the authority and responsibility under the commerce clause to ensure that interstate commerce is not burdened by State actions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In fact, the exercise of such congressional power is necessary in order to prevent excessive burdens from being placed on businesses engaged on interstate activity by virtue of their customer's residing in a particular State. Congress must act to ensure certainty, predictability, and fairness of taxation of multistate corporations. The lack of a bright-line physical presence standard encourages each State to act in its own self interest by taking action to maximize its revenues, regardless of  the potential double taxation that results.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me address a few concerns that have been raised about the bill. Opponents claim that BATSA includes so many exceptions to the physical presence standard that large, multistate companies will utilize the legislation to ensure they pay minimum State tax nationwide. But our bill explicitly States that it preserves States' authority to adopt or continue to use their own tax compliance tools.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In response to those who say that this legislation will be a huge hit to State budgets, the figures just don't add up. There have been a number of studies done, but even the highest revenue estimate represents only a very small percentage of the total amount of business activity taxes collected by the States. The studies leave out one important fact, however: Companies affected by double-taxation are going to declare less income in their home States, if they have to pay taxes on that same income  to another State.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me cite just one example from a company in my State. In 2005, Citigroup paid 63 percent of all it State and local taxes to New York State and New York City, all based on physical presence in the State and the city. As more States follow the lead of New Hampshire, the city and State of New York will be getting less from Citibank, one way or another, as they won't want to be double taxed, once by New York because of our physical presence and again in New Hampshire and other States because they  have customers in those States. This is why any revenue loss estimates from any city or State are overblown.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In short, this is no longer a theoretical discussion. Federal legislation is required to stop this food fight.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe that Congress has a duty to prevent some States from impeding the free flow and development of interstate commerce and to prevent double taxation. That is why I am asking my colleagues on both sides of the aisle, including the chairman and ranking member of the Finance Committee, to carefully consider this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300030" topic="Introducing S. 1726. A bill to regulate certain State taxation of interstate commerce, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to thank my colleague from New York, Senator Schumer, for the work he has done on this bill. He shares my grave concerns about the devastating impact that legal interpretations of Public Law 86-272 are having on foreign and interstate commerce. I'm pleased that we can work together in a bipartisan effort to make changes to a law that is in serious need of updating and clarification in view of the more service-oriented economy we have today driven  in large part by modern technology's profound transformation of business transactions. This is why we are introducing the Business Activity Tax Simplification Act of 2007, or BATSA, today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress has a Constitutional responsibility to ensure that interstate commerce is not unduly burdened by State actions, including unfair and burdensome taxation of such commerce. Public Law 86-272 was enacted almost 50 years ago, for just these purposes. Ways of conducting multi-state business have changed, and, in the absence of any clarifying legislation, some state courts have interpreted taxation activity under an "economic presence" approach. This approach does not reflect the intent  or spirit of the Commerce Clause of the Constitution; furthermore, it creates a climate of uncertainty that inhibits business expansion and innovation. Businesses have to take into account the very real possibility that they will be taxed multiple times for the same business</paragraph>
    <paragraph>States' efforts to impose improper business activity taxes have been furthered by the Supreme Court's recent silence on this issue. Recent State court rulings are in conflict with the high Court's ruling in Quill Corp. v. North Dakota in 1992. In that ruling,  the Supreme Court prohibited States from forcing out-of-state corporations to collect sales and use taxes unless such corporation had a physical presence in the taxing State. As my colleague from  New York pointed out a few minutes ago, State courts in both New Jersey and West Virginia have held that the physical presence test in Quill only applies to sales and use taxes, not business activity taxes. I share my colleague's deep concern with the fact that the appeals of these two cases to the Supreme Court were denied certiorari just last week. This denial underscores the urgency of BATSA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This effort by a large number of States to impose business activity taxes based on economic presence has the potential to open a Pandora's Box of negative implications for businesses. Without clarification by Congress, States will be free to enact revenue-raising nexus legislation and policies that, by definition, will not and cannot take into account the national impact of such activities. The eleventh-hour enactment of economic nexus legislation by the New Hampshire State Legislature just days  after the Supreme Court denial of certiorari in the New Jersey and West Virginia cases is a sign of things to come. For many businesses, this will serve as a death knell for growth and expansion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>BATSA will help clarify the intent of Public Law 86-272. BATSA codifies the "physical presence" standard and will eliminate confusion for State tax administrators and businesses alike. It's consistent with current law and the notion that a tax should not be imposed by a State unless that State provides benefits or protections to the taxpayer. BATSA clarifies that an out-of-state business must have nexus under both the Due Process Clause and the Commerce Clause. This standard is also consistent  with the standards we have in place with regard to our trading partners abroad.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>BATSA modernizes Public Law 86-272 by extending the protections under that law to include solicitation activities performed in connection with all sales and transactions, not just tangible personal property. BATSA applies to all business activity taxes, not just net income taxes. This includes gross receipts taxes, gross profits taxes, single business taxes, franchise taxes, capital stock taxes and business and occupation taxes. It does not apply to transaction taxes such as sales and use taxes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>BATSA protects the free flow of information, critical in our modern era of Internet business and protects the activities where the business is a consumer in that State. And, as my colleague, Senator Schumer, rightly pointed out, it is counterintuitive to impose taxes on an out-of-state company purchasing goods or services from an in-State company, since the out-of-state company isn't generating any revenue for the State.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>BATSA upholds the approach of disregarding certain de minimus activities codified in Public Law 86-272.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>States have argued that BATSA will result in substantial lost State tax revenue. In fact, according to the Congressional Budget Office, the projected total loss of revenue to states from BATSA in year one of enactment represents just 0.2 percent of all State and local taxes paid by businesses in 2005. And the CBO cost estimate is actually less than the cost claimed by the National Governor's Association in its own revenue estimates.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I will tell you what BATSA does not do. BATSA does not help large companies avoid paying their fair share of State taxes, stating explicitly that States retain the authority to adopt or continue to use anti-tax avoidance compliance tools. It expressly endorses statutory and regulatory tools at States' disposal to combat tax abuse. Industry and activity-specific safe harbors included in prior bills do not exist in this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the glaring absence of Supreme Court clarification on Quill Corp. v. North Dakota, and in the presence of confusing state court interpretations of that decision and ongoing, and legally-creative revenue-raising schemes by States, it's imperative that Congress act now to preserve the free flow of commerce between States. The Business Activity Tax Simplification Act of 2007 provides that clarification. BATSA ensures that one standard of taxation applies for taxing multi-state companies, so that  companies are not unjustly taxed multiple times by different States on the same income. I hope that our colleagues here in the Senate will support this important legislation that will protect the business expansion in our country that keeps our economy competitive and thriving.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="Introducing S. 1727. A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for a credit against income tax for certain educator expenses, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1727">S. 1727</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today, along with my good friends, Senators Warner, Chambliss, Snowe, Isakson, Lugar, Cornyn, Coleman, and Voinovich, to introduce the Teacher Tax Credit Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As we approach the end of the school year, it is appropriate once again to consider tax relief to help cover the out-of-pocket expenses our Nation's teachers incur to improve the education of our children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many times in the past, we have come to the floor to offer legislation on this subject. In 2001, Senator Warner and I offered legislation which resulted in the enactment of the existing $250 teacher tax deduction. That deduction expires at the end of this year. Earlier this session, Senator Warner and I offered legislation to make that deduction permanent, raise it to $400, and expand it to cover professional development expenses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, we introduce legislation that would provide teachers with an alternative tax credit for books, supplies, and equipment they purchase for their students, as well as for professional development expenses. The tax credit would be set at 50 percent of such expenditures so that teachers would receive 50 cents of tax relief for every dollar of their own money they spend, up to $300.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our rationale in proposing a tax credit as an alternative to the existing deduction is simple, deductions only reduce tax liability indirectly, by reducing taxable income. The value of the deduction is equal to the taxpayer's marginal tax rate, or what we call their tax "bracket." For example, for teachers in the 25 percent tax bracket, a $100 deduction would reduce their tax liability by 25 percent, or $25.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By contrast, the tax credit we are proposing would reduce the amount of taxes paid by a teacher by 50 percent for each dollar that a teacher spends on school supplies or professional development expenses, regardless of the tax bracket the teacher is in. A teacher who took the maximum credit amount of $300 would save 50 percent of that amount--$150--in taxes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have made an effort to ensure that the tax benefit we are proposing will make all teachers who use it better off, relative to the current deduction. Let me take a moment to explain how we have done this: first, the tax credit is structured as an alternative teachers can choose either the deduction or the credit, whichever works best for their tax situation. Second, the level of the credit, if adopted in its present form, would provide a net after-tax benefit of $150. This is significantly  higher than the net after-tax benefit that most teachers can receive using the current $250 deduction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is even higher than the net after-tax benefit that would result from the $400 deduction Senator Warner and I proposed earlier this year. Teachers in the 25 percent tax bracket would get a net after-tax benefit of $100 from a $400 deduction, so they will see an increase of $50 under the credit system that we are proposing today. Even teachers in the highest tax bracket, which is currently set at 35 percent, would see a small increase in the net benefit they would receive under this  credit, compared to a $400 deduction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I should also note that some teachers make so little they do not even have the tax liability to offset this credit. To make sure these teachers are also compensated for the money they spend on classroom supplies and professional development, the credit Senator Warner and I are proposing is fully refundable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is remarkable how much the average teacher spends every year out of  his or her own pocket to buy supplies and other materials for their students. Many of us are familiar with a survey of the National Education Association that found that teachers spend, on average, $443 a year on classroom supplies. Other surveys show that they are spending even more than that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The NEA's data also shows that the average teacher in the U.S. still does not make $50,000, and in many States, including Maine, they average less than $40,000. When you realize that the average teacher is not particularly well paid, it speaks volumes about their dedication that they are willing to make that kind of investment to support the teaching they provide to their students.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Indeed, I have spoken to dozens of teachers in my home State who tell me they routinely spend far in excess of the $300 credit limit on materials they use in their classrooms. At every school I visit, I find teachers who are spending their own money to improve the educational experiences of their students by supplementing classroom supplies. Year after year, these teachers spend hundreds of dollars on books, bulletin boards, computer software, crayons, construction paper, tissue paper, stamps  and inkpads. For example, Anita Hopkins and Kathi Toothaker, elementary school teachers from Augusta, Maine, purchase books for their students to have as a classroom library as well as workbooks and sight cards. They also purchase special prizes for positive reinforcement for students. Mrs. Hopkins estimates that she spends $800 to $1,000 of her own money on extra materials to make learning fun and to create a stimulating learning experience.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is important that this credit also be available to teachers who incur expenses for professional development. While this tax relief provides modest assistance to educators, it is my view that students are its ultimate beneficiaries. Studies consistently show that well-qualified teachers, and involved parents, are the most important contributors to student success. Educators themselves understand just how important professional development is to their ability to make a positive impact in the  classroom. Teachers in Maine repeatedly tell me that they need, and want, more professional development. But tight school budgets often make funds to support this development impossible to get. By providing a credit for professional development expenses, this amendment will help teachers take that additional course or pursue that advanced degree that will make them even better at what they love to do.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our bill makes it a priority to reimburse educators for just a small part of what they invest in our children's future. It is both sound education policy and sensible tax policy. I hope our colleagues will join us in support of this important initiative.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that a letter of support be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300099" topic="Introducing S. 1727. A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for a credit against income tax for certain educator expenses, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today in support, once again, of America's teachers by joining with Senator Collins in introducing the Teacher Tax Credit Act of 2007. Other original cosponsors of this bill include Senators Chambliss, Coleman, Cornyn, Isakson, Lugar, Snowe, and Voinovich.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator Collins and I have worked closely for some time now in support of legislation to provide our teachers with tax relief in recognition of the many out-of-pocket expenses they incur as part of their profession. In the 107th Congress, we were successful in providing much needed tax relief for our Nations' teachers with passage of <bill type="h" number="3090">H.R. 3090</bill>, the Job Creation and Worker Assistance Act of 2002.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation, which was signed into law by President Bush, included the Collins/Warner Teacher Tax Relief Act of 2001 provisions that provided a $250 above-the-line deduction for educators who incur out-of-pocket expenses for supplies they bring into the classroom to better the education of their students. These important provisions provided almost half a billion dollars worth of tax relief to teachers all across America in 2002 and 2003.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the 108th Congress we were able to successfully extend the provisions of the Teacher Tax Relief Act for 2004 and 2005. In the 109th Congress we were able to successfully extend the provisions for 2006 and 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While these provisions will provide substantial relief to America's teachers, our work is not yet complete.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is now estimated that the average teacher spends $826 out of their own pocket each year on classroom materials--materials such as pens, pencils, and books. First-year teachers spend even more. Why do they do this? Simply because school budgets are not adequate to meet the costs of education. Our teachers dip into their own pocket to better the education of America's youth.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Moreover, in addition to spending substantial money on classroom supplies, many teachers spend even more money out of their own pocket on professional development. Such expenses include tuition, fees, books, and supplies associated with courses that help our teachers become even better instructors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The fact is that these out-of-pocket costs place lasting financial burdens on our teachers. This is one reason our teachers are leaving the profession. Little wonder that our country is in the midst of a teacher shortage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Accordingly, Senator Collins and I have joined together to take another step forward by introducing legislation today that creates a refundable tax credit for teachers. The Teacher Tax Credit Act of 2007 will simply provide a refundable tax credit up to $150 for classroom expenses and professional development expenses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent to have printed in the Record at the end of my statement the attached letter from the National Education Association endorsing the Collins-Warner Teacher Tax Credit Act of 2007. I will also ask unanimous consent to have printed in the Record at the end of my statement the attached letter from the Virginia Education Association endorsing the Collins-Warner Teacher Tax Credit Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, our teachers have made a personal commitment to educate the next generation and to strengthen America. In my view, the Federal Government should recognize  the many sacrifices our teachers make in their career.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to the refundable tax credit legislation that we are introducing today, earlier this year Senator Collins and I introduced <bill type="s" number="505">S. 505</bill>, The Teacher Tax Relief Act of 2007. <bill type="s" number="505">S. 505</bill> will build upon current law by increasing the above-the-line deduction, as President Bush has called for, from $250 allowed under current law to $400; allowing educators to include professional development costs within that $400 deduction; and making the teacher tax relief provisions in the law permanent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Teacher Tax Credit Act of 2007 is another step forward in providing our educators with the recognition they deserve.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the letters to which I referred be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="Introducing S. 1729. A bill to amend titles 18 and 28 of the United States Code to provide incentives for the prompt payments of debts owed to the United States and the victims of crime by imposing surcharges on unpaid judgments owed to the United States and to the victims of crime, to provide for offsets on amounts collected by the Department of Justice for Federal agencies, to increase the amount of special assessments imposed upon convicted persons, to establish an Enhanced Financial Recovery Fund to  enhance, supplement, and improve the debt collection activities of the Department of Justice, to amend title 5, United States Code, to provide to assistant United States attorneys the same retirement benefits as are afforded to Federal law enforcement officers, and for authorized purposes; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1729">S. 1729</bill>] Mr. President, today I join with Senator Cochran to introduce a bill that will provide parity between the retirement benefits granted to assistant U.S. attorneys and those granted to other Federal law enforcement officers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are 5,500 assistant U.S. attorneys in 93 offices throughout the United States, all of whom are serving on the front lines to uphold the rule of law. Having served as a prosecutor for many years in Vermont, I know well the integral role prosecutors play in the administration of justice. Prosecutors are a crucial component of our justice system, and should be recognized as such when they reach the end of their careers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Probation officers, deputy marshals, corrections officers, and even corrections employees not serving in a law enforcement role receive enhanced benefits greater than those received by assistant U.S. attorneys. This is an inequity that should be remedied. By correcting this disparity, Congress would also help the Federal justice system retain experienced prosecutors. Of all the prosecutors who leave the government for the private sector, 60 to 70 percent do so with experience of between 6 and  15 years. With the Department of Justice's rapidly expanding role in combating terrorism, we cannot afford to lose the experienced men and women who serve in this vital role.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation also addresses concerns about the cost to the Federal Government of providing enhanced retirement benefits to assistant U.S. attorneys. Proponents of the bill have helped craft provisions that would assist the Department of Justice in recovering money owed to the Federal Government as a result of judgments and other fines. By bolstering the Department's ability to collect the funds it is owed, resources would be freed up to provide the parity in retirement benefits sought by  assistant U.S. attorneys. The result of the creative efforts to fund these benefits in an alternative manner is that the Department of Justice will, through its duties as the Nation's law enforcement agency, be able to provide the benefits its employees deserve at little or no cost to the taxpayer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By passing this legislation, we will signal the Federal Government's recognition that prosecutors in our society fulfill a critical role. Congress can send the message that the service of these prosecutors is a valued and indispensable component of our Federal justice system. I hope all Senators will join us in supporting this legislation to ensure that Federal policy equally respects the contributions of all members of the law enforcement community in keeping our society safe and secure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300090" topic="Introducing S. 1730. A bill to amend part A of title IV of the Social Security Act, to reward States for engaging individuals with disabilities in work activities, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1730">S. 1730</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to introduce Pathways to Independence Act of 2007, along with Senators Conrad, Stabenow, Snowe, and Collins. This legislation includes two important provisions that will help States transition Temporary Assistance for Needy Fami1ies, TANF, recipients who have disabilities into work.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>States currently face a conflict between the new Federal TANF requirements, as reauthorized by the Deficit Reduction Act of 2006, DRA, and the nondiscrimination requirements of the Americans with Disabilities Act. In order to comply with the ADA, States must make modifications to the work requirements they impose on TANF recipients with disabilities to ensure that they can participate in the program and move toward gainful employment. However, under new Federal TANF rules, States only get credit  when recipients participate in a narrow set of activities for a specific number of hours each week, with limited flexibility for people with disabilities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our legislation would allow States to create modified employability plans for people with disabilities and get credit toward the TANF participation rate if  recipients comply with the requirements in those plans. This would encourage States to engage people with disabilities in appropriate employment-focused activities without fear of facing Federal penalties for not meeting their TANF work rates. The bill also would allow states To exclude people with  pending SSI applications and severe temporary disabilities from the work rates.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation allows states to receive full credit when a modified employability plan is developed for a family that includes a person with a disability. The bill requires States that receive credit for families on their caseload with modified employability plans to submit annual reports to the Department of Health and Human Services, HHS, on the types of modifications made and disabled populations served. It also requires HHS to compile this information and send an annual report to Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This approach is appealing to States for many reasons. It allows States to design a system and receive credit for moving a person progressively over time from rehabilitation toward work. It also creates a more realistic work structure for individuals with disabilities and/or addictions who otherwise may fall out of the system either through sanction or discouragement, despite their need for financial assistance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In July 2002, the General Accounting Office reported that as many as 44 percent of TANF families have a parent or child with a physical or mental impairment. This is almost three times higher than the rate among the non-TANF population in the United States. In 8 percent of TANF families, there is both a parent and a child with a disability; among non-TANF families, this figure is 1 percent. The GAO's work confirmed the findings of earlier studies, including work by the Urban Institute and the  HHS Inspector General.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These figures mean that we need to make sure that the TANF program gives States the ability and incentives to serve families in their TANF programs and help them to move from welfare to work. This is the lesson that Oregon and many other States already have learned when they developed and refined their TANF programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Most individuals with disabilities who receive TANF are able to engage in work activities and move toward employment, and many will either need no modifications to standard work activities or only minor modifications. Those with more serious conditions may need more intensive services and more significant adjustment to the basic work requirements. Under the bill, a qualified professional must make a determination that an individual has a disability and the state must document the types of modifications,  if any, that the individual needs to succeed in moving toward employment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our bill proposes the creation of a more appropriate path for those who have disabling conditions, both short- and long-term, recognizing the barriers many of these families face both financially and emotionally. The current strategy of rapid employment for all TANF recipients is not always feasible. This bill will help families with disabilities achieve and maintain stability during the transition from welfare to becoming more financially secure and independent of Government assistance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over 20 individual States, including Oregon, and the National Governors Association, representing all 50 States and five territories have identified problems with how the current rules affect their ability to serve individuals with disabilities appropriately and meet the TANF work requirements. They have asked for modifications to the new TANF requirements like the ones proposed in our bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I look forward to working with my cosponsors, Senators Conrad, Stabenow, Snowe, and Collins on these important provisions, and I urge my colleagues to join us in support of this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill and letters of support be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300027" topic="Introducing S. 1731. A bill to provide for the continuing review of unauthorized Federal programs and agencies and to establish a bipartisan commission for the purposes of improving oversight and eliminating wasteful Government spending; to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1731">S. 1731</bill>] Mr. President, I rise to introduce the United States Authorization and Sunset Commission Act of 2007. I am very pleased to be joined by my colleagues and good friends, Senator George Voinovich and Senator Saxby Chambliss, who share my commitment that every dime sent by taxpayers to Washington, DC, is spent wisely.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The United States Authorization and Sunset Commission Act of 2007 creates an eight member bipartisan Commission, made up of four Senators and four Representatives. The Commission will look at the effectiveness and efficiency of all Federal programs, but will especially focus on unauthorized and ineffective programs. The bill is modeled after the sunset process that the State of Texas instituted in 1977 to identify and eliminate waste, duplication, and inefficiency in government agencies. This  process has led to the elimination of dozens of agencies that have outlived their usefulness and has saved Texas taxpayers hundreds of millions of dollars.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The job of the Commission is to ask the fundamental question: "Is an agency or program still needed?"</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Commission has two major responsibilities. First, the Commission must submit a legislative proposal to Congress at least once every 10 years that includes a review schedule of at least 25 percent of unauthorized Federal programs and at least 25 percent of ineffective Federal programs or where effectiveness cannot be shown by the Office of Management and Budget's, OMB, Performance Assessment Rating Tool, PART. The Commission's schedule will abolish each program if Congress fails to either  reauthorize the program or consider the Commission's recommendations within 2 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second, the Commission must conduct a review of each program identified in its review schedule and send its recommendations for congressional review. Congress will then have 2 years to consider and pass the Commission's recommendations or to reauthorize the program before it is abolished.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress has two bites of the apple when it comes to evaluating Federal spending. First, when it authorizes a program and second when it appropriates the money for it. Yet a study by the Congressional Budget Office found that Congress spent just under $160 billion in 2006 on agencies and programs despite the fact that their authorization had expired. The list included hundreds of accounts, big and small, ranging from the Coast Guard, $8 billion, to the Administration on Aging, $1.5 billion, to  section 8 tenant-based housing, $15.6 billion, to foreign relations programs, $9.5 billion. Many of these expired programs and agencies, perhaps most, deserve reauthorization. Nonetheless, Congress should aggressively determine whether these programs and agencies are working as intended and the Commission will help serve this purpose.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, the Commission will use OMB's PART, which is a tool to assess and improve program performance. PART looks at all factors that affect and reflect program performance including program purpose and design, performance measurement, evaluations, and strategic planning, program management, and program results. Using PART, OMB has scored 793 Government programs and found that 4 percent are ineffective and the results for 24 percent could not be shown. Programs rated as "ineffective" or</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Commission's work will be guided by 10 criteria, including the program's effectiveness and efficiency, achievement of performance goals, and whether the program has fulfilled its legislative intent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately Congress has a tendency to create commissions and then ignore their work and continue on with business as usual. This bill solves this problem. It requires Congress to consider, debate, and vote on the Commission's report under expedited procedures.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The United States Authorization and Sunset Commission Act of 2007 is an important step to getting our fiscal house in order and to making sure that Congress gets back to the hard work of oversight to determine if programs actually fulfill their stated purpose or yield some unintended or counterproductive results. Periodic assessments are essential to good Government and this is what the Commission will provide to Congress and to taxpayers across the country. For this reason, I ask that my colleagues  join me in cosponsoring the United States Authorization and Sunset Commission Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300098" topic="Introducing S. 1731. A bill to provide for the continuing review of unauthorized Federal programs and agencies and to establish a bipartisan commission for the purposes of improving oversight and eliminating wasteful Government spending; to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I am pleased to join my good friend and colleague Senator Cornyn in introducing the United States Authorization and Sunset Commission Act of 2007. This legislation would create a bipartisan commission to make recommendations to Congress on whether to reauthorize, reorganize, or terminate Federal programs. It would establish a systematic process to review unauthorized programs and agencies, and, if applicable, programs that are rated as ineffective or results  not demonstrated under the  Program Assessment Rating Tool, PART. The Comptroller General and the Director of the Congressional Budget Office, CBO, would serve as ex-officio members, bringing their knowledge and experience and that of their organizations to the process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Earlier this year, as it does every year, the CBO reported on programs that at one time had an explicit authorization that has either expired or will expire during the current session. This is always a lengthy report that runs 75 pages or more. In recent years, the total amount of unauthorized programs receiving appropriations reported by CBO has ranged between $160 billion and $170 billion annually.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I make this point, not to criticize or to imply that all unauthorized programs should be eliminated. Instead, it is to point out that what we are doing now is not working for us. We know that oversight is an important part of our job, but oversight takes time. How do we explain to our constituents that we do not have the time to distinguish between worthwhile programs and those that have outlived their purpose, are poorly targeted, operate inefficiently, or simply are not producing results?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a sponsor of The Stop Over-Spending Act of 2007, "S.O.S.," legislation, which includes several provisions from bills I introduced earlier this year, I want to work with my colleagues to pass legislation that allows us to convert some of the time spent on the annual budget cycle into time spent on oversight. A biennial budget cycle plus commissions such as this one and others that I have proposed to examine entitlement programs and increase program accountability all have a similar goal--to  provide the time and the tools to reinvigorate congressional oversight.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation does not take away our obligation to make difficult decisions about what programs to continue and those that we can no longer afford to support. What it does do is provide an opportunity to work smarter. I believe by establishing this Commission to do a thorough examination of programs and agencies, using established criteria, and a transparent reporting process, that we can carry out our responsibilities more efficiently and effectively.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support The United States Authorization and Sunset Commission Act of 2007.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="Introducing S. 1733. A bill to authorize funds to prevent housing discrimination through the use of nationwide testing, to increase funds for the Fair Housing Initiatives Program, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1733">S. 1733</bill>] Mr. President, today, I introduce the Housing Fairness Act of 2007, legislation that would strengthen efforts to detect discrimination and enforce equal housing opportunities. This legislation is especially timely given that June is National Homeownership Month.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Housing Fairness Act promotes equal housing opportunities for all people by authorizing funds to process complaints, investigate cases of housing discrimination, and develop and operate education and outreach programs to inform the general public of fair housing rights. The legislation also creates a competitive matching grant program for private nonprofit organizations to examine the causes of housing discrimination and segregation and their effects on education, poverty and economic development.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Despite the passage of the Fair Housing Act almost 40 years ago, more than 4 million fair housing violations still occur each year. When the Department of Housing and Urban Development designated certain real estate companies for investigation, studies uncovered an 87 percent rate of racial steering and a 20 percent denial rate for African-Americans and Latinos. In part due to fair housing violations, the homeownership gap between people of different racial and ethnic groups is larger than it  was in 1940. These facts confirm that we need to be doing more to promote fair housing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I invite my colleagues to cosponsor this legislation and work with me to find solutions to further detect discrimination and enforce the Fair Housing Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="Introducing S. 1734. A bill to provide for prostate cancer imaging research and education; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1734">S. 1734</bill>] Mr. President, today I rise to introduce the Prostate Research, Imaging, and Men's Education Act. This important legislation addresses the urgent need for the development of new technologies to detect and diagnose prostate cancer, and for the education of the dangers of this deadly disease.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank my colleagues, Senator FRANK LAUTENBERG and Senator JOHN KERRY, for joining me as original cosponsors of this important legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Prostate cancer is the second most common cancer in the United States, and the second leading cause of cancer related deaths in men. This cancer strikes one in every six men, making it even more prevalent than breast cancer, which strikes one in every seven women.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 2007, more than 218,000 men will be diagnosed with prostate cancer, and more than 27,000 men will die from the disease. One new case occurs every 2.5 minutes and a man dies from prostate cancer every 19 minutes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Prostate Research, Imaging, and Men's Education Act, also known as the PRIME Act, will mirror the investment the Federal Government made in advanced imaging technologies, which led to life-saving breakthroughs in detection, diagnosis and treatment of breast cancer. This bill directs the Secretary of the Department of Health and Human Services, HHS, to expand research on prostate cancer, and provides the resources to develop innovative advanced imaging technologies for prostate cancer detection,  diagnosis, and treatment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Prostate Research, Imaging, and Men's Education Act would also create a national campaign conducted through HHS to increase awareness about the need for prostate cancer screening, and the development of better screening techniques. Since African American men are 56 percent more likely to develop prostate cancer compared with Caucasian men and nearly 2.5 times as likely to die from the disease, this campaign will work with the Offices of Minority Health at HHS and the Centers for Disease Control  and Prevention to ensure that this effort will reach the men most at risk from this disease.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Prostate Research, Imaging and Men's Education Act will also promote research that improves prostate cancer screening blood tests. According to a recent National Cancer Institute study, current blood tests result in false-negative reassurances and numerous false-positive alarms. Some 15 percent of men with normal blood test levels actually have prostate cancer. Even when levels are abnormal, some 88 percent of men end up not having prostate cancer but undergoing unnecessary biopsies. Furthermore,  the prostate is one of the last organs in a human body where biopsies are performed blindly, which can miss cancer even when multiple samples are taken.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Government initiative in research and education can be the key to diagnosing prostate cancer earlier and more accurately. This legislation would strengthen our efforts to fight this disease.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As June is Men's Health Month, this is an ideal time to draw attention to the issue affecting so many men across the Nation. I ask all my fellow Senators to join with me in ensuring the health of our husbands, brothers, sons, and friends against this disease.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300034" topic="Introducing S. 1736. A bill to amend title II of the Social Security Act to provide that the eligibility requirements for disability insurance benefits under which an individual must have 20 quarters of Social Security coverage in the 40 quarters preceding a disability shall not be applicable in the case of a disabled individual suffering from a covered terminal disease; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1736">S. 1736</bill>] Mr. President, today I am introducing the Claire Collier Social Security Disability Insurance Fairness Act. This legislation will ensure that individuals suffering from certain terminal diseases are entitled to receive Social Security disability benefits. Under current law, an individual who contracts a covered terminal illness, and who has not been part of the workforce for a period of time, may not qualify for Social Security disability benefits they would otherwise be entitled to.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill is named after Claire Collier, a Stamford, Connecticut mother of three, who I first met a few years ago after she was diagnosed with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, ALS, in 2003. ALS, commonly known as Lou Gehrig's disease, first strikes the nerve cells, then weakens the muscles, causes paralysis and tragically leads to death.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Three years ago, Claire applied for Social Security disability benefits. However, she was denied the benefits because she did not have enough work credits. Ms. Collier, who worked for more than 15 years as an events planner, does not qualify for Social Security disability benefits, even though she paid Social Security and Medicare taxes for more than 15 years. The reason is the Social Security Act mandates that an individual earn 20 quarters of Social Security earnings during the 10 years preceding  a disability to collect benefits. This discriminates against people who have earned the required number of credits outside of the time period prescribed under current law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under the present system, hardworking Americans, such as Claire Collier, are being denied benefits at a time when they need them most. In Claire's case, the rules are especially unfair since she has been penalized for choosing to stay at home with her children prior to being diagnosed with ALS.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill I am sponsoring will change the eligibility standard. The Claire Collier legislation will amend the Social Security Act to provide that the eligibility standard for disability insurance benefits not be applicable in the case of a disabled individual suffering from a terminal illness.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Passage of this important legislation will simply ensure fairness. We should reward individuals who contribute to Social Security, not punish them. The Claire Collier Social Security Disability Insurance Fairness Act will eliminate inequity in the current system. I look forward to working with  my colleagues to see that this legislation is not only passed by this body soon, but that it is signed into law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By Mr. BIDEN (for himself and Mrs. BOXER)</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="1738">S. 1738</bill>. A bill to establish a Special Counsel for Child Exploitation Prevention and Interdiction within the Office of the Deputy Attorney General, to improve the Internet Crimes Against Children Task Force, to increase resources for regional computer forensic labs, and to make other improvements to increase the ability of law enforcement agencies to investigate and prosecute predators; to the Committee on the Judiciary.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300008" topic="Introducing S. 1736. A bill to amend title II of the Social Security Act to provide that the eligibility requirements for disability insurance benefits under which an individual must have 20 quarters of Social Security coverage in the 40 quarters preceding a disability shall not be applicable in the case of a disabled individual suffering from a covered terminal disease; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today to introduce the Combating Child Exploitation Act of 2007. This legislation takes a bold step forward in addressing child exploitation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And, Mr. President, let me assure you, we need bold action. We have taken some important steps here in the Senate, including passing the Jacob Weterling Act, the Pam Lyncher Act, the Amber Alert program, and last year's Adam Walsh Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But, this is a problem that keeps growing and growing, and we need bold action to address this problem. If we do not act, we will probably be back here naming a new bill after another unfortunate child victim.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bottom line is that the Internet has facilitated an exploding, multi-billion dollar market for child pornography, with 20,000 new images posted every week. This is a market that can only be supplied by the continued sexual assault and exploitation of more children and the research shows that victims are getting younger and they are being exposed to more sadistic abuse.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The FBI and the Department of Justice have testified before Congress that there are hundreds of thousands of people trafficking child pornography in this country and millions around the world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are not making a dent in this problem.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Don't get me wrong, there are many Federal, State and local investigators and prosecutors out there working tirelessly, but need to do much more.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have not dedicated enough Federal agents to this problem and we have not provided enough support for States and local government.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The most troubling aspect, one that led to the drafting of this legislation is that we know where many of these people are and if we set the right priorities we can go pick them up.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me repeat that, we have new investigative techniques that will allow us to identify many of the people who are trafficking child pornography and we can go pick them up.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A very conservative estimate is that there are more than 400,000 people who we know who are trafficking child pornography on the Internet in the U.S. right now.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We can, with minimal effort, take these people down. But, due to lack of resources we are investigating less than 2 percent of these cases. Again, we are only investigating 2 percent of the known child pornography traffickers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We also know that when law enforcement agents do investigate these cases, there is a local abused child in 30 percent off the cases. And, research shows that at least 55 percent of child pornography possessors have previously sexually assaulted children or attempted to do so. So, by picking up these known offenders, we are saving children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, it is important to note that every time one of these images or videos are shared, the child is victimized again and again.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, to help ensure that law enforcement has the capacity to get the job done, I am introducing the Combating Child Exploitation Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, this legislation will establish a Special Counsel in the Deputy Attorney General's Office to coordinate all activities related to preventing child exploitation. This will be one person who will be held accountable for results.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We will also congressionally require that there be at least one Internet Crimes Against Children Task Force, CAC, in each State. This program is poised to become the backbone for our investigative efforts here in the U.S. by forming a network of highly trained investigators to focus exclusively on combating child exploitation. Under this bill, we will triple the funding for the ICAC program to help with hiring, training, and investigative resources to form this Nation-wide network.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, we will authorize over 250 new Federal agents to focus exclusively on this problem, including 125 new FBI agents, which will double the number of agents under the Innocent Images Program at the FBI, 95 new agents for the Immigration and Customs Enforcement Agency, ICE, and 31 new postal inspectors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill will help us form a coordinated effort to go after child predators. As stated previously, we know where many of these people are and we need to go get them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In my view, it is inexcusable that we are not putting the resources toward tracking the ones down who we know about and doing much more to find the others who are lurking in the shadows.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation will get us on the right track and I urge my colleagues to support this effort.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300084" topic="Introducing S. 1739. A bill to amend section 35 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to improve the health coverage tax credit, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1739">S. 1739</bill>] Mr. President, last month, the Government Accountability Office, GAO, released yet another report about the Trade Adjustment Assistance, TAA, health coverage tax credit, HCTC. The report confirms what many in Congress have been saying since the HCTC program began, the credit is not enough, the program has several barriers to enrollment, the premiums are prohibitively high for some workers because of medical underwriting, and the program is very confusing and expensive to administer.  Although the GAO reported a $19 million decrease in costs of administration between 2003 and the end of fiscal year 2006, administrative costs still make up approximately 34 percent of the total spending for the HCTC.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Trade Adjustment Assistance Act is up for reauthorization this year. It is long past time for Congress to focus on the problems with the TAA health coverage tax credit and reauthorization presents us with that opportunity. That is why I am introducing legislation today that will make much-needed improvements to the HCTC program. And, I am proud that the distinguished Senator from Ohio, Mr. Brown, is joining me in introducing this important bill. The TAA Health Coverage Improvement  Act of 2007 offers solutions to many of the problems with the HCTC identified by the GAO. This legislation will go a long way to make the TAA health care tax credit a realistic option for displaced workers and their families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When Congress passed the Trade Act of 2002, we made a promise to American workers that the potential loss of jobs will not equal the loss of health care coverage. Unfortunately, Congress has failed to make good on that promise. Since we passed this bill, I have heard from steel retirees and widows in my State about how unaffordable the TAA health care tax credit is. And I have been very frustrated, just as I was when this bill passed, that we were not able to make the credit more affordable and  accessible for people who need it the most--laid-off workers and retirees with very limited income. We can fix these problems by including provisions from the TAA Health Coverage Improvement Act in the TAA reauthorization bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For a good number of supporters of the Trade Act of 2002, the health insurance tax credit was the single most important factor in overcoming their concerns about giving the President fast-track authority to move trade agreements through Congress. In my own judgment, the fast-track would not have passed Congress without the health care tax credit. The TAA health credit was the trade-off to balance the President's authority.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Yet, the success many of us envisioned for the health care tax credit has not been realized through implementation. The number of people who have been able to access the health care tax credit over the last 2 years is extremely disappointing. As of January 31, 2007, only 15,506 out of 252,280 who are eligible for the credit are enrolled  in the program. That is just over 6 percent, which means that almost 94 percent of those eligible are not participating.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In my home State of West Virginia, we have worked hard to promote the HCTC for trade-displaced workers. When Weirton Steel instituted significant layoffs, thousands of employees  lost their jobs. In the aftermath, State and national officials, health plan staff, and representatives of the Independent Steelworkers Union and United Steel Workers worked collaboratively to provide continuous health care coverage for HCTC-eligible workers and retirees. The community really came together and worked around the clock to educate workers and retirees about their coverage options and to ensure they were enrolled in the HCTC.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Loss of employment is absolutely devastating to workers and their families. While health care coverage alone cannot replace job loss, it does help to ease the burden on displaced workers and their dependents. West Virginia is a model example of how HCTC can work. However, with only 6 percent of those eligible for HCTC enrolled across the country, there is still much more that needs to be done.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I must say to my colleagues that Congress has had a hand in these disappointing enrollment figures. We have ignored every opportunity to improve the health coverage tax credit and enhance the lives of workers displaced by trade. Members of this body have previously voted against TAA bills that would have extended Trade Adjustment Assistance to service workers and also addressed some of the problems the GAO has identified with the health coverage credit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The TAA Health Coverage Improvement Act makes long overdue improvements to the TAA health care tax credit. First, this legislation addresses the issue of affordability. In addition to the GAO, several consumer advocacy groups and research organizations, including the Commonwealth Fund, the Center on Budget and Policy Priorities, and Families USA, have cited affordability of the credit as the primary reason for low participation in the HCTC program. The bottom line is that a 65 percent subsidy  is not enough. With a 65 percent credit, an eligible individual still has to pay an average of $2,104 in annual premium costs for single coverage plus additional amounts for deductibles and co-payments. This figure is particularly astounding given the fact that the average worker, while actively employed and earning a paycheck, paid</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation also addresses the issue of affordability by placing limits on the use of the individual market, as Congress intended under the original law. The Trade Act of 2002 specified that the health insurance credit could not be used for the purchase of health insurance coverage in the individual market except for HCTC-eligible workers who previously had a private, non-group coverage policy 30 days prior to separation from employment. However, States have been allowed by this Administration  to create State-based coverage options in the individual market for any HCTC beneficiaries, including those who did not have individual market coverage one month prior to separation from employment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of the Administration's interpretation of the law, there are people who had employer-based coverage prior to separation from employment who are now being covered in the individual market. This was not the intent of the law. To make matters worse, this interpretation undermines the consumer protections set forth in the law because individual market plans are allowed to vary premiums based on age and medical status. In one state that GAG reviewed for a previous report, because of medical  underwriting, HCTC recipients in less-than-perfect health were charged almost 6 times the premiums charged to recipients rated in the healthiest category. The legislation I am introducing today addresses this problem by clarifying that States can only designate individual market coverage within guidelines of 30-day restriction and by requiring individual market plans to be community-rated.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second, this legislation guarantees that eligible workers will have access to comprehensive group health coverage. Group coverage is what people know. The vast majority of laid-off workers and PBGC retirees had employer-sponsored group coverage prior to losing their jobs or pension benefits. The TAA Health Coverage Improvement Act designates the Federal Employees Health Benefit Plan, FEHBP, as a qualified group option in every State, so that displaced workers Nationwide will have access to the  same type of affordable, comprehensive coverage they were used to when they were employed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Third, the TAA Health Coverage Act clarifies the 3 month continuous coverage requirement. Under the original TAA statute, displaced workers are required to maintain 3 months of continuous health insurance coverage in order to qualify for certain consumer protections. Those protections are guaranteed issue, no preexisting condition exclusion, comparable premiums, and comparable benefits. Congress intended this 3 month period to be counted as the 3 months prior to separation from employment. However,  the administration has interpreted the 3 month requirement as 3 months of health insurance coverage prior to enrollment in the new health plan, which usually is after separation from employment and after certification of TAA eligibility. Many laid-off workers and PBGC recipients cannot afford to maintain</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Fourth, this bill allows spouses and dependents to receive the health coverage tax credit. Over the last 2 years, younger spouses and dependents of Medicare-eligible individuals have not been able to receive the subsidy because eligibility runs through the worker or retiree. This technicality is unfair to individuals who rely on health coverage through their spouses or parents. The TAA Health Coverage Improvement Act allows younger spouses and dependent children to retain eligibility for the  health coverage tax credit in the event the qualified beneficiary becomes eligible for Medicare.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, this legislation streamlines the HCTC enrollment process and makes it easier for trade-displaced workers to access health insurance coverage. According to GAO, two of the factors contributing to low participation include the complex nature of the HCTC program and the inability of workers to pay 100 percent of the premium during the up to 3 months before they begin to receive advance payments. The TAA Health Coverage Improvement Act improves consumer information about the HCTC by requiring  that the Treasury Secretary's eligibility notice include a description of the HCTC program; specific contact information for state offices responsible for determining eligibility and providing enrollment assistance; a list of the HCTC coverage options in the sate; and a statement informing eligible individuals of the deadline to enroll in HCTC in order to avoid lapses in coverage. Additionally, our legislation includes</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a former Governor, I know how important Trade Adjustment Assistance is to individuals who have lost their jobs due to trade. In West Virginia, thousands of workers have lost their jobs as a result of trade policy. While adjusting to the loss of employment, these individuals still have to pay mortgages, put food on the table, and care for their families. Finding affordable health care adds a significant burden to their worries. The TAA health coverage tax credit is designed  &lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page:  <bill type="s" number="8711">S8711</bill>]&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/center&gt;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, the HCTC program is not living up to its potential. The Government Accountability Office has given us a very specific diagnosis of the problems. Now, it is up to us to fix them. I look forward to working with my colleagues to pass this important legislation in conjunction with reauthorization of the Trade Adjustment Assistance program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300052" topic="Introducing S. 1743. A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to repeal the dollar limitation on contributions to funeral trusts; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1743">S. 1743</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to introduce a bill to eliminate the current dollar limitation on Qualified Funeral Trusts, QFTs. Congress created these savings vehicles in 1997 to assist individuals and families who wanted to plan for, and prepay, funeral expenses. Yet, funeral costs are rising  rapidly, and the arbitrary cap that Congress imposed on QFTs makes planning more difficult. Today I am proud to introduce this bipartisan legislation,  along with my colleague from Wisconsin, the chairman of the Special Committee on Aging, Senator Kohl. We are also joined by two of our distinguished colleagues, Senators Specter and Crapo. The change would have a positive impact on the lives of older Americans and on their families. In addition, according to the Joint Committee on Taxation, it would have a slight, but positive, impact on the Federal treasury.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When Congress created QFTs, it did so as a tax simplification measure. Unfortunately, it capped the size of these trusts at $7,000, adjusted regularly for inflation. This year, the inflation-adjusted cap is $8,800, but in many instances, this amount is no longer sufficient to cover a family's funeral expenses. In Utah, the average cost of a full funeral and burial is $12,685. I am sure that in many other states it is even higher. Because of this contribution limit, even those who preplan their  own funerals too often leave their heirs with substantial expenses. Even those who attempt to cover the entire expense may not have enough money to cover all costs after administrative fees and taxes are deducted.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This proposal would make Qualified Funeral Trusts more effective. The principal reason individuals set up Qualified Funeral Trust plans is to lift a financial burden from their children. Ordinarily, trusts for funeral expenses are grantor trusts, and the beneficiary is responsible for paying any tax on income generated by the trust. Congress recognized, however, that this result created an administrative burden for the beneficiary or the funeral director trustee. As a result, Congress enacted  Section 685 of the Internal Revenue Code, allowing funeral director trustees to elect to pay the tax on income earned by funeral trusts. This tax simplification measure eased the paperwork burden and administrative costs on funeral director trustees, who were previously required to issue hundreds of 1099 forms to their elderly customers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me give you an example of how the current cap creates unnecessary confusion for families. I have used this example before. It remains worth telling. Four years ago, a constituent of mine wrote me about this situation. He was suffering from Parkinson's disease. So he began planning his own funeral in order that these decisions and this  burden would be lifted from his children. Because of the cap on QFTs, however, which at the time was $7,800, this Utahn was not able to fully fund the funeral services he desired. It became necessary to have one of his sons complete this planning for him by opening up his own, separate trust that would help to cover the remaining expenses. We should not be making it hard for families to do the right thing. We should not be making families jump through extra hoops when all they are trying to do  is make these responsible decisions, well in advance of need.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For older Americans, the primary benefits of this legislation are the ability to have all the money they have saved in the trust be applied to final expenses, instead of taxes, and the incentive to increase the amount of their contribution. Sixty percent of prefunded funerals were funded by trusts and elimination of the cap should raise this percentage. For funeral directors, this change would eliminate the burden and expense of issuing information documents to report income earned from the trust.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The National Funeral Directors Association supports this legislation. So too do numerous funeral homes that serve the people of Utah.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have no doubt that many more of these funeral businesses, many of which are family-owned and family-run, that serve local communities from coast to coast support this legislation as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think we can all agree that we should make it easier for those who are willing to provide for these necessary expenses in advance. Today, I ask my colleagues to join me in an effort to enact this important measure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
</record>
