<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1177387200" ordinal="60" title="CONGRATULATING THE UNIVERSITY OF WISCONSIN WOMEN'S HOCKEY TEAM">
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of <bill type="sr" number="168">S. Res. 168</bill>, which was submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300042" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today, as a proud alumnus, I congratulate the University of Wisconsin for another fantastic season. This year, the University of Wisconsin women's hockey team defended its National Collegiate Athletic Association Championship, earning its second straight title.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The hard work of the Badger women's hockey team culminated in a 4-1 victory over the University of Minnesota-Duluth in the NCAA championship game on March 18, 2007, in Lake Placid, NY. The Badgers finished their season on a 26-game unbeaten streak and totaled an outstanding final record of 36-1-4.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I commend and congratulate Coach Mark Johnson, a member of the championship Badger hockey team of 1977. The Badgers won the title at Lake Placid, the site of the 1980 "Miracle on Ice" U.S. Olympic hockey team, of which Johnson was a member.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The continuing success of University of Wisconsin athletics has made the people of Wisconsin, and alumni throughout the country, proud to be Badgers. The success of this superb team helps remind sports fans in Wisconsin and around the country of UW-Madison's place as a dominant force in Big Ten and national athletics.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table, and that any statements relating thereto be printed in the Record, without intervening action or debate.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
