<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1177516815" ordinal="41" title="STATEMENTS ON INTRODUCED BILLS AND JOINT RESOLUTIONS">
  <speaking speaker="300034" topic="Introducing S. 1204. A bill to enhance Federal efforts focused on public awareness and education about the risks and dangers associated with Shaken Baby Syndrome; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1204">S. 1204</bill>] Mr. President, today I rise to introduce the Shaken Baby Syndrome Prevention Act of 2007, important legislation that promotes awareness and prevention of Shaken Baby Syndrome, a devastating form of child abuse that results in the severe injury, disability or death of hundreds of children each year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Child abuse and neglect is a well-documented tragedy for some of our youngest and most vulnerable citizens. According to the National Child Abuse and Neglect Data System (NCANDS) almost 900,000 children were victims of abuse and neglect in 2005. More than four children die every single day as a result of abusive maltreatment in this country. Babies are particularly vulnerable; in 2005, children aged 12 months or younger accounted for nearly 42 percent of all child abuse and neglect fatalities  and children under age 3 accounted for almost 77 percent. Yet even these disturbing statistics may not paint an accurate picture; most experts agree that child abuse is widely under-reported.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Abusive head trauma, including Shaken Baby Syndrome, is the leading cause of death of physically abused children, in particular for infants younger than one. When a frustrated caregiver loses control and violently shakes a baby or impacts the baby's head, the trauma can kill the child or cause severe injuries, including loss of vision, loss of hearing, brain damage, paralysis, and/or seizures, resulting in lifelong disabilities and creating profound grief for many families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Far too many children have experienced the horrible devastation of Shaken Baby Syndrome. A 2003 report in the Journal of the American Medical Association estimates that as a result of Shaken Baby Syndrome, an average of 300 U.S. children will die each year, and 600 to 1,200 more will be injured, of whom two-thirds will be infants younger than one. Medical professionals believe that thousands of Shaken Baby Syndrome cases are misdiagnosed or undetected, as many children do not immediately exhibit  obvious symptoms after the abuse.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Prevention programs can significantly reduce the number of cases of Shaken Baby Syndrome. For example, the Upstate New York SBS Prevention Project at Children's Hospital of Buffalo has used a simple video to educate new parents before they leave the hospital, reducing the number of shaken baby incidents in the area by nearly 50 percent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In Connecticut, a multifaceted prevention approach involving hospitals, schools, childcare providers, and community-based organizations in awareness and training activities, including home visits and targeted outreach, has raised awareness and encouraged prevention across the state. Hospitals in many States educate new parents about the dangers of shaking a baby, yet it is estimated that less than 60 percent of parents of newborns receive information about the dangers of shaking a baby. Without  more outreach, education and training, the risk of Shaken Baby Syndrome will persist.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With the introduction of the Shaken Baby Syndrome Prevention Act of 2007, I hope to reduce the number of children injured or killed by abusive head trauma, and ultimately to eliminate Shaken Baby Syndrome. Our initiative provides for the creation of a public health campaign, including development of a National Action Plan to identify effective, evidence-based strategies for prevention and awareness of SBS, and establishment of a cross-disciplinary advisory council to help coordinate national  efforts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The campaign will educate the general public, parents, child care providers, health care professionals and others about the dangers of shaking, as well as healthy preventative approaches for frustrated parents and caregivers coping with a crying or fussy infant. The legislation ensures support for families who have been affected by SBS, and for families and caregivers struggling with infant crying, through a 24-hour hotline and an informational website. All of these activities are to be implemented  through the coordination of existing programs and/or the establishment of new efforts, to bring together the best in current prevention, awareness and education practices to be expanded into areas in need.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Awareness is absolutely critical to prevention. Families, professionals and caregivers responsible for infants and young children and must learn about the dangers of violent shaking and abusive impacts to the head.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On behalf of the victims of Shaken Baby Syndrome, including Cynthia from New York, Hannah from California, Sarah from New York, Kierra from Nevada, Miranda from Pennsylvania, Taylor from Illinois, Cassandra from Arizona, Gabriela from Florida, Amber from New York, Bennett from Missouri, Jamison from Florida, Maggie from Texas, Dalton from Indiana, Stephen from Texas, Kaden from Washington, Joseph from Texas, Dawson from Pennsylvania, Macie from Minnesota, Jake from Maine, Benjamin from Michigan,  Chloe from New Mexico, Madison of Oklahoma, Peanut from Texas, Nykkole from Minnesota, Gianna from Rhode Island, Brynn from Washington, Rachael from Texas, Jack from Maryland, Ryan from Virginia, David from California, Reagan from Virginia, Skipper from New York, and many other innocent lives lost or damaged, I look forward to working with my colleagues to see that this legislation becomes law so that we can expand efforts to eradicate Shaken Baby Syndrome.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that a list of groups supporting this resolution be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the list was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300090" topic="Introducing S. 1205. A bill to require a pilot program on assisting veterans' service organizations and other veterans' groups in developing and promoting peer support programs that facilitate community reintegration of veterans returning from active duty, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1205">S. 1205</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to introduce the Heroes Helping Heroes Demonstration Program of 2007, along with my distinguished colleague from Iowa, Senator Harkin. I ask unanimous consent that the text of this bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our intention is to expand the use of peer-support approaches to assist the reintegration of America's veterans as they return from active duty to their homes and communities. We hope that this legislation will demonstrate the effectiveness of peer-support approaches and ease the burden of the social, economic, medical and psychological struggles our veterans face.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Deployed soldiers face extreme stress and at times devastating injuries. Left untreated, this stress can have devastating impact on soldiers and their families. Army researchers have found that alcohol misuse went from 13 percent among soldiers to 21 percent one year after returning from Iraq and Afghanistan. It also has been found that soldiers with anger and aggression issues increase from 11 percent to 22 percent after deployment. Furthermore, the best studies to date have shown that up to  one-third of our current war veterans are coping with a serious mental health problem, most notably Post Traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to these personal struggles, returning soldiers also face serious social and economic challenges. Data from the U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics indicates that unemployment among soldiers returning to civilian life is 15 percent--three times the national average. Those soldiers planning to divorce their spouse rose from nine percent to 15 percent after time spent in the combat zone. Unfortunately, as more troops are deployed, deployments are extended and breaks between deployments  become shorter these problems will only become more prevalent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At present, the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs are struggling to meet the needs of returning veterans. Situations like those recently uncovered at Walter Reed Hospital demonstrate a health care system stretched to its limits. Furthermore, it would require significant additional resources to build up traditional service organizations and approaches to be sufficient to deal with these serious problems.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have risen on this floor many times to speak about the need to adequately address the mental health and physical health needs of our citizens. However, there has never been a case when the responsibility and duty of this body and our country has been clearer than the duty to aid our veterans who have sacrificed their bodies, minds and lives for this country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Fortunately, "peer-support" approaches offer a low cost and effective adjunct to traditional services by allowing the heroes of our country to help each other. Veteran peer-support offers two things that no kind of professionalized service can ever hope to: the support of someone who has had the same kinds of experiences and truly understands what the veteran is going through; and the potential of a large pool of experienced volunteers who can assist and support returning veterans at very little  cost.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The effectiveness of these approaches has been documented in a variety of domains. Specifically, for mental health disorders like PTSD and depression, peer-support programs have shown that participation yields improvement in psychiatric symptoms and decreased hospitalizations, the development of larger social support networks, enhanced self-esteem and social functioning, as well as lower services costs. The Substance Abuse and Mental Health Service Administration (SAMHSA), and even the President's  New Freedom Commission on Mental Health, have recognized peer-support approaches as an emerging best practice that is helping people recover from traumatic events.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although the peer-support approach is promising, the need for this type of assistance is growing and far exceeds the services that are available. A report from the National Symposium for the Needs of Young Veterans hosted by AMVETS recognized this need in Voices for Action: A Focus on the Changing Needs of America's Veterans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation that I am introducing today requires the Veterans Administration to create a pilot project. This project would demonstrate and assess the feasibility of funding community based veterans' organizations and groups to create and expand peer-support programs for veterans. It also authorizes $13.5 million over three years for this program. These funds will be used to support the development or expansion of peer-support programs in up to 20 non-profit organizations that support the  reintegration of veterans on a local and national level.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The use of peer-support approaches is supported by veterans, veterans' organizations and mental health professionals. I ask for unanimous consent to include in the record the following letters from the Iraq and Afghanistan Veterans of America, Disabled American Veterans, the National Coalition for Homeless Veterans, Vets4Vets and the American Psychological Association.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am pleased that Senator Harkin has joined me in this effort. Our legislation is an important step to expand and improve the support available to our veterans and their transition back to community life. We hope that this bill will continue to focus attention on the needs of our veterans who have given so much to their country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="NATIONAL COALITION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I am pleased to join with the distinguished Senator from Oregon, Senator Smith, to introduce the Heroes Helping Heroes Act, to expand the availability of peer support programs for veterans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As our military personnel return from combat, they face daunting challenges in transitioning back to civilian life. They have to deal with family issues arising from their long absence from home. They have to find new employment. They also have to cope with separation from their close friends. After spending many months if not years with the men and women in their unit--sharing intense wartime experiences and looking out for each other--they may not find that same close support when they return.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, many members of our Armed Forces have endured tremendous stress during combat, which can trigger severe mental health issues after they have returned home. Research shows that one in three veterans of the war in Iraq, and one in nine veterans of the war in Afghanistan, are coping with a serious mental health problem, including depression, substance abuse, and/or post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD). Untreated and under-treated stress exposure for soldiers results in a higher incidence  of suicide, higher divorce rates, and higher rates of drug or alcohol abuse. Additionally, there have been almost 25,000 non-fatal American casualties. Such injuries often have serious impacts on the ability of transitioning veterans to reintegrate into their home and community life.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Currently, VA facilities are overwhelmed by the sheer number of veterans who need assistance. The Government Accountability Office (GAO) reported that many VA medical facilities are unprepared to care for the mental health needs of the number of veterans who will need services. Peer support approaches offer a low-cost and effective supplement to traditional services by allowing veterans to help each other. In peer support programs, transitioning veterans can talk to someone who had similar experiences  and understands what they are going through. Veteran peer counselors who are trained to provide support and refer for services when necessary can provide outreach to other veterans and assist in a smooth transition back to civilian life.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Heroes Helping Heroes program will allow veterans' service organizations to develop or expand peer support programs. Veterans' service organizations and other non-profits that serve veterans are well-equipped to provide such peer support programs. Given that the VA is stretched to capacity, these organizations are able to run such programs in addition to mental health services provided by professional counselors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Substance Abuse and Mental Health Service Administration (SAMSHA) and the President's New Freedom Commission on Mental Health have recognized peer support approaches as an emerging best practice in helping people to recover from traumatic events. Research has found that peer support programs are effective in alleviating PTSD symptoms and depression, reducing the likelihood of hospitalization, and increasing social support.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When members of our Armed Forces come home from war, this does not necessarily mean that the war is over for them. Many continue to carry physical and psychological wounds and scars. We have a profound moral contract to care for those who have fought for our country and sacrificed so much. One additional way to make good on that contract in a cost-effective way is to expand the availability peer support programs nationwide. To that end, I urge my colleagues to join with Senator Smith  and me in sponsoring the Heroes Helping Heroes Act.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300075" topic="Introducing S. 1206. A bill to amend title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 and the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967 to clarify the age discrimination rules applicable to the pension plan maintained by the Young Woman's Christian Association Retirement Fund; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1206">S. 1206</bill>] Mr. President, I rise to introduce a bill that will clarify the legal status of the Young Women's Christian Association's Retirement Fund.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The YWCA Retirement Fund is one of the oldest pension plans serving the retirement needs of women. This bill will help protect the retirement security of thousands of YWCA employees nationwide who serve well over a million users.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Whether it is providing day care for working mothers, keeping a battered women's shelter open, or meeting the other pressing needs of women in our communities, the YWCA has a long tradition of service. Those who work at our local YWCAs deserve to know that their retirement plan is secure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, the YWCA Retirement Fund is a unique pension program. First, approximately 90 percent of its participants are women. Second, it is a multiple employer pension plan--one that relies on 300 local YWCAs to make funding contributions. And lastly, since it was established in 1924, the pension plan's structure has remained generally unchanged--it is partially a defined benefit plan, and partially a defined contribution plan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Recently, some employers have transformed their traditional defined benefit pension plans into various types of "hybrid" plans, and in the process, some have reduced the rate at which benefits accrue for their older workers. Older workers have successfully challenged some of these arrangements as age discriminatory. During its more than 80-year history, the YWCA Retirement Fund has never treated any worker differently based on age or longevity of employment. Most of the controversy surrounding  these plans focuses on how employers treat certain participants when they convert their pre-existing pension plans. But the YWCA pension program never converted--its basic structure has remained the same since it was established in 1924.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The success of some of these lawsuits has raised questions about whether the YWCA pension plan could be found to be age discriminatory merely on the basis of its design. This threat is particularly acute given the fact that the YWCA Retirement Fund is a multiple employer pension plan--a plan that relies on contributions from each local  YWCA. This enormous potential liability would be shared jointly by all local YWCAs. Under current law, even the mere  threat of a lawsuit could cause local YWCAs to end their participation in this plan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation merely delineates many of the unique characteristics of the YWCA pension plan and clarifies what age discrimination standard applies to the plan with respect to any future legal claim. This bill protects participants from being treated differently on the basis of age, while eliminating the potential crippling legal threat that currently exists.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Legislation was enacted in 2004--Public Law 108-476--to clarify the legal status of the YMCA pension plan, a plan that is similar to the YWCA plan. Congress was right to protect the YMCA pension plan then and now it is time to protect the pension plan serving our YWCAs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300063" topic="Introducing S. 1207. A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to increase and extend the energy efficient commercial buildings deduction; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1207">S. 1207</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to introduce legislation entitled Giving Reductions to Energy Efficient New Buildings, the GREEN Buildings Act. This bill will extend the energy efficient building tax deduction from December 31, 2008 until December 31, 2013. This bill will also increase the tax deduction from $1.80 to $2.25 per square foot.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our Nation is diligently searching to find the long-term solutions to global warming and, how to reduce our carbon foot print. As Congress continues to search for these solutions, we must continue to provide incentives to those who have the knowledge and resources to make an impact now. Congress understands the impact `green buildings' have on reducing our Nation's energy consumption and carbon emissions. That is why in the Energy Policy Act of 2005 we created a tax deduction for energy efficient  buildings. Unfortunately, that deduction will expire on December 31, 2008. Congress must not allow this deduction to expire. Building energy efficient buildings is one of the key things being done right now to reduce carbon dioxide emissions as well as reduce our Nation's energy consumption.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Commercial buildings are a substantial part of our Nation's energy consumption and can be a key to reducing demand for electricity. These buildings are responsible for 40 percent of total U.S. energy consumption, they use 70 percent of the nation's electricity and they are accountable for 40 percent of the U.S. carbon dioxide emissions. They are a major piece to enabling our Nation's energy independence and to solving the global warming puzzle and Congress must not overlook them or leave them  out.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The average life-span of a commercial building is 75 years. We must use our resources, to build energy-efficient buildings today and make these buildings truly ready for the future. One way to do so is to provide incentives to those who are willing to step up to the plate and accept the challenge.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Another benefit from building energy efficient or green buildings is that they also improve our health. Americans spend about 90 percent of their time indoors. The concentration of indoor pollutants is sometimes 10 to 100 times more than outdoor pollutants increasing the frequency of illnesses and ailments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Researchers have proven that employees who are exposed to more sunlight are more productive workers. They have proven that by changing the carpets on the floor and paint on the walls workers have less respiratory ailments. These are simple things that can be done to increase employees' health and their productivity and our nation's overall success.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our Nation is doing a good job of researching and developing new technologies to reduce our dependence on foreign energy and to combat global warming, and Congress has helped move these technologies along by providing incentives in the way of tax deductions. Unfortunately, many of these incentives have an expiration date that expires too soon to provide the help it is intended to provide. Congress needs to keep these incentives intact and provide stability so companies and investors can be assured  of their investment. In turn, maintaining these incentives will advance our Nation's energy independence and reduce our carbon dioxide emissions--two very important goals. I urge my fellow Senators to support this sensible and much needed tax incentive. We don't have another 75 years to wait.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300037" topic="Introducing S. 1208. A bill to provide additional security and privacy protection for social security account numbers; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1208">S. 1208</bill>] Mr. President, today I am introducing a piece of legislation called the "Social Security Account Number Protection Act" that would restrict the ability of companies to sell or purchase Social Security numbers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me describe why this legislation is so necessary.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On February 15, 2005, Georgia-based data warehouser ChoicePoint disclosed that it had compromised the private customer data of 145,000 individuals. Criminals posing as legitimate small business people had purchased files on about 145,000 people, some of whom were later defrauded.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One of the critical pieces of information that ChoicePoint sold to these criminals was Social Security numbers. That's Social Security numbers of 145,000 people in all 50 states.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Here is a statistic that I found incredible: Choice Point has 17,000 business "customers" for such information. Can you imagine your Social Security number potentially being sold to 117,000 businesses? And that's just one of the companies that was selling databases that included Social Security numbers at the time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I bet that most Americans were surprised to find out that it was perfectly legal for companies to sell their Social Security numbers to tens of thousands of other companies. If you took a national survey and asked Americans this question: "Do you think that private companies should have the ability to purchase and sell your Social Security number?" I assure you that the answer would overwhelmingly be "no."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the 109th Congress, when the Senate Commerce Committee marked up <bill type="s" number="1408">S. 1408</bill>, the ID Theft Protection Act, I offered an amendment that very simply said that it should be illegal to sell or purchase Social Security numbers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This as a commonsense amendment, and it passed unanimously. The ID Theft Protection Act was reported by the Commerce Committee in December 2005, but the bill did not make it to the Senate floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But the problem of ID theft has not gone away. In its most recent survey, the Better Business Bureau estimated that approximately 8.9 million Americans were victims of identity theft in 2006. The total U.S. annual identity fraud cost is an estimated $52.6 billion per year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We will shortly be marking up another ID theft bill in the 110th Congress, through the Commerce Committee. The bill the Commerce Committee is considering now does not have provisions restricting the sale or purchase of Social Security numbers, and I intend to offset an amendment to fix that, with the language that I am introducing as standalone legislation today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I should note that the FTC issued a report on ID theft just this month, which emphasized the importance of protecting Social Security numbers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The FTC report said the following about Social Security numbers: "Consumer information is the currency of identity theft, and perhaps the most valuable piece of information for the thief is the SSN. The SSN and a name can be used in many cases to open an account and obtain credit or other benefits in the victim's name."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In fact elsewhere in the report, the FTC underscored that Social Security numbers are "the most valuable commodity for an identity thief."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One of the FTC's top recommendations was that federal agencies should reduce the unnecessary use of Social Security numbers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And it's clear that the FTC heard from many Americans who were unhappy with the widespread overuse of Social Security numbers. Indeed, the FTC report notes that one of the main concerns that Americans have in protecting their identity is "the overuse of Social Security numbers as identifiers."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It stands to reason that the more that Social Security numbers are sold from one business to another for marketing and other commercial purposes, the greater the chance that the numbers will be lost, misplaced, stolen, leaked, or otherwise fall into the wrong hands.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, I'll be the first to recognize that there are some instances where the use of Social security numbers is appropriate. So my amendment has a number of reasonable exceptions to the prohibition on the sale of Social Security numbers, for purposes such as national security, public health, law enforcement, administration of federal or state tax laws, credit reporting agencies, prevention and investigation of ID theft, and tracking of missing and abducted children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What's more, my bill allows an "opt-in" clause. That is, it allows individuals, if they so choose, to agree in writing to have their Social Security number sold or purchased by others--provided the individual provides his affirmative consent, and the individual is not obligated to provide the Social Security number as a condition for conducting a transaction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think these are reasonable exemptions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I should add that in the 109th Congress, Senators SPECTER and LEAHY also introduced <bill type="s" number="1332">S. 1332</bill>, a bill that similarly restricts the sale of Social Security numbers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So this is a bipartisan concept, and I hope that my legislation will have bipartisan support when it reaches the floor of the U.S. Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="Introducing S. 1209. A bill to provide for the continued administration of Santa Rosa Island, Channel Islands National Park, in accordance with the laws (including regulations) and policies of the National Park Service, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1209">S. 1209</bill>] Mr. President, I am pleased to join my colleague Senator Boxer in introducing the Channel Islands National Park Management Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation seeks to clarify the future use and management of the park, and specifically protects Santa Rosa Island for the use of the public.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The taxpayers paid approximately $30 million to acquire Santa Rosa Island in 1986 to restore its native ecology and provide public access.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, late last year during conference negotiations a provision was slipped into the fiscal year 2007 Defense Authorization bill seeking to overturn a court-approved settlement agreement which requires the phasing out of private hunting on Santa Rosa Island.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under a binding court settlement in the late 1990s, non-native deer and elk must be removed from Santa Rosa Island over a phased, 4-year period beginning in 2008.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, from mid-August through mid-November, a large portion of the island is closed to the public so that the island's prior owners can run a trophy hunting operation targeting the deer and elk on the island.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under the settlement, this hunting operation was to end in 2011 allowing the island to be completely open to the public year round.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, under last year's provision, the prior owners will seek to continue charging $16,000 or more for their privately operated hunting trips.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Even though the Government purchased the island from them for $30 million in taxpayer money, the prior owners would seek to keep essentially everything they had before--and that's simply not in the public interest.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Some may be interested in learning a little history and background on this gem of an island: Santa Rosa Island is approximately 53,000 acres and lies about 50 miles west of Ventura Harbor. It is the second largest of the five islands making up the Channel Islands National Park. It is extremely rugged and pristine, with terrain ranging from grassy hills to steep, wind-carved canyons to white sandy beaches. Craggy, steep cliffs overlook rocky tide pools along its coast. Wildflowers cover many parts  of the island during the spring and summer. It is ecologically sensitive and includes several endemic plants and species. For example, it is the only place in the world to see the island fox and spotted skunk in their natural habitat. A variety of shore birds--like the snowy plover--and sea mammals--such as seals and sea lions--breed on its beaches. It is seen by many scientists as one of the nation's most unique places.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The limitation of public access to the island to accommodate privately run hunting trips would be a tragedy. This is the public's land. It's a national park, and the public should be able to visit it and enjoy its breath-taking beauty and remoteness.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also want to address one issue the provision in last year's Defense Authorization bill purportedly seeks to address: enhancing hunting opportunities for disabled veterans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While no one opposes providing hunting opportunities for our veterans, it is clear that it is neither a practical nor viable option to use Santa Rosa Island as a hunting reserve for injured and disabled veterans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This view is now supported by the Paralyzed Veterans of America, PVA, an organization which previously expressed support for the provision overturning the settlement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Notably, in July 2006, the PVA reached the conclusion following an investigative visit to Santa Rosa that the "numerous obstacles inherent to the island, including ingress and egress, logistics, personal safety and cost, far outweigh the possible, limited benefit it could provide."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Furthermore, it should be pointed out that in California today, there are already 9 military installations that permit hunting--five that can accommodate disabled servicemembers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Two of these military installations, Camp Pendleton and Vandenberg Air Force Base, are relatively close to the Channel Islands National Park, and allow disabled veterans to hunt a variety of animals, including deer, waterfowl, quail, feral pigs, small game, and coyote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Altogether there are over 100 U.S. military installations where hunting is permitted, over 70 of which are currently accessible to disabled servicemembers and veterans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Naturally, the Park Service is firmly opposed to the provision seeking to overturn the settlement. But it is also important to note that neither the Department of Defense nor the Veterans Administration asked for the language.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Consequently, I strongly believe that the Park Service should continue managing this National Park for the benefit of the general public. To allow any less would be a waste of taxpayer dollars and wrongly limit the public's access to this national treasure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I strongly believe that we must do everything to protect the island for the public and oppose any measures that could continue to restrict access to the island.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation we are introducing today would safeguard the island in just this manner. I urge my colleagues to support this legislation and I ask unanimous consent that the text of this proposed legislation be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="Introducing S. 1210. A bill to extend the grant program for drug-endangered children; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1210">S. 1210</bill>] Mr. President, today I am introducing with Senator Grassley, as well as Senators KOHL, FEINGOLD and DURBIN as original co-sponsors, the Drug Endangered Children Act of 2007. This bill would take an important grant program for drug-endangered children that Congress authorized in the USA PATRIOT Reauthorization Act, and extend it for two additional years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In particular, the USA PATRIOT Reauthorization Act authorized $20 million in Federal grants for fiscal years 2006 and 2007 to States to assist in the treatment of children who have been endangered by living at a home where methamphetamine has been manufactured or distributed. But unless we pass new legislation, that authorization will not continue beyond the current fiscal year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A companion bill was introduced earlier this year by California Congressman DENNIS A. CORDOZA, with bipartisan support in the House.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The White House's Office of National Drug Control Policy, or ONDCP, has documented that innocent children are sometimes found in homes and other environments, hotels, automobiles, apartments, etc., where methamphetamine and other illegal substances are produced.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>According to the El Paso Intelligence Center (EPIC) National Clandestine Laboratory Seizure System, there were 1,660 children affected by or injured or killed at methamphetamine labs during 2005.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These children who live at or visit drug-production sites or are present during drug production face a variety of health and safety risks, including: inhalation, absorption, or ingestion of toxic chemicals, drugs, or contaminated foods that may result in nausea, chest pain, eye and tissue irritation, chemical burns, and death; fires and explosions; abuse and neglect, and hazardous lifestyles, presence of booby traps, firearms, code violations, and poor ventilation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Where children are involved, drug lab seizures must go beyond the normal response from law enforcement, fire and HAZMAT organizations. Additional agencies and officials often must be called in to assist, including emergency medical personnel, social services, and physicians.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Recognizing this need, the ONDCP several years ago announced a national Drug Endangered Children (DEC) initiative to assist with coordination between existing State programs and create a standardized training program to extend DEC to states where such a program does not yet exist.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a result of this initiative, several states developed DEC programs, to coordinate the efforts of law enforcement, medical services, and child welfare workers, to ensure that children found in these environments receive appropriate attention and care.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These DEC programs began to develop interagency protocols to support drug-endangered children, addressing issues such as: staff training, including safety and cross training; roles and responsibilities of agencies involved; appropriate reporting, cross-reporting, and information sharing; safety procedures for children, families, and responding personnel; interviewing procedures; evidence collection and preservation procedures, and medical care procedures.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Protocols were designed to identify and provide guidance on the variety of issues that responding agencies needed to address in these situations, such as taking children into protective custody and arranging for child protective services, immediately testing the children for methamphetamine exposure, conducting medical and mental health assessments, and ensuring short- and long-term care.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, the ONDCP's initiative, which had been funded in part through a DOJ award of $2.124 million under the Community Oriented Policing Services (COPS) Methamphetamine Initiative of 2003, was not continued thereafter.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The USA PATRIOT Reauthorization Act that we passed in 2005, establishing a specific grant program for this purpose, recognized the need to continue this initiative. Unfortunately, this grant program that we authorized was never funded. In fiscal year 2006, the program that we authorized was appropriated no funds at all.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In fiscal year 2007, the House of Representatives voted to include $5 million for this important program as part of its CJS Appropriations bill. But unfortunately, the 109th Congress adjourned without passing most of its FY2007 appropriations bills, and the Continuing Resolution we passed to keep the government running did not fund this provision either.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So the bill that I introduce today would give the Congress another chance to revive this important initiative. And it can't come too soon for places like Merced, California, where three-quarters of all foster care cases are reported to be methamphetamine-related.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to adopt this legislation and ask unanimous consent that the text of this bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="Introducing S. 1210. A bill to extend the grant program for drug-endangered children; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I am pleased to join my colleague today, Senator FEINSTEIN, in introducing the Drug Endangered Children Act (DEC) of 2007. As U.S. Senators representing States that have been among the hardest hit by the scourge of meth, we have witnessed first hand how this horrible drug has devastated individual lives and families. We have seen the havoc wreaked on the environment as well as the child welfare system and we have listened to the horror stories of those caught  in the grips of addiction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last year we worked together in a bi-partisan effort to pass the Combat  Meth Act, which was eventually included in the USA PATRIOT Act Reauthorization. The result has been a dramatic decrease in the number of clandestine meth lab seizures. While this is certainly welcome news, particularly for our first responders and local law enforcement community, last year there were over 6,400 clandestine meth lab incidents throughout the country. In my home State,  we saw a 73 percent decrease in the number of meth lab incidents compared to the previous year yet there were still over 300 incidents last year alone. Clearly, the Combat Meth Act has made progress against locally produced meth, but further action is needed to fully combat this epidemic.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In spite of our success and ongoing efforts to reduce the dangers from "mom and pop" meth labs, new and more disturbing instances of meth production, trafficking, and abuse are becoming more prevalent throughout the country. In the State of Missouri, police recently made seven meth-related arrests in just as many hours in the tiny, quiet town of Ozark. The house where these arrests were made belonged to a 45-year-old grandmother, who was baby sitting her infant grandson while his mother was  away at school. Upon her arrest she admitted to using meth, but denied she was a dealer. However, while police searched the house, six more individuals were picked up on meth-related charges. When it was all said and done, three children under the age of 3 watched as the police arrested their parent or grandparent for selling or possessing this dangerous drug.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sadly, this was not an unusual incident. Since 2002, more than 12,000 children throughout the country have been affected, injured, or killed at meth lab sites and thousands more have been sent to foster homes or were victims of meth-related abuse in the home. In Iowa, the Department of Health reports that over 1,000 children over the past 4 years were classified as victims of abuse, and that nearly half of child abuse cases have been meth-related.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Due to the shocking number of children that were being victimized by meth in one form or another, I joined my colleagues in supporting the "Drug Endangered Children Act of 2005." This bill which passed into law as part of the USA PATRIOT Act Reauthorization, established a national grant program to support state Drug Endangered Children programs and to assist local law enforcement, medical services, and child welfare workers to ensure that victimized children would receive proper attention and  treatment after living in these terrible environments. I'm pleased to report that since we implemented this grant program, a large number of communities throughout the nation have formed multi-disciplinary alliances for the benefit of drug-exposed children. There are 16 communities throughout Iowa that have taken advantage of these grants and more are in the process of planning and setting up programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Drug Endangered Children Act of 2007 would re-authorize this important grant program for an additional 2 years and assist States in coordinating law enforcement, medical services, and child welfare efforts, to ensure that children found in such environments receive appropriate attention and care. I am pleased to join with my colleague again as we work together to renew this wonderful and worthwhile program. I ask that my colleagues join us in support of this important legislation and pass  the Drug Endangered Children Act of 2007.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="Introducing S. 1211. A bill to amend the Controlled Substances Act to provide enhanced penalties for marketing controlled substances to minors; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1211">S. 1211</bill>] Mr. President, today I join with Senator Grassley in introducing the Saving Kids from Dangerous Drugs Act of 2007. This bill would increase the criminal penalties that apply when criminals market their illegal drugs to our children, using appalling techniques like the recently reported sales on our streets of candy-flavored methamphetamine.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In particular, the bill would: double the maximum penalties applicable to drug crimes if a criminal defendant manufactures, offers, distributes, or possesses with intent to distribute a controlled substance that is flavored, colored, packaged or otherwise altered in a way that is designed to make it more appealing to a person under the age of 21; if the violation is a repeat offense, the maximum sentence would be tripled; and a mandatory minimum prison sentence of at least a year would apply  in every case involving illegal drugs that targets its marketing at minors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The growing problem of marketing illegal drugs to minors was highlighted in a recent USA Today article, entitled "Flavored Meth Use on the Rise," which stated, "Reports of candy-flavored methamphetamine are emerging around the nation, stirring concern among police and abuse prevention experts that drug dealers are marketing the drug to younger people."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Normally, methamphetamine--a highly addictive stimulant--is a brownish, bitter-tasting crystalline powder. But drug dealers, recognizing that this may not be appealing to children or teenagers, have reacted by reaching a new low: they are using candy and soda flavors to market their meth.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Soda flavors. Strawberry methamphetamine that they market as "Strawberry Quick." Reddish methamphetamine marketed as an energy drink like "Red Bull." Even "chocolate quick."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Scott Burns, Deputy Drug Czar at the White House Office of National Drug Control Policy, warns that this development may negatively affect the gains we have recently made in getting the word out to our young people about how horrible this drug is.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>According to the National Survey on Drug Use and Health, the number of people 12 and older who used methamphetamine for the first time in the previous year decreased from 318,000 people in 2004 to 192,000 people in 2005. That's the good news.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But Deputy Drug Czar Burns warns that with drug dealers having a tougher time selling their product, especially to young people, "they have to come up with some sort of gimmick." And that gimmick, he warns, is the use of flavored methamphetamine.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In my own State of California, San Francisco police since late January have arrested teens with quantities of meth designed to taste like chocolate. The Haight-Asbury clinic also confirms chocolate-flavored methamphetamine being used on the streets.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dr. Alex Stalcup, a nationally renowned drug counselor, reports seeing teenage patients at the New Leaf Treatment Center suffering the ill effects of flavored methamphetamine since the first of this year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One of Dr. Stalcup's patients was unaware that the substance was meth at all, and said he was told that it was a solidified form of the energy drink Red Bull. Dr. Stalcup warns that this new form of the drug also may be more likely to lead to an overdose, by users who may not be aware of, or who may underestimate, a candy-flavored drug's impact.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Perhaps the first report of this problem emerged in late January, when a Carson City, Nevada police informant purchased 2 grams of a strawberry-flavored methamphetamine from an alleged member of the Lima Street gang. Officers later served a search warrant on his home and found more. Police bulletins warned this "new type of meth will be more attractive to a younger crowd and may surface in schools."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Additional reports also came in. On February 13, a police officer in Greene County, MO, seized a bag of "strawberry meth" from a female passenger in a car stopped in a rural area of Greene County, MO. And in Idaho, the Administrator of the Governor's Office of Drug Control Policy warned of how drug dealers were producing "strawberry quick" and "chocolate quick" forms of meth, to attract young buyers and spawn a new generation of drug buyers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Idaho Press-Tribune even reported that at Valentine's Day, drug dealers compressed the flavored form of the drug into heart-shapes, colored it bright pink, and wrapped it in shiny paper.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Based on intelligence gathered by Drug Enforcement Administration agents from informants, users, police and drug counselors, flavored crystals are now available in California, Nevada, Washington, Idaho, Texas, New Mexico, Missouri and Minnesota.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill I offer today would address this problem, by enacting penalties to discourage colored and flavored drugs and the marketing of drugs to minors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under current law, there is already an enhanced penalty if someone distributes illegal drugs to a minor. The maximum sentence is doubled, and tripled for a repeat offense, and there is a minimum of at least a year in prison. But the enhancement applies only if there is an actual distribution to a minor. Even possession with intent to distribute doesn't qualify. And current law doesn't address flavored drugs or marketing illegal drugs in ways appealing to kids.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill I introduce would fix that. If someone manufactures, creates, distributes, or possesses with intent to distribute an illegal drug that is flavored, colored, packaged or altered in a way designed to make it more appealing to someone under age 21, they would face this same enhanced penalty.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill will send a strong and clear message to the drug dealers--if you flavor up your drugs or alter them in a way that makes it more appealing to our children, there will be a very heavy price to pay.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Flavored meth is designed to get people to try it a few times. It's all about hooking young people. And that is truly tragic. Listen to what one former addict wrote after hearing about this new development:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>They do need to worry about our children because I happen to know quite a few 10 and 12 year olds on up that are already using it and selling it out there. So whoever thinks it's not a threat to our children--WRONG WRONG WRONG! It's more and more dangerous out there when people cannot handle it and they develop a chemical imbalance and lose their mind to where they don't even know who they are anymore. I happen to know a very, very young pretty girl I've met, and she will never come back to who  she was. She's gone. She is crazy and is gonna end up hurt then dead one of these days. I pray for this girl all the time .....</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Estimates now place the number of habitual meth users worldwide at 26 million worldwide--more than the combined total for heroin and cocaine. It is extraordinarily addictive. We must act to preserve the gains we have made, and keep kids from getting cruelly tricked into an addiction they may never break.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These new penalties will make dealers think twice before flavoring up their drugs, and punish them appropriately if they don't. I urge my colleagues to support this legislation and ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="Introducing S. 1211. A bill to amend the Controlled Substances Act to provide enhanced penalties for marketing controlled substances to minors; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I am pleased to join my colleague today, Senator FEINSTEIN, in introducing the Saving Kids from Dangerous Drugs Act of 2007. I believe we have a moral obligation in this country to ensure our young people have every opportunity to grow up without being accosted by drug pushers at every turn, whether on TV, in the movies, or on the way to school.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This important legislation comes in response to the recent warnings issued by the Drug Enforcement Administration and the Office of National Drug Control Policy of candy-flavored meth and other illegal drugs being colored, packaged, and flavored in ways that appear to be designed to attract use by children and minors. As co-chairman of the Senate Caucus on International Narcotics Control, I can tell you that the most at-risk population for drug abuse is our young people. Research has shown time  and again that if you can keep a child drug-free until they turn 20, chances are very slim that they will ever try or become addicted. Unfortunately, unscrupulous drug dealers are all too aware of statistics like these and have developed new techniques and marketing gimmicks to lure in younger users. As a parent and now grandparent, this is extremely worrisome.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last year, we worked to pass the Combat Meth Act into law. Since that time, the number of clandestine meth lab seizures have dropped dramatically across the country. By placing the essential ingredient pseudoephedrine behind the counter, we have lifted a heavy burden from the shoulders of our local law enforcement and made our communities a safer place to live and raise a family. In my home State of Iowa alone, the number of seizures fell a remarkable 73 percent since the sale of pseudoephearine  was restricted. But as anyone can tell you, we have a long way to go.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Despite our best efforts and recent success, meth continues to wreak havoc on families and communities across the country. While local "mom and pop" meth labs are being dismantled everywhere, drug dealers continue to look for new ways to market their poison. This legislation is intended to protect our young people by expanding existing penalties for those marketing their poison to kids.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Currently Federal law enhances Federal penalties for selling drugs to anyone under the age of 21. When a violation occurs, the Federal penalties are doubled--tripled for a repeat offense--and a mandatory minimum of at least 1 year also applies. However, only the dealer who directly sells drugs to someone under 21 is subject to a double sentence.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Saving Kids from Dangerous Drugs Act would expand the circumstances under which these enhanced penalties apply. Under our bill, the enhanced penalties that already exist would also apply to anyone who "manufactures, creates, distributes, or possesses with intent to distribute a controlled substance that is flavored, colored, packaged or otherwise altered in a way that is designed to make it more appealing to a person under 21 years of age, or who attempts or conspires to do so."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The fight against meth and other dangerous drugs is and will continue to be an ongoing struggle. We must adapt and change our tactics just as the dealers, distributors, and pushers have changed theirs. We must do all we can to protect the most vulnerable among us and send a clear message to those wishing to prey on our youth.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask that my colleagues join us in support of this important legislation and pass the Drug Endangered Children Act of 2007.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Ms." name="MIKULSI" of="">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1212">S. 1212</bill>] Mr. President, acknowledging the social workers' presence on Capitol Hill this week for their Annual Leadership Meeting Lobby Day, I rise today to introduce the "Clinical Social Work Medicare Equity Act of 2007." I am proud to sponsor this legislation that will ensure clinical social workers receive Medicare reimbursements for the mental health services they provide in skilled nursing facilities. Under the current system, social workers are not paid for the services they provide.  Psychologists and psychiatrists, who provide similar counseling, are able to separately bill Medicare for their services.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since my first days in Congress, I have been fighting to protect and strengthen the safety of our Nation's seniors. Making sure that seniors have access to quality, affordable mental  health care is an important part of this fight. I know that millions of seniors do not have access to, or are not receiving, the mental health services they urgently need. Nearly 6 million seniors are affected by depression, but only one-tenth ever receive treatment. According  to the American Psychiatric Association, up to 25 percent of the elderly population in the United States suffers from significant symptoms of mental illness and among nursing home residents the prevalence is as high as 80 percent. These mental disorders, which include severe depression and debilitating anxiety,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a former social worker, I understand the role social workers play in the overall care of patients and seniors. This bill protects patients across the country and ensures that seniors living in underserved urban and rural areas, where clinical social workers are often the only available option for mental health care, continue to receive the treatment they need. Clinical social workers, much like psychologists and psychiatrists, treat and diagnose mental illnesses. In fact, clinical social workers  are the primary mental health providers for nursing home residents and seniors residing in rural environments. Unlike other mental health providers, clinical social workers cannot bill Medicare directly for the important services they provide to their patients. Protecting</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Before the Balanced Budget Act of 1997, clinical social workers billed Medicare Part B directly for mental health services they provided in nursing facilities for each patient they served. Under the Prospective Payment System, services provided by clinical social workers are lumped, or "bundled," along with the services of other health care providers for the purposes of billing and payments. Psychologists and psychiatrists, who provide similar counseling, were exempted from this system and  continue to bill Medicare directly. This bill would exempt clinical social workers, like their mental health colleagues, from the Prospective Payment System, and would make sure that clinical social workers are paid for the services they provide to patients in skilled nursing</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill is about more than paperwork and payment procedures. This bill is about equal access to Medicare payments for the equal and important work done by clinical social workers. It is about making sure our Nation's most vulnerable citizens have access to quality, affordable mental health care. The overarching goal we should be striving to achieve for our seniors is an overall improved quality of life. Without clinical social workers, many nursing home residents may never get the counseling  they need when faced with a life threatening illness or the loss of a loved one. I think we can do better by our Nation's seniors, and I'm fighting to make sure we do.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Clinical Social Work Medicare Equity Act of 2007 is strongly supported by the National Association of Social Workers. I also want to thank Senators STABENOW and INOUYE for their co-sponsorship of this bill. I look forward to working with my colleagues to enact this important legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that a letter of support be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the letter was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300060" topic="Introducing S. 1214. A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modify the partial exclusion for gain from certain small business stocks; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1214">S. 1214</bill>] Mr. President, this week we are celebrating National Small Business Week to recognize the contributions made by small businesses, which are the engine of our economic growth. During 2005, more than 25 billion small businesses in the United States contributed $918 billion to the economy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many of our most successful corporations started as small businesses, including AOL, Apple Computer, Compac Computer, Datastream, Evergreen Solar, Intel Corporations, and Sun Microsystems. As you can see from this partial list, many of these companies played an integral role in making the Internet a reality.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, Senator Snowe and I are introducing the Invest in Small Business Act of 2007, to encourage private investment in small businesses by making changes to the existing partial exclusion for gain from certain small business stock.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are at an integral juncture in developing technology to address global climate change. I believe that small business will repeat the role it played at the vanguard of the computer revolution by leading the Nation in developing the technologies to substantially reduce carbon emissions. Small businesses already are at the forefront of these industries, and we need to do everything we can to encourage investment in small businesses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Back in 1993, I worked with Senator Bumpers to provide a partial exclusion for gain from the sale of small business stock. This provision would provide a 50 percent exclusion for gain for individuals from the sale of certain small business stock that is held for five years. Since the enactment of this provision, the capital gains rate has been lowered twice without any changes to the exclusion. Due to the lower capital rates, this provision no longer provides a strong incentive for investment  in small businesses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Invest in Small Business Act makes several changes to the existing provision. This legislation increases the exclusion amount from 50 percent  to 75 percent and decreases the holding period from five years to four years. This bill would allow corporations to benefit from the provision as long as they own less than 25 percent of the small business corporation stock.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Currently, the exclusion is treated as a preference item for calculating the alternative minimum tax (AMT). The Invest in Small Business Act of 2007 would repeal the exclusion as an AMT preference item. Under current law, the nonexcluded amount of gain is taxed at 28 percent. This legislation would tax the nonexcluded portion at the lower capital gains rate of 15 or 5 percent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Invest in Small Business Act of 2007 will provide an effective tax rate of 3.75 percent for the gain from the sale of certain small businesses. This lower capital gains rate will encourage investment in small businesses. In addition, the changes made by the Invest in Small Business Act of 2007 will make more taxpayers eligible for this provision.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As we celebrate the success of entrepreneurs this week, it is an appropriate time to encourage new investment. The Invest in Small Business Act of 2007 strengthens an existing tax incentive to provide an appropriate incentive to encourage innovation and entrepreneurship.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill and a summary of the bill be printed in the Record</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300036" topic="Introducing S. 1216. A bill to allow certain nationals of Mexico entering the State of New Mexico on a temporary basis to travel up to 100 miles from the international border between the State of New Mexico and Mexico, and for other purposes; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1216">S. 1216</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today with Senator Bingaman to introduce a bill of importance to the economic development of our Southwest border States, the Laser Visa Extension Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The United States and Mexico have had special travel rules for Mexican nationals who visit our country for short periods of time since 1953. These visitors can come into our country with a document known as a "laser visa" or "border crossing card", which is an alternative to a passport and must be obtained from the U.S. government. In the 1990s, the rule was that anyone who held such a document could travel up to 25 miles from the Mexico/U.S. border.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1999, Arizona and the Border Trade Alliance mounted a successful campaign to extend the mileage limit in Arizona to 75 miles because there is no large town within 25 miles of the Arizona/Mexico border, so Arizona wasn't getting the economic benefits of these travelers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Similarly, there is no large town within 25 miles of the New Mexico/Mexico border, so my constituents do not get the economic benefits of laser visa travelers. This disparity needs to be corrected. Moreover, all four Southwest border States should see the same benefits of laser visa travelers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Therefore, the bill I am introducing today extends the distance laser visa holders can travel into the United States to 100 miles, regardless of which State they are in. Such an extension will allow more towns in all four of our Southwest border States to reap the economic benefits of short-term visitors to our country who hold a travel document issued by our Federal Government.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="Introducing S. 1219. A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide taxpayer protection and assistance, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1219">S. 1219</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to introduce the "Taxpayer Protection and Assistance Act of 2007" with Senators Smith, Akaka, Durbin, Kerry, and Lieberman. My colleagues may recall that similar legislation, <bill type="s" number="832">S. 832</bill>, was introduced last Congress and ultimately reported out of the Finance Committee last year but unfortunately it never made it to the floor of the Senate. This Congress, the House has already passed taxpayer rights legislation  which makes me optimistic that many of these long overdue reforms may finally become law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This Act is a combination of a variety of well-vetted provisions that will ensure that our Nation's taxpayers are better able to prepare and file their tax returns each year in a fashion that is fair, reasonable and affordable. As long as we continue to require taxpayers to determine their own tax liability, Congress has a responsibility to ensure that we do not leave taxpayers vulnerable to abuses from those masquerading as tax professionals. The current environment is bad for everyone including  the majority of tax return preparers who provide professional and much needed services to taxpayers in their communities. I encourage all of my colleagues to work with us to pass this legislation before the next filing season begins.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The first section of the Taxpayer Protection and Assistance Act would create a $10 million matching grant program for lower income tax preparation clinics much like the program we currently have in place for tax controversies. I have seen first hand the impact free tax preparation clinics can have on taxpayers and their communities, as we are fortunate to have one of the best State-wide programs in the Nation in New Mexico. Tax Help New Mexico, which has been in operation for many years, helped  over 20,000 New Mexicans prepare and file their returns last year, resulting in over $20 million in refunds--all without refund anticipation loans. This program has turned into one of the best delivery mechanisms for public assistance I have seen in the State and has been fortunate</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The second set of provisions contained in this legislation would ensure that when taxpayers hire someone to help them with their tax returns they can be sure that the person is competent and professional. The first part of the bill makes sure that an enrolled agent, a tax professional licensed to practice before the IRS, shall have the exclusive right to describe him or herself as an "enrolled agent," "EA," or "E.A." In New Mexico, enrolled agents play an important role in helping taxpayers  with problems with the IRS and with preparing their returns. Enrolled agents have earned the right to use their credentials. Furthermore, we should protect the credentials of those who have taken the rigorous exams and have experience in tax preparation rather than allow others to confuse the public into thinking they too have the same credentials.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The next part of the bill requires the Secretary of the Treasury to determine what standards need to be met in order for a person to prepare tax returns commercially. Like all other tax professionals, this will require people who make a living preparing tax returns to pass a minimum competency exam and take brush up courses each year to keep up to date with changes in tax law. The majority of tax return preparers already meet these standards, including many who have received credentials from  the State or from a nationally recognized association of accountants or tax return preparers. We provide specific authority to the Secretary to determine whether people who have already taken a written proficiency exam as part of some other tax return credentialing will need to take the new exam. The Secretary will be  able to exercise these authorizations only after thorough review of the specific examination and only for</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The fourth set of provisions would directly address the problems with refund anticipation loans (RALs)--a problem throughout the country, but one that is particularly troublesome in New Mexico. First, this bill requires refund loan facilitators to register with the Treasury Department. Refund loan facilitators are those people who solicit, process, or otherwise facilitate the making of a refund anticipation loan in relation to a tax return being electronically filed. The legislation also requires  these refund loan facilitators to properly disclose to taxpayers that they do not have to get a RAL in order to file their return electronically, as well as clearly disclose what all the costs involved with the loan. Finally, the refund loan facilitators must disclose to taxpayers when the loans would allow their refunds to be offset by the amount of the loan. Much like the public</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The next section of the bill is an issue that my colleague from Hawaii, Senator AKAKA, has been actively working on for the last several years. This provision would authorize the Treasury Department to award grants to financial institutions or charitable groups that help low income taxpayers set up accounts at a bank or credit union. Because many taxpayers do not have checking or savings accounts, their refunds from IRS cannot be electronically wired to them. The alternative is to have  the check mailed to the taxpayer or to have the refund immediately loaned to the taxpayer in the form of a RAL. Of course, getting people to set up a checking or savings account for purposes of receiving their tax refund will also have the benefits of getting many of these people to start saving for the first time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, we have added two new provisions to clarify existing law. The first clarifies that the National Taxpayer Advocate has the authority to issue taxpayer assistance orders in cases involving closing agreements and compromises. The other clarifies that the Secretary of the Treasury has the authority to take into account a taxpayers specific facts and circumstances when evaluating an offer in compromise. Both of these provisions are the result of bipartisan negotiations and are an improvement  to our tax system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I hope my colleagues will join with me and the cosponsors of this bill to pass this important legislation. Our voluntary tax system is dependent on taxpayers being able to receive the best advice and assistance possible. We have a responsibility to our Nation's taxpayers to make sure that they do receive such advice and assistance. This bill goes a long way toward that goal.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400629" topic="Introducing S. 1222. A bill to stop mortgage transactions which operate to promote fraud, risk, abuse, and under-development, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1222">S. 1222</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to reintroduce legislation to protect American consumers and homeowners from fraudulent and abusive mortgage lending practices. Mortgage fraud and abuse are growing problems in this country, problems that are depriving thousands of Americans of their dream of homeownership and often their hard-earned life savings. These problems are also costing the mortgage industry hundreds of millions of dollars each year and making the housing market, which is critical  to our economy and the stability of our neighborhoods, more vulnerable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although the data in this area is limited, mortgage fraud, which takes a variety of forms from inflated appraisals to the use of straw buyers, is a growing problem. In September of 2002, the FBI had 436 mortgage fraud investigations. Currently, they have more than 1,036--an increase of 137 percent in less than 5 years. And of the 1,036 current cases, more than half have expected losses of more than $1 million. This is due largely to the housing boom which has driven up housing prices across the  country. Nearly $2.37 trillion in mortgage loans were made during 2006, and the number may be even higher this year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But mortgage fraud is not just about dollars and statistics; it's about real people, real homes, and real lives. I first introduced this legislation last year after my hometown Chicago Tribune featured a series of articles about mortgage fraud in Illinois, which, along with Georgia, South Carolina, Florida, Missouri, Michigan, California, Nevada, Colorado and Utah, is among the FBI's top-ten mortgage fraud "hot spots."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Tribune stories highlighted the plight of the good folks on May Street in Chicago, who saw a block's worth of homes go boarded up in the span of a just few years, as swindlers racked up hundreds of thousands of dollars in bad loans. The shells of houses were left behind as sad reminders of broken dreams. The Tribune highlighted the plight of 75-year-old Ruth Williams, who had to spend her personal funds to clear the title to her home after fraudsters secured $400,000 in loans on three buildings  they didn't own. A recent Tribune investigation turned up a 91-year-old woman defrauded into signing away her brick Chicago home, her sole asset, leaving her with nothing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Law enforcement, consumer groups and many in the mortgage industry are working extremely hard to combat fraud and abusive lending practices. I applaud their good work. Now, Congress should come to the table and do its part, and I'm pleased to introduce legislation today with my good friend Senator Durbin to address this important issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The STOP FRAUD Act, which was first introduced in February 2006, is aimed at stopping mortgage transactions which operate to promote fraud, risk, abuse and underdevelopment. This year, the bill includes new provisions to protect the legal rights of borrowers with particularly risky subprime loans. The Act provides the first Federal definition of mortgage fraud and authorizes stiff criminal penalties against fraudulent actors. STOP FRAUD requires a wide range of mortgage professionals to report  suspected fraudulent activity, and gives these same professionals safe harbor from liability when they report suspicious incidents. It also authorizes several grant programs to help State and local law enforcement fight fraud, provide the mortgage industry with updates on fraud trends, and further support the Departments of Treasury, Justice and Housing and Urban Development's fraud-fighting efforts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At a time when many homeowners are concerned about losing their home to foreclosure, and policymakers are worried about fraudulent, deceptive, and even just plain confusing lending practices that are roiling communities across the country, STOP FRAUD provides $25 million for housing counseling. The Department of Housing and Urban Development will contract with public or private organization to provide information, advice, counseling, and technical assistance to tenants, homeowners, and other  consumers with respect to mortgage fraud and other activities that are likely to increase the risk of foreclosure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Act also protects the legal rights of borrowers with risky, subprime loans. The greatest growth in the mortgage lending market is in subprime loans and some have estimated that more than 2 million homeowners with subprime mortgages are at risk of losing their homes. If a borrower receives a subprime mortgage with any one of several high-risk characteristics, the Act protects the rights of borrowers to challenge lending practices in foreclosure proceedings. The high-risk characteristics targeted  by this Act include loans for which the borrower does not have the ability to repay at the maximum rate of interest, loans whose true long-term costs are not clearly disclosed to the borrower, stated-income and no-documentation loans, and loans with unreasonable prepayment penalties.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many States are actively trying to prevent a wave of expected foreclosures as housing prices stop rising while adjustable rates on many risk loans start rising. STOP FRAUD instructs the Government Accountability Office to evaluate the various State initiatives and report to Congress on lending practices and regulations related to mortgage fraud and deception, predatory lending, and homeownership preservation efforts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We cannot sit on the sidelines while increasing numbers of American families face the risk of losing their homes. There is excellent work being done by the Banking Committees in the House and Senate to tackle some of the thorniest and most challenging problems affecting the mortgage industry today. I look forward to working with my colleagues on comprehensive legislation to protect consumers and strengthen the housing market. The STOP FRAUD Act is just the beginning of an important Federal response.  It is a tough, cost-effective, and balanced way to address the serious problem of mortgage fraud in our country and to provide additional protections for vulnerable borrowers. I urge my colleagues to join me in this important effort.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300063" topic="Introducing S. 1223. A bill to amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to support efforts by local or regional television or radio broadcasters to provide essential public information programming in the event of a major disaster, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1223">S. 1223</bill>] Mr. President, I come to the floor to speak about the First Response Broadcasters Act, legislation I am introducing today along with Senators Stevens, Carper and Pryor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As my State suffered the devastating impact of Hurricanes Katrina and Rita and the levee breaks that followed, we learned that one of the most vital relief supplies is information. In providing it, all of our local media--newspapers, broadcasters and web sites included--did amazing work to keep the people of my State informed, even when displaced thousands of miles away. But with phone lines down and streets too flooded to move around, the sound of a local radio or television station was for  many of my constituents the only voice in those first few dark nights after the hurricanes. Our local broadcasters provided life-saving information and comfort when both were needed the most. Many of them worked through unimaginable technical and emotional obstacles, staying on the air as their facilities and staff homes were destroyed, and loved ones remained missing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With the entire industry dependent on public airwaves, broadcasters have a duty to serve the public in times of crisis. As local radio and television stations stand up, as so many did, to put commercial interests aside to serve the public interest, the federal government  should be ready to stand with them. This is not a new partnership.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under laws going back to 1951, radio and television stations are today required to participate in the national Emergency Alert System (EAS), and many stations have protected, government-funded circuits connecting them to emergency command centers. This legislation would directly connect more stations nationwide to this network by authorizing $6.5 million to FEMA to set up Primary Entry Point radio stations in another twenty five states and U.S. territories. Currently there are thirty-two stations  and two under development in Alabama and Mississippi.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A Primary Entry Point (PEP) station is a radio broadcast station designated to provide public information following national and local emergencies where there is no commercial power. For example, WWL Radio in New Orleans was the only PEP station in the Gulf Coast after Katrina and it provided radio broadcasts for two weeks after the storm until commercial power was restored. FEMA commissioned recommendations from the Primary Entry Point Advisory Committee, a non-profit group they set up to oversee  the stations, and just needs the additional funds to build the additional facilities. Included in the findings of the legislation is a comprehensive list of the states that are currently without PEP stations and which would benefit from this provision. There are also States which have PEP stations, but because of geographic limitations, require an additional station to fully cover the State. This bill would provide those two additional stations in Kansas and Florida.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But what good is this successful emergency information chain if the last link fails? By technical necessity, this last link is right in the disaster's path. Simply put, the transmitter needs to be in the same area as the people in need of warning. Despite our Federal investments in the emergency system and entry point stations, there were several Gulf Coast broadcasters after the hurricanes that could not stay on the air simply because the government took their fuel away. They were told they  weren't on the list."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation puts these broadcasters on the list, where they belong. To protect vital broadcast infrastructure and encourage more broadcasters to deploy disaster-resistant telecommunications equipment, this bill would also create a 3-year pilot program managed by the Federal Emergency Management Agency to provide annual matching grants to qualified First Response Broadcasters for the protection and reinforcement of critical-to-air facilities and infrastructure. The program would receive $10  million per year to fund matching program grants, and grants could also be used for projects to enhance essential disaster-related public information services.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As the program encourages both disaster preparedness and community coordination, increased scoring would be granted to applications from broadcasters who form cooperative proposals with other broadcasters in the area or those who submit plans in conjunction with local or State governments. Priority scoring would also be given to applicants in disaster-prone areas and also based on the public service merits of the broadcasters disaster programming plan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>No disaster warning, evacuation plan or emergency instruction matters if it can't get to the people who need it. This is why the Federal Communications Commission and a presidential advisory panel have each recommended we take steps to keep these lifesaving broadcasts on the air.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In particular, this bill would require that the Federal Emergency Management Agency and other Federal response agencies, in coordination with State and local authorities and the National Guard, honor press access guidelines and credentials set by the local governing authority in the declared disaster area. For example, if the City of New Orleans issued press credentials before the disaster and the city decided to continue honoring them post-disaster, FEMA officials operating in the area would  be required to honor those credentials as well. The local entity, at its own discretion, would be able to request that this credentialing authority be passed instead to federal or state officials.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Along these same lines, the bill would also direct the Federal Emergency Management Agency to coordinate with local and State agencies to allow access, where practicable and not impeding recovery or endangering public safety, into the disaster area for personnel and equipment essential to restoring or maintaining critical-to-air broadcast infrastructure. The priority policies and procedures for this coordination would be similar to those practiced for restoring public utilities, and would include  access for refueling generators and re-supplying critical facilities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For all journalists working to tell the story-newspapers and web sites included-the First Response Broadcasters Act makes sure that the local officials, who know local reporters best, decide where the journalists can go, not some Washington bureaucrat who just stepped off the plane.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In closing, I would like to submit for the record the stories of a few incredible broadcasters who through recent disasters have demonstrated exactly the type of response this bill is intended to encourage. I would also like to submit for the record a list of organizations which have already endorsed this legislation-including the state broadcasting associations from every one of the 50 states and the District of Columbia.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Broadcasters have a duty to the American people to spread the word in times of crisis. No one else can do it. They are already a key part of our national emergency response plan, and have been for more than 50 years. This bill merely reinforces this fact and secures the logical extension of commitments already made by Federal government. We have a responsibility to make sure the tools are protected to make the system work.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Broadcasters are first responders--and with this bill today, we will strengthen our essential partnership with them for the benefit of all Americans. I urge my colleagues to support this important legislation and ask unanimous consent that the text of the legislation, the broadcaster stories, and a list of the organizations already supporting this bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300013" topic="Introducing S.J. Res. 12. A joint resolution providing for the recognition of Jerusalem as the undivided capital of Israel before the United States recognizes a Palestinian state, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Foreign Relations.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="sj" number="12">S.J. Res. 12</bill>] Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the text of the joint resolution be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the joint resolution was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
</record>
