<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1196960402" ordinal="62" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <narrative>AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET -- (Senate - December 06, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="14998">S14998</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, December 6, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. in order to conduct a hearing on foreign assistance to Pakistan.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate, in order to conduct an Executive Business Meeting on Thursday, December 6, 2007, at 10 a.m. in room SD-226 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Agenda</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I. Bills: <bill type="s" number="352">S.352</bill>, Sunshine in the Courtroom Act of 2007 (Grassley, Schumer, Leahy, Specter, Graham, Feingold, Cornyn, Durbin); <bill type="s" number="344">S.344</bill>, A bill to permit the televising of Supreme Court proceedings (Specter, Grassley, Durbin, Schumer, Feingold, Cornyn); <bill type="s" number="1638">S.1638</bill>, Federal Judicial Salary Restoration Act of 2007 (Leahy, Hatch, Feinstein, Graham, Kennedy); <bill type="s" number="1829">S.1829</bill>, Protect Our Children First Act of 2007 (Leahy, Hatch); <bill type="s" number="431">S.431</bill>, Keeping the Internet Devoid of Sexual Predators Act of 2007 (Schumer, McCain,  Grassley, Specter, Kyl); and <bill type="s" number="2344">S.2344</bill>, Internet Safety Education Act of 2007 (Menendez).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>II. Nomination: Ronald Jay Tenpas to be Assistant Attorney General for the Environment and Natural Resources Division, Department of Justice.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON READINESS AND MANAGEMENT SUPPORT">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on Readiness and Management Support of the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday December 6, 2007, at 2:30 p.m., in open session to receive a report of the Commission on Army Acquisition and Program Management in Expeditionary Operations.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
