<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1227200405" ordinal="84" title="EXECUTIVE CALENDAR AND NOMINATIONS DISCHARGED">
  <narrative>EXECUTIVE CALENDAR AND NOMINATIONS DISCHARGED -- (Senate - November 20, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="10765">S10765</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300037" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the Senate consider Calendar No. 757, the nomination of William Carr; and that the Judiciary Committee be discharged of PN1113, the nomination of Ricardo H. Hinojosa; that the Senate proceed en bloc to their consideration; that the nominations be confirmed en bloc; the motions to reconsider be laid on the table en bloc; that any statements related  thereto be printed in the RECORD; that no further motions  be in order; and that the President be immediately notified of the Senate's actions.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The nominations considered and confirmed en bloc are as follows:</chair>
  <chair>William B. Carr, Jr., of Pennsylvania, to be a Member of the United States Sentencing Commission for a term expiring October 31, 2011.</chair>
  <chair>Ricardo H. Hinojosa, of Texas, to be a Member of the United States Sentencing Commission for a term expiring October 31, 2013.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300037" topic="UNITED STATES SENTENCING COMMISSION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Foreign Relations Committee be discharged of PN730; the HELP Committee be discharged of PN2019, PN2020, PN2022, PN2132, PN2024, PN2104, and PN2119; and the Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee be discharged of PN2058 and PN2086; and that the Senate proceed en bloc to their consideration; that the nominations be confirmed en bloc, and the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table; that no further motions be in order,  and any statements relating to the nominations be printed in the Record; that the President be immediately notified of the Senate's action, and the Senate return to legislative session.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The nominations considered and confirmed en bloc are as follows:</chair>
  <chair>Gene Allan Cretz, of New York, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotenitiary of the United States of America to Libya.</chair>
  <chair>Douglas D. Randall, of Missouri, to be a Member of the National Science Board, National Science Foundation, for a term expiring May 10, 2014.</chair>
  <chair>Ray M. Bowen, of Texas, to be a Member of the National Science Board, National Science Foundation, for a term expiring May 10, 2014.</chair>
  <chair>France A. Cordova, of Indiana, to be a Member of the National Science Board, National Science Foundation, for a term expiring May 10, 2014.</chair>
  <chair>To be medical director&lt;br&gt;Paul J. Andreason</chair>
  <chair>To be senior surgeon&lt;br&gt;Kenneth L. Brooks</chair>
  <chair>To be surgeon&lt;br&gt;Anthony M. Dunnigan</chair>
  <chair>To be senior assistant surgeon&lt;br&gt;Daisy Y. Eng</chair>
  <chair>To be dental director&lt;br&gt;Michael C. Arnold</chair>
  <chair>To be senior dental surgeon &lt;br&gt;Anita Arnold</chair>
  <chair>To be dental surgeon &lt;br&gt;Ruben S. Acuna</chair>
  <chair>To be nurse director &lt;br&gt;Ana Marie L. Balingit-Wines</chair>
  <chair>To be senior nurse officer &lt;br&gt;Victoria L. Anderson</chair>
  <chair>To be nurse officer &lt;br&gt;Dawn A. Anderson-Gary</chair>
  <chair>To be senior assistant nurse officer&lt;br&gt;Mark D. Cruz</chair>
  <chair>To be assistant nurse officer &lt;br&gt;James K. Lyons</chair>
  <chair>To be engineer director &lt;br&gt;David M. Apanian</chair>
  <chair>To be senior engineer officer &lt;br&gt;Steven L. Bosiljevac</chair>
  <chair>To be engineer officer&lt;br&gt;Steven J. Dykstra</chair>
  <chair>To be senior assistant engineer officer &lt;br&gt;Sean T. Bush</chair>
  <chair>To be scientist director &lt;br&gt;Peter I. Hartsock</chair>
  <chair>To be senior scientist &lt;br&gt;Christine J. Benally</chair>
  <chair>To be scientist &lt;br&gt;Rachel N. Avchen</chair>
  <chair>To be environmental health officer director &lt;br&gt;Alan S. Echt</chair>
  <chair>To be senior environmental health officer&lt;br&gt;Eric J. Esswein</chair>
  <chair>To be environmental health officer &lt;br&gt;Charles M. Blue</chair>
  <chair>To be senior assistant environmental health officer &lt;br&gt;Robert A. Gibbs</chair>
  <chair>To be veterinary director &lt;br&gt;Sean F. Altekruse</chair>
  <chair>To be senior veterinary officer &lt;br&gt;Terri R. Clark</chair>
  <chair>To be veterinary officer &lt;br&gt;Gregory L. Langham</chair>
  <chair>To be pharmacist director &lt;br&gt;J. R. Eric Edwards</chair>
  <chair>To be senior pharmacist &lt;br&gt;Christine Hee-Kyung Chung</chair>
  <chair>To be pharmacist &lt;br&gt;Matthew R. Baker</chair>
  <chair>To be senior dietitian &lt;br&gt;Juli M. Haws</chair>
  <chair>To be dietitian &lt;br&gt;Robert M. Collison</chair>
  <chair>To be senior therapist &lt;br&gt;Jessie Whitehurst</chair>
  <chair>To be therapist&lt;br&gt;Corey S. Dahl</chair>
  <chair>To be health services director &lt;br&gt;William M. Gosman</chair>
  <chair>To be senior health services officer &lt;br&gt;Carol E. Auten</chair>
  <chair>To be health services officer &lt;br&gt;David J. Bellware</chair>
  <chair>To bie senior assistant health services officer &lt;br&gt;Brian T. Burt</chair>
  <chair>G.P. Peterson of Colorado, to be a Member of the National Science Board, National Science Foundation, for a term expiring May 10, 2014.</chair>
  <chair>Barbara Ernst Prey, of New York, to be a Member of the National Council on the Arts for a term expiring September 3, 2014.</chair>
  <chair>To be medical director &lt;br&gt;Matthew T. McKenna</chair>
  <chair>To be senior surgeon&lt;br&gt;Timothy R. Cote</chair>
  <chair>To be surgeon &lt;br&gt;Henry C. Baggett III</chair>
  <chair>To be senior assistant surgeon &lt;br&gt;Scott J. Filler</chair>
  <chair>To be senior dental surgeon &lt;br&gt;Seyed H. Mortazavi</chair>
  <chair>To be dental surgeon &lt;br&gt;Juan K. Packer</chair>
  <chair>To be senior assistant dental surgeon &lt;br&gt;Jodine C. Anderson</chair>
  <chair>To be nurse director &lt;br&gt;Holly A. Williams</chair>
  <chair>To be senior nurse officer &lt;br&gt;Ann M. McCarthy</chair>
  <chair>To be nurse officer &lt;br&gt;Kristal E. Dye</chair>
  <chair>To be senior assistant nurse officer &lt;br&gt;Anne M. Arceo</chair>
  <chair>To be engineer officer &lt;br&gt;Jeffrey A. Murray</chair>
  <chair>To be senior assistant engineer officer &lt;br&gt;Varsha B. Savalia</chair>
  <chair>To be scientist &lt;br&gt;David J. McIntyre</chair>
  <chair>To be senior environmental health officer &lt;br&gt;Paul M. Lewis</chair>
  <chair>To be environmental health officer &lt;br&gt;Brian L. Lewelling</chair>
  <chair>To be senior assistant environmental health officer &lt;br&gt;Jeffrey T. Dickson</chair>
  <chair>To be pharmacist &lt;br&gt;Steven A. Labrozzi</chair>
  <chair>To be senior assistant pharmacist &lt;br&gt;Kristina J. Ballinger</chair>
  <chair>To be senior assistant therapist &lt;br&gt;James M. Cowher</chair>
  <chair>To be health services officer director &lt;br&gt;Clifford D. Brown</chair>
  <chair>To be health services officer &lt;br&gt;Irwin W. Fish</chair>
  <chair>To be senior assistant health services officer &lt;br&gt;Julia H. Bryan</chair>
  <chair>To be junior assistant health services officer &lt;br&gt;Kristi R. Anderson</chair>
  <chair>Alfred S. Irving, Jr., of the District of Columbia, to be an Associate Judge of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia for the term of fifteen years.</chair>
  <chair>Kathryn A. Oberly, of the District of Columbia, to be an Associate Judge of the District of Columbia Court of Appeals for the term of fifteen years.</chair>
</record>
