<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1171515600" ordinal="28" title="HAPPY BIRTHDAY, SENATOR KENNEDY">
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, President John F. Kennedy was fond of quoting the Biblical passage of the New Testament:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For unto whomsoever much is given of him shall be much required.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That was quoted from the 12th chapter of the Gospel of St. Luke, verse 48, the King James version.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When I think of that passage, I think of the life, the career, and the accomplishments thus far of my dear friend, my dear friend and colleague, Senator TED KENNEDY, who will turn 75 years old--Oh, to be 75 again--he will turn 75 years old, on February 22. The Senate will be out of session on February 22.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When TED KENNEDY came to the Senate in 1962, I would already have been here 4 years. So when he, TED KENNEDY, came to the Senate in 1962, much had already been given to Senator TED KENNEDY. He had been born into a wealthy and remarkably, remarkably talented family. His father, a financial genius, had been an Ambassador to England--think of that, Ambassador to England--and  the very first Commissioner of the Securities and Exchange Commission.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One of his brothers, one of TED KENNEDY's brothers, had been a Senator--I can see him now, as it were--and was then President of the United States, but had been a Senator. Another brother was the Attorney General of the United States, and would eventually join TED in the Senate in 1965.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As for Senator EDWARD "TED" KENNEDY, himself, he had attended two of our country's premier educational institutions, Harvard College, and, yes, the University of Virginia. And he, TED KENNEDY, had already accumulated a lifetime of political experience by the tender age of 30 when he came to this Senate. How remarkable--just burst upon the landscape. I remember. Therefore, as the Scripture tells us, we had a right to expect much from TED KENNEDY when he came to the Senate.  We had a right to expect much. What about our expectations? He delivered. He delivered.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the Senate, TED KENNEDY became the heart and the conscience, yes, of American liberalism. And he has been one of the most effective--I know. I have been here. I have watched him. I did not particularly like him at the beginning. He did not like me. Each of us knew that. We did not care who else knew it. It did not matter.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the Senate, Senator Kennedy became the heart and the conscience of American liberalism. He has been one of the most effective national legislators--read the RECORD; read the history of the Senate--he has been one of the most effective national legislators of the 20th century. And as one who knows something about American history and the history of the Senate, he has been one of the most effective national legislators of all time in the Senate. I have not lived all time, but  I know something about all time. I know something about the Senate and know something about the history of the Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>TED KENNEDY has been one of the most effective national legislators of the 20th century or of all time as far as this Republic stands. His imprint is on nearly every piece of progressive legislation crafted during the past 45 years. I will read that again. I want to make sure I believe that myself. His imprint is on nearly every piece of progressive legislation crafted during the past 45 years: the Occupational Safety and Health Act, OSHA; the Voting Rights Act; the Age Discrimination  Act; the Freedom of Information Act; the Americans with Disabilities Act; health care reform; increases in the Federal minimum wage. These are but a few of his, TED KENNEDY's, legislative monuments. Additionally, he has been among those few at the very forefront of promoting women's rights and women's equality.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He, EDWARD M. KENNEDY, TED KENNEDY, is the Senate's Mr. Health Care. He is the Senate's Mr. Civil Rights, to a great extent. He is the Senate's Mr. Human Rights. As his Senate record reveals, Senator Kennedy is a man--a Senator--of remarkable compassion, who has labored mightily on behalf of his fellow citizens.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although born to a life of privilege, TED KENNEDY has dedicated his life--if  I ever saw a dedication to public service--dedicated his life to public service.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Senator" name="M, EDWARD" of="">
    <paragraph>KENNEDY, TED KENNEDY, has spent more than half of his life in the Senate. I have done that, too. I was just contemplating and figuring in my head. Yes, that is a long time. He has spent more than half of his life in the Senate, yes. Yes, I have spent more than half of mine, but I am not the subject of this.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He, TED KENNEDY, is now second in seniority in the Senate. He, TED KENNEDY, is the third longest serving Senator in the history of the United States of America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As I wish my dear friend TED KENNEDY the happiest of birthdays, perhaps I should point out that our relationship--his and mine--did not begin--I think I have already hinted at that--on the friendliest of terms. I first encountered TED KENNEDY during the bitter and famous 1960 West Virginia Democratic primary. TED KENNEDY was in the State helping his brother John F. Kennedy, who was running for President. I, ROBERT C. BYRD, was supporting the other guy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1971, he, TED KENNEDY, was running for reelection to his position as the Senate Democratic whip. Again, I supported the other guy--me.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1976, I was running for the position of Senate majority leader. This time, he, TED KENNEDY, was supporting the other guy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This hardly seemed the beginning of a beautiful relationship, but it was.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>During our service together in the Senate, I came to admire TED KENNEDY--yes, I came to admire him--as a dedicated Senator of incredible tenacity and admirable legislative skills. I found him to be an indefatigable worker who could accomplish, yes, what seemed to be legislative miracles. Sometimes they were.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I, personally, will always be grateful for the support, the unstinting support, that Senator TED KENNEDY gave to me during the years that it was my privilege to serve, yes, serve as the Senate Democratic leader. And I was. I was the leader, the Senate Democratic leader. When times got tough, as they sometimes do for a Senate leader, I knew that I could always count--I could always count; yes, even without asking him, I knew where he stood--I could always count on him. It may have been  a needed vote. It may have been his assistance in building support for a legislative proposal. Whatever was needed, he, EDWARD M. KENNEDY, TED, was there.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He was there, he was always there for me, and I am grateful. As a result, our friendship has developed and strengthened.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today I am proud to call Ted Kennedy one of my best and dearest friends. I have to say he is my best and dearest friend. I will always value his friendship. I especially appreciate the way he has extended that friendship not only to me but also to all the people of West Virginia. And he did much of that before he became a friend of mine.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I close this brief statement about admiration for Ted Kennedy with these words:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator TED KENNEDY is a public servant. He is a dedicated legislator. He is a great Senator of our times who endeavors to live for his fellow man.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Happy birthday, TED KENNEDY. God bless you. Because of you, we are a better country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
  <chair> The Senator from Montana.</chair>
</record>
