<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1202230801" ordinal="47" title="DESIGNATING FEBRUARY 2008 AS &quot;GO DIRECT MONTH&quot;">
  <narrative>DESIGNATING FEBRUARY 2008 AS "GO DIRECT MONTH" -- (Senate - February 05, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="671">S671</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the consideration of <bill type="sr" number="443">S. Res. 443</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <chair>The assistant legislative clerk read as follows:</chair>
  <chair>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="443">S. Res. 443</bill>) designating February 2008 as "Go Direct Month."</chair>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="443">S. Res. 443</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="443">S. Res. 443</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas, in fiscal year 2007, nearly 60,000 checks issued by the Department of the Treasury, worth approximately $56,000,000, were endorsed by forgery;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Department of the Treasury receives approximately 1,400,000 inquiries each year regarding problems with paper checks;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, each month, nearly 12,000,000 social security and other Federal benefit payments are made with checks;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the United States would generate approximately $132,000,000 in annual savings if all Federal benefit checks were paid by direct deposit;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the use of direct deposit is a more secure, reliable, and cost-effective method of payment than paper checks because the use of direct deposit--</chair>
  <chair>(1) helps protect against identity theft and fraud;</chair>
  <chair>(2) provides easier access to funds during emergencies and natural disasters; and</chair>
  <chair>(3) provides the people of the United States with more control over their money;</chair>
  <chair>Whereas the Department of the Treasury and the Federal Reserve Banks have launched Go Direct, a national campaign to motivate people who receive Federal benefit payments to use direct deposit to receive those payments;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Go Direct works with more than 1,100 partners across the Nation, including financial institutions, advocacy groups, and community organizations;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas more than 130 financial institutions representing 25,000 branches nationwide participated in the 2007 "</chair>
  <chair>Go Direct Champions" competition to encourage the use of direct deposit among people who receive Federal benefit payments; and</chair>
  <chair>Whereas more than 1,600,000 people in the United States have switched from paper checks to direct deposit to receive Federal benefit payments since Go Direct launched in the fall of 2004: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) designates February 2008 as "</chair>
  <chair>Go Direct Month";</chair>
  <chair> (2) supports the goals and ideals of the Go Direct campaign;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) commends Federal, State, and local governments, nonprofit agencies, and the private sector for promoting February as Go Direct Month; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) encourages people in the United States who are eligible to receive social security or other Federal benefit payments to--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) participate in events and awareness initiatives held during the month of February with respect to using direct deposit;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) become informed about the convenience and safety of direct deposit; and</chair>
  <chair> (C) consider signing up for direct deposit of social security or other Federal benefit payments. &lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
