<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1193068802" ordinal="5" title="SCHEDULE">
  <narrative>SCHEDULE -- (Senate - October 22, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="13169">S13169</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today following the remarks of the two leaders, the Senate will conduct a period of morning business for 1 hour. The time in morning business will be equally divided and controlled between the leaders or their designees. The Senate will then resume the Labor appropriations bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that after the morning business time has expired, whatever time Senator McConnell and I may use will not be deemed to go against the morning business for other Senators.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="ORDER OF PROCEDURE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, last Friday there was a 1 p.m. filing deadline for first-degree amendments to the bill. Today we should have a good idea of which amendments will be offered and will require rollcall votes. The Senate will vote today at 5:30 and there could be more than one rollcall vote. We will complete action on this bill tomorrow morning, so Members should be prepared to cast a number of votes prior to the Senate recessing for the caucus luncheons on Tuesday.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have had my staff check with the managers of the bill and their staffs, and there could be anywhere from one to five votes tonight. It is up to the managers of this bill. Senators will be advised of that at some subsequent time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I note the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <chair>The assistant legislative clerk proceeded to call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="ORDER OF PROCEDURE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
