<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1184212800" ordinal="42" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <narrative>AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET -- (Senate - July 12, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="9184">S9184</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="AD HOC SUBCOMMITTEE ON STATE, LOCAL AND PRIVATE SECTOR FOR PREPAREDNESS AND INTEGRATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Ad Hoc Subcommittee on State, Local, and Private Sector Preparedness and Integration of the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs be authorized to meet on Thursday, July 12, 2007, at 2 p.m., in order to conduct a hearing entitled "Private Sector Preparedness, Part II: protecting our critical infrastructure."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Thursday, July 12, 2007, at 10 a.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This hearing will address issues relating to telephone number portability.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND NATURAL RESOURCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Thursday, July 12, 2007, at 9:30 a.m. in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of this hearing is to consider the nominations of Clarence H. Albright, of South Carolina, to be Under Secretary of Energy; Lisa E. Epifani, of Texas, to be an Assistant Secretary of Energy for Congressional and Intergovernmental Affairs; James L. Caswell, of Idaho, to be Director of the Bureau of Land Management; and Brent T. Wahlquist of Pennsylvania, to be Director of the Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="COMMITTEE ON FINANCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Finance be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, July 12, 2007, at 10 a.m., in room 215 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building, to hear testimony on "Airport Airways Trust Fund: The Future of Aviation Financing."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="COMMITTEE ON HEALTH, EDUCATION, LABOR AND PENSIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions be authorized to hold a hearing on the nomination of Dr. James W. Holsinger to be Medical Director and Surgeon General of the Public Health Service, Department of  Health and Human Services during the session of the Senate on Thursday, July 12, 2007 at 10 a.m., room G50 of the Dirksen Senate office building.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="COMMITTEE ON INDIAN AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Indian Affairs be authorized to meet on Thursday, July 12, 2007, at 9:30 a.m. in room 485 of the Russell Senate Office Building to conduct an oversight hearing on transportation issues in Indian country.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet to conduct a markup session on Thursday, July 12, 2007, at 10 a.m. in Dirksen room 226.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Agenda</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I. Bills</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="1145">S.1145</bill>, Patent Reform Act of 2007, (Leahy, Hatch, Schumer, Cornyn, Whitehouse);</paragraph>
    <paragraph>S.--, School Safety and Law Enforcement Improvements Act, (Chairman's mark);</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="1060">S. 1060</bill>, Recidivism Reduction &amp; Second Chance Act of 2007, (Biden, Specter, Brownback, Leahy, Kennedy, Schumer, Whitehouse, Durbin)</paragraph>
    <paragraph>II. Nominations </paragraph>
    <paragraph>William Lindsay Osteen, Jr. to be United States District Judge for the Middle District of North Carolina; Martin Karl Reidinger to be United States District Judge for the Western District of North Carolina; Timothy D. DeGiusti to be United States District Judge for the Western District of Oklahoma; Janis Lynn Sammartino to be United States District Judge for the Southern District of California.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>III. Resolutions </paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="sr" number="248">S. Res. 248</bill>, Honoring the life and achievements of Dame Lois Browne Evans (Brown);</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Res. 236, Supporting the goals and ideals of the National Anthem Project (Bayh, Craig, Kennedy, Cardin, Durbin).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="PERMANENT SUBCOMMITTEE ON INVESTIGATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations of the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs be authorized to meet on Thursday, July 12, 2007, at 9 a.m., in order to conduct a hearing entitled "Dirty Bomb Vulnerabilities: fake companies, fake licenses, real consequences."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="SELECT COMMITTEE ON INTELLIGENCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Select Committee on Intelligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on July 12, 2007 at 2:30 p.m., to hold a closed hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON NATIONAL PARKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on National Parks of the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Thursday, July 12, 2007, at 2:30 p.m., in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the hearing is to receive testimony on the following bills: <bill type="s" number="488">S. 488</bill> and <bill type="h" number="1100">H.R. 1100</bill>, to revise the boundary of the Carl Sandburg Home National Historic Site in the State of North Carolina; <bill type="s" number="617">S. 617</bill>, to make the National Parks and Federal Recreational Lands Pass available at a discount to certain veterans; <bill type="s" number="824">S. 824</bill> and <bill type="h" number="995">H.R. 995</bill>, to amend Public Law 106-348 to extend the authorization for establishing a memorial in the District of Columbia or its environs to honor veterans who became disabled  while serving in the Armed Forces of the United States; <bill type="s" number="955">S. 955</bill>, to establish the Abraham Lincoln National Heritage Area; <bill type="s" number="1148">S. 1148</bill>, to establish the Champlain Quadricentennial Commemoration Commission and the Hudson-Fulton 400th Commemoration Commission; <bill type="s" number="1182">S. 1182</bill>, to amend the Quinebaug and Shetucket Rivers Valley National Heritage Corridor Act of 1994 to increase the authorization of appropriations and modify the date on which the authority of the Secretary</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON SECURITIES, INSURANCE, AND INVESTMENT">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, Subcommittee on Securities, Insurance, and Investment be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on July 12, 2007, at l0 a.m., to conduct a hearing entitled "A Global View: Examining Cross-Border Exchange Mergers."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
