<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1177603218" ordinal="57" title="STATEMENTS ON INTRODUCED BILLS AND JOINT RESOLUTIONS--APRIL 25, 2007">
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="Introducing S. 1224. A bill to amend title XXI of the Social Security Act to reauthorize the State Children's Health Insurance Program, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1224">S. 1224</bill>] Mr. President, when we enacted the Children's Health Insurance Program a decade ago, we made a promise to low-income working families to assist them in obtaining health insurance coverage for their children, and we must continue to keep that promise. Today, with Senators Rockefeller and Snowe, I am pleased to introduce The Children's Health Insurance Program Reauthorization Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>CHIP has been a significant success, and has made a real difference in many children's lives. Over the past decade, the percentage of uninsured children has dropped dramatically, even though more and more of their parents have been losing coverage because employers decide to reduce it or drop it entirely.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In its first year, the program enrolled nearly a million children, and enrollment has grown ever since. Average monthly enrollment is now 4 million, and over 6 million have been enrolled for at least part of the year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We know CHIP has made a difference in the lives of millions of children, but we also know that this is no time to rest on past success. We can and must do more to enroll the 6 million uninsured children who are eligible but not enrolled for CHIP and Medicaid, and to expand coverage so that all children can obtain the health care they need.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill we are introducing today reauthorizes the program and it will make sure that states have enough funds to provide health care to all children who need this assistance. No parents should be faced with the impossible decision of whether they can afford to take their sick child to the doctor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill establishes a strong, reliable financing structure for CHIP. It more than doubles the Federal resources currently available over the next 5 years for covering children through CHIP. It ensures that all states will have the Federal matching funds needed both to sustain their existing programs and to move forward to cover the millions of children who are eligible for CHIP and Medicaid but remain unenrolled.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Millions of uninsured children in America isn't just wrong. It's unacceptable. We need to act now in getting to guarantee them the health coverage they need.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill adopts a variety of approaches to help states increase their enrollment. It strengthens CHIP by expanding the current program, improving its outreach, and making sure that all children have access to dental care and mental health services, so that good health care can be a reality for every child in America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Quality health care for children isn't just a good option or a nice idea. It's not merely something we wish we could do. It's something we have to do. It's an obligation. We started earlier this year by pledging what is needed in the budget, but we also need a CHIP reauthorization that gives children the coverage we've promised them for the healthy future they deserve. The bill we're introducing today does that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There's a reason the CHIP program has always enjoyed bipartisan support.  It's because all of us know how important it is that all children have the chance to get a healthy start in life. I look forward to working to make sure all children get the health care they need, and I urge my colleagues to support this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300084" topic="Introducing S. 1224. A bill to amend title XXI of the Social Security Act to reauthorize the State Children's Health Insurance Program, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, this week is Cover the Uninsured Week. And, I cannot think of a more appropriate time to introduce the legislation that Senators Olympia Snowe, Ted Kennedy, and I introduced yesterday--the Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP) Reauthorization Act of 2007 (<bill type="s" number="1224">S. 1224</bill>). There are more than 45 million uninsured people in our country today, and 9 million of them--20 percent--are children. This is an embarrassing statistic for the wealthiest country  in the world, and it has catastrophic consequences for our children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1964, when I first came to West Virginia as a VISTA volunteer in Emmons, I was shocked to learn that many of the school-age children living there had never been to a dentist before. I made raising health care standards one of my first priorities in Emmons, and we ultimately got a bus to bring children to the Tiskelwah grade school in Charleston for dental care. Now, more than 30 years later, there are still children in West Virginia and throughout the Nation without access to adequate dental  care.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Several weeks ago, millions across the country mourned the death of twelve year old Deamonte Driver, whose lack of dental care led to fatal brain infection. His death was a sad reminder of how our country continues to fail in its efforts to ensure access to vital medical care for our nation's youth. Yet, Deamonte was not the only child to succumb to the perils of inadequate health coverage. There are countless other children who have suffered the same fate. We must make universal coverage for  children a national priority and reauthorization of CHIP is the first step in that process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When CHIP was established in 1997, nearly 10 million children were uninsured. Congress responded by making a landmark, bipartisan commitment to help states provide comprehensive health insurance coverage to millions of these children. As a result, 6 million children have access to medical benefits through CHIP that they would have otherwise been forced to do without. I am proud to have been a part of CHIP's creation, and I am especially proud of the progress this program has made in providing  working families an affordable and dependable option for protecting the health and well-being of their children. A healthy start in life is a necessary component in preparing our children to lead healthy, happy and productive lives in the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, however, we find ourselves in a situation strikingly similar to the dilemma we faced in 1997--more than 9 million children are currently without health insurance in this country. In fact, in 2005, the number of uninsured children increased for the first time since CHIP was enacted. This means that, despite our best efforts, we have taken a step backwards in terms of covering children. We cannot allow this trend to continue. Instead, we must make covering children a top priority--just like  we did in 1997.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The CHIP Reauthorization Act makes health insurance coverage for children a priority. Not only does this important legislation renew and strengthen the commitment we made to our working families 10 years ago; it also provides significant new Federal resources for states to reach the 6 million additional children who are currently eligible for Medicaid and CHIP, but unenrolled. With many states already leading the charge on children's health and the additional federal support this legislation  provides them, the Nation will be able to take another substantial step forward toward ensuring that all of America's children have comprehensive health insurance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our bill strengthens the underlying CHIP financing formula to provide states a stable and reliable source of funding for their efforts to cover more uninsured children. It also combines a variety of approaches, such as Express Lane eligibility, to help states enroll more uninsured kids who are currently eligible for CHIP or Medicaid. These innovative approaches will allow states to reach millions of additional children, particularly in rural parts of the country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am especially proud of our efforts to permit states to provide more meaningful coverage for children by including other vital benefits like dental care and mental health services. I have already talked about the importance of oral health for a child, but I'd also like to say something about children's mental health. I spend a lot of time with veterans, many who suffer from Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD), and when those veterans get home, their children often suffer as well. We also need  to consider the mental health of our children more broadly. Children are living in very tough times. They face enormous amounts of mental pressure from a variety of sources. If the Virginia Tech tragedy taught us anything, it taught us that we need to hug our children everyday and that we need to get appropriate help for our children when they have mental health needs, no matter how big or small.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While I had hoped that we could require Early Periodic Screening Diagnostic and Treatment (EPDST) services as part of this bill, I believe we were able to reach an appropriate compromise that will help us to achieve broad bipartisan support. I am still as committed as I ever have been to including EPDST services in CHIP. However, Senators Snowe, Kennedy, and I wanted to craft a bill that could pass the Senate, and we believe we have achieved that objective.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A final component of our legislation that I would like to highlight are the important steps we take to develop child-focused quality measures that will directly improve the coverage provided to children enrolled in CHIP. We establish a new child health quality initiative to enhance data collection, identify best practices, develop a pediatric electronic medical record, and disseminate health quality information. We hope this new initiative will greatly improve the health outcomes of children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In closing, I'd like for our country to get to the point where we never have to have another Cover the Uninsured Week again. Of course I greatly appreciate all the wonderful work the Robert Wood Johnson Foundation has done over the years to raise awareness about the uninsured problem. My hope is that we will eventually have universal coverage for all. Certainly, we can take the first step toward achieving that goal by providing health care coverage for all of our Nation's children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With this reauthorization bill, Congress now has an opportunity to make profound positive changes in the lives of millions of American children and their families. I urge my colleagues to join us in supporting the passage of the CHIP Reauthorization Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
</record>
