<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1228928403" ordinal="55" title="COMMENDING IDAHO ON WINNING TO HOST THE 2009 SPECIAL OLYMPICS WORLD WINTER GAMES">
  <narrative>COMMENDING IDAHO ON WINNING TO HOST THE 2009 SPECIAL OLYMPICS WORLD WINTER GAMES -- (Senate - December 10, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="10885">S10885</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that the Commerce Committee be discharged from further consideration and the Senate now proceed to <bill type="sr" number="196">S. Res. 196</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will report the resolution by title.</narrative>
  <narrative>The assistant legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="196">S. Res. 196</bill>) commending Idaho on winning the bid to host the 2009 Special Olympics World Winter Games.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="196">S. Res. 196</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, is as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="196">S. Res. 196</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas Special Olympics is an international nonprofit organization that promotes personal development through sports training and competition; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Special Olympics advances the understanding of intellectual disabilities in the community and the Nation through participation and fellowship; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Special Olympics serves more than 2,500,000 individuals with intellectual disabilities; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Special Olympics offers more than 200 programs in over 160 countries; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Special Olympics offers 30 Olympic-type summer and winter sports to both children and adults with intellectual disabilities; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Boise, Idaho won the international bid to host the 2009 Special Olympics World Winter Games to be held February 6 through 13, 2009; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas thousands of athletes are expected to compete in the 2009 Special Olympics World Winter Games; and &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the 2009 Special Olympics World Winter Games will be the largest multi-sport event ever held in the State of Idaho: Now, therefore, be it &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate-- &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) applauds the goals and principles of Special Olympics; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) salutes the athletes, coaches, family members, friends, and volunteers that make Special Olympics possible; and</chair>
  <chair> (3) congratulates the State of Idaho on its selection as the host for the 2009 Special Olympics World Winter Games. &lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
