<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1190131202" ordinal="7" title="DC VOTING RIGHTS AND COLLEGE ACCESS">
  <narrative>DC VOTING RIGHTS AND COLLEGE ACCESS -- (Senate - September 18, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="11615">S11615</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, let me also say this about the remarks I am about to give. This has no negative reflection on my distinguished colleague, the Senator from Kentucky. He and I disagree on a number of issues. We have had longstanding debates here on the Senate floor about how he feels about campaign finance reform. He approaches this on an intellectual basis. I think I am right; he thinks he is right. But it doesn't take away from my respect for his having the right to have an opinion here  in the Senate about the issue of campaign finance. The same, I think, on the issue of flag burning, for example. He will disagree with me on the DC Voting Rights bill. That is his privilege. He does it on an intellectual basis, a conclusion that he has reached. So my remarks have nothing to do, in any way, with an intention to denigrate my friend's feelings about this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Yesterday we celebrated the 220th anniversary of the signing of our Constitution, and I talked about it yesterday. In its preamble, our Founders laid out the values to which our Nation has aspired: justice, domestic tranquility, common defense, general welfare, the blessings of liberty. The Government which has endured, our Government, and served us so well, recognized these goals could only be secured by equal representation. That means the right to vote, the right to elect individuals who will  protect and promote our personal rights as well as the national interest.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The universal right to vote was established a long time ago with the 15th amendment, which barred discrimination based on race, with the 19th amendment, which guaranteed the  right for women to vote, and with the Voting Rights Act, which ensured enforcement of these laws for people no matter their color.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1873, Susan B. Anthony faced trial for voting illegally, a woman who voted. In her defense she said:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the first paragraph of the Declaration of Independence is an assertion of the natural right of all to the ballot; for how can "the consent of the governed" be given, if the right to vote be denied?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today the right to equal representation is still denied to residents of the District of Columbia. These nearly 600,000 Americans pay Federal taxes, sit on juries, serve in our Armed Forces. Yet they are given only a delegate in the Congress, not a real voting Member. This is nothing more than shadow representation. This injustice has stood for far too long. We haven't voted on this matter for some 50 years. It is time we did that again. Shadow representation is shadow citizenship.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This afternoon we will move to vote on a bill that honors the residents of the District who responsibly meet every single expectation of American citizenship but are denied this basic civil right in return. I commend Senator Lieberman, who has taken the leadership on this issue for no reason or agenda other than he thinks it is the right thing to do.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge all my colleagues to vote for cloture so we can guarantee the full rights of citizenship for District residents.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also urge my colleagues to support reauthorization of the DC College Access Act, which we will vote on this morning. This provides to District students who would otherwise be unfairly disadvantaged by the lack of in-State universities. It provides scholarships to make up the difference between in-State and out-of-State public universities. It doesn't allow any student to get in who is not qualified. It does allow a differential in the method of paying. The DC College Access Act levels the playing  field and unlocks the doors to education and all the opportunity it affords to thousands of American students right here in the District of Columbia.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
