<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1205164802" ordinal="43" title="EXPRESSING THE SYMPATHY OF THE SENATE TO FAMILIES OF WOMEN AND GIRLS MURDERED IN GUATEMALA">
  <narrative>EXPRESSING THE SYMPATHY OF THE SENATE TO FAMILIES OF WOMEN AND GIRLS MURDERED IN GUATEMALA -- (Senate - March 10, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="1823">S1823</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be discharged from further consideration of <bill type="sr" number="178">S. Res. 178</bill> and the Senate proceed to its consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <chair>The bill clerk read as follows:</chair>
  <chair>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="178">S. Res. 178</bill>) expressing the sympathy of the Senate to the families of women and girls murdered in Guatemala, and encouraging the United States to work with Guatemala to bring an end to these crimes.</chair>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the amendment at the desk be agreed to; the resolution, as amended, be agreed to; the amendment to the preamble be agreed to; the preamble, as amended, be agreed to; the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table with no intervening action or debate; and that any statements relating to the measure be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The amendment (No. 4149) was agreed to, as follows:</chair>
  <chair> On page 5, strike line 7 through line 11, and insert the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) urges the Government of Guatemala to strengthen laws with respect to domestic violence and sexual harassment, to improve the integrity of the prosecutorial and judicial systems, and to provide the resources and commitment necessary to adequately enforce justice for crimes against women;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; On page 5, insert "continue to" before "incorporate" in line 13.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; On page 5, insert "continue to" after "encourages the Secretary of State to" in line 18.</chair>
  <chair> On page 7, beginning in line 7, strike "all instances of improper investigatory methods" and insert "instances of failure to investigate and prosecute crimes". &lt;p&gt;</chair>
  <chair>The amendment (No. 4150) was agreed to, as follows:</chair>
  <chair>Strike the third whereas clause of the preamble and insert the following:</chair>
  <chair>Whereas, while the overall murder rate in Guatemala has increased substantially, the rate at which women have been murdered in Guatemala has increased at an alarming rate, almost doubling from 2001 to 2006;</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="178">S. Res. 178</bill>), as amended, was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble, as amended, was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, as amended, with its preamble, as amended, will be printed in a future edition of the RECORD.</chair>
</record>
