<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1169053202" ordinal="40" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="COMMITTEE ON AGRICULTURE, NUTRITION AND FORESTRY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition and Forestry be authorized to conduct a hearing during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, January 17, 2007 at 9:30 a.m. in 328A, Senate Russell Office Building. The purpose of this committee hearing will be to consider Working Land Conservation: Conservation Security Program and Environmental Quality Incentive Programs.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science and Transportation be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, January 17, 2007, at 10 a.m. in room SR-253 of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the hearing is to evaluate the status of implementation of the aviation security recommendations of the 9/11 Commission.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENVIRONMENT AND PUBLIC WORKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Environment and Public Works be authorized to meet in Executive Session during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, January 17, 2007, at 9:45 a.m. in SD-406.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Agenda</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rules: Rules of the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="COMMITTEE ON FINANCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Finance be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, January 17, 2007, at 10 a.m., in 215 Dirksen Senate Office Building, to organize for the 110th Congress. The Committee will also consider an Original Bill entitled, "The Small Business and Work Opportunity Act of 2007."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, January 17, 2007, at 9:30 a.m. to hold a hearing on Iraq.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet to conduct a hearing on "Paying Off Generics to Prevent Competition with Brand Name Drugs: Should it Be Prohibited?" on Wednesday, January 17, 2007, at 10:00 a.m. in Dirksen Senate Office Building room 226.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Witness List</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Panel I: Hon. Jon Leibowitz, Commissioner, Federal Trade Commission, Washington, DC.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Panel II: Billy Tauzin, CEO, PhRMA, Washington, DC; Merril Hirsh Partner, Ross, Dixon, and Bell LLP, Washington, DC; Bruce Downey, Chairman and CEO, Barr Pharmaceuticals, Inc., Washington, DC; Michael Wroblewski, Consumers Union, Non-Profit Publisher of Consumer Reports, Yonkers, NY.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="SELECT COMMITTEE ON INTELLIGENCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Select Committee on Intelligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on January 17, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. to hold a closed hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON READINESS AND MANAGEMENT SUPPORT">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on Readiness and Management Support be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, January 17, 2007, at 2:30 p.m., to receive testimony on abusive practices in Department of Defense Contracting for services and inter-agency contracting.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
