<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1190131202" ordinal="52" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <narrative>AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET -- (Senate - September 18, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="11678">S11678</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, September 18, 2007, at 10 a.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The hearing will focus on the National Football League Retirement System and the current compensation system for NFL retirees with claims of advanced injuries that became symptomatic after retiring from the NFL.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="COMMITTEE ON FINANCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Finance be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, September 18, 2007, at 10 a.m., in room 215 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building, to hear testimony on "Breaking the Methamphetamine Supply Chain: Meeting Challenges at the Border."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, September 18, 2007, at 2:30 p.m., to hold a nomination hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet to conduct a hearing entitled "Examining Approaches to Corporate Fraud Prosecutions and the Attorney-Client Privilege Under the McNulty Memorandum" on Tuesday, September 18, 2007 at 10:30 a.m., in the Dirksen Senate Office Building, room 226.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Panel I: Karin Immergut, United States Attorney, District of Oregon, U.S. Department of Justice, Chair; and White Collar Subcommittee for the Attorney General's Advisory Committee, Portland, Oregon.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Panel II: Dick Thornburgh, Of Counsel, K&amp;L Gates, Washington, DC; Daniel Richman, Professor, Columbia Law  School, New York, NY; Michael Seigel, Professor, University of Florida Levin College of Law, Gainesville, FL; and Andrew Weissmann, Partner, Jenner &amp; Block, New York, NY.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="SELECT COMMITTEE ON INTELLIGENCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Select Committee on Intelligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on September 18, 2007, at 2:30 p.m., to hold a closed business meeting.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
