<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1204650002" ordinal="34" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <narrative>AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET -- (Senate - March 04, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="1545">S1545</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300080" topic="COMMITTEE ON ARMED SERVICES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, March 4, 2008, at 9:30 a.m., in open and closed session in order to receive testimony on the United States Central Command and Special Operations Command in review of the Defense authorization request for fiscal year 2009 and the Future Years Defense Program.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300080" topic="COMMITTEE ON BANKING, HOUSING, AND URBAN AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on March 4, 2008, at 10 a.m., in order to conduct a hearing entitled "The State of the Banking Industry."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300080" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, March 4, 2008, at 2:30 p.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building, in order to conduct a hearing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of this hearing is to evaluate operational incidents associated with oil spills. The Subcommittee will examine non-tank vessel fuel tank design, the Coast Guard's Vessel Traffic System, and the U.S. vessel pilot system.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300080" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND NATURAL RESOURCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate in order to conduct a hearing on Tuesday, March 4, 2008, at 10:00 a.m., in room SD 366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building. At this hearing, the Committee will hear testimony regarding Energy Information Administration's revised Annual Energy Outlook.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300080" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, March 4, 2008, at 9:30 a.m. in SD-410, in order to conduct a hearing on Kosovo.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300080" topic="COMMITTEE ON HOMELAND SECURITY AND GOVERNMENTAL AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, March 4, 2008, at 2:30 p.m. in order to conduct a closed hearing entitled "NSPD-54/HSPD-23 and the Comprehensive National Cyber Security Initiative."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300080" topic="COMMITTEE ON VETERANS' AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent for the Committee on Veterans' Affairs to be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, March 4, in order to conduct a joint hearing with the House Veterans' Affairs Committee to hear the legislative presentation from the Veterans of Foreign Wars of the U.S. The Committee will meet in room 216 of the Hart Senate Office Building, at 9:30 a.m.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300080" topic="SELECT COMMITTEE ON INTELLIGENCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Select Committee on Intelligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on March 4, 2008, at 2:30 p.m. in order to hold a closed hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300080" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON STRATEGIC FORCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on Strategic Forces of the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, March 4, 2008, at 2:30 p.m., in open and closed session in order to receive testimony on military space programs in review of the defense authorization request for fiscal year 2009 and the future years defense program.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300080" topic="AD HOC SUBCOMMITTEE ON DISASTER RECOVERY AND THE AD HOC SUBCOMMITTEE ON STATE, LOCAL, AND PRIVATE SECTOR PREPAREDNESS AND INTEGRATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Ad Hoc Subcommittee on Disaster Recovery and the Ad Hoc Subcommittee on State, Local, and Private Sector Preparedness and Integration of the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, March 4, 2007, at 10 a.m. in order to conduct a joint hearing entitled, "Is Housing Too Much To Hope For?: FEMA's Disaster Housing Strategy."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
