<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1178726404" ordinal="13" title="PRESCRIPTION DRUG USER FEE AMENDMENTS OF 2007">
  <chair> Under the previous order, the Senate will resume consideration of <bill type="s" number="1082">S. 1082</bill>, which the clerk will report.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I yield myself 6 minutes of our time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, we will see later this morning the successful conclusion of this legislation. We have some important matters to consider, which we will do in a very short period of time. But as we are coming into the closing time for this amendment, I think it is appropriate that we review very quickly what this legislation does and what it does not do.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am a strong believer in this legislation, which has strong bipartisan support. I am enormously grateful to Senator Enzi and Members on our side of the aisle as well as those on the other side for all of their help and assistance in getting us to the point where we are ready to take final action on something that makes a major difference to families in America. We ensure the safety of our prescription drug system and also are making very important progress in the safety of our food  supply.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is, in an important way, breakthrough legislation. I will review quickly what this does and then come back to the amendments that are before the Senate and how we think the Senate should dispose of them; why this legislation is urgent, why it is extremely important, and why the American people deserve the best.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Very quickly, again, there is strong emphasis on safer food and safer medicines for families in this country. We spelled out at the earlier part of our presentations the effective systems we have supported to make sure we are going to have the safest prescription drug program in the world, using different kinds of modern technologies and also modern surveillance systems for monitoring postmarketing safety. This will ensure in the future we are going to have the safest prescription drug program  in the world. We will have safer medicines.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We will also have safer food for families and pets. I think all Americans have been alarmed, as they should have  been, by what has been reported in the news in the last few weeks. Many families have lost their pets because the agency lacked the  authorities provided in this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We will have earlier warnings on drug safety problems using extremely elaborate systems of postmarketing surveillance. These systems will use both public and private centers to collect information that the FDA will use to find early warnings of possible harm. In these cases, the agency will be able to take expeditious action. That has never been done before.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are going to have better medicines for children. We are enormously appreciative of the excellent work that has been done by Senator Dodd and Senator Clinton. This was done in a bipartisan way with Senator DeWine, who is not here. We all realize that children are not little people; children are children, and therefore their bodies react differently to various kinds of prescription drugs. This legislation provides mechanisms to get information on safe and effective use of medications  in children as well as to promote studies of drugs in pediatric populations. In the past few years, we have made enormous progress and we believe this legislation will help to an even greater extent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are going to have more transparency and stronger science at the FDA because of the wonderful work done by Senator Mikulski. She and others worked to assure that we have greater awareness by the public of what is happening at the agency.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is greater focus and attention on making sure the agency is going to have the best in terms of the new sciences. We are in the life science century at the present time. This has been impressed on the country with the extraordinary convention on biosciences that took place in Boston in the last few days. There I listened and read about the potential the life sciences have, not only in terms of energy and agriculture but also in terms of medicines. The United States is absolutely poised to  continue to be the world leader in these fields, with all of its implications of healthier families here and around the world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We need to make sure we are going to have the best kind of science at the FDA. We do that in the way we have given greater authority over the development of the science function at FDA. We also provided a rather unique foundation that will be able to use public and private funding. This foundation will seek out the best and the newest modalities to help speed the review of various prescription drugs. That is going to be enormously important because time means cost. If we are able to resolve these  issues more quickly the costs will be more understandable and reasonable to consumers and we will get them faster.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Briefly to comment on some of the amendments, we have taken a position in our proposal that both the safety and efficacy of particular prescription drugs is a function that ought to be considered in tandem. I know there are those who think we ought to separate those functions. We can imagine a circumstance, for example, where the side reaction of a particular drug is that individuals lose all of their hair and they become nauseated. Clearly I am describing the impact of methotrexate. That can  happen to an individual on many anticancer drugs. You wouldn't prescribe that for athlete's foot because the side effects are so dramatic, but you would approve that for another kind of regime to try to treat cancer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We also have items on civil penalties for the first time. There is a question of what those civil penalties should be. I want them to be higher, but I am mindful as well that this is the first time we are going to have those civil penalties. We are going to be working on those matters with the House. I basically think they should be a little higher, but I listened to my colleague on this issue and we are going to try to make sure we get something that is going to be fair and can do the job.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am also mindful of the concern we have in terms of the potential of conflicts of interest. I will reserve my time to be able to deal with this issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a very important issue. We want to make sure, on the one hand, as we have these breakthroughs in science, that we are going to have the best experts participating in these review groups. We also have to be sensitive to the issues of conflicts of interests. I know the Senator from Illinois has a proposal on this.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I will reserve the rest of my time to be able to discuss that later.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300075" topic="ELEMENTS TO ASSURE SAFE USE">
    <paragraph>Madam President I rise to engage in a colloquy with the Senator from Wyoming and ranking member of the Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee, Senator ENZI.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, I would like to thank the chairman and the ranking member of the HELP Committee for their efforts to address the issue of access to health care in frontier areas. Much of Alaska is a frontier area and it is not an easy task to access health care in general, let alone find a specialist to obtain needed medications.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Toward that end, I am pleased that the bill before us today recognizes the problem of access and provides a willing provider in a frontier area with the ability to receive the training and certification necessary to prescribe a drug that has potential serious risks. For clarification purposes, I would like to ask the Senator from Wyoming if it is the intent of Congress that section 202 of <bill type="s" number="1082">S. 1082</bill>, the FDA Revitalization Act, allows all physician and nonphysician health care providers in frontier  areas to be able to receive "training or certification" so that the provider can prescribe or dispense a particular drug without the need for an additional degree or medical specialty?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300041" topic="ELEMENTS TO ASSURE SAFE USE">
    <paragraph>Yes. This is the intent.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300075" topic="ELEMENTS TO ASSURE SAFE USE">
    <paragraph>And under the provisions of section 202, would the willing health care provider be able to receive this training or certification through remote learning methods so that a provider would not need to travel vast distances in order to get the requisite training?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300041" topic="ELEMENTS TO ASSURE SAFE USE">
    <paragraph>Yes. The language in the bill recognizes that travel in frontier areas, particularly in remote places such as Alaska, can be time-consuming and expensive, so it specifically notes that the training or certification should be available in a widely available training or certification method, such as an online course or through the mail. This is intended to reduce the amount of travel and expense a willing provider in a frontier area must undertake in order to be able to prescribe or dispense  needed medicines to their</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300075" topic="ELEMENTS TO ASSURE SAFE USE">
    <paragraph>I thank the Senator. And since the provider would not be required to obtain an additional degree or medical specialty, and the training or certification would hopefully be through an online course or through the mail, is there any indication of how long such training would take for the provider to be deemed sufficiently trained to prescribe a specific drug?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300041" topic="ELEMENTS TO ASSURE SAFE USE">
    <paragraph>While I cannot give the Senator a guaranteed time frame, I would point out that the training and certification is specifically for the drug the provider is seeking to prescribe or dispense--not for a range of drugs. Thus, the time frame should not be a lengthy one, particularly if the training can be conducted online.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300075" topic="ELEMENTS TO ASSURE SAFE USE">
    <paragraph>Now, I understand that many physicians around the country are invited to attend conferences or training seminars in order to be certified to prescribe certain drugs. Given the low volume of the high risk drugs we are talking about that are likely to be dispensed in frontier areas, how can we ensure that a willing provider will be able to access this training? What is the incentive for a drug manufacturer or the FDA to include frontier area among the areas where training and certification  would be available?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300041" topic="ELEMENTS TO ASSURE SAFE USE">
    <paragraph>I thank the Senator for that question. The language in the bill specifically says that the training or certification shall be available to any willing provider from a frontier area. Shall be available--not may be available, but shall. It is the intent of Congress in this section to direct the FDA to guarantee that a willing provider will have access to the training and certification needed to prescribe a particular drug. And again, the language that encourages the availability of an  online course or course through the mail is one way to provide for that training or certification at minimal cost.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300075" topic="ELEMENTS TO ASSURE SAFE USE">
    <paragraph>I thank the Senator for that clarification. I bring this colloquy to the Senate floor today because I want to ensure that every  American has access to prescription drugs regardless of whether they live in a large urban city like New York, or a frontier community like Bethel, AK. I believe that with the modifications that have been made to this bill, we will be able to achieve that.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300042" topic="ELEMENTS TO ASSURE SAFE USE">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I am pleased to support <bill type="s" number="1082">S. 1082</bill>, the Food and Drug Administration Revitalization Act of 2007. This much-needed legislation improves our country's prescription drug and medical device safety, and responds to problems that Congress is long overdue in addressing. This legislation strengthens the Food and Drug Administration, a body that has been continually underfunded and weakened by political and corporate interests. While I would like to see an even stronger bill  passed, this legislation drastically improves our current policies that regulate the FDA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My constituents in Wisconsin largely trust that their food, medications, and medical devices are safe. I generally trust that they are as well. We all depend on the FDA to ensure that our lives are not jeopardized by faulty products or contaminated food. However, recently a steady stream of dangerous drugs, food, and devices have made their way into Americans' homes. Vioxx, antidepressant drugs for children, salmonella poisoning in food, pet food contaminations--these are just a few of the most  publicized instances that have harmed and even killed people in our country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Numerous investigations have been conducted in order to better understand why these events have occurred. The conclusions to these studies have found that we need a better FDA. We need to provide the agency with the legal authority necessary to ensure our safety, and we need to provide the FDA with the necessary funding to do its job. It is clear that the agency's authority has been watered down over the years as a result of corporate influence, and our citizens have suffered the consequences.  This bill takes important steps to put safety over profit margins, and it has been long awaited.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I commend the immense bipartisan effort that has been put into crafting this legislation. This is not an easy topic to tackle. It is a complex topic rife with political infighting, but today we have legislation that both parties and even many companies are fine with. Granted, the bill may be too far-reaching for some, and for others like me, it doesn't necessarily go far enough, but this is something that will pass that is a vast improvement from current law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I was glad to support Senator Durbin's amendment to improve the FDA's oversight and ability to respond to contaminated pet food. Like the bill as a whole, I think we need to do more to ensure that the ingredients used in both pet and human food are free from contamination, but this amendment was an important step in the right direction. The amendment strengthens the standards for pet food processing and ingredients and at the same time improves the FDA's ability to react to a problem  through better detection, an adulterated food registry, and improved communication with the public. I hope this will be a platform for improving Federal oversight of the human food supply, which has been shown many times over the last year to be at risk.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In my home State of Wisconsin, the outbreak of E.coli last summer, later linked to bagged spinach, killed an elderly woman and sickened at least fifty others. The spinach was traced back to four fields on four ranches in California. The FDA itself admits that "There has been a long history of E. coli O157:H7 outbreaks involving leafy greens from the central California region", and yet mostly depends on the industry to self-regulate. In fact, on the FDA Web site about this particular outbreak,  it says, "[the] FDA and the State of California expect the industry to develop a comprehensive plan which is designed to minimize the risk of another outbreak." I am concerned that all too often the FDA is allowing the food industry to dictate the rules and whether to implement food safety protections. This bill is a step in the right direction, but more steps are likely needed and I look forward to working with my colleagues on these.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Along these lines, I was glad to offer an amendment and have it accepted in the bill that would require the FDA to resume annual reports on the level of pesticide residues in domestic and imported food and agricultural products. Moreover, my amendment requires the FDA to make the report more useful for Congress and the public. Specifically the amendment requires the FDA to work with other agencies to include similar data collected by other government agencies, conduct more advanced statistical  analysis, report on efforts to prevent smuggling through mislabeling one product as another, and target future testing on products or countries, in the case of exports, that show relatively more prohibited pesticides. The recent headlines about contaminated</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While this pesticide residue amendment is important to improve consumers' confidence in the food they eat, it also can be important for U.S. farmers. For example, Wisconsin's ginseng growers have suffered a double insult over the past few years--facing unfair competition from imported ginseng that was treated with chemicals illegal in the U.S. and then often having that ginseng misbranded as the superior quality Wisconsin ginseng. My amendment and the improved pesticide residue data and ability  to focus on certain products should help FDA identify and seize unsafe products such as contaminated ginseng imports.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On another note, I am disappointed that the bill does not actually allow importing lower cost prescription drugs. While the Dorgan-Snowe amendment was accepted in the bill, it was modified and effectively nullified by the Cochran amendment, which I strongly opposed</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A competitive marketplace for prescription drugs will help in containing the skyrocketing costs of prescription drugs. Over the past 4 years, I have worked in a bipartisan fashion to allow the safe importation of prescription drugs from abroad. I am a proud cosponsor of the Pharmaceutical Market Access and Drug Safety Act, which the provisions in the Dorgan-Snowe amendment were based on. This legislation would have allowed the importation of FDA-approved drugs from countries with FDA-comparable  regulations, such as Canada. This legislation will finally allow the importation of safe and affordable prescriptions drugs to the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As I travel around Wisconsin listening to people's concerns, the high cost of health care continues to be at the top of the list, and this includes prescription drugs. The strong bipartisan support for reimportation makes clear that Americans of all political backgrounds want the Federal Government to support consumers, rather than the interests of drug companies, and make safe and affordable prescription drugs available to those who need them. The failure to include strong reimportation legislation  in this bill is unfortunate, but we are getting closer to enacting reimportation with each vote. I fully expect this to pass in the near future, and I urge my colleagues to join me in supporting efforts to legalize reimportation. As I stated earlier, I will support the final FDA Revitalization Act, but I am disappointed that strong reimportation language is not included.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400576" topic="ELEMENTS TO ASSURE SAFE USE">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I appreciate the attention to drug safety on the part of Senators KENNEDY and ENZI. The drug safety problems our nation experienced surrounding Vioxx and the SSRIs demanded that we take a serious look at the FDA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I appreciate the hundreds and hundreds of staff hours that have gone into working on this legislation both before and after the HELP Committee markup.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When the Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee marked up this legislation, I strongly opposed it. I appreciate the willingness of Senators KENNEDY and ENZI to listen to my concerns and take action to address them. Many of the changes I requested are included in the final product that we vote on today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill has come a very long ways since its consideration in the HELP Committee. Instead of requiring a risk evaluation and mitigation strategy, REMS, for every drug, a REMS may  only be requested when there is a scientific reason for one. In giving new regulatory authority to the FDA, we must be extremely cautious that we do not hurt access to new and innovative prescription drugs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I appreciate that the concept, introduced by Senators GREGG, BURR, and myself, to establish a surveillance system for adverse prescription drug events has been included in this legislation. This will now allow cooperation with academic institutions that have the expertise to evaluate the signals from that surveillance system and ensure that both patients and doctors have the information they need to make decisions about the risks and benefits of medical drugs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a practicing physician, I know that it is impossible to ever completely eliminate drug risks. The right approach is to provide accurate risk information and preserve the doctor-patient relationship. I appreciate the progress made in the bill towards this end.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I appreciate the willingness of Senators KENNEDY and ENZI to work with me on preserving the doctor-patient relationship. The FDA's job is to approve drugs as safe and effective--not to dictate which doctors can prescribe which drugs to which patients. Medicine is not just a science; it is also an art.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation will ensure that patients have access to potentially lifesaving drugs that might not otherwise be approved because of known adverse events caused by the drug. This legislation establishes that the agency will not limit or restrict distribution or use unless a drug has been shown to actually cause an adverse event.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also appreciate the efforts of my colleague Senator Roberts in preserving the right to commercial free speech, as intended by the Constitution, in direct-to-consumer, DTC, advertising. While I am not a big fan of DTC, I am a big fan of the Constitution. I am pleased that a compromise was reached to remove the ban on DTC from this bill and instead ensure that drug companies are held accountable if their advertisements are false or misleading.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I appreciate the willingness of Senators KENNEDY and ENZI to accept an amendment that will provide a date certain for a safety evaluation of the drug RU-486.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The two user fee agreements for prescription drugs and medical devices, PDUFA and MDUFMA, have been negotiated between industry representatives and the FDA. The industry indicates what it will pay for faster drug approvals and the FDA commits to achievable performance goals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I appreciate the work of FDA Commissioner Dr. Andrew von Eschenbach in crafting fair and reasonable proposals for both prescription drug and medical device companies. It is critical that we focus on public health and safety, and also hold the FDA accountable for improved agency performance goals. Maintaining timely and efficient patient access to lifesaving and life-enhancing medical drugs and devices is a win for the industry, doctors, and patients. I look forward to seeing how the new performance  goals in both the PDUFA and MDUFMA agreements will both help keep the pipeline of innovation moving forward and improve communication and understanding between agency staff and manufacturers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I can vote in favor of this legislation today because of the enormous progress made. However, there are some workability issues with both the Best Pharmaceuticals for Children Act and the Pediatric Research Improvement Act. These issues need to be resolved so that the FDA has the authority to do its job quickly and effectively.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Best Pharmaceuticals for Children Act, BPCA, has generated more clinical information for the pediatric population than any other legislative or regulatory effort to date. I am concerned about this reauthorization of the Best Pharmaceuticals for Children Act because chips away at incentives that have been getting real results for kids.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am also concerned that part of the bill, pediatric medical devices, would authorize $30 million in demonstration grants for improving the availability of pediatric devices. While this has a worthy goal, more accountability is needed for this program to ensure that such grants are used for helping save the lives of children. Additionally, the bill's sponsors failed to do their homework in examining existing Federal programs. The fact is, the National Institutes of Health already has a program  for this purpose. In order to preserve a heritage for our grandchildren, Congress needs to do the hard work of taking an inventory of existing programs before we authorize new ones.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, I appreciate the enormous amount of work that has gone into improving this legislation. It is critical that in addressing drug safety that we do not harm access to new and lifesaving medical technologies.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300034" topic="ELEMENTS TO ASSURE SAFE USE">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I rise to support passage of the committee substitute to <bill type="s" number="1082">S. 1082</bill>, the Food and Drug Administration Revitalization Act, FDARA. This legislation contains tremendous advances for children and their families through the reauthorization of the Best Pharmaceuticals for Children Act, BPCA, and the Pediatric Medical Device Safety and Improvement Act, which I authored, as well as the reauthorization of the Pediatric Research Equity Act, PREA, which was introduced by my colleague,  Senator Clinton.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I congratulate Chairman Kennedy and Ranking Member ENZI for their efforts in putting this complex bill together and thank them both for working with me to ensure these vital programs for children can thrive well into the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have had good debate on this legislation. I want to thank my friend from Colorado, Senator Allard, for the floor debate we had on BPCA. I want to assure him and those that voted for his amendment that this bill is about increasing pediatric clinical trials and improving our knowledge about products being used in children where previously we have had no information. BPCA is and has always been about striking an appropriate balance between the cost to consumers and benefits to children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ten years ago when Senator Mike DeWine and I undertook this effort, only 11 drugs on the market that were being used in children had actually been tested and studied for their use. Prior to the enactment of BPCA 10 years ago, pediatricians were essentially flying blind because they lacked information regarding the safety and effectiveness of drugs they were prescribing for children. But it was children who suffered the most from taking drugs where so little was known about their effects.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What we have learned over the past 10 years of experience is that children have been exposed to ineffective drugs, ineffective dosing, overdosing, or side effects from drugs that were previously unknown. In 10 years, nearly 800 studies involving more than 45,000 children in clinical trials have been completed. Useful new pediatric information is now part of product labeling for more than 119 drugs. In sum, there has been a twentyfold increase in the number of drugs studied in infants, children,  and adolescents as a result of BPCA since its enactment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Children with a wide range of diseases such as HIV/AIDS, cancer, allergies, asthma, neurological and psychiatric disorders, and obesity can now lead healthier, more productive lives as a result of new information about the safety and efficacy of drugs they use to treat and manage their diseases where previously there was none.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This successful program for children will expire on September 30 unless we act to reauthorize it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The reauthorization of BPCA contained within <bill type="s" number="1082">S. 1082</bill>, makes several important improvements to this program which I have spent many months developing. It is my belief that these improvements will help ensure that this program continues to thrive well into the future. I strongly support the 5-year authorization of this program so that we can closely monitor how the program is working and make improvements as they are needed in the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="1082">S. 1082</bill> will increase the amount and quality of pediatric information by streamlining BPCA and PREA at the Food and Drug Administration, FDA, and ensuring that labeling changes as a result of BPCA are communicated to physicians. <bill type="s" number="1082">S. 1082</bill> will improve transparency and accountability by making market exclusivity determinations and written requests for pediatric studies public within 30 days of exclusivity being awarded. It also will improve the accuracy and speed of labeling changes  &lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page:  <bill type="s" number="5763">S5763</bill>]&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/center&gt;</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="1082">S. 1082</bill> will ensure that BPCA continues to yield more and better drug studies in children, while addressing the minority of cases where the incentive of 6 months additional market exclusivity has far exceeded the "carrot" it was intended to provide to drug sponsors. It improves market certainty by not allowing pediatric exclusivity to be granted within nine months of the end of the drug's patent and increases data about the use and applicability of BPCA through reports conducted by the Institute  of Medicine, IOM, and the Government Accountability Office to review the program and assess the impact of the changes made within the legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>BPCA has shown us that it is unsafe to simply treat children as smaller versions of adults. Children face a similar inequity with respect to medical devices. Far too few medical devices are specifically designed for children's small and growing bodies. Experts say that the development of children's medical devices lags 5 to 10 years behind that of adults. That is largely due to the limited size of the market for pediatric devices.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When a medical device suitable for a child is needed to save that child's life but it does not exist, doctors are often forced to "jury-rig" adult versions of the device or, in some cases, perform a riskier surgery on the child. Ventilator masks, for instance, are far too large to fit over a baby's mouth. Often, the only alternative is to run an invasive tube down the baby's throat.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of what we witnessed over the past ten years with the market incentives provided under BPCA, I introduced an initiative called the Pediatric Medical Device Safety and Improvement Act to create similar incentives for device manufacturers. This legislation also streamlines the approval process for cutting-edge technology and establishes grants for matchmaking between inventors and manufacturers and the Federal Government.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Balancing incentives with safety, the legislation closely mirrors recommendations made by the IOM in its 2005 report on pediatric medical device safety to improve the serious flaws in the current postmarket safety surveillance of these devices. Specifically, the IOM called for and the legislation allows the FDA to require postmarket studies as a condition of clearance or approval for certain categories of devices and it gives the FDA the ability to require studies longer than 3 years with respect  to a device that is to have significant use in pediatric populations if such studies would be necessary to address longer term pediatric questions, such as the impact on growth and development.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Some in the medical device industry continue to offer proposals to chip away at the authorities in the legislation intended to ensure the FDA can request manufacturers to conduct postmarket safety surveillances and ensure devices used in children are safe. I am disheartened by anyone who would attempt to deprive children and physicians of information that pertains to device safety and I will strongly oppose attempts to weaken the postmarket safety standards contained within the legislation as  the bill heads to conference.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The faster we can get new, safe pediatric devices to market, the fewer parents have to stake their children's lives on improvisation and guesswork.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have previously mentioned the broad-ranging support for these important initiatives for children but it is worth restating that the level of support from pediatricians, patient advocacy organizations, drug and device companies, and many others indicates that this important legislation will greatly benefit children and their families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to thank the tremendous work of the staff on this bill. They have devoted countless hours and many weekends to working on this legislation. Specifically, I want to thank David Bowen and David Dorsey with Senator Kennedy and Shana Christrup, Keith Flanagan and Amy Muhlberg with Senator Enzi who worked so closely with my office on the pediatrics initiatives in title IV of this legislation. I also want to thank Kate Leone with Senator HARRY REID whose terrific leadership  helped guide this legislation to passage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also want to acknowledge the leadership of the American Academy of Pediatrics and the Elizabeth Glaser Pediatric AIDS Foundation whose staff, Mark Del Monte, Jeanne Ireland and Elaine Vining, have provided tremendous technical assistance on the pediatrics initiatives in <bill type="s" number="1082">S. 1082</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Before I close I want to address the other provision in this legislation which reauthorizes vital user fee programs at the FDA for drugs and devices and addresses the important issue of drug safety at the FDA, an agency that regulates 25 percent of the products consumed by Americans. In recent years, we have witnessed a public crisis of confidence in the FDA's ability to ensure that the drugs taken by millions of Americans are safe and effective once they are on the market. My colleagues and  I on the Health, Education, Labor and Pensions, HELP, Committee heard testimony about the internal crisis within the scientific community at the FDA about inappropriate influences on decisionmaking.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I was deeply troubled by the recent Union of Concerned Scientists study showing that of nearly 1,000 FDA scientists questioned, 420 reported that they knew of cases in which the Department of Health and Human Services or FDA political appointees have inappropriately injected themselves into FDA determinations or actions. The same study also found that 378 FDA scientists disagreed or strongly disagreed that the FDA is acting effectively to protect public health. With Vioxx, antidepressants in  children, and now Ketek, the FDA has repeatedly been accused of suppressing internal safety concerns and ignoring repeated warnings of safety concerns from the FDA's own scientists.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We need to restore the public trust in this vital agency, rid it of undue influences that benefit a political, rather than a public health, agenda, and, above all, we need to adequately fund the FDA through the appropriations process so that the agency is less reliant on user fees collected from private industry. Congress must act swiftly to give the FDA more resources. That, I believe, is how we maintain the FDA as the world's gold standard in drug and device safety.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator Grassley and I authored one of the first drug safety and clinical trials bills in the Senate in the wake of the Vioxx scandal that would have given FDA's office of postmarket drug surveillance the independence, stature and funding to take action when a safety problem arises. We reintroduced the bill this congress with several colleagues on the HELP Committee including Senators MIKULSKI and BINGAMAN and I thank them for their support. While I do not agree with some  of my colleagues who have argued that this authority would create a bigger bureaucracy at the FDA, our experience showed us that the support to move such a proposal simply wasn't there.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, I believe that my colleagues and I were able to make significant improvements to <bill type="s" number="1082">S. 1082</bill> with respect to drug safety. I believe those improvements will strengthen science at the FDA, improve transparency of decisionmaking so that dissenting views can be heard, and improve safety of drugs once they are on the market.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The drug safety and clinical trials components of <bill type="s" number="1082">S. 1082</bill> are by no means perfect. In fact, I have serious concerns about what I view as inadequate enforcement authority in the bill and am particularly concerned about whether the bill will prevent companies from withholding information about clinical trials which were negative or were trials that companies abandoned because initial results were negative. As demonstrated by Ketek, I am also concerned about whether this bill does enough to capture  clinical trials conducted overseas. I hope we can improve on these provisions when this bill goes to conference with the House.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today the Senate voted on an important issue dealing with conflicts of interest on FDA advisory committees. As demonstrated by the FDA advisory committee considering Vioxx, it is clear that the FDA's policy with respect to financial conflicts of interest wasn't working. The FDA has made modifications to its policy and the underlying legislation makes several additional improvements. I believe the  amendment offered by Senators DURBIN and &lt;b&gt;BINGAMAN</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, I voted against the amendment because I was concerned about the impact a hard and fast limit of one waiver per committee meeting would have on timely access to drugs and new drug information. Specifically, the Pediatric Advisory Committee, a standing FDA advisory committee which relies on experts with specific expertise in pediatric issues, is an important component of the Best Pharmaceuticals for Children Act program. I was concerned that setting an arbitrary limit on the number of  waivers per committee meeting would further complicate an already small pool of qualified individuals in fields such as pediatrics.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am disappointed that an agreement on the amendment was not reached between the bill managers and sponsors of the amendment so that the Senate bill could contain the important provisions dealing with recruitment and outreach. It is my hope that we can find a way to address these issues in the conference with the House.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Taken as a whole, the underlying legislation is vital to our nation's children as well as consumers needing timely access to safe and effective drugs. Therefore, it is essential that the House act quickly so that we can send a conference report to the President in the coming months. I urge the House to pass all of the major provisions contained in <bill type="s" number="1082">S. 1082</bill>. I support this legislation and look forward to continuing to work with my colleagues on both sides of the aisle and in both Chambers so that  we can send this legislation to the President for his signature.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="ELEMENTS TO ASSURE SAFE USE">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I would like to take some time to talk about some issues that I haven't spent a great deal of time describing to the Senate about <bill type="s" number="1082">S. 1082</bill>, the Food and Drug Administration Revitalization Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, I thank Senator Roberts and Senator Harkin for working with Senator Enzi and me and with many members of the committee on the important issue of direct-to-consumer, or DTC, advertising.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have worked together to accomplish our common goal--a constitutionally sound, effective, workable way to see that DTC ads provide accurate information to patients about the drugs they are taking.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Some have advocated a ban on such advertising altogether, but Senator Enzi and I rejected that approach since it failed to meet the constitutional test. Instead, we included a more measured provision in our legislation that allows FDA to impose a moratorium in extraordinary circumstances where needed to protect public health.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>During our committee's consideration of this issue, Senator Roberts brought up his concerns that even this limited provision fell afoul of recent Supreme Court decisions on free speech. Senator Harkin raised his strong interest in seeing that these DTC ads include strong, effective safety information that is clearly and prominently presented to consumers in a way that does not gloss over important information. Senator Enzi and I committed to work with Senator Roberts  to see that any provision on DTC met the constitutional threshold, and we agreed to work with Senator Harkin to make certain that it provided strong safety information to consumers. The result of our discussions is an amendment that our two colleagues offered. It is a true bipartisan compromise, worked out by two Senators committed to making real progress on an important issue, and I am pleased to support the amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Instead of the moratorium included in our original bill, the Roberts-Harkin amendment puts in place strong safety disclosures for DTC ads, coupled with effective enforcement. Under current law, safety disclosures can be an afterthought--a rushed disclaimer read by an announcer at the conclusion of a TV ad while distracting images help gloss over the important information provided. Our proposal requires safety announcements to be presented in a manner that is clear and conspicuous without distracting  imagery.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We also give FDA the authority to require safety disclosures in DTC ads if the risk profile of the drug requires them. Senator Roberts had a concern that this authority not be used indiscriminately, so we have made clear that the required disclosure must pertain to a specific identified risk.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have made important improvements in FDA's ability to enforce the requirement to provide clear and accurate information to consumers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For advertisements, as in so many other areas, FDA's enforcement tools are now limited. Although FDA does have the capacity under current law to remove a drug from the market for misleading ads, that authority is not often used and rightly so, since it punishes patients for the transgressions of the manufacturers. Since removing a drug from the market is an empty threat, FDA is often left with little option but to make polite requests to companies to change their ads. Under the Roberts-Harkin  amendment, FDA will have the ability to levy fines of up to $150,000 for false or misleading ads.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is unacceptable for patients to be put at risk by inaccurate ads. The Roberts-Harkin amendment makes certain that FDA will have the ability to see that this does not occur, in a way that is clearly consistent with the Constitution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The amendment is a victory for bipartisan common sense on a difficult issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would also like to address the affect of title II of this bill. Generally speaking, title II grants the FDA new authority to conduct postapproval safety surveillance activity in order to improve drug safety.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In enacting title II, we do not intend to alter existing State law duties imposed on the holder of an approved drug application to obtain and disclose information regarding drug safety hazards either before or after the drug receives FDA approval or labeling. Nor are we expressing a belief that the regulatory scheme embodied in the bill is comprehensive enough to preempt the field or every aspect of State law. FDA's approved label has always been understood to be the minimum requirement necessary  for approval. In providing the FDA with new tools and enhanced authority to determine drug safety, we do not intend to convert this minimum requirement into a maximum.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As the Institute of Medicine and others have found, the FDA's past performance has been inadequate. While we fully expect substantial improvement as a result of the enactment of this bill, we cannot and do not expect the FDA or this new process to identify every drug-specific safety concern before a drug manufacturer becomes aware or should have become aware of such concerns. Nor are the bill's requirements that holders disclose certain safety information to the Government intended to substitute  for the disclosure requirements that may be required under State law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would also like to focus on another aspect of our legislation, the Reagan-Udall Foundation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>During the discussions that led to consideration of this bill, we heard time and again that there was a major need for better research tools to aid FDA in evaluating the safety of drugs and help researchers move through the long process of developing drugs more effectively. Every day that a new medicine is needlessly delayed is another day that a patient does not receive a treatment that could well mean the difference between health and continued illness. If new research tools and better ways  to evaluate the safety and effectiveness of drugs could be developed, patients will benefit from quicker drug development. If current procedures can be made more effective, then the cost of developing new drugs will drop.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One area where scientists can make real progress is developing new cell lines and new genetic techniques for testing drugs that reduce the need for costly forms of testing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Reagan-Udall Foundation sets up a way to develop these new tools--not so they can help just one researcher or one company, but so they can help the entire research enterprise. New ways to test drugs for effectiveness and safety  will bring new advances to patients quicker and more smoothly. Through the Reagan-Udall Foundation, they will be available to the FDA and to the entire research enterprise. This new foundation is not many pages in a long bill,  but it is an important component to help get needed medicines to patients as quickly as safety will allow.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also wish to mention another critical aspect of our legislation--its registry of clinical trials.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This provision serves two essential purposes. First, it allows patients who want to enroll in those trials an accessible and central Internet site to find out which trials are being conducted and whether they might be eligible.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This provision builds on an existing provision of law to create a clinical trials site, but report after report has shown that the requirement to list trials has not been complied with. Our legislation puts more force in the requirement to list trials so that patients will benefit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Listing trials is important for patient access--but reporting results is critical for safety. Our legislation requires that the results of trials be reported. No longer will companies be able to hide the outcome of a trial that did not turn out the way they hoped.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Examples of this kind of abuse are shocking. The manufacturer of the antidepressant drug Paxil conducted five clinical trials of the drug in adolescents and children, yet published only one study whose mixed results it deemed positive. The company sat on two major studies for up to 4 years, although the results of one were divulged by a whistleblower and all of the studies were submitted to the FDA when the company sought approval for new uses of Paxil. At that time it became apparent that Paxil  was no more effective than a placebo in treating adolescent depression.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under the bill, these kinds of abuses will not be permitted, since clinical trials will have to be reported--no matter what the result.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator Enzi, Senator Dodd and many others in the committee worked hard to get this provision right. We require immediate listing of all publicly available data and require a negotiated rulemaking, backed by the full authority of statute to develop the precise requirements for other results information to be included.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to thank my colleagues for considering these comments as they relate to <bill type="s" number="1082">S. 1082</bill>, and I urge my colleagues to support the bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400576" topic="ELEMENTS TO ASSURE SAFE USE">
    <paragraph>Madam President, as we debate the important issue of drug safety, I want to address the safety of one drug in particular: RU-486 or mifepristone. This drug was approved in 2000 under a special pathway, subpart H drug approval that is reserved for drugs that treat severe or life-threatening illnesses. Subpart H approvals generally require a special "restricted distribution" approval process. Unfortunately some drugs, RU-486 for example, approved under subpart H have caused serious  adverse health events in women.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Every drug approved under Subpart H is listed on the Food and Drug Administration's Web site. The vast majority of drugs listed combat HIV or specific types of cancer. One governs the use of thalidomide in treating leprosy. These drugs are supposed to relate to the treatment of life-threatening illnesses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One example of a subpart H approval makes a mockery of the regulatory process by an expedited approval of two extremely risky drugs for abortions. Pregnancy is not an illness and certainly not one that is life-threatening in the first 7 weeks, unless it is a tubal or ectopic pregnancy in which case RU-486 abortions are absolutely contraindicated.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>RU-486 was inappropriately approved in 2000. RU-486 was approved using special "subpart H" regulations to address problems for "certain new drug products that have been studied for their safety and effectiveness in treating serious or life-threatening illnesses . . ." and under restricted distribution conditions due to serious hazards presented by the drug; for example, severe hemorrhage and ectopic pregnancies. This was an inappropriate approval of RU-486 as pregnancy is not normally a life-threatening  condition. Today many health care providers do not follow the limited distribution requirements of RU-486's approval.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>RU-486 has put women's lives at risk. To date there have been six North American deaths related to the use of the RU-486 abortion regimen: five Americans and one Canadian have died from septic shock stemming from infection by the anaerobic bacteria Clostridium sordellii. Five other international deaths have been related to RU-486.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>RU-486 causes serious safety issues. More than 1,000 adverse event reports--232 hospitalizations, 116 blood transfusions, and 88 cases of infection--have been submitted regarding RU-486 and are significant because they confirm that large numbers of mifepristone patients require surgical intervention for infection, hemorrhage, complications from ectopic pregnancy, and incomplete abortions. While lives have been lost from the use of RU-486, not a single case has been documented where RU-486 has  been used to save a woman's life.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>RU-486 is not always effective and when it is not the consequences are dire. I recently learned of a woman who was given RU-486 after she had a seizure. Her physicians assumed that the seizure was life-threatening to the baby she was carrying and gave her RU-486 for a therapeutic abortion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>RU-486 was not effective in her case and the woman carried the baby to term. When the baby was born at a low birth weight, it also suffered from failure to thrive. That baby has had three subsequent brain surgeries due to hydrocephalus. The baby also suffers from idiopathic lymphocytocholitis--an inflammatory disease of the colon, which is extremely rare in children. It is clear that RU-486 not only is unsafe in women, but it is also not completely effective. And when it is not effective, the  results are devastating.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I appreciate the desire to effect safer drugs through this bill. Senator Kennedy and Senator Enzi have done a great deal of work in designing the REMS scheme for certain drugs to ensure that they can be safely and effectively used.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under the risk evaluation and mitigation system, REMS, provisions of this drug safety bill, a drug that has previously been approved under subpart H is deemed to have a REMS. Every REMS is subject to a periodic review. Therefore, RU-486 is deemed to have a REMS and is subject to periodic review.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am pleased that the amendment offered by Senator DeMint was accepted by the full Senate. Senator DeMint's amendment sets a "date certain" REMS assessment for RU-486 to properly evaluate its drug safety risks in women. Women in this country deserve to know the safety risks associated with RU-486.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Who yields time? The Senator from Illinois.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I have an amendment pending and scheduled for a vote this morning on the conflict of interest provision. I believe I have 5 minutes to speak to it.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator does have 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask the chairman and ranking member if this a convenient time to raise the issue?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thank you very much.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Yesterday I proposed this amendment with Senator Bingaman. The Food and Drug Administration Advisory Committees make important decisions, life-and-death decisions. They decide whether the drugs and medical devices which are going to be used in America are safe and effective. In other words, if a person in America has a prescription from a doctor and takes this drug, is it going to be good for their health, or bad?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a critical situation. If they make the wrong decision, if the advisory committee turns a dangerous drug loose on the market, it can have terrible consequences, so these committees literally have life-and-death decisions in their hands on approving drugs, on deciding what the warning labels say, deciding what you have to say in advertising. There might be a danger in these drugs. These advisory committees are the juries of scientific experts who have to make these calls. That is one of  the most important decisions of our Government.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>They are not just life-and-death decisions, they are decisions involving millions and millions of dollars. Drug companies spend a fortune over a long period of time trying to bring a drug to  market. They would hope this will be a drug very popular and profitable for them and their shareholders. That is a natural inclination of a business. So the advisory committee not only decides the safety and efficacy of the product, it makes a decision which has  a direct impact worth millions of dollars to the drug companies involved.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Do you know what we found out? We found out over the last 10 years many people sitting on these advisory committees, those who are actually sitting on the so-called juries and deciding the fate of these drugs, have a conflict of interest. Some of them were already receiving, from the companies that make the drugs, tens of thousands of dollars in consulting fees and speaking fees. It turns out they are on the payroll, some of them, of the very companies on which they are being asked to stand in  judgment. That is a conflict of interest which people cannot accept and I cannot accept.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Food and Drug Administration argues that there are so few experts that we have to sometimes turn to those who have a conflict of interest; there is no place else to go. So occasionally we have to put a waiver in and allow someone to sit on an advisory committee panel who frankly has a financial interest in the company they are making a decision about.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That worries me. Because if you are going to have truly objective jurisdictions, that are right for the consumers of America, that approve drugs or disapprove them on the merits, not because of some inclination or prejudice which you might bring to the table, you don't need these conflicts of interest.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So basically what Senator Bingaman and I have said is: Let's strengthen the conflict-of-interest provisions on advisory committees. Let's make certain that there is confidence in the process. We know what happened with Vioxx. There were 10 people sitting on the advisory committee who had a financial conflict of interest. Had they been removed from the deliberation, the panel would not have recommended they go back on the market, endangering the health of thousands of Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>How can you ever justify that kind of conflict of interest? Our language tightens it. What we are trying to do is to make sure the Food and Drug Administration, with this amendment, limits the number of waivers to one per each advisory committee meeting, allows advisory committees to receive information from guest experts who have a financial conflict but prevents those experts from participating in the deliberations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>They can come in and express their point of view and then leave the room before the deliberation and the vote take place. And also strengthen the provisions to increase the outreach for new experts. The Food and Drug Administration has to do a better job of cultivating this new cadre of trustworthy experts who can serve on these advisory committees.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have 125 medical schools in this country, 90 schools of pharmacy, 40 schools of public health. If the FDA is more aggressive in filling the slots on the advisory committees, we can remove this shadow of doubt which is over this process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, some will argue: Well, the FDA has come forward with draft guidance to improve this. This is draft guidance. They are suggestions. This is law. This tells them they will have to follow the law to avoid these conflicts of interest. This is not an idea that Senator Bingaman and I bring to the table without support.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent, Madam President, to have printed in the Record with my remarks letters from the Consumers Union, the Union of Concerned Scientists, and a broader letter from 11 different organization that support this amendment, that would reduce and eliminate the conflicts of interest when it comes to approving new drugs and medical devices. What is at stake is the integrity of the Food and Drug Administration, the integrity of the process, and making certain we can say, with  a straight face to American consumers, the products that are coming to the market, the life-and-death decisions that are being made that bring them to the market are being made by people who do not have a financial conflict of interest with these devices. I urge my colleagues to support the Durbin-Bingaman amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent these letters be printed in the Record after my remarks.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> The Senator from Wyoming is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I wish to thank the Senator from Massachusetts, Mr. Kennedy, for the statement he made a little bit earlier but mostly for the 2 1/2  years' worth of effort he and I have put into this bill. It has been a very cooperative process between he and I and between the Members on both sides of the aisle on the committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There have been a lot of points raised about food and drug safety, particularly drug safety. It has been a cooperative process, as I mentioned. We have had a lot of questions. We have had some disagreements. But what that has resulted in is going back and getting more information and finding a way that we can come up with a solution that will provide more assurance to Americans that their drugs will be safe.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also wish to thank the people at the Food and Drug Administration for their participation in this lengthy process and providing answers. It has been a long road for this bill. I do strongly urge my colleagues to vote "yes" on final passage and endorse the most comprehensive drug safety overhaul in more than a decade.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Completion of this bill marks yet another significant step in the process, but there is more work to be done. The House needs to pass their version of the legislation, and then the two bodies need to work out differences in the conference committee. My hope and expectation is that the House will act in a reasonable manner and soon because this is widely considered to be must-pass legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This key FDA package includes four reauthorizations that must be done this year, along with the essential new authorities for the FDA to be able to react in a timely way to safety problems that arise after a drug has been brought to the market.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to take a couple minutes to recap for my colleagues the path this legislation has taken thus far. The Senate Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions conducted a top-to-bottom review of the FDA's drug safety and approval processes over 2 years ago. We did that at the same time the Finance Committee was doing a review of the FDA's safety approval processes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We used this information plus information from other Senators to do this bill. The bill is a culmination of that review and our continued evaluation and analysis of the FDA. The changes made in the drug safety components of this legislation are critical to restoring peace of mind to Americans who want to be assured the drugs they purchase to treat illnesses and chronic medical conditions can be relied upon and trusted.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Given the limitations we identified during our review of the FDA, I felt strongly it was necessary to correct those problems and ensure that the FDA has the right tools in the toolbox to address drug safety after the drug is on the market. That is why this bill creates the Risk Evaluation and Mitigation Strategy or REMS. The REMS give the FDA the full toolbox of options for dealing with potential safety problems, even if they are discovered after the drug is first marketed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our goal is to get the drugs to the market quicker and to discover problems faster and get them corrected. With this new toolbox, the FDA has the ability to identify side effects after the drug is marketed through active surveillance. FDA has the authority to request a separate study or clinical trial to learn more about a particular potential safety problem.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>FDA can also obtain timely label changes for the first time under this Risk Evaluation and Mitigation Strategy System. Through the REMS process, the bill also makes several key improvements to how patients get their information through advertising and labeling.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I wish to thank my colleague, Senator Roberts, for his tireless efforts to provide an appropriate balance for direct-to-consumer advertising. It was not an easy task to reconcile some very different opinions. I am so pleased we were able to reach a resolution on this issue that we can all support.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also thank my colleagues, Senator Harkin and Senator Kennedy, for their hard work on this issue. Senator Roberts had planned to vote for <bill type="s" number="1082">S. 1082</bill> but cannot be here today because he is in Kansas showing the President the damage from the tornadoes. I wish him all the best in helping his State recover from that tragedy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The FDA currently has very little authority to require labeling changes after a drug is brought to market. We have included provisions that ensure discussions between FDA and a drug manufacturer regarding the labeling changes come to a close quickly and effectively, rather than relying on FDA's nuclear option, which is pulling the drug completely off the market.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation gives FDA the tools needed to get drugs to the market quickly and efficiently and to respond to potential problems the same way, especially when lives are on the line and people need new drugs and therapies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>FDA currently has no mechanism from active, routine surveillance of potential safety problems. It cannot easily detect safety problems after a drug has been put on the market. This legislation fixes that challenge and ensures that FDA has the right tools to address drug safety after the drug is on the market.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation allows for routine, active safe monitoring using large linked databases, what I call health IT for drug safety. I wish to thank Senator Gregg for being the champion of this provision and ensuring that we crafted this provision properly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Not every drug will need a REMS. However, every drug will need a very active FDA, an FDA with all the necessary tools to identify and quickly manage additional risks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Title IV of the bill before us contains a number of critical provisions to improve children's health. Up to 75 percent of drugs used by kids have not been tested in kids. Without information from pediatric studies, kids are often overdosed, underdosed or receive ineffective treatment. They may suffer needlessly or even die. The Best Pharmaceuticals for Children Act makes drugs safer for kids by creating incentives to perform pediatric drug studies. The incentives have produced astonishing results.  In the 7 years before BPCA incentives, a total of 11 pediatric studies were performed; 7 years, 11 studies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the 10 years since incentives were authorized, at least 132 studies have been completed and more are underway. As a grandfather, I am very happy that the law is in place. If my grandson Trey is sick, I want the drugs he needs to have been tested for kids. All of us want that for our children and grandchildren.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also reauthorizes a companion study, the Pediatric Research Improvement Act, which enables FDA to require a pediatric study if it is not done under the incentive program or through the National Institutes of Health. These two laws work together as a carrot and a stick. I strongly support their reauthorization and continuing to keep them together.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, so far I have only talked about drugs for kids. The bill will also make medical devices safer for kids. Devices designed for adults might not fit in kids. A scaled-down device might fit at first, but a child can grow out of it, so doctors have to jury-rig adult devices, improvise or use more invasive treatments. In addition, the market for kids' devices is small, and the development costs are very high, so few kids' devices get made.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill before us creates new incentives to grow the market for kid's medical devices. I am hopeful these new incentives will be as helpful as the kids' drug incentive. I would like to thank Senator Alexander, Senator Allard, Senator Bond, Senator Dodd, Senator Clinton, and others for their leadership on behalf of kids.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A number of other FDA issues were also addressed during debate of this legislation. The legislation was improved when the Senate adopted a food safety amendment by a vote of 94 to 0. This amendment adds additional food safety provisions to better protect our pet food supply and track when food is adulterated. My colleagues and I also reached consensus that the issue of follow-on biologics will be addressed in the Help Committee early this summer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As my colleagues know, I have some concerns with the Dorgan amendment on drug importation that was adopted last week. I supported the Cochran safety amendment that was also adopted. I did not support the Dorgan approach to foreign drug importation because I do not believe it adequately ensures the safety of the prescription drug supply.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I was pleased to work with my colleague, Senator Dorgan, to add some very significant anticounterfeiting language to the bill in the managers' amendment. But a lot of work still remains. I support the process moving forward, and I will continue to work with my colleagues and Senator Dorgan and Senator Snowe to improve this language during the conference process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, I would like to thank Senator Hatch for his work on the antibiotics and other Hatch-Waxman issues and the follow-on biologics. Senator Hatch was responsible for the first FDA Revitalization Act in 1990, before I was even elected a Member of the Senate. I would like to thank him for helping me to bring that full circle and for the mentoring he has done as a former chairman of the committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I will have a lot more thank-yous to deliver after the votes, but right now we have a bit of business left to conduct.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor and retain the remainder of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Massachusetts.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, how much time remains?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The managers have 14 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I yield myself 4 minutes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Massachusetts is recognized for 4 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I commend my colleague from Illinois and my colleague from New Mexico for their amendment on the conflicts of interest and for working with us to address these issues in appropriations bills during the past year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Their amendment includes many thoughtful proposals I support: including the right to call for the FDA to improve its outreach to experts who have no conflicts of interest and their right to call for greater transparency in the process of waivers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But where I disagree with my friend from Illinois and New Mexico is that there should be an inflexible cap on the number of waivers for conflicts of interests an advisory committee can grant, no matter what the expertise of the scientists involved.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The amendment would impose a one-size-fits all, one waiver per conflict, per committee, relegating any additional members with conflicts to a secondary guest status on the committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The FDA has recently issued a policy not to grant a waiver for a financial interest that exceeds $50,000 and will allow those who receive a waiver for a lesser conflict to serve only as members who can participate in committee discussions but not vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The hallmark of this proposal is the flexibility it gives to ensure the committees will have the adequate expertise. If one or more experts with financial conflicts in excess of $50,000 have expertise that is essential to a committee, the Commissioner can grant the needed waivers. This is expected to be rare, but it can happen if needed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under the Durbin amendment, by contrast, the FDA can grant only one waiver per meeting. There is no flexibility on this point.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The FDA is already experiencing difficulty in filling vacancies on advisory committees. The Durbin amendment, no matter how well-intentioned, would worsen the problems, making it harder to fill critical vacancies and slowing the process of reviewing new medicines.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let's look at the problem FDA is facing now. The Antiviral Drugs Advisory Committee needs six experts with specialized knowledge in the fields of clinical pharmacology, internal medicine, infectious diseases, microbiology, virology, immunology, pediatrics, and other specialties. These experts are needed to review the safety and effectiveness of new medicines for pandemic flu, HIV/AIDS, and other serious infections. The Anesthesiology and Respiratory Therapy Devices Panel has nine vacancies. The  Ophthalmology Panel is in need of nine experts. The Advisory Committee on Peripheral and Central Nervous System Drugs needs six members--on and on down the list, the story is the same, critical vacancies, missed opportunities, and missed expertise. I am not for conflicts of interest. I am against them. But they are a fact of life.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We need policies that reflect the current reality of research in the life sciences. We have increased transparency in this legislation so there will be wide understanding of exactly how decisions are made. This is the most important. In the time of life sciences, we are talking about cross-fertilization of different ideas. Visit the Institute of Medicine. They are talking about the life sciences and work that is taking place. Flip a molecule and it could be relevant to alternative fuels. Flip  it again and it can be relevant to agriculture. Flip it again and it can be relevant to the health sciences. We need all of these disciplines working together. To take one particular requirement and exclude the possibility of getting the best in terms of future scientists, we need integrity in the FDA, integrity in decisionmaking, integrity when they grant waivers. The public ought to have the right to know. We have a balance in here. Hopefully, we will retain it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I withhold the remainder of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Iowa.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I yield myself 5 minutes out of the 10 allotted to me.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="">
    <paragraph>I am going to speak about amendment No. 1039. I ask unanimous consent that Senators MIKULSKI, BROWN, SNOWE, and BINGAMAN be added as cosponsors.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="">
    <paragraph>This amendment is important because <bill type="s" number="1082">S. 1082</bill> does not sufficiently address the underlying problems I have found existing at the Food and Drug Administration during my tenure as chairman of the Senate Finance Committee looking into the problems of the Food and Drug Administration, with the goal in mind that the Federal Government should only be paying for drugs that are safe. That problem is the lack of equality between the Office of New Drugs, which reviews drug applications and  decides whether to approve a drug for marketing, and the Office of Surveillance and Epidemiology, the office which monitors and assesses the safety of drugs postmarketing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many times I quote the Institute of Medicine as justification for my amendment. They recognize this problem. The Institute of Medicine recognizes joint authority between these two offices for postapproval regulatory action related to safety. Even the Consumers Union supports this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Having equality between preapproval and postapproval offices at the FDA is fundamental to real reform. Concentrating on the entire life cycle of drugs  is critical. After all, the vast majority of a drug's life cycle is spent postapproval. In essence, the bill before us promotes the status quo when it comes to the specific role played by the Office of Surveillance. That means the Office of Surveillance and Epidemiology will remain nothing more than a  mere consultant to the Office of New Drugs. This is not acceptable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Amendment 1039 gives the Office of Surveillance sign-off authority. They are experts in postmarketing safety. Even the Institute of Medicine recognized that through their recommendations. Let me be clear: This is not the amendment Senator Dodd and I originally proposed. I still believe an independent postmarketing safety center would be best to solve the problem. But under the process, that is not going to happen. Through this amendment, at least joint postmarketing decisionmaking between  the Office of Surveillance and the Office of New Drugs will allow the office with the postmarketing safety expertise to have a say in what drug safety action will be taken by the FDA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The problem is not only the FDA having enough tools--this bill gives additional tools--it is about FDA managers disregarding concerns raised by its own scientists in the Office of Surveillance and not taking prompt action. This amendment makes common sense when you weigh the evidence I presented over the last 3 years about these problems at the FDA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Opponents of this amendment say it is unnecessary because the bill includes a dispute resolution process with strict deadlines. But that process is for disputes between the FDA and the drug company, not internal disagreements between FDA offices.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Getting down to brass tacks, when the office that looks at postmarketing surveillance is under the thumb of the Office of New Drugs, and the Office of New Drugs says: This drug is safe, they aren't going to want to get egg on their faces by listening to the advice of the Office of Postmarketing Surveillance. If that had been the case, Dr. Graham, in the case of Vioxx, and Dr. Mosholder, in the case of antidepressant drugs, when kids were committing suicide, would have been listened to, but  they weren't until they came as whistleblowers to the Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have to have it so that we have enough independent decisionmaking within the FDA to make sure these drugs are safe.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment provides an approach with checks and balances between the office that approves a drug for marketing and the office that watches a drug once it is on the market.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator has used 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I yield myself such time as I need.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise in opposition to the amendment offered by my colleague from Iowa, Senator Grassley, No. 1039, regarding the joint signing authority under the Office of New Drugs and the Office of Surveillance and Epidemiology. This amendment would add an unnecessary layer of bureaucracy into an agency that we have designed to be nimble and responsive in their process to deal with emerging drug safety issues.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Before the bill is passed, the option after market is to suggest changes or pull the drug off the market, kind of a nuclear option. The underlying bill has surveillance and techniques to notice problems quicker. That is why we will be able to get drugs on to the market faster. The underlying bill does have a dispute resolution process with firm and tight deadlines. There is both one with companies and with staff disputes. It requires by its very nature close collaboration between the two offices.  This amendment only serves to separate what should be a together process and delay what should be a rapid process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to oppose the amendment. The tools we have put in the toolbox will do what the Senator from Iowa wants to have done, which is quick response when there is a problem. I hope we don't add this extra layer of bureaucracy. We looked at this problem through a number of hearings and a number of concerns by members on the committee from both sides and came up with this third way for being able to do it that had not been polarized and that had some agreement. I hope people will stick  with what is in the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor and reserve the remainder of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Iowa.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I yield myself such time as I consume on amendment No. 998. I ask unanimous consent that Senators DODD, SNOWE, and BINGAMAN be added as cosponsors.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="">
    <paragraph>This amendment provides for the application of stronger civil monetary penalties for violations of approved risk evaluation and mitigation strategies. Currently, the bill before us contains penalties, but those penalties won't mean much to large global corporations. In fact, the penalties amount to the cost of doing business. This amendment is intended, then, to give the Food and Drug Administration, the watchdog, some bite along with its bark.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is opposition to having strong civil monetary penalties, but that does not make sense to this Senator. Even the Consumers Union supports this amendment. The reality is, drug companies provide lifesaving pharmaceuticals throughout the world. The pharmaceutical companies make miracles happen. Before a drug is approved, a drug company has an incentive to provide evidence of a drug's effectiveness to the Food and Drug Administration. Without it, they can't sell drugs in this country. However,  once a drug is already being sold in the marketplace, drug companies have almost no incentive to look for and evaluate safety issues. The bottom line is, sometimes market forces guide businesses in a way that may be contrary to the public interest.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have seen this happen many times. For the Food and Drug Administration's new authorities to be meaningful in this legislation, there must be stronger civil monetary penalties in the underlying bill; hence, my amendment. Fines are nothing more than the cost of doing business, and we can't change behavior. More importantly, we can't even deter bad behavior. If a company does what it is supposed to do, a drug company doesn't need to fear any penalties. It is that simple.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask Members of the Senate to support this amendment because it adds real teeth to the FDA's bite.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank Senators KENNEDY and ENZI for the tremendous efforts they went to in bringing this bill to the Senate floor. Again, I want to make this bill even better. They have already included several ideas Senator Dodd and I have shared with them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I reserve the remainder of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Who yields time?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I yield myself such time as I need.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank the Senator from Iowa, Mr. Grassley, for his participation in this bill. It has been tremendous. I mentioned the hearings he held, as we were holding hearings, as there were some crises with food and drugs. The valuable information he shared with us, as well as amendments, as he has correctly stated, are already a part of the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With respect to amendment No. 998, I also have to oppose this amendment regarding the level of civil monetary penalties that can be assessed for violations of the drug safety plan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I appreciate Senator Kennedy's earlier comments. The level of civil penalties in the underlying bill was carefully crafted to reflect existing FDA policies for other regulated products. This is the first time we have had civil penalties in this portion covering the area of food and drugs. It was no small feat to get a consensus position so that we could have civil penalties in the bill, and I think that is necessary.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is a precedent for the levels that we have selected, the current levels. Medical devices has the same levels. I reiterate that has never before been available to the FDA as a tool on drug safety issues, but we are providing it as a tool. Furthermore, I believe the very threat of a civil penalty is sufficient to deter bad behavior. This is the name-and-shame principle. The fine may be affordable to the company, but the loss of reputation is not.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to oppose this amendment as well. This is not the end of the process. I suspect the House will have something to say on it, as I have mentioned to the Senator from Iowa before. There will be additional negotiations, I am certain, on civil penalties. I hope we will stick with the civil penalties that have a basis in the medical devices as some basis from which to negotiate  and would hope that the Senate position will be the one that is in the bill. I ask people to oppose the amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor and reserve the remainder of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Massachusetts.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, how much time do I have?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator has 10 minutes remaining.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I yield myself 5 minutes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I support the comments Senator Enzi has made about the fines. We are going to have to look at this in conference, and it is clear the House is going to raise the fines, it seems to me, as Senator Enzi pointed out. So we will have a chance to look at it in conference. I think that is probably the best way to do it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me point out two other items--something I think most Americans have been concerned about in recent times. It was reported today that China has detained managers from two companies linked to contaminated foods. As a first step, we need to determine the extent of the contamination and see how far into the food supply this internal adulteration has gone.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Yesterday's report from the FDA that contaminated wheat flour from China was fed to fish raised for human consumption is another example of the need for a comprehensive examination of our food safety system. We also found out yesterday that what we thought was contaminated highly processed wheat gluten was actually unprocessed wheat flour spiked with melamine to make it appear to be higher quality.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A month ago, the FDA warned that certain types of pet food were suspected of being contaminated. Then, there were more kinds of pet food. Then it was hogs being fed the contaminated food, but those had been caught before human consumption. Then we found out that tens of millions of chickens eaten by people had been fed the tainted food. Yesterday, we were informed that fish raised for human consumption had been fed contaminated food.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The incremental expansion of this crisis raises serious concerns about the FDA's ability to rapidly identify the source of food-related problems and bring to bear the effective tools. We know the issue of food safety is divided into different kinds of committees, but it has to be of concern to American families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have included strong new protections to allow FDA to better ensure the safety of human and pet foods, but this is a first step. Senator Enzi and Senator Durbin have joined with me and others and we are committed to taking a comprehensive look at the safety of our food supply and we are committed to taking the actions, with our colleagues, needed to ensure that the foods our families and pets eat are as safe as possible.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As part of the managers' package adopted last night, we included important new provisions to allow the FDA to oversee the safety of farm-raised fish. We owe this--this is a story in the paper today--to Senators LINCOLN and PRYOR and SESSIONS on this important proposal.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This morning's newspaper talks about doctors reaping millions for the use of anemia drugs. People are going to wonder what we are doing in this bill, if anything, on this issue. Well, this is not what the FDA does exactly. It is safety and efficacy. But there are different agencies in what they call health research and quality. AHRQ has responsibility for this. We will be in touch with them to examine this issue and provide better guidance and recommendations to doctors and patients.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The FDA does not practice medicine. But this kind of action has to be of concern because it reflects itself in increased costs to the American consumer, and it does raise health issues as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So this is illustrative of the range of different areas of concerns the American families have. We believe we have made very important and substantial progress in trying to address those questions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, at this time I will withhold the remainder of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Who yields time?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I have to make some comments in regard to the other amendment we will be voting on this morning, which I also hope people will oppose, and that is amendment No. 1034, offered by my colleague from Illinois, Senator Durbin.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The FDA relies on 30 advisory committees to provide independent expert advice, which lends credibility to the product review process and informs consumers of trends and product development. Given the complex issues that are considered by the FDA, outside help is needed and beneficial, and it is advisory. The decisions are not made by the committees. They advise. But any scientist who is expert enough to merit interest by the FDA has almost certainly merited interest by other entities, such as  granting agencies and companies involved in the field.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment would seriously limit the FDA's ability to access the best experts in the field to assist the Agency with its decisionmaking process. It would restrict FDA to granting only one waiver per committee meeting.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>How would the FDA decide who gets that one waiver? Who is more worthy, the toxicologist, the drug safety expert, the specialist in women's health? These are not easy answers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The FDA, in March, released a guidance document outlining strict new limits on evaluating advisory personnel committee members for service. The comment period on this guidance has not even closed. It is premature to void that guidance before we even know whether and how it will work.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let's take a step back and think about what might happen if we do not allow people who have worked with or for industry to be involved in an advisory committee meeting.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Louis Pasteur was a brilliant microbiologist who revolutionized human food and health safety. Every time you buy milk in the grocery store, you are benefiting from his contributions to society. But under the Durbin amendment, Pasteur would probably not have been able to serve on any advisory committee. You see, Pasteur's research was funded by the wine industry.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, do you want to prevent the FDA from benefiting from the advice of the best and the brightest they have to offer? We do want to move so there are not conflicts of interest. I think the guidelines that are out there, if finalized, will do that. The amendment almost gets into a position of not conflicts of interest but biases--much harder to determine. If we are going to do that, we will never be able to have anybody on any of the committees, particularly with the expertise we need.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I ask we oppose that amendment as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield time to the Republican leader.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Republican leader is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300072" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I thank my friend from Wyoming.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I wish to take a moment to congratulate Senator Enzi on this wonderful, bipartisan effort he has been engaged in with our friend from Massachusetts, Senator Kennedy. They have worked tirelessly for the past 3 weeks, through markup and floor consideration.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also wish to commend Senator Gregg, who worked very hard with Senator Enzi to reach a bipartisan compromise on this important measure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I particularly wish to note Senator Roberts was instrumental in working out the problems with direct-to-consumer advertising provisions. I know he would have liked to have been here today to support this bill, but he is out in Kansas with the President touring hurricane damage in his State.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Also, I wish to commend Senator Cochran. We appreciate his efforts to ensure that any proposal to bring drugs in from other countries must be certified by the Secretary of Health and Human Services as safe for the American people.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So again, I thank the Senator from Wyoming for his extraordinary accomplishment in moving this important, bipartisan legislation forward.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With that, I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Who yields time?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I think we are about--I see my friend from Iowa on his feet so I will withhold. I will make a very brief comment at the very end, so I withhold.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Iowa.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I yield myself such time as I might consume. I only have 2 1/2  minutes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On the very important amendment about making sure there is adequate cooperation and dialog between the Office of New Drugs and the Office of Postmarket Surveillance, I wish to make clear this amendment is not, as some have characterized it, about process. It seems to me this is the ultimate of insurance to do the right thing to protect the American people on the safety of drugs. It is based on so many examples I found over the last 3 years, where there was not the respect for the Office of Postmarketing  Surveillance there ought to be from the Office of New Drugs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A lot of safety issues would not have gotten out if we had not had a lot of red-blooded, patriotic whistleblowers who would come to Congress, such as Dr. Graham, for instance, in the case of Vioxx, such as Dr. Mosholder, in the case of depressants for children who were committing suicide. This ended up with Vioxx coming off the market. This ended up with black-box safety measures in the case of the antidepressants.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Institute of Medicine has recognized the importance of these two groups within the FDA working very closely together on making a determination on postmarketing surveillance. That is what my amendment does. It makes sure this process works the way the Institute of Medicine indicated it should.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So as you consider voting on this amendment, I ask my colleagues--himself or herself--one basic question before voting: Since the Institute of Medicine recommends equality between the preapproval process--in other words, before a drug is marketed--and the postapproval process at the FDA, why not vote for this amendment and improve postmarketing safety for the American people?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Who yields time?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, in a few minutes, we will be prepared to vote. I yield myself 3 or 4 minutes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I will include in the Record, at the conclusion of this debate, the names of the staff on our committee who have done superb work. It has been extraordinary and on both sides of the aisle. We are enormously appreciative and grateful.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am also personally appreciative of the work of my friend and colleague, the Senator from Ohio, Mr. Brown, who was here yesterday and filled in. I had the opportunity to travel to Ireland, where they signed and put in place, after 400 years of struggle, the democratic institutions over there, in a very moving ceremony, which President Bush had supported--a very special day.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation is a reflection of 2 1/2  years of hearings under the leadership of Senator Enzi, when he was chair of the committee, and myself. It incorporates the Institute of Medicine's recommendations, by and large, after they had months and months of hearings. The American people ought to understand the legislation, which reflects bipartisan support in the Senate, is a reflection of the best judgments we could have as a result of months and years of working on this issue and of  the membership on it. We are enormously grateful.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation is going to make the prescription drugs our families take safer and our food safer. That is very important. It is going to ensure that the Agency has resources to do follow-on reviews to continue its important function to be the world leader, the gold standard, for safety for our people and the example for the rest of the world. So this is very important legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are reminded every day of the additional kinds of challenges we are facing in terms of safety for our families. We are very aware of it. Senator Enzi and I and the members of our committee are going to continue our study, our review, and continue our activity to ensure we are going to have the best in terms of a safe and secure food supply, pharmaceutical supply, and take advantage of this life science century so every American is going to have the best and, hopefully, at the most  reasonable price, so they can have healthier and stronger families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I yield back my remaining time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Wyoming is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I have a number of people I need to thank for their efforts on this bill, and I will do that following the vote so that we don't hold up the vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There has been tremendous cooperation, effort, knowledge, and capability that has been involved, not just of the Senators but also of the staffs. The staffs on both sides of the aisle have spent countless hours on this, even on weekends. In fact, I know of one day on one weekend they worked about 20 hours together to pull this thing together and get some of the final issues worked out. But they worked the entire weekend for at least the last three weekends. They will look forward to a little  time to rest, and we will probably give them a day. That is because we have so many things happening in the committee, and Senator Kennedy and I are determined to get a lot of that done to help the American people with their health and with their education and in the area of workplace safety and training and pensions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But on this bill, I hope people will join us in supporting it. Of course I hope they will join us in maintaining a balance to take it to conference committee and to defeat the three amendments that are before us this morning.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield back the remainder of my time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Under the previous order, there will be 2 minutes for debate equally divided prior to a vote in relation to amendment No. 1039.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I will speak in favor of 1039. I have 30 seconds, did you say, or 1 minute?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator has 1 minute.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, one of the issues that has been very much a shortcoming within the FDA besides lack of respect for the scientific process, but it is involved in the issue of this amendment as well, is whether scientists in the FDA who have the responsibility of postmarketing surveillance get the respect they ought to from the Office of New Drugs that previously had approved the drug. We have found in the case of Vioxx, in the case of antidepressants for children, and in a lot of  other areas as well that this has just not been the case.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My amendment will follow the Institute of Medicine recommendation and make sure there is adequate time and consideration given to postmarketing surveillance, the same as there is to the approval of the drug in the first place. So I ask for approval of this amendment. It is backed by the Institute of Medicine.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Wyoming is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I oppose the amendment. I appreciate the thought that went into it, and I know that before we did this bill and put into place some of the processes we have in the toolbox for postapproval--which, nevertheless, existed before for the FDA--this amendment would have been necessary. But in light of the toolbox we provide and the dispute resolution we have, it would add an unnecessary layer of bureaucracy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have designed the bill to be a nimble and responsive process to deal with emerging drug safety issues. We want drugs on the market faster, we want to know about anything that goes wrong faster, and we think that is built into it. We do have a dispute resolution in the bill with tight guidelines that will result in rapid approvals. We don't need the additional process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The amendment separates what should be together and delays what  should be rapid. So I urge my colleagues to oppose the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask for the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there a sufficient second? There appears to be a sufficient second.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, parliamentary inquiry: Could we ask unanimous consent that we have the yeas and nays on the other two amendments? I ask unanimous consent that it be in order now for the yeas and nays on the other two amendments and then on final passage.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection? Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the Chair.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there a sufficient second on the remaining amendments? There appears to be a sufficient second. The yeas and nays are ordered on the remaining amendments as well.</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will call the roll.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>I announce that the Senator from Indiana (Mr. BAYH) and the Senator from South Dakota (Mr. JOHNSON) are necessarily absent.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300069" topic="">
    <paragraph>The following Senators are necessarily absent: the Senator from Kansas (Mr. BROWNBACK), the Senator from Idaho (Mr. CRAPO), the Senator from Arizona (Mr. MCCAIN), the Senator from Kansas (Mr. ROBERTS), and the Senator from Louisiana (Mr. VITTER).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Are there any other Senators in the Chamber desiring to vote?</chair>
  <narrative>The result was announced--yeas 46, nays 47, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300041" topic="">
    <paragraph>I move to reconsider the vote, and I move to lay that motion on the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The motion to lay on the table was agreed to.</narrative>
  <chair> Under the previous order, there will be 2 minutes for debate equally divided prior to a vote in relation to amendment No. 998.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="">
    <paragraph>I have 1 minute?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> One minute.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, the issue is the level of civil and monetary penalties. If the fines are nothing more than the cost of doing business, you can't change behavior and you can't deter bad behavior. My feeling is the levels in this underlying bill are not high enough to get the attention of the drug companies. After all, if a company does what it is supposed to do, a drug company doesn't need to fear any penalties. It is that simple.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask my colleagues to support my amendment so it has real teeth.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Wyoming.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I have to oppose this amendment in keeping with having a balance in the bill that we have agreed on. This is the first time civil monetary penalties have been assessed for violations of the drug safety plan. That is what is in our bill. We do have civil penalties in the bill. The civil penalties are the same as the medical devices. That is how we decided at what level to do it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We added civil penalties, and there will be more work done on this issue probably as we get to conference. I want to establish the fact that civil penalties are in the bill. I want to arrive at the level that the civil penalties are assessed with more consideration and with debate with the House. This amendment could burden small businesses and create problems there.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Civil penalties are part of the bill we put together with a compromise. I ask that my colleagues vote against the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on agreeing to amendment No. 998. The yeas and nays have been ordered. The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>I announce that the Senator from South Dakota (Mr. Johnson) is necessarily absent</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300069" topic="">
    <paragraph>The following Senators are necessarily absent: the Senator from Kansas (Mr. Brownback), the Senator from Idaho (Mr. Crapo), the Senator from Arizona (Mr. McCain), the Senator from Kansas (Mr. Roberts), and the Senator from Louisiana (Mr. Vitter).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Are there any other Senators in the Chamber desiring to vote?</chair>
  <narrative>The result was announced--yeas 64, nays 30, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I move to reconsider the vote and to lay that motion on the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The motion to lay on the table was agreed to.</narrative>
  <chair> Under the previous order, there will be 2 minutes of debate, equally divided, prior to a vote in relation to amendment No. 1034.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, 2 years ago, an advisory committee of the FDA sat down to judge painkiller drugs and whether they were safe to sell to America. They made the recommendation that selling Vioxx to America was safe. Ten of the members of that advisory committee had a financial conflict of interest when they made the decision. Had those 10 members with the conflict not been there, the panel would not have recommended keeping those drugs on the market.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment Senator Bingaman and I offer will take the conflict of interest out of the advisory committees. We will allow one waiver for someone with a conflict of interest, and we will say that others who participate as guest experts have to leave the room before any deliberation or vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We will hear from the other side that the Food and Drug Administration has an idea of how they are going to change this rule at some future time.  This is not an idea we are proposing, it is a law--a law to protect the integrity of the advisory committees and the drugs and medical devices which are sold across America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, the FDA has a new policy, a new procedure out there.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Basically, what the Durbin amendment says is, one size fits all. That concept has been rejected by the Europeans, rejected by the Canadians, and basically rejected by the Institute of Medicine. In this life science century, researchers who are looking at cancer drugs may be examining 15 different components. Are we going to say that if a conflict exists with one of those components that they meet the Durbin amendment standard. This would exclude some of the most knowledgeable people in this country  from participating in the review of breakthrough drugs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The FDA says they have adopted transparency. Everyone in the Senate is going to know who sits on the advisory committees. There is a financial limitation of $50,000 at the FDA now. Everyone is going to know the existence of any conflicts. It is a new day out there. We have now have transparency, but virtually everyone who understands that we are in the life science century says we have to have the best scientific minds at the table, and so the Institute of Medicine said: Don't go with a one-size-fits-all,  which the Durbin amendment does.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> All time has expired.</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will call the roll.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>I announce that the Senator from South Dakota (Mr. Johnson) is necessarily absent.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300069" topic="">
    <paragraph>The following Senators are necessarily absent: the Senator from Kansas (Mr. Brownback), the Senator from Idaho (Mr. Crapo), the Senator from Arizona (Mr. McCain), the Senator from Kansas (Mr. Roberts), and the Senator from Louisiana (Mr. Vitter).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Are there any other Senators in the Chamber desiring to vote?</chair>
  <narrative>The result was announced--yeas 47, nays 47, as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> Under the previous order, the committee substitute amendment, as modified and amended, is agreed to, the motion to reconsider is considered made and laid upon the table, and the cloture motion on the bill is withdrawn.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask for the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there a sufficient second? There is a sufficient second.</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will call the roll.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>I announce that the Senator from South Dakota (Mr. Johnson) is necessarily absent.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300069" topic="">
    <paragraph>The following Senators are necessarily absent: the Senator from Kansas (Mr. Brownback), the Senator from Idaho (Mr. Crapo), the Senator from Arizona (Mr. McCain), the Senator from Kansas (Mr. Roberts), and the Senator from Louisiana (Mr. Vitter).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Are there any other Senators in the Chamber desiring to vote?</chair>
  <narrative>The result was announced--yeas 93, nays 1, as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> Under the previous order, the motion to reconsider is considered made and laid upon the table, and the title amendment which is at the desk is agreed to, and the motion to reconsider is considered made and laid upon the table.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that Senator Kennedy and I have a few minutes here to thank some of the people involved. I have checked with the people who would be involved with the judges, and they have no objection.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300041" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I do want to take a few minutes to thank the leaders, particularly the majority leader, who, after some difficulties last week, helped to smooth some things out and make it possible for us to move on a little bit on the bill. His coordination and leadership were indispensable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank the Republican leader for the way he participated in the bill and, again, made sure we were working across the aisle and getting difficulties smoothed out.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I definitely wish to thank the chairman of the committee for the outstanding work he did through the entire process. As we mentioned a number of times, it has been a very lengthy process, but he has always been so forthright and knowledgeable and willing to work under all kinds of circumstances and difficulties. Because of his dedication and abilities, I have learned a lot about running the committee from him and I have learned a lot about getting a bill passed from him and have enjoyed working  with him over the last 2 years on a number of bills.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank the staff people who have worked so hard. They have spent many evenings and even weekends away from their homes. They worked virtually through the night to get some of these issues worked out. The way we work a bill, it is a work in progress until it is finished. It is not finished yet; we have got to work with the House side yet, and we will do that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is such an important bill for the country. My HELP team worked overtime to get this bill to the floor and passed in the Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would first like to thank my health policy director, Shana Christrup. Shana was promoted to her leadership position in January of this year. She took ahold of the reins, has incredible knowledge, dedication, and negotiating experience and expertise that helped bring this bill to fruition.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also want to greatly thank Amy Muhlberg, our crackerjack expert who knows all things FDA. Her knowledge and drafting skills were central to this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank Keith Flanagan for his work on the children's statutes in this bill, and Dave Schmickel, who is our resident drug patent expert, for his ongoing work on follow-on biologics.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Others on the team I would like to thank include Todd Spangler and Brittany Moore, who provided the required backup that goes with moving a bill of this magnitude.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, I thank my staff director, Katherine McGuire, whose steady hand in negotiating and communication skills and ability to juggle a number of issues at the same time and tap dance and do all sorts of things that make these bills possible provided the cement for the entire process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would also like to thank Ilyse Schuman, my chief counsel, for her precision and attention to detail.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank Amy Angelier Shank for her great work on the budget aspects of the bill; my press team, Craig Orfield and Mike Mahaffey; and my chief of staff, Flip McConnaughey, who was good at putting out brushfires throughout the process and kind of maintaining the core to our whole process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On Senator Kennedy's staff, I would like to thank Michael Myers, David Bowen, David Dorsey, Missy Rohrbach, Jeff Teitz, David Noll, and Tom Kraus. Senator Kennedy's staffers were reasonable negotiators throughout the process and open and patient to hearing all sides of any issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As I mentioned before, Senator Hatch was responsible for the first FDA Revitalization Act, and I would like to thank him and his staff, Patty DeLoatche and Trish Knight, for helping me with the second FDA Revitalization Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With Senator Gregg's office, and for his assistance with the health IT for drug safety, I thank Dave Fisher and Liz Wroe.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Stephanie Carlton from Senator Coburn's staff and Jenny Ware with Senator Burr were also integral to many parts of the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to thank my colleague from Kansas, Senator Roberts, and his staff, Jennifer Swenson, Kate Anderson, and Mike Seyfert, for their incredible work on our direct-to-consumer advertising.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also thank my colleague, Senator Harkin, and his staffer, Mike Woody, for his hard work on the issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank Meghan Hauck, who is with Senator McConnell, for her great assistance throughout the process and her tireless hours.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank Isaac Edwards, Amanda Makki, Tyler Thompson, Jennifer Claypool, and Mary-Sumpter Johnson.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, there is a group of people without whom none of this would have happened. They work behind the scenes and make the rest of us look good. I am talking about the dedicated folks at legislative counsel, Stacy Kern-Scheerer, Bill Baird, Amy Gaynor, and the rest of the legislative counsel team. They have drafted forever on this, and redrafted, helped make this concept a reality. They did it with class, grace, patience, kindness, and I cannot thank them enough.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Massachusetts.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, one of the great joys of serving in the Senate has been working with my friend and colleague from Wyoming, Senator Enzi, on different legislation. He does it the old-fashioned way. He believes that what we ought to do is have the hearings on the problem and then listen to various alternatives and then try to work out a solution and carry the process forward. That is the old-fashioned way. Today people look at different issues, file bills, and try and ward  off interventions. He has a deep-seated conservative philosophical commitment. He and I differ on some matters, but we always try to find common ground. We have been able to find it certainly on this legislation and many other pieces of legislation. I look forward to continuing this tradition. I am personally grateful to him for all his help in guiding us. You can see the closeness of these votes. This is enormously important</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I see Sherrod Brown, the Senator from Ohio, was kind enough yesterday to stand in for me when I had the great honor to witness the coming together in Northern Ireland after 400 years of  conflict and the establishment of democratic institutions in a very momentous historical moment. When I left Monday night, there was a certain element of chaos surrounding this bill, and coming back early this morning, under the great work of Senator Enzi  and Senator Brown, we had an orderly path to proceed. He is knowledgeable about health issues and had a very distinguished record on health policy before he came to the Senate. He has not missed a beat in working through the issues. He has been invaluable to me personally and to our committee. I thank Senator Brown for all of his good work.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Quickly: I would like to thank my friend, Senator Dodd for his work on all of the issues that affect kids' drugs and devices; Senator Clinton for her work on drugs and devices; Senator Mikulski for her work on the issues of transparency, enormously important provisions on which this legislation depends; Senator Hatch for his work on antibiotics; Senator Gregg for his work on the databases and Web portal; Senators ROBERTS and HARKIN for  their work on the direct to consumer advertising issue, which involves a lot of different policy issues and a lot of emotion and feeling. They worked very hard with the staff, we had very solid recommendations on this; Senator Stabenow for her work on the citizens' petitions in order to help get product onto the markets in a quicker way. I would also like to thank Senator Brown and Senator Brownback, for their enormously creative innovative idea with regard to neglected diseases. This</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These are some of the items. Again, we thank staff members: From my staff, Dave Bowen, David Dorsey, David Noll, and Caya Lewis, all who have spent a great deal of time and effort over these past weeks, Michael Myers and Carmel Martin and Missy Rohrbach, Tom Kraus, I thank them enormously.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I express appreciation to Senator Enzi's staff. If people try to find solutions, rather than perpetuate differences, it makes an enormous difference. That was certainly true of all the staffs on our committee. I thank Amy Muhlberg and David Schmickel and Keith Flanagan and Katherine McGuire, Shana Christrup; Senator Brown's staff: Ellie Dehoney; Senator Dodd: Tamar Magarik; Senator Mikulski: Ellen-Marie Whelan; Senator Hatch's staff: Patty DeLoatche,  and Trisha Knight; Mike Woody from Senator Harkin; Senator Gregg: Liz Wroe; Senator Roberts: Jennifer Swenson, Mike Seyfert, and Kate Anderson; Senator Clinton's staff: Ann Gavaghan and Andrea Palm. I am sure I might have missed someone, but we will make sure they are included in the RECORD.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We thank all our colleagues and friends. We look forward to meeting with the House and reflecting the Senate's best judgment on the legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, over the past 10 days we have had a good debate about important issues affecting the safety of our Nation's citizens, about the drugs they use when they are ill, and about the food they eat every day.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="1082">S. 1082</bill> will reauthorize two important user fee programs at the FDA. First among these is the prescription drug user fee program. In 2008, the program is projected to supply the FDA with nearly $400 million to help support new drug reviews and monitor the safety of drugs once they are approved and on the market. Additionally, the bill will reauthorize the medical device user fee program, which subsidizes the medical device review process. Both these programs speed new medical products to patients  by enhancing the resources the FDA can devote to medical product review, without changing the standards that must be met for FDA approval or clearance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These resources to enhance speedy access to drugs and biologics are balanced with several significant provisions that will improve postapproval drug safety. A public-private partnership involving the FDA will build a network of health care databases to gather far better information about the safety risks of prescription drugs. Expanded drug user fees would also be used to develop this active surveillance system for all FDA approved drugs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill will create an additional risk-based method for approving and monitoring new drugs and biologics, called risk evaluation and mitigation strategies, or REMS. A REMS consists of a flexible collection of tools that the agency can apply to address the unique risks associated with a new drug. From labeling changes to postapproval safety studies to measures to assure safe use of a drug, the bill gives FDA important new authorities to address safety issues that arise after a drug is approved.  For the first time, civil money penalties will deter noncompliance. The bill increases drug user fees to implement the REMS and enhance the postapproval drug safety system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Furthermore, this legislation would improve transparency, strengthen the agency's science-based culture, and inspire the trust of the American public. For example, it would require the FDA to identify and disclose conflicts of interest among advisory committee members who provide the agency expert scientific recommendations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It would also improve access to information for patients and health care providers by launching a pubic database with the results of clinical trials. A clinical trials registry would enhance patient enrollment and provide a mechanism to track the progress of clinical trials.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, the legislation would establish the Reagan-Udall Foundation for the FDA to head collaborative research projects, among the FDA, academic institutions, and industry intended to improve medical product development and evaluation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I appreciate Senator Dodd and Senator Clinton's leadership to promote the safety of drugs and devices used to treat children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank Senator Roberts and Senator Harkin for working with Senator Enzi and me to design constitutionally sound, effective, and feasible controls on DTC advertising. The amendment we produced will ensure the information that ads provide is accurate, clear, and conspicuous without imposing a moratorium.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I commend Senators Stabenow, Brown, Lott, Thune, Coburn, and Hatch for coming to a solution on the issue of citizens' petitions. They were able to craft an amendment that ensures that only citizens' petitions with meritorious claims could delay approval of a generic drug and that frivolous petitions will not lead to unwarranted delays in the approval of new generic drugs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I applaud Senator Brownback and Senator Brown for their novel proposal to encourage investment in new medicines for neglected tropical diseases. Their proposal entitles companies that develop new therapies or vaccines to a voucher allowing them a  priority review at the FDA for a product of their choosing. It would provide pharmaceutical manufacturers a significant incentive without raising costs to consumers or relaxing the safety standards applied to the drug given priority review.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would also like to draw attention to the essential amendment introduced by Senator Hatch, with important contributions from Senators Brown, Burr, Stabenow, and others. The amendment would close a loophole that did away with the incentive to bring old but never approved antibiotics to market. It would also establish a public process to identify drug-resistant infections that are orphan diseases and that could be treated with orphan drugs. Additionally, the amendment would make  certain molecules that are a part of old active ingredients eligible for recognition as new active ingredients, provided they will be used for a new indication. This provision includes limits that would prevent pharmaceutical manufacturers from abusing the process to extend the life of old active ingredient drugs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, I am grateful to my friend, Senator Enzi, for his leadership and commitment to addressing prescription drug safety. We have worked together for over 2 1/2  years to develop this legislation, and I am proud of where we are today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have already thanked a number of people, and I would also like to thank, on Senator Enzi's staff, Ilyse Schuman, and on my own staff, Stacy Sachs, Molly Nicholson, Jeff Teitz, and Charlotte Burrows, and two of my interns, Ashley Bennett and Lara Mounir.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would also like to thank the many other staff members, both on and off the committee, who did such great work on this bill: Carmen Green, Nancy Hardt, Paula Burg, Lisa German, Jessica Gerrity, Dora Hughes, Ed Ramos, Ben Klein, Jim Esquea, David Lazarus, Lisa Layman, Jenny Ware, Mary-Sumpter Johnson, Stephanie Carlton, and Jennifer Claypool.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would also like to thank the legislative counsels Bill Baird, Amy Gaynor, and Stacey Kern-Scheerer for all of their hard work on this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300083" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today the Senate voted to approve <bill type="s" number="1082">S. 1082</bill>, the Food and Drug Administration Revitalization Act. I am very pleased the Senate took this action and I now look forward to its consideration in the House.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, I was not present to vote for the bill, but I would like the record to reflect that I had planned to vote in favor of this legislation. Just last weekend, Kansas experienced a horrible disaster when a tornado devastated an entire community and took the lives of several Kansans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Late last Friday evening, the town of Greensburg, KS, was literally wiped off the map by an enormous tornado. As a result of this and storms associated with the system, 12 Kansans are confirmed dead, and all of the 1500 residents of Greensburg have been displaced. What we have experienced in Greensburg is unlike any other event in recent Kansas history. The hospital is gone, the schools are gone, every church is gone, virtually every business in the community is gone, including all of Main Street.  Estimates are that fully 95 percent of the structures in the town are damaged or destroyed. Because of this devastation, I invited President Bush to come to Greensburg, KS, and view the damage from this unspeakable disaster. Today, President Bush is in Greensburg, and I, along with other members of the Kansas congressional delegation, are showing him the devastation this community has experienced, so I could not be present to vote for <bill type="s" number="1082">S. 1082</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, I want my colleagues to know that I support this legislation and would have voted in favor of the bill if I were present. I believe <bill type="s" number="1082">S. 1082</bill> will give FDA the tools to ensure drug safety and will renew some very important prescription drug and medical device programs. I am also pleased the bill includes an amendment I sponsored with Senators Harkin, Burr, and Coburn to improve the drug advertisement provisions in the underlying bill. This amendment was accepted  unanimously by the Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our amendment addresses the first amendment concerns with the advertising provisions in the original bill and gives the FDA the tools they need to protect the public from false or misleading prescription drug advertisements. We believe this amendment is a more commonsense approach to dealing with prescription drug advertisements and ensures the public will get truthful and accurate information about new prescription drugs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I especially want to thank Chairman Kennedy, Ranking Member Enzi, and Senator Harkin for their leadership and hard work on this issue. I also thank Senators Burr and Coburn for their cooperation and cosponsorship of my amendment. This amendment represents the result of our efforts to achieve an outcome that is acceptable to all of us. The agreement that was accepted today is a fair compromise that addresses the concerns of all of the Members involved</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I voted against Senator Durbin's amendment because it would have forced the removal of the best scientific minds from the oversight of the safety of our Nation's food and prescription drug approval process. Though well intentioned, the Durbin amendment would have limited the advice available to the Food and Drug Administration for critical decisions pertaining to consumer safety. I will support the efforts to ensure that conflicts of interest do not interfere  with the safety of the American people, and I will work to ensure that the country's best experts continue to secure our medications and food supply.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
