<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1185422400" ordinal="64" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <narrative>AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET -- (Senate - July 26, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="10207">S10207</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Thursday, July 26, 2007, at 10 a.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building. The purpose of this hearing is to explore U.S. readiness for and the consumer impact of the nationwide transition from analog television broadcasting to digital television broadcasting.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENVIRONMENT AND PUBLIC WORKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Environment and Public Works be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, July 26, 2007 at 10 a.m., in room 406 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building in order to conduct a hearing entitled, "Examining the Case for the California Waiver: An Update from EPA."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Thursday, July 26, 2007, at 2:30 p.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building. The hearing will focus on proposed efforts to improve the safety of the Nation's railroads through targeting highway-rail grade crossing safety, reducing employee hours of service and fatigue, and developing and using new rail  safety technology.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="COMMITTEE ON FINANCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Finance meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, July 26, 2007, at 3 p.m., in room 215 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building, to consider <bill type="s" number="1607">S. 1607</bill>, the "Currency Exchange Rate Oversight Reform Act of 2007," with a substitute amendment, and to consider favorably reporting pending nominees who have responded to all written questions and been cleared by both sides.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, July 26, 2007, at 9:30 a.m. to hold a hearing on Extraordinary Rendition.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, July 26, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. to hold a hearing on the United Nations Human Rights Council.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="COMMITTEE ON HEALTH, EDUCATION, LABOR, AND PENSIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions be authorized to meet in executive session during the session of the Senate on Thursday, July 26, 2007 at 9:30 a.m. in SR-325. We will be considering the following:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Agenda</paragraph>
    <paragraph>1. <bill type="s" number="625">S. 625</bill>, Family Smoking Prevention and Tobacco Control Act</paragraph>
    <paragraph>2. <bill type="s" number="1183">S. 1183</bill>, Christopher and Dana Reeve Paralysis Act</paragraph>
    <paragraph>3. <bill type="s" number="579">S. 579</bill>, Breast Cancer and Environmental Research Act of 2007</paragraph>
    <paragraph>4. <bill type="s" number="898">S. 898</bill>, Alzheimer's Breakthrough Act of 2007</paragraph>
    <paragraph>5. <bill type="s" number="1858">S. 1858</bill>, Newborn Screening Saves Lives Act of 2007</paragraph>
    <paragraph>6. The following nominations:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Diane Auer Jones, of Maryland, to be Assistant Secretary for Postsecondary Education, Department of Education</paragraph>
    <paragraph>David C. Geary, of Missouri, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the National Board for Education Sciences</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Miguel Campaneria, of Puerto Rico, to be a Member of the National Council on the Arts</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="COMMITTEE ON INDIAN AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Indian Affairs be authorized to meet Thursday, July 26, 2007, at 9:30 a.m. in room 485 of the Russell Senate Office Building to conduct a hearing on the nomination of Charles W. Grim to be Director of the Indian Health Service.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President I ask uanimous consent that the Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate in order to conduct a markup on Thursday, July 26, 2007, at 10 a.m. in SD-226.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Agenda</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I. Bills: S.----, School Safety and Law Enforcement Improvements Act  (Chairman's mark); <bill type="s" number="1060">S. 1060</bill>, Recidivism Reduction &amp; Second Chance Act of 2007 (Biden, Specter, Brownback, Leahy, Kennedy, Schumer, Whitehouse, Durbin); <bill type="s" number="453">S. 453</bill>, Deceptive Practices and Voter Intimidation Prevention Act of 2007 (Obama, Schumer, Leahy, Cardin, Feingold, Feinstein, Kennedy, Whitehouse); and <bill type="s" number="1692">S. 1692</bill>, A bill to grant a Federal Charter to Korean War Veterans Association (Cardin,  Isakson, Kennedy).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>II. Nomination: Rosa Emilia Rodriguez-Velez to be United States Attorney for the District of Puerto Rico.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection,it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="SELECT COMMITTEE ON INTELLIGENCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Select Committee on Intelligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on July 26, 2007 at 2:30 p.m. to hold a closed hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON WATER AND POWER">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on Water and Power of the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Thursday, July 26, 2007 at 2:30 p.m. in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the hearing is to receive testimony on the following bills: <bill type="s" number="300">S. 300</bill>, to authorize appropriations for the Bureau of Reclamation to carry out the Lower Colorado River Multi-Species Conservation Program in the States of Arizona, California, and Nevada, and for other purposes; <bill type="s" number="1258">S. 1258</bill>, to amend the Reclamation Safety of Dams Act of 1978 to authorize improvements for the security of dams and other facilities; <bill type="s" number="1477">S. 1477</bill>, to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to carry out the Jackson  Gulch rehabilitation project in the State of Colorado; <bill type="s" number="1522">S. 1522</bill>, to amend the Bonneville Power Administration portions of the Fisheries Restoration and Irrigation Mitigation Act of 2000 to authorize appropriations for fiscal years 2008 through 2014, and for other purposes; and <bill type="h" number="1025">H.R. 1025</bill>, to authorize the Secretary of the Interior</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
