<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1202317202" ordinal="47" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <narrative>AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET -- (Senate - February 06, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="750">S750</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON ARMED SERVICES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the committee on armed services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, February 6, 2008, at 9:30 a.m. in open session to receive testimony on the defense authorization request for fiscal year 2009, the Future Years Defense Program, and the fiscal year 2009 request for operations in Iraq and Afghanistan.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND NATURAL RESOURCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, February 6, 2008, at 10 a.m., in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building in order to conduct a hearing. At this hearing, the Committee will hear testimony regarding Department of Energy's budget for fiscal year 2009.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENVIRONMENT AND PUBLIC WORKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Environment and Public Works be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, February 6, 2008 at 10 a.m. in room 406 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building in order to hold a hearing entitled, "Perectives on the Surface Transportation Commission Report."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENVIRONMENT AND PUBLIC WORKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Environment and Public Works be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, February 6, 2008 in room 410 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building at 10:05 a.m. in order to hold a business meeting to consider the following item: <bill type="s" number="2146">S. 2146</bill>, a bill to authorize the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to accept, as part of a settlement, diesel emission reduction Supplemental Environmental Projects,  and for other purposes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON FINANCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Finance be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, February 6, 2008, at 10 a.m., in room 215 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building, in order to hear testimony on "The President's Fiscal Year 2009 Budget Proposal."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, February 6, 2008, at 9:30 a.m. in order to hold a hearing on denuclearization of the Korean peninsula.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, February 6, 2008, at 1 p.m. in order to hold a nomination hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, February 6, 2008, at 3 p.m. in order hold a briefing on Sudan.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
