<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1217088004" ordinal="22" title="UNANIMOUS-CONSENT REQUEST--S. 3001">
  <narrative>UNANIMOUS-CONSENT REQUEST--S. 3001 -- (Senate - July 26, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="7523">S7523</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the consideration of Calendar No. 732, <bill type="s" number="3001">S. 3001</bill>, the DOD authorization, at a time determined by the majority leader, following consultation with the Republican leader, and that when the bill is considered, the only first-degree amendments in order be those that are germane to <bill type="s" number="3001">S. 3001</bill>, <bill type="h" number="5668">H.R. 5668</bill>, the House companion measure, and items within the jurisdiction of the House Armed Services Committee, and that the first-degree  amendments be subject to second-degree amendments which are germane to the amendment to which it was offered; that upon the disposition of all amendments, the bill be read a third time and the Senate vote on passage of the bill; that upon passage, it then be in order for the Senate to consider, en bloc, the following calendar items: Nos. 733, 734, and 735; that all after the enacting clause of each bill be stricken and the following divisions of <bill type="s" number="3001">S. 3001</bill>, as passed by the Senate, be inserted as follows: Division A--S. 3002, Division B--S. 3003, Division C--S. 3004; that these bills be read a third time, passed, and the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table, en bloc; further, that the consideration of these items appear separately in the Record; provided further, that the Senate then proceed to the consideration of Calendar No. 758, <bill type="h" number="5658">H.R. 5658</bill>, the House companion; that all after the</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300052" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, reserving the right to object, although I may not personally have an objection to this, this consent would limit the rights of Senators to offer amendments to the Defense authorization bill. This is an agreement that would need to be cleared by all Senators on both sides. Given the detailed limitations of what can be offered to this bill, I will have to object on behalf of the Members on this side of the aisle.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I would say to my friend, the only requirement was that the amendments be germane. There were unlimited amendments as long as they relate to what we are dealing with on our side.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300052" topic="">
    <paragraph>On behalf of our side, I have been asked to object. I apologize to my dear friend from Nevada.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I understand the objection. The Senator from Utah is certainly not supposed to be totally aware of all that is in the Defense bill. But this agreement would allow scores of amendments because it would be anything that is germane. That is certainly nothing unusual. So I understand.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
