<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1222444802" ordinal="91" title="CELEBRATING 100 YEARS OF 4-H IN ARKANSAS">
  <narrative>CELEBRATING 100 YEARS OF 4-H IN ARKANSAS -- (Senate - September 26, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="9647">S9647</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300068" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, tomorrow evening, Arkansas 4-H will cap a year long celebration, "Honoring the Past, Celebrating the Future," at the 4-H Centennial gala in Little Rock, AR. Nearly 1 year ago, on October 1, 2007, the 4-H Centennial Celebration kicked off in Searcy, AR, located in White County, where Arkansas 4-H began.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Founded as a boys' corn and cotton club in 1908, Arkansas 4-H soon expanded to include girls' canning clubs and is now one of the largest youth development programs in Arkansas. The mission of 4-H is to provide opportunities for youth to acquire knowledge, develop life skills, form attitudes, and practice behavior that will enable them to become self-directing, productive, and contributing members of society.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is exemplified in the pledge every Arkansas 4-Her recites: I pledge my Head to clearer thinking; my Heart to greater loyalty; my Hands to larger service; my Health to better living for my club, my community, my country, and my world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, what great words to live by.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Approximately 133,000 young people, in all 75 Arkansas counties, participate in Arkansas 4-H clubs. Arkansas 4-H carries out its mission across our diverse State in inner cities, suburbs, and rural communities. It seeks to break barriers among our youth by focusing on a philosophy of learning by doing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Associated with the University of Arkansas's Division of Agriculture, through the Cooperative Extension Service, 4-H members can select activities in 82 project areas from automotive and clothing to space camp and show horse competitions. In addition, Arkansas 4-H youth receive more than $80,000 in college scholarships each year at the State level for their 4-H work.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So as Arkansas 4-H culminates its year long celebration, I want to extend my congratulations on a tremendous 100 years and wish 4-H the best for another 100 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would also like to take this time to recognize the over 40 clubs statewide that joined the Centennial Club Circle to help fund centennial activities this year. They include the following:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Garland County Teen Leader Club, Garland County; Busy Beavers 4-H Club, Pope County; Elkins 4-H Club, Washington County; Galloping Clovers, Yell County; Fusion 4-H Club, Columbia County; Town &amp; Country 4-H Club, Benton County; Bear Pride 4-H Club, White County; Yellowjackets 4-H Club; Grant County; Rocky Top 4-H Club, Crawford County; 4-H Soaring Eagles Group, Cross County; Perry County Teen Leaders, Perry County; Vilonia 4-H Club, Faulkner County; Centerton 4-H Club, Benton County; Pastoria  4-H Club, Jefferson County; Western Wranglers 4-H Horse &amp; Pony Club, Lawrence  County; Alpena 4-H Club, Boone County; Monette Buffalo Island 4-H Club, Craighead County; Lakeside 4-H Club, Sevier County; Gaither-Valley 4-H Club, Boone County; Olvey 4-H Club, Boone County; Decatur 4-H Club, Benton County; Gravette Gleamers-4-H, Benton County; Chambers 4-H Club, Crawford County; Hilltop Kids 4-H Club, Pope County; Carnall 4-H Club, Sebastian County; Franklin County 4-H Shooting Sports Club, Franklin County; Hurricane Creek 4-H Club, Franklin County; Franklin County Teen Leaders Club, Franklin County; Pulaski County Teen Leaders Club, Pulaski County; Berryville 4-H Club, Carroll County; Atkins 4-H Club, Pope County; Shining Stars 4-H Club, Clark County; Salem Superstars 4-H Club, Saline County; Chapel Hill 4-H Club, Sevier County; Spirit of 76 4-H Club, Arkansas County; Batesville Pioneer 4-H Club, Independence County; Hector 4-H Club, Pope County; El Paso 4-H Club, White County; Towers 4-H Club, Union County; Magic Clovers 4-H Club, Saline County; Lion's Pride 4-H Club, White County; Johnson County 4-H Teen Leaders Club, Johnson County; Hasbrook Road 4-H Club, Craighead County; Bethlehem 4-H Club, Columbia</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
