<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1172509203" ordinal="16" title="STATEMENTS ON INTRODUCED BILLS AND JOINT RESOLUTIONS--THURSDAY, FEBRUARY 16, 2007">
  <speaking speaker="300080" topic="Introducing S. 639. A bill to establish digital and wireless networks to advance online higher education opportunities for minority students; to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="639">S. 639</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to introduce two communications bills.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, I am introducing the Child Safe Viewing Act, a bill to develop the next generation of parental control technology. Last year, following several hearings and forums on decency, I concluded that the V-Chip is not an adequate solution for parents to prevent their children from viewing adult content, especially in a world of 500 channels and video streaming.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>During the 1996 Telecommunications Act debate, President Clinton urged inclusion of a mandatory V-Chip device, and in collaboration with Congress, the FCC, and the entertainment industry, the V-Chip was born. The V-Chip was an important beginning to control child access to adult material. Over a decade has passed since the 1996 Act, and the world of communications has changed. However, the issues that inspired the V-Chip continue to exist today for not only television but for the Internet and  other video streaming devices.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Child Safe Viewing Act is a pragmatic approach to addressing the pitfalls of video content not intended for kids, and it acts on current law. It simply directs the Federal Communications Commission to begin a proceeding on the requirements in Section 551 of the V-Chip law. Section 551 states that the Commission shall take action on alternative blocking technology as it is developed. This mandate is clear and the time has come. We must engage in this issue now to ensure that families have  the tools to keep inappropriate and sometimes dangerous material out of their children's view.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am also introducing ED 1.0, a bill to advance online higher education opportunities for minorities. Last Congress, Senator ALLEN and I introduced a bill that would establish a digital and wireless network technology program for minority-serving institutions, and it was reported favorably by the Commerce Committee. Regrettably, I am concerned that the cost of the bill will prohibit it from moving in this Congress. But the needs of this Nation's minorities are not standing still.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>ED 1.0 would allow some of our goals to move forward now by creating a pilot online degree program at four minority-serving institutions. African-American, Hispanic, and Tribal serving colleges and universities in socially and economically disadvantaged areas would be eligible to participate in this program to help define what works in ensuring that minorities are obtaining higher education degrees</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With the high costs of networks and limited availability of resources, the program would provide a national "lessons learned" about how to develop and implement flexible degree programs in fields such as health or education, which are currently underserved in the disadvantaged community. The goals of ED 1.0 will make education a reality for thousands of Americans, and I hope this bill will have the support of my colleagues.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
</record>
