<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1204045202" ordinal="24" title="INDIAN HEALTH CARE IMPROVEMENT ACT">
  <narrative>INDIAN HEALTH CARE IMPROVEMENT ACT -- (Senate - February 26, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="1197">S1197</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I regret having missed the final vote for the Indian Health Care Improvement Act of 2007. I support the passa ge of this bill and would have voted in the affirmative.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It has been over 15 years since the Indian Health Care Improvement Act has been reauthorized. It is critical to strengthen the provision of care, through the Indian Health Service, IHS, to American Indian and Alaska Native populations, who suffer from significant health disparities compared to the general U.S. population, including a life expectancy that is 2.4 years lower, and significantly higher death rates from tuberculosis, alcoholism, diabet es, suicide, and infant mortality.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Indian Health Service derives its authorities from the Indian Health Care Improvement Act and its mission is to improve the health status of American Indians and Alaskan Natives by constructing, maintaining, and managing health care delivery and sanitation systems through a network of 49 hospitals, 6,500 IHS, tribal, and private contract facilities. The IHS provides ambulatory, emergency, dental, and preventative health services to 58 percent of the 3.3 million Ame rican Indians and Alaska</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Specifically, the reauthorization will improve the recruitment and  retention of health providers in the IHS, provide support for American Indians and Alaska Natives to enter the health professions, provide funds for the construction of health and sanitation facilities, expand Medicare, Medicaid, and CHIP reimbursement and enrollment to all American Indians and Native Alaskans health programs, eliminate Medicare and CHIP cost-sharing and premiums for American Indians and Native Alaskans served</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I commend the work of both the Senate Indian Affairs and Finance Committees and, most importantly, Senators Dorgan and Murkowski for their leadership and  commitment to this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
