<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1222444802" ordinal="77" title="CONGRATULATING THE INSTITUTE OF REAL ESTATE MANAGEMENT">
  <narrative>CONGRATULATING THE INSTITUTE OF REAL ESTATE MANAGEMENT -- (Senate - September 26, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="9642">S9642</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300014" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today I wish to congratulate the Institute of Real Estate Management, IREM, on its 75th anniversary. As an affiliate of the National Association of Realtors, IREM advocates on behalf of the real estate management industry. With 80 U.S. chapters, eight international chapters, and several partnerships around the globe, IREM constantly strives to promote the principles of professional real estate management.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ethics are the cornerstone of the IREM mission. The IREM Code of Professional Ethics seeks to defend the public interest, promote healthy competition, and guarantee that IREM members will act ethically. Actively and strictly enforced, the Code of Professional Ethics provides a foundation for public trust in the integrity and expertise of professional real estate managers. IREM's commitment to ethics underlies its 75 years of success as a professional association.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would also like to congratulate IREM Kentucky chapter 59, which will be celebrating its 40th anniversary on November 10, 2008. Kentucky chapter 59 is the largest IREM chapter in the Commonwealth of Kentucky and serves as an excellent resource on real estate management education and information for its members.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I congratulate IREM on more than seven decades of dedication to the real estate management profession. By providing dedicated service to its members, as well as maintaining high standards for the real estate industry as a whole, IREM serves as an exemplary model of a professional association.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
