<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1172682003" ordinal="20" title="TRIBUTE TO HENRY WADSWORTH LONGFELLOW">
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, yesterday, February 27 marked the 200th anniversary of the birth of one of America's greatest and best loved poets, Henry Wadsworth Longfellow. His magnificent poems portray the unique character of the Nation and its history and are an essential part of our cultural legacy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He is especially beloved in Massachusetts. He was a member of the Harvard faculty for many years, and the beautiful Longfellow House and the Longfellow National Historic site are among the most popular sites in our State for residents and tourists alike.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He was famed throughout the world for his extraordinary narrative poems, and in his later years he was known as "the grand old man of American letters." One of his classic poems in the genre was "The Building of the Ship," which drew on his love of the sea and knowledge of ship building from his early years in Portland, ME. Two lines near the end are some of his most famous "Thou, too, sail on, O Ship of State! Sail on, O Union, strong and great!" which President Abraham Lincoln found immensely  inspiring.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Another of his most famous narrative poems is "Paul Revere's Ride," which has always been a special favorite of mine. It tells the remarkable story of that early American patriot and his dramatic ride from Boston to Lexington and Concord at the beginning of the Revolutionary War. It is one of the most well-known poems in America, which students have memorized for generations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On this bicentennial anniversary of his birth, I would like to share that poem with my colleagues. I ask unanimous consent that it be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Paul Revere's Ride</paragraph>
    <paragraph>&lt;center&gt;--&lt;em&gt;Henry Wadsworth Longfellow.&lt;/em&gt;</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
