<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1182355236" ordinal="50" title="CELEBRATING ACCOMPLISHMENTS OF TITLE IX OF EDUCATION AMENDMENTS OF 1972">
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate now proceed to the immediate consideration of <bill type="sr" number="242">S. Res. 242</bill>, submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table, and any statements relating thereto be printed in the Record, without intervening action or debate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="242">S. Res. 242</bill>) was agreed to.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The preamble was agreed to.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>
      <bill type="sr" number="242">S. Res. 242</bill>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>Whereas 35 years ago, on June 23, 1972, the Education Amendments of 1972 containing title IX was signed into law by the President;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Representatives Patsy T. Mink and Edith Green led the successful fight in Congress to pass this legislation;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas title IX prohibits discrimination on the basis of sex in the administration of any education program receiving Federal financial assistance;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas remarkable gains have been made to ensure equal opportunity for women and girls under the inspiration and mandate of title IX;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas title IX serves as the nondiscrimination principle in education;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas title IX has increased access and opportunities for women and girls; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas title IX has increased educational opportunities for women and girls, increased access to professional schools and nontraditional fields of study, and improved employment opportunities;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas title IX has increased opportunities for women and girls in sports, leading to greater access to competitive sports, and building strong values such as teamwork, leadership, discipline, work ethic, self-sacrifice, pride in accomplishment, and strength of character;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas on October 29, 2002, title IX was named the "Patsy Takemoto Mink Equal Opportunity in Education Act" in recognition  of Representative Mink's heroic, visionary, and tireless leadership in developing and winning passage of title IX; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas while title IX has been instrumental in fostering 35 years of progress toward equality between men and women in educational institutions and the workplace, there remains progress to be made, Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate celebrates--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) the accomplishments of title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972, also known as the Patsy Takemoto Mink Equal Opportunity in Education Act, in increasing opportunities for women and girls in all facets of education; and</paragraph>
    <paragraph> (2) the magnificent accomplishments of women and girls in sports.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
