<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1217260803" ordinal="19" title="TRIBUTE TO FRANK VAN BUER">
  <narrative>TRIBUTE TO FRANK VAN BUER -- (Senate - July 28, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="7565">S7565</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today to pay tribute to a selfless public servant from my great State of Illinois, Mayor Frank Van Buer, of DeKalb, who passed away July 23, 2008, after a battle with pancreatic cancer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mayor Van Buer was born in Savanna, IL, on the banks of the Mississippi River. While in high school, Frank worked as a union laborer and  truck driver. He joined the U.S. Air Force and spent 4 years in Germany and Libya. When he returned to the United States in 1957, Van Buer moved to DeKalb to attend Northern Illinois University, NIU. He earned a B.S. in social science in 1960 and completed a master's degree in economics in 1964. In 1968, Mayor Van Buer  earned a Ph.D. in economics from the University of Illinois. He was tenured on the faculty of the Department of Economics at NIU in 1970, and taught there until 1995.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While on the NIU faculty, Mayor Van Buer gave generously of his skills in administration and budgeting. He directed NIU's Office of Budget and Planning, responsible for the administration of annual operating budgets in excess of $100 million. And he traveled around the world, working in developing nations in Africa and Asia to provide technical assistance in planning and budgeting.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mayor Van Buer was a man of integrity who strongly believed in open government. Mayor Van Buer was first elected by his community to the DeKalb County Board in 2002, and he was re-elected in 2004. He was elected mayor of DeKalb in 2005. During his tenure as mayor, he made it a priority to revitalize DeKalb's urban core.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to his service at NIU and with the city of DeKalb, Mayor Van Buer was active in leadership with the Ben Gordon Mental Health Center and the Kishwaukee Symphony Orchestra.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My thoughts and prayers are with the mayor's family and friends, especially his wife of over 50 years, Mary Beth, their three children, and five grandchildren.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
