<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1194973204" ordinal="12" title="EXECUTIVE SESSION">
  <narrative>EXECUTIVE SESSION -- (Senate - November 13, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="14238">S14238</bill>]</narrative>
  <chair> Under the previous order, the Senate will proceed to executive session to consider the following nomination, which the clerk will report.</chair>
  <chair>The legislative clerk read the nomination of Robert M. Dow, Jr., to be United States District Judge for the Northern District of Illinois.</chair>
  <chair> Under the previous order, the time until 10:10 a.m. shall be equally divided between the leaders and their designees.</chair>
  <chair>The Senator from Illinois.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="NOMINATION OF ROBERT M. DOW, JR., TO BE UNITED STATES DISTRICT JUDGE FOR THE NORTHERN DISTRICT OF ILLINOIS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I wish to thank Senator Reid and Senator Leahy, Chairman of the Senate Judiciary Committee, for bringing Robert Dow up for a vote this morning in the Senate. I enthusiastically support his nomination. If confirmed, he will fill a Federal District Court vacancy in Chicago that has been pending for over a year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Robert Dow is an outstanding lawyer and an outstanding person. We have a process in Illinois that has worked almost flawlessly for the last 11 years, where we have bipartisan cooperation in screening judicial candidates. We have had the cooperation of the White House and leaders on both sides of the aisle, and we have not run into a problem. Robert Dow is the latest example.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Dow was recommended for this position by former Speaker of the House Dennis Hastert, the Republican leader in our delegation, with the understanding he faced a veto from myself or Senator Obama if we objected. Having met the man, having reviewed his background, there is no objection. He is an extraordinarily gifted and talented person.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He is a partner at one of Chicago's largest and most prestigious law firms--Mayer Brown--and he has been named as one of the 21 leading lawyers in the United States in the field of telecom, broadcast, and satellite.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are many things you can say about Robert Dow, but I think there is one that stands out, as I reflect on what he had to say to us. Robert Dow has received an accolade that is noteworthy. In 2004, he received the annual Pro Bono Service Award from his law firm, which has over 1,500 attorneys, for his personal commitment to unpaid legal work to help those less fortunate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That means a lot to me. It says he understands that being an attorney is not just a job, it is a profession, and a profession carries with it social responsibilities. His willingness to help the disadvantaged went a long way in convincing me he will bring to the court the kind of temperament and values which are so important.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The nomination of Robert Dow is a tribute to the successful bipartisan approach and the fact both parties look forward to his tenure on the Federal bench and the contributions he will make. Speaker Hastert, Senator Obama, and I stand today excited about the prospect that Mr. Dow will soon fulfill this vacancy, which has been there for too long.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask my colleagues to join me in supporting Mr. Dow to be a district court judge in the Northern District of Illinois.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="NOMINATION OF ROBERT M. DOW, JR., TO BE UNITED STATES DISTRICT JUDGE FOR THE NORTHERN DISTRICT OF ILLINOIS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, the Senate continues, as we have all year, to make progress filling judicial vacancies when we have the cooperation of the White House. The nomination before us today for a lifetime appointment to the Federal bench is Robert Michael Dow, Jr., for the Northern District of Illinois. He has the support of both home-State Senators. I thank Senators Durbin and Obama for their work in connection with this nomination.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After we consider the confirmation of this nominee today, the Senate will have confirmed 35 nominations for lifetime appointments to the Federal bench this session alone. That matches the total number of judges confirmed for 2004. It exceeds the total number of judicial nominations that a Republican-led Senate confirmed in all of 1999, 2005 or 2006 with a Republican majority; all of 1989; all of 2001; all of 1983, when a Republican-led Senate was considering President Reagan's nominees; all of  1993, when a Democratic-led Senate was considering President Clinton's nominees; and, of course, the entire 1996 session during which a Republican-led Senate did not confirm a single one of President Clinton's circuit nominees.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Already this year, we have confirmed five circuit judges to the Federal  bench, including the nominations of Judge Jennifer Walker Elrod and Judge Leslie Southwick who became the fourth and fifth circuit court nominees we confirmed so far this year. That matches the total number of circuit court judges confirmed in all of 1989 and all of 2004, when a Republican-led Senate was considering this President's nominees. It matches the number of President Clinton's  circuit court nominations confirmed by this time in 1999 with a Republican-led Senate and is five more than the Republican-led Senate confirmed in the entire 1996 session. That was the session in which not a single circuit court nominee was confirmed. It is more than were confirmed in the entire 1983 and 1993 sessions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When this nomination is confirmed today, the Senate will have confirmed 135 total Federal judicial nominees in my tenure as Judiciary Chairman. During the Bush Presidency, more circuit judges, more district judges--more total judges--were confirmed in the first 24 months that I served as Judiciary chairman than during the 2-year tenures of either of the two Republican chairmen working with Republican Senate majorities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Administrative Office of the U.S. Courts will list 47 judicial vacancies and 14 circuit court vacancies after today's confirmations. At the end of the 109th Congress, the total vacancies when Republicans controlled the Senate were 51 judicial vacancies and 15 circuit court vacancies. Despite the additional 5 vacancies that arose before the start of the 110th Congress, the current vacancy totals under my chairmanship of the Judiciary Committee are below where they were under a Republican led-Judiciary  Committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The President has sent us only 21 nominations for these remaining vacancies. Twenty-six of these vacancies--more than half--have no nominee. Of the 17 vacancies deemed by the Administrative Office to be judicial emergencies, the President has yet to send us nominees for nine, more than half of them. Of the 14 circuit court vacancies, six--nearly half--are without a nominee. If the President would decide to work with the Senators from Michigan, Rhode Island, Maryland, California, New Jersey, and  Virginia, we could be in position to make even more progress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Of the 26 vacancies without any nominee, the President has violated the timeline he set for himself at least 18 times--18 have been vacant without so much as a nominee for more than 180 days. The number of violations may in fact be much higher since the President said he would nominate within 180 days of receiving notice that there would be a vacancy or intended retirement rather than from the vacancy itself. We conservatively estimate that he also violated his own rule 7 times in connection  with the nominations he has made. That would mean that with respect to the 47 vacancies, the President is out of compliance with his own rule more than half of the time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today we consider the nomination of Robert Michael Dow, Jr. He is a partner at the law firm of Mayer, Brown, Rowe &amp; Maw, LLP, where he has worked almost his entire career. He received his B.A. from Yale University where he graduated summa cum laude and his J.D. from Harvard Law School where he graduated cum laude. A Rhodes Scholar, Mr. Dow earned a master and doctorate degrees from Oxford University. Mr. Dow also served as a law clerk to Judge Joel M. Flaum on the United States Court of Appeals  for the Seventh Circuit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I congratulate the nominee and his family on his confirmation today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(At the request of Mr. Reid, the following statement was ordered to be printed in the Record.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400629" topic="NOMINATION OF ROBERT M. DOW, JR., TO BE UNITED STATES DISTRICT JUDGE FOR THE NORTHERN DISTRICT OF ILLINOIS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise to express my support for the confirmation of Robert M. Dow, Jr. to the U.S. District Court for the Northern District of Illinois.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am very pleased that this nomination has continued the bipartisan approach to filling judgeships in the Federal district courts--an approach that has served Illinois well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Dow has an impressive record of professional achievement and an admirable commitment to public service. He has demonstrated fairness, decency, integrity, and a strong personal character that I expect will benefit the people of Illinois and all those with cases before the Northern District.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Most recently, Mr. Dow was a partner at the Chicago law firm of Mayer Brown. He earned his B.A. from Yale University where he graduated Phi Beta Kappa in 1987, and his J.D. from Harvard Law School, where he graduated cum laude in 1993. Mr. Dow was also a Rhodes Scholar who received degrees in international relations from Oxford University.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Dow has also distinguished himself in his professional career, where he has received a number of honors and accolades. Mr. Dow has been named a "leading lawyer" 5 years in a row by Chambers USA Guide to America's Leading Business Lawyers. He has been listed the past 2 years as an Illinois Super Lawyer in appellate law, and by the Best Lawyers in America in communications law. Mr. Dow also received an award for excellence in undergraduate teaching when he served as a teaching fellow at Harvard  University.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Importantly, Mr. Dow has also been an engaged member of the Chicago community. In 2003, he served as a fellow for Leadership Greater Chicago, which stresses the development of community awareness and partnerships among leaders in the city. He is also an active member in a number of legal and academic associations as well as in his church.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, Mr. Dow has a track record of personal commitment to pro bono service. Early in his career, he provided aid and advice to nonprofit organizations and a local court. Over the years, Mr. Dow has volunteered hundreds of hours to pro bono service, and continues to do so. He recently earned his firm's annual pro bono award. This kind of public service is essential to our legal system. When legal professionals provide voluntary expert legal counsel to those who cannot afford it, it shores  up the integrity of our Nation's justice system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is good news for Illinois that Robert Dow will be joining the district court. I thank him in advance for his service and congratulate him on his confirmation today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="NOMINATION OF ROBERT M. DOW, JR., TO BE UNITED STATES DISTRICT JUDGE FOR THE NORTHERN DISTRICT OF ILLINOIS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask for the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there a sufficient second? There appears to be a sufficient second.</chair>
  <chair>The question is, Will the Senate advise and consent to the nomination of Robert M. Dow, Jr., to be a U.S. district court judge for the Northern District of Illinois.</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will call the roll.</narrative>
  <narrative>The assistant legislative clerk called the roll.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="NOMINATION OF ROBERT M. DOW, JR., TO BE UNITED STATES DISTRICT JUDGE FOR THE NORTHERN DISTRICT OF ILLINOIS">
    <paragraph>I announce that the Senator from Delaware (Mr. Biden), the Senator from New York (Mrs. Clinton), the Senator from Connecticut (Mr. Dodd), the Senator from Missouri (Mrs. McCaskill), the Senator from Illinois (Mr. Obama), and the Senator from Vermont (Mr. Sanders) are necessarily absent.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300069" topic="NOMINATION OF ROBERT M. DOW, JR., TO BE UNITED STATES DISTRICT JUDGE FOR THE NORTHERN DISTRICT OF ILLINOIS">
    <paragraph>The following Senators are necessarily absent: the Senator from North Carolina (Mr. Burr), the Senator from Oklahoma (Mr. Coburn), the Senator from Idaho (Mr. Crapo), the Senator from Nevada (Mr. Ensign), the Senator from Oklahoma (Mr. Inhofe), the Senator from Florida (Mr. Martinez), the Senator from Arizona (Mr. McCain), and the Senator from Kansas (Mr. Roberts).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Are there any other Senators in the Chamber desiring to vote?</chair>
  <narrative>The result was announced--yeas 86, nays 0, as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>[Rollcall Vote No. 408 Ex.]</narrative>
  <narrative>Akaka</narrative>
  <narrative>Alexander</narrative>
  <narrative>Allard</narrative>
  <narrative>Barrasso</narrative>
  <narrative>Baucus</narrative>
  <narrative>Bayh</narrative>
  <narrative>Bennett</narrative>
  <narrative>Bingaman</narrative>
  <narrative>Bond</narrative>
  <narrative>Boxer</narrative>
  <narrative>Brown</narrative>
  <narrative>Brownback</narrative>
  <narrative>Bunning</narrative>
  <narrative>Byrd</narrative>
  <narrative>Cantwell</narrative>
  <narrative>Cardin</narrative>
  <narrative>Carper</narrative>
  <narrative>Casey</narrative>
  <narrative>Chambliss</narrative>
  <narrative>Cochran</narrative>
  <narrative>Coleman</narrative>
  <narrative>Collins</narrative>
  <narrative>Conrad</narrative>
  <narrative>Corker</narrative>
  <narrative>Cornyn</narrative>
  <narrative>Craig</narrative>
  <narrative>DeMint</narrative>
  <narrative>Dole</narrative>
  <narrative>Domenici</narrative>
  <narrative>Dorgan</narrative>
  <narrative>Durbin</narrative>
  <narrative>Enzi</narrative>
  <narrative>Feingold</narrative>
  <narrative>Feinstein</narrative>
  <narrative>Graham</narrative>
  <narrative>Grassley</narrative>
  <narrative>Gregg</narrative>
  <narrative>Hagel</narrative>
  <narrative>Harkin</narrative>
  <narrative>Hatch</narrative>
  <narrative>Hutchison</narrative>
  <narrative>Inouye</narrative>
  <narrative>Isakson</narrative>
  <narrative>Johnson</narrative>
  <narrative>Kennedy</narrative>
  <narrative>Kerry</narrative>
  <narrative>Klobuchar</narrative>
  <narrative>Kohl</narrative>
  <narrative>Kyl</narrative>
  <narrative>Landrieu</narrative>
  <narrative>Lautenberg</narrative>
  <narrative>Leahy</narrative>
  <narrative>Levin</narrative>
  <narrative>Lieberman</narrative>
  <narrative>Lincoln</narrative>
  <narrative>Lott</narrative>
  <narrative>Lugar</narrative>
  <narrative>McConnell</narrative>
  <narrative>Menendez</narrative>
  <narrative>Mikulski</narrative>
  <narrative>Murkowski</narrative>
  <narrative>Murray</narrative>
  <narrative>Nelson (FL)</narrative>
  <narrative>Nelson (NE)</narrative>
  <narrative>Pryor</narrative>
  <narrative>Reed</narrative>
  <narrative>Reid</narrative>
  <narrative>Rockefeller</narrative>
  <narrative>Salazar</narrative>
  <narrative>Schumer</narrative>
  <narrative>Sessions</narrative>
  <narrative>Shelby</narrative>
  <narrative>Smith</narrative>
  <narrative>Snowe</narrative>
  <narrative>Specter</narrative>
  <narrative>Stabenow</narrative>
  <narrative>Stevens</narrative>
  <narrative>Sununu</narrative>
  <narrative>Tester</narrative>
  <narrative>Thune</narrative>
  <narrative>Vitter</narrative>
  <narrative>Voinovich</narrative>
  <narrative>Warner</narrative>
  <narrative>Webb</narrative>
  <narrative>Whitehouse</narrative>
  <narrative>Wyden</narrative>
  <narrative>Biden</narrative>
  <narrative>Burr</narrative>
  <narrative>Clinton</narrative>
  <narrative>Coburn</narrative>
  <narrative>Crapo</narrative>
  <narrative>Dodd</narrative>
  <narrative>Ensign</narrative>
  <narrative>Inhofe</narrative>
  <narrative>Martinez</narrative>
  <narrative>McCain</narrative>
  <narrative>McCaskill</narrative>
  <narrative>Obama</narrative>
  <narrative>Roberts</narrative>
  <narrative>Sanders</narrative>
  <narrative>The nomination was confirmed.</narrative>
  <chair> Under the previous order, the motion to reconsider is laid on the table. The President will be immediately notified of the Senate's action.</chair>
</record>
