<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1201280402" ordinal="9" title="HONORING OUR ARMED FORCES">
  <narrative>HONORING OUR ARMED FORCES -- (Senate - January 25, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="304">S304</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300072" topic="CORPORAL JOSHUA M. MOORE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise to speak about a young Kentuckian who was taken from this world entirely too soon. CPL Joshua M. Moore of Lewisburg, KY, was lost in Baghdad while serving our country. He was 20 years old.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the early morning hours of May 30, 2007, Corporal Moore was driving a humvee when an improvised explosive device set by terrorists went off. The force of a 55-gallon drum of homemade explosives overturned the humvee and tragically took Corporal Moore's life.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For his valor in uniform, Corporal Moore received numerous medals and awards, including the Bronze Star Medal and the Purple Heart. His family saw him laid to rest in Lewisburg, in Logan County, KY, with full military honors, including a 21-gun salute and a flyover of military aircraft.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Corporal Moore's funeral service was held at Lewisburg Elementary School, where Josh had attended years before and where he returned every time he came home on leave to speak to the young students about his life of service as a soldier.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This remarkable young man, who did not live to see 21, believed it was important to describe the honor of fighting to defend one's country with the young children in his hometown.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>"He has set a good example for the young kids around here. A lot of kids looked up to Josh. He will be missed greatly," says his mother, Carolyn.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Josh worried what to say about the reality of war to kids as young as 7 years old. But his father, Seymore, encouraged him to talk about the dedication a soldier must have. He told him to describe the rigorous physical training, the strange new places he saw, and the new friends he made.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After Josh would return to Iraq, the students he had met would write him letters to read the next time he came home. "He sat and read these--every one of these before he went back," said Seymore.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Surely to Carolyn and Seymore, it seems like just yesterday when Josh was a child himself. When he was 3 years old, Josh found his dad's old Cub Scout uniform and wore it all the time. He even insisted on wearing it in his preschool picture--against his mother's better judgment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After attending Lewisburg Elementary, Josh went on to Lewisburg Middle School and Logan County High School and was a consistently strong student. He played basketball at Lewisburg Middle, became a Babe Ruth baseball all-star, and made the Logan County High baseball team--all despite the fact that, at 5 foot 6, his friends teasingly called him "Little Moore."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As important as sports were to Josh, however, this young man learned early the importance of patience. When he was almost 16, Josh wanted to buy a new car. His parents offered to help pay up to $500. But Josh had his eye on a neighbor's car, a burgundy Pontiac Grand Am with a $1,500 pricetag.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Carolyn and Seymore told Josh he would have to come up with the rest of the money, so he quit high school sports and got a part-time job. Two weeks before his 16th birthday, Josh approached his parents and slapped $1,000 onto the coffee table. He said, "Here is my part. Where is yours?" That Grand Am was his by his 16th birthday.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Josh graduated from Logan County High in 2005 and hoped one day to join the Kentucky State Police. But after working for a short time at a factory, one day Josh came home to his family and announced, "I am the property of the U.S. Government."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>"They are going to shave your head," Josh's mother said.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>"They have to leave an inch of hair," replied Josh.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>His parents were nervous for their son and suggested he try a different branch of the service. A relative in the Navy offered to help.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But Josh was not interested. "Josh wanted to be where the action was," says Seymore, and to him that meant serving as an infantryman in the U.S. Army. "No matter what he did," Carolyn adds, "he wanted to be the best."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Josh did his basic training at Fort Benning, GA, and graduated among the top 20 soldiers in his class. Of the many things he learned there, one was the ability to say when he had been wrong. And in a letter to his mom, Josh admitted, "I am bald."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Corporal Moore was assigned to C Company, 1st Battalion, 18th Infantry Regiment, 1st Infantry Division, based out of Schweinfurt, Germany. In addition to Germany and Iraq, Corporal Moore saw service in Kuwait.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While in the Middle East, a lieutenant asked Josh's commanding officer who his smartest and quickest soldier was, and the officer said Corporal Moore, thinking Josh would receive an award. Instead, the lieutenant made Josh a radio operator.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At first Josh thought he had been demoted. But his old drill sergeant told him this was an honor, as communications  were critical to the unit. After this pep talk, Josh assumed his new role with relish.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The lieutenant who selected him later told Josh's family that when Josh was away on leave, it was hard on the unit because no one else could meet the high standard he set for the job.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This wonderful Kentucky family is in my thoughts and prayers today as I recount Josh's story. He is loved and remembered by his mother, Carolyn Moore; his father, Jeff "Seymore" Moore; his brother, Richard Pierce; his sisters, Carrie Cantarelli and Ashley Moore; his grandparents, Jeanette Rose and David and Barbara Knight; his girlfriend, Amber Miles; and many other beloved friends and family members.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Corporal Moore's funeral service was held at Lewisburg Elementary School, the only place in Logan County large enough to hold the hundreds--hundreds--who came to pay their final respects.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ronnie Forrest, Josh's pastor for many years, from Lewisburg's Mount Pleasant Baptist Church, expressed best how this young man inspired so many in his short time on this Earth.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is what he said: Josh "didn't want to die, he didn't intend to die, but he was willing to lay down his life." Pastor Forrest said at the service: "That's what a hero is."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>No words that Mr. Forrest could say, I could say, or anyone could say will fill the void in the hearts of Josh's family and friends. But I hope the knowledge that those who knew Josh saw him for what he was--a hero--fills them with pride. And I am proud to recount his story for my fellow Senators.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, this Senate expresses its deepest gratitude for CPL Joshua M. Moore's service. He laid down his life for his country, his loved ones, and his young pen pals from Lewisburg Elementary. We will forever honor that sacrifice.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The majority leader is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="CORPORAL JOSHUA M. MOORE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I certainly join with my friend from Kentucky in  the respect we show for this young man.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
