<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1189094404" ordinal="22" title="COLLEGE COST REDUCTION AND ACCESS ACT--CONFERENCE REPORT">
  <narrative>COLLEGE COST REDUCTION AND ACCESS ACT--CONFERENCE REPORT -- (Senate - September 06, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="11206">S11206</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I submit a report of the committee of conference on the bill (<bill type="h" number="2669">H.R. 2669</bill>) and ask for its immediate consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>The committee of conference on the disagreeing votes of the two Houses on the amendment of the Senate to the bill (<bill type="h" number="2669">H.R. 2669</bill>), to provide for reconciliation pursuant to section 601 of the concurrent resolution on the budget for fiscal year 2008, having met, after full and free conference, have agreed to recommend and do recommend to their respective Houses as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>That the House recede from its disagreement to the amendment of the Senate and agree to the same with an amendment, signed by a majority of the conferees of both Houses.</narrative>
  <chair> The Senate will proceed to the consideration of the conference report.</chair>
  <narrative>(The conference report is printed in the proceedings of the House in the RECORD of today, September 6, 2007.)</narrative>
  <chair> The Senator from Massachusetts.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="ORDERS FOR FRIDAY, SEPTEMBER 7, 2007">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that when the Senate completes its business today, it stand adjourned until 8:55 a.m., Friday, September 7; that on Friday, following the prayer and pledge, the Journal of proceedings be approved to date, the morning hour be deemed expired, the time for the two leaders be reserved for their use later in the day, and that the Senate then resume consideration of the conference report to accompany <bill type="h" number="2669">H.R. 2669</bill>, as provided for under a previous order.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
