<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1213027204" ordinal="17" title="125TH ANNIVERSARY OF THE FOUNDING OF WILLOW LAKE, SOUTH DAKOTA">
  <narrative>125TH ANNIVERSARY OF THE FOUNDING OF WILLOW LAKE, SOUTH DAKOTA -- (Senate - June 09, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="5388">S5388</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300058" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today I pay tribute to the 125th anniversary of the founding of the community of Willow Lake, SD. After 125 years, this progressive community will have a chance to reflect on its past and future, and I congratulate the people of Willow Lake for all they have accomplished.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Willow Lake, located in Clark County, was originally plotted on the northeast corner of the lake in 1883. When the Manitoba Railroad was surveyed to come about 2 miles south of the city, the decision was made to move the town to its present location. Willow Lake grew with the evolution of the Manitoba Railroad to the Great Northern in 1890. A tornado and several fires swept through the town during the turn of the 20th century, destroying most of the primarily wooden structures. Shortly thereafter,  the town fathers mandated that all Main Street buildings were to be made of brick to withstand the elements of eastern South Dakota.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, Willow Lake has come a long way from the days of railroad commerce. The town now boasts a variety of businesses in both the service and manufacturing sectors, including a grain elevator, multiple construction companies, and a K-12 public school. The people of Willow Lake will celebrate their achievements July 4-6, 2008, with a rodeo, car show, fireworks display, and parade as well as an all school reunion which, as reported by Paul Harvey, is held each and every year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Willow Lake is a credit to Clark County and to the State of South Dakota. I am proud to join with the community members of Willow Lake in celebrating the last 125 years, and looking forward to a promising future.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
