<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1195059601" ordinal="54" title="BREAST CANCER RESEARCH STAMP EXTENSION">
  <narrative>BREAST CANCER RESEARCH STAMP EXTENSION -- (Senate - November 14, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="14416">S14416</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of Calendar No. 473, <bill type="s" number="597">S. 597</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the bill by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A bill (<bill type="s" number="597">S. 597</bill>) to extend the special postage stamp for breast cancer research for 2 years.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the bill.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the amendment at the desk be considered and agreed to, the bill, as amended, be read a third time, passed, the motion to reconsider be laid on the table, and that any statements be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The amendment (No. 3676) was agreed to, as follows:</chair>
  <narrative>(Purpose: To extend the special postage stamp for breast cancer research for 4 years)</narrative>
  <narrative> In section 1, in the section heading, strike "&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;2-YEAR" and insert "4-YEAR".</narrative>
  <narrative> In section 1, strike "2009" and insert "2011".&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask that the title amendment be agreed to.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The title amendment (No. 3678) was agreed to, as follows:</chair>
  <chair>Amend the title so as to read: "To extend the special postage stamp for breast cancer research for 4 years.".</chair>
  <chair>The bill (<bill type="s" number="597">S. 597</bill>), as amended, was ordered to be engrossed for a third reading, was read the third time, and passed, as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="s" number="597">S. 597</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. 4-YEAR EXTENSION OF POSTAGE STAMP FOR BREAST CANCER RESEARCH.</chair>
  <chair> Section 414(h) of title 39, United States Code, is amended by striking "2007" and inserting "2011".&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
