<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1168448402" ordinal="8" title="LOBBYING AND ETHICS REFORM LEGISLATION">
  <speaking speaker="300072" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to say to my good friend, the majority leader, I share his view that we ought to make progress on this bill. There are a number of amendments already pending. We will be working together during the course of the morning to get some votes scheduled. I share his view that we ought to finish this bill next week. So we will be going forward in a cooperative frame of mind.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is an important piece of legislation. It has bipartisan support, as illustrated by the fact that the majority leader and myself are cosponsors of the substitute he offered yesterday. This is a piece of legislation that ought to be passed and ought to be passed soon in the Senate and will be done with a broad bipartisan basis of support.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I look forward to working with my friend during the course of the day to get votes in the queue so we can move forward.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The majority leader is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, if I could say one thing before the Republican leader leaves. I want everyone to hear what I said before. The first measure Senator McConnell and I introduced, <bill type="s" number="1">S. 1</bill>, will be the most significant lobbying and ethics reform bill since Watergate, if nothing else happens. And then we went a step further and, on a bipartisan basis, offered the substitute amendment which moves the ball down the field by a long way.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill is significant, and if nothing else happens other than <bill type="s" number="1">S. 1</bill> and the substitute, this will be a tremendously important piece of legislation in the annals of the history of this country. We have a lot of other people who want to improve the bill in their mind, and that is what this amendment process is all about. But we cannot lose sight of the fact that this is a significant move forward in ethics and lobbying reform with the two measures that have been put forward on a bipartisan basis.  We have done already, some good work for the Senate.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Republican leader is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300072" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I might add, I agree with everything the majority leader said. This substitute is essentially what passed the Senate last year 90 to 8. The Senate is ready to act or close to ready to finish this important piece of legislation. We were last year. It was bogged down in the legislative process in dealing with the other body. But we are going to pass this next week with an overwhelming bipartisan vote. And the majority leader and I will be working together  to make that possible.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
