<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1216310404" ordinal="62" title="IN SUPPORT OF THE VERY ENERGETIC RADIATION IMAGING TELESCOPE ARRAY SYSTEM (VERITAS)">
  <narrative>IN SUPPORT OF THE VERY ENERGETIC RADIATION IMAGING TELESCOPE ARRAY SYSTEM (VERITAS) -- (Senate - July 17, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="6946">S6946</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300078" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Rules Committee be discharged from further consideration of <bill type="sj" number="35">S.J. Res. 35</bill>, and the Senate proceed to its immediate consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will report the joint resolution by title.</narrative>
  <narrative>The assistant legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A joint resolution (<bill type="sj" number="35">S.J. Res. 35</bill>) to amend Public Law 108-331 to provide for the construction and related activities in support of the Very Energetic Radiation Imaging Telescope Array System (VERITAS).</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the joint resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300078" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the joint resolution be read a third time and passed, the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table, with no interviewing action or debate, and any statements related to the measure be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The joint resolution (<bill type="sj" number="35">S.J. Res. 35</bill>) was ordered to be engrossed for a third reading, was read the third time, and passed, as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sj" number="35">S.J. Res. 35</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair> Resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. LOCATION OF VERITAS PROJECT.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Public Law 108-331 (118 Stat. 1281) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) in the long title, by striking "on Kitt Peak near Tucson, Arizona" and inserting "in Arizona"; and</chair>
  <chair> (2) in section 1, by striking "on Kitt Peak near Tucson, Arizona" and inserting "at the Fred Lawrence Whipple Observatory Base Camp on Mount Hopkins, Arizona, or other similar location".&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
