<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1212595202" ordinal="51" title="NOTICE OF HEARING">
  <narrative>NOTICE OF HEARING -- (Senate - June 04, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="5118">S5118</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND NATURAL RESOURCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to announce for the information of the Senate and the public that a hearing has been scheduled before Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The hearing will be held on June 17, 2008, at 2:30 p.m, in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the hearing is to receive testimony on the following bills: <bill type="s" number="1774">S. 1774</bill>, to designate the John Krebs Wilderness in the State of California, to add certain land to the Sequoia-Kings Canyon National Park Wilderness, and for other purposes; <bill type="s" number="2255">S. 2255</bill>, to amend the National Trails System Act to provide for studies of the Chisholm Trail and Great Western Trail to determine whether to add the trails to the  National Trails System, and for other purposes;  <bill type="s" number="2359">S. 2359</bill>, to establish the St. Augustine 450th Commemoration Commission, and for other purposes; <bill type="s" number="2943">S. 2943</bill>, to amend the National Trails System Act to designate the Pacific Northwest National Scenic Trail; <bill type="s" number="3010">S. 3010</bill>, to reauthorize the Route 66 Corridor Preservation Program; <bill type="s" number="3017">S. 3017</bill>, to designate the Beaver Basin Wilderness at Pictured</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of the limited time available for the hearing, witnesses may testify by invitation only. However, those wishing to submit written testimony for the hearing record should send it to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, United States Senate, Washington, DC 20510-6150, or by e-mail to rachel</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For further information, please contact David Brooks at (202) 224-9863 or Rachel Pasternack at (202) 224-0883.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
