<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1192550402" ordinal="53" title="SUPPORTING THE GOALS AND IDEALS OF RED RIBBON WEEK">
  <narrative>SUPPORTING THE GOALS AND IDEALS OF RED RIBBON WEEK -- (Senate - October 16, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="12943">S12943</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400357" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the consideration of <bill type="sr" number="348">S. Res. 348</bill>, which was submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="348">S. Res. 348</bill>) supporting the goals and ideals of Red Ribbon Week.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300075" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today in support of a resolution that commemorates the Annual Red Ribbon Campaign. I am honored to again seek the Senate's continuing support and recognition of Red Ribbon Week, which is October 23 through October 31.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1985, Special Agent Enrique "Kiki" Camarena of the Drug Enforcement Administration was kidnapped, tortured, and murdered in the line of duty by drug traffickers. Shortly after Agent Camarena's death, Congressman Duncan Hunter and high school friend Henry Lozano launched "Camarena Clubs" in the agent's hometown of Calexico, CA. In honor of Agent Camarena, hundreds of club members wore red ribbons and pledged to lead drug-free lives. The campaign quickly gained statewide and then national  prominence. In 1988, what is now the National Family Partnership organized the first National Red Ribbon Week, an 8-day event proclaimed by the U.S. Congress and chaired by then-President and Mrs. Reagan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This campaign is now the oldest and largest drug prevention program in the  Nation, reaching millions of youth through Red Ribbon Week events. Red Ribbon Week memorializes Agent Camarena, and all those who have lost their lives in the war on drugs, by educating young people about the dangers of drug abuse, promoting drug-free activities, and supporting everyone who has stood strong against illicit drugs. The red ribbon that we will wear during Red Ribbon  Week is a symbol of zero tolerance for illegal drug use and our commitment to help people, especially children, make the right life decisions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In Alaska, Red Ribbon Week is a statewide celebration involving thousands of school children and other supporters. On October 22, the Municipality of Anchorage, in conjunction with the Alaska Red Ribbon Coalition and the Boys and Girls Clubs of Alaska, will host a Red Ribbon Week kickoff. The Red Ribbon Coalition is comprised of the Anchorage School District, the Alaska State Troopers, the U.S. Drug Enforcement Administration, and the U.S. Department of Justice. In addition, the Alaska National  Guard and 43 Boys and Girls Clubs across Alaska will help other Alaskan communities celebrate Red Ribbon Week throughout the State.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As people across the country stand together against drugs, I thank my colleagues for joining me in what will hopefully be a continuation of the tradition of congressional support and recognition of Red Ribbon Week.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400357" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motion to reconsider be laid on the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="348">S. Res. 348</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="348">S. Res. 348</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas the Red Ribbon Campaign was established to commemorate the service of Enrique "Kiki" Camarena, an 11-year special agent of the Drug Enforcement Administration who was murdered in the line of duty in 1985 while engaged in the battle against illicit drugs;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Red Ribbon Campaign has been nationally recognized since 1988 to preserve Special Agent Camarena's memory and further the cause for which he gave his life, and is now the oldest and largest drug prevention program in the Nation, reaching millions of young people each year during Red Ribbon Week;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Governors and Attorneys General of the States, the National Family Partnership, Parent Teacher Associations, Boys and Girls Clubs of America, and more than 100 other organizations throughout the United States annually celebrate Red Ribbon Week during the period of October 23 through October 31;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the objective of Red Ribbon Week is to promote the creation of drug-free communities through drug prevention efforts, education, parental involvement, and community-wide support;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas drug abuse is one of the major challenges that the Nation faces in securing a safe and healthy future for our families;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas drug and alcohol abuse contribute to domestic violence and sexual assault, and place the lives of children at risk;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, although public awareness of illicit drug use is increasing, emerging drug threats and growing epidemics such as the abuse of prescription medication--the second most abused drug by youth, methamphetamine, and inhalants demand attention;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas drug dealers are specifically targeting children by marketing illicit drugs that mimic the appearance and names of well known brand-name candies and foods; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas parents, youths, schools, businesses, law enforcement agencies, religious institutions, service organizations, senior citizens, medical and military personnel, sports teams, and individuals throughout the United States will demonstrate their commitment to healthy, productive, and drug-free lifestyles by wearing and displaying red ribbons during this week-long celebration: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) supports the goals and ideals of Red Ribbon Week;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) encourages children and teens to choose to live drug-free lives; and</chair>
  <chair> (3) encourages the people of the United States to promote the creation of drug-free communities and to participate in drug prevention activities to show support for healthy, productive, and drug-free lifestyles.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
