<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1178726404" ordinal="41" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON AGRICULTURE, NUTRITION, AND FORESTRY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry be authorized to conduct a hearing during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, May 9, 2007, at 9:30 a.m. in 328A, Russell Senate Office Building. The purpose of this committee hearing will be to consider Energy and Rural Development issues for the Farm bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, May 9, 2007, at 2:30 p.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building. The purpose of the hearing is to review all-terrain vehicle, ATV, issues and possible legislative approaches to obtaining ATV safety.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, May 9, 2007, at 9:30 a.m. to hold a hearing on climate change.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, May 9, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. to hold a nomination hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet to conduct a markup on Wednesday, May 9, 2007, at 10 a.m. in Dirksen Room 226.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I. Bills: <bill type="s" number="221">S. 221</bill>, Fair Contracts for Growers Act of 2007, (Grassley, Feingold, Kohl, Leahy, Durbin); and <bill type="s" number="376">S. 376</bill>, Law Enforcement Officers Safety Act of 2007, (Leahy, Specter, Grassley, Kyl, Sessions, Cornyn).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON VETERANS' AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent for the Committee on Veterans' Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, May 9, 2007, to hold a hearing on pending benefits legislation. The hearing will take place in room 562 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building beginning at 9:30 a.m.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="SPECIAL COMMITTEE ON AGING">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Special Committee on Aging be authorized to meet today, Wednesday, May 9, 2007, from 3 p.m.-5 p.m. in Dirksen 106 for the purpose of conducting a hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON PRIVATE SECTOR AND CONSUMER SOLUTIONS TO GLOBAL WARMING AND WILDLIFE PROTECTION.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Environment and Public Works Subcommittee on Private Sector and Consumer Solutions to Global Warming and Wildlife Protection be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, May 9, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Technologies and practices to reduce greenhouse gas emissions.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
