<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1197478803" ordinal="61" title="CONGRATULATING BOYS TOWN ON ITS 90TH ANNIVERSARY CELEBRATION">
  <narrative>CONGRATULATING BOYS TOWN ON ITS 90TH ANNIVERSARY CELEBRATION -- (Senate - December 12, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="15372">S15372</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate now proceed to the consideration of <bill type="sr" number="403">S. Res. 403</bill>, which was submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="403">S. Res. 403</bill>) congratulating Boys Town on its 90th anniversary celebration.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed  to, and the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="403">S. Res. 403</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="403">S. Res. 403</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas on Wednesday, December 12, 2007, Boys Town celebrates the 90th anniversary of the date Father Flanagan founded Boys Town to serve hurting children and their families;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Father Flanagan's legacy, Boys Town, is a beacon of hope to thousands of young people across the Nation;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas in 2006 nearly 450,000 children and families found help through the Boys Town National Hotline, including 34,000 calls from youth where hotline staff intervened to save a life or provide therapeutic counseling, and nearly 1,000,000 more children were assisted through outreach and training programs;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Boys Town continues to find new ways to bring healing and hope to more children and families;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas new programs at Boys Town seek to increase the number of children assisted and bring resources and expertise to bear on the problems facing our Nation's children; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Boys Town's mission is to change the way America cares for children and families by providing and promoting a continuum of care that strengthens them in mind, body, and spirit: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) expresses its heartfelt congratulations to the Boys Town family on the historic occasion of its 90th anniversary; and</chair>
  <chair> (2) extends its thanks to the extraordinary Boys Town community for its important work with our Nation's children and families. &lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
