<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1177603218" ordinal="40" title="FOOD AND DRUG ADMINISTRATION REVITALIZATION ACT">
  <speaking speaker="300049" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, the Food and Drug Administration, FDA, plays a major role in ensuring that the American people have access to the safe and effective medicines that they need. In fact, FDA-regulated products account for about 25 cents of every consumer dollar spent. At the heart of all FDA's regulatory activities is a judgment about whether a product's benefits to users will outweigh its risks. These judgments must be science-based to allow the agency to provide the most health promotion  and protection at the least cost to the public. As we work on FDA legislation this year, we need to keep that science-based mission at the forefront of our decision making.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last week, the HELP Committee reported <bill type="s" number="1082">S. 1082</bill>, the Food and Drug Administration Act, FDARA. The bill couples must-pass reauthorizations of the Prescription Drug User Fee Act, PDUFA, and the Medical Device User Fee and Modernization Act, MDUFMA, with tour additional pieces of legislation that I am unable to support at this time. It is my hope that we can continue to work in a bipartisan way to improve this bill as it moves to the floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Prescription Drug User Fee Act, PDUFA, first enacted in 1992, gives the FDA the authority to collect user fees from pharmaceutical manufacturers in order to enhance their ability to ensure timely access to safe and effective medicines. By reducing the length of review time required to approve a drug, PDUFA has clearly been a success.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Following the success of PDUFA, Congress enacted the Medical Device User Fee and Modernization Act; MDUFMA in 2002. Like with prescription drugs, MDUFMA funds have been essential to reducing the length of time of the approval process and other improvements critical to the success of the device review process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This year, both the PDUFA and MDUFMA reauthorizations have been negotiated between the FDA and industry and are worthy of support. In fact, I believe these agreements improve both programs and will improve the safety of these products in the marketplace. If we do not renew these programs by September 30, we risk losing this essential source of funding and patients will face longer review times and  diminished access to much needed medicines and devices.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, the Kennedy-Enzi language also includes provisions on drug safety and pediatric medicines and devices. All are important issues, but each title of the bill includes provisions that I believe could do more harm than good.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Originally, drug safety legislation was intended to address legitimate concerns many had about how long it took FDA to identify unexpected complications after a drug was approved and to provide FDA with additional authorities to act in those instances.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Kennedy-Enzi language attempts to address the length of time it can take to identify problems by including language that directs the FDA to establish an active surveillance system. This is essential to addressing any potential problems with postmarket drug safety. I strongly support this in concept but feel the language needs to be strengthened to ensure that the FDA has the direction it needs to implement a robust system in an expedited timeframe. Information collected must be standardized,  and the overall system should be validated. Without these and</paragraph>
    <paragraph>other important benchmarks included in my Safer DATA bill, we are essentially setting the FDA up for failure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While not going far enough on drug surveillance, the bill goes too far on providing FDA with new authorities. The Kennedy-Enzi language imposes new requirements on manufacturers to develop Risk Evaluation and Mitigation Strategies, REMS, and gives the FDA the authority to require them in both the preapproval and postmarket settings. Importantly, the standards by which FDA can impose REMS are very broad and lack specific requirements through which this standard is triggered. This gives the FDA  excessive discretion on imposing REMS on manufacturers even when a drug has a low risk profile.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While clearly the FDA needs new authorities, it is critical to strike a balance, and I fear the Kennedy-Enzi language has gone too far and will slow the approval of new medicines and thereby reduce access.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Instead, the language should be modified so that REMS only applies when the Secretary determines that the new active surveillance system has signaled a risk. At that point, FDA should have the authority to require manufacturers to judiciously minimize risks without encumbering drug availability or interfering with drug research, development, and delivery. Any expansion of FDA authority should respect this approach.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Kennedy-Enzi language also gives the FDA the authority to require prereview of direct-to-consumer advertising, specific drug advertising disclosures, and a 2-year moratorium on direct-to-consumer advertising. As drafted, these provisions raise a variety of first amendment issues, specifically the 2-year ban on advertising. Much can be done to ensure that consumers receive information that is not false or misleading without banning patient access to health care information.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Kennedy-Enzi language also includes three separate pediatrics bills: the reauthorization of the Best Pharmaceuticals for Children Act, BPCA, the reauthorization of the Pediatric Research Equity Act, PREA, and the Pediatric Medical Device Safety and Improvement Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To encourage the study of more drugs in the pediatric population, BPCA as originally enacted as part of the Food and Drug Administration Modernization Act in 1997, and reauthorized in 2002, grants an additional 6 months of patent life to a product or pediatric exclusivity in exchange for the voluntary studies of prescription drugs conducted on children. Since its enactment, BPCA has been viewed as a highly successful program and has produced at least 132 completed studies, leading to at least  115 pediatric label changes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under the Kennedy-Enzi language, the pediatric exclusivity would be capped at 3 months if annual sales for all drugs with the same active ingredient are over $1 billion in any year. This cap for "blockbuster" drugs unfairly segments patent protection regimes by making more successful drugs subject to reduced incentives. Our health care system needs to enhance research into children's drugs, not reduce the incentives for manufacturers that produce them. Simply put, the current program is working,  and imposing a "cap" on the pediatric exclusivity award will reduce the incentive to conduct pediatric studies and, however formulated, would significantly complicate the administration of the program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enacted in 2003, PREA gives the FDA authority to require pediatric studies on the same approved indication of a certain drug in adults. BPCA and PREA work hand in hand to encourage the further study of prescription drugs in pediatric populations. It is because of the great success of these two programs that I am pleased that the bill requires both programs to be reauthorized together in 2012. This joint sunset date allows for further reauthorizations to continue to balance the incentives and  authorities that drive pediatric study.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One troubling aspect of the BPCA and PREA reauthorizations is the creation of an internal review committee. Nobody would argue that pediatric populations should not get special consideration within the inner workings of the agency; however, as drafted, the internal review committee conflicts with the current staff functions of the FDA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Pediatric Medical Device Safety and Improvement Act aims to improve the process for approving pediatric medical devices and encourages research, development, and manufacture of pediatric devices through demonstration grants and incentives. It modifies the human device exemption for medical devices to allow manufacturers to earn a profit for HDE-approved pediatric devices but maintains the requirement that a humanitarian use device is limited to one that treats and diagnoses diseases or conditions  that affect fewer than 4,000 individuals in the United States. This is a good policy, which will help foster the development of pediatric devices. Unfortunately, the bill also expands FDA's authority to require companies to conduct postmarket studies of adult devices, even in</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Of additional concern is that at this time, many provisions of the bill have never been scored by CBO. The provisions in this bill have a significant impact on the FDA and require a number of changes at the agency that will require significant dollars. Because PDUFA and MDUFMA are based on negotiations between industry and the administration, any changes that impact that careful compromise need to be fully vetted and understood. Unfortunately, at this time we do not have that information.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is clear to all that there are numerous complicated issues involved. Some provisions provide a great benefit, while others may have graver consequences than even the bill's sponsors would intend. It is my hope that as we deal with these issues, we can do so in a manner that is science based and favors patient access over regulatory burden.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask that the following statement of HHS Secretary Leavitt be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
</record>
