<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1173801604" ordinal="18" title="IMPROVING AMERICA'S SECURITY ACT OF 2007--Continued">
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I say to my colleagues, on the pending legislation, <bill type="s" number="4">S. 4</bill>, the Senate has now used up all the time postcloture so that what stands--if I could put it in a more negative light than I should--before the Senate and the vote on final passage of this important legislation is disposition of the remaining germane amendments and any other matters that can be passed by consent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are working on a managers' amendment which would contain the matters about which there is unanimous consent. We are whittling down the number of germane amendments that will need to be voted on. I say to my colleagues we hope to be able soon to announce when the last few votes on amendments and final passage will occur. But they will definitely occur this afternoon.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank the Chair, and pending further developments, I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300008" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300008" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I have spoken to the manager of the bill, and I am--with his permission and their permission--going to speak. But as soon as they are ready to reclaim the floor, to close this down, I am prepared to stop at that point, or before.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the Senator is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300008" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I know there is not a lot of time, but the amendment that is at the desk, No. 383, that I have--I ask it be called up and be considered.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is all about rail safety. The Federal Government currently has no say on where 90-ton rail tankers, filled with chlorine or other hazardous chemicals, are shipped around the Nation. The Naval Research Laboratory, at my request, some months ago, issued a report. The context of my inquiry with them was: What would happen if one of these 90-ton chlorine gas tanker cars exploded--for example, where a terrorist put C-2 underneath there in a populated area and blew it up?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What made me think of it was, you may remember almost 2 years ago now, out in North Dakota, one of these tankers leaked, and the end result was a number of adjoining towns, small towns, had to be evacuated because it was so deadly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I asked the question of the Naval Research Center. As you know, some of our best scientists in the world are there. I asked: What would happen? What would happen if a 90-ton tanker containing chlorine were to be blown up in a major metropolitan area?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the report submitted to me be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300008" topic="">
    <paragraph>Let me summarize the report.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The answer was "over 100,000 people could be seriously harmed or even killed in the first half an hour." Let me say that again. One of these tankers filled with chlorine gas--and there are hundreds, up and down the road, going through major metropolitan areas, from Los Angeles to New York and everywhere in between--what would happen if a terrorist were to explode one of those in a major metropolitan area? The answer was: "over 100,000 people could be seriously harmed or even killed in the  first half an hour."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Said another way: What happens if one of these is blown up in a freight yard in Philadelphia, PA, right along the Schuylkill River, 10 blocks, 15 blocks from City Hall, the University of Pennsylvania, Drexel University--a very populated area? Within one-half hour, 100,000 people could be seriously harmed or even killed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>How long would it take to evacuate that area? Imagine evacuating downtown New York City, Baltimore, Miami, Seattle--you name the city.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So what is the problem? Well, the problem is--and we have seen in recent reports--insurgents in Iraq are using chlorine in their attacks on civilians. There is little doubt terrorists who are targeting us here at home are paying attention. In these roadside bombs, they are--thank God they have not gotten it down very well yet--but they are injecting chlorine into that carnage they cause because they know the consequence of the dissemination of the highly toxic substance in a populated area.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nevertheless, we continue to allow these 90-ton--that is a standard: 90-ton--rail tanks containing chlorine and other hazardous chemicals to roll unprotected through the hearts of our largest cities in high-threat areas. We know the rail industry has adamantly opposed any attempt to allow local officials, in conjunction with the Department of Homeland Security and security people, to reroute these tankers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, again, look where this tanker is sitting, as shown in this picture. Do these buildings look familiar to you? This is an actual photograph of a 90-ton chlorine gas tanker car sitting in the direct view--if you look over the top of it, you can see the Hart Building, you can see the Dirksen Building, and you can see the U.S. Capitol.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By the way, I know my friend, the Presiding Officer, a former board member of Amtrak, a guy who has fought very hard to protect Amtrak--we take the train almost every day together back and forth to and from Delaware--I say to my colleagues, go on down to the station this afternoon and follow us down whenever we finish and get on the train. If it is not an Acela, stand in the back car of an Amfleet train. You can look out the back window. Watch as we pull out of the station. Tell me how many cops  you see. Tell me how many cameras you see. Tell me how much protection exists there.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Look at this tanker car, shown in this picture, sitting right out there--in the middle of nowhere, in the middle of everywhere.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, folks, the idea we do not even have as an option the ability of our security people and the mayors and local  officials to suggest these tankers bypass their cities so, God forbid, if something happens, they are not as high a prize of a target--by the way, the less sensational damage able to be done, the less likelihood it will be picked as a target.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because someone could legitimately argue: BIDEN, you are taking this out of the route--and we have other maps showing the routes of the various alternative routes that could be used to avoid the major cities. Now, they could say: You are going to be going through more rural areas. Yes, serious damage could be done in rural areas, but the prize for the terrorist is much lower. The likelihood of them concluding that instead of coming down from, for example, Newark, NJ, all the way down into  Augusta--you can, in fact, reroute these on Norfolk Southern, which goes through much less populated areas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>People legitimately say: Aren't you putting those folks at risk? No matter where these cars are, we are at risk. But again, where is the likely target? Where are terrorists going to risk their lives to be able to go in and do damage? They will do it where the most people are.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I know the rail industry, as I said, is adamantly opposed to amendment No. 306, and is likely opposed to the updated version we will vote on today. But in the face of such risks, I do not know how we can let their opposition determine whether we go forward.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment is very limited. It simply states the Secretary of Homeland Security, not the rail industry--the rail industry is not the bad guy--should determine the most secure routes for the shipments of the most dangerous chemicals, and that ownership of the track is not to be considered in making this risk-based determination; meaning, if you have something going down on a CSX track that is owned by CSX, they should be able to use and be diverted to a Norfolk Southern track. I could give  you examples all across the country, as the Presiding Officer knows.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, all I am saying is, let the Department of Homeland Security determine whether the most dangerous chemicals are able to be diverted around the most populated areas in our country. And do not--do not--in fact, use as an impediment the idea the track upon which it is being carried is not owned by the company whose car is on that track.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is all we are doing, Mr. President. The amendment would apply to only .36 percent--less than a third of a percent--of all the shipments that occur on our rail system. It only applies to through-shipments; it does not apply to the destination city. Some of this stuff goes into large populations, where that is the end point. It doesn't say it cannot go there, but it does say we should reduce the probability of catastrophic damage by allowing them to be rerouted, if that is the judgment of  the Department of Homeland Security.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A similar amendment was passed by voice vote in the House Homeland Security Committee today. Not one Republican or Democrat spoke in opposition to this measure. This amendment will ensure that the Senate is on the right side of the issue as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I was asked by my colleague from Connecticut, one of the two managers, that he be added as a cosponsor. I ask unanimous consent his name be added.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300008" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I understand that a man with whom I hardly disagree, Senator Inouye, has reservations. I hope he will reconsider those reservations. Again, all we are doing is letting the Department of Homeland Security, in conjunction with local officials, make the judgment whether the risk is so high that it warrants it being rerouted. Of all the cargo on all of the tracks in America, we are talking about .36 of 1 percent, all that is transported on rail. So we are not asking  much. The downside of us being mistaken is significant.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I close by quoting from the rail industry's letter opposing this amendment. They say:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rerouting would not eliminate the risk, but instead shift it from one population to another.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is true, but this amendment says the Department of Homeland Security, not the rail industry, should determine how to weigh and respond to this known potentially catastrophic risk. What did we just debate last week on the floor? The allocation of resources for Homeland Security should be going toward the danger lines. There is nothing that is risk free--nothing. It is a little like my friend from Delaware and I have heard so much every time we come up with rail security legislation. We are  told we cannot secure every mile of track. That is true, we can't, but there is a big difference with a terrorist taking a single train off a track somewhere in rural America and a terrorist taking a train at 140 miles an hour into the most visited area in Washington, DC, Union Station, at a high speed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is a difference between blowing up a tunnel underneath the Chesapeake Bay or the Hudson River and blowing up a tunnel in the middle of some rural area. Terrorists pick targets for the greatest effect. So the idea that we would not reroute--if the Department of Homeland Security determined it made sense--a series of chlorine gas tankers from a major metropolitan area to a more rural area seems to me to be such a silly argument to make.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The idea is, how do we reduce the risk for the most people of the United States of America? Again, I will end where I began. When this was called to my attention some years ago, I went to the Naval Research Laboratory and I asked them--and I have included this in my statement--to tell me what would happen--and, again, it doesn't take much for terrorists to figure out a way to puncture a hole in the bottom or the side of one of these tanks by use of explosives or other devices. The answer was  that if that were to occur in a highly populated area, "over 100,000 could be seriously harmed or even killed in the first half hour."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Imagine how many people we get to evacuate reasonably so that there is essentially no one left in a half hour. If the gun goes off right now, how long does it take downtown Manhattan or downtown Washington, DC, or Capitol Hill to evacuate people so they are not around? If you don't evacuate--to say it another way--within a half hour, a whole lot more than 100,000 people will be seriously injured or will die.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I know the Senator from Connecticut supports this amendment. I don't know what the view of our colleague from Maine is. I hope they understand how limited this amendment is, how consequential it is. I hope my colleagues, when it comes time to vote, will vote in favor of this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank the Chair and I thank the managers. I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Maine is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, the amendment offered by the senior Senator from Delaware is actually more under the jurisdiction of the Commerce Committee than the Homeland Security Committee. Nevertheless, in the absence of a member of the Commerce Committee on the Senate floor, I want to express my concern about the amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As I understand it, the effect of the amendment would be to require that hazardous materials on rail cars be routed around high-threat areas, with some exceptions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The problem is that the Commerce Committee title on rail security already has a section that addresses hazardous materials by requiring a mitigation plan that can include rerouting but only when the homeland security advisory system is at a high or severe level of threat or when specific intelligence indicates that there is a specific or imminent threat.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think this amendment, while well-intentioned, creates all sorts of practical problems. The Chamber of Commerce, which is rating this as a key vote, lists some of those that I want to read from a letter that we received from the Chamber today. The letter reads:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Biden amendment, which would require mandatory rerouting of shipments of hazardous materials around high threat corridors, would not reduce risk to homeland security. It would only reallocate risk among population centers. In fact, the amendment would actually increase risk by either eliminating routes that provide optimal  overall safety and security, or by adding hundreds of miles and additional days to the journeys of shipments of hazardous materials via less direct routes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In other words, if we are causing this hazardous material to be on its journey far longer because it is not going by  the more direct route, that could in fact increase the problems or the chances of the hazardous material being attacked. The letter goes on to point out that the railroads have been working with the Federal Government, with chemical manufacturers, and with consumers to explore the use of coordinated routing arrangements to reduce mileage  and time in the transit of highly hazardous materials.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment seems to be going in the opposite direction. Another one of my colleagues has raised the issue of chlorine shipments to wastewater treatment plants. Those shipments need to be made. It raises a lot of practical questions about how to move this material. Another colleague raised the issue to me of whether this would result in more trucks on our highways carrying hazardous materials.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I think that while I agree with the overall intent of the amendment, I am much more comfortable with the approach taken by the Commerce Committee--a committee which, unfortunately, I don't serve on, so I don't have the level of expertise that its members have in talking about this issue. I do expect some members of the Commerce Committee to come to the floor and debate this issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I do want my colleagues to know that the distinguished Senator's amendment is controversial, that it may have unintended consequences. Based on my knowledge of the issue, I hope it will be defeated.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thank you.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Delaware is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300008" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I appreciate the comments of the Senator from Maine. She may have misunderstood two aspects of the amendment. One, it doesn't mandatorily require rerouting at all. It says the Department of Homeland Security can reroute, if they determine it should be rerouted.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>No. 2, the freight industry, where they made the judgment on how much further in distance it would travel if, in fact, you were to reroute, factored in only that it had to be rerouted on their own tracks. So the idea being that they would not be able to--this happens all the time, where other tracks are used; for example, the Chesapeake using Norfolk Southern track.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>No. 3, the Chamber of Commerce is opposed because it costs more money. A lot of these things cost more money. Will it cost more money to be able to reroute up to one-third of 1 percent of the freight on rail? Yes. But I ask the rhetorical question: What will it cost if one of these tankers goes off in a populated area? What will the cost then be to the very businesses that are most concerned about it?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Fourth, this doesn't affect destination. If the chlorine gas tanker car is going to a water treatment facility, it still goes to that facility. Nothing changes. What we could have changed is what we did in Delaware, not use chlorine. There are other means by which water can be purified. We have done it in our home State. That is what you should do. But that doesn't stop this car, or any other car, from going to such a facility.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me emphasize again that there is no prohibition on end point distribution. If the car is designed to go to a facility in the center of a city, it goes to the center of the city. There is nothing you can do about that. That is very different than--I am making up these numbers for illustration--you may have one of these tankers going in once a month versus 50 going through the same city in a month or 100 in a month. This is all about percentages. You play the percentages. Again, it is true,  rerouting may render cities in North Dakota--well, they would not be rerouted in North Dakota, but I referenced the small towns. There was a chlorine gas tanker car going across the top of the Nation and, thank God, what happened was it went off in a rural part of the world. You were able to evacuate the three cities and nobody died. Had that same thing occurred in the middle of Chicago, you would not be able to evacuate the city. We would not have had time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, yes, it is true. Are you going to put a different population at risk? Yes, about one-tenth, one-twentieth, one one-hundredth or one one-thousandth of the population, depending on where it is rerouted. So it is a little bit like saying: Why do we spend so much money worrying about the Sears Tower? It is there, it is big, and it is a target. Is it possible that a terrorist would go into a building that is two stories and blow it up? Yes. Can they fly an aircraft into a rural town grain elevator?  Yes. But that is not what we are worried about. They are not likely to do that. They are likely to fly a plane, plant a bomb, do something devastating where the most people are.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I find it to be a totally disingenuous argument. This is about the bottom line. I measure the bottom line--as I suspect all of us would if we thought about it--in human life.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bottom line, in terms of the dollars, the impact that would occur in a catastrophic circumstance is if there is a town of 1,000 people and a town of 6 million people, there is a phenomenal difference whether that chlorine gas tanker car gets exploded.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me summarize. It is indicated by the Department of Homeland Security again that an explosion of a rail tanker carrying chlorine would kill 17,500 individuals, require the hospitalization of another 100,000--and only then if we evacuate within a half an hour. We can evacuate a city of 1,000 people in half an hour. We cannot evacuate a city of 4 million people in half an hour. So it matters.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If this rail tanker goes off in New York City, my friend from New York is going to be on the floor again pointing out the catastrophic impact. If it goes off in rural Delaware, it will be a tragedy for me and my constituency, but there will be a significant magnitude of difference.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So everything we do in terms of allocation of resources goes in this place to deal with protecting the most people who can be protected: The shipment originates or the point of destination is in the high-threat corridor; no practical alternative routes exist. If they don't exist, it doesn't get rerouted. Rerouting would not increase the likelihood of an attack. It would decrease the likelihood of an attack because people attack targets that have the maximum impact. This would not increase the  total number of cars on the track. It would allow the potential for homeland security to reroute them away from the places that would do the most damage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank the Chair and yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Maine.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I do expect additional Members on my side of the aisle to come and debate this issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I wish to clarify that the language, as I read it, in the Senator's amendment, is not discretionary, it is mandatory. It does allow for some certain significant exceptions for the Department to make findings on, but it clearly says:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The regulations issued under this section shall--</paragraph>
    <paragraph>(1) except as provided in--</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The subsections part--</paragraph>
    <paragraph>provide that any rail shipment containing high hazard materials be rerouted around any high threat corridor. &lt;p&gt;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I don't see it as giving the Department great discretion if that determination is made because of the word "shall," which is not permissive, it is mandatory. There are some exceptions later which the Senator has referred to, such as the origination point or point of destination being within the high-threat corridor. But as I read the amendment, it pretty clearly calls for rerouting.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I wanted to clarify that issue. Maybe I misunderstood the Senator from Delaware, but I thought he was saying it did not require rerouting.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300008" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, if the Senator will yield, she is correct, but it only requires the Secretary to do it if he or she concludes that there is a safer way to reroute the shipment. If the conclusion made by the Secretary is that in a high-risk corridor the rerouting would not result in an increased safety margin for the shipment, then he or she need not reroute it. But it is correct, the presumption is, in a high-risk corridor we reroute if it is not a point of destination or origin but  only if the determination by the Secretary is that the shipment, in fact, would be safer to be rerouted. It is on page 4 of the amendment. It is section 2, subparagraph E, "Transportation and Storage of High Hazard Materials through High Threat Corridor" areas. It says:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In General.--The standards for the Secretary to grant exceptions under section  (d)(4) shall require a finding by the Secretary that--</paragraph>
    <paragraph>(A) the shipment originates or the point of destination is in the high threat corridor;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>(B) there is no practical alternative route;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>(C) there is an unanticipated, temporary emergency that threatens the lives of persons or property in the high threat corridor;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>(D) there would be no harm to persons or property beyond the owners or operator of the railroad in the event of a successful terrorist attack on shipment; or</paragraph>
    <paragraph>(E) rerouting would increase the likelihood of a terrorist attack on the shipment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bottom line is that it should be left to the discretion of the Secretary to decide not to reroute rather than the privately owned railroad. I thank the Senator for her clarification.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="">
    <paragraph>I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300087" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300087" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I will speak briefly because I know the floor leader for the minority side has people coming to speak to respond to the amendment. I am not speaking on the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the Senator is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300087" topic="U.S. ATTORNEYS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise because I heard Attorney General Gonzales speak about the growing, disheartening, and alarming scandal with the U.S. attorneys. I wish to say, first, that this is a serious issue. In every district in America, the U.S. attorney represents the enforcer of the Federal law without fear or favor. U.S. attorneys over decades have built up a reputation of being not part of politics but, rather, enforcing the law, as they say, without fear or favor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over every Justice Department office in every corner of the land is the eagle perched on a branch, with her claw holding a bunch of arrows. When you see that symbol, it denotes strength, but it denotes fairness and impartiality. That fairness, that impartiality has received a serious blow--maybe not a mortal blow because of the resilience of our country, but a serious blow--over what has happened in the Justice Department over the last several months.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What we have had in the past is misstatement after misstatement about what has happened. The story has kept changing, we can't get the truth, and that is why we had no choice but to undertake our own investigation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me say that time and time again we have heard falsehoods. We were told that all seven of the eight U.S. attorneys were fired for performance reasons. It now turns out this was false, as their glowing performance evaluations attest.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We were told by the Attorney General he would "never, ever make a change for political reasons." It now turns out all this was false, as the evidence makes clear this approach was based purely on politics to punish prosecutors who were perceived to be too light on Democrats or too tough on Republicans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We were told by the Attorney General this was "an overblown personnel matter." It now turns out, however, that far from being a low-level personnel matter, this was a longstanding plan to exact political vendettas or make political payoffs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We were told the White House was not involved in the plan to fire these U.S. attorneys. It now turns out this was a complete falsehood. Harriet Miers was one of the masterminds of this plan, as demonstrated by numerous e-mails made public today. She communicated extensively with Kyle Sampson about firing of U.S. attorneys. In fact, she originally wanted to fire and replace the top prosecutors in all 93 districts in the country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We were told that Karl Rove had no involvement in getting his protege appointed U.S. attorney in Arkansas. In fact, there is a letter from the Department of Justice:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Department is not aware of Karl Rove playing any role in the decision to appoint Mr. Griffin.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Griffin was the attorney whom they appointed. It now turns out this was a falsehood, as demonstrated by Mr. Sampson's e-mail:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Getting him--</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Griffin--</paragraph>
    <paragraph>was important to Harriet, Karl, et cetera. &lt;p&gt;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We were told the change to the PATRIOT Act was an innocent attempt to fix a legal loophole, to help the war on terrorism, not a cynical strategy to bypass the Senate's role in serving as a check and balance. It now turns out this, too, was a falsehood--another one--as demonstrated by an e-mail from Mr. Sampson:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I strongly recommend that as a matter of administration, we utilize the new statutory provisions that authorize the AG to make USA appointments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Sampson specifically argued that by using these provisions, the administration "can give far less deference to home State Senators and thereby get (1) our preferred person appointed and (2) do it faster and more efficiently at less political cost to the White House."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So it has been misstatement after misstatement. To put it delicately, prevarication after prevarication, changes in stories, coverups in stories. And the only reason, frankly, we are getting to the truth is we have the majority, and we have the ability to subpoena and have hearings and investigate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A few minutes ago, Attorney General Gonzales spoke. I have to say I have no animus toward Attorney General Gonzales. In fact, I like the man. He seems to me to be a genuinely nice man. He doesn't seem to me to be one of these hard popular warriors who populate the administration in such large numbers and, frankly, we have seen in Justice Department appointees throughout the Justice Department in far too great a number. But simply being a nice person, being a "nice guy" is not enough, particularly  when you are not performing your job.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Attorney General got up and said:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am ultimately responsible, but simply claiming responsibility is not enough.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He said:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I was not involved in any memos or discussions of what was going on.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is his quote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He said:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many decisions are delegated.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, did the Attorney General not know that eight U.S. attorneys were to be fired? If he didn't know, he shouldn't be Attorney General, plain and simple. That is not a minor personnel decision. That is a major act that has now shaken the integrity of the U.S. Attorney's Offices--not only those in question but all of them--to the core.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To simply say decisions were delegated, that is a sorry excuse. And then, of course, if the Attorney General knew, that one doesn't work either.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Attorney General has said:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I will do the best I can to maintain the confidence of the American people.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Attorney General, you have already lost that confidence. It has not simply been on this issue, although this is the straw that has broken the camel's back, and when you sat in a room with Senator Leahy and Senator Feinstein and Senator Specter and myself last Thursday and seemed to give this crisis, most considered crisis, the back of your hand and say it is not terribly important and don't worry, we will fix it without caring about it, my total confidence was shaken,  and I believe the others in the room felt the same.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This was, as I said, the straw that broke the camel's back. It was hardly the only decision. On issue after issue, the Attorney General has not stood up for the rule of law, which is his foremost duty. On issue after issue, whether it be wiretaps, whether it be national security letters, whether it be the unitary theory of the Executive, allowing the Executive to do everything with no checks and balances, this Secretary has been a rubberstamp for policies that the courts have found repeatedly  unconstitutional.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Attorney General, unfortunately, in my judgment, misconceives his role. The Attorney General misconceives his role because he still sees himself as counsel to the President, his previous job, where he rubberstamped everything the President did. But when you are the President's counsel, your job is to serve the President, period. When you become Attorney General, you have a higher  duty. That duty is the rule of law--to preserve it, to protect it,  to defend it. For whatever reason, the Attorney General doesn't see that as his role. His time in office should be over.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The U.S. attorneys scandal and all the other instances where the Attorney General did not protect the rule of law are just too great a weight for the office to bear. To simply say "I am responsible" and not tell people what it is all about makes no sense. We just saw Scooter Libby be convicted. Many said he was a fall guy. We are not going to have another Scooter Libby, another fall guy. Kyle Sampson did many wrong things, and it is very possible he broke the criminal law, but, as Harry Truman  said, the buck stops at the top. The buck stops with the Attorney General. It defies belief that his chief of staff was making all these major decisions without his knowledge, particularly when it is clear that at least on a few instances he admits he had phone calls from the President and from others about this issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to say one other thing, because this issue is not going to go away. This issue is going to stay with us until we find out everything that has happened, for the sake of punishing those who did wrong but also, more importantly, to clear the air and restore the good name of the U.S. attorneys who were fired incorrectly and of the U.S. attorneys--a more numerous group--who were not involved in this issue but whose reputations have been called into question. Tomorrow, if someone is indicted  by a U.S. attorney who had no involvement in this scandal and their defense attorney says politics was involved, the public may believe it, given what we have seen happen thus far. So it is our obligation, it is our moral imperative to get to the bottom of this, to clear the air, and to restore the reputation of U.S. Attorney's Offices now and into the future, and that is just what we will do.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam President, I yield the floor, and I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="U.S. ATTORNEYS">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, we are making progress in disposing of the final amendments pending as we head toward final passage of <bill type="s" number="4">S. 4</bill>. So at this time, I would like to propound a unanimous consent request that there are a number of pending amendments which I understand can be considered and agreed to without the necessity of a rollcall vote, and two of these amendments will have second-degree amendments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I now ask unanimous consent that it be in order for the Senate to proceed en bloc to the consideration of the following amendments, that they be agreed to en bloc, and that the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, the Kyl amendment, No. 357, with a Feingold second-degree amendment, No. 441.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second, a Schumer amendment, No. 337, with a modification that is at the desk, and with an Ensign second-degree amendment, No. 448.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Third, a Bond amendment, No. 389, with a modification at the desk.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Fourth, and finally, a Stevens amendment, No. 299.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, these amendments have been cleared on this side of the aisle, and I do not object.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300040" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I speak today about my amendment to create the law enforcement assistance force. This amendment is a common-sense idea and I hope my colleagues would adopt this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My amendment proposes the creation of a law enforcement assistance force which is a system for retired law enforcement personnel to apply to DHS, and complete the necessary paperwork and training, before a disaster occurs. Then, when disaster happens, DHS would have a pool of qualified first responders who could be called into action. These volunteers would be detailed to a Federal, State, or local law enforcement agency to work side by side with law enforcement located in affected communities.  The amendment also provides that DHS would reimburse volunteers for their costs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The need for properly trained first responders was never greater than it was immediately after Hurricane Katrina. In the wake of this disaster, I toured the gulf region and saw the devastation firsthand. A situation caused by natural disaster was made worse by the way Federal, State and local government responded. I say this not to criticize anyone but to propose a way to improve how America will respond in the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the aftermath of any disaster, there is an acute need for trained rescue and recovery personnel. These needs are often met by volunteers who, having seen their fellow Americans in need, travel across country to answer the call for help. In the aftermath of Katrina, there was no shortage of volunteers who answered this call. Their willingness to help is a testament to the American spirit. Unfortunately, these volunteers were not used in a way that was equal to their spirit or the needs of the  people affected by this storm.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As the media reported, FEMA diverted many volunteer first responders to places outside of the disaster area. Some highly skilled emergency response volunteers were sent to Arkansas to prepare paperwork. Others were  diverted to Atlanta to hand out fliers and still others were forced to attend "sensitivity training" seminars. Meanwhile, in the hardest hit areas of the gulf region, people suffered. Many needed basic medical care and supplies. The resources  of local first responders and government officials were strained. The local responders needed reinforcements, especially when lawlessness broke out. Responding to a disaster is always a difficult job. But like we advise at-risk communities to take steps to prepare for potential disasters, the Federal Government also has an obligation to prepare in advance as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My amendment creates a process to enable FEMA and DHS to put qualified first responders in place in the immediate aftermath of disaster. It will ensure a better Federal response by providing State and local communities with the reinforcements they need. I believe there is a willingness on the part of retired law enforcement to volunteer their experience and expertise in times of crisis. In fact, the idea for this amendment was given to me by a friend of mine, Tom Page, who is a retired Las Vegas  Metro Police officer. I thank him for this suggestion and I urge my colleagues to adopt the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300010" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I would like to commend Senators LIEBERMAN and COLLINS for all their hard work on <bill type="s" number="4">S. 4</bill> and I would especially like to thank them for their support of my amendment calling for further congressional review and action with regard to the recommendations of the 9/11 Commission.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The 9/11 Commission identified many shortfalls, some in the intelligence community and some in congressional oversight.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We can never ease the pain and anguish of the 9/11 families resulting from the deaths of their loved ones. It is possible, however, to do everything within our power to ensure more American families are not subjected to a similar nightmare.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We owe it to the 9/11 families as well as the American people to adopt reforms that will improve intelligence collection and dissemination, as well as will improve congressional oversight.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Putting our own house in order may not be popular, but it is the right thing to do.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I look forward to working with the chairman and ranking member, as well as the members of the Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee to continue to improve U.S. intelligence and congressional oversight of U.S. intelligence.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In closing, I would also like to thank Ms. Holly Idelson of Senator LIEBERMAN's staff and Mr. Brandon Milhorn of Senator COLLINS's staff for their assistance to me and my staff. Both of these young people went out of their way to assist us, and I am grateful to them for their courteous demeanor and their professional conduct.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300021" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I rise today in support of Senate amendment No. 389 offered by my colleague from Missouri, Senator BOND. It is appropriate that this amendment be offered to the 9/11 bill as it is a first step in implementing one of the few outstanding recommendations made by the 9/11 Commission--to reform congressional oversight of the intelligence community. I am proud to be a cosponsor of this important amendment and thank Senator BOND for his leadership on this  issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The 9/11 Commission suggested that the rules of the House of Representatives and the Senate lack the power, influence and sustained capability to effectuate oversight of the intelligence community. As such, they recommended that Congress establish one committee in each House of Congress with both authorizing and appropriation authority for the intelligence community or create a joint committee based on the model of the old Joint Committee on Atomic Energy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Just this year, the House of Representatives amended their rules to create a new panel on the Appropriations Committee with members of both the Intelligence Committee and the Appropriations Committee. While the House provision does not meet the 9/11 Commission recommendation in full, the Senate has not acted at all. As every Member of this body knows, reforming Congress, especially the Senate, can be difficult and will face much resistance. However, the Senate should not be an exception to government  reform after September 11, 2001. We should lead by example. We owe the American public and the families of those lost on September 11, 2001 to continue to improve intelligence collection and coordination as well as to improve congressional oversight.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I know many have ideas on reform in the Senate, and we should explore those. We need to find the most effective way to conduct vital, and often difficult, intelligence oversight. That is why this amendment is so important--it asks the Senate Select Committee on Intelligence and the Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee to each review the 9/11 Commission's recommendation. Members of the Senate with expertise in reform and intelligence will review the oversight process and develop  recommendations on the most valuable reforms.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In conclusion, I hope all my colleagues will support this amendment and work with the committees in the Senate to improve the congressional oversight process.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300052" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, we certainly know how complicated and even vexing the process of reforming the intelligence community is. On the one hand, we now have in place a new structure, with an overarching office of the Director of National Intelligence, that is responsible for addressing many of the institutional and structural impediments that led to our intelligence community's underperformance in the last years of the 20th century, leaving us more vulnerable to the attacks of September  11. The second and recently confirmed Director of the Office of National Intelligence, Mike McConnell, assumes leadership in a structure that is up and running, if still on its shakedown cruise. In Mike McConnell we have a leader that will take the DNI to the levels of authority and accomplishment we in Congress who created the Office of the DNI intended.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Throughout the IC we have seen many promising developments. Agencies are infused with resources and focus, and they are addressing our priority and hard targets like no other time during my 30 years in the Senate. Mike Hayden at CIA is providing leadership to an organization that is truly beginning to reach out of its petrified structures and mindset of the past to bravely and creatively take on the intelligence challenges of today and tomorrow. As a member of the Intelligence Committee, I make  every effort to commend and encourage all of these positive developments, and I know I am joined by most of my colleagues.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is the good news. The bad news is that intelligence reform has many unfinished aspects. There are still deep cultural problems with the way certain IC organizations, particularly the CIA, work. We still have far to go and addressing the challenge of hard targets, like North Korea and Iran. All of these challenges will take time and leadership to address.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The 9/11 Commission's report on the intelligence failures leading to September 11 also focused how Congress needed to change. The report stated:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under the terms of existing rules and resolutions the House and Senate intelligence committees lack the power, influence, and sustained capability to meet this challenge.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Commission recommended:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Either Congress should create a joint committee for intelligence ..... or it should create House and Senate committees with combined authorizing and appropriations powers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We began to improve congressional oversight with <bill type="sr" number="445">S. Res. 445</bill>, passed immediately after the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004. We removed term limits, raised the stature of the committee to an A Committee, and returned to the use of designated staff. But this was tinkering in comparison to the 9/11 Commission's recommendation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I recognize this is a difficult question, for all of the reasons of congressional resistance and established prerogatives. But I think that we should not abandon addressing the very substantive question of the current structure that greatly limits intelligence committee control over intelligence community appropriations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Therefore, I am pleased that amendment No. 389 has been accepted to <bill type="s" number="4">S. 4</bill>, and I commend the author of this amendment, the vice chairman of the Senate Select Committee on Intelligence, Senator Bond. I am pleased to  note that this amendment has the cosponsorship of the chairman of the committee, Senator Rockefeller. This amendment requests a joint review of this question be conducted by both the Intelligence and the Homeland Security  Committees, and be presented by year's end. This is not a radical proposal, in and of itself, but keeps the Senate focused on an unresolved question, a question whose importance to the question of congressional oversight of our intelligence community cannot be underestimated.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Intelligence reform is an ongoing process. I happen to believe that, when our institutional will flags or is diverted, we should remind ourselves of the costs of intelligence failure, and steel ourselves to the fact that intelligence will play a larger role in our national defense for the foreseeable future. And we should never abandon our oversight of intelligence reform, our dedication to supporting the most dynamic intelligence community, and our responsibility to conducting this oversight  in the most effective manner possible.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I thank the Chair and my friend from Maine, and I notify our colleagues that we are working very hard to eliminate the remaining objections on components of the managers' amendment. We anticipate at least one more rollcall vote on one of the pending amendments and then final passage, and hopefully that will happen soon.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Pending that, Madam President, I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300049" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300049" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, while we are waiting here to line up a vote on this amendment and this bill, I will speak briefly relative to my thoughts on how this bill is evolving. Like everyone, I was very impressed with the work of the 9/11 Commission. I think they did a superb job of pointing out what were, unfortunately, very significant problems which we have as a nation relative to our preparedness to fight terrorism. I had the good fortune to chair the Homeland Security Subcommittee of  the Appropriations Committee for the last 2 years and spent a considerable time before that working on the accounts of the FBI. We worked hard, honestly, to try to address some of the issues which were raised by the 9/11 Commission and, as a practical matter, the great majority of the issues raised by the 9/11 Commission have been addressed and are moving forward, hopefully, to a constructive resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill, although it has the 9/11 Commission imprimatur on it as its name, is more of a clutter--a collection of various ideas, some of which the 9/11 Commission agrees with, some of which I suspect they never even thought of discussing and, as a practical matter, the bill as a whole, in my humble opinion, in its present form would actually end up undermining rather than improving our safety as a nation. There are a number of reasons for that, but at the moment the most significant reason is  the unionization language in this bill which essentially says the TSA will become a unionized organization.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When we originally set up the TSA, which was a matter of considerable debate on this floor, that issue was at the essence, at the center, of the discussion as to why and how we were going to set up the TSA. The belief was at the time we set up the TSA and the commitment was at that time that we would not create a unionized organization.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Why was that? It is not that unions do not do good work. Unions do extraordinary work. They have been one of the great forces in American culture for producing and mainstreaming many Americans, from the standpoint of income and social activity, having a group to participate with. They have been an extraordinarily positive force. But the belief was--and it is an accurate belief arrived at after considerable thought and a great deal of debate--that unionizing TSA would be like unionizing the military,  to give an example.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The TSA is the front line of our defense relative to protecting airplanes that fly in America today. We know air traffic is the No. 1 source for attack from the al-Qaida interests. We know that they, in their handbooks and their training manuals, constantly come back to the use of aircraft as a weapon, and unfortunately we saw them use it on 9/11.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Having a secure transportation industry, especially in the aircraft area, is absolutely critical to our protecting our Nation from acts of terrorism. That is why we put in place the TSA. They are the front line of securing our air transportation system in this country. They are like a military force. Their purpose is to be moved around quickly to areas of weakness. Their purpose is to make sure they execute efficiently the review of people getting on aircraft to make sure those people are appropriately  screened.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>You cannot have incompetence. You can't have inefficiency. You can't have poorly trained people or people who do not sort of get with the program. You must have a very disciplined, focused group of individuals managing the security at our airports. That is the goal we were hoping to accomplish with the TSA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It was fully understood, because I was involved in the debate, that when we set up the TSA it would not be unionized because union rules inherently create delay and they create stricture and straitjackets and make it very difficult to manage different issues that have to be managed aggressively and with fluidity by the leadership of the TSA and the TSA teams on the ground.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To create a unionized TSA will take away that flexibility, that efficiency. It will take away the ability to assure the people who are doing the screening will be the best we can get and they are doing it in the most effective way that can be done. In my opinion, putting this language in this bill, if it were to pass, would undermine security generally.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are other issues with this bill which I can assure you, in my reading of the 9/11 Commission report, they did not think of in the terms this bill is structured: specifically, the formula for the distribution of funds. I chaired the Appropriations subcommittee which had responsibility for distributing funds relative to terrorist activity in this country. We do have this pool of funds which is distributed to all the States and all the regions in this country under a formula. My opinion is  if you want to effectively use that money, it should be threat based. That should be the No. 1 priority and the No. 1 criterion. Is the money going where the threat is highest?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We know there are certain targets in this country which are high-threat areas: New York City, the subway system specifically, but a lot of parts of New York City; Los Angeles; Washington, DC. These are clearly high-priority targets when you are talking about terrorists. Terrorists have goals. One of their goals is to destroy our culture and kill as many Americans as they can, according to al-Qaida, but another is to make a statement internationally. That is why they picked the World Trade Center.  That was a recognized international symbol.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I know there are places in New Hampshire that are probably susceptible to terrorist attack. I am sure they are. But the fact is, it is unlikely, if you are ordering priorities, that most of them are going to be very high on a priority list for terror attack--certainly one structured by an al-Qaida type organization. They may be from domestic terrorism; that is different--domestic terrorism such as hit Oklahoma City. But if there were a structured terrorist attack from an Islamic fundamentalist  group, we can prioritize what is the terrorist threat and what is not the terrorist threat.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The money should go to the threat. Now how does that affect New Hampshire? It means New Hampshire would get less money. As the chairman of an Appropriations subcommittee, I had responsibility for this area up until this year, when I switched over to foreign affairs accounts. I strongly promoted the program of putting the money where the threat was, to the disadvantage of New Hampshire, because I felt that was the way it should be done.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now this bill comes along and tries to reorder that in a way that essentially says every State, every community will get, for lack of a better word,  "walking around money" for purposes of buying security, to the detriment of the high-threat areas. We only have so much money.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Once we have secured the high-threat areas and we are fairly comfortable, then we can start distributing it maybe more broadly and without any accountability for threat. But initially the distribution should be based on threat.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Yes, every State should get some, but it should not be under the formula that is in this bill. It should be a much lower absolute commitment of dollars and a much higher commitment of dollars in the threat area. This is what bothers me about this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, there is the ability of people to get access to classified intelligence briefings and materials. This is playing with fire when we start significantly expanding access to this type of material. Because it is this material falling into the wrong hands by accident, which it might be, or just oversight, because it is in so many hands, because it is expanded by this bill and going into so many hands, that if it falls into the wrong places, people can trace the source, and protecting  these sources of where we get intelligence is absolutely the most critical thing we have to do. If we have a good source of intelligence on how people want to attack us, protecting that source is absolutely essential.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Some of the intelligence material that will be released under this bill--with good intentions, but, unfortunately, the Congress tends to be a sieve, and no matter how aggressively people try to protect that information, it seems to get out--could easily expand the number of people available who have access to this information to a point where the security of the administration will come into question.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So these are very serious issues relative to this bill. The most serious is the unionization of a nonunion, lean, effective organization which would protect our transportation system, especially air traffic; the failure to put the money on the target which is threatened; and the issue of expanding the availability of very sensitive intelligence information in a way that might undermine the sources of that information.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Those are the reservations I have about this bill. That is why I will not be able to support the bill when it comes up for final passage should it be in its present form.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Connecticut.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, we are coming to the moment when we adopt the managers' amendment and proceed to final passage. I want to respond to some of the things said by my friend from New Hampshire.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the Senator may proceed.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>In response to my friend from New Hampshire, two things: One is, <bill type="s" number="4">S. 4</bill> is a direct response not just to the original 9/11 Commission in 2004, which was the basis of the Intelligence Reform Terrorism Prevention Act of that year, but it is a response directly to the appeal the 9/11 Commission issued in December of 2005 that there was unfinished business.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That appeal was not only seconded but echoed and amplified by the various organizations representing families who lost loved ones on 9/11 in the terrorist attack of that day.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So this legislation before the Senate now, about to go to final amendment consideration and adoption, includes improvements in information sharing--the critical question of connecting the dots before the terrorists can strike us so we can stop them from doing so. It creates a new dedicated grant fund to support interoperable communications equipment--complicated words which simply mean whether in a crisis, a potential terrorist attack, or a natural disaster such as Katrina, our firefighters,  our police officers, our emergency responders can talk to each other as they were not able to do on &#xD0;9/11.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a balanced, progressive recommendation to solve once and for all by legislation the ongoing dispute about how to distribute homeland security grant funding. We have improved the security requirements of the so-called visa waiver program. We have strengthened the Privacy and Civil Liberties Board and done much else. There is a lot constructive here. One of the parts of this legislation that I believe still should be the least controversial and, frankly, not the most important but an act  of fairness consistent with our effort to improve homeland security, was simply to give the transportation security officers at the Transportation Security Agency, who now can join a union but cannot collectively bargain, the same right to collectively bargain in very limited areas without the right to strike, the same rights that most other employees</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is unfortunate that is so much the focus of discussion about this bill because this bill is a direct response to the appeals of the 9/11 Commissioners and the 9/11 families to take constructive action to respond to the statements that the Commission itself made in 2004 and again in 2005: America is safer than it was on 9/11/01 but not yet safe enough.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill, which is not controversial and ought to receive nonpartisan support, will make the people of America, in an age of terrorism, safer yet than they have been before. It is why I strongly urge my colleagues across party lines to support final passage of the legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I hope soon to be able to propound a series of unanimous consent agreements. I am waiting for final clearance from my ranking member. As soon as that happens I will rise to do so.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that notwithstanding its adoption, the Ensign amendment No. 448 be considered a first-degree amendment, agreed to, and that it be inserted at the appropriate place in the bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300092" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300092" topic="REQUESTED RESIGNATIONS OF SEVEN UNITED STATES ATTORNEYS">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I have sought recognition to comment about the events in the Department of Justice over the course of the past 10 days, with respect to the request for the resignations of seven United States attorneys and the disclosures that the FBI was improperly using national security letters.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With respect to the matter about the request for resignations of the United States attorneys, I believe it is important for the Judiciary Committee to proceed with its inquiry to find out exactly what happened. There is no doubt--I think it is undisputed--that the Attorney General has the authority to replace United States attorneys. There is a serious question if they are replaced for improper motives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We know when President Clinton was elected, one of his first acts in early 1993, when he took office, was to replace all 93 of the United States attorneys. I had the occasion recently to discuss this with the Attorney General of Pennsylvania, Tom Corbett, who was a U.S. attorney at that time for the Western District of Pennsylvania. In 1993, he had the position in the United States attorneys organization to make those telephone calls. That was handled in due course, and nobody challenged the  President's authority to replace United States attorneys.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, questions have arisen as to whether United States attorneys were replaced improperly--for example, the question has been raised as to U.S. Attorney Lam in the Southern District of California, in San Diego, and whether she was replaced because of her conviction of former Congressman Duke Cunningham, now serving an 8-year sentence, and whether she was about to investigate other people who were politically powerful.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ms. Lam was questioned about that. I asked her whether she considered the  request for her resignation to be inappropriate. She said she was surprised by it. I pressed her for her own conclusion. I think we may need more by way of inquiry to examine what her performance ratings were to see if there was a basis for her being asked to resign.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We had a situation with Mr. Cummins, who was a U.S. attorney in the Eastern District of Arkansas. He received a telephone call, which he then relayed to other dismissed United States attorneys, and he did it by e-mail very shortly after the telephone call. The question I had for Mr. Cummins was, what was said? The e-mail did not contain the language of the caller from the Department of Justice. It had Mr. Cummins' sense, or feelings, that it was a warning. After little discussion, one lawyer  to another, he said it may have been friendly advice. Well, that perhaps requires a little more analysis, if not a little more inquiry.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Then we have the situation with the U.S. attorney from New Mexico, where, according to the news reports--and we have to find this out from the actual witnesses--there had been concerns expressed by people in New Mexico as to whether he was doing his job properly. On those concerns--at least according to the press--we have to find this out from the witnesses. Those calls, according to members of the press, or according to what has been reported in the press, were relayed to White House officials,  and they passed them on to the Department of Justice.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have to look at that and ask ourselves the question of whether there is impropriety in that. If the Department of Justice is to evaluate whether a United States attorney ought to be retained, is it relevant as to what people think about him or her? The comments may require that we look at whether he was doing the job. Those are matters we have yet to determine. So when we have declarations made on the Senate floor that are conclusory, condemning the Department of Justice for what it has done,  I say that is premature.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When the issue came up about the hearing that was a week ago today, in my capacity as ranking member of the committee, I was asked to waive the 7-day rule, and I agreed to do so. I agreed to do so because I thought it was important to move ahead promptly. When Senator Leahy has raised the issue about other witnesses coming in, I think he is correct on that. The issue was raised about bringing in former White House Counsel Harriet Miers, issues were raised about bringing in people from  the Department of Justice and other people in the office of the White House Counsel. I think that ought to be done. I do not think it is necessary to subpoena them. We will see.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Before subpoenas ought to be issued, or before there even ought to be an issue raised about subpoenas, we ought to make a determination as to whether people are willing to come in voluntarily. When you talk about subpoenas, the first public reaction is: Why do they have to be subpoenaed? Why don't they come in voluntarily? Do they have something to hide? The next inference or question is: Are they guilty of something that they have to be subpoenaed?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So let us proceed in the regular course of business. I was a district attorney for some 8 years and an assistant DA before that, and I have been on the Judiciary Committee for 27 years. The regular way to do business is to ask people to come in. If they refuse, then you can talk about subpoenas and you can get tough if it is necessary to do that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I regret I could not be here when Senator Schumer was on the floor earlier today. He has made public statements about the Attorney General politicizing the office. Well, that may be Senator Schumer's opinion, his judgment. But let's get down to specific facts as to what is involved in the  politicization. We are all working here in a political field. I, frankly, have a concern to see Senator PETE DOMENICI on the Web site of the Democratic Senate Campaign Committee. I have a little concern about some of the statements that have been made by Members of this body, rushing to judgment, before we have had these witnesses in.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There has been a request for witnesses from the administration, from the White House. Well, why condemn the parties and condemn the Department until we have found out what the facts are? My view, as I expressed last Thursday in the Judiciary Committee's executive session, has been to tone down the rhetoric. We are now on the heels of the issue of the request for resignations of the United States attorneys.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have the disclosures that the Federal Bureau of Investigation had misused the national security letters. We gave them broader powers in the PATRIOT Act. We broadened the powers from cases involving foreign powers to national security matters generally. We put in a provision as to exigent circumstances, which means an emergency. Until we find, at least preliminarily, that the FBI used the exigent category more broadly--in some situations, they were to get statements on probable cause for the  judicial authorization. In giving the FBI these broader powers under the--Madam President, the Senate is not in order.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senate will be in order.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300092" topic="REQUESTED RESIGNATIONS OF SEVEN UNITED STATES ATTORNEYS">
    <paragraph>We gave the FBI these broader powers under the PATRIOT Act because of the importance of fighting terrorism, and that is a major problem of the United States today, an enormous problem worldwide. We are concerned that where the FBI exercises these greater powers there has to be an appropriate regard for civil liberties and for constitutional rights. If it weren't for the fact we inserted in the reauthorization the authority of the inspector general to make these audits, we would not  have found out what was going on.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So then in evaluating what the Department of Justice has done, I think it is important to look thoroughly at the issues raised by the inspector general. It is a thick volume. We are going to need oversight hearings. Senator Leahy, chairman of the Judiciary Committee, already announced that. I think we may have to go further and consider changing the authority of the FBI under the PATRIOT Act. If they do not use the powers within the confines the Congress has prescribed and the President  authorized, then we may have to limit their power.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are serious issues that confront the Department of Justice at this time and the Judiciary Committee, in its oversight capacity and investigative capacity, has the full authority of power to find out what the facts are, and we will speak plainly. I will have no hesitation in making a factually based judgment if they have acted improperly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let us see the background of the firing of these U.S. attorneys, and let us see what the details are on the national security letters and what the Department of Justice does to correct the situation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Connecticut is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I am very happy to indicate to our colleagues we have reached agreement on a series of unanimous consent requests that will allow us to move to final passage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the pending amendment be set aside and the Senate proceed to the consideration of a series of amendments, which have been cleared on our side and by Senator Collins on her side. The amendments are as follows:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sununu amendment No. 291; Grassley amendment No. 293, with a modification; Coleman amendment No. 341; Feinstein amendment No. 323; Salazar amendment No. 290, with a further modification; Carper amendment No. 368; Akaka amendment No. 392; Lieberman amendment No. 332, with a modification; Lieberman-Collins amendment No. 391; Lieberman-Collins amendment No. 431; Wyden-Bond amendment No. 348; Byrd amendment No. 404; Pryor amendment No. 388, with a modification; Lieberman-McCain amendment No. 411,  with a modification; Landrieu amendment No. 456;  Coleman amendment No. 414, with a modification; Inouye-Stevens-Lieberman amendment No. 412, with a modification; Menendez amendment No. 354, with a modification.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that these amendments be agreed to en bloc; that the motions to reconsider be laid on the table, en bloc; that any statements thereon be printed in the Record as if read; and that consideration of these items appear separately in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, on behalf of the Commerce Committee, I ask unanimous consent that the pending amendment be set aside and the Senate proceed en bloc to the consideration of a series of amendments which have been cleared by the chair and ranking member of the Commerce Committee, Senators INOUYE and STEVENS.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The amendments are as follows: Inouye-Stevens amendment No. 423 with a modification; Inouye-Stevens amendment No. 424 with a modification; Rockefeller amendment No. 340; Kerry amendment No. 307; Murray amendment No. 358 with a modification; Lautenberg amendment No. 359 with a modification; Cardin amendment No. 394.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On behalf of the Banking Committee, Senators DODD and SHELBY, I ask that the following amendments within their jurisdiction which they have cleared also be considered: Dodd amendment No. 415, Kohl amendment No. 371 with a modification.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that these amendments be agreed to en bloc, the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table, en bloc, that any statements thereon be printed in the Record, and that the consideration of these amendments appear separately in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I now ask unanimous consent that amendments Nos. 321 and 336 be withdrawn and that amendment No. 367 be further modified with the changes at the desk and that the amendment be considered and agreed to and the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I now ask unanimous consent that following adoption of the substitute amendment and the bill has been read a third time, there then be 20 minutes for debate prior to the vote on passage of the bill, and that each of the following be afforded 5 minutes: Senators COLLINS, LIEBERMAN, MCCONNELL, and REID.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="">
    <paragraph>Reserving the right to object, I may have missed the complete unanimous-consent request because I did not have that final page of the agreement. Will the Senator inform me whether there is a vote ordered on the Biden amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Yes, Madam President. I thank my friend from Maine. I am sorry she didn't get this page. What I will do after this unanimous-consent request, hopefully, is agreed to, setting 20 minutes of debate and final passage, is to ask what the pending business is, which is the Biden amendment, and then I will urge action on the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="">
    <paragraph>I have no objection.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, what is the pending amendment?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Amendment No. 383 offered by Senator Biden.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask for the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there a sufficient second?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I move to table the Biden amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> First, is there a sufficient second?</chair>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I move to table the Biden amendment, and I ask for the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there a sufficient second on the motion to table?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>I announce that the Senator from South Dakota (Mr. JOHNSON) is necessarily absent.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300069" topic="">
    <paragraph>The following Senator was necessarily absent: the Senator from Arizona (Mr. MCCAIN).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Are there any other Senators in the Chamber desiring to vote?</chair>
  <narrative>The result was announced--yeas 73, nays 25, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I move to reconsider the vote, and I move to lay that motion on the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The motion to lay on the table was agreed to.</narrative>
  <chair> Without objection, the substitute amendment, as amended, is agreed to.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="IMPLEMENTED RECOMMENDATION">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I note that the underlying legislation contains a sense of the Senate resolution that the Senate should implement the recommendation of the 9/11 Commission to "create a single, principal point of oversight and review for homeland security." This provision was added during committee markup by the Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee. I would ask my colleague, hasn't the Senate already implemented this recommendation?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="IMPLEMENTED RECOMMENDATION">
    <paragraph>Indeed, we have. Near the end of the 108th Congress we passed <bill type="sr" number="445">S. Res. 445</bill>, which created the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs as the principal point of oversight and review for homeland security in the Senate.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="IMPLEMENTED RECOMMENDATION">
    <paragraph>I appreciate the Senator's recollection. <bill type="sr" number="445">S. Res. 445</bill> established the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. It also provided that the newly established committee would have referral and oversight of all matters relating to the Department of Homeland Security, with certain exceptions. One of those exceptions was with respect to functional oversight of customs revenue or commercial functions performed by any personnel of the Department of Homeland Security. Does the  Senator recall the basis for that exception?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="IMPLEMENTED RECOMMENDATION">
    <paragraph>Indeed, I do. This is an issue that goes back to the creation of the Department of Homeland Security and passage of the Homeland Security Act of 2002. The Finance Committee held a hearing in July 2002, followed by a letter to the chairman and ranking member of the Governmental Affairs Committee. We stressed the importance of preserving the revenue collection and trade facilitation functions of the U.S. Customs Service, even as that agency moved into the Department of Homeland Security  with an added national security focus.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="IMPLEMENTED RECOMMENDATION">
    <paragraph>I appreciate the Senator's recollection of our efforts on this issue. I would add that following that hearing and our letter, we worked closely with the Committee on Governmental Affairs to develop text that would keep intact the commercial functions of the Customs Service. Under the final legislation, authorities vested in the Secretary of the Treasury relating to customs revenue functions remained with the Secretary of the Treasury unless delegated to the Secretary of Homeland Security.  By order of the Secretary, dated May 15, 2003, Treasury Order 100-16, the Secretary of the Treasury delegated to the Secretary of Homeland Security general authority over customs revenue functions, subject to certain exceptions that preserved Treasury's oversight of the Customs Service with respect to policy matters and the authority to issue regulations and determinations. That delegation of authority remains in place to this day.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="IMPLEMENTED RECOMMENDATION">
    <paragraph>Yes. And I believe we can both agree that our efforts were successful in preserving the revenue functions, commercial functions, and commercial operations of the Customs Service within the Department of Homeland Security, including oversight of those functions and commercial operations within the Committee on Finance.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="IMPLEMENTED RECOMMENDATION">
    <paragraph>I concur entirely. And those efforts served as the context for the retention of Finance Committee oversight of customs revenue functions and commercial operations in <bill type="sr" number="445">S. Res. 445</bill>. The Finance Committee has exercised oversight of those functions for almost 200 years, and we as a nation continue to benefit from that accumulated expertise.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="IMPLEMENTED RECOMMENDATION">
    <paragraph>That is right. In fact, we can point to the enactment of the Security and Accountability For Every Port Act of 2006, otherwise known as the SAFE Port Act, as an example of that.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="IMPLEMENTED RECOMMENDATION">
    <paragraph>I agree. The SAFE Port Act demonstrated that the Finance Committee and Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee, together with the Commerce Committee, could work together to enact strong legislation to secure our borders and protect the trade-based economic security of our country. That legislation is strong precisely because it was the product of the Finance Committee's focus on customs functions and commercial operations, coupled with the Homeland Security and Governmental  Affairs Committee's focus on border security and the Commerce Committee's expertise relating to our Nation's seaports.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="IMPLEMENTED RECOMMENDATION">
    <paragraph>Indeed. The enactment of that legislation demonstrates that the retention of Finance Committee jurisdiction over customs revenue functions and commercial operations does not in any way diminish the effective oversight of other functions within the Department of Homeland Security by the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, nor does it detract from the Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee as the principal point of oversight and review for homeland  security matters in the U.S. Senate. In fact, by drawing on the focus and expertise of both committees, we improve overall Senate oversight of the homeland security interests and economic security interests of the United States.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="IMPLEMENTED RECOMMENDATION">
    <paragraph>I agree entirely. Consequently, I must note for the record that I don't see any need to include the sense of the Senate resolution that has been added to the underlying legislation by the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="IMPLEMENTED RECOMMENDATION">
    <paragraph>I agree with my colleague and note the same. However, since it is merely a sense-of-the-Senate resolution, and is not binding in any way, I think it is sufficient to note our objections for the record at this time. The provision is not worth objecting to any more than that. We have already established a principal point of oversight and review for homeland security in the U.S. Senate. The current balance reflected in <bill type="sr" number="445">S. Res. 445</bill> has been proven to work and need not be disturbed.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="IMPLEMENTED RECOMMENDATION">
    <paragraph>I agree.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="CARGO SECURITY ON PASSENGER PLANES">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I am pleased that in this new Congress, we are able to take up and pass a bill that implements the 9/11 Commission recommendations. Even though aviation security has improved greatly in the last 5 years, there are still holes in the system--as we discovered last summer with the aviation terrorist plot uncovered by the British authorities. Therefore, implementing these recommendations is crucial.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300056" topic="CARGO SECURITY ON PASSENGER PLANES">
    <paragraph>I agree with the Senator from California that implementing these recommendations is crucial to continuing to increase aviation security, to prevent our Nation from experiencing a tragedy like 9/11 again.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="CARGO SECURITY ON PASSENGER PLANES">
    <paragraph>Madam President, one hole in aviation security is the cargo that is carried on passenger planes. The bill does strengthen security for cargo on passenger planes. First, the bill requires screening of all of the cargo going on passenger aircraft. Second, the bill requires the Transportation Security Administration to implement a program--either random or risked-based--to place blast-resistant containers on passenger planes. However, the program does not implement the 9/11 Commission  recommendation to require one blast-resistant cargo container on every plane.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The 9/11 Commission recommended, "TSA should require that every passenger aircraft carrying cargo deploy at least one hardened container to carry any suspect cargo." Therefore, all passenger planes should have at least one blast-resistant container for cargo.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300056" topic="CARGO SECURITY ON PASSENGER PLANES">
    <paragraph>I expect that TSA would examine this recommendation when developing a plan to deploy blast-resistant cargo containers on airplanes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="CARGO SECURITY ON PASSENGER PLANES">
    <paragraph>I thank the Senator for his support. We owe this to the American people. We cannot allow terrorists to exploit holes in our aviation security system.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300056" topic="OVERSIGHT">
    <paragraph>Madam Pesident, the expertise exhibited under the Commerce Committee's jurisdiction is reflected in the substitute amendment to <bill type="s" number="4">S. 4</bill>, before us today, which incorporates three Commerce Committee reported bills: <bill type="s" number="184">S. 184</bill>, the Surface Transportation and Rail Security Act of 2007; <bill type="s" number="509">S. 509</bill>, the Aviation Security Improvement Act; and <bill type="s" number="385">S. 385</bill>, the Interoperable Emergency Communications Act. Prior to the reorgnization of the Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committees, HSGAC,  and thereafter, the Commerce Committee's jurisdiction under the Senate rules over all aspects of transportation safety and security issues encompassing maritime, Coast Guard, aviation, rail, pipeline, and trucking, and telecommunications matters, remain untouched.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Some unfairly claim that problems we are having improving our national security result from an outdated committee system. I respectfully disagree. This claim is simply a sound bite that ignores the truth and short changes the potential for real solutions. The real problem is the result of creating a new department from scratch by merging 22 Federal agencies with varying missions, without any true realignment for non-security related missions, into one mammoth Federal department and then refusing  to fully fund the necessary initiatives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am surprised that a few of my colleagues would suggest that through oversight through several committees of the Department, its Agencies, and the $34.8 billion in programs weakens DHS. To the contrary, using the several committees, each with its own significant expertise, actually improves the quality and scope of congressional oversight, and therefore, the effectiveness and accountability of the Department itself. It is the failure to conduct agency oversight that causes the most harm, as  we have seen at DHS over the past few years. Well coordinated and responsible engagement with DHS by  committees will only further the Senate's oversight responsibilities for and the public's understanding of the critical work now being done by the Department and of the numerous challenges that remain.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="sr" number="445">S. Res. 445</bill> embraced that approach, and <bill type="s" number="4">S. 4</bill> which will pass the Senate today demonstrates the success of that approach. In fact, the SAFE Ports Act, Public Law 109-347, and <bill type="s" number="4">S. 4</bill> are a reflection of the positive progress Congress can make when committees work together in our respective fields of expertise to conduct oversight and craft legislation to address identified vulnerabilities.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300094" topic="OVERSIGHT">
    <paragraph>I concur with my chairman, Senator INOUYE. The Commerce Committee has worked for over a decade to improve transportation security and has had to deal with the inertia of the Federal Government as well as fight entrenched interests to change the way we secure our transportation system. As far back as 1996 we began discussing the security advantages of transferring security functions from the airline industry to the Federal</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Government. Similarly, we initiated action on the Maritime Transportation Security Act of 2002 prior to 9/11 in order to address a broad range of criminal activity at our ports. The attacks of 9/11 created sufficient public pressure for Congress to fundamentally change the way the Federal Government secures our aviation system and ports.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In particular, Aviation and Transportation Security Act, ATSA, Public Law 107-71, established the Transportation Security Administration, TSA, within the Department of Transportation to be "responsible for security in all modes of transportation, including: carrying out chapter 449, relating to civil aviation security, and related research and development activities; and security responsibilities over other modes of transportation that are exercised by the Department of Transportation."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The creation of the Department of Homeland Security, DHS, and the Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee, HSGAC, did not alter TSA's authority or the Commerce Committee's subject matter jurisdiction. The Senate engaged in a healthy debate on the floor and made clear that the authority being transferred to the HSGAC under <bill type="sr" number="445">S. Res. 445</bill> did not affect the Commerce Committee's jurisdictional authority over transportation security programs, the Coast Guard and communications matters  conducted through the Federal Communications Commission, FCC, and the Department of Commerce. In large part, the debate focused on the difficulty of separating transportation safety issues from transportation security issues. It is difficult, if not impossible, to separate safety and security issues from general transportation policy. To consider security without understanding the impacts of the</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300056" topic="OVERSIGHT">
    <paragraph>I agree. Without such context, security decisions will be made in a vacuum that, at best, might produce misguided or extraneous efforts, and, at worst, could cripple the transportation modes that ensure the free flow of commerce and travel that our Nation has been built upon. The Commerce Committee has passed three of the most significant transportation security bills considered since 9/11 and has been successful because of its understanding of the industry and past work on safety  and security issues. The distinguished majority leader and Senator MCCONNELL recognized this when crafting S. Res 445 and the Senate approved.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="OVERSIGHT">
    <paragraph>My colleagues from the Senate Commerce Committee are correct. <bill type="sr" number="445">S. Res. 445</bill>, as introduced by me and Senator MCCONNELL and as passed by the Senate, proposed continued oversight of transportation security by the Commerce Committee.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300056" topic="OVERSIGHT">
    <paragraph>The Department consists of 22 separate agencies. These agencies are responsible for everything from international trade to animal health inspection. It would be unwise for the Senate to suggest that a single committee should manage oversight of those 22 agencies and each of their multiple missions just because the Secretary does not like to travel to the Hill and testify. The Senate cannot abdicated its oversight responsibilities because the Department thinks it takes up too much  time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And so, I respectfully but deeply disagree with the nonbinding measure in the underlying bill suggesting that this Senate should neglect its oversight duty--and put aside much of its long-standing expertise--because the Department is too busy to come tell us what they are doing. While I and many of my colleagues discussed striking this provision from the underlying bill, the majority leader noted that it was simply the work product of one committee. I would like to ask the majority leader if  it is intention to continue to operate under <bill type="sr" number="445">S. Res. 445</bill> given the recent success of legislation like Public Law 109-347 and <bill type="s" number="4">S. 4</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="OVERSIGHT">
    <paragraph>The Senator is correct. <bill type="sr" number="445">S. Res. 445</bill> determines Senate oversight and jurisdictional authorities.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300034" topic="TRANSIT SECURITY">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I thank the majority leader for this colloquy and for his work with the chairmen and ranking members of many of the committees who have been involved in putting together the legislation to implement the recommendations of the 9/11 Commission. The Banking Committee took this task very seriously. I am pleased to report that the committee unanimously reported <bill type="s" number="763">S. 763</bill>, the Public Transportation Terrorism Prevention Act of 2007, which has been incorporated into the 9/11 legislation  as title XIV. Transit security has long been a focus of the Banking Committee, where we have held several hearings and reported similar legislation in each of the last two Congresses. While the Banking Committee's previous legislation also passed the Senate, once as a freestanding bill and as title VII of the SAFE Port Act, it has yet to become law. I will continue</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Transportation security was also addressed more broadly in title VIII of this legislation. As title VIII called for national transportation security and information plans, I worked very closely with my fellow chairmen and ranking members from the Commerce Committee, Senators INOUYE and STEVENS, who have jurisdiction over other modes of transportation security besides public transportation. Together we reached an agreement, represented in the Inouye amendment, No. 423, between the  Commerce, Banking, and Homeland Security Committees. I am very pleased that this amendment was agreed to, and it is my intention to continue our close working relationship on these issues throughout the conference process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Banking Committee was also very engaged in other areas of the bill that involved the committee's jurisdiction. Since 9/11, we have worked with and overseen the Federal financial regulators as they have implemented sophisticated preparedness requirements for the institutions under their jurisdiction. Title VII, as proposed, authorized the Secretary of the Department of Homeland Security to create another series of requirements. Although these requirements are voluntary, Federal financial regulators  and the financial services industry have expressed</paragraph>
    <paragraph>concerns about the impact of these requirements, and I share their concerns. A letter from the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System staff dated March 1, 2007 explains that the "voluntary standards [of Title VII are] not appropriate to meet the objective of greater preparedness and resiliency." The letter states that it would "be desirable that Title VII reflect the unique relationships that already exist within the banking and finance sector and not impose any new requirements  that duplicate actions that have already been  taken by the Federal financial institutions regulators." The American Bankers Association in a letter dated February 28, 2007, stated "ABA is concerned that this program would be redundant to and potential conflict with the existing</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have proposed amendments intended to address these concerns, working with Chairman Lieberman and Ranking Member Collins. The final legislation will include an amendment to clarify that institutions in a sector, such as financial services, must obey their sector regulators and to emphasize that this program is voluntary and does not supersede the institutions' responsibilities to maintain the high standards required by their regulators.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Another amendment that I authored pertains to title X of the underlying bill. I commend Senators Lieberman and Collins for their efforts in addressing an important issue under this title--to ensure that the Department of Homeland Security thoroughly discerns the risks to America's critical infrastructure. As originally drafted, however, I was concerned that the bill would not ensure that DHS adequately consults with the Federal agencies best equipped to assess and prioritize  risks in specific sectors of the economy. From the perspective of the Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs Committee, I can tell you, for example, that no one has greater expertise or technical resources for assessing the vulnerabilities of our financial infrastructure than our Federal financial regulators. It is for that reason that my amendment effectively removed language that would place limits on the DHS' use of information from sector-specific agencies in the formulation of their risk assessments and prioritized lists. It is my belief that we need to encourage greater coordination between these specialized agencies and the Department of Homeland Security, not restrict it. This is true in areas outside of the financial services sector. In matters of public health, DHS should consult the Department of Health and Human</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, although it pertains to the assessment of U.S. critical infrastructure, title X does not include any reporting requirement on the government's ability to ensure that U.S. industry reduces interruption of critical infrastructure operations during a national emergency and minimizes the impact of such a catastrophe. My amendment requires reports to the Committees on Banking, Housing and Urban Affairs as well as to Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, along with their House committee  counterparts, on compliance with subsections (a) and (c) of section 101 of the Defense Production Act of 1950 to meet this requirement. As chairman of the Committee with jurisdiction over this law, it is important to me that we oversee appropriate U.S. industrial preparedness to meet critical infrastructure needs in times of national emergency. I appreciate the cooperation of my colleagues in the development of all of these important provisions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Once again, I thank the majority leader for his excellent work in bringing all of these committees together and fashioning an excellent bill. This demonstrates that the jurisdictional lines established in <bill type="sr" number="445">S. Res. 445</bill> continue to work.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. REID I thank the Senator from Connecticut. The Senator is correct that <bill type="sr" number="445">S. Res. 445</bill> determines Senate oversight and jurisdictional authorities, and I acknowledge the important role that the Banking Committee has played and will continue to play on this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300021" topic="TRANSIT SECURITY">
    <paragraph>Madam President I rise today in opposition to this final bill because I believe one of the provisions included will greatly undermine our homeland security efforts. Specifically, the provision would mandate that the Transportation Security Administration have the ability to collectively bargain with Government unions representing airport security screeners. This will create unnecessary red tape and bureaucracy and tie the hands of our security personnel. While this provision may  be beneficial to the union bosses, it is not beneficial to Georgians and the American people.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>TSA must have the flexibility to respond when our security is threatened. In this current era of unpredictable threats, TSA must be able to continually change its systems to meet the changing security environment. If we mandate that TSA must negotiate with the unions for every change in circumstance, it will negate the agency's ability to respond quickly to terrorist threats and other emergencies. I just don't think that is common sense.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In fact, when TSA was created, the agency was given the authority to decide whether to engage in collective bargaining with airport baggage screeners, and TSA concluded that such negotiations would weaken its ability to protect the American people. This authority was not recommended in the 9/11 Commission Report.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now let's be clear--the issue here is not whether TSA employees should be allowed to join a union but whether TSA must collectively bargain with Government unions before it changes personnel and policies. At the present time, airport screeners may voluntarily join a union and TSA will withhold union dues at an employee's request. The union, however, has no standing to negotiate with TSA on behalf of their members.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would just note that this restriction is not unique to TSA. Other Federal agencies that collect and respond to intelligence in an effort to address homeland security, such as the FBI, CIA, and Secret Service, all have the same restriction. This is done as an acknowledgement that highly sensitive security information should only be released on a need-to-know basis. Collective bargaining, conversely, would require the release of sensitive information to external negotiators and arbitrators, which  would increase the risk of sensitive information getting in the wrong hands.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>TSA must be able to quickly shift employees based on intelligence and airport traffic demands while modifying procedures at a moment's notice. For example, this past August, following an attempted United Kingdom airline bombing, TSA overhauled its procedures in less than 12 hours to prevent terrorists from smuggling liquid explosives onto any U.S. flights. Not only did this flexibility ensure that no U.S. flights were cancelled due to the change, most importantly, it ensured the safety and security  of the United States. This past December, during a major snowstorm in Denver, local TSA employees were unable to get to the airport. However, due to the current policies, TSA was able to deploy officers from Salt Lake City, Las Vegas, and Colorado Springs to the Denver airport. This deployment</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We should remember that TSA exists to protect American lives, and its focus must remain on homeland security and not on labor negotiations. I am extremely concerned that the provision included in this bill will lead to a change in culture within the agency, and I just don't think our hard-working TSA employees gain much from this.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am proud of our dedicated TSA employees in Georgia, and we already have a "pay for performance" system in place that weeds out nonperformers.  The system is based upon technical competence, readiness for duty, and operational performance. But under the proposed changes, the most effective security employees will be punished by the change in pay practices.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, we should be concerned about what this means to passengers and the American taxpayers. The collective bargaining system would not reward good screening performance or customer service. Additionally, implementing the infrastructure for collective bargaining would cost hundreds of millions of dollars and TSA would be forced to relocate thousands of personnel. For Georgians, fewer personnel means fewer screening lanes and longer lines at airports like Hartsfield-Jackson International Airport  in Atlanta.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our national security is too important to risk. It is no accident that we have not had a terrorist attack on domestic soil since September 11, 2001. But that is not to say that it can't happen again. The terrorists only have to get it right once. But we have to get it right every time. So let's not hinder our ability to do that. Our homeland security infrastructure must be able to operate in real time. We should not tie the very hands we rely upon to protect us here at home. It is disappointing  that this provision is included in this bill, and I urge my colleagues to oppose final passage.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300061" topic="TRANSIT SECURITY">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I rise today to discuss three proposed amendments to <bill type="s" number="4">S. 4</bill>, Improving America's Security by Implementing Unfinished Recommendations of the 9/11 Commission Act. I thank Senators Lieberman, Collins, Dodd and Shelby for working with me and my staff on provisions to protect seniors in the event of an emergency. Unfortunately, two important provisions were pulled at the behest of Republicans to limit the number of amendments offered by Democrats.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It has been almost 2 years since our Nation reeled from the tragic and shameful images of seniors abandoned during the aftermath of Hurricane Katrina. Sadly, we now know that 71 percent of the people who died were older than 60. Last year, as the ranking member of the Special Committee on Aging, we held a hearing to examine how prepared the Nation is to care for our seniors in the event of a national emergency. What we learned was disheartening.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We learned that our Nation is woefully unprepared to meet the unique needs of our seniors in the event of a terrorist attack, natural disaster, or other emergency. Cookie cutter emergency plans are of little use to seniors, especially those who depend on others for assistance in their daily lives. We need specific plans, programs, and information for all seniors facing emergencies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is why Senators Wyden, Coleman and I offered several amendments to the 9/11 legislation to ensure that the Department of Homeland Security place seniors on the forefront of its emergency planning agenda. The first amendment, which is supported by the American Public Health Association, is an important step towards ensuring that seniors are protected when the next national emergency occurs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment would ensure that any recipient of a homeland security grant, under title II, will include in its State, local, or tribal homeland security plan the evacuation, transportation, and health care needs of the elderly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It would also require that the needs of the elderly are incorporated into any preparedness exercises or trainings for emergency responders to ensure they are adequately prepared to safeguard our seniors in the event of an emergency.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment would have sent a strong signal to States and communities that are engaged in emergency planning that seniors must be a priority. Unfortunately, this is one of the amendments pulled from a manager's package of approved amendments at the last minute.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am also pleased to be an original cosponsor of Senator Wyden's amendment to establish a Special Needs Registry Pilot Project, which is supported by the National Association of Area Agencies on Aging. One of the most useful recommendations from our Aging Committee hearing last year was to follow the lead of counties like Miami-Dade in Florida. They have successfully set up a voluntary registry where seniors can list where they live, their transportation limitations, their health needs,  and whether they may need help getting food and other supplies during an emergency.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It's clear that more cities and counties could benefit from these kinds of special needs registries. That's why this amendment would have created a pilot project for local emergency management agencies to set up and test these registries, allowing first responders to locate and care for seniors before and during emergencies. It was our hope that this pilot project would have helped spark a nationwide effort to establish special needs registries; unfortunately this amendment was also pulled at  the last minute.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On a brighter note, I thank Chairman Dodd and Ranking Member Shelby again for working with me and Senator Coleman to successfully include a provision, supported by the American Public Health Association, in title XIV that would ensure that public transportation workers are trained to meet the evacuation needs of seniors in the event of a crisis. This is particularly important since so many of our seniors utilize public transportation for access to their everyday needs.  Furthermore, only public transportation has the capacity to move millions of people and provide first responders with critical support in major evacuations of urban areas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This provision will go a long way to ensure that our seniors are taken care of if we have another emergency or disaster. Unfortunately, two crucial provisions intended to safeguard the needs of seniors were not included in the final bill due to partisan efforts to limit Democratic amendments. Hurricanes Katrina and Rita taught us many painful lessons that should never be forgotten. I will not forget and I intend to pursue legislation aimed at explicitly safeguarding the needs of America's seniors  in the event of an emergency. The time to act to protect our seniors is now.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300081" topic="TRANSIT SECURITY">
    <paragraph>Madam President, today the Senate will vote on a matter of utmost importance--enacting the remaining 9/11 Commission recommendations. Since their publication 2 1/2  years ago, roughly half of the recommendations have been left unaddressed, while many that have been adopted into law have not been effectively implemented. <bill type="s" number="4">S. 4</bill>, the Improving America's Security Act, is a critical step to ensuring our Nation's safety.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill includes an important new interoperability grant program. Tragedies such as September 11, the Station Fire in my home State of Rhode Island, and Hurricane Katrina have demonstrated the need for interoperable communications equipment among first responders. More communities require access to funding to create interoperable communications networks, and I have long supported increasing accessibility for interoperability grants to local and state governments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am also pleased that this bill includes a transit security program that I helped author as a member of the Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs Committee. The committee has been well aware of the need for this legislation since the tragic events of 9/11, spending significant time and effort to improve our Nation's transit security system. The Senate has passed transit security legislation in the last two Congresses, only to have them each stall prior to enactment. While our Nation acted quickly  after 9/11 to secure airports and airplanes against terrorists, major vulnerabilities remain in surface transportation. As the 9/11 Commission concluded, "opportunities to do harm are as great, or greater, in maritime and surface transportation" as in commercial aviation. The time to act is now.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Transit is vital to providing mobility for millions of Americans and offers tremendous economic benefits to our Nation. In the United States, people use public transportation over 32 million times each weekday compared to 2 million passengers who fly daily. Paradoxically, it is the very openness of the system that makes it vulnerable to terrorism. When one considers this and the fact that roughly $7 per passenger is invested in aviation security, but less than one cent is invested in the security  of each transit passenger, the need for an authorized transit security program is clear.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, the bill provides important protections for Transportation Security Officers at the Transportation Security Administration that have been long absent, including whistleblower protections, the right to appeal to the Merit Systems Protection Board, and certain collective bargaining rights.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Lastly, while Providence is now 1 of 39 urban areas eligible for the Urban Area Security Initiative grants, something that I have long sought, believing the city faces risks from terrorism, I was disappointed that Senator Leahy's amendment to restore the minimum allocation to 0.75 percent for States under the State Homeland Security Grant Program failed. With this funding, Rhode Island has been able to make critical improvements, but adequate funding is still needed, and it is my hope  that the highest minimum funding level will prevail in conference with the House of Representatives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Implementing the final recommendations of the 9/11 Commission builds and improves on the work that has been done since the attacks of September 11, and I am pleased to support this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300042" topic="TRANSIT SECURITY">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I want to add my thoughts to the debate on the Improving America's Security Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, I preface my remarks by applauding the chairman and ranking member of the Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee for their work on this important bill. This bill makes crucial and long overdue improvements in transportation security, critical infrastructure protection, and emergency response capabilities. There is no higher priority than protecting homeland security, and this bill is a key component in that effort.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nearly 6 years since the horrific attacks of September 11, we are still struggling to give our first responders, law enforcement officers, and the employees of the Department of Homeland Security the resources they need to keep us safe. I thank these brave men and women who work daily to protect this Nation. They are on the front lines of the fight against terrorism. They are the ones who are called on to stop and respond to any future attack upon our Nation. This bill includes important resources  these brave men and women need to perform their critical tasks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am pleased that the Senate has increased funding for State homeland security grants, emergency management performance grants, emergency communications and the Urban Area Security Initiative. I have long advocated for greater funding of emergency management grants because they are crucial in assisting State and local officials in preparing for all-hazards emergencies. These grants provide emergency managers with the resources they need to increase coordination and planning so that if an emergency  occurs, State and local officials will respond much more efficiently and effectively.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is my hope that this bill represents a lasting shift in priorities, a shift towards an enhanced focus on the most pressing threats facing our country. We are still spending almost twice as much on Iraq as is allocated for homeland security, diplomacy, and international assistance combined. The billions we spend each month in Iraq could be invested in the protection of critical infrastructure and our system of national preparedness and response that failed in the wake of Hurricane Katrina.  As we consider the budget resolution and the defense and homeland security appropriations bills this year, I encourage my colleagues to take a broader view when it comes to our national security priorities and make the tradeoffs that must be made.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am particularly pleased that the Federal Agency Data Mining Reporting Act is included in this bill as section 504. I have been working on this legislation for a number of years with Senator Sununu, Senator Leahy, and Senator Akaka. I am glad that Senator Sununu and Senator Akaka successfully offered the legislation as an amendment to <bill type="s" number="4">S. 4</bill> when it was before the Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many law-abiding Americans are understandably concerned about the specter of secret government programs analyzing vast quantities of public and private data about their pursuits, in search of patterns of suspicious activity. Four years after we first learned about the Defense Department's program called Total Information Awareness, there is still much Congress does not know about the Federal Government's work on data mining. This bill is an important step in allowing Congress to conduct oversight  of any such programs or related research development efforts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Federal Agency Data Mining Reporting Act would require Federal agencies to report annually on their development and use of data mining technologies to discover predictive or anomalous patterns indicating criminal or terrorist activity the types of pattern-based data analysis that raise the most serious privacy concerns. As amended on the floor, it would also allow classified information, law enforcement sensitive information, trade secrets, and proprietary business information to be provided  to the relevant committees separately, in a nonpublic form, under appropriate security measures.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Intelligence and law enforcement agencies would not be doing their job if they did not take advantage of new technologies. But when it comes to pattern-based data mining, Congress needs to understand whether it can be effective in identifying terrorists, and Congress needs to consider the privacy and civil liberties implications of deploying such technology domestically. I hope these reports will help Congress--and to the extent possible, the public--finally understand what is going on behind  the closed doors of the executive branch, so that we can start to have the policy discussion about data mining that is long overdue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am concerned about the ongoing development of the Information Sharing Environment without adequate privacy and civil liberties guidelines. In the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004, Congress mandated that the President create an Information Sharing Environment, ISE, for the sharing of terrorism information among Federal agencies, State and local governments, and the private sector. This is a critical goal in our counterterrorism efforts. But that legislation also required  that the President issue privacy guidelines for the ISE, in recognition of the serious privacy and civil liberties implications of facilitating more sharing of information among these entities. Those privacy guidelines were issued in December, but in my view are wholly inadequate. They touch on the most significant privacy issues and provide a framework for agencies to think about the privacy issues that might arise, but they do not include specific guidelines</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill mandates the declassification of the aggregate amount of the intelligence budget. This reform has a long history going back to the Church and Pike Commissions. It is supported by the current Senate Select Committee on Intelligence. It was also one of the recommendations of the 9/11 Commission, which stated that "when even aggregate categorical numbers remain hidden it is hard to judge priorities and foster accountability." I concur with the Commission, that aggregate budget figures</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I was pleased to support Senator McCaskill's amendment to ensure that workers at the Transportation Security Administration are afforded the same workplace protections as other DHS employees. The low retention rate at TSA resulting in part from lack of workers' rights threatens our security. This amendment will address this concern while giving administrators the flexibility they need to respond to imminent threats.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am pleased that this bill includes provisions to ensure proper oversight of homeland security grants. I am deeply troubled by reports of improper  oversight of expenditures at DHS, including an article in the Washington Post last November stating that the Department was unable to locate one-third of the files needed to perform an audit of its contracts. I therefore supported Senator Coburn's amendment to require DHS to perform audits on homeland  security grants. While I understand concerns that this requirement could have led to delays in the issuance of grants in fiscal year 2008, I did not think it was unreasonable to require DHS to conduct the audits required in a timely manner. I will continue to work with my colleagues to improve oversight of homeland security funding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I supported several amendments that would have added funding for critical security needs not fully addressed in this bill. I do not take lightly a decision to vote in favor of spending more money. Fiscal responsibility is one of my highest priorities, but it is imperative that we provide the resources needed to combat terrorism.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I voted for this bill because it makes key changes to address security needs. However, our Nation's vulnerabilities demand more and I will continue to work to ensure that our vital homeland security needs are met.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="TRANSIT SECURITY">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I support the Improving America's Security Act of 2007 because it takes a giant step in implementing the recommendations of the 9/11 Commission. Keeping America safe requires more than expensive weapons and war funding; it also requires a commitment to homeland security. This legislation shows that commitment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We learned on September 11 and during Hurricane Katrina how important it is for our first responders to be able to communicate with each other. For years, I have been urging the Department of Homeland Security to establish a dedicated funding source for interoperable communications equipment. I am pleased that this legislation creates a grant program dedicated to improving operability and interoperability at local, regional, State and Federal levels.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am also pleased that this legislation moves us closer to the equitable distribution of homeland security grant funding. For 5 years, the largest homeland security grant programs have distributed funds using a formula that arbitrarily sets aside a large portion of funds to be divided equally among the States, regardless of size or need. The current "small State formula" has severely disadvantaged States such as Michigan with high populations. In addition, it reduces the amount of funding that  can be allocated to States with highest risks. Although I am disappointed that the Senate failed to pass two amendments that I supported that would have lowered the minimum funding level even further, the .45 percent minimum in the underlying bill is an improvement from the current .75 percent base funding amount.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation also includes language that I authored that directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish international border community interoperable communications demonstration projects on the northern and southern borders to improve collaboration and help identify common frequencies for cross border communications. These interoperable communications demonstration projects will address the interoperable communications needs of police officers, firefighters, emergency medical technicians,  National Guard, and other emergency response providers at our borders by identifying common international cross-border frequencies for communications equipment; fostering the standardization of interoperable communications equipment; identifying solutions that will expeditiously facilitate communications interoperability across national</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Also included in the legislation is language that I authored that will require the Department of Homeland Security to conduct a cost-benefit analysis of the Western Hemisphere Travel Initiative, WHTI, before publishing the final rule. The WHTI will require individuals from the United States, Canada, and Mexico to present a passport or other document proving citizenship before entering the United States. Although we all share the goals of the Western Hemisphere Travel Initiative to make our borders  as secure as they can be, we need to make sure that we are achieving that goal in a way that will not cause economic harm to our States. I am also pleased that language was included in the bill that I worked with Senator Coleman on to require the Department of Homeland Security to sign a memorandum of understanding</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation also takes important steps to shore up rail, transit and cargo security in the United States. The legislation establishes a grant fund for system wide Amtrak security improvements and much needed infrastructure upgrades as well as authorizes an existing grant program for improving intercity bus and bus terminal security. It establishes a grant program for freight and passenger rail security upgrades and requires railroads shipping high-hazard materials to create threat mitigation  plans. It authorizes studies to find ways to improve passenger and baggage security screening on passenger rail service between the U.S. and Canada. The bill will hopefully move us closer to addressing something I have been trying to get implemented at our northern car and truck border crossings for years: establishing a preclearance system. The study is required to identify what exactly is needed to perform prescreening of rail passengers on the northern border.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am pleased that the Senate retained language that will require that TSA screeners finally come under an unambiguous personnel system. A further amendment that I supported will finally give Transportation Security Administration screeners the whistleblower protections afforded to most other Federal workers, including law enforcement officers. It also gives them the right to appeal suspensions and to collectively bargain, just like their counterparts in the Border Control, FEMA and the Capitol  Police.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also requires studies on how to improve the safety of transporting radioactive and hazardous materials and shipments of explosives and radioactive materials on our highways. I am pleased that this legislation requires the screening of all cargo carried on passenger airplanes within 3 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The intelligence failures before the Iraq war were, to a significant degree, the result of the CIA shaping intelligence to support administration policy. The CIA's errors were all in one direction, making the Iraqi threat clearer, sharper and more imminent, thereby promoting the decision to remove Saddam from power. Nuances, qualifications and caveats were dropped. "Slam dunk" was the assessment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Among the most important things we can do to keep this from happening again is to strengthen congressional oversight to ensure that intelligence community assessments are objective and uninfluenced by the policy judgments of whatever administration is in power. The 9/11 Commission agreed, stating in its report that "Of all our recommendations, strengthening congressional oversight may be among the most difficult and important." Section 1102 of <bill type="s" number="4">S. 4</bill>  bill is directed at that goal.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Too often Congress is stonewalled or slow-walked by the executive branch in accessing intelligence information necessary to make policy and conduct oversight of the intelligence community. Section 1102 of this bill adds a new section 508 to the National Security Act that will ensure Congress has access to intelligence information critical to do its job.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Section 508 requires elements of the intelligence community to provide, upon request from congressional committees of jurisdiction, timely access to intelligence information. The requirement would apply unless the President certified that the requested documents were not being provided because the President was asserting a constitutional privilege. Requiring the  intelligence community to respond to requests for information from the vice chairman and  ranking member of the Senate and House intelligence committees, respectively, will encourage rigorous oversight regardless of which party controls the Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to providing information in a timely manner, we expect the intelligence community to provide Congress its assessment of intelligence matters uninfluenced by the policy goals of the administration. However, an Office of Management and Budget--OMB--memorandum directs executive branch agencies to clear, through OMB, legislative proposals, agency reports, and testimony on pending legislation. The memo also states that "If agencies are asked by Congressional Committees to report or testify  on pending legislation or wish to volunteer a report, similar clearance procedures are followed."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our intelligence agencies should not have to get permission from the OMB, or any other executive branch official to share their views with the Congress. Section 1102 of the bill adds a new section 508 (d) to the National Security Act that says no executive branch official can require the intelligence community to get permission to testify or to submit testimony, legislative recommendations or comments to the Congress. Section 508 (d) is based on authority that exists for numerous other executive  branch agencies, including the Securities and Exchange Commission, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Comptroller of the Currency, the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision, the Federal Housing Finance Board, and the National Credit Union Administration.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A CRS legal review of direct reporting requirements like the one created by section 508 (d) states that "direct reporting provisions are well within the Congress's constitutional authority to inform itself in order to perform its legislative function which has been consistently acknowledged by Supreme Court decisions, and dates back to the early enactments of the First Congress in 1789." The CRS review calls Department of Justice objections to direct reporting requirements "without substantial  merit."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, it is important for whistleblowers to know that they can come directly to Congress if they have evidence that someone has made a false statement to the Congress. And the Congress has a right to that information--even if it is classified.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Section 1102 of the bill adds a new section 509 to the National Security Act making it clear that intelligence community employees and contractors can report classified information directly to appropriate Members of Congress and cleared staff if the employee reasonably believes that the information provides direct and specific evidence of a false or inaccurate statement to Congress contained in an intelligence assessment, report or estimate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Section 509 is substantively the same as section 225 of the Senate-passed version of the intelligence reform legislation. Section 225 was stripped from the intelligence reform bill in conference. Section 509 is also similar to a provision that passed the Senate twice previously. Once as part of the fiscal year 1998 Intelligence Authorization Act and once as a stand alone measure <bill type="s" number="1668">S. 1668</bill>, in the 105th Congress. <bill type="s" number="1668">S. 1668</bill> passed the Senate 93-1.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Section 509 is also consistent with congressional findings passed in the 105th Congress as part of the Intelligence Community Whistleblower Protection Act of 1998 and incorporated by reference into the intelligence reform bill. Those findings state among other things that:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress, as a co-equal branch of Government, is empowered by the Constitution to serve as a check on the executive branch; in that capacity, it has a "need to know" of allegations of wrongdoing within the executive branch, including allegations of wrongdoing in the Intelligence Community; .....</paragraph>
    <paragraph>(N)o basis in law exists for requiring prior authorization of disclosures to the intelligence committees of Congress by employees of the executive branch of classified information about wrongdoing within the Intelligence Community .....</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am pleased that the Senate will soon pass this legislation, for the families and friends of those we lost on September 11, 2001, and for the safety and security of our Nation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="TRANSIT SECURITY">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I will vote today in favor of final passage of the Improving America's Security by Implementing Unfinished Recommendations of the 9/11 Commission Act of 2007, <bill type="s" number="4">S. 4</bill>, but I do so with a heavy heart.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am truly disappointed that the chairman and ranking member of the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, Senators Lieberman and Collins, decided to arbitrarily lower the minimum allocation for States under the State Homeland Security Grant Program and the Law Enforcement Terrorism Prevention Program from the 0.75 percent that has existed for the past 5 years to 0.45 percent. Not only would this change to the formula result in the loss of millions in homeland  security funding for the fire, police, and rescue departments in small- and medium-sized States, like Vermont, Connecticut, and Maine, it also would deal a crippling blow to their efforts to launch federally mandated multiyear plans to build and sustain their terrorism preparedness.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>During the Senate floor debate on <bill type="s" number="4">S. 4</bill>, I offered with Senators Thomas, Stevens, Roberts, Pryor, Sanders, Enzi, Hatch, Whitehouse, and Lincoln an amendment to restore the minimum allocation for States under the State Homeland Security Grant Program from 0.45 percent, which is proposed by the underlying bill, to 0.75 percent, which is current law. As with current law, the State minimum under our amendment would have continued to apply only to 40 percent of the overall funding  under this program. The majority of the funds would continue to be allocated based on risk assessment criteria, as are the funds under the several separate discretionary programs that Congress has established for solely urban and high-risk areas, which also are governed by risk assessment calculations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, this amendment lost by a vote of 49 yeas to 50 nays. This is a marked change from just last year, when the 0.75 percent minimum allocation was overwhelmingly defended when 64 Senators voted against an amendment that would have lowered the minimum to 0.25 percent. Fifteen Senators changed their votes from last year, including HSGAC Chairman Lieberman and Ranking Member Collins, whose States stand to lose the most from the decreased minimum.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill that passed the Senate today would reduce the all-State minimum for SHSGP and the Law Enforcement Terrorism Prevention Program to 0.45 percent. The House bill reduces it even further to 0.25 percent. Due to the formula differences, there is no guarantee that the minimum will not be even further reduced during conference negotiations. Small- and medium-sized States face the loss of millions of dollars for our first responders if the minimum is lowered.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By reducing the all-State minimum to 0.45 percent, the underlying bill would reduce the guaranteed dollar amount for each State by 40 percent. With appropriations for formula grants having been cut by 60 percent since 2003--from $2.3 billion in 2003, to $900 million in fiscal year 2007--further reductions in first responder funding would hamper even more each State's efforts to prevent and deal with potential terrorist attacks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In fiscal year 2007, State Homeland Security and Law Enforcement Terrorism grants were funded at $525 million and $375 million, respectively, for a total of $900 million. Under the current all-State minimum of 0.75 percent, the base amount States receive is $6.75 million. Based on fiscal year 2007 levels, each State would face a loss of an estimated $2.7 million, or 40 percent, under the new 0.45 percent formula, which would be a real blow to our first responders.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And the cuts will be even deeper should the President's budget request for next year be approved. The President has requested only $250 million for these two important first responder grant programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My colleagues from our largest States--and apparently some small- and medium-sized States--seem to forget that the terrorist attacks of 9/11 added to the responsibilities and risks of first responders nationwide. I wrote the current all-State minimum formula as part of the USA PATRIOT Act  of 2001 to guarantee that each State receives at least 0.75 percent of the national allotment to help meet their national domestic security needs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Every State--rural or urban, small or large--has basic domestic security needs and deserves to receive Federal funds under this partnership to meet both those needs and the new homeland security responsibilities the Federal Government demands. Of course, high-density urban areas and high-risk centers have even greater needs, which is why this year alone we provided $1.3 billion for homeland security programs for which only a small number of urban areas are eligible to apply. All of these needs  deserve and need to be met. I have worked hard over the years to help address the needs of larger States and high-density areas, and I have opposed the Bush Administration's efforts to pit our States against each other, as they have tried to mask their efforts to cut overall funding for first responders.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Smaller States, especially, would never be able to fulfill those essential duties on top of their daily responsibilities without Federal support, especially given that DHS is currently suggesting that States will pay for REAL ID implementation, an estimated $16 billion, with first responder grants. My colleagues should be warned that if the minimum drops further--compounded by substantial drops in overall first responder funding--then small- and medium-sized States will not be able to meet those  Federal mandates for terrorism prevention, preparedness, and response.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Some from urban States argue that Federal money to fight terrorism is being sent to areas that do not need it and is "wasted" in small towns. They claim the formula is highly politicized and insists on the redirection of funds to urban areas that they believe face heightened threat of terrorist attacks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What critics of the all-State minimum seem to forget since the September 11 terrorist attacks, the Federal Government has asked all State and local first responders to defend us as never before on the front lines in the war against terrorism. Emergency responders in one State have been given the same obligation as those in any other State to provide enhanced protection, preparedness, and response against terrorists.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The attacks of 9/11 added to the responsibilities and risks of first responders across the country. In recent years, due to the 0.75 percent all-State minimum allocation for formula grants that has existed in law, first responders have received resources to help them meet their new responsibilities and have made our neighborhoods safer and our communities better prepared.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is much left undone in securing our Nation. I hope that the Senate's conferees will resist calls for further needless reductions to the all-State minimum base and risk the preparedness efforts in small States like their own. I trust they will do all they can during conference negotiations to ensure continued support and resources for our police, fire, and EMS services in every State if we expect them to continue protecting us from terrorist or responding to terrorist attacks, as well as  carrying out their ongoing responsibilities in helping to keep our communities safe and prepared.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="TRANSIT SECURITY">
    <paragraph>Madam President, now is the time to implement the unfinished recommendations of the 9/11 Commission.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I commend Senators LIEBERMAN and COLLINS for their leadership and the Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee for its work on this important legislation. More than 5 years after 9/11 despite tens of billions of dollars spent America's ports, rails, airports, borders, nuclear powerplants and chemical plants still are not completely safe. It has been more than 2 years since the 9/11 Commission issued its final recommendations, and here we are, today, still debating  the same issues.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation builds upon previous efforts to enhance homeland security and includes several critical provisions to allocate homeland security resources based on risk, ensure that first responders have interoperable communications equipment, and improve government-wide information sharing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I especially am pleased to note three provisions included in this bill that I have championed for some time. This legislation specifies that States can use Federal grants to design, conduct, and evaluate mass evacuation plans and exercises. While most cities and States have evacuation plans, the lack of training drills and exercises makes it difficult to address problems and work out solutions before lives are at risk in a real emergency. As we learned from Hurricanes Katrina and Rita, there  is no substitute for being prepared. We may only have one chance to get it right.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, this legislation makes important structural changes to strengthen the Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board. Again, I commend Senators LIEBERMAN and COLLINS for including a broad statutory mandate and subpoena power for the Board. This bill also would require Senate confirmation for the chair and the vice-chair of the Board, as well as mandatory public reporting by the Board and reports for Congress. These provisions are key to ensuring the integrity of the Privacy  and Civil Liberties Oversight Board.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, this bill improves intelligence and information sharing within the Federal Government and with State and local governments. I am pleased that the bill we consider today would make the program manager for the Information Sharing Environment, ISE, permanent and authorize additional funds and staff to accomplish the ISE mission. The bill also requires additional reports to Congress on the status of ISE development. These comprehensive new requirements would improve and strengthen government  information sharing structures, which will mean a more integrated intelligence network and a more secure Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The 9/11 Commission gave Congress a critically important job by charging us with making structural changes to close the gaps in America's homeland security defenses. This legislation responds to that challenge, and I support its final passage.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Under the previous order, there will be 20 minutes of debate divided between the managers and the leaders.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="TRANSIT SECURITY">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I first want to thank our colleagues for their cooperation in moving forward this very important piece of legislation. When the 9/11 Commission completed its report and made its findings to Congress, the Homeland Security Committee, which I chaired at the time, worked very hard to produce a major overhaul of our intelligence community--in fact, the most sweeping changes in more than 50 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That legislation, for example, created the Director of National Intelligence and also established the National Counterterrorism Center, which brings together analysts from the 15 agencies involved in intelligence gathering and analysis. We took a major step forward.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now we are on the verge of finishing the job. I salute the chairman of the committee, Senator Lieberman, for making this legislation the top priority of our committee under his chairmanship. The legislation is going to help implement the unfinished recommendations of the 9/11 Commission. As I said, most of the recommendations were included in the 2004 Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act. But there were some significant ones that were not completed. Thus, this legislation  improves intelligence and information sharing, and it authorizes the Homeland Security Grant Program, which has been so important in improving the capabilities of our communities and States which are, after all, our partners in improving homeland security.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We worked very hard, the chairman and I and the rest of the committee members, to devise a formula that would be fair to all States, that would allocate the majority of the funding based on an analysis of risk, vulnerability, and consequences but also ensure that each and every State receive a predictable, steady level of funding so that each State can be improved and have a basic preparedness level.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think we struck the right balance in that area. This bill would authorize a bit over $3 billion for each of the next 3 years for this new Homeland Security Grant Program. Included in that program is an emphasis on prevention. We  all are very focused on recovery and response in the event of a terrorist attack, but we believe it is very important to also focus on preventing attacks from happening in the first place. Our legislation would do that by providing  that at least 25 percent of the overall funding for the urban areas and State Homeland Security Grant Programs must be used for law enforcement terrorism prevention activities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Another important section of this bill creates a program to deal with communications equipment interoperability. We know that lives were lost on 9/11 because the various first responders could not communicate with one another. As a result, firefighters, police officers, and emergency medical personnel lost their lives and suffered injuries. Much to our dismay, we also found as part of our investigation into the failed response to Hurricane Katrina that exactly those same interoperability problems  were occurring in Louisiana, in particular. We simply must tackle this problem. It is too big a problem and too expensive a problem for States and communities to do on their own. That is why we have a partnership, a grant program that would be administered by FEMA and dedicated to improving the survivability and the interoperability of communications equipment used by our courageous first responders and emergency managers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, that program would authorize $3.3 billion over the next 5 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also makes a number of important improvements to prevent terrorists from traveling to our country; to strengthen the Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board; to improve private sector preparedness, since we know that 85 percent of critical infrastructure is in the private sector; and to improve transportation security planning and overall security of our transportation system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It has been a great pleasure to work with the chairman and the members of our committee, as well as the Commerce Committee and other Members who have been interested, to bring this bill to the floor, and I believe it will help make our Nation safer.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Connecticut.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="TRANSIT SECURITY">
    <paragraph>Madam President, first, let me thank my ranking member, the Senator from Maine. I was thinking, as she was speaking, that when the transition occurred at the beginning of this 110th session of Congress I said to her, all that would change in our working relationship was our title, the title that each of us had. As I look back on our work together on this bill, <bill type="s" number="4">S. 4</bill>, I am pleased to say that we worked with the same spirit of cooperation that we did under her chairmanship in 2004  when we had our first legislative response to the 9/11 Commission and we adopted the Intelligence Reform and Terrorist Prevention Act of 2004. So I thank Senator Collins.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank her staff for their work, and I thank my staff as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam President, I note the presence on the floor of the majority leader. I thank him for making adoption of this legislation a priority for this Congress. Here is why. This bill will strengthen our ability not just to respond to terrorist attacks but also to prepare our Federal, State, and local governments to respond to natural disasters. In that sense, <bill type="s" number="4">S. 4</bill> is not only a response to finish the mission given us by the 9/11 Commission that learns from the lessons of the first months of implementation  of that Commission report, but it also applies to lessons learned from Hurricane Katrina. We are trying to create an all-hazards approach in our Government that increases our homeland security against the threat of a terrorist attack and also prepares our Government to respond better to natural disasters. I do not want to repeat some of the points in this legislation that Senator Collins focused on. I will just pick a few additionally.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One is that <bill type="s" number="4">S. 4</bill> recognizes that 85 percent of the critical infrastructure in our country that is potentially a target for terrorist attack in our great open society is privately owned. For the first time, we establish a voluntary program where the private sector can come in and have their facilities certified as, I would use the term "terrorist resistant."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In another section we declassify the bottom line of the intelligence budget. That was a specific recommendation of the 9/11 Commission in the interests of transparency and accountability.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We also greatly improve the provisions that in our law and policy are aimed at disrupting terrorist infiltration of our borders. This bill requires the Department of Homeland Security and the Department of State to strengthen the security provisions of the so-called visa waiver program. It also authorizes an electronic travel system that would require travelers to apply in advance for authorization to visit the United States, thus allowing their names to be checked against terrorist watch lists.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am very proud of the bill we present after almost 2 weeks of debate to our colleagues in the Senate for final consideration. I know it will strengthen the homeland security of the American people. It enjoyed strong nonpartisan support in our committee, coming out with a vote of 16 to 0 with one abstention.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I gather there will be a significant number of "no" votes on the final passage because of one section, and I regret that. I wish our colleagues would vote favorably because I know they support almost all of this bill because it is good for the security of the American people at home.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The one section, obviously, is the one that deals with the collective bargaining rights of transportation security officers. I sure hope we can continue to discuss this section: why we think it is fair, why we are totally convinced its implementation will have no adverse effect on public safety--no more than the collective bargaining rights of Capitol Police officers or local firefighters or police officers or members of the Border Patrol or other law enforcement agencies in the Department of  Homeland Security in any way adversely affects the carrying out of the duties to protect the American people.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam President, I also want to thank the chairman and ranking member of the Commerce Committee, Senators INOUYE and STEVENS, for producing the rail and aviation security portions of this bill, and the chairman and ranking member of the Banking Committee, Senators DODD and SHELBY, who contributed important mass transit security provisions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would be remiss if I didn't also thank the majority leader, Senator REID, for working with all of the committees involved to bring this comprehensive measure before tbe Senate. We have had 2 weeks of often spirited debate, and votes on some important amendments. Now, I believe we are ready to pass this bill, and I look forward to working with my colleagues to conference this measure with the House, and moving the legislation onto the President's desk for signature.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>September 11, 2001, was a tragedy of unspeakable proportions, and it is for the men and women who died in the terrorist attacks that we work to enact this legislation. The attacks changed the course of history for our Nation and marked our nascent century as a new and dangerous era. Overnight, we became aware of our vulnerability to an enemy that doesn't wear uniforms nor follows any traditional laws of combat. Rather, they move silently among us, probing for weaknesses while plotting attacks  on innocent civilians.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The families of those we lost on 9/11 have worked with us for years to get the 9/11 Commission recommendations implemented. I must thank them as well for their steadfast and courageous advocacy often in the face of seemingly insurmountable odds. They worked with us to pass the bill that Senator MCCAIN and I introduced to create the 9/11 Commission. They monitored the work of the 9/11 Commission, and testified before its members. And then they helped us win the fight to implement the Commission's  recommendations in the Intelligence Reform and Terrorist Prevention Act of 2004.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In January, Senator COLLINS and I held a hearing on this legislation and heard from three family members who urged us to complete the job of enacting and implementing the 9/11 Commission's recommendations. When we pass this bill today, they will be watching. And they will know that they had a hand in its success.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator REID made adoption of this legislation a priority for this Congress. Here is why: This bill will strengthen our ability not just to respond to terrorist attacks but also to prepare our  Federal, State, and local governments to better respond to natural disasters.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are trying to create an "all hazards" approach that increases our homeland security against the threat of terrorist attack, but also prepares our government to respond better to natural disasters since it failed to prepare or respond adequately to Hurricane Katrina.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>How do we do this? Let me briefly describe a few of the provisions in this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, we would improve information and intelligence sharing among Federal, State, and local officials. We know that before 9/11, different agencies had different pieces of information that, had they been put together, should have aroused suspicion about the attack that was to come. One of the most important innovations since 9/11 has been the establishment of fusion centers to share information within and between States. This legislation would create standards for the fusion centers, require  the Department of Homeland Security to provide support and coordination, and authorize the assignment of homeland security intelligence analysts to the fusion centers to serve as conduits for sharing information. The legislation also encourages the elimination of the "need to know" standard, which allows the information holder in a given Federal agency to control dissemination, and instead, encourages a "need to share" standard--obviously with appropriate safeguards.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second, this legislation provides support and resources to first responders through a balanced and better funded Homeland Security Grant Program. We would authorize over $3.1 billion for each of the  next 3 years for key grants to reverse a precipitous decline in funding for homeland security over the past 4 years. We believe we have achieved a balanced proposal that gives the vast majority of the money out based on risk but still recognizes that risk is an art, not a science, and terrorists could strike anywhere. In an all-hazards approach, first responders everywhere need assistance to protect not just against a potential terrorist attack but also against natural disasters.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Third, we will help first responders attain the interoperable communications we know they need to save lives. We have known of this problem for decades, and on 9/11, when fire fighters and police officers could not communicate with one another inside the World Trade Center, hundreds of first responders lost their lives. So, we have created a grant program--authorized at $3.3 billion over 5 years--that will require States to spend their grant money consistent with their statewide communications  interoperability plans and the National Emergency Communications Plan. In other words, their spending must be part of a statewide plan connected to the national plan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Fourth, this legislation contains provisions to improve our ability to disrupt terrorist infiltration of our borders. It requires the Departments of Homeland Security and State to strengthen the security of the visa waiver program, by requiring better reporting by foreign countries in the visa waiver program of lost or stolen passports, requiring countries to share information about prospective visitors who may pose a threat to the U.S., and authorizing an electronic travel system that would  require travelers to apply in advance for authorization to visit the U.S., thus allowing their names to be checked against terrorist watch lists.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Fifth, this bill moves to ensure that as we fight terrorism, we do not trample on the rights of Americans we are pledged to defend. Included here are provisions to strengthen the Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board by requiring its members to be confirmed by the Senate and by giving the Board subpoena power through the Attorney General.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation also includes a provision similar to one I was pleased to cosponsor in committee with Senator MCCASKILL that will ensure Transportation Security Administration screeners--known as Transportation Security Officers--have the same employment rights as others in TSA and throughout the Department of Homeland Security. There is no good reason to deny TSOs these rights. Other law enforcement officers at Immigration and Customs Enforcement and Customs and Border Protection have  these rights, with no negative effect on their performance of their security mission. In fact, Capitol Police also enjoy these rights and protections. This is simply a question of equality.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So this is a comprehensive bill. There are many other worthy aspects that I have not described. But I am convinced that, as a package, if this legislation passes and becomes law, the American people will be safer from the consequences of natural disasters, such as Hurricane Katrina, than they are today. And we will have done everything possible to make sure no other Americans suffer the loss that so many experienced after the brutal terrorist attacks of 9/11.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the preface to the 9/11 Report, Chairman Kean and Vice Chairman Hamilton wrote, quoting here, "We hope our report will encourage our fellow citizens to study, reflect--and act."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have studied. We have reflected. Now is the time to act to build a safer and more secure America for the generations to come.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, I would like to pay tribute to my dedicated and exceptional staff, who have sacrificed nights, weekends, family time in the name of a safer America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I particularly want to thank my Homeland Security Committee staff director Mike Alexander for his leadership in expertly guiding this legislation through drafting, markup, floor amendments, and onto final passage. I also want to thank the committee's deputy chief counsel Kevin Landy, whose drive and attention to detail resulted in superior legislation. Thanks also to Eric Anderson, Christian Beckner, Janet Burrell, Scott Campbell, Troy Cribb, Aaron Firoved, Elyse Greenwald, Beth Grossman, Seamus  Hughes, Holly Idelson, Kristine Lam, Nate Lesser, Jim Mcgee, Sheila Menz, Larry Novey, Deborah Parkinson, Leslie Phillips, Alistair Reader, Patricia Rojas, Laurie Rubenstein, Mary Beth Schultz, Adam Sedgewick, Todd Stein, Donny Williams, Jason Yanussi, and Wes Young--all on my committee staff. And thanks to Purva Rawal, Vance Serchuk, and Cherrie Daniels on my personal office staff.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I must also thank Senator COLLINS' staff director Brandon Milhorn and the Senator's entire staff for working with us to move this very important legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But bottom line, thank you to our colleagues, thanks to the 9/11 Commission, thanks to the 9/11 families who have stuck with this mission to protect the American people from ever having to suffer the grievous loss they did at the hands of terrorists on 9/11.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I hope our colleagues will join together across party lines to support this very nonpartisan homeland security measure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Republican leader.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300072" topic="TRANSIT SECURITY">
    <paragraph>Madam President, let me congratulate Chairman Lieberman and Ranking Member Collins on their Herculean effort on this legislation. I particularly commend our ranking member, Senator Collins, for fighting the good fight when there were some reservations on our side about a major portion of this bill which will compel me to vote against the bill. I know Senator Collins made every effort to strip the provision that I and others find so offensive,  but regretfully the provision was not stripped.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In a few minutes the Senate will vote on final passage of Improving America's Security Act of 2007. It has, as I indicated, some good features. At its core, it seeks to improve America's security, but on balance it would also do much to weaken it. I plan to vote against the bill, and I urge my Senate colleagues to do the same.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But, before I cast my vote, a little background. Many of our Democratic friends spent last year campaigning on the claim that Republicans ignored the recommendations of the 9/11 Commission. We didn't. Of the Commission's 39 recommendations, we implemented 37. Nor are the remaining two recommendations at issue today. Both parties agree they should not be in the bill, so the two provisions that we did not adopt of the 9/11 Commission, both sides agreed we should not adopt. So I will oppose this  bill on the basis of my answer to a simple question: Does it weaken America's security or strengthen it? The answer that I and many of  my colleagues have come with is, regretfully, the former.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill would weaken America's security because of a single dangerous provision, and that at the insistence of big labor that Democrats include collective bargaining rights for airport security screeners, rights that Congress has refused to give them in the past because of the impact it would have on our ability to react to terrorist threats.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress would not grant screeners collective bargaining rights back in 2002. We have had this debate before. We had it at the time of the creation of the Department of Homeland Security--if it has a familiar ring to it, to many of my colleagues, we chose not to adopt that provision then, and we hopefully will not, ultimately, this time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The difference is the Democrats are letting the fight play out. They are stretching it out based on a political calculation. They already know how this showdown is going to end. The President threatened to veto any bill that makes airport security more like the department of motor vehicles. So they are delaying passage knowing it won't be accepted, for an applause line down the road.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Republicans tried to inject meaning into this bill to include provisions that would improve security. For example, we proposed an amendment that would make it a crime to recruit terrorists, that would authorize the deportation of suspected terrorists, that would make it easier to detain dangerous illegal aliens and would increase penalties for people who cruelly call families of soldiers overseas and falsely report their loved one has died. But our colleagues on the other side of the aisle rejected  all of those provisions, opting instead to pump for big labor. They are turning their backs on their own campaign promises in the process by ignoring a key recommendation of the 9/11 Commission that the United States do everything in its power to constrain terrorists' mobility.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>TSA workers showed that mobility after the United Kingdom bombing threat in August when they showed up for work that morning at 4 a.m. and they were briefed on the situation overseas and they immediately implemented new protocols. Anyone who traveled to or from an American airport that day would not even have known anything had happened. The execution was seamless. It was a different story in Great Britain, where collective bargaining is the norm. Dozens of flights were canceled while new procedures  were instituted. The Democrats know Americans will not stand for that approach to terrorism in our country, but they are counting on the President and the Republicans to stop it for them. That way, they can call us obstructionists and get another applause line in the bargain and maybe even a headline or two. It is a shame because there are some good things in the bill, such as new performance standards and auditing requirements for DHS grants. But we will let them have their applause line.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Republicans have never played games with national security, and we are not going to start now. Therefore, I will vote against the bill, and for the sake of the American people and their continued security, I would strongly urge my other colleagues to do the same, while saying once again how much I commend the Senator from Maine for her efforts to get this bill in the proper form, and there are provisions in the bill not as a result of any of the efforts of the ranking member of the committee.  I commend her for her efforts but, regretfully, must oppose final passage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The majority leader.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="TRANSIT SECURITY">
    <paragraph>Madam President, this should be a time of celebration, not a time of finger-pointing. In fact, the fact is, it is true that a number of recommendations the 9/11 Commission recommended we did do. But, as you know, the Commissioners themselves graded the administration on what needed to be done to implement the Commission's recommendations. That is where we get into the Es, Fs, and incompletes. So there is no question this legislation absolutely is totally necessary.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Following the terrible attacks on September 11, our country turned to a respected group of Democrats and Republicans, the 9/11 Commission, an independent bipartisan Commission, to review the lessons of that tragic day and to find a better way to protect the homeland fight on the war on terrorism. Under difficult circumstances, including a lack of cooperation, in instances, from the White House, the Commission did an outstanding job.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In July of 2004, it made a number of recommendations to Congress and the administration about how best to secure America from al-Qaida and other terrorist groups. Their recommendations were commonsense solutions. These commonsense solutions were designed to keep America safe. But, unfortunately, over the last 2 1/2  years, many of the Commission's recommendations have been ignored, and too many of our communities remain dangerously unprepared to prevent or respond to a terrorist attack.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, in a few minutes, the Senate will correct that mistake. We will enhance the security of our transportation system at our ports. We will provide America's first responders with the technology they need to communicate with each other when a Katrina or another terrorist attack strikes, and we will put new security requirements in place to keep terrorists from traveling to the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is an important piece of legislation we are going to pass. We are going to pass it, as I said, in a short time. I thank Chairman Lieberman and his ranking member, Senator Collins, for their efforts on this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I said before this legislation was taken up on the floor that we have two people who set the example for how you should legislate. They got along well in their committee. When she was chairman, Senator Lieberman worked well with her, and it has worked the same way. I commend and applaud both of these legislators. They have done a tremendous job trying to work through this issue. Anything that has been slowed down in this legislation has not been their fault--in fact, quite to the contrary.  They have worked tirelessly to bring this legislation here today so we can have this vote. They reported a strong bill out of the Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee. It has only been strengthened by the amendment process before the full Senate over the past several days.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, we do not need to redebate the issue regarding collective bargaining. Collective bargaining has been in this country for a long time, and it is here to stay. There is nothing in this piece of legislation that is in any way going to impair the security of this Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I wish to thank the entire 9/11 Commission for their service, but especially I wish to thank 9/11 Commissioner Tim Roemer and the 9/11 family, but especially Carol Ashley, Beverly Eckert, Mary Fetchet, and Carie Lemack, members of Families of September 11 and VOICES of September 11th. Their input in this legislation has been essential. Former</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congressman Roemer spent time here on the Senate floor. No one could ever accuse Congressman Roemer of being some wild-eyed liberal. He is a moderate, and he is from the State of Indiana. He has worked very hard on the Commission and to move this legislation forward. I underline and underscore my appreciation for his input and also for the families and the two letters they wrote during the debate. Their letters served as a reminder of what this legislation is about: protecting America against  terrorism. Our country will be safer, stronger, and more secure as a result of their efforts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The first responsibility of Government is to protect our people--the people of Colorado, the people of Nevada, the people of Maine, the people of Connecticut, Alabama, Nebraska, and Missouri. The Senators are here assembled, everyone in their seats. Our No. 1 job is to protect our people. By passing the legislation today, we will help ensure the Senate meets its obligation, and we will, once and for all, write the lesson of that terrible September 11 day into law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In their report to the Nation, the 9/11 Commission wrote, "The men and women of the World War II generation rose to the challenges of the 1940s and the 1950s. They restructured the government so it could protect the country. That is now the job of the generations that experienced 9/11."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is what the legislation is all about.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, I applaud and commend the two managers of the bill, those who offered amendments and debated the issue. This is good legislation, good for the country. It makes America a better place. I urge my colleagues to vote for this legislation so we can take another step to fulfilling the directives we were given by the 9/11 Commission.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Maine.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="TRANSIT SECURITY">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that a list of the homeland security staffers on the Republican side who worked so hard on this bill be printed in the Record at this point.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="TRANSIT SECURITY">
    <paragraph>I also wish to add my voice in thanks to the families of the victims of 9/11. They have truly been the committee's inspiration as we worked on these issues for the last 4 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The majority leader.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="TRANSIT SECURITY">
    <paragraph>For the information of all Members, we are working--Senator McConnell and I--on a consent agreement to deal with the Iraq debate tomorrow. Hopefully, we will be able to resolve the Iraq debate. Thursday, we will be able to deal with the U.S. attorneys bill and some judicial nominees. We do not have that worked out yet, so everyone stay tuned.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This will be the last vote today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The bill having been read the third time, the question is, Shall it pass?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="TRANSIT SECURITY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask for the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there a sufficient second?</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will call the roll.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="TRANSIT SECURITY">
    <paragraph>I announce that the Senator from South Dakota (Mr. Johnson) is necessarily absent.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300069" topic="TRANSIT SECURITY">
    <paragraph>The following Senator was necessarily absent: the Senator from Arizona (Mr. McCain).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Are there any other Senators in the Chamber desiring to vote?</chair>
  <narrative>The result was announced--yeas 60, nays 38, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="TRANSIT SECURITY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I move to reconsider the vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="TRANSIT SECURITY">
    <paragraph>I move to lay that motion on the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The motion to lay on the table was agreed to.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="TRANSIT SECURITY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="TRANSIT SECURITY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="TRANSIT SECURITY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask to speak as in morning business for such time as I might consume, and if there are other Members who are wondering how long that might be, it wouldn't be probably for more than 15 minutes at the most.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Iowa is recognized.</chair>
</record>
