<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1185854400" ordinal="61" title="75TH ANNIVERSARY OF THE MILITARY ORDER OF THE PURPLE HEART">
  <narrative>75TH ANNIVERSARY OF THE MILITARY ORDER OF THE PURPLE HEART -- (Senate - July 31, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="10529">S10529</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412244" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the Armed Services Committee be discharged from further consideration of <bill type="sc" number="26">S. Con. Res. 26</bill> and the Senate proceed to its consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered. The clerk will report the concurrent resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A concurrent resolution (<bill type="sc" number="26">S. Con. Res. 26</bill>) recognizing the 75th anniversary of the Military Order of the Purple Heart and commending recipients of the Purple Heart for their courageous demonstrations of gallantry and heroism on behalf of the United States.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412244" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the concurrent resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table en bloc, and that any statements relating thereto be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The concurrent resolution (<bill type="sc" number="26">S. Con. Res. 26</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The concurrent resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair> <bill type="sc" number="26">S. Con. Res. 26</bill></chair>
  <chair>Whereas the Purple Heart is a combat decoration awarded to members of the Armed Forces who are wounded by an instrument of war wielded by the enemy;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Purple Heart is awarded posthumously to the next of kin in the name of members of the Armed Forces who are killed in action or die of wounds received in action;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Purple Heart was originally conceived as the Badge of Military Merit by General George Washington on August 7, 1782;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas 2007 marks the 225th anniversary of the Badge of Military Merit, the predecessor of the Purple Heart;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the practice of awarding the Purple Heart was revived in 1932, the 200th anniversary of George Washington's birth, out of respect for his memory and military achievements;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas more than 1,535,000 Purple Hearts have been awarded to members of the Armed Forces who fought in defense of freedom and democracy in World War I, World War II, the Korean War, the Vietnam War, Operation Desert Storm, Operation Enduring Freedom, Operation Iraqi Freedom, and other expeditionary conflicts;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas approximately 550,000 recipients of the Purple Heart are alive today;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the organization known as the Military Order of the Purple Heart was formed on October 19, 1932, for the protection and mutual interest of members of the Armed Forces who have received the Purple Heart; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Military Order of the Purple Heart is composed exclusively of recipients of the Purple Heart and is the only veterans' service organization comprised strictly of combat veterans: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved by the Senate (the House of Representatives concurring), That Congress--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) congratulates the Military Order of the Purple Heart on its 75th anniversary as a national organization whose goals are to preserve and sustain the honor of the Armed Forces;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) commends all recipients of the Purple Heart for their courageous demonstrations of gallantry and heroism on behalf of the United States; and</chair>
  <chair> (3) encourages the people of the United States to take time to learn about the Purple Heart and the honor, courage, and bravery it symbolizes.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
