<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1191254402" ordinal="53" title="SUPPORTING THE GOALS AND IDEALS OF NATIONAL PASSPORT MONTH">
  <narrative>SUPPORTING THE GOALS AND IDEALS OF NATIONAL PASSPORT MONTH -- (Senate - October 01, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="12385">S12385</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400050" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of <bill type="sr" number="338">S. Res. 338</bill>, submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="338">S. Res. 338</bill>) supporting the goals and ideals of National Passport Month.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today in support of this resolution that would designate the month of September as "National Passport Month."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Travel book publishers, along with travel editors from some of the most prestigious media outlets in the United States and many student travel organizations, have designated September as "National Passport Month" as part of a campaign to educate the public about the importance of having a passport.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This resolution supports the goals and ideals of "National Passport Month" and calls on the Federal Government, States, schools, businesses and the people of the United States to observe the month of September with programs and activities that will encourage Americans to get their passports and see the world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since 2000, the number of passport applications received by the U.S. State Department has increased by 66 percent. This year, the State Department is expected to issue a record 17 million passports, up from last year's record of 12 million.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This surge in passport applications has led to longer processing times, averaging 6 to 8 weeks. As a result, there have been significant increases in public requests for expedited processing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The designation of September as "National Passport Month" will serve as an important reminder for the American people to plan ahead and begin their passport application process early.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Despite the significant increase in the number of passport applications being processed, fewer than 23 percent of Americans have passports.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This number is far too low. International travel provides a unique perspective of the world and is an invaluable opportunity to interact with the global community and experience world cultures first hand.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to encourage the American people to get their passports and see the world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The designation of September as "National Passport Month" will not only encourage the American people to avoid delays and get their passports early, but it will also acknowledge the positive impact of international travel in promoting understanding, tolerance, acceptance, and goodwill throughout the world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On September 5, 2007, the U.S. House of Representatives unanimously agreed to an identical resolution introduced by Congresswoman BARBARA LEE. It is my hope that this body will do the same. I urge my colleagues to support this resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400050" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table, and that any statements relating thereto be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="338">S. Res. 338</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="338">S. Res. 338</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas, through international travel, Americans can individually play a major role towards improving foreign relations by building bridges and making connections with citizens of other countries;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas interacting with the global community inspires Americans to reflect on the diverse multi-cultural background that has defined the United States as a great country of cooperation and progress;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas having a passport and traveling abroad creates connections with the global community;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas having a passport and traveling abroad promotes understanding and goodwill throughout the world, opening the doors to increased peace, tolerance, and acceptance; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas having a passport and traveling abroad opens up a wealth of educational opportunities and experiences for Americans of all ages;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas having a passport and traveling abroad enables Americans to see first-hand the effect of the United States on the world, including the tremendous amount of humanitarian aid given by the United States through both public and private sectors;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas having a passport and traveling abroad reminds Americans that they are members of a global family and gives them opportunities to mend rifts around the world;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas fewer than 23 percent of Americans have passports, thereby limiting their ability to travel outside the United States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the more Americans travel outside the United States, the more they will experience opportunities to increase their understanding of the world and the place of the United States in it;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the creation and support of a National Passport Month signals to Americans the important role they can play as ambassadors for the United States by serving as agents of understanding, tolerance, and mutual respect; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas travel publishers along with travel editors from the most prestigious media outlets in the United States, student travel organizations, and book sellers have designated September as "National Passport Month" to educate the public about the importance of having a passport and the positive impact international travel has on individuals: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) supports the goals and ideals of National Passport Month; and</chair>
  <chair> (2) calls on the Federal Government, States, localities, schools, nonprofit organizations, businesses, other entities, and the people of the United States to observe National Passport Month with appropriate ceremonies, programs, and activities.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
