<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1227200405" ordinal="77" title="SENATE RESOLUTION 719--RECOGNIZING NATIONAL AMERICAN INDIAN AND ALASKA NATIVE HERITAGE MONTH AND CELEBRATING THE HERITAGE AND CULTURE OF AMERICAN INDIANS AND ALASKA NATIVES AND THE CONTRIBUTIONS OF AMERICAN INDIANS AND ALASKA NATIVES TO THE UNITED STATES">
  <narrative>SENATE RESOLUTION 719--RECOGNIZING NATIONAL AMERICAN INDIAN AND ALASKA NATIVE HERITAGE MONTH AND CELEBRATING THE HERITAGE AND CULTURE OF AMERICAN INDIANS AND ALASKA NATIVES AND THE CONTRIBUTIONS OF AMERICAN INDIANS AND ALASKA NATIVES TO THE UNITED STATES -- (Senate - November 20, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="10755">S10755</bill>]</narrative>
  <narrative>Mr. DORGAN (for himself, Ms. Murkowski, Mrs. Boxer, Mrs. Clinton, Mr. Schumer, Mr. Salazar, Mr. Feingold, Mr. Tester, Mr. Domenici, Mr. McCain, Mr. Wyden, Mr. Baucus, Ms. Cantwell, Mr. Nelson of Nebraska, Mrs. Feinstein, Mr. Bayh, Mr. Thune, Mr. Bingaman, Mr. Conrad, and Mr. Johnson) submitted the following resolution; which  was referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="sr" number="719">S. Res. 719</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative>Whereas from November 1, 2008, through November 30, 2008, the United States celebrates National American Indian and Alaska Native Heritage Month;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas American Indians and Alaska Natives are descendants of the original, indigenous inhabitants of what is now the United States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, in 2000, the United States Census Bureau reported that there were more than 4,000,000 people in the United States of American Indian and Alaska Native descent;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, on December 2, 1989, the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate held a hearing exploring the contributions of the Iroquois Confederacy, and its influence on the Founding Fathers in the drafting of the Constitution of the United States with the concepts of freedom of speech, the separation of governmental powers, and checks and balances among the branches of government;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Senate has reaffirmed that a major national goal of the United States is to provide the resources, processes, and structure that will enable Indian Tribes and tribal members to obtain the quantity and quality of health care services and opportunities that will eliminate the health disparities between American Indians and the general population of the United States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Congress recently reaffirmed its trust responsibility to improve the housing conditions and socioeconomic status of American Indians and Alaska Natives by providing affordable homes in a safe and healthy environment;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, throughout its course of dealing with Indian Tribes, the United States Government has engaged in a government-to-government relationship with Tribes;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the United States Government owes a trust obligation to Tribes, acknowledged in treaties, statutes, and decisions of the Supreme Court, to protect the interests and welfare of tribal governments and their members;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas American Indians and Alaska Natives have consistently served with honor and distinction in the Armed Forces of the United States, some as early as the Revolutionary War, and continue to serve in the Armed Forces in greater numbers per capita than any other group in the United States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas American Indians and Alaska Natives speak and preserve indigenous languages and have contributed hundreds of words to the English language, including the names of people and locations in the United States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Congress has recognized Native American code talkers who served with honor and distinction in World War I and World War II, using indigenous languages as an unbreakable military code, saving countless American lives;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas American Indians and Alaska Natives are deeply rooted in tradition and culture, which drives their strength of community; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas American Indians and Alaska Natives of all ages celebrate the great achievements of their ancestors and heroes and continue to share their stories with future generations: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) recognizes the celebration of National American Indian and Alaska Native Heritage Month during the month of November 2008;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) honors the heritage and culture of American Indians and Alaska Natives and the contributions of American Indians and Alaska Natives to the United States; and</narrative>
  <narrative> (3) urges the people of the United States to observe National American Indian and Alaska Native Heritage Month with appropriate programs and activities.&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300037" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, on October 30, 2008, President Bush issued a proclamation designating November 2008 as National American Indian and Alaska Native Heritage Month. The President follows a tradition of Presidents since 1990 of issuing proclamations making November the month for recognizing the significant contributions of tribal governments and individual Native Americans to our Nation's history and development.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress also has traditionally recognized the contributions of Native Americans to the United States in the form of resolutions, findings, coins and medals. The resolution, which I am sending to the desk to ask for its immediate consideration, continues in that tradition.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This resolution recognizes some of the many contributions that Native Americans have made to help build our great Nation as well as the continued contributions of Native Americans to the growth of the United States. From contributions to the United States and the world in the fields of agriculture, medicine, music, language, and art to influencing the founding documents of our Federal Government to the use of native languages to develop an unbreakable military code that helped defeat the Axis  powers in World War II, Indian Tribes and individual Native Americans have shaped our Nation's history in remarkable ways.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Through this resolution, we celebrate these and many other contributions of tribal governments and Native Americans during the month of November. I urge all citizens, and local, State, tribal and Federal Governments and agencies to take time this month to learn more about the many facets of Native American history, traditions, and their important contributions to the formation of the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This year, the United States Senate and the Congress as a whole acted on two important pieces of legislation that seek to meet our Nation's legal, treaty and trust obligations to promote health care and housing for the residents of Indian Country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="1200">S. 1200</bill>, the Indian Health Care Improvement Act of 2008, passed the Senate in February of this year with a margin of 83-10. As Chairman of the Committee on Indian Affairs, this legislation has been the priority for the Committee in the 110th Congress. The Indian health care act was last authorized in 1992, and this bill would help bring Indian health care into to 21st century. I am proud to report that we were able to pass this legislation out of the Senate for the first time in almost a decade.  A number of Senators were instrumental moving this legislation forward in the Senate. Unfortunately, our work was not completed. The House was unable to pass the legislation and it remains unauthorized as the health care needs of Native Americans remain sorely under-funded and services remain outdated. Indian health care will continue to remain a priority for the committee and every effort will be made to reauthorize this legislation as soon as possible.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to the Indian Health Care Improvement Act, the Senate approved a $1 billion authorization for additional funding for the Indian Health Service as a part of the Senate Budget Resolution. Congress also passed a $250 million authorization for Indian health care through an amendment to the Tom Lantos and Henry J. Hyde United States Global Leadership Against HIV/AIDS, Tuberculosis, and Malaria Reauthorization Act of 2008.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In September of this year, Congress succeeded in enacting the Native American Housing and Self-Determination Assistance Reauthorization Act of 2008. This bill makes long needed improvements to Native housing programs, and authorizes the flexible use of funding to strengthen Native communities through economic and community development.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While health care and housing are critically important to Indian Country and represent significant steps forward in fulfilling the trust obligation between Congress and the First Americans, it is important to acknowledge several other achievements in the 110th Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress passed into law the Code Talkers Recognition Act of 2008 which provides well-deserved Congressional gold medals to each tribe that had members who were Code Talkers in any foreign conflict. Each next of kin to the valiant Code Talker who served their country will receive a silver duplicate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Higher Education Reauthorization Act was passed into law, which reauthorized the Tribally Controlled Colleges and Universities Assistance Act, increasing the amount of money per student in tribal colleges and universities. A study has been requested of the General Accountability Office which will allow for an evaluation of public schools on Indian lands to assist Congress in meeting its obligations to Indian education.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress also passed the Fostering Connections to Success and Increasing Adoptions Act allowing Tribes for the  first time to directly administer foster care and adoption programs offered by the Federal government, allowing tribes to continue strengthening their communities by ensuring safe and caring homes for their Native children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress passed the Native American $1 Coin Act, which recognizes the contributions of Native Americans to the development of the United States through an annually changing image on the reverse of the Sakakawea $1 coin that is now in circulation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress also passed into law a joint resolution designating November 28, 2008 as Native American Heritage Day, honoring the contributions and achievements of our First Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Treaty of Fort Laramie and other treaties acknowledged the specific obligations that the United States owes to the Tribes located in my State of North Dakota. Much has been done this Congress to begin to fulfill this legal responsibility and the more general trust responsibility that Congress owes to all Indian Tribes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, as is evident with Congress' failure to pass the Indian Health Care Improvement Act of 2008, much still remains to be done. The resolution before the Senate today would simply honor the hard work, traditions, culture, and contribution of the First Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask that this resolution be adopted quickly and that it act as an encouragement to all people of the United States to observe the month of November as National American Indian and Alaska Native Heritage Month.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
