<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1202230801" ordinal="45" title="PROVIDING FOR EXTENSIONS OF LEASES FOR CERTAIN LAND BY MASHANTUCKET PEQUOT (WESTERN) TRIBE">
  <narrative>PROVIDING FOR EXTENSIONS OF LEASES FOR CERTAIN LAND BY MASHANTUCKET PEQUOT (WESTERN) TRIBE -- (Senate - February 05, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="670">S670</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Indian Affairs be discharged from further consideration of <bill type="s" number="2457">S. 2457</bill> and that the Senate proceed to its immediate consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will report the bill by title.</narrative>
  <narrative>The assistant legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A bill (<bill type="s" number="2457">S. 2457</bill>) to provide for extensions of leases of certain land by Mashantucket Pequot (Western) Tribe.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the bill.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the amendment at the desk be agreed to, the bill, as amended, be read the third time and passed, a motion to reconsider be laid upon the table, and any statements relating to this measure be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The amendment (No. 3988) was agreed to, as follows:</chair>
  <narrative>(Purpose: To prohibit gaming activities on certain land)</narrative>
  <narrative> At the end, add the following:</narrative>
  <narrative> (c) Prohibition on Gaming Activities.--No entity may conduct any gaming activity (within the meaning of section 4 of the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act (25 U.S.C. 2703)) pursuant to a claim of inherent authority or any Federal law (including the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act (25 U.S.C. 2701 et seq.) and any regulations promulgated by the Secretary of the Interior or the National Indian Gaming Commission pursuant to that Act) on any land that is leased with an option to renew the lease  in accordance with this section. &lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <narrative>The bill (<bill type="s" number="2457">S. 2457</bill>), as amended, was ordered to be engrossed for a third reading, was read the third time, and passed, as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="s" number="2457">S. 2457</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. EXTENSIONS OF LEASES OF CERTAIN LAND BY MASHANTUCKET PEQUOT (WESTERN) TRIBE.</narrative>
  <narrative> (a) In General.--Any lease of restricted land of the Mashantucket Pequot (Western) Tribe (referred to in this section as the "Tribe") entered into on behalf of the Tribe by the tribal corporation of the Tribe chartered pursuant to section 17 of the Act of June 18, 1934 (25 U.S.C. 477), may include an option to renew the lease for not more than 2 additional terms, each of which shall not exceed 25 years, subject only to the approval of the tribal council of the Tribe.</narrative>
  <narrative> (b) Liability of United States.--The United States shall not be liable to any party for any loss resulting from a renewal of a lease entered into pursuant to subsection (a).</narrative>
  <narrative> (c) Prohibition on Gaming Activities.--No entity may conduct any gaming activity (within the meaning of section 4 of the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act (25 U.S.C. 2703)) pursuant to a claim of inherent authority or any Federal law (including the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act (25 U.S.C. 2701 et seq.) and any regulations promulgated by the Secretary of the Interior or the National Indian Gaming Commission pursuant to that Act) on any land that is leased with an option to renew the lease  in accordance with this section.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</narrative>
</record>
