<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1185854400" ordinal="52" title="PROVIDING FOR THE REAPPOINTMENT OF ROGER W. SANT">
  <narrative>PROVIDING FOR THE REAPPOINTMENT OF ROGER W. SANT -- (Senate - July 31, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="10525">S10525</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412244" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Rules Committee be discharged from further consideration of <bill type="sj" number="7">S.J. Res. 7</bill> and that the Senate then proceed to its consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered. The clerk will report the joint resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A joint resolution (<bill type="sj" number="7">S.J. Res. 7</bill>) providing for the reappointment of Roger W. Sant as a citizen regent of the Board of Regents of the Smithsonian Institution.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the joint resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412244" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the joint resolution be read three times, passed, and the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table; that any statements relating to the joint resolution be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The joint resolution (<bill type="sj" number="7">S.J. Res. 7</bill>) was ordered to be engrossed for a third reading, was read the third time, and passed, as follows:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>
      <bill type="sj" number="7">S.J. Res. 7</bill>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>Resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled, That, in accordance with section 5581 of the Revised Statutes (20 U.S.C. 43), the vacancy on the Board of Regents of the Smithsonian Institution, in the class other than Members of Congress, occurring because of the expiration of the term of Roger W. Sant of Washington, D.C., as filled by the reappointment of Roger W. Sant, for a term of 6 years, effective October 25, 2007.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
