<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1201280402" ordinal="40" title="CONGRATULATING THE UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA AT BERKELEY MEN'S WATER POLO TEAM">
  <narrative>CONGRATULATING THE UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA AT BERKELEY MEN'S WATER POLO TEAM -- (Senate - January 25, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="366">S366</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the consideration of <bill type="sr" number="427">S. Res. 427</bill>, submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="427">S. Res. 427</bill>) congratulating the University of California at Berkeley men's water polo team for winning the 2007 National Collegiate Athletic Association Division I Championship.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution and preamble be agreed to en bloc, the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table, with no intervening action, and that any statements relating to the resolution be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="427">S. Res. 427</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="427">S. Res. 427</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas the University of California at Berkeley (California) Golden Bears won the 2007 National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA) Men's Water Polo Championship, 8-6, over the University of Southern California Trojans on December 2, 2007, at the Avery Aquatics Center at Stanford University;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the California Golden Bears had a 28-4 overall record during the 2007 season;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas in 2007 the California Golden Bears won a Division I men's water polo title for the 2nd year in a row and the 13th time in school history;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Michael Sharf was named the 2007 NCAA Tournament Most Valuable Player, Zac Monsees, and Jeff Tyrrell were named to the NCAA Tournament 1st team, and Spencer Warden was named to the NCAA Tournament 2nd team; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Michael Sharf, Zac Monsees, and Mark Sheredy were named as first-team All-Americans, Adam Haley was named a second-team All-American, and Jeff Tyrrell and Spencer Warden were selected as third-team All-Americans for their exceptional contributions during the 2007 season: Now, therefore, be it</chair>
  <chair> Resolved, That the Senate congratulates the University of California at Berkeley men's water polo team for winning the 2007 National Collegiate Athletic Association Division I Championship. &lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
