<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1194973204" ordinal="39" title="TRIBUTE TO FATHER BONIFACE HARDIN AND SISTER JANE SCHILLING">
  <narrative>TRIBUTE TO FATHER BONIFACE HARDIN AND SISTER JANE SCHILLING -- (Senate - November 13, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="14281">S14281</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300070" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today I pay tribute to two Hoosiers who have touched the Indianapolis community and the world through their tireless leadership and commitment to the positive effect that education can have on both individuals and the communities in which they live. Over the years I have admired Father Boniface Hardin and Sister Jane Schilling for their dedication to both their religious calling as well as the more temporal needs of our communities as they worked to fight racial injustice  and poverty through education and empowerment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1977, Father Hardin and Sister Jane founded Martin University, an institution dedicated to serving low-income, minority, and adult learners,  while at the same time welcoming students of all backgrounds. In the ensuing 30 years, Martin University has changed the lives of thousands of students. It has grown from a converted church and school to a beautiful campus in the Martindale-Brightwood neighborhood of Indianapolis that serves as a tremendous  resource to both faculty and students as well as the surrounding community.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As Father Hardin and Sister Jane step down as president and vice president of Martin University, I am hopeful that you will join me, the board of trustees, faculty, staff, students, alumni, and friends of the university in congratulating them on their many years of service to the people of Indianapolis. I wish them both every continuing success as they pursue new and exciting opportunities to offer important service to many more of the people they have dedicated their lives to helping.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
