<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1184299200" ordinal="33" title="NATIONAL SUMMER LEARNING DAY">
  <narrative>NATIONAL SUMMER LEARNING DAY -- (Senate - July 13, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="9224">S9224</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Judiciary Committee be discharged from further consideration of <bill type="sr" number="268">S. Res. 268</bill>, and that the Senate then proceed to its consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered. The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="268">S. Res. 268</bill>) designating July 12, 2007, as "National Summer Learning Day."</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table, en bloc, and that any statements relating to the resolution be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="268">S. Res. 268</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="268">S. Res. 268</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas all students experience a measurable loss of mathematics and reading skills when they do not engage in educational activities during the summer months;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas summer learning loss is greatest for low-income children, who often lack the academic enrichment opportunities available to their more affluent peers;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas recent research indicates that  2/3  of the achievement gap between low-income children and their more affluent peers can be explained by unequal access to summer learning opportunities, which results in low-income youth being less likely to graduate from high school or enter college;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas recent surveys indicate that low-income parents have considerable difficulty finding available summer opportunities for their children;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas structured enrichment and education programs are proven to accelerate learning for students who participate in such programs for several weeks during the summer;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas students who participate in the Building Educated Leaders for Life ("BELL") summer programs gain several months' worth of reading and mathematics skills through summer enrichment, and students who regularly attend the Teach Baltimore Summer Academy for 2 summers are  1/2  year ahead of their peers in reading skills;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas thousands of students in similar programs make measurable gains in academic achievement;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas recent research demonstrates that most children, particularly children at high risk of obesity, gain weight more rapidly when they are out of school during the summer;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Summer Learning Day is designed to highlight the need for more young people to be engaged in summer learning activities and to support local summer programs that benefit children, families, and communities;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas a wide array of schools, public agencies, nonprofit organizations, universities, museums, libraries, and summer camps in many States across the United States, will celebrate annual Summer Learning Day on July 12, 2007: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) designates July 12, 2007, as "National Summer Learning Day", in order to raise public awareness about the positive impact of summer learning opportunities on the development and educational success of the children of our Nation;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) urges the people of the United States to promote summer learning activities, in order to send young people back to school ready to learn, to support working parents and their children, and to keep the children of our Nation safe and healthy during the summer months; and</chair>
  <chair> (3) urges communities to celebrate, with appropriate ceremonies and activities, the importance of high quality summer learning opportunities in the lives of young students and their families.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
