<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1216310404" ordinal="59" title="NOTICE OF HEARING">
  <narrative>NOTICE OF HEARING -- (Senate - July 17, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="6945">S6945</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND NATURAL RESOURCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to announce for the information of the Senate and the public that a hearing has been scheduled before the Subcommittee on National Parks. The hearing will be held on Wednesday, July 30, 2008, at 2:30 p.m., in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the hearing is to receive testimony on the following bills: <bill type="s" number="1816">S. 1816</bill>, to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to establish a commemorative trail in connection with the Women's Rights National Historical Park to link properties that are historically and thematically associated with the struggle for women's suffrage, and for other purposes; <bill type="s" number="2093">S. 2093</bill>, to amend the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate a segment of the Missisquoi and Trout Rivers in the State of Vermont for study  for potential addition to the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System; <bill type="s" number="2535">S. 2535</bill>, to revise the boundary of the Martin Van Buren National Historic Site, and for other purposes; <bill type="s" number="2561">S. 2561</bill>, to require the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a theme study to identify sites and resources to commemorate and interpret the Cold War; <bill type="s" number="3011">S. 3011</bill>, to amend the Palo Alto Battlefield National Historic Site Act of 1991 to expand the boundaries of the historic site, and for other purposes; <bill type="s" number="3113">S. 3113</bill>, to reinstate the Interim Management Strategy governing off-road vehicle use in the Cape Hatteras National Seashore, North Carolina, pending the</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of the limited time available for the hearing, witnesses may testify by invitation only. However, those wishing to submit written testimony for the hearing record should send it to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, United States Senate, Washington, DC 20510-6150, or by email to rachel</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For further information, please contact David Brooks at (202) 224-9863 or Rachel Pasternack at (202) 224-0883.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
