<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1193932801" ordinal="60" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <narrative>AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET -- (Senate - November 01, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="13713">S13713</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400272" topic="COMMITTEE ON FINANCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Finance be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, November 1, 2007, at 10 a.m., in room 215 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building, in order to consider pending nominations.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400272" topic="COMMITTEE ON HEALTH, EDUCATION, LABOR, AND PENSIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions be authorized to meet during the Session of the Senate in order to conduct a hearing on the nominations of Gregory Jacob, of New Jersey, to be Solicitor of Labor for the U.S. Department of Labor, and the nomination of Howard Radzely, of Maryland, to be Deputy Secretary of Labor for the U.S. Department of Labor. The hearing will commence on Thursday, November 1, 2007, at 10 a.m. in  room 430 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400272" topic="COMMITTEE ON INDIAN AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Indian Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, November 1, 2007, at 9:30 a.m. in room 628 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building in order to conduct an oversight hearing on the Impact of the Flood Control Act of 1944 on Indian Tribes along the Missouri River.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400272" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate in order to conduct an Executive Business Meeting on Thursday, November 1,2007, at 10 a.m. in room SD-226 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Agenda</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I. Bills: <bill type="s" number="1946">S. 1946</bill>, Public Corruption Prosecution Improvements Act (Leahy, Cornyn, Sessions); <bill type="s" number="2168">S. 2168</bill>, Identity Theft Enforcement and Restitution Act (Leahy, Specter, Durbin, Grassley); and <bill type="s" number="352">S. 352</bill>, Sunshine in the Courtroom Act of 2007 (Grassley, Schumer, Leahy, Specter, Graham, Feingold, Cornyn, Durbin).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>II. Nominations: John Daniel Tinder, to be United States Circuit Judge for the Seventh Circuit and Julie L. Myers, of Kansas, to be an Assistant Secretary of Homeland Security.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400272" topic="SELECT COMMITTEE ON INTELLIGENCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Select Committee on Intelligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on November 1, 2007 at 2:30 p.m. in order to hold a closed hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400272" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON FEDERAL FINANCIAL MANAGEMENT, GOVERNMENT INFORMATION, FEDERAL SERVICES, AND INTERNATIONAL SECURITY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Governmental Affairs' Subcommittee on Federal Financial Management, Government Information, Federal Services, and International Security be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, November 1, 2007, at 2 p.m. in order to conduct a hearing entitled "Small Business Administration: Is the 7 (a) Program Achieving Measurable Outcomes?"</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400272" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON PRIVATE SECTOR AND CONSUMER SOLUTIONS TO GLOBAL WARMING AND WILDLIFE PROTECTION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Environment and Public Works, Subcommittee on Private Sector and Consumer Solutions to Global Warming and Wildlife Protection, be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, November 1, 2007, at 9 a.m. in room 406 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building in order to hold a business meeting to consider the America's Climate Security Act of 2007, <bill type="s" number="2191">S. 2191</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON PRIVATE SECTOR AND CONSUMER SOLUTIONS TO GLOBAL WARMING AND WILDLIFE PROTECTION">
    <paragraph>I note the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <chair>The legislative clerk proceeded to call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON PRIVATE SECTOR AND CONSUMER SOLUTIONS TO GLOBAL WARMING AND WILDLIFE PROTECTION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
