<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1193414402" ordinal="34" title="NATIONAL BE BEAR AWARE AND WILDLIFE STEWARDSHIP MONTH">
  <narrative>NATIONAL BE BEAR AWARE AND WILDLIFE STEWARDSHIP MONTH -- (Senate - October 26, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="13494">S13494</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="EXPRESSING SYMPATHY FOR THE VICTIMS OF THUNDERSTORMS IN ILLINOIS, IOWA, MINNESOTA, OHIO AND WISCONSIN">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed en bloc to the consideration of the following Calendar items: No. 444 and No. 445.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered. The clerk will report the resolutions by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="347">S. Res. 347</bill>) designating May 2008 as "National Be Bear Aware and Wildlife Stewardship Month".</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="346">S. Res. 346</bill>) expressing heartfelt sympathy for the victims of the devastating thunderstorms that caused severe flooding during August 2007 in the States of Illinois, Iowa, Minnesota, Ohio, and Wisconsin, and for other purposes.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolutions.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="EXPRESSING SYMPATHY FOR THE VICTIMS OF THUNDERSTORMS IN ILLINOIS, IOWA, MINNESOTA, OHIO AND WISCONSIN">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the amendment to the resolution, where applicable, be agreed to; that the resolutions, as amended, if amended, be agreed to en bloc; the amendment to the preamble, where applicable, be agreed to; the preambles, as amended, if amended, be agreed to, en bloc; that the title amendment to <bill type="sr" number="346">S. Res. 346</bill> be agreed to and the motions to reconsider be laid on the table, en bloc, the consideration of these items appear separately in the Record, and any statements  be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="347">S. Res. 347</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="347">S. Res. 347</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas wildlife and wildlife viewing enrich the shared outdoor heritage of the people of the United States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas it is possible to enjoy wildlife in a way that is prudent, safe, and educational and that has minimal adverse effects on wildlife;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the people of the United States should be aware of the potential for conflict between humans and wildlife;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the people of the United States should learn the safety and stewardship techniques that can prevent such conflicts;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas some groups, such as the Center for Wildlife Information and State and Federal wildlife associations, in cooperation with State and Federal wildlife and land management agencies, have taken important proactive steps to create educations toolkits and design programs to educate outdoor enthusiasts; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas educational efforts can raise awareness of the potential for such conflict, help minimize such conflict, and promote the responsible enjoyment of wildlife: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate designates May 2008 as "National Be Bear Aware and Wildlife Stewardship Month".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;S. RES. 346</chair>
  <chair>The Senate proceed to consider the resolution (<bill type="sr" number="346">S. Res. 346</bill>) expressing heartfelt sympathy for the victims of the devastating thunderstorms that caused severe flooding during August 2007 in the States of Illinois, Iowa, Minnesota, Ohio, and Wisconsin, and for other purposes, which had been reported from the Committee on the Judiciary with an amendment and an amendment to the preamble.</chair>
  <chair>[Strike the preamble and insert the part printed in italic]</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="346">S. Res. 346</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>[Whereas, during August 2007, severe thunderstorms were responsible for bringing as much as 18 inches of torrential rain to parts of the States of Illinois, Iowa, Minnesota, Ohio, and Wisconsin, resulting in devastating floods;</chair>
  <chair>[Whereas these storms tragically took the lives of 14 people;</chair>
  <chair>[Whereas these storms injured countless other people, damaged or destroyed thousands of homes, and devastated businesses and institutions;</chair>
  <chair>[Whereas, on August 21, 2007, the Governor of Minnesota declared Fillmore, Houston, Steele, Olmsted, Wabasha, and Winona Counties, Minnesota, to be in a state of disaster as a result of these storms, and subsequently Dodge and Jackson Counties, Minnesota, received a Federal major disaster declaration as well;</chair>
  <chair>[Whereas, on August 20 and 21, 2007, the Governor of Wisconsin declared Crawford, La Crosse, Richland, Sauk, and Vernon Counties, Wisconsin, to be in a state of disaster as a result of these storms;</chair>
  <chair>[Whereas, on August 22, 2007, and in the days following, the Governor of Iowa declared Allamakee, Appanoose, Boone, Calhoun, Cherokee, Davis, Humboldt, Mahaska, Montgomery, Palo Alto, Pocahontas, Union, Van Buren, Wapello, Wayne, Webster, and Winneshiek Counties, Iowa, to be in a state of disaster as a result of these storms;</chair>
  <chair>[Whereas, on August 22, 2007, the Governor of Ohio declared Allen, Crawford, Hancock, Hardin, Putnam, Richland, Seneca, Van Wert, and Wyandot Counties, Ohio, to be in a state of disaster as a result of these storms;</chair>
  <chair>[Whereas, on August 24, 2007, and in the days following, the Governor of Illinois declared Cook, DeKalb, DuPage, Grundy, Lake, LaSalle, Kane, Knox, McHenry, Warren, and Will Counties, Illinois, to be in a state of disaster as a result of these storms;</chair>
  <chair>[Whereas President Bush declared 8 counties in Minnesota, 8 counties in Ohio, 14 counties in Wisconsin, 6 counties in Illinois, and 14 counties in Iowa to be major disaster areas as a result of these storms, and individuals and families, State and local Governments, and certain private nonprofit organizations in these areas became eligible for individual or public Federal disaster assistance or both;</chair>
  <chair>[Whereas numerous individuals and entities have selflessly and heroically given of themselves and their resources to aid in the disaster relief efforts; and</chair>
  <chair>[Whereas the catastrophic injury, death, and damage in Illinois, Iowa, Minnesota, Ohio, and Wisconsin would have been even worse in the absence of local relief efforts: Now, therefore, be it]</chair>
  <chair>Whereas, during August 2007, severe thunderstorms were responsible for bringing as much as 18 inches of torrential rain to parts of the States of Illinois, Iowa, Minnesota, Ohio, Oklahoma, and Wisconsin, resulting in devastating floods;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas these storms tragically took the lives of at least 20 people;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas these storms injured countless other people, damaged or destroyed thousands of homes, and devastated businesses and institutions;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, on August 20, 2007, the Governor of Oklahoma declared Blaine, Caddo, Canadian, Cleveland, Comanche, Cotton, Custer, Dewey, Grady, Jefferson, Kingfisher, Kiowa, Lincoln, Logan, McClain, Muskogee, Okfuskee, Oklahoma, Okmulgee, Pontotoc, Pottawatomie, Seminole, Stephens, and Washita Counties, Oklahoma, to be in a state of emergency as a result of these storms;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, on August 21, 2007, the Governor of Minnesota declared Fillmore, Houston, Steele, Olmsted, Wabasha, and Winona Counties, Minnesota, to be in a state of disaster as a result of these storms, and subsequently Dodge and Jackson Counties, Minnesota, received a Federal major disaster declaration as well; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, on August 20 and 21, 2007, the Governor of Wisconsin declared Crawford, La Crosse, Richland, Sauk, and Vernon Counties, Wisconsin, to be in a state of disaster as a result of these storms;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, on August 22, 2007, and in the days following, the Governor of Iowa declared Allamakee, Appanoose, Boone, Calhoun, Cherokee, Davis, Humboldt, Mahaska, Montgomery, Palo Alto, Pocahontas, Union, Van Buren, Wapello, Wayne, Webster, and Winneshiek Counties, Iowa, to be in a state of disaster as a result of these storms;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, on August 22, 2007, the Governor of Ohio declared Allen, Crawford, Hancock, Hardin, Putnam, Richland, Seneca, Van Wert, and Wyandot Counties, Ohio, to be in a state of disaster as a result of these storms;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, on August 24, 2007, and in the days following, the Governor of Illinois declared Cook, DeKalb, DuPage, Grundy, Lake, LaSalle, Kane, Knox, McHenry, Warren, and Will Counties, Illinois, to be in a state of disaster as a result of these storms;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas President Bush declared 8 counties in Minnesota, 8 counties in Ohio, 22 counties in Oklahoma, 14 counties in Wisconsin, 6 counties in Illinois, and 14 counties in Iowa to be major disaster areas as a result of these storms, and individuals and families, State and local Governments, and certain private nonprofit organizations in these areas became eligible for individual or public Federal disaster assistance or both;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas numerous individuals and entities have selflessly and heroically given of themselves and their resources to aid in the disaster relief efforts; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the catastrophic injury, death, and damage in Illinois, Iowa, Minnesota, Ohio, Oklahoma, and Wisconsin would have been even worse in the absence of local relief efforts: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) expresses heartfelt sympathy for the victims of the devastating thunderstorms that caused severe flooding during August 2007 in the States of Illinois, Iowa, Minnesota, Ohio, [Oklahoma,] and Wisconsin;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) conveys gratitude to the local, State, and Federal officials and emergency personnel who responded swiftly to the crisis, including emergency management teams in each of the affected States, Michael Chertoff, Secretary of Homeland Security, and David Paulison, Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) recognizes the generous and selfless support of citizens, local businesses, the American Red Cross, the United Way, Catholic Charities, and the Salvation Army; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) reaffirms support for helping the victims of the flooding rebuild their homes and lives.</chair>
  <chair>The amendment (No. 3471) was agreed to, as follows:</chair>
  <chair>AMENDMENT NO. 3471&lt;center&gt;(Purpose: To amend the title of the resolution)&lt;/center&gt;</chair>
  <chair> Amend the title to read as follows: "Expressing heartfelt sympathy for the victims of the devastating thunderstorms that caused severe flooding during August 2007 in the States of Illinois, Iowa, Minnesota, Ohio, Oklahoma, and Wisconsin, and for other purposes."&lt;p&gt;</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="346">S. Res. 346</bill>), as amended, was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The amendment to the preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble, as amended, was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, as amended, with its preamble, as amended, reads as follows:</chair>
  <narrative>(The resolution will be printed in a future edition of the RECORD.)</narrative>
</record>
