<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1185854400" ordinal="49" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <narrative>AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET -- (Senate - July 31, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="10523">S10523</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300100" topic="COMMITTEE ON ARMED SERVICES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on July 31, 2007, at 9:30 a.m., in open session (and possibly closed session) to consider the following nominations:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Admiral Michael G. Mullen, USN for reappointment to the grade of Admiral and to be Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff; and General James E. Cartwright, USMC for reappointment to the grade of General and to be Vice Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300100" topic="COMMITTEE ON BANKING, HOUSING, AND URBAN AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on July 31, 2007, at 9:30 a.m., to conduct a hearing entitled "The State of the Securities Markets."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300100" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, July 31, 2007, at 10 a.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The hearing is on the nominations of Vice Admiral Thomas J. Barrett, USCG (Ret.), to be Deputy Secretary, U.S. Department of Transportation, Mr. Ronald Spoehel, to be Chief Financial Officer, National Aeronautics and Space Administration, Rear Admiral William G. Sutton, Jr., USN (Ret.), to be Assistant Secretary of Commerce, U.S. Department of Commerce, and Mr. Paul R. Brubaker, to be Administrator of the Research and Innovative Technology Administration, U.S. Department of Transportation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300100" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, July 31, 2007, at 2:30 p.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of this hearing is to examine three major consumer protection and fraud prevention issues under the jurisdiction of the Federal Trade Commission: 1. The effectiveness of the national Do-Not-Call registry and current legislative proposals to improve the Do-Not-Call Implementation Act of 2003; 2. The effectiveness of CROA and possible legislative initiatives to clarify the language of the act; and 3. Telemarketing fraud, particularly against older Americans.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300100" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND NATIONAL RESOURCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, July 31, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building. The purpose of this hearing is to receive testimony on renewable fuels infrastructure.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300100" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENVIRONMENT AND PUBLIC WORKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Environment and Public Works be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, July 31, 2007, at 9:30 a.m. in room 406 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building, in order to conduct a business meeting.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The meeting will consider the following agenda:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Bill to reauthorize the provision of technical assistance to small public water systems, <bill type="s" number="1429">S. 1429</bill>; Ban Asbestos in America Act, <bill type="s" number="742">S. 742</bill>; Toxic Right to Know Protection Act, <bill type="s" number="595">S. 595</bill>; California waiver decision deadline bill, <bill type="s" number="1785">S. 1785</bill>; National Infrastructure Improvement Act, <bill type="s" number="775">S. 775</bill>; The Multinational Species Conservation Funds reauthorizations, <bill type="h" number="5">HR 5</bill>O and <bill type="h" number="465">HR 465</bill>; The Captive Primate Safety Act, <bill type="s" number="1498">S. 1498</bill>; U.S. Army Corps of Engineers Resolutions; Nomination of Robert Lyle Laverty to be Assistant Secretary  for Fish, Wildlife, and Parks, U.S. Department of the Interior; Nomination of Robert Lance Boldrey nominee for reappointment to the Board of Trustees for the Morris K. Udall Scholarship and Excellence in National Environmental Policy Foundation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300100" topic="COMMITTEE ON FINANCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Finance be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, July 31, 2007, at 10 a.m., in room 215 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building, to hear testimony on "Carried Interest, Part II."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300100" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, July 31, 2007, at 9:30 a.m. in order to hold a hearing on nuclear energy and nonproliferation challenges.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300100" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet in order to conduct a hearing entitled "Evaluating the Propriety and Adequacy of the Oxycontin Criminal Settlement" on Tuesday, July 31, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. in the Dirksen Senate Office Building room 226.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Panel I: John L. Brownlee, United States Attorney, Western District of Virginia, Roanoke, VA;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Panel II: Marianne Skolek, LPN, Myrtle Beach, SC; Vikramaditya Khanna, Professor of Law, University of Michigan Law School, Ann Arbor, MI; Sidney M. Wolfe, M.D., Director, Public Citizen's Health Research Group, Washington, DC; Virginia Pagano, Police Officer, Philadelphia Police Department, Narcotics Bureau, Philadelphia, PA; Jay P. McCloskey, Former U.S. Attorney, Maine, McCloskey, Mina, Cunniff &amp; Dilworth, LLC, Portland, ME; James Campbell, M.D., Professor of Neurosurgery, Johns Hopkins Hospital,  Baltimore, MD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300100" topic="COMMITTEE ON VETERANS' AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Veterans' Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, July 31, to conduct a hearing on DoD/VA collaboration and cooperation and the education needs of returning service members. The committee will meet in Dirksen 562, at 9:30 a.m.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300100" topic="SELECT COMMITTEE ON INTELLIGENCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Select Committee on Intelligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on July 31, 2007 at 2:30 p.m. to hold a closed hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300100" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON ANTITRUST, COMPETITION POLICY, AND CONSUMER RIGHTS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on the Judiciary Subcommittee on Antitrust, Competition Policy and Consumer Rights be authorized to meet on Tuesday, July 31, 2007 at 10 a.m. in order to conduct a hearing entitled "The Leegin Decision: the end of the consumer discounts or good antitrust policy" in room 226 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Witness list: Pamela Jones Harbour, Commissioner, Federal Trade Commission Washington, DC; Robert Pitofsky, Sheehy Professor of Antitrust Law and Regulation, Georgetown University Law School, Washington, DC; Marcy Syms, Chief Executive Officer, SYMS, Secaucus, NJ; Stephan Bolerjack, Attorney at Law, Dykema Gossett PLLC, Representing the National Association of Manufacturers, Detroit, MI; and Janet L. McDavid, Attorney at Law, Hogan &amp; Hartson, Washington, DC.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
