<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1171386003" ordinal="36" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="COMMITTEE ON AGRICULTURE, NUTRITION, AND FORESTRY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition and Forestry be authorized to conduct a hearing during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, February 13, 2007, at 9:45 a.m. in 328A, Russell Senate Office Building. The purpose of this committee hearing will be to consider "Rural Development--Challenges and Opportunities."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold a business meeting during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, February 13, 2007, at 10 a.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of this meeting will be to consider and approve the following legislation following bills: <bill type="s" number="184">S. 184</bill>, <bill type="s" number="509">S. 509</bill>, <bill type="s" number="385">S. 385</bill>, <bill type="s" number="93">S. 93</bill>, <bill type="s" number="84">S. 84</bill>, <bill type="s" number="39">S. 39</bill>, and to make nominations for promotion in the United States Coast Guard.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND NATURAL RESOURCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, February 13, 2007, at 10 a.m. in room SD-106 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the hearing is to receive testimony on the Stern Review of the Economics of Climate Change, examining the economic impacts of climate change and stabilizing greenhouse gases in the atmosphere.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENVIRONMENT AND PUBLIC WORKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Environment and Public Works be authorized to meet for a hearing on Tuesday, February 12, 2007, at 10 a.m. in SD-106. The purpose of the hearing is to review the report and recommendations of the U.S. Climate Action Partnership.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="COMMITTEE ON HEALTH, EDUCATION, LABOR, AND PENSIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, February 13, 2007, at 10 a.m. in SD-430.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="COMMITTEE ON HOMELAND SECURITY AND GOVERNMENTAL AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs be authorized to meet on Tuesday, February 13, 2007, at 10 a.m. for a hearing titled "The Homeland Security Department's Budget Submission for Fiscal Year 2008."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="COMMITTEE ON SMALL BUSINESS AND ENTREPRENEURSHIP">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate for a hearing entitled "Alternatives for Easing the Small Business Health Care Burden," on Tuesday, February 13, 2007, beginning at 10 a.m. in room 428A of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="COMMITTEE ON VETERANS' AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Veterans' Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, February 13, 2007, to hold a hearing on Veterans Programs for Fiscal Year 2008.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The hearing will take place in room 418 of the Russell Senate Office Building beginning at 9:30 a.m.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="SELECT COMMITTEE ON INTELLIGENCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Intelligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on February 13, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. to hold a closed hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
