<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1179158403" ordinal="23" title="STATEMENTS ON INTRODUCED BILLS AND JOINT RESOLUTIONS">
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="Introducing S. 1376. A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to revise and expand the drug discount program under section 340B of such Act to improve the provision of discounts on drug purchases for certain safety net providers; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1376">S. 1376</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to introduce legislation with my colleague from South Dakota, Senator THUNE, designed to address the growing burden faced by this Nation's health care safety net institutions in being able to provide adequate pharmaceutical care to the most vulnerable patient populations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Communities across the country rely on public and nonprofit hospitals to serve as the health care "safety net" for low-income, uninsured, and underinsured patients. With the ever-increasing cost of pharmaceuticals, these institutions are struggling more and more to provide basic pharmaceutical care to those least able to afford it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Fortunately, many safety net hospitals are currently able to participate in the Federal 340B Drug Discount Program, which enables them to purchase outpatient drugs for their patients at discounted prices. These hospitals, known as "covered entities" under the 340B statute, include high-Medicaid disproportionate share hospitals, DSH, large and small urban hospitals, and certain rural hospitals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am introducing legislation today, the 340B Program Improvement and Integrity Act of 2007, which would extend discounted drug prices currently mandated only for outpatient drugs to inpatient drugs purchased by covered entities under the 340B program. Although the Medicare Modernization Act, MMA, of 2003 permitted pharmaceutical manufacturers to offer 340B drug discounts to covered entities, this legislation did not include a mandate. Without a mandate we have seen very little willingness on  the part of manufactures to offer 340B drug discounts for inpatient drugs. As the prices of pharmaceutical drugs continue to increase sharply, the need for these inpatient discounts grows more and more acute.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My legislation would also expand participation in the program to a subset of rural hospitals that, for a variety of reasons, cannot currently access 340B discounts. These newly eligible rural hospitals include critical access hospitals, sole community hospitals, and rural referral centers. In proposing this modest expansion to the program, we have struck an important balance between ensuring a close nexus with low-income and indigent care, ensured that a significant portion of savings is passed  on to the Medicaid Program, and strengthened the integrity of the program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Specifically, newly eligible rural hospitals would have to meet appropriate standards demonstrating their "safety net" status, as do all hospitals that currently participate in the program. For example, sole community hospitals and rural referral centers, all of which are paid under the prospective payment system, would be required under this legislation to serve a significant percentage of low-income and indigent patients, have public or nonprofit status, and, if privately owned and operated,  to have a contract with State or local government to provide a significant level of indigent care. All standards are designed to reinforce the obligation of these covered entities to continue serving low-income and uninsured patients.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation would also generate savings for the Medicaid Program by requiring participating hospitals to credit to their Medicaid agencies a significant percentage of their savings on inpatient drugs. It would address the overall efficiency and integrity of the 340B program through improved enforcement and compliance measures with respect to manufacturers and covered entities. This is designed to improve program administration and to prevent and remedy instances of program abuse.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the end, this legislation would accomplish several important goals. It would help safety net providers stretch their already limited resources through increased access to discounted pharmaceuticals; it would enhance 340B program integrity by making sure participants are complying with program rules; and it would help to improve the care provided to this Nation's most vulnerable populations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to cosponsor this important legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="Introducing S. 1377. A bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior to convey to the City of Henderson, Nevada, certain Federal land located in the City, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1377">S. 1377</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today for myself and Senator ENSIGN to introduce the Southern Nevada Limited Transition Area Act. This bill will allow one of Nevada's fastest growing communities to diversify its economy, to create space for important small businesses and parks, and to encourage appropriate development around an urban airport.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation was first introduced in the 108th Congress. Its purpose is to convey approximately 502 acres of land from the Bureau of Land Management to the city of Henderson, NV, for the development of an employment and business center and urban green spaces. The parcels are located just west and south of the Henderson Executive Airport.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Bureau of Land Management has designated these parcels for disposal because of the urban surroundings, which renders them difficult for the agency to manage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation will enhance the ability of a rapidly growing community to diversify its economy, gainfully employ its residents, and encourage proper land use. The parcels are located in a fast growing area of the city, but are impacted by aircraft noise and overflights from the nearby Henderson Executive Airport. This makes the property unsuitable for residential use. But rather than shying away from it because of the limitations on its use, the city of Henderson has put together a forward-looking  plan that will turn the area into a bustling business center.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Once the Bureau of Land Management conveys the land to Henderson, the city would then sell, lease or otherwise convey subdivided lots at fair market value. Consistent with the Southern Nevada Public Land Management Act, 85 percent of the proceeds would then return to the BLM's Special Account for a variety of conservation purposes in Nevada, 10 percent will go towards community water developments, and 5 percent will support the State of Nevada's general education program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The city of Henderson's leaders are dedicated to making the city a national model of logical development, diversified employment, and fiscal sustainability. This bill helps establish the conditions needed to realize that vision. In addition to productively diversifying the land use pattern in the Las Vegas Valley, the proposed development of this land will encourage a broad range of employment opportunities for the region, while also helping to pay for public infrastructure in nearby residential  areas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I greatly appreciated the hearing that the Energy and Natural Resources Committee had on this bill last Congress. At that hearing, the Department of the Interior and others expressed strong support for our legislation. A few minor revisions were requested by the administration, and I have incorporated those changes into the bill we are introducing today. I look forward to working with the committee to move this legislation in an expeditious manner during this Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="Introducing S. 1379. A bill to amend chapter 35 of title 28, United States Code, to strike the exception to the residency requirements for United States attorneys; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1379">S. 1379</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to introduce the U.S. Attorney Local Residency Restoration Act along with Senators Schumer, Baucus, and Tester.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Simply put, this legislation would eliminate the other language that the Department of Justice had inserted into the PATRIOT Act reauthorization dealing with U.S. attorneys.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The first provision added allowed the Attorney General to appoint interim U.S. attorneys to vacancies indefinitely without Senate confirmation, and I authored a bill to restore the law to require interim appointments by the Attorney General for only 120 days, and then the district courts can appoint the interim U.S. attorney if a permanent replacement has not been nominated and confirmed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill has passed this body, and I hope will be signed into law soon.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, I am offering this legislation to restore the residency requirement for sitting U.S. attorneys.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Before the change, the law required that U.S. attorneys live within his district while serving. It seems logical that the U.S. attorney should live in the district that he is heading.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, the Department of Justice added language in the PATRIOT Act reauthorization that allows a U.S. attorney to live outside of his district if the Attorney General assigns dual or additional responsibilities to him.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While U.S. attorneys in both Democratic and Republican administrations have served dual roles in the past, this administration has once again abused its new authority--this time by placing numerous U.S. attorneys in full-time positions throughout the Department of Justice, at times in a manner that allows the Department to avoid Senate confirmation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In fact, Dennis Boyd, executive director of the National Association of Assistant U.S. Attorneys, which represents current Federal prosecutors, has said, "I can't think of a time when there's been this many U.S. attorneys doing double duty at one time."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Currently, there are several U.S. attorneys, that we know about, who are serving in a second full-time position here in Washington, while still retaining their responsibilities back in their districts. For example, Michael J. Sullivan, the U.S. attorney in Boston, has been serving as the Acting Director of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives in Washington for the past 6 months, a position that requires Senate confirmation;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mary Beth Buchanan, U.S. attorney in Pittsburgh, is also the acting director of the Office of Violence Against Women, a position that requires Senate confirmation, and prior to that she served as Director of the Executive Office of U.S. Attorneys; and Kevin O'Connor, U.S. attorney in Connecticut, is also serving as an Associate Deputy Attorney General coordinating antigang policies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Of course, the most well-known example is William Mercer, U.S. attorney in Montana. Mr. Mercer has been effectively absent for nearly 2 years from his State. First, serving as Principal Associate Deputy Attorney General, and now working as Acting Associate Attorney General, another position that requires Senate confirmation. In fact, through staff interviews we have learned that he is only in his State 3 or 4 days a month.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Moreover, his consistent absenteeism was having such a negative effect on the district that it led to the point where U.S. District Chief Judge Donald Molloy of Billings, MT, felt compelled to write to the Attorney General on October 20, 2005, to complain. In that letter, Chief Judge Molloy wrote that Mr. Mercer's dual roles have led to "a lack of leadership" in the Montana office and created "untoward difficulties for the court" and for career prosecutors. Chief Judge Molloy also wrote that  Mr. Mercer was violating Federal law because he "no longer resides in Montana" and instead was living with his family in the Washington, DC, area.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These facts on their own are cause for alarm.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, what is even more disconcerting is the way that Mr. Mercer and the Department of Justice have handled this situation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We know that the Attorney General responded to Chief Judge Molloy in a letter on November 10, 2005, stating that Mr. Mercer "is in compliance with the residency requirement" under Federal law because he "is domiciled in Montana, returns there on a regular basis, and will live there full-time as soon as his temporary assignment is completed."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We also know through interviews of DOJ staff that Mr. Mercer worked with Will Moschella and Senate staff during November 2005 to insert the residency exemption language into the PATRIOT Act reauthorization.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In fact, according to the Washington Post, the response from the Attorney General to Chief Judge Molloy occurred on the very same day that DOJ asked for the language to be inserted into the PATRIOT Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>All this resulted in a change in the law, thus eviscerating the conflict.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, even beyond this turn of events, what is truly breathtaking about this administration's actions with regard to Mr. Mercer is that in trying to defend its actions to force numerous U.S. attorneys to resign from office, this same Justice Department criticized David Iglesias for being "an absentee landlord."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I firmly believe, what is sauce for the goose is sauce for the gander. You can't one day try to change the law to make it easier for U.S. attorneys to serve in 2 full-time jobs at the same time and then the next day fire someone for not being fully present in his job, especially when the absence is much more limited and based on service to the country in the naval reserves.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While there are times when U.S. attorneys may be relied upon to fill in temporarily, changing the law to ensure that they can hold two full-time jobs is unacceptable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Serving as U.S. attorney is a full-time job, and each district throughout this country deserves to have the best qualified person in the district focused on the tasks at hand.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am quite certain that there are many fine first assistant U.S. attorneys capable of stepping up to fill the shoes of an absent U.S. attorney; however, these are not the individuals the President has nominated and the Senate has confirmed to serve those positions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These districts deserve nothing less than the undivided attention of their Senate-confirmed U.S. attorneys.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300003" topic="Introducing S. 1380. A bill to designate as wilderness certain land within the Rocky Mountain National Park and to adjust the boundaries of the Indian Peaks Wilderness and the Arapaho National Recreation Area of the Arapaho National Forest in the State of Colorado; to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1380">S. 1380</bill>] Mr. President, today I am proud to co-sponsor legislation that  will designate Rocky Mountain National Park as "wilderness."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation will protect an area that was formed millions of years ago when massive glaciers carved an impressive landscape. The Rocky Mountain National Park Wilderness Act will ensure that it remains unchanged in years to come.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today marks the beginning of a new chapter in the long history of the Park. As a fifth generation Coloradan and someone who grew up in the shadow of Rocky Mountain National Park, it is an honor to have worked on this bill. With the introduction of this legislation we continue to follow an important wilderness tradition in Colorado.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Colorado and its representatives have long played an important role in the development of Wilderness in our Nation. This dates back to the original Wilderness Act. Congressman Wayne Aspinall, who represented Colorado's 4th Congressional District and chaired the Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs, played a pivotal role in creating the Nation's wilderness system with the 1964 Wilderness Act. From the inception of the original Wilderness Act through the continued development of wilderness  in Colorado one thing has remained the same: a commitment to working together to find compromise and solutions that work for everyone.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The principle of compromise has held true from the Colorado National Forest Wilderness Act of 1980 to the Spanish Peaks Wilderness Act in 2000, and it is now true with the Rocky Mountain National Park Wilderness Act. I am especially proud of the legislation that my colleagues and I have introduced because it will preserve the natural elements of the Park while protecting water, the West's most valuable resource.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In a time when wells are being shut down just east of the park, the protection of water is more important than ever, and it is vital to preserving the agricultural heritage of this area. I am extremely pleased that we have been able protect both wilderness and water.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to thank everyone that has been involved in the development of this bill, my colleagues in the United States Congress, the local officials that communicated with our offices, and the private citizens that shared their thoughts with us on the creation of this bill. I would specifically like to recognize former Senators Bill Armstrong and Hank Brown, and former Representatives Joe Johnson and David Skaggs. We would not be introducing this legislation today without these efforts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Rocky Mountain National Park Wilderness Act will ensure that Americans, now and in the future, have the ability to enjoy the Park.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="Introducing S. 1382. A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to provide the establishment of an Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Registry; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1382">S. 1382</bill>] Mr. President, I rise to introduce the ALS Registry Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Lou Gehrig brought Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis, ALS, to the public's attention more than 65 years ago and his courage put a human face' on this terrible disease. Each of us has a Lou Gehrig back in our home State, someone who shows great tremendous courage and grace as they wrestle with ALS.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over the years, I have worked closely with the Nevada ALS Association and have met with many Nevadans who have been touched by this devastating illness. One of these Nevadans was a man by the name of Steve Rigazio who was invited to testify before the Labor/HHS/Education Appropriations Subcommittee in May of 2000. Steve was at the height of his career when he was diagnosed with ALS. He worked through the ranks of the Nevada Power Company, the largest utility company in the State, for 16 years  until he became president. He played semi-professional baseball. He also played and coached recreational hockey.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After his diagnosis, Steve continued to show up for work at 6 a.m. for as long as he could. Sadly just 20 months after he testified so movingly before Congress, Steve Rigazio died of ALS on December 27, 2001 at the age of 47. He left behind a family that included a wife, two children and hundreds of friends. The ALS Steve Rigazio Voice of Courage Award was named in his honor as a living testimony to the life of this special man.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Every year approximately 5,600 Americans will learn they have ALS. There is no cure for ALS and there is only one FDA approved drug to specifically treat ALS. That drug only works for 20 percent of patients, and even for them, it merely extends life for a few months.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>ALS has proven particularly hard for scientists and doctors to tackle for a number of reasons. One of those reasons is there is not a centralized place where data on the disease is collected. Currently, there is only a patchwork of data about ALS that does not include the entire U.S. population and only includes limited data for specific purposes, such as to determine the relationship between military service and the disease. Perhaps the most obvious example of the limitations of current surveillance  systems and registries is that we do not know with certainty how many people are living with ALS in the United States today. Over 136 years after the discovery of ALS, estimates on its prevalence still vary by as much as 100 percent, from a low of about 15,000 patients to as many as thirty 30,000.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation I am introducing today would create an ALS registry at the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, CDC, and will aid in the search for a cure to this devastating disease. The registry will collect data concerning: the incidence and  prevalence of ALS in the U.S.; the environmental and occupational factors that may contribute to the disease; the age, race or ethnicity, gender and family history of individuals diagnosed; and other information essential to the study of ALS.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A national registry will help arm our Nation's researchers and clinicians with the tools and information they need to make progress in the fight against ALS. The data made available by a registry will potentially allow scientists to identify causes of the disease, and maybe even lead to the discovery of new treatment, a cure for ALS, or even a way to prevent the disease in the first place.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I first introduced this legislation in 2005. Since that time, we have appropriated funding to begin work on the development of a National ALS Registry at the CDC. As a result, the CDC has begun pilot proams that will: Develop and test strategies to efficiently identify ALS patients, and (2) determine how to obtain data from existing registries and databases. These pilot programs will help to expedite the development of the registry established by this legislation. This is especially important  considering the life expectancy for a person with ALS is 2 to 5 years from the time of diagnosis.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The establishment of a registry will bring new hope to tens of thousands of patients and their families that ALS will no longer be a death sentence. No one wants to wait another 136 years before a cure is found. I urge my colleagues to support the swift passage of the ALS Registry Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="Introducing S. 1384. A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to repeal authority for adjustments to per diem payments  to homeless veterans service centers for receipt of other sources of income, to extend authorities for certain programs to benefit homeless veterans, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1384">S. 1384</bill>] Mr. President, today I introduce legislation that would enhance and improve services for homeless veterans administered by the Department of Veterans Affairs. This bill addresses a number of areas related to care and benefits for homeless veterans. It would modify the funding mechanism for community-based services to homeless veterans, expand capacity of services for women veterans, and improve outreach to servicemembers who are at risk of becoming homeless.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, this legislation would lift a number of restrictions on VA's grant and per diem program. This program compensates community shelters for the services they provide to homeless veterans. VA currently pays $27 per day to community shelters for each veteran served. However, $27 is barely sufficient to cover existing costs, and rising energy prices are stretching resources even more.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To meet the needs of their clients, many shelters seek additional sources of funding, but their per diem payments from VA are in turn offset by the amount of this additional funding. By eliminating this offset, the bill would enable providers to expand their services to veterans, and to receive funding from other sources to accomplish these expansions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation would also address the gap in domiciliary care for homeless women veterans. Women veterans are a growing proportion of the active duty force and overall veteran population. Homelessness among female veterans is a serious problem, and many facilities do not yet have the capacity to meet this demand. Domiciliary care is an essential component of treatment and rehabilitation, especially for mental health and substance abuse conditions which afflict many homeless veterans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill would require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to ensure that domiciliary programs have the capacity to accommodate women veterans, and that their specific safety and security concerns are addressed. As women become a larger proportion of the homeless veteran population, VA must have the capacity to meet their needs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, this legislation would increase efforts to identify and assist servicemembers who are at risk of becoming homeless. It would make permanent an already established and successful program to aid incarcerated veterans in their transition back to civilian life. The program identifies at risk individuals and refers them to counseling and services, including health care, job training and placement, and housing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Building on the success of that program, the bill would also create a similar program to identify and support at risk individuals in their transition from military to civilian life. It has been proven through smaller scale efforts that this process can reduce the incidence of homelessness and other problems among new veterans who are being separated from military service.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over 1 million servicemembers have served in Iraq and Afghanistan, and as they transition from military service to civilian life some will be at risk of homelessness. Any effort VA can make to assist these servicemembers will improve lives and reduce the demand for VA homeless services in the years to come. We have all heard the sad and shocking statistic that one out of every three homeless persons on the street at any given time is a veteran. This bill is another step in attempting to address  and solve this shameful problem.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe that this bill adjusts existing programs to take full advantage of existing resources and effective initiatives. I urge all of my colleagues to support this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300078" topic="Introducing S. 1385. A bill to designate the United States courthouse facility located at 301 North Miami Avenue, Miami, Florida, as the &quot;C. Clyde Atkins United States Courthouse&quot;; to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1385">S. 1385</bill>] Mr. President, I have introduced a bill that will honor one of Florida's great jurists, the Honorable C. Clyde Atkins, by naming the Federal building at 301 North Miami Avenue in Miami, FL, the "C. Clyde Atkins United States Courthouse." This is a fitting tribute to Judge Atkins. His public service provides a model for members of the legal profession, indeed, for all Americans, who respect the rule of law and believe in equal justice under law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Before becoming a judge, Judge Atkins, who earned his law degree at the University of Florida, already had distinguished himself in private practice. He served as the president of both the Florida bar and the Dade County Bar Association. In 1966, President Johnson appointed Judge Atkins to serve on the U.S. District Court for the Southern District of Florida. He served until his death in 1999 at the age of 84. From 1977 until 1982, Judge Atkins was the chief judge for the Southern District, and  his leadership ensured that the court remained effective through a period when Miami confronted serious problems involving refugees, violence, and drug smuggling.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Judge Atkins rendered important decisions in the areas of civil rights and civil liberties. By the luck of the draw, he was assigned to many controversial cases, earning him the nickname "Hard Luck Clyde," and it was for those rulings, often involving important civil rights and civil liberties issues, that he will be best remembered.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For example, in a decision involving Miami's homeless population, he ordered the creation of "safe zones" where the homeless could congregate without fear of arrest. This important decision had a ripple effect, helping to give rise to efforts throughout the Nation to rehabilitate the homeless through training and the creation of shelters. He also ruled in support of Cuban and Haitian refugees who were held at Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, and against the government's repatriation policy. And finally,  he presided over the desegregation of Dade County's public schools for more than 20 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Judge Atkins was a person of faith. He was the first Catholic appointed to the bench in the Southern District, and Pope Benedict VI named him a Knight of St. Gregory. Judge Atkins also earned recognition from the National Conference of Christians and Jews, the Anti-Defamation League, and the American Judicature Society, to name a few.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The proposal to name the courthouse in Miami after Judge Atkins has been supported by leaders of the bar in the Southern District, including the Dade County Bar Association. Passage of my bill will ensure that the C. Clyde Atkins Courthouse will stand as an enduring tribute to an admired and respected Federal judge and the principles for which he stood for generations to come.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300081" topic="Introducing S. 1386. A bill to amend the Housing and Urban Development Act of 1968, to provide better assistance to low- and moderate-income families, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1386">S. 1386</bill>] Mr. President, today I introduce the Homeownership Protection and Enhancement Act of 2007, HOPE Act. This legislation would reauthorize and amend Section 106 of the Housing and Urban Development Act of 1968, so that we can improve on Federal efforts to support and sustain homeownership.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As we all know, during the past several years, housing prices in cities and States around the country have far outpaced any increase in wages. Families have been stretching themselves financially to get into homeownership, and many families have started using alternative or exotic mortgages loan products to purchase their homes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>According to First American Loan Performance, in 2006, in my own State of Rhode Island, nearly 16 percent of all home-purchase loans were "interest only." However, as home prices have declined, many people who took out these exotic loans are now finding they owe more than the value of their property.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Center for Responsible Lending estimates that nationally one in five subprime loans originated during the prior 2 years will end in foreclosure, costing homeowners $164 billion, mostly in lost equity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>`It appears that we are just at the beginning of what could be a perfect storm, as many credit-stressed borrowers still face resets of these exotic adjustable-rate and payment option loans. There were 1.2 million foreclosures reported nationwide last year, up 42 percent from 2005, according to RealtyTrac, a database of foreclosed properties. RealtyTrac also reports 430,000 foreclosure filings in the first quarter of 2007, a 35 percent jump over the same period in 2006.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The increasing rate of foreclosures across the country is troubling. Not only are individual families losing their homes and their financial nest eggs, but there is a negative ripple effect across communities and the economy. That is why I am introducing the Homeownership Protection and Enhancement Act, or HOPE Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill seeks to help States establish and enhance outreach programs to proactively find homeowners at risk of losing their homes and help them avoid foreclosure. States will be rewarded for having set up effective programs to help curtail foreclosures with additional funding and resources. An incentive is provided for more States to follow suit and reach out to delinquent borrowers, offer them access to financial counseling, and, when appropriate, help them negotiate a plan to restructure  their debt.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In particular, the HOPE Act provides $50 million for the creation and operation of State Homeownership Protection Centers. The centers can serve as a one-stop resource, offering consumers a broad range of services and assistance, such as financial assessments, counseling, or referrals to families in need. It authorizes $260 million in competitive grants to States who operate State Homeownership Protection Centers for revolving loan funds to offer one-time grants or subsidized loans to qualified  families. It increases funding to $300 million for effective HUD-approved counseling agencies. Finally, it sets aside $5 million for the creation of a Federal database on defaults and foreclosures to improve oversight of public and private efforts to sustain homeownership.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, to help prevent future borrowers from taking on unsustainable mortgages and falling into foreclosure, the HOPE Act would create an affirmative duty for lenders and servicers to engage in reasonable loss mitigation prior to foreclosure. It would also require notifications by lenders and servicers to borrowers regarding the full array of counseling services available in their State at every critical step, at application, at closing, and upon delinquency. Finally, if a State has a State  Homeownership Protection Center, lenders and servicers would be required to refer borrowers who are 60 days or more delinquent to the center so that it can proactively attempt to reach distressed borrowers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am introducing the HOPE Act because when homes get foreclosed on, it is not just the borrowers and lenders who pay the price, whole neighborhoods suffer. Housing industry experts estimate that for every foreclosure within an eighth of a mile of a house, two and a half city blocks in every direction, the property value of surrounding homes drops by about 1 percent. I believe that the Federal Government has a responsibility to step in and ensure that millions of Americans, including neighbors  who never took out a risky loan and have scrimped and saved to pay their bills on time, are not adversely affected by the subprime foreclosure crisis.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation is targeted relief that will help more families keep their homes and save communities nationwide millions of dollars. We need to act swiftly before personal financial tragedies turn into a full blown national financial crisis.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The HOPE Act will set us on the path to meeting an important national goal, creating sustainable homeownership. I hope my colleagues will join me in supporting this bill and other foreclosure prevention efforts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300091" topic="Introducing S. 1388. A bill establish a commercial truck highway safety demonstration program in the State of Maine, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1388">S. 1388</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to join my colleague, Senator Collins, to introduce legislation that will rectify an impediment to international commerce flowing through Maine, but more importantly, will offer a measure of protection that many of my constituents in Maine do not currently possess.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As many of our colleagues know, expanding upon the current Federal truck weight limitation of 80,000 pounds is often looked upon as dangerous, flaunting the safety of drivers who may be faced with a truck weighing as much as 143,000 pounds, the limit on Interstates in Massachusetts and New York. While I certainly concur that safety of drivers is very important, and I have the record to prove it, I ask you do not overlook the safety of pedestrians as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In Maine, where we currently have a limited exemption along the Maine Turnpike, many trucks traveling to or from the Canadian border or into upstate Maine are not able to travel on our Interstates as a result of the 80,000 pound weight limit. This forces many of them onto secondary roads, many of which are two-lane roads running through small towns and villages in Maine. Tanker trucks carrying fuel are passing elementary schools, libraries, and weaving through traffic to reach our Air National  Guard station. Not only is this an inefficient method of bringing necessary fuel guardsmen that provide our national security, but imagine if you will one of those tanker trucks rupturing on Main Street, potentially causing serious damage to property, causing traffic chaos, and most importantly, killing or injuring drivers and pedestrians.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is not a far-fetched scenario. In fact, two pedestrians were killed in the past year in Maine as a result of overweight trucks on local roadways, one tragic instance occurring within sight of the nearby Interstate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What is the result of such traffic? According to study conducted by the Maine Department of Transportation, traffic fatalities involving trucks weighing 100,000 pounds are 10 times greater on secondary roads in Maine than on the exempted interstates. Serious injuries are seven times more likely. Not to mention the exorbitant cost of maintaining these secondary roads, forced to handle these massive trucks. These roads were not designed to handle this kind of traffic. Our interstates were, yet  these trucks are consistently prevented from traveling on them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The argument against such trucks is that it is a "slippery slope" that if you allow one State to have such an exemption, pretty soon you'll have to give every State such an exemption. Well, I would like to remind the opponents of this amendment that we are halfway there already. A total of 27 States already have some type of exemption, and 47 States allow trucks weighing over 80,000 pounds on some roads within their State. To offer a clear picture of this, if you are driving a truck weighing  100,000 pounds, you can leave Gary, IN, just outside of Chicago, and can operate that vehicle all the way to Portland, ME. There, of course, they have to unload the additional weight to continue on the Interstate, or travel the remainder of the way through the State on these local roads, endangering the populace and other drivers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Conversely, you can operate a truck weighing 90,000 pounds from Kansas City, MO, and travel to Seattle, WA. So I ask you, is this truly a legitimate reason for opposition while my constituents are taking their lives in their hands when merely crossing Main Street?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would especially like to thank Senator Collins for her steadfast effort as, side-by-side, we continue to seek a resolution to this issue.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="Introducing S. 1388. A bill establish a commercial truck highway safety demonstration program in the State of Maine, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise to join with my senior colleague from Maine in sponsoring the Commercial Truck Highway Safety Demonstration Program Act, an important bill that addresses a significant safety problem in our State.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under current law, trucks weighing 100,000 pounds are allowed to travel on the portion of Interstate 95 designated as the Maine Turnpike, which runs from Maine's border with New Hampshire to Augusta, our capital city. At Augusta, the turnpike designation ends, but I-95 proceeds another 200 miles north to Houlton. At Augusta, however, heavy trucks must exit the modern four-lane, limited-access highway and are forced onto smaller, two-lane secondary roads that pass through cities, towns, and villages.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Trucks weighing up to 100,000 pounds are permitted on interstate highways in New Hampshire, Massachusetts, and New York as well as the Canadian Provinces of New Brunswick and Quebec. The weight limit disparity on various segments of Maine's Interstate Highway System is a significant impediment to commerce, increases wear-and-tear on our secondary roads, and, most important, puts our people needlessly at risk.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator Snowe and I have introduced this legislation several times in recent years. We do so this year with a renewed sense of urgency, and in sorrow. Just last week, Susan Abraham, a bright and talented 17-year-old high school student from Hampden, ME, lost her life when her car was struck by a heavy truck on Route 9. The truck driver could not see Susan's small car turning onto that two-lane road as he rounded a corner. It was an accident but one that would have been avoided had the  truck remained on the interstate highway. Interstate 95 runs less than three-quarters of a mile away, but Federal law prevented the truck from using that modern, divided highway, a highway that was designed to provide ample views of the road ahead.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That preventable tragedy took place almost 1 year to the day after Lena Gray, an 80-year-old resident of Bangor, was struck and killed by a tractor-trailer as she was crossing a downtown street. Again, that accident would not have occurred had that truck been allowed to use I-95, which runs directly through Bangor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The problem Maine faces due to the disparity in truck weight limits affects many communities, but it is clearly evident in the eastern Maine cites of Bangor and Brewer. In this region, a 2-mile stretch of Interstate 395 connects two major state highways that carry significant truck traffic across Maine. I-395 affords direct and safe access between these major corridors, but because of the existing Federal truck weight limit, many heavy trucks are prohibited from using this multilane, limited  access highway.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Instead, these trucks, which sometimes carry hazardous materials, are required to maneuver through the downtown portions of Bangor and Brewer on two-lane roadways. Truckers are faced with two options; the first is a 3.5 mile diversion through downtown Bangor that requires several very difficult and dangerous turns. The second route is a 7.5 mile diversion that includes 20 traffic lights and requires travel through portions of downtown Bangor as well. Congestion is a significant issue, and safety  is seriously compromised as a result of these required diversions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In June 2004, Wilbur Smiths Associates, a nationally recognized transportation consulting firm, completed a study to examine the impact a Federal weight exemption on nonexempt portions of Maine's Interstate Highway System would have on safety, pavement, and bridges. The study found that extending the current truck weight exemption on the Maine Turnpike to all interstate highways in Maine would result in a decrease of 3.2 fatal crashes per year. A uniform truck weight limit of 100,000 pounds on  Maine's interstate highways would reduce highway miles, as well as the travel times necessary to transport freight through Maine, resulting in safety, economic, and environmental benefits. Moreover, Maine's extensive network of local roads would be better preserved without the wear and tear of heavy truck traffic.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Most important, however, a uniform truck weight limit will keep trucks on the interstate where they belong, rather than on roads and highways that pass through Maine's cities, towns, and neighborhoods.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to the safety of motorists and pedestrians, there is a homeland security aspect to this as well. An accident or attack involving a heavy truck carrying explosive fuel or a hazardous chemical on a congested city street would have devastating consequences. That risk can be alleviated substantially by allowing those trucks to stay on the open highway.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation that Senator Snowe and I are introducing addresses the safety issues we face in Maine because of the disparities in truck weight limits. The legislation directs the Secretary of Transportation to establish a commercial truck safety pilot program in Maine. Under the pilot program, the truck weight limit on all Maine highways that are part of the interstate highway system would be set at 100,000 pounds for three years. During the waiver period, the Secretary would study  the impact of the pilot program on safety and would receive the input of a panel on which State officials, and representatives from safety organizations, municipalities, and the commercial trucking industry would serve. The waiver would become permanent if the panel determined that motorists were safer as a result of a uniform truck weight limit on Maine's Interstate Highway System.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Maine's citizens and motorists are needlessly at risk because too many heavy trucks are forced off the interstate and onto local roads. The legislation Senator Snowe and I are introducing is a commonsense approach to a significant safety problem in my State. Our efforts are widely supported by public officials throughout Maine, including the Governor, the Maine Department of Transportation, the Maine Secretary of State, and the Maine State Police. I urge my colleagues to support this  important legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400629" topic="Introducing S. 1389. A bill to authorize the National Science Foundation to establish a Climate Change Education Program; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1389">S. 1389</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to introduce legislation, cosponsored by Ms. Snowe and Mr. Bingaman, to better educate Americans about climate change. We are today introducing the Climate Change Education Act, to broaden Americans' understanding of global warming.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There may still be disputes about exactly how much humans contribute to the warming of our atmosphere. But there is near certainty that the air we breathe is being changed by ever increased levels of greenhouse gases, with effects on climate, resources, and habitats.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last week, I attended a hearing of the Foreign Relations Committee, where the issue of climate change was shown to also affect our national security. A report issued by a panel of distinguished military leaders concluded that climate change will be globally  destabilizing, leading to diminished access to fresh water, reduced food production as India and sub-Saharan Africa become hotter and drier, increased health crises as vector-borne diseases spread,  and displacement of large populations as sea levels rise and coastal lands flood. As scarcities increase, conflicts over diminishing resources will also increase. Governments in resource-stressed countries may collapse. Environmental stresses may lead to human migration and refugees.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I mention this to emphasize that climate change has surprising ramifications, and that there is still much that we can all learn about this issue, with effects that go well beyond traditional environmental concerns. It is important that we all become better informed, that we analyze the information about climate change, so that we can learn how to more rationally respond.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We believe it is important to educate our Nation about the causes and effects of climate change and about how we might effectively respond. Reaching a solution to the challenge of climate change will require changes in both national policy and in our use of energy and resources. All of this will require a thoughtful understanding of the issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Climate Change Education Act would create a program at the National Science Foundation, which would provide opportunities for students and citizens to learn more about global warming. The program would include a national information campaign to promote new approaches to addressing climate change and would also establish a competitive program to provide grants to develop education materials. Earlier this month, the House of Representatives passed the campanion, <bill type="h" number="1728">H.R. 1728</bill>, to this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
