<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1179763212" ordinal="26" title="TRIBUTE TO KEN CROCKETT">
  <speaking speaker="300084" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I wish to recognize the decade-plus of  service that Ken Crockett has dedicated to the State of West Virginia. For the last 11 years, Ken has served as the director of the West Virginia Japan Office in Nagoya, which sits in the Aichi Prefecture of Japan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>West Virginia has opened trade offices throughout the world in order to encourage economic relationships with our State. The Japan Office has helped draw a number of Japanese businesses to open new locations in West Virginia, as well as helped the businesses already in West Virginia export their products to Japan. In addition to the economic benefits of this relationship, the Japan office has facilitated a number of cultural and educational exchanges--all under Ken's leadership.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In Ken's years as director of the West Virginia Japan Office, our State and Japan have seen a dramatic, if not astronomical, rise in their economic relations. West Virginia is currently home to 19 Japanese companies that have created thousands of direct and indirect jobs for our State's citizens. Japanese investors have been, and continue to be, outstanding corporate citizens of West Virginia--contributing economically and culturally to the quality of the State.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have seen Ken's work firsthand on a number of occasions in Japan on trade missions with various Governors. Ken's relationships and his presence in Nagoya have been very valuable for our development efforts. He operated with a strong dedication to our collective goals and an understanding of both Japan and West Virginia.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Very soon, Ken will be embarking on a new career with NGK Spark Plugs--West Virginia's first major Japanese investor--and a trailblazer for our State's Japanese automotive industry. Ken will bring to that job the same determination, commitment, and hard work ethic he brought to the State's economic development efforts. We look forward to working with him in his new position as we continue to strengthen our ties with our State's existing Japanese investors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I thank the Senate and ask that my colleagues join me in recognizing Ken's service to my State and wish him the best in his future endeavors.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
