<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1171386003" ordinal="12" title="MAKING FURTHER CONTINUING APPROPRIATIONS FOR THE FISCAL YEAR 2007">
  <chair> Under the previous order, the Senate will resume consideration of <bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill>, which the clerk will report by title.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I can do this, I think in 5 or 6 minutes. I yield myself such time as I may consume. Am I recognized?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today is the 136th day of fiscal year 2007. It is  past time to complete the remaining nine fiscal year 2007 appropriations bills. Agencies have limped along through October, November, December, January, and half of February based on a very restrictive continuing resolution. Thirteen of the fifteen departments do not know how much money they will have for a fiscal year that is now one-third gone, one-third over.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a deplorable way to run a government, any government, specifically the Federal Government--this Government.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under the existing continuing resolution, our veterans hospitals are confronting the need to deny health care to 500,000 veterans and to force 850,000 veterans to wait longer for their care. <bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill> includes an increase of $3.6 billion to solve the problem. On this, the 136th day of fiscal year 2007, it is time to act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under the existing continuing resolution, the Social Security Administration is facing longer lines for approving benefits, and furloughs of employees. The 1-800 Medicare call centers, which have received over 35 million calls from the elderly with questions about their coverage, will have to shut down for the final months of the fiscal year. <bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill> solves those problems. It is time to act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under the existing continuing resolution, the Department of Defense will have to delay elective surgeries, nonemergency care, and increase the cost of some pharmaceuticals for Active-Duty members, their families, and retirees. <bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill> includes an increase of $1.4 billion to solve the problem. It is time to act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under the existing continuing resolution, funding for highways and transit is frozen at fiscal year 2006 levels, putting 160,000 jobs at risk. <bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill> fully funds the highway and transit guarantees. It is time to act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under the existing continuing resolution, no funds are provided to the Department of Defense to build the facilities needed to bring our troops back home from Europe. <bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill> includes $1 billion to solve that problem. It is time, again I say, to act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>According to the White House Office of the Global AIDS Coordinator, under the existing continuing resolution 110,000 to 175,000 people will likely die of HIV-related causes. <bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill> includes a $1.4 billion increase to help HIV victims. It is time to act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill> complies with the $872.8 billion statutory cap on spending. It contains no earmarks and, I should say, eliminates 9,300 prior earmarks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Hallelujah. It eliminates 9,300 prior earmarks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill> cuts 125 accounts below fiscal year 2006 levels and freezes 450 accounts at the 2006 level. <bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill> is tough, it is disciplined, and it addresses critical needs. It is time to act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge Members to vote aye on the cloture motion and on the resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, how much time do we have remaining?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator has about 4 minutes remaining.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the Chair. I yield the floor and suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will call the roll.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>I announce that the Senator from Delaware (Mr. BIDEN) and the Senator from South Dakota (Mr. JOHNSON) are necessarily absent.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300069" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>The following Senator was necessarily absent. The Senator from Kansas, Mr. BROWNBACK.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Are there any other Senators in the Chamber desiring to vote?</chair>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays resulted--yeas 71, nays 26, as follows:</narrative>
  <chair> On this vote, the yeas are 71, the nays are 26. Three-fifths of the Senators duly chosen and sworn having voted in the affirmative, the motion is agreed to.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>I move to reconsider the vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>I move to lay that motion on the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The motion to lay on the table was agreed to.</narrative>
  <chair> The Senator from Georgia.</chair>
</record>
