<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1213977603" ordinal="30" title="STATEMENTS ON INTRODUCED BILLS AND JOINT RESOLUTIONS">
  <narrative>STATEMENTS ON INTRODUCED BILLS AND JOINT RESOLUTIONS -- (Senate - June 20, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="5941">S5941</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300084" topic="Introducing S. 3173. A bill to amend part E of title IV of the Social Security Act to allow children in foster care to be placed with their parents in residential family treatment centers that provide safe environments for treating addiction and promoting healthy parenting; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="3173">S. 3173</bill>] Mr. President, I rise before you today to introduce the Keeping Families Safe Act of 2008 which seeks to keep families together when a parent is in a residential substance abuse treatment facility. Numerous studies have shown the benefits of keeping families united as a parent undergoes substance abuse treatment. In fact, one study found that 60 percent of mothers who participated in the Pregnant and Postpartum Women and Their Infants program were completely clean and sober six  months after their discharge. This same study found that 88 percent of these children were still with their mothers six months after the mother was discharged. However, only 5 percent of all substances abuse treatment facilities are able to accommodate children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress has shown support for comprehensive family based substance abuse treatment facilities in the past. In 2006, Congress passed the Deficit Reduction Act, which included a $40 million grant program, to promote two key goals, substance abuse services for families in the child welfare system, and regular caseworker visits.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Keeping Families Safe Act is one way to invest in children and families. This legislation would allow children, who are in foster care, to be with their parent while he or she is receiving treatment at residential comprehensive family-based substance abuse treatment centers. These facilities provide comprehensive services to both parent and child. If this family based approach is not available, these children would often be forced to claim Federal funding in the foster care system. By using  these funds instead to go to the residential facility with their parent, the chances for success are much greater.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Family based substance abuse treatment centers have proven to be an effective means of treating substance abuse and reuniting families. Many of the parents in treatment are there in hopes of overcoming their addiction and reuniting with their children. This bill is designed to give them that chance. I urge my colleagues to support this important legislation to help keep families together and provide another funding source for these important facilities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be placed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="s" number="3173">S. 3173</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "Keeping Families Safe Act of 2008".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. FINDINGS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Congress makes the following findings:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) The 2001 report by the Center for Substance Abuse Treatment (CSAT) of the Pregnant and Postpartum Women and Their Infants Program, which provides comprehensive, family-based treatment for substance abusing mothers and their children, found that at 6 months post treatment--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) 60 percent of the mothers remained alcohol and drug-free;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) drug-related offenses declined from 28 percent to 7 percent; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) 75 percent of the mothers had physical custody of 1 or more children.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) The 2003 evaluation of the Center for Substance Abuse Treatment (CSAT) of the  Pregnant and Postpartum Women and Their Infants Program of 24 residential family-based treatment programs 6 months after treatment revealed the following successful outcomes for mothers and their children:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) 60 percent of the mothers in the programs remained completely clean and sober 6 months after discharge.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) 44 percent of the children in the programs were returned to their mothers from foster care.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) 88 percent of the children treated in the programs with their mothers remained stabilized and living with their mothers, 6 months after discharge.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) The Center for Substance Abuse Treatment (CSAT) of the Pregnant and Postpartum Women and Their Infants Program has found that rates of premature delivery, low birth weight, and infant mortality were improved for women who participated in the program, the costs of treating such women were offset by as much as 3 to 4 times the savings that resulted from reduced costs of crime, foster care, Temporary Assistance to Needy Families (TANF) assistance, and adverse birth outcomes.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 3. AUTHORITY FOR STATES TO MAKE FOSTER CARE MAINTENANCE PAYMENTS TO RESIDENTIAL FAMILY TREATMENT CENTERS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) In General.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) IN GENERAL.--Section 472 of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 672) is amended--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) in subsection (b)(2)--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) by inserting "or a residential family treatment center" after "child-care institution"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) by inserting "or residential family treatment center" after "such institution"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) in subsection (c)--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) by striking "and" before "(2)"; and</narrative>
  <narrative> (ii) by inserting before the period at the end the following: "; and (3) the term `residential family treatment center' means a State licensed program that enables parents and their children to live in a safe environment for a period of not less than 6 months and provides, on-site or by referral, substance abuse treatment services, children's early intervention services, family counseling, legal services, medical care, mental health services, nursery and preschool, parenting skills training,  pediatric care, prenatal care, sexual abuse therapy, relapse prevention, transportation, and job or vocational training or classes leading to a secondary school diploma or a certificate of general equivalence".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) EFFECTIVE DATE.--The amendments made by paragraph (1) shall take effect on October 1, 2008, without regard to whether regulations implementing such amendments are promulgated by such date.</narrative>
  <narrative> (b) Evaluation and Report.--The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall, by grant, contract, or interagency agreement, evaluate the foster care maintenance payments made under section 472(b)(2) of the Social Security Act on behalf of a child who is in a residential family treatment center (as amended by subsection (a)(1)(A)) and, not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, shall submit a report to Congress on the results of such evaluation that includes an analysis  of the outcomes for the children in foster care on whose behalf such payments are made.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</narrative>
</record>
