<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1220976002" ordinal="53" title="NOTICE OF HEARINGS">
  <narrative>NOTICE OF HEARINGS -- (Senate - September 09, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="8216">S8216</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="PERMANENT SUBCOMMITTEE ON INVESTIGATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to announce for the information of the Senate and the public that the Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations of the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs will hold a hearing entitled, "Dividend Tax Abuse: How Offshore Entities Dodge Taxes On U.S. Stock Dividends." The Subcommittee hearing will examine how some financial institutions have designed, marketed, and implemented transactions to enable foreign taxpayers, including offshore  hedge funds, to dodge millions of dollars of taxes on U.S. stock dividends. The hearing will also examine whether current law relating to dividend taxation and withholding should be strengthened. The Subcommittee expects to issue a Subcommittee staff report in conjunction with the hearing summarizing its investigative findings and recommendations. Witnesses will include representatives of U.S. financial institutions, offshore hedge funds, a tax expert, and the Internal Revenue Service.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Subcommittee hearing is scheduled for Thursday, September 11, 2008, at 9 a.m., in Room 106 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building. For further information, please contact Elise Bean of the Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations at 202-224-9505.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300060" topic="COMMITTEE ON SMALL BUSINESS AND ENTREPRENEURSHIP">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to inform Members that the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship will hold a hearing entitled "Business Start-up Hurdles in Underserved Communities: Access to Venture Capital and Entrepreneurship Training," on Thursday, September 11, 2008 at 10 a.m., in room 428A of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300037" topic="COMMITTEE ON INDIAN AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to announce that the Committee on Indian Affairs will meet on Thursday, Thursday, September 11, at 9:30 a.m. in room 628 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building to conduct a hearing on (1) <bill type="s" number="3128">S. 3128</bill>, the White Mountain Apache Tribe Rural Water System Loan Authorization Act; (2) <bill type="s" number="3355">S. 3355</bill>, the Crow Tribe Water Rights Settlement Act of 2008; and (3) <bill type="s" number="3381">S. 3381</bill>, a bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Commissioner of Reclamation, to develop  water infrastructure in the Rio Grande Basin, and to approve the settlement of the water rights claims of the Pueblos of Nambe, Pojoaque, San Ildefonso, Tesuque, and Taos.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Those wishing additional information may contact the Indian Affairs Committee at, 202-224-2251.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND NATURAL RESOURCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, the Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources will hold a business meeting on Thursday, September 11, 2008 at 12 noon, in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the Business Meeting is to consider pending legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For further information, please contact Sam Fowler at (202) 224-7571 or Amanda Kelly at (202) 224-6836.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to announce for the information of the Senate and the public that a hearing has been scheduled before the Energy Subcommittee of the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. The hearing will be held on Tuesday, September 16, 2008, at 2:30, in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the hearing is to receive testimony on recent analyses of the role of speculative investment in energy markets.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of the limited time available for the hearing, witnesses may testify by invitation only. However, those wishing to submit written testimony for the hearing record should send it to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, United States Senate, Washington, DC 20510-6150, or by email to Gina weinstock@energy.senate.gov.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For further information, please contact Angela Becker-Dippmann at (202) 224-5269 or Gina Weinstock at (202) 224-5684.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
