<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1174665652" ordinal="20" title="STATEMENTS ON INTRODUCED BILLS AND JOINT RESOLUTIONS">
  <speaking speaker="400629" topic="Introducing S. 976. A bill to secure the promise of personalized medicine for all Americans by expanding and accelerating genomic research and initiatives to improve the accuracy of disease diagnosis, increase the safety of drugs, and identify novel treatments; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="976">S. 976</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today joined by my colleague Senator RICHARD BURR, to reintroduce the Genomics and Personalized Medicine Act of 2007. This bill will expand and accelerate scientific advancement in the field of genomics, which is already beginning to change the paradigm of medical practice as we know it, and has profound implications for health and health care in this nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The "miracles of medicine" have been demonstrated since early man. Many of the traditional medicines used today, such as aspirin and morphine, are derivatives of plants ancient people used to treat illnesses and injuries centuries ago. Since those ancient times, our knowledge of medicine and disease has expanded tremendously. Today, modern breakthroughs in the fields of genetics and genomics have uncovered another layer of complexity in the way we treat and prevent disease.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over the past decade, we have unlocked many of the mysteries about DNA and RNA, their structure, and how their code is translated into the proteins that make up the tissues and organs of the human body. Researchers have also made discoveries about the various functions of DNA such as replication, genetic recombination and regulation, just to name a few, and have developed the necessary technologies to do all of this work.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This knowledge isn't just sitting in books on the shelf nor is it confined to the work benches of laboratories. We have used these research findings to pinpoint the causes of many diseases, such as sickle cell anemia, cystic fibrosis, and chronic myelogenous leukemia. Moreover, scientists have translated this genetic knowledge into several treatments and therapies prompting a bridge between the laboratory bench and the patient's bedside.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We've made so many achievements and come a long way in our understanding and application of genetics knowledge. And yet, we are just beginning to realize the full potential of this science to predict the onset of disease, diagnose earlier, and develop therapies that can treat or cure Americans from so many afflictions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Just 4 years ago, scientists at the National Institutes of Health and the Department of Energy reached another major landmark, with the completion of the sequencing of the entire human genome, our genetic blueprint described by many as the Holy Grail of biology and hailed as one of the greatest scientific achievements to date.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The completion of the Human Genome Project has paved the way for a more sophisticated understanding of disease causation. The HGP has expanded focus from the science of genetics, which refers to the study of single genes, to include genomics, which describes the study of all the genes in an individual, as well as the interactions of those genes with each other. The role environmental factors play in promoting disease and the potential influence they have at the genetic level is also an area of  interest.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We know that all human beings are 99.9 percent identical in genetic makeup, but differences in the remaining 0.1 percent hold important clues about the causes of disease and response to drugs. Simply put, the study of genomics will help us learn why some people get sick and others do not, and use this information to better prevent and treat disease.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The relatively new field of genomics is key to the practice of personalized medicine. Personalized medicine is the use of genomic and molecular data to better target the delivery of health care, facilitate the discovery and clinical testing of new products, and help determine a patient's predisposition to a particular disease or condition. Personalized medicine represents a revolutionary and exciting change in the fundamental approach and practice of medicine</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Pharmacogenomics, or the study of how genes affect a person's response to drugs, is a critical component of personalized medicine. Currently, so-called blockbuster drugs are typically effective in only 40 to 60 percent of patients who take them. Other studies have found that up to 15 percent of hospitalized patients experience a serious adverse drug reaction, causing an estimated 100,000 deaths each year. Pharmacogenomics has the potential to dramatically increase the effectiveness and safety  of drugs, both of which are major health care concerns.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have a growing number of examples of how pharmacogenomics research has helped to save lives. For example, the chemotherapy Purinethol is a lifesaver for kids with leukemia, but in some cases, patients suffer severe, sometimes fatal, side effects. In the 1990's, researchers identified the gene variant that prevents affected patients from properly breaking down Purinethol, allowing doctors to screen patients and adjust dosages for safer use of the drug.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Herceptin, another example, is a breast cancer drug that initially failed in clinical trials. However, researchers discovered that 1 in 4 breast cancers have too many copies of a certain gene, which helps cells grow, divide and repair themselves. Extra copies of this gene cause uncontrolled and rapid growth resulting in tumor formation. As it turns out, Herceptin is an effective drug for patients with this type of cancer, with significantly improved survival for affected women. Herceptin offers  a clear illustration of the power of personalized medicine and highlights the importance of incorporating genetic analysis in the development and application of new therapies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Realizing the promise of personalized medicine will require continued Federal leadership and agency collaboration; expansion and acceleration of genomics research; a capable genomics workforce; incentives to encourage development of genomic tests and therapies; and greater attention to the quality of genetic tests, direct-to-consumer advertising and use of personal genomic information.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Genomics and Personalized Medicine Act of 2007 will address many of these issues. The bill requires the Secretary of the Department of Health and Human Services to establish the Genomics and Personalized Medicine Interagency Working Group to expand and accelerate genomics research through enhanced communication, collaboration and integration of relevant activities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Genetic and genomics research will be expanded, to increase the collection of data that will advance both fields, through the support of the biobanking initiative aimed at increasing and improving genomic screening tools, diagnostics and therapeutics. The Secretary will also establish a national distributed database so data finding can be shared.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill requests that the Secretary support efforts to improve the adequacy of genetics and genomics training through modernized curricula and review of relevant certifications, and by identifying alternative education options such as distance or on-line learning programs. In addition, the Secretary will promote initiatives to increase the integration of genetics and genomics into all aspects of medical and public health practice, with specific focus on training and guideline development for  providers without expertise or experience in the field of genomics.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill also requests the National Academies of Science to formally study the development of companion diagnostic tests and to provide expert guidance about the level of incentives and potential approaches to really move this area forward.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last but not least, the bill focuses on the safety, efficacy and availability of information about genetic tests, including pharmacogenetic and pharmacogenomics tests. The Secretary will contract with the Institute of Medicine to conduct a study and make recommendations regarding Federal oversight and regulation of genetic tests. After this study is complete, the Secretary will develop a decision matrix to help determine which types of tests require review and the level of review needed for such  tests as well as the responsible agency. The Secretary will also establish a specialty area for molecular and biochemical genetics tests at CMS and direct a review by the CDC of direct-to-consumer marketing practices.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In conclusion, we stand at this new and expansive frontier of personalized medicine we must explore and test the hypotheses and innovations in the area of genomics that can protect and promote our health. Genomics holds unparalleled promise for public health and for medicine, and the Genomics and Personalized Medicine Act of 2007 will help us to fulfill this promise. I  urge my colleagues to support me in passing this critical legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300100" topic="Introducing S. 979. A bill to establish a Vote by Mail grant program; to the Committee on Rules and Administration.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="979">S. 979</bill>] Mr. President, on Election Day 2006 in Tillamook County, OR, 13 inches of rain fell. Roads were closed. Parts of the county became unreachable. Governor Kulongoski declared a state of emergency. And yet--70 percent of the voters in the county still cast their ballots.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Why? Because Oregonians in Tillamook County and all over the State cast their votes by mail.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Even without weather like this, folks in other States around the country had trouble casting their votes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In Denver, CO, hundreds of voters were turned away when the database of registered voters crashed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nearly a quarter of precincts in Indianapolis, IN, resorted to paper ballots when poll workers couldn't figure out how to connect optical scan voting machines with the new touch-screen models.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In Johnson County, KS, poll workers used hand lotion to prevent the county's touch-screen voting machines from spitting out cards.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In Missouri, poll workers were demanding photo identification despite a court ruling barring the practice.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In Shaker Heights, OH, voters were turned from the polls when electronic voting machines failed to work.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Voters in Washington State received phone calls instructing them to vote at the wrong precinct.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A polling location in New Mexico received 150 ballots instead of 1,500.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The list goes on and on.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The point is, vote by mail has worked in Oregon and not just in this election, but in every election it has been used.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It's a pretty simple system. Voters get their ballots in the mail. Wherever and whenever they would like, right up to Election Day, voters complete their ballots and return them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Vote by mail makes polling place problems a thing of the past--no more polls opening late and no more long lines.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There's no more confusion about whether you are on the voter rolls. Either you get the ballot in the mail, or you don't and if you don't, you have ample time to contact your election officials to sort it out.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Vote by mail dramatically reduces the chance of voter fraud. Trained election officials match the signature on each ballot against the signature on each voter's registration card and no ballot is processed or counted until officials are satisfied that the two signatures match.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Vote by mail ensures a paper trail--each voter marks up their ballot and sends it in. That ballot is counted and then becomes the paper record used in the event of a recount.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There's less risk of voter intimidation and that's why a 2003 study of Oregon voters showed that those groups that would likely be most vulnerable to coercion, including the elderly, actually prefer vote by mail.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Vote by mail leads to more educated voters. Because folks get their ballots weeks before the election, they have the time they need to get educated about the candidates and the issues, and deliberate in a way not possible at a polling place.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And vote by mail generates costs savings that can be spent on other priorities like education, law enforcement and roads. Because there is no longer any need to transport equipment to polling stations and to hire and train poll workers, Oregon has reduced its election-related costs by 30 percent since implementing vote by mail.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think the Oregon experience can be copied elsewhere and that's why I am introducing my Vote by Mail Act of 2007 today, which creates a three year, $18 million grant program to help states adopt vote by mail election systems like the one that Oregon voters have been successfully using for some time now.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To participate in the grant program, States must demonstrate that the vote by mail system they intend to implement includes the same elements that have made Oregon's system so successful, including a system for recording electronically each voter's registration and signature and a process for ensuring that the signature on each VBM ballot is verified against that voter's electronically recorded signature. States that decide to participate in the program have the option of adopting vote by mail  State-wide, within a group of selected counties, or even in a single county. States transitioning to vote by mail State-wide will receive $2 million. States transitioning to VBM less than State-wide will receive $1 million.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think that vote by mail will improve the elections in every State that adopts it. But to be sure, my bill instructs the Government Accountability Office to evaluate the benefits of vote by mail and to produce a study comparing traditional voting methods and vote by mail.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to lend their support to the Vote by Mail Act of 2007. I believe it can help ensure hassle-free elections and help rebuild confidence in our election system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because right now, some folks feel like they are so powerless to do anything to fix things that they throw their hands in the air and walk away. And society suffers. For democracies to work there needs to be public engagement. But that requires a sense of investedness--unless I think of the government as my government, which means it's considering my interests and, more importantly, trying to solve them, it's pretty hard to stay invested.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The sense of resignation, of frustration, even dislocation, expressed by some folks troubles me. And I consider it my job to foster a greater sense of public investment. This means making sure that the government works for everyone and that there are tangible results that you can show people so that they understand that it's their government and that it works for them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think election reform like my vote by mail bill accomplishes this goal at the most basic level. Without fair, trouble-free elections, you've got serious problems. You don't even get past go. The public can't have confidence in its government if it doesn't have confidence in the system that elected that government. As we saw in 2000 in Florida, it is extremely difficult to untangle problems after Election Day so you really have to get it right the first time. Vote by mail helps ensures this.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am pleased to have my esteemed colleague from Massachusetts, Senator Kerry as an original co-sponsor. I am also pleased that Congresswoman SUSAN DAVID of California is introducing the House companion bill. I am also happy to announce that the American Association of People with Disabilities, the American Postal Workers Union, Common Cause, and the National Association of Postal Supervisors are publicly supporting this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="Introducing S. 980. A bill to amend the Controlled Substances Act to address online pharmacies; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="980">S. 980</bill>] Mr. President, I am pleased to join with Senator Sessions to re-introduce the Online Pharmacy Consumer Protection Act. Our legislation protects the safety of consumers who wish to fill legitimate prescriptions over the Internet, while holding accountable those who operate unregistered pharmacies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation imposes basic, commonsense requirements on an industry that presents both promise and peril.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, this bill establishes disclosure standards for Internet pharmacies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second, this bill prohibits an Internet pharmacy from dispensing or selling a controlled substance without an in-person examination by a physician.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Third, it allows a State Attorney General to bring a civil action in a federal district court to enjoin a pharmacy operating in violation of the law, and to enforce compliance with the provisions of this law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The disclosure requirements contained in this bill will allow patients to differentiate between shady off-shore pharmacies and legitimate licensed ones. Under this legislation, pharmacies must clearly disclose: the name and address of the pharmacy. Contact information for the pharmacist-in-charge. A list of States in which the pharmacy is licensed to operate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>They must also clearly post a statement that they comply with the requirements in this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill states that pharmacies can dispense to patients only if they have a valid prescription from a practitioner who has performed an in-person examination. This requirement will ensure that doctors can verify the health status of a patient and ensure that the drug he or she will receive from the pharmacy is medically appropriate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation recognizes that in the case of an emergency, a patient may not always be able to see his or her typical physician. For that reason, it allows a doctor to designate a covering practitioner to write a valid prescription if he or she is not available.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, this bill contains real penalties to hold accountable those who continue to operate pharmacies in violation of these requirements.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, for Internet sales of controlled substances, the bill makes clear that such activities are subject to the current Federal laws against illegal distributions and the same penalties applicable to hand-to-hand sales.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second, the bill increases the penalties for illegal distributions of controlled substances categorized by the DEA as Schedule III, IV and V substances, with new penalties if death or serious bodily injury results, and longer periods of supervised release available after convictions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also allows a State's Attorney General to file a Federal motion to stop these pharmacies from operating illegally, no matter where the entity is headquartered. Previously, this type of enforcement would require a filing in every state.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Prescription drug abuse is a growing front on the War on Drugs, with 15.1 million adults admitting to abuse of prescription drugs in a 2003 study. That's a 94 percent increase in the last decade.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last month, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention reported that deaths from accidental drug overdoses nearly doubled from 1999 to 2004, increasing from 11,155 in 1999 to 19,838 in 2004. Accidental drug overdoses are now the Nation's second-leading cause of accidental death, behind automobile crashes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The CDC attributed the rise in drug overdose deaths to a higher use of prescription painkillers and increasing numbers of overdoses of cocaine and prescription sedatives. These increases did not occur in our inner cities; instead, the increase was described as being fueled by prescription drug abuse in middle-class, rural America--with overdose death rates doubling in 23 States, mostly in the South and Midwest.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ready access to controlled substances over the Internet is helping to fuel these addictions. A study conducted by the National Center on Addiction and Substance Abuse at Columbia University found at least 344 websites offering controlled substances.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>89 percent of these pharmacies do not require a prescription from a physician, accepting either an online consultation or no prescription at all.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>38 percent of these pharmacies claim their drugs are shipping within the United States, putting them within the reach of U.S. law enforcement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We also know that internet pharmacies fill a disproportionate number of prescriptions for controlled substances. According to data from the National Community Pharmacy Association (NCPA)-Pfizer Digest, controlled substances account for only 11 percent of the business at community "brick and mortar" pharmacies. 89 percent of their business consists of non-controlled prescription drugs. In contrast, approximately 95 percent of the business done by internet pharmacies is controlled substances.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To understand how many of these Internet pharmacy websites exist, just visit any Internet search engine. Type in the name of any controlled substance, like Vicodin, Oxycontin, codeine, or even anabolic steroids. Several websites will appear, offering to sell you these drugs without a prescription and without a medical examination. Some of these websites simply ask patients to send copies of medical records, with no verification of their validity. Patients use these pharmacies to obtain addictive  drugs like Vicodin and Oxycontin. They can receive these dangerous drugs without a doctor performing a physical exam to ensure that an underlying health condition will not cause a dangerous side effect. Often, a credit card is all that is required.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Law enforcement officials are well aware of this growing problem but face many challenges in trying to  find and prosecute rogue pharmacy operators. Last year, Attorney General Alberto Gonzales appeared before the Senate Judiciary Committee and warned at  that time how "the purchase of ..... controlled pharmaceuticals on the Internet is of great concern." He said that the Internet's wide accessibility and anonymity "give drug abusers the ability to circumvent the law, as well as sound medical practice, a[s] they dispense potentially dangerous controlled  pharmaceuticals," and said that, with "no identifying ..... information on these websites, it is very difficult for law enforcement to track any of the individuals behind them."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In January of this year, Attorney General Alberto Gonzales again appeared before the Senate Judiciary Committee. The problem had only grown worse. He described the non-medicinal use of controlled substance prescription drugs as "the fastest rising category of drug abuse in recent years." He noted how "[r]ogue pharmacies operating illicitly through the Internet increasingly have become a source for the illegal supply of controlled substances," and offered to work with Congress to try to adopt  additional enforcement tools that may be appropriate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe that the bill I introduce today will address many of these problems that the Attorney General has identified.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At the same time, receiving medications from a legitimate, licensed Internet pharmacy is one of the new conveniences ushered in by the Internet age. This bill preserves the ability of well run pharmacies and well intentioned patients to access controlled substances by means of the Internet.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In closing, I want to share with you the story of Ryan T. Haight of La Mesa, CA. Ryan was an 18-year-old honor student from La Mesa, CA, when he died in his home on February 12, 2001.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>His parents found a bottle of Vicodin in his room with a label from an out-of-state pharmacy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It turns out that Ryan had been ordering addictive drugs online and paying with a debit card his parents gave him to buy baseball cards on eBay.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Without a physical exam or his parents' consent, Ryan had been obtaining controlled substances, some from an Internet site in Oklahoma. It only took a few months before Ryan's life was ended by an overdose on a cocktail of painkillers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ryan's story is just one of many. Internet pharmacies are making it increasingly easy for teens like Ryan to access deadly prescription drugs. That is why I support this legislation. It creates sensible requirements for Internet pharmacy websites that will not impact access to convenient, oftentimes cost-saving drugs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to join me in supporting this legislation and I ask unanimous consent that the text of the legislation be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300088" topic="Introducing S. 980. A bill to amend the Controlled Substances Act to address online pharmacies; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, after working together with Senator FEINSTEIN, I am pleased to help introduce the Online Pharmacy Consumer Protection Act of 2007. I have worked to take the lead in protecting consumers specifically as it relates to the sale and distribution of controlled substances over the internet and holding liable those who do so via unregistered online pharmacies. I commend Senator FEINSTEIN for her leadership on this issue and look forward to working with her  to pass this important piece of legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill would prohibit the distribution of controlled substances by means of the Internet without a valid prescription and provides for the legitimate online distribution of those drugs in certain circumstances. This past January, Attorney General Gonzalez testified to the Judiciary Committee that abuse of controlled substances is being fed by "the proliferation of illicit Web sites that offer controlled substances for sale, requiring little more than a cursory online questionnaire and charging  double the normal price." Gonzales further testified that "[w]e must preserve legitimate access to medications over the Internet while preventing online drug dealers from using cyberspace as a haven for drug trafficking. I look forward to working with the Congress to ensure that controlled substances are dispensed over the Internet only for legitimate medical purposes."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Recently, there has been an explosion in the number of online pharmacies that provide controlled substances to users without valid prescriptions. Most illegal drug abuse involving prescription drugs is associated with Internet purchases, where users are given a prescription without ever seeing a doctor. The most prominent abuse occurs with regard to controlled substances such as Hydrocodone, Valium, Xanax, OxyContin, and Vicodin.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A 2006 study reported that "a staggering 89 percent of sites selling controlled prescription drugs have no prescription requirements." According to the study, 15.1 million adults admitted to abusing prescription drugs, including 2.3 million abusers between the ages of 12 and 17. Currently, there is no way to police this illegal activity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The ease with which consumers may purchase controlled substances from online pharmacies without a prescription is shocking. Often consumers can obtain a prescription from physicians employed by the online pharmacy by simply filling out a brief questionnaire on the pharmacy's website. Most online pharmacies have no way to verify that the consumer ordering the prescription is actually who they claim to be, or that the medical condition the consumer describes actually exists. Thus, drug addicts  and minor children can easily order controlled substances and prescription drugs over the internet simply by providing false identities or  describing non-existent medical conditions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 2001, Ryan Haight, a California high school honors student and athlete, died from an overdose of the painkiller hydrocodone that he purchased from an online pharmacy. The doctor prescribing hydrocodone had never met or personally examined Ryan. Ryan simply filled out the pharmacy's online questionnaire, and described himself as a 25-year-old male suffering from chronic back pain. Ryan's death could have been avoided. I believe that Congress is in the best position to help prevent teenagers  from purchasing controlled substances and prescription drugs from online rouge pharmacies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also believe that Congress has the ability to help prevent adult prescription drug abuse by making it harder to purchase these drugs online without a valid prescription. The Online Pharmacy Consumer Protection Act would: (1) provide criminal penalties for those who knowingly or intentionally (unlawfully) dispense controlled substances over the Internet, (2) give state attorneys general a civil cause of action against anyone who violates the Act if they have reason to believe that the violation  affects the interests of their state's residents, and (3) allow the Federal Government to take possession of any tangible or intangible property used illegally by online pharmacies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Online Pharmacy Consumer Protection Act would also require online pharmacies to: (1) file a registration statement with the Attorney</paragraph>
    <paragraph>General and meet additional registration requirements promulgated by him/her, (2) report to the Attorney General any controlled substances dispensed over the Internet, and (3) comply with licensing and disclosure requirements.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Online Pharmacy Consumer Protection Act of 2007 takes a substantial step towards plugging a loophole in our drug laws by regulating the practice of distributing controlled substances via the internet.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By holding unregistered online pharmacies accountable for their activity, we are ensuring that those who seek to purchase prescription drugs by using the internet are protected from those engaged in reprehensible business practices.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Once again I thank Senator FEINSTEIN for her leadership in addressing this serious issue. I commend this bill to my colleagues for study and I urge them to support this important legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300022" topic="Introducing S. 982. A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for integration of mental health services and mental health treatment outreach teams, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="982">S. 982</bill>] Mr. President, today, Senator Collins and I are reintroducing the Positive Aging Act, to improve the accessibility and quality of mental health services for our rapidly growing population of older Americans. I want to thank Senator Collins for her leadership on aging issues, and for partnering with me on numerous pieces of legislation and initiatives related to these and other important health issues.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are pleased to be reintroducing this important legislation in anticipation of reauthorization of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAMHSA).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to acknowledge and thank our partners from the mental health and aging community who have collaborated with us and have been working diligently on these issues for many years, including the American Psychological Association, the American Association for Geriatric Psychiatry, the National Association of Social Workers, the Alzheimer's Association, the New York City Chapter of the Alzheimer's Association, the American Association of Homes and Services for the Aging, the American Academy  of Child and Adolescent Psychiatry, the American Mental Health Counselors Association, the American Society on Aging, the Depression and Bipolar Support Alliance, the Geriatric Mental Health Alliance of New York, the Gerontological Society of America, Mental Health America, the National</paragraph>
    <paragraph>American society today has benefited tremendously from advances in medical science that are helping us to live longer than ever before. In New York State alone, there are an estimated two and a half million citizens aged 65 or older. And this population will only continue to grow as the first wave of Baby Boomers turns 65 in less than ten years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>According to a December 2006 report from the U.S. Census Bureau, the number of older Americans aged 65 and over is expected to double over the next 25 years, and nearly 20 percent of citizens will be 65 years or older by the year 2030. Further, the fastest growing segment of the U.S. population is the age group of Americans who are 85 and older.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although it is encouraging that our Nation's citizens are living longer than ever before, mental and behavioral health challenges accompany this increased longevity. So as we look forward to leading longer lives, we must also acknowledge the challenges that we face related to the quality of life as we age.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although most older adults enjoy good mental health, it is estimated that nearly 20 percent of Americans age 55 or older experience a mental disorder. In New York State alone, there are an estimated 366,000 adults aged 55 or older with mental health or substance abuse disorders. Nationally, it is anticipated that the number of seniors with mental and behavioral health problems will almost quadruple, from 4 million in 1970 to 15 million in 2030.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Among the most prevalent mental health concerns older adults encounter are anxiety, depression, cognitive impairment, and substance abuse. When left untreated, these problems can have severe physical and psychological implications. In fact, men age 85 and older have the highest rates of suicide in our country and depression is the foremost risk factor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The physical consequences of mental health disorders can be both expensive and debilitating. Depression has a powerful negative impact on ability to function, resulting in high rates of disability. The World Health Organization projects that by the year 2020, depression will remain a leading cause of disability, second only to cardiovascular disease. Even mild depression lowers immunity and may compromise a person's ability to fight infections and cancers. Research indicates that 50-70 percent  of all primary care medical visits are related to psychological factors such as anxiety, depression, and stress. Further, evidence suggests that an estimated 75 percent of seniors who commit suicide have visited a primary care professional within a month of their death.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mental disorders do not have to be a part of the aging process because we have effective treatments for these conditions. But despite these effective treatments, too many American seniors go without the services they need and deserve because of poor integration of physical and mental health care. As of 2006, only 37 percent of New Yorkers who suffer from depression had obtained mental health treatment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The current divide in our country between health care and mental health care manifests itself in many ways. Too often physicians and other health professionals fail to recognize the signs and symptoms of mental health problems. Even more troubling, knowledge about treatment is simply not accessible to many primary care practitioners. As a whole, we have failed to fully integrate mental health screening and treatment into our health service systems.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These missed opportunities to diagnose and treat mental health disorders are taking a tremendous toll on seniors and increasing the burden on their families and our health care system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is within our power and our responsibility to bridge the gap between physical and mental health care and help promote the well-being of older Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In last year's reauthorization of the Older Americans Act, Senator Collins and I successfully enacted Title I of the Positive Aging Act of 2005, which authorized grants for the delivery of mental health screening and treatment  services for older adults and grants to promote awareness and reduce stigma regarding mental disorders in later life.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While this took an important step toward improving mental health services for older adults, significant efforts are necessary to ensure comprehensive geriatric mental health care.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is why I am reintroducing the Title II provisions of the Positive Aging Act of 2005 as the Positive Aging Act of 2007 with my cosponsor Senator Collins. This legislation would amend the Public Health Service Act to improve access to mental health services for our nation's seniors by integrating mental health services into primary care and community settings.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Specifically, the Positive Aging Act of 2007 would fund demonstration projects to support integration of mental health services in primary care settings.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It would fund grants for community-based mental health treatment outreach teams to improve older Americans' access to mental health services.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation would also ensure that these geriatric mental health programs have proper attention and oversight by: mandating the designation of a Deputy Director for Older Adult Mental Health Services in the Center for Mental Health Services; including representatives of older Americans or their families and geriatric mental health professionals on the Advisory Council for the Center for Mental Health Services; and requiring state plans under Community Mental Health Services Block Grants  to include descriptions of the states' outreach to and services for older individuals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And because substance-related disorders require the same attention as mental health conditions, the Positive Aging Act of 2007 will target substance abuse in older adults in projects of national significance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, we are fortunate to have a variety of effective treatments to address the mental health needs of American seniors. I believe that we owe it to older adults in this country to do all that we can to ensure that they have access to high quality mental health care, so they can enjoy their golden years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Positive Aging Act of 2007 takes a critical step in this direction, and I look forward to working with my colleagues to enact this legislation during the upcoming SAMHSA reauthorization.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that letters of support be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the letters were ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
</record>
