<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1169744418" ordinal="14" title="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY RULES OF PROCEDURE">
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today the Judiciary Committee held its first business meeting of the year. I can now report to the Senate that we have organized our subcommittees, including our creation of a new subcommittee on Human Rights, named our subcommittee chairs and ranking members, adopted our committee rules and adopted our funding resolution. I thank our ranking member, Senator Specter, and all members of the committee for their cooperation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We were delayed a few weeks by the failure of the Senate to pass organizing resolutions on January 4, when this session first began. The Republican caucus had meetings over several days after we were in session before finally agreeing on January 12 to <bill type="sr" number="27">S. Res. 27</bill> and <bill type="sr" number="28">S. Res. 28</bill>, the resolutions assigning Members to Senate committees.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Judiciary Committee has traditionally met on Thursday. Regrettably, the delay in Senate organization meant that I could not notice or convene a meeting of the committee the morning of January 11, as I had hoped. We devoted the intervening Thursday to our oversight hearing with the Attorney General. January 18 was the date the Attorney General selected as most convenient for him, and we accommodated him in that scheduling.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, I can report to the Senate, in accordance with Senate Rule 26.3, that the Judiciary Committee has, again, designated Thursday mornings as our regular meeting days for the transaction of business. The Judiciary Committee has also reported the authorization resolution required by Senate Rule 26.9. In addition, the Judiciary Committee adopted its rules. In accordance with Senate Rule 26.2, I ask that a copy of the rules of the Senate Judiciary Committee be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
</record>
