<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1201626002" ordinal="40" title="ECONOMY AND FORECLOSURES">
  <narrative>ECONOMY AND FORECLOSURES -- (Senate - January 29, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="440">S440</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, last night, President Bush spoke of the bipartisan effort we've seen to put together an economic stimulus package.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have joined this chorus of praise. It is important for us to remember that despite our differences, we can find common ground in pursuit of common good.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The stimulus package is in markup today in the Finance Committee. I am confident that Chairman Baucus and Senator Grassley will send a bill to the floor that all 100 Senators can proudly support.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We all agree that with our economy ailing, homeowners struggling and energy prices rising, this short-term stimulus plan will help working Americans make ends meet.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But I think we also all agree that this is only the first step. A short-term solution will help, but we must create long-term solutions that will treat the cause rather than the symptoms.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>President Bush suggested last night that this could be accomplished with more tax cuts for the wealthy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We strongly disagree. No one wondering if they can make their next mortgage payment or whether they can afford to retire believes that more tax cuts for the rich will solve this problem.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This morning, the Reno Gazette Journal reported that home foreclosures in Washoe County--the Reno area of Nevada--skyrocketed 614 percent in 2007 from the year before.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This pain isn't just felt in one area or neighborhood. Foreclosures have risen in all parts of the Truckee Meadows.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One realtor said:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It's ridiculous. I'm up to 22 right now. A year ago, I had zero. I have potentially another 50 homes not foreclosed on yet but are on the brink. And that's just me.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Experts say this crisis in Reno, throughout Nevada, and all over America is going growing worse.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nationally, foreclosures jumped 79 percent in 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One of America's largest lenders, Countrywide, just reported that one out of every three subprime loans is now delinquent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And this is affecting not just the families who may lose their homes--but their neighbors who are seeing property values drop, and all of us who are faced with the collateral damage of a badly damaged housing market.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We call on President Bush to work with us to solve this and other economic problems.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We need to provide tax incentives for companies to invest in renewable energy. This will create jobs, save consumers money, and protect our air.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>America's infrastructure is crumbling. We saw it in the bridge collapse. Investing in our infrastructure will not only strengthen our communities, it will strengthen our economy by creating good-paying jobs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For every $10 billion we spend on infrastructure, we create 47,500 new jobs. And for every $10 million capital investment in public transportation, we create $30 million in sales for businesses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Instead of cutting funding for community block grants and the Consumer Credit Council in his budget, the President should sit down with us to come up with real long-term solutions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With less than a year to go in his term, we can still come together to solve these problems and get America's economy working again.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
