<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1185336000" ordinal="45" title="TO AMEND U.S. TROOP READINESS, VETERANS' CARE, KATRINA RECOVERY, AND IRAQ ACCOUNTABILITY APPROPRIATIONS ACT, 2007">
  <narrative>TO AMEND U.S. TROOP READINESS, VETERANS' CARE, KATRINA RECOVERY, AND IRAQ ACCOUNTABILITY APPROPRIATIONS ACT, 2007 -- (Senate - July 25, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="10045">S10045</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Agriculture be discharged from further consideration of <bill type="s" number="1716">S. 1716</bill> and that the Senate proceed to its immediate consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will report the bill by title.</narrative>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>The bill (<bill type="s" number="1716">S. 1716</bill>) to amend the U.S. Troop Readiness, Veterans' Care, Katrina Recovery, and Iraq Accountability Appropriations Act, 2007, to strike a requirement relating to forage producers.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the bill.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the bill be read a third time and passed, the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table, and any statements relating to the measure be printed in Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The bill (<bill type="s" number="1716">S. 1716</bill>) was ordered to be engrossed for a third reading, was read the third time, and passed, as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="s" number="1716">S. 1716</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,</chair>
  <chair>The U.S. Troop Readiness, Veterans' Care, Katrina Recovery, and Iraq Accountability Appropriations Act, 2007 (Public Law 110-28; 121 Stat. 112) is amended by striking section 9012.</chair>
</record>
