<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1221062403" ordinal="28" title="REMEMBERING DON HASKINS">
  <narrative>REMEMBERING DON HASKINS -- (Senate - September 10, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="8271">S8271</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300027" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today I wish to pay tribute to Don Haskins, a great Texan, legendary basketball coach, and remarkable man who passed away earlier this week at his home in El Paso.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Haskins, who started his career coaching small-town high school basketball teams, served as the head coach at Texas Western College, now the University of Texas at El Paso, UTEP, from 1961 to 1999. His decision to "put my five best guys on the court" in the 1966 NCAA national championship game against the Kentucky Wildcats is now widely regarded as a catalyst for racial integration in college sports. The Texas Western Miners, with an all-Black starting lineup, beat the Wildcats 72-65. Their  inspiring story is told in the film, "Glory Road," and the book of the same name.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over his long career, Coach Haskins compiled a 719-353 record and earned a place in the Naismith Memorial Basketball Hall of Fame in 1997 and the Texas Sports Hall of Fame in 1987. Over the years, he turned down lucrative job offers in order to stay at UTEP. He retired in 1999 with the fourth best record in history that included winning seven Western Athletic Conference, WAC, championships and four WAC tournament titles.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While Coach Haskins was known for his tough and competitive spirit, he is also remembered for his selfless acts of kindness.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>According to an Associated Press report, "USC coach Tim Floyd, a former Haskins assistant, said he once got a call from the mayor of Van Horn, a small town about 120 miles east of El Paso, to thank Haskins for giving a ride to a family of five stranded along the highway.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>" `He'd been coyote hunting and saw a station wagon broken down,' Floyd recalled this week. `He put them (the family) in his truck, drove them to El Paso, put them up in a hotel for two nights, and gave them $1,000.'</paragraph>
    <paragraph>"The family drove to Los Angeles after Haskins also helped get their car repaired. The coach never told anyone about it, not even his wife, according to Floyd.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>"Floyd said he never told the story before, mostly because Haskins wouldn't have wanted anyone to know.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>" `I'm only telling it now because he's gone,' Floyd said. `I want people to know.' "</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In deciding to devote the best years of his life and career to the people of Texas, Coach Haskins built a legacy that will continue to inspire generations. I join with all Texans as we mourn his passing and extend our deepest condolences to his family.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
