<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1212422402" ordinal="5" title="NATIVE AMERICAN HOUSING ASSISTANCE">
  <narrative>NATIVE AMERICAN HOUSING ASSISTANCE -- (Senate - June 02, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="4857">S4857</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that amendment No. 4820 be modified with the changes at the desk, notwithstanding passage of <bill type="s" number="2062">S. 2062</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <chair>Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The amendment (No. 4820), as modified, is as follows:</chair>
  <chair> On page 15, line 8, insert "the demonstration program under" after "guarantees under".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; On page 19, strike lines 1 through 13 and insert the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(c) Applicability.--The provisions of paragraph (2) of subsection (a) regarding binding commitments for the remaining useful life of property shall not apply to a family or household member who subsequently takes ownership of a homeownership unit.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; On page 22, line 9, insert "in accordance with section 202" after "infrastructure".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; On page 29, strike line 18 and insert the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(iv) any other legal impediment.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(E) Subparagraphs (A) through (D) shall not apply to any claim arising from a formula current assisted stock calculation or count involving an Indian housing block grant allocation for any fiscal year through fiscal year 2008, if a civil action relating to the claim is filed by not later than 45 days after the date of enactment of this subparagraph.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; On page 32, strike line 18 and insert the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(a) Authority.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) IN GENERAL.--Subject to paragraph (2), to the extent and in such&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; On page 33, between lines 5 and 6, insert the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(2) LIMITATION.--The Secretary may guarantee, or make commitments to guarantee, under paragraph (1) the notes or obligations of not more than 4 Indian tribes or tribally designated housing entities located in each Department of Housing and Urban Development Office of Native American Programs region.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; On page 36, line 12, strike "shall" and insert "may".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; On page 37, lines 5 and 6, strike "such sums as are necessary" and insert "$1,000,000".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Beginning on page 39, strike line 1 and all that follows through page 41, line 14.</chair>
  <chair> Beginning on page 42, strike line 8 and all that follows through page 43, line 21.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
