<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1170867604" ordinal="41" title="CONGRATULATING THE INDIANAPOLIS COLTS FOR WINNING SUPER BOWL XLI">
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate now proceed to the consideration of <bill type="sr" number="75">S. Res. 75</bill>, which was submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered. The clerk will report.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300070" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I am pleased to join my colleague Senator Bayh in submitting a resolution congratulating the Indianapolis Colts on their historic season, culminating Sunday in a thrilling victory over the Chicago Bears in Super Bowl XLI.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Like so many of my fellow Hoosiers, I have enjoyed cheering on the Colts since the Irsay family brought them to Indianapolis almost a quarter of a century ago. Over the years Colts owner and CEO Jim Irsay and president Bill Polian have brought together a remarkable group of dedicated professionals such as Tony Dungy and players who through their hard work and dedication to community service are a credit to the Colts organization, the City of Indianapolis, and the State of Indiana.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Special recognition should be given to Tony Dungy as the first head coach of African-American descent to lead his team to victory in the Super Bowl. I have enjoyed following Coach Dungy remarkable leadership and appreciate the example he sets for all Hoosiers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am hopeful that each of my colleagues in the Senate will join Senator Bayh and me in congratulating the Colts on this signal achievement.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
