<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1175184011" ordinal="61" title="UNANIMOUS-CONSENT AGREEMENT--S. 5 AND S. 30">
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that on Tuesday, April 10, following morning business, the Senate proceed en bloc to the consideration of <bill type="s" number="5">S. 5</bill> and <bill type="s" number="30">S. 30</bill>; that the bills be debated concurrently for a time limitation of 20 hours, with the time divided as follows: 5 hours each under the control of the majority and Republican leaders or their designees; 5 hours each under the control of Senators Harkin and Brownback or their designees; that no amendments or motions  be in order to either bill; that upon the completion of debate, the bills be read for a third time en bloc, and that each bill be required to receive 60 affirmative votes to pass; and that if neither achieves 60 votes, then <bill type="s" number="5">S. 5</bill> be returned to the Senate Calendar, and <bill type="s" number="30">S. 30</bill> be placed on the Senate Calendar; that <bill type="s" number="5">S. 5</bill> be the first vote in the sequence; and that there be 2 minutes of debate between</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that <bill type="s" number="30">S. 30</bill> be held at the desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, again, I do this often because it is necessary often, and that is we do a lot together. This is a unanimous consent on one of the most contentious issues in the country today: stem cell research. The distinguished Republican leader and I were able to work this out. I expressed appreciation to him and the others who felt so strongly about this on the other side of the aisle. This will be good. We can move on after this matter is determined one way or the other when we  return from our work period.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
