<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1173974406" ordinal="53" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <speaking speaker="300081" topic="COMMITTEE ON ARMED SERVICES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, March 15, 2007, at 9:30 a.m., in open session to receive testimony on the posture of the United States Army in review of the Defense authorization request for fiscal year 2008 and the future years defense program.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300081" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Thursday, March 15, 2007, at 10 a.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building. The purpose of the hearing is to review the U.S. Coast Guard budget.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300081" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, March 15, 2007, at 9:30 a.m. to hold a nomination hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300081" topic="COMMITTEE ON HEALTH, EDUCATION, LABOR, AND PENSIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions be authorized to meet in executive session during the session of the  Senate on Thursday, March 15, 2007 at 4 p.m. in the President's Room, S-216, of the Capitol building. We will be considering the following:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>1. <bill type="s" number="624">S. 624</bill>, the National Breast and Cervical Cancer Early Detection Program Reauthorization Act of 2007</paragraph>
    <paragraph>2. <bill type="s" number="845">S. 845</bill>, Keeping Seniors Safe From Falls Act of 2007</paragraph>
    <paragraph>3. <bill type="s" number="657">S. 657</bill>, the Trauma Care Systems Planning and Development Act of 2007</paragraph>
    <paragraph>4. W. Craig Vanderwagen, of Maryland, to be Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response, Department of Health and Human Services</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300081" topic="COMMITTEE ON HOMELAND SECURITY AND GOVERNMENTAL AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs be authorized to meet on Thursday, March 15, 2007, at 10 a.m. to consider the nomination of Gregory B. Cade to be Administrator of the U.S. Fire Administration at the Department of Homeland Security.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300081" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet to conduct a markup on Thursday, March 15, 2007, at 10 a.m. in Dirksen Room 226.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Agenda</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I. Committee Authorization</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Authorization of Subpoenas in Connection with Investigation into Replacement of U.S. Attorneys</paragraph>
    <paragraph>II. Bills</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="236">S. 236</bill>, The Federal Agency Data Mining Reporting Act of 2007; Feingold, Sununu</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="261">S. 261</bill>, Animal Fighting Prohibition Enforcement Act of 2007; Cantwell, Specter, Durbin, Kyl, Feinstein, Feingold, Kohl</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="376">S. 376</bill>, Law Enforcement Officers Safety Act of 2007; Leahy, Specter, Kyl, Cornyn, Grassley, Sessions</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="231">S. 231</bill>, A bill to authorize the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant Program; Feinstein, Cornyn, Kohl, Durbin, Biden, Grassley</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="368">S. 368</bill>, COPS Improvements Act of 2007; Biden, Leahy, Kohl, Feinstein, Schumer, Durbin, Specter</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="627">S. 627</bill>, Safe Babies Act; Harkin, Specter</paragraph>
    <paragraph>III. Resolutions</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="sc" number="14">S. Con. Res. 14</bill>, Commemorating the 85th anniversary of the American Hellenic Educational Progressive Association; Snowe</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300081" topic="SELECT COMMITTEE ON INTELLIGENCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Select Committee on Intelligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on March 15, 2007 at 2:30 p.m. to hold a Business Meeting..</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300081" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON TRANSPORTATION AND INFRASTRUCTURE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on Transportation and Infrastructure be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, March 15, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The agenda to be considered: Hearing on Water Resources Needs and the President's Budget Proposal for the Army Corps of Engineers for fiscal year 2008.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
