<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1170781203" ordinal="38" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <speaking speaker="412249" topic="COMMITTEE ON ARMED SERVICES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, February 6, 2007, at 9:30 a.m., in open session to receive testimony on the fiscal year 2008 budget request and the fiscal years 2007 and 2008 war supplemental requests in review of the defense authorization request for fiscal year 2008 and the future years defense program.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412249" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENVIRONMENT AND PUBLIC WORKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Environment and Public Works be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, February 6, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The agenda to be considered: Oversight of Recent EPA Decisions.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412249" topic="COMMITTEE ON FINANCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Finance be authorized to meet during the session on Tuesday, February 6, 2007, at 2:45 p.m., in 215 Dirksen Senate Office Building, to hear testimony on "The President's Fiscal Year 2008 Budget Proposal."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412249" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, February 6, 2007, at 10 a.m. to hold a hearing on Somalia.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412249" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet to conduct a hearing on "Preserving Prosecutorial Independence: Is the Department of Justice Politicizing the Hiring and Firing of U.S. Attorneys?" for Tuesday, February 6, 2007 at 9:30 a.m. in Dirksen Senate Office Building Room 226.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Witness List: The Honorable Mark Pryor, United States Senator [D, AR]; The Honorable Paul J. McNulty, Deputy Attorney General, U.S. Department of Justice, Washington, DC; Mary Jo White, Partner, Debevoise &amp; Plimpton, LLP, New York, NY; Laurie L. Levenson, Professor of Law, Loyola Law School, Los Angeles, CA; Stuart M. Gerson, Partner, Epstein Becker &amp; Green, Washington, DC.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412249" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet to conduct a hearing on "Judicial Nominations" for Tuesday, February 6, 2007 at 2:30 p.m. in Dirksen Senate Office Building Room 226.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Witness List: John Preston Bailey to be U.S. District Judge for the Northern District of West Virginia; Otis D. Wright II to be U.S. District Judge for the Central District of California; George H. Wu to be U.S. District Judge for the Central District of California.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412249" topic="SELECT COMMITTEE ON INTELLIGENCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Select Committee on Intelligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on February 6, 2007 at 2:30 p.m. to hold a closed hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
