<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1193846401" ordinal="44" title="PERMITTING COLLECTION OF DONATIONS IN SENATE BUILDINGS TO BE SENT TO MILITARY PERSONNEL">
  <narrative>PERMITTING COLLECTION OF DONATIONS IN SENATE BUILDINGS TO BE SENT TO MILITARY PERSONNEL -- (Senate - October 31, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="13645">S13645</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate now proceed to the consideration of <bill type="sr" number="361">S. Res. 361</bill>, which was submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="361">S. Res. 361</bill>) to permit the collection of donations in Senate buildings to be sent to United States military personnel on active duty overseas participating in or in support of Operation Iraqi Freedom, Operation Enduring Freedom, and the war on terrorism.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, and the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="361">S. Res. 361</bill>) was agreed to, as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="361">S. Res. 361</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair> Resolved,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. COLLECTION OF DONATIONS TO UNITED STATES MILITARY PERSONNEL.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) In General.--Notwithstanding any other provision of the rules or regulations of the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) a Senator, officer, or employee of the Senate may collect from another Senator, officer, or employee of the Senate within Senate buildings nonmonetary donations to be sent to United States military personnel on active duty overseas participating in or in support of Operation Iraqi Freedom, Operation Enduring Freedom, and the war on terrorism; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) a Senator, officer, or employee of the Senate may work with a nonprofit organization with respect to the delivery of donations that are collected as described in paragraph (1).</chair>
  <chair> (b) Effective Period.--This resolution shall be in effect until December 31, 2007.  &lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
