<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1202749203" ordinal="14" title="INTELLIGENCE AUTHORIZATION ACT FOR FISCAL YEAR 2008--CONFERENCE REPORT">
  <narrative>INTELLIGENCE AUTHORIZATION ACT FOR FISCAL YEAR 2008--CONFERENCE REPORT -- (Senate - February 11, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="844">S844</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate now proceed to the conference report to accompany <bill type="h" number="2082">H.R. 2082</bill>, the Intelligence authorization conference report.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered. The clerk will report.</chair>
  <chair>The bill clerk read as follows:</chair>
  <chair>The committee of conference on the disagreeing votes of the two houses on the amendment of the Senate to the bill (<bill type="h" number="2082">H.R. 2082</bill>), to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2008 for intelligence and intelligence-related activities of the United States Government, and for other purposes, having met, after full and free conference, have agreed to recommend and do recommend to their respective houses this report, signed by a majority of the conferees.</chair>
  <chair> Without objection, the Senate will proceed to the consideration of the conference report.</chair>
  <narrative>(The conference report is printed in the House proceedings of the Record of December 6, 2007, beginning at page H14462.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I send a cloture motion to the desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The cloture motion having been presented under rule XXII, the Chair directs the clerk to read the motion.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>Cloture Motion</narrative>
  <narrative>We, the undersigned Senators, in accordance with the provisions of Rule  XXII of the Standing Rules of the Senate, do hereby move to bring to a close debate on the conference report to accompany <bill type="h" number="2082">H.R. 2082</bill>, Intelligence Authorization Act.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent the mandatory quorum call be waived.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
