<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1179244824" ordinal="19" title="WATER RESOURCES DEVELOPMENT ACT--Continued">
  <speaking speaker="300099" topic="WARNER AMENDMENT NO. 1134">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate return to consideration of <bill type="h" number="1495">H.R. 1495</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300099" topic="WARNER AMENDMENT NO. 1134">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I think we have just seen an extraordinary chapter of how two leaders can come together and structure a procedure by which this Senate can go forward and achieve its objectives. I am totally supportive of the procedure enunciated by our two distinguished leaders because I strongly support the need for getting this appropriations legislation through and on to the President's desk so that we can fund adequately our Armed Forces, particularly those engaged in Iraq and  Afghanistan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The leadership further decided that those Senators who wish to address the conferees could do so by adding amendments to this bill. My understanding is that there are two amendments that have been filed on the other side of the aisle: one by Mr. Feingold and another by Mr. Levin. And in consultation with the distinguished Republican leader, I now file an amendment on this side of the aisle, although I am hopeful my amendment would not be viewed purely as a Republican amendment  but that it could be a vehicle by which we can reach some level, hopefully a significant level, of bipartisan consensus on the several principles I have enunciated in this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Throughout the course of this debate on Iraq, since the President's announcement of a new strategy on January 10 of this year, there have been groups of Republicans and Democrats that have voiced our concerns about the strategies being employed in Iraq, and we continue to do so by virtue of this process now decided upon by the leadership whereby amendments to this bill can be brought up, which amendments reflect the sentiments of those who are sponsoring them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At the present time, my amendment is sponsored by my principal cosponsor, the Senator from Maine, Ms. Collins, although I have been in consultation with a number of other Senators on this side of the aisle, as well as Senators on the other side of the aisle.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Given the brevity of the time today, since Senators have returned from their constituencies largely this morning, and the fact that we have been trying to work out the procedure just adopted by the Senate by the two leaders, it has not been possible for me to isolate a fixed set of cosponsors. Nevertheless, I do know of a number, certainly on this side, and I am hopeful on the other side, and now that this amendment is filed tonight, it is my expectation and hope that Senators will be adding  their names as cosponsors. I urge that be done at the earliest opportunity because, as I understand it, and the leadership will subsequently address, I think, the Senate tonight respecting the legislative program tomorrow as to when my amendment, with such cosponsors</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me now turn to addressing the specifics of this amendment at this time. This amendment, in its preamble, has the following: We entitle it the "President's Strategy In Iraq." Section 1. Findings regarding progress in Iraq, the establishment of benchmarks to measure that progress, and reports to the Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The recitation in the first section of this amendment is a series of statements factually describing the situation as we, the sponsors of this amendment, feel have taken place, largely since January 10 of this year. Foremost among those obligations is, of course, our recognition of the enormity of the sacrifice of the men and women of the Armed Forces and their families and others who have taken an active role in carrying out our strategies in Iraq, not just since January 10 of this year but  prior thereto, in the regrettably long period of time that this conflict in Iraq has persisted.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Following those statements, we then go to section 2, which is entitled, "Conditioning of Future United States Strategy in Iraq on the Iraqi Government's Record of Performance on its Benchmarks."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In General. The United States strategy in Iraq, hereafter, shall be conditioned on the Iraqi government meeting benchmarks as told to Members of Congress by the President, the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense, and the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, and reflected in the Iraqi Government's commitments to the United States, and to the international community, including .....</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For example, benchmarks--and I shall read but several. First and foremost:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Forming a Constitutional Review Committee and then completing the Constitutional review;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enacting and implementing legislation on de-baathification;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enacting and implementing legislation to ensure  the equitable distribution of hydrocarbon resources of the people of Iraq without regard to the sect or ethnicity of recipients, and enacting and implementing legislation to ensure that the energy resources of  Iraq benefit Sunni Arabs, Shia Arabs, Kurds, and other Iraqi citizens in an equitable manner.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enacting and implementing legislation on procedures to form semi-autonomous regions;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enacting and implementing legislation establishing an Independent High Electoral Commission; provincial elections law; provincial council authorities; and a date for provincial elections.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I shall not read further from this document. It will be a matter of record. But these benchmarks were ones put forth by the Iraqi Government, in large measure. What we are doing now is requiring the following:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The President shall submit reports to the Congress on how the sovereign government of Iraq is, or is not, achieving progress towards accomplishing the aforementioned benchmarks, and shall advise the Congress on how that assessment requires, or does not require, changes to the strategy announced on January 10, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Reports Required.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>(1) The President shall submit an initial report, in classified and unclassified format, to the Congress, not later than July 15, 2007, assessing the status of each of the specific benchmarks established above, and declaring, in his judgment, whether satisfactory progress towards meeting these benchmarks is, or is not, being achieved.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>(2) The President, having consulted with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense, the Commander, Multi-National Forces-Iraq, the United States Ambassador to Iraq, and the Commander of U.S. Central Command, will prepare the report and submit the report to Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>(3) If the President's assessment of any of the specific benchmarks established above is unsatisfactory, the President shall include in that report a description of such revisions to the political, economic, regional, and military components of the strategy, as announced by the President on January 10, 2007. In addition, the President shall include in the report, the advisability of implementing such aspects of the bipartisan Iraq Study Group, as he deems appropriate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And, as is well documented in the Senate, and well-respected, if I may say, by the Senate--the work of the Iraq Study Group.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>(4) The President shall submit a second report to the Congress, not later than September 15, 2007, following the same procedures and criteria outlined above.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>(5) The reporting requirement detailed in section 1227 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2006 is hereby waived from the date of the enactment of this Act through the period ending September 15, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is put in there for the reason that we believe these reports by the President will supplant whatever reports had been required by that act. The force and effect of the requirement for those reports will pick up and continue after September of this year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>(c) Testimony before Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>(1) Prior to the submission of the President's second report on September 15, 2007, and at a time to be agreed upon by the leadership of the Congress and the Administration, the United States Ambassador to Iraq and the Commander, Multi-National Forces Iraq--</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is General Petraeus--</paragraph>
    <paragraph>will be made available to testify in open and closed sessions before the relevant committees of the Congress.&lt;p&gt;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I will now refer to the section titled "Limitations on Availability of Funds" in this appropriations bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Limitation. No funds appropriated or otherwise made available for the "Economic Support Fund" and available for Iraq may be obligated or expended unless and until the President of the United States certifies in the report outlined in subsection (2)(b)(1) above and makes a further certification in the report outlined in subsection (2)(b)(4) above that Iraq is making progress in each of the benchmarks set forth in section 2 above.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To give the President a certain amount of flexibility--and this is the provision I am particularly indebted to our distinguished colleague, Ms. Collins of Maine, who has worked with me on it, as well as Senator Coleman and others who have been working with me--we provide the following:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The President may waive the requirements of this section if he submits to Congress a written certification setting forth the detailed justification for the waiver, which shall include a detailed report describing the actions being taken by the United States to bring the Iraqi government into compliance with the benchmarks set forth in section 2 above. The certification shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We proceed to a section entitled "Redeployment of U.S. Forces from Iraq." There has been considerable publicity attached to certain actions having been taken by the Council of Representatives in Iraq--that is their basic name for their parliament--and to clarify that we have put in the following requirement:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The President of the United States, in respecting the sovereign rights of the nation of Iraq, shall direct the orderly redeployment of elements of U.S. forces from Iraq, if the components of the Iraqi government, acting in strict accordance with their respective powers given by the Iraqi Constitution, reach a consensus as recited in a resolution, directing a redeployment of U.S. forces.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, proceeding to another section, "Independent Assessments."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Assessment by the Comptroller General.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Not later than September 1, 2007, the Comptroller general of the United States shall submit to Congress an independent report setting forth--</paragraph>
    <paragraph>(A) the status of the achievement of the benchmarks specified in section 2 above; and</paragraph>
    <paragraph>(B) the Comptroller General's assessment whether or not each such benchmark has [or has not] been met.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>(b) Assessment of the capabilities of Iraq Security forces.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a section which I worked on, now, for over 2 months, laying a foundation, with consultations with the White House senior staff, the Secretary of Defense, and indeed a private organization here, a well-respected organization, independent of any affiliation with the Government, to participate in performing this report, as well as a very senior and highly respected retired military officer who, hopefully, will be designated to head up this report.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believed it was imperative that the Congress needed to have an independent report, and by "independent," I mean a report performed by a private sector entity with the advice and participation of at least one senior retired military officer, and maybe others, so that we can have a report to put side by side with the periodic evaluations of the Department of Defense as to the military--professional ability, capability, training, and equipment of the Iraqi security forces. That is essential.  So that is the essence of this provision which I now read.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>(1) In General.--There is hereby authorized to be appropriated for the Department of Defense, $750,000, that the Department, in turn, will commission an independent private sector entity which operates as a 501(c)(3) with recognized credentials and expertise in militarily affairs, to prepare an independent report assessing the following:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>(A) The readiness of the Iraqi security forces--ISF [referred to] to assume responsibility for maintaining the territorial integrity of Iraq, denying international terrorists a safe haven, and bringing greater security to Iraq's 18 provinces in the next 12-18 months, and bringing an end to sectarian violence to achieve national reconciliation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>(B) The training, equipping, command, control and intelligence capabilities and logistics capacity of the ISF [Iraqi Security Forces].</paragraph>
    <paragraph>(C) The likelihood that given the ISF's record of preparedness to date, following years of training and equipping by U.S. forces, the continued supports of U.S. troops will contribute to the readiness of the ISF to fulfill the missions outlined in subparagraph (A).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>(2) Report.--Not later than 120 days after the enactment of this Act, the designated private sector entity shall provide an unclassified report, with a classified annex, containing its findings, to the House and Senate Committees on Armed Services, Appropriations, Foreign Relations/International Relations, and Intelligence.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Having worked on this report some 2 months now, I submitted it to colleagues in the House of Representatives. I am pleased to say that those colleagues saw fit to include that basic language on reporting and establishing this independent entity and individuals to study the Iraqi security forces. This provision which I have just read was contained in the House appropriations bill. It is my hope and expectation that it will be included by this Senate, the appropriators, in their bill such that  it will emerge as part of the final conference report of the House and the Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I once again thank many individuals who have worked with me and their respective staffs, who worked beginning last week on the final draft. They worked over the weekend, worked on Monday, worked today to create this document. I am hopeful a good number of our colleagues will see fit to cosponsor this document, which document and amendment will be discussed tomorrow in such brief period as outlined by the leadership. They will define it tonight, and then it will be voted upon.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I send the amendment to the desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300099" topic="TITLE--PRESIDENT'S STRATEGY IN IRAQ">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I yield the floor. I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="TITLE--PRESIDENT'S STRATEGY IN IRAQ">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="TITLE--PRESIDENT'S STRATEGY IN IRAQ">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, what is the pending business now before the Senate?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Warner amendment No. 1134 is the pending business.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="TITLE--PRESIDENT'S STRATEGY IN IRAQ">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, it is my understanding we are on WRDA, then, <bill type="h" number="1495">H.R. 1495</bill>?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> That is correct.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="TITLE--PRESIDENT'S STRATEGY IN IRAQ">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that on Wednesday, May 16, when the Senate resumes consideration of <bill type="h" number="1495">H.R. 1495</bill>, the time until 10:30 a.m. be for debate prior to the votes on the motions to invoke cloture on the following amendments: Feingold second-degree amendment No. 1098, Levin amendment No. 1097, Warner amendment No. 1134, and the Cochran amendment No. 1135, with the time equally divided and controlled between the majority and Republican leaders or their designees; that the  votes occur in the order listed above; and that there be 2 minutes of debate prior to each vote, equally divided and controlled, and that each vote in this sequence after the first be limited to 10 minutes; that if cloture is not invoked, then the amendment be withdrawn; that no other amendments be in order prior to the cloture votes; and that second-degree amendments may be</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="TITLE--PRESIDENT'S STRATEGY IN IRAQ">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I now ask unanimous consent that upon disposition of the amendments covered under this agreement, the Senate resume debate on the motion to proceed to <bill type="s" number="1348">S. 1348</bill>, comprehensive immigration legislation, with the time until 2 p.m. for debate prior to a vote on the motion to invoke cloture on the motion to proceed--Mr. President, I withdraw this aspect of the consent request at this time, and stop where I was where there was no objection.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> It is withdrawn.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I send a cloture motion to the desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The cloture motion having been presented under rule XXII, the Chair directs the clerk to read the motion.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I send a cloture motion to the desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The cloture motion having been presented under rule XXII, the Chair directs the clerk to read the motion.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300072" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the pending amendment to the bill be set aside, and on behalf of Senator Cochran, I call up an amendment to the bill, which is at the desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered. The clerk will report.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300072" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the reading of the amendment be dispensed with.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300072" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I now send a cloture motion to the pending Warner amendment to the desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The cloture motion having been presented under rule XXII, the Chair directs the clerk to read the motion.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300072" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I send a cloture motion to the desk to the Cochran amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The cloture motion having been presented under rule XXII, the Chair directs the clerk to read the motion.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300042" topic="SECTIONS 2006, 2007, AND 2008">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to engage the distinguished chairman from California and the distinguished majority leader in a colloquy with respect to the provisions in section 2006, 2007, and 2008 (c) and (e) of the Water Resources Development Act of 2007, <bill type="s" number="1248">S.1248</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="SECTIONS 2006, 2007, AND 2008">
    <paragraph>I would be happy to respond to the Senator from Wisconsin.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="SECTIONS 2006, 2007, AND 2008">
    <paragraph>I, too, am happy to engage in a colloquy with the Senator from Wisconsin.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300042" topic="SECTIONS 2006, 2007, AND 2008">
    <paragraph>I appreciate the efforts and success of the chairman and the Environment and Public Works Committee in reporting a Water Resources Development Act that includes many important Corps of Engineers reforms. I would simply like to clarify that it is the intent of the committee and of the majority leader that these provisions be retained through conference and enacted into law. These provisions should be the minimum reforms coming out of conference.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="SECTIONS 2006, 2007, AND 2008">
    <paragraph>I concur that this is the committee's intent.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="SECTIONS 2006, 2007, AND 2008">
    <paragraph>I support the understanding reached by the chairman and the Senator from Wisconsin.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300042" topic="SECTIONS 2006, 2007, AND 2008">
    <paragraph>I would like to point out some of the critical elements to ensuring meaningful independent review of Corps of Engineers water resources projects that are contained in section 2007 of <bill type="s" number="1248">S.1248</bill>. Section 2007 is the same language that was adopted on the Senate floor during last summer's consideration of the Water Resources Development Act of 2006. Though the House of Representatives has an independent review provision in their bill, there are several important distinctions between the  House and the Senate provisions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senate provision houses responsibility for independent review in the Office of the Secretary of the Army and makes independent review mandatory for any project meeting the review triggers. The mandatory review triggers and placement of responsibility for carrying out independent reviews outside the Office of the Chief of Engineers are essential for ensuring full independence of the review process. The Senate provision gives the independent review panels the ability to review those issues  deemed significant by the panel. This is essential for ensuring that all relevant study issues are examined by the panel. The House of Representatives provision gives the Chief of Engineers essentially unlimited authority to restrict the scope of a panel's review. The Senate provision places limits on the Corps' ability to ignore panel recommendations by requiring the Secretary of the Army to provide a written explanation regarding the rejection of any panel recommendations and by requiring the Corps to prove why it</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Importantly, the Senate provision ensures that the independent review panel will review the draft study released for public comment and will have the benefit of public comment to help guide their review. The House bill in general requires that independent review be complete before there is a draft study for review. That would limit a fundamental purpose of independent review, which is to ensure review of draft studies and limit public participation in the independent review process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask my colleagues to concur with the importance of retaining these critical elements of independent review contained in Section 2007.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="SECTIONS 2006, 2007, AND 2008">
    <paragraph>I concur that these are fundamental elements of meaningful independent review and concur that it is the committee's intent to retain these elements and that we will strenuously support them in the conference.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="SECTIONS 2006, 2007, AND 2008">
    <paragraph>I support the understanding reached by the chairman and the Senator from Wisconsin.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300042" topic="SECTIONS 2006, 2007, AND 2008">
    <paragraph>Mitigation for Corps of Engineers civil works projects is another important area that must be improved. Despite the clear mitigation requirements established for water resources projects in the Water Resources Development Act of 1986, the Government Accountability Office reported in 2002 that the Corps of Engineers does not mitigate at all for almost 70 percent of its projects. To help address this problem, the Senate provision requires the Secretary to ensure that mitigation for  water resources projects complies fully with the mitigation standards and policies established pursuant to section 404 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act, 33 U.S.C. 1344. This will help protect the environment and is consistent with the fundamental principal that we will hold the Federal Government to the same environmental criteria as private enterprise.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, in order to ensure that mitigation produces the same or greater ecosystem values as those lost to a water resources project, the Senate provision requires that the Corps of Engineers implement not less than in-kind mitigation. To ensure that mitigation will be effective, the Senate bill requires the preparation of detailed mitigation plans, requires that mitigation be monitored until ecological success criteria are met, and requires the Corps of Engineers to consult yearly with applicable  Federal and State agencies on the status of individual mitigation efforts. The Senate provision applies the new mitigation standards to projects that the Corps of Engineers has determined must be reevaluated for other reasons. The Senate provision also requires the Corps to establish a publicly accessible mitigation tracking system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The language of sections 2008(c) and (e) obtained bipartisan support from the Environment and Public Works Committee last Congress and was included in the Senate Water Resources Development Act of 2006.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask my colleagues to concur with the importance of retaining these key elements of mitigation reform contained in section 2008(c) and (e).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="SECTIONS 2006, 2007, AND 2008">
    <paragraph>I concur that these are fundamental elements of meaningful mitigation reform and concur that it is the committee's intent to retain these elements and that we will strenuously support them in the conference.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="SECTIONS 2006, 2007, AND 2008">
    <paragraph>I support the understanding reached by the chairman and the Senator from Wisconsin.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300042" topic="SECTIONS 2006, 2007, AND 2008">
    <paragraph>Lastly, section 2006 of <bill type="s" number="1248">S. 1248</bill> would update the Corps' woefully out-of-date Principles and Guidelines, P&amp;G, and related planning documents by establishing a Cabinet-level interagency working group to revise the guidelines and regulations and circulars, which have not been revised since their inception in 1983. Numerous  studies have called for updating the Corps' planning guidelines to provide an increased focus on protecting and restoring  the environment and to modernize and incorporate new methods and more cost-effective approaches to solving water problems. More than a decade of reports from the National Academy of Sciences, Government Accountability Office, Army inspector general, U.S. Commission on Ocean Policy, and independent experts have</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These flaws have increased taxpayer costs and environmental degradation with antiquated economic analysis of projects and in some cases overly structural projects. It is vital that these planning guidelines be modernized so that they no longer promote projects that destroy healthy natural ecosystems and lure development in high risk areas. It is also essential that the provision to require the Corps to adopt those revisions, subject to public comment, be retained.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The language of section 2006 obtained bipartisan support from the Environment and Public Works Committee last Congress and was included in the Senate Water Resources Development Act of 2006.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask my colleagues to concur with the importance of retaining these elements.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="SECTIONS 2006, 2007, AND 2008">
    <paragraph>I concur that these are fundamental elements of meaningful reform of the Corps of Engineers planning guidelines and concur that it is the committee's intent to retain these elements and that we will strenuously support them in the conference.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="SECTIONS 2006, 2007, AND 2008">
    <paragraph>I support the understanding reached by the chairman and the Senator from Wisconsin.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300042" topic="SECTIONS 2006, 2007, AND 2008">
    <paragraph>I thank the chairman and the majority leader for engaging in this colloquy. Instituting meaningful reforms to the Corps of Engineers' planning process is essential for protecting public safety, the environment, and the taxpayers. I remain committed to ensuring that meaningful reforms are included in the next Water Resources Development Act that is enacted into law. I thank the chairman and the majority leader for their commitment as well.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="MIDDLE CREEK PROJECT">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I thank Chairman Boxer and the Committee on Environment and Public Works for their hard work on <bill type="s" number="1248">S. 1248</bill>, the Water Resources Development Act of 2007 and the bill currently being considered by the Senate, <bill type="h" number="1495">H.R. 1495</bill>. The bill represents years of negotiations by her, members of the committee, and staff, and I appreciate her leadership in bringing a bill forward for this body's consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="MIDDLE CREEK PROJECT">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I thank the leader for his comments. I appreciate the leader's continued support for this reauthorizing legislation and the authorization of the new projects for navigation, flood and coastal storm damage reduction, ecosystem restoration and environmental remediation, and water storage and water quality.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="MIDDLE CREEK PROJECT">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I generally support this bill and understand that many of the projects are necessary to improve and maintain safe communities. But I am concerned about the effects of one project on Indian lands.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Both <bill type="s" number="1248">S. 1248</bill> and <bill type="h" number="1495">H.R. 1495</bill> include authorizing language for a flood damage reduction and environmental restoration project on Middle Creek, located in Lake County, CA. I certainly defer to the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers and the California congressional delegation as to the project's importance and the most appropriate plan to implement it, but would my friend from California describe the impact of the project on Indian lands in the area?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="MIDDLE CREEK PROJECT">
    <paragraph>Mr. Leader, the Middle Creek Project will restore lands within the Middle Creek floodplain and study area. I believe the project will reconnect the floodplain of Middle Creek to the historic Robinson Lake wetland area by breaching the existing levee system and creating inlets that direct flows into the study area. The restoration will provide flood damage reduction by relocating residents of the Robinson Rancheria from the floodplain.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="MIDDLE CREEK PROJECT">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I understand the Rancheria's current casino will not be affected by this project if implemented--that the Rancheria could continue, if it chooses, to operate this casino once the project is completed. Is this correct?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="MIDDLE CREEK PROJECT">
    <paragraph>Mr. Leader, that is correct.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="MIDDLE CREEK PROJECT">
    <paragraph>Madam Chairman, I understand that neither the Senate nor the House bill authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to take land into trust for purposes of gaming on behalf of the Rancheria?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="MIDDLE CREEK PROJECT">
    <paragraph>Mr. Leader, the bill under consideration would authorize the Middle Creek Project. The bill does not expressly authorize the United States to take land into trust for the Rancheria.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="MIDDLE CREEK PROJECT">
    <paragraph>Thank you for that clarification. Madam Chairman, in Senate Report 110-58, the committee recommends that, in exchange for the existing reservation lands that would be included in the floodplain, the Secretary of the Interior accept three parcels of land into trust for the benefit of the Rancheria. Would you describe these parcels and their location in relation to the Rancheria's current reservation boundaries?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="MIDDLE CREEK PROJECT">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I appreciate the interest of the Senator from Nevada in the effect of this project on the Rancheria. Since 1981, the Secretary of the Interior has held 37 acres in trust on behalf of the Rancheria. The parcels discussed in the committee report are currently owned by the Rancheria and are very close to their current reservation boundary. Two of the three parcels are along the Clear Lake shoreline. The committee believed it was appropriate to compensate the Rancheria  by allowing them to add to their reservation lands that are approximately 1 mile away from their current reservation boundary and which the tribe already owns.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="MIDDLE CREEK PROJECT">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I thank my friend from California for describing the lands. While neither the House nor Senate bills would authorize the Secretary to take the transferred lands into trust as "restored lands" for the purpose of the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act, the report recommends the Secretary do so.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I understand the Rancheria can continue to operate its on-reservation casino should this project be implemented, and I do not oppose the Rancheria's right to do so because these lands are located within its traditional reservation boundary and were taken into trust before the enactment of the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act, IGRA, thus the casino was opened consistent with the requirements of IGRA. But as you know, I have long opposed off-reservation gaming, and while I understand that neither bill  would authorize gaming on the transferred parcels, I do not support the committee's recommendation that the Secretary declare these parcels "restored lands." As we know, should the Secretary declare the parcels as "restored lands," the Rancheria</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="MIDDLE CREEK PROJECT">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, the California delegation strongly supports the projects included in <bill type="s" number="1248">S. 1248</bill>. I hear the majority leader's concerns. Being chair of the committee, I, of course, support the language in the committee's recommendation with respect to the land transfer for the Robinson Rancheria, should the bill be enacted. While I may disagree with the leader's position as it concerns this particular project, I appreciate his comments and support for the legislation as a whole.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="MIDDLE CREEK PROJECT">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I appreciate the clarifications and explanations that my friend from California has provided.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="MIDDLE CREEK PROJECT">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
