<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1204045202" ordinal="46" title="IP-ENABLED VOICE COMMUNICATIONS AND PUBLIC SAFETY ACT OF 2007">
  <narrative>IP-ENABLED VOICE COMMUNICATIONS AND PUBLIC SAFETY ACT OF 2007 -- (Senate - February 26, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="1205">S1205</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300078" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ha ve a unanimous consent request that has been cleared on both sides. I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of Calendar No. 327, <bill type="s" number="428">S. 428</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the bill by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A bill (<bill type="s" number="428">S. 428</bill>) to amend the Wireless Communications and Public Safety Act of 1999, and for other purposes.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the bill, which had</narrative>
  <narrative> This Act may be cited as the "IP-Enabled Voice Communications and Public  Safety Act of 2007".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. DUTY TO PROVIDE 9-1-1 AND E-9-1-1 SERVICE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) IN GENERAL.--The Wireless Communications and Public Safety Act of 1999 (47 U.S.C. 615 et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;"SEC. 7. IP-ENABLED VOICE SERVICE PROVIDERS.</narrative>
  <narrative> "(a) IN GENERAL.--It shall be the duty of every IP-enabled voice service provider engaged in interstate or foreign communication to provide 9-1- 1 service, including enhanced 9-1-1 service, to its subscribers in accordance with orders of the Commission in effect on the date of enactment of the IP-Enabled Voice Communications and Public Safety Act of 2007, as such orders may be modified by the Commission from time to time.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(b) Access to 9-1-1 Components.--</narrative>
  <narrative> "(1) REGULATIONS.--Within 90 days after the date of enactment of the IP-Enabled Voice Communications and Public Safety Act of 2007, the Commission shall issue regulations g ranting IP-enabled voice service providers right of access to 9-1-1 components that are necessary to provide 9-1-1 service, on the same rates, terms, and conditions that are provided to commercial mobile service providers. In promulgating the regulations, the Commission shall take into account any technical, network</narrative>
  <narrative> "(c) SAVINGS CLAUSE.--Nothing in the IP-Enable d Voice Communications and Public Safety Act of 2007 shall be construed as repealing or otherwise altering, modifying, affecting, or superseding Federal regulations obligating an IP-enabled voice service provider to provide 9-1-1 service or enhanced 9-1-1 service.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(d) LIMITATION ON COMMISSION.--Nothing in this section shall be construed to permit the Commission to issue regulations that require or impose a specific technology or technological standard.</narrative>
  <narrative> "(e) &lt;b&gt;FCC AUTHORITY TO REQUIRE</narrative>
  <narrative> "(8)</narrative>
  <narrative> "(10) Enhanced ip-enabled 9-1-1 service.--The term</narrative>
  <narrative> (1) by striking "carrier," in subsection (a) and inserting "carrier, IP-enabled voice service provider, or alternat ive emergency communications service provider,";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) by striking "its" the first place it appears in subsection (a) and inserting "their";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) by striking "emergency calls or emergency services." in subsection (a) and inserting "emergency calls, emergency services, or alternative emergency communications services.";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) by striking "service shall" in subsection (b) and inserting "service, or IP-enabled voice service, shall";</narrative>
  <narrative> (5) by striking "wireless." in subsection (b) and in serting "wireless, IP-enabled, or alternative emergency communications.";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (6) by striking "communications," in subsection (c) and inserting "communications, IP-enabled voice service communications, or alternative emergency communications,"; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (7) by striking "wireless." in subsection (c) and inserting "wireless, IP-enabled, or alternative emergency communications.".</narrative>
  <narrative> (b) DEFINITIONS.--Section 6 of the Wireless Communications and Public Safety Act of 1999 (47 U.S.C. 615b), as amend ed by section 2(b), is further amended by adding at the end thereof the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(12) ALTERNATIVE EMERGENCY COMMUNICATIONS SERVICE.--The term `alternative emergency communications service' means the provision of emergency information to a public safety answering point via wire or radio communications, and may include 9-1-1 and enhanced 9-1-1 Services.</narrative>
  <narrative> "(13) ALTERNATIVE EMERGENCY COMMUNICATIONS SERVICE PROVIDER.--The term `alternative emergency communications service provider' me ans an entity other than a local exchange carrier, wireless carrier, or an IP-enabled voice service provider that is required by the Commission or, in the absence of any such requirement, is specifically authorized by the appropriate local or State 9-1-1 governing authority, to provide alternative emergency communications services.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 4. STATE AUTHORITY OF FEES.</narrative>
  <narrative> Nothing in this Act, the Communications Act of 1934 (47 U.S.C. 151 et seq.), the Wireless Communic ations and Public Safety Act of 1999 (47 U.S.C. 615a), or any Federal Communications Commission regulation or order shall prevent the imposition on, or collection by, a provider of IP-enabled voice services or commercial mobile service, of any fee or charge specifically designated by a State, political subdivision thereof, or Indian tribe for the support of 9-1-1 or E 099-1-1 services if that fee</narrative>
  <narrative> To ensure efficiency, transparency, and accountability in the collection and expenditure of 9-1-1 fees, the Federal Communica tions Commission shall submit a report within 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, to the Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the House of Representatives Committee on Energy and Commerce detailing the status in each State of the collection and distribution of 9-1-1 fees and include findings on the amount of</narrative>
  <narrative> "(1) NATIONAL PLAN REQUIRED.--No more than 270 days af ter the date of the enactment of the IP-Enabled Voice Communications and Public Safety Act of 2007, the Office shall develop and report to Congress on a national plan for migrating to a national IP-enabled emergency network capable of receiving and responding to all citizen activated emergency communications and improving information sharing among all emergency response entities.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(2) CONTENTS OF PLAN.--The plan required by paragraph (1) shall--</narrative>
  <narrative> "(A) outline the potential benefits of such a mig ration; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(B) identify barriers that must be overcome and funding mechanisms to address those barriers;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(C) provide specific mechanisms for ensuring the IP-enabled emergency network is available in every community and is coordinated on a local, regional, and Statewide basis;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(D) identify location technology for nomadic devices and for office buildings and multi-dwelling units;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(E) include a proposed timetable, an outline of costs and potential savings;</narrative>
  <narrative> "(F) provide specific</narrative>
  <narrative> "(I) document solutions</narrative>
  <narrative> "(3) CONSULTATION.--In developing the plan required by</narrative>
  <narrative> (b) AVAILABILITY OF PSAP INFORMATION.--The Federal Communications Commission may compile a list of public safety answering point contact infor mation, testing procedures, classes and types of services supported by public safety answering points, selective router contact information, or other information concerning necessary 9-1-1 components, for the purpose of assisting providers in complying with this section, and may make any portion of such information available to the public if such</narrative>
  <narrative> (4) Public Safety Answering Point certification and testing requireme nts;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) validation procedures for inputting and updating location information in relevant databases; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (6) the format for delivering address information to Public Safety Answering Points.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 7. ENFORCEMENT.</narrative>
  <narrative> The Commission shall enforce the Wireless Communications and Public Safety Act of 1999 (47 U.S.C. 615a) as if that Act were part of the Communications Act of 1934. For purposes of this section, any violation of the Wireless Communications and Public Sa fety Act of 1999 (47 U.S.C. 615a), or any regulation promulgated under that Act, is deemed to be a violation of the Communications Act of 1934 or a regulation promulgated under the Communications Act of 1934, respectively.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 8. COMPLETION OF THE HATFIELD REPORT.</narrative>
  <narrative> (a) IN GENERAL.--Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Federal Communications Commission shall remit all amounts promised for the completion of an update to the Report on T echnical and Operational Issues Impacting the Provision of Wireless Enhanced 9-1-1 Services by Dale N. Hatfield filed at the Commission on October 15, 2002, in WT Docket No. 02-46.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) SUBMISSION OF REPORT.--Mr. Hatfield shall submit his written findings as of May 1, 2006, to the Federal Communications Commission not later than 60 days after receiving the payment described in subsection (a).&lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300094" topic="SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I congratulate the Senator from Florida for this bill as modified. I think it is a step in the right direction. I am pleased to support the bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300078" topic="SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I thank the distinguished Senator from Alaska because he has been very much a part of this effort, along with Senator Inouye.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a result of several things they did, I now ask u nanimous consent that the amendment at the desk be considered and agreed to, the committee-reported substitute, as amended, be agreed to, the bill, as amended, be read a third time, passed, and the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table; and that any statements relating to the bill be printed in the Record, without intervening action or debate.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The amendment (No. 4086) was agreed to, as follows:</chair>
  <narrative>(Purpose: To clarify the FCC's authority to require 9-1-1 service, and for other purposes)</narrative>
  <narrative> On page 11, strike lines 1 through 7 and insert the following:</narrative>
  <narrative> "(e) FCC Authority To Require 9-1-1 Service.--The Commission may require any provider of a voice service that is a substitute for telephone exchan ge service (as defined in section 3(47) of the Communications Act of 1934 (47 U.S.C. 153(47))) to provide 9-1-1 service, including enhanced 9-1-1 service, to its subscribers. Nothing in this subsection shall limit or otherwise affect the authority of the Commission under the Communications Act of 1934 (47 U.S.C. 151 et seq.).".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; On page 11, beginning in line 12, strike "that term" and insert "the term `Interconnected VoIP Service' ".</narrative>
  <narrative> On page 11, beginning in line 14, strike "(47 C.F.R</narrative>
  <narrative> (b) AVAILABILITY OF PSAP INFORMATION.--The Federal Communications Commission may compile a list of public safety answering point contact information, as well as contact information for 9-1-1 component providers, for the purpose of assisting IP-enabled voice service providers and others in complying with this Act an d section 158(d) of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act (47 U.S.C. 942(d)) as amended by subsection (a), and may make any portion</narrative>
  <narrative> SEC. 7. Section 2301 of the Implementing Recommendations of the 9/11 Commission Act of 2007 (47 U.S.C. 901 no te) is amended by striking "the `Improving Emergency Communications Act of 2007'." and inserting "the `911 Modernization Act'.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The committee amendment, in the nature of a substitute, as amended, was agreed to.</narrative>
  <narrative>The bill (<bill type="s" number="428">S. 428</bill>), as amended, was ordered to be engrossed for a third reading, was read the third time, and passed, as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="s" number="428">S. 428</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "IP-Enabled Voice Communications and Public Safety Act of 2007".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. DUTY TO PROVIDE 9-1-1 AND E-9-1-1 SERVICE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) IN GENERAL.--The Wireless Communications and Public Safety Act of 1999 (47 U.S.C. 615 et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;"SEC. 7. IP-ENABLED VOICE SERVICE PROVIDERS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(a) IN GENERAL.--It shall be the duty of every IP-enabled voice service provider engaged in interstate or foreign communication to provide 9-1-1 service, including enhanced 9-1 91 service, to its subscribers in accordance with orders of the Commission in effect on the date of enactment of the IP-Enabled Voice Communications and Public Safety Act of 2007, as such orders may be modified by the Commission from time to time.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(b) Access to 9-1-1 Components.--</narrative>
  <narrative> "(1) REGULATIONS.--Within 90 days after the date of enactment of the IP-Enabled Voice Communications and Public Safety Act of 2007, the Commission shall issue regulations granting IP-enabled voice service pro viders right of access to 9-1-1 components that are necessary to provide 9-1-1 service, on the same rates, terms, and conditions that are provided to commercial mobile service providers. In promulgating the regulations, the Commission shall take into account any technical, network</narrative>
  <narrative> "(c) SAVINGS CLAUSE.--Nothing in the IP-Enabled Voice Communications and Public Sa fety Act of 2007 shall be construed as repealing or otherwise altering, modifying, affecting, or superseding Federal regulations obligating an IP-enabled voice service provider to provide 9-1-1 service or enhanced 9-1-1 service.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(d) LIMITATION ON COMMISSION.--Nothing in this section shall be construed to permit the Commission to issue regulations that require or impose a specific technology or technological standard.</narrative>
  <narrative> "(e) FCC Authority To Require 9-1-1 Service.--The Commission</narrative>
  <narrative> "(10</narrative>
  <narrative> (1) by striking "carrier," in subsection (a) and inserting "c arrier, IP-enabled voice service provider, or alternative emergency communications service provider,";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) by striking "its" the first place it appears in subsection (a) and inserting "their";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) by striking "emergency calls or emergency services." in subsection (a) and inserting "emergency calls, emergency services, or alternative emergency communications services.";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) by striking "service shall" in subsection (b) and inserting "service, or IP-enabled voice service, shall";</narrative>
  <narrative/>
  <narrative> (b) DEFINITIONS.--Section 6 of the Wireless Communications an d Public Safety Act of 1999 (47 U.S.C. 615b), as amended by section 2(b), is further amended by adding at the end thereof the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(12) ALTERNATIVE EMERGENCY COMMUNICATIONS SERVICE.--The term `alternative emergency communications service' means the provision of emergency information to a public safety answering point via wire or radio communications, and may include 9-1-1 and enhanced 9-1-1 Services.</narrative>
  <narrative> "(13) ALTERNATIVE EMERGENCY COMMUNICATIONS SERVICE PROVIDER.--The term `alt ernative emergency communications service provider' means an entity other than a local exchange carrier, wireless carrier, or an IP-enabled voice service provider that is required by the Commission or, in the absence of any such requirement, is specifically authorized by the appropriate local or State 9-1-1 governing authority, to provide alternative emergency communications services.".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 4. STATE AUTHORITY OF FEES.</narrative>
  <narrative> Nothing in this Act, the Communications Act  of 1934 (47 U.S.C. 151 et seq.), the Wireless Communications and Public Safety Act of 1999 (47 U.S.C. 615a), or any Federal Communications Commission regulation or order shall prevent the imposition on, or collection by, a provider of IP-enabled voice services or commercial mobile service, of any fee or charge specifically designated by a State, political subdivision thereof, or Indian tribe for the support of 9-1-1 or E 099-1-1 services if that fee</narrative>
  <narrative> To ensure efficiency, transparency, and accountability in the collection an d expenditure of 9-1-1 fees, the Federal Communications Commission shall submit a report within 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, to the Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the House of Representatives Committee on Energy and Commerce detailing the status in each State of the collection and distribution of 9-1-1 fees and include findings on the amount of</narrative>
  <narrative> "(1)</narrative>
  <narrative> "(E) include a proposed timetable, an outline of costs an d potential savings;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(F) provide specific legislative language, if necessary, for achieving the plan;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(G) provide recommendations on any legislative changes, including updating definitions, to facilitate a national IP-enabled emergency network;</narrative>
  <narrative> "(H) assess, collect, and analyze the experiences of the PSAPs and related public safety authorities who are conducting trial deployments of IP-enabled emergency networks as of the date of enactment of the IP-Enabled Voice Communications and Public S afety Act of 2007;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(I) document solutions that a national IP-enabled emergency network will provide for 9-1-1 access to those with disabilities and needed steps to implement such solutions, including a recommended timeline for such implementation; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(J) analyze technologies and efforts to provide automatic location capabilities and provide recommendations on needed regulatory or legislative changes necessary to implement automatic location solutions for 9-1-1 purposes.</narrative>
  <narrative> "(3) CON SULTATION.--In developing the plan required by paragraph (1), the Office shall consult with representatives of the public safety community, groups representing those with disabilities, technology and telecommunications providers, and others it deems appropriate."; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) by striking "services." in subsection (b)(1) and inserting "services, and for migration to an IP-enabled emergency network.".</narrative>
  <narrative> (b) AVAILABILITY OF PSAP INFORMATION.--The Federal Communications Commission may compile a list</narrative>
  <narrative> (3) call-handling in the event of call over flow or network outages;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) Public Safety Answering Point certification and testing requirements;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) validation procedures for inputting and updating location information in relevant databases; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (6) the format for delivering address information to Public Safety Answering Points.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 7. ENFORCEMENT.</narrative>
  <narrative> The Federal Communications Commission shall enforce the Wireless Communications and Public Safety Act of 1999 (47 U.S.C. 615a) as if that Act were part of</narrative>
  <narrative> (a) IN GENERAL.--Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act,  the Federal Communications Commission shall remit all amounts promised for the completion of an update to the Report on Technical and Operational Issues Impacting the Provision of Wireless Enhanced 9-1-1 Services by Dale N. Hatfield filed at the Commission on October 15, 2002, in WT Docket No. 02-46. &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) SUBMISSION OF REPORT.--Mr. Hatfield shall submit his written findings as of May 1, 2006, to the Federal Communications Commission not later than 60 days after receiving the payment desc ribed in subsection (a).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 9. 9/11 COMMISSION ACT OF 2007.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Section 2301 of the Implementing Recommendations of the 9/11 Commission Act of 2007 (47 U.S.C. 901 note) is amended by striking "the `Improving Emergency Communications Act of 2007'." and inserting "the `911 Modernization Act'.".</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300078" topic="SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I thank the Senate. This has been 2 years coming because 2 years ago, a young mother in Deltona, FL, which is north of Orlando in Volusia County, watched her baby die as she tried in vain to reach emergency 911. She had a telephone that she did not realize, because it was voice over the Internet, there was no provision for emergency 911 services.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Following that tragedy of the death of that child, where a 911 emergency response team never arrived because they di d not receive the call, we introduced this bipartisan legislation that requires all VOIP providers to offer the emergency 911 service, and this legislation gives them the tools they need in order to do that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have been working on this legislation a long time. It passed the Commerce Committee unanimously in 2005. It was also added to a Senate port security bill in 2006, and then the conference committee stripped it out.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since the bill was first introduced, to the credit of the Federal Communication s Commission, they took some action to require that VOIP customers have full access to the emergency 911. We appreciate that very much. But there are holes in those regulations. Those holes need to be filled, and this legislation we passed tonight--and is very similar to a House bill that passed a couple of months ago--will fill those legislative holes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation will resolve any remaining questions regarding the Federal Communications Commission jurisdiction over VOIP services by requiring full ac cess to 911 service by the VOIP customers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill also resolves any issues relating to the potential liability of the VOIP providers that offer access to 911 services. The legislation also requires the national E-911 Implementation Coordination Office to work with industry to oversee the next generation of emergency 911 network.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This network is going to be resilient and redundant. It is going to allow 911 calls to automatically be routed to a functional 911 call center in the event of a disaste r. Think about what happened down in New Orleans during Katrina. We had a certain way these 911 calls had to go to get to the emergency call center. Some of those lines were out of service, and so those calls never got there.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This new system is going to send these little packets of information in any route it can to get to that call center. It is going to be redundant, it is going to be resilient so we will not have a repeat of people desperately down in New Orleans making 911 calls and not getting a re sponse.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a chart that pretty well depicts that every day thousands of Americans rely on these call centers so they can reach responders, and every day we have to wait to upgrade the network and those lives are at risk.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have gone all the way from just the rotary service telephones to the future, where we have something like these iPhones we have today that have so many different services on them. We need a system that can get this emergency service through these new kinds of mechanisms. Tha t is what we are going to do.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Going back to this terrible tragedy that happened a couple years ago in my State, this is just one newspaper headline that said trying to get that 911 call, it couldn't go because there was not a provision in VOIP.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Lives have been lost. Lives were at risk. They are still at risk until we can get this legislation signed into law. I am extremely grateful to the Senate for having passed this legislation tonight.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
