<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1182960005" ordinal="37" title="HONORING J. CLEVELAND CADY">
  <speaking speaker="300026" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today I wish to recognize the contributions of a New Yorker with North Dakota ties--J. Cleveland Cady.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A few weeks ago while reading the New York Times, I happened across an article that referenced Mr. Cady's contributions to Manhattan's architecture. Mr. Cady was a prominent architect in New York during the late 1800s. He designed the American Museum of Natural History as well as the original Metropolitan Opera House. He also designed a significant portion of a fairly notable institution we know today as Yale University.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This article caught my eye because of a special connection between Mr. Cady and the State of North Dakota.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Early in the last century, a young North Dakotan named William Langer was attending a concert during his time at Columbia University when he noticed a beautiful woman sitting below him on the orchestra level. According to the William Langer Papers  collected at the University of North Dakota, Mr. Langer was fond of recalling how he managed to have the woman's date called away on a phantom phone call. Seizing his opportunity, Mr. Langer approached the  young lady and struck up a conversation. They began a long courtship shortly thereafter before marrying in 1918.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That woman was Lydia Cady, the daughter of J. Cleveland Cady.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sadly, Mr. Cady died just 1 year after his daughter's wedding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, as the New York Times piece indicates, Mr. Cady's momentous architectural contributions continue to shape the landscape of New York City today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In much the same way, his son-in-law's achievements played a key role in shaping the North Dakota of today. "Wild Bill" Langer was a larger-than-life figure in North Dakota politics for nearly half a century. Mr. Langer was elected attorney general of North Dakota in 1916. He went on to be elected Governor of North Dakota in 1932 and again in 1936. He then represented North Dakota in the U.S. Senate from 1941 to 1959, holding the seat I am now privileged to hold. In the Senate, Bill Langer  was a champion for a range of issues that remain important to North Dakota today, including rural electrification, agriculture, and health care.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the New York Times article on Mr. Cady's architecture be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
</record>
