<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1181750406" ordinal="60" title="NATIONAL HUNTINGTON'S DISEASE AWARENESS DAY">
  <speaking speaker="400272" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate now proceed to the consideration of <bill type="sr" number="234">S. Res. 234</bill>, which was submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300055" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I rise today to support a resolution designating June 15, 2007, as "National Huntington's Disease Awareness Day," a devastating disorder that affects an estimated 1 in every 10,000 persons. We need to raise awareness of Huntington's disease, which is a progressive degenerative neurological disease that causes total physical and mental deterioration over a 12-15 year period. Though Huntington's disease typically begins in midlife, between the ages of 30 and 45, onset  may occur as early as the age of 2. The average lifespan after onset of Huntington's disease is 10 to 20 years. The younger a person contracts the disease, the more rapid the progression. Additionally, children who develop the juvenile form of the disease rarely live to adulthood, and a child of a Huntington's disease parent has a 50-50 chance of inheriting the Huntington's disease gene.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since the discovery of the gene that causes Huntington's disease in 1993, the pace of Huntington's disease research has accelerated. Although scientists and researchers are hopeful that breakthroughs are forthcoming, no cures for this disease currently exist.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The need for heightened awareness of Huntington's disease was brought to my attention by constituents who suffer from this disease. For the benefit of these individuals and for the well-being of sufferers in your own State and around the Nation, I ask you to join me in this effort to raise awareness of Huntington's disease.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400272" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motion to reconsider be laid on the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
