<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1184040000" ordinal="40" title="MAKING MINORITY PARTY APPOINTMENTS">
  <narrative>MAKING MINORITY PARTY APPOINTMENTS -- (Senate - July 10, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="8964">S8964</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate now proceed to the consideration of <bill type="sr" number="266">S. Res. 266</bill>, which was submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <chair>The assistant legislative clerk read as follows:</chair>
  <chair>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="266">S. Res. 266</bill>) making minority party appointments for the 110th Congress.</chair>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent the resolution be agreed to, and the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="266">S. Res. 266</bill>) was agreed to, as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="266">S. Res. 266</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Resolved, That the following be the minority membership on the following committees for the remainder of the 110th Congress, or until their successors are appointed:</chair>
  <chair>The Committee on Energy and Natural Resources: Mr. Domenici, Mr. Craig, Ms. Murkowski, Mr. Burr, Mr. DeMint, Mr. Corker, Mr. Barrasso, Mr. Sessions, Mr. Smith, Mr. Bunning, and Mr. Martinez;</chair>
  <chair>The Committee on Environment and Public Works: Mr. Inhofe, Mr. Warner, Mr. Voinovich, Mr. Isakson, Mr. Vitter, Mr. Barrasso, Mr. Craig, Mr. Alexander and Mr. Bond;</chair>
  <chair>The Committee on Finance: Mr. Grassley, Mr. Hatch, Mr. Lott, Ms. Snowe, Mr. Kyl, Mr. Smith, Mr. Bunning, Mr. Crapo, Mr. Roberts and Mr. Ensign;</chair>
  <chair>The Committee on Indian Affairs: Ms. Murkowski, Mr. McCain, Mr. Coburn, Mr. Barrasso, Mr. Domenici, Mr. Smith and Mr. Burr.</chair>
</record>
