<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1170781203" ordinal="40" title="DESIGNATING FEBRUARY 6, 2007, AS &quot;RONALD REAGAN DAY&quot;">
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the consideration of <bill type="sr" number="73">S. Res. 73</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will state the resolution by title.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300003" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, the resolution I am honored to submit today with my colleague, Senator Feinstein, is to commemorate today, February 6, 2007--what would be Ronald Reagan's 96th birthday--as Ronald Reagan Day.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>President Ronald Wilson Reagan, a man of humble background, worked throughout his life serving freedom and advancing the public good, having been employed as an entertainer, union leader, corporate spokesman, Governor of California and President of the United States. In 1981, when Ronald Reagan was inaugurated President, he inherited a disillusioned Nation shackled by rampant inflation and high unemployment. During Mr. Reagan's presidency he worked in a bipartisan manner to enact his bold agenda  of restoring accountability and common sense to government, which led to an unprecedented economic expansion and opportunity for millions of Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Reagan's commitment to an active social policy agenda for the Nation's children helped lower crime and drug use in our neighborhoods. President Reagan's commitment to our armed forces contributed to the restoration of pride in America, in her values and in those cherished by the free world, and prepared America's Armed Forces to meet 21st Century challenges. President Reagan's vision of "peace through strength" led to the end of the Cold War and the ultimate demise of the Soviet Union,  guaranteeing basic human rights for millions of people. It is entirely appropriate that on February 6, 2007, which will be the 96th anniversary of Ronald Reagan's birth, and the third since his passing, we declare February 6th, 2007, to be Ronald Reagan Day and urge all citizens to take cognizance of this event and participate fittingly in its observance.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300072" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that I be added as a cosponsor to this resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that I also be added as a cosponsor to this resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and that the motion to reconsider laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
