<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1169614800" ordinal="36" title="STATEMENTS ON INTRODUCED BILLS AND JOINT RESOLUTIONS">
  <speaking speaker="400621" topic="Introducing S. 371. A bill to amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to clarify the house parent exemption to certain wage and hour requirements; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="371">S. 371</bill>] Mr. President, today I rise to discuss an issue that is near and dear to my heart, because it involves children and youth in our foster care system. Inconsistencies in our Federal wage laws, coupled with increases in the minimum wage, are financially crippling the private, non-profit organizations and institutions that make up a necessary part of our communities' support systems for the most vulnerable in our society, the children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>More than 500,000 children are in America's foster care system at any given time, because their own families are in crisis or unable to provide for their essential well-being--most because they have been subject to abuse and neglect. Thankfully, most of these children are able to be placed with individual caring families. But for those children without a suitable or available foster family, they are placed in one of the many group homes associated with our foster care system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many of these group homes are specially tailored to the specific needs of foster care children by offering unique programs and on-site education to help heal the emotional scarring they have experienced.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These homes--often run by private, non-profit organizations--are dedicated to providing residential care and treatment for the "orphans of the living," and they have long been a vital part of the social service networks in America's communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An essential component of the foster care network is the presence of caring parents in a family-like situation. And as in traditional parenting, the houseparents of group foster homes seek to provide the same love, care, and supervision of a traditional family for the five to eight children that reside with them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Houseparents volunteer to permanently reside at the group home in order to create a family- like environment for those without a true sense of home--one that offers a structured atmosphere where these most vulnerable youth can heal, grow, and become productive members of society.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Foster care alumni studies show us that it is the consistent and life-long connection of caring foster parents that plays the biggest role in helping foster children transition into society.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, our current laws are working against this cause, forcing group homes to move away from what they know is best for the children and preventing them from providing the most appropriate and consistent care. These youth so desperately need the stability that a family- like situation can provide. And this is what my amendment seeks to address.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Traditionally, in addition to a modest, fixed salary, houseparents have received food, lodging, insurance, and transportation free of charge.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1974, Congress recognized and confirmed the unique role houseparents serve when it passed the Hershey Exemption. This amended the Fair Labor Standards Act to preserve the appropriate method of compensation for houseparents--and allowed the lodging and food provided them to be considered when determining an appropriate salary for married houseparents serving with their spouse at nonprofit educational institutions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Through this exemption, Congress supplied a way for these vital social services to continue to be provided by non-profit organizations in a way that is cost-effective, and at the same time appropriate and meaningful to both the children and the houseparents.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, since the addition of this exemption, the demographics of America and of America's foster children have changed. Research now shows that due to the negative experiences some youth have faced, they may find a better environment for growth and healing in having a single houseparent of the same sex.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our labor standards for these group homes have not kept pace with the ever-changing needs of these children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because the Hershey Exemption was only extended to married couples, group homes are now forced to choose between what is cheaper and what is best for the children. Unfortunately, the financial realities of the situation  place these facilities in a compromising situation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>You see, when a group home employs a single houseparent for a home, they are required to pay them as an hourly employee, whereas married houseparents serving together are allowed to be paid as salaried employees.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a result, it costs a facility in Florida more than $74,000 annually at the current minimum wage rate to provide a full-time, single houseparent using the traditional live-in model.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In response, most facilities have resorted to teams of houseparents that work in 8 or 12 hour shifts--just to avoid the additional costs of overtime pay. Yet even this team model is pricey and means tough coordination and inconsistencies in care for these children. It also destroys the family-like arrangement of the home.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If the minimum wage bill--to which I am offering this bill as an amendment--passes, it will cost facilities across the U.S. in excess of $84,000 annually to house and employ a single, full-time houseparent in a foster care or educational group home. However, if it were a married couple serving in the same environment it would only require minimum wage guidelines being met.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Can you see how this inconsistency in our labor laws is, and will continue to be, crippling for the private, non-profit facilities?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In order to enable group homes to provide the most appropriate and consistent care for foster and emotionally scarred youth, my amendment will extend the Hershey Exemption to single houseparents, allowing them to be treated as salaried employees when free lodging and board are provided.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Voting in favor of my amendment will enable private, non-profit group homes to continue providing these vital services for our communities, with a stronger atmosphere of love and growth for the children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Voting against this amendment will--that is, allowing it not to pass--will mean that the already heavy financial burden for these facilities will continue to grow. Homes will be forced to close or have to scale back on the number of children they can help.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To vote against this amendment is to turn children out on the street at a time when they need us most.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a loving parent and grandparent, I want what is best for my children and for my grandchildren--I want to make sure they have whatever they need to overcome the obstacles of life and succeed. This is also what we should seek for foster children and the hurting youth in our communities--to provide the loving homes and facilities for them that provide what they need most and in the most appropriate and consistent way possible.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of this bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be reprinted in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300036" topic="Introducing S. 374. A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide the same capital gains treatment for art and collectibles as for other investment property and to provide that a deduction equal to fair market value shall be allowed for charitable contributions of literary, musical, artistic, or scholarly compositions created by the donor; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="374">S. 374</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to introduce again legislation to eliminate one of the great inconsistencies in the Internal Revenue Code. I would like to thank my colleague, the senior Senator from New York, Senator SCHUMER, for again working with me on this important piece of legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill we are introducing today is designed to restore some internal consistency to the tax code as it applies to art and artists. No one has ever said that the tax code is fair even though it has always been a theoretical objective of the code to treat similar taxpayers similarly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our bill would address two areas where similarly situated taxpayers are not treated the same. These two areas are internal inconsistencies contained within the tax code. Internal inconsistency number one deals with the long-term capital gains tax treatment of investments in art and collectibles. The second internal inconsistency involves how charitable contributions of art by the artist are treated under the law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Long-term capital gains tax treatment of art is inherently unfair. If a person invests in stocks or bonds and sells at a gain, the tax treatment is long term capital gains. The top capital gains tax rate is 15 percent. However, if the same person invests in art or collectibles the top rate is hiked up to 28 percent. Art for art's sake should not incur a higher tax rate simply for revenue's sake. That is a big impact on the pocketbook of the investor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Art and collectibles are alternatives to financial instruments as an investment choice. To create a tax disadvantage with respect to one investment compared to another creates an artificial market and may lead to poor investment allocations. It also adversely impacts those who make their livelihood in the cultural sectors of the economy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Santa Fe, NM, is the third largest art market in the country. We have a diverse colony of artists, collectors and  gallery owners. We have fabulous Native American rug weavers, potters and carvers. Creative giants like Georgia O'Keeffe, Maria Martinez, E. L. Blumenshein, Allan Houser, R.C. Gorman, and Glenna Goodacre have all chosen New Mexico as their home and as their artistic subject. John Nieto, Wilson Hurley, Clark Hulings, Veryl Goodnight, Bill  Acheff, Susan Rothenberg, Bruce Nauman, Agnes Martin, Doug Hyde, Margaret Nez, and Dan Ostermiller are additional examples of living artists creating art in New Mexico.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Art, antiques, and collectibles are a $12 to $20 billion annual industry nationwide. In New Mexico, it has been estimated that art and collectible sales range between $500 million and one billion a year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Economists have always been interested in the economics of the arts. Adam Smith is a well-known economist. He was also a serious, but little-known essayist on painting, dancing, and poetry. Similarly, Keynes was both a famous economist and a passionate devotee of painting. However, even artistically inclined economists have found it difficult to define art within the context of economic theory.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When asked to define jazz, Louis Armstrong replied: "If you gotta ask, you ain't never going to know." A similar conundrum has challenged Galbraith and other economists who have grappled with the definitional issues associated with bringing art within the economic calculus. Original art objects are, as a commodity group, characterized by a set of attributes: every unit of output is differentiated from every other unit of output; art works can be copied but not reproduced; and the cultural capital  of the nation has significant elements of public good.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because art works can be resold, and their prices may rise over time, they have the characteristics of financial assets, and as such may be sought as a hedge against inflation, as a store of wealth, or as a source of speculative capital gain. A study by Keishiro Matsumoto, Samuel Andoh and James P. Hoban, Jr. assessed the risk-adjusted rates of return on art sold at Sotheby's during the 14-year period ending September 30, 1989. They concluded that art was a good investment in terms of average  real rates of return. Several studies found that rates of return from the price appreciation on paintings, comic books, collectibles and modern prints usually made them very attractive long-term investments. Also, when William Goetzmann was at the Columbia Business School, he constructed an art index and concluded that painting price movements and stock market fluctuations are correlated.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I conclude that with art, as well as stocks, past performance is no guarantee of future returns, but the gains should be taxed the same.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1990, the editor of Art and Auction asked the question: "Is there an `efficient' art market?" A well-known art dealer answered "Definitely not. That's one of the things that makes the market so interesting." For everyone who has been watching world financial markets lately, the art market may be a welcome distraction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Why do people invest in art and collectibles? Art and collectibles are something you can appreciate even if the investment doesn't appreciate. Art is less volatile. If buoyant and not so buoyant bond prices drive you berserk and spiraling stock prices scare you, art may be the appropriate investment for you. Because art and collectibles are investments, the long-term capital gains tax treatment should be the same as for stocks and bonds. This bill would accomplish that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Artists will benefit. Gallery owners will benefit. Collectors will benefit. And museums benefit from collectors. About 90 percent of what winds up in museums like New York's Metropolitan Museum of Art comes from collectors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Collecting isn't just for the hoyty toity. It seems that everyone collects something. Some collections are better investments than others. Some collections are just bizarre. The internet makes collecting big business, and flea market fanatics are avid collectors. In fact, people collect the darndest things. Books, duck decoys, chia pets, snowglobes, thimbles, handcuffs, spectacles, baseball cards, teddy bears, and guns are a few such "collectibles".</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For most of these collections, capital gains isn't really an issue, but you never know. You may find that your collecting passion has created a tax predicament--to phrase it politely. Art and collectibles are tangible assets. When you sell them, capital gains tax is due on any appreciation over your purchase price.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill provides capital gains tax parity because it lowers the top capital gains rate from 28 percent to 15 percent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As I stated earlier, the second internal inconsistency deals with the charitable deduction for artists donating their work to a museum or other charitable cause. When someone is asked to make a charitable contribution to a museum or to a fund raising auction, it shouldn't matter whether that person is an artist or not. Under current law, however, it makes a big difference. As the law stands now, an artist/creator can only take a deduction equal to the cost of the art supplies. Our bill will allow  a fair market deduction for the artist.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It's important to note that our bill includes certain safeguards to keep the artist from "painting himself a tax deduction." This bill applies to literary, musical, artistic, and scholarly compositions if the work was created at least 18 months before the donation was made, has been appraised, and is related to the purpose or function of the charitable organization receiving the donation. As with other charitable contributions, it is limited to 50 percent of adjusted gross income (AGI). If  it is also a capital gain, there is a 30 percent of AGI limit. Mr. President, I believe these safeguards bring fairness back into the code and protect the Treasury against any potential abuse.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I hope my colleagues will help us put this internal consistency into the Internal Revenue Code.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="Introducing S. 376. A bill to amend title 18, United States Code, to improve the provisions relating to the carrying of concealed weapons by law enforcement officers, and for other purposes; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="376">S. 376</bill>] Mr. President, in 2003, Senator Campbell and I, joined by 68 other Senators, introduced a bill that allowed a qualified retired or current law enforcement officer to carry a concealed firearm across State lines. The Senate passed our bill by unanimous consent, which was signed into law in July 2004. Passage of the Law Enforcement Safety Officers Act was a resounding vote of confidence in the men and women who serve their communities as protectors of the peace, and their Nation as the  first line of defense in any emergency.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But since enactment of the Law Enforcement Officers Safety Act, it has become clear that qualified retired officers have been subject to varying and complex certification procedures from State to State. In many cases, differing interpretations have complicated the implementation of the law, and retired officers have experienced significant frustration in getting certified to lawfully carry a firearm.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With the input of the law enforcement community, this bill proposes modest amendments to streamline the current law, which will give retired officers more flexibility in obtaining certification, and provides room for the variability in certification standards among the several States. For example, where a State has not set active duty standards, the retired officer can be certified pursuant to the standards set by any law enforcement agency in the State.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to these adjustments, the bill also makes clear that Amtrak officers, along with officers of the Executive branch of the Federal Government, are covered by the law. The bill also reduces from 15 to 10 the years of service required for a retired officer to qualify under the law. Though these changes broaden the reach of the law, the requirements for eligibility still involve a significant term of service for a retired officer to qualify, and a demonstrated commitment to law enforcement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill makes sensible improvements to existing law by providing the flexibility needed to permit qualified retired law enforcement officers to carry concealed firearms in a legal and responsible manner.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With the enactment of the Law Enforcement Officers Safety Act, Congress and the President also recognized that law enforcement officers are never "off-duty." The dedicated public servants who are trained to uphold the law and keep the peace deserve our support not just in their professional lives, but also when they go off-duty or into retirement. Convicted criminals often have long and exacting memories, and to the extent we can, we must aid these public servants with the tools they need to  keep themselves and their families safe. Because one thing we know for sure is that a law enforcement officer is a target, whether in uniform or out, and whether active or retired. We also act in our own interest when we help law enforcement officers with the ability to answer the call of duty wherever they may be. Society's trust in the men and women who serve should include the faith that the responsibilities we entrust to them do not disappear once State lines are crossed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 2004, Congress listened carefully to the concerns of the law enforcement community and responded appropriately. Let us do so again with these sensible improvements.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask for unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300070" topic="Introducing S. 377. A bill to establish a United States-Poland parliamentary youth exchange program, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Foreign Relations.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="377">S. 377</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to offer legislation urging the Administration to develop a United States-Poland Parliamentary Youth Exchange Program. I am pleased that my colleague from Indiana, Congressman PETE VISCLOSKY, has agreed to again introduce this important legislation in the House of Representatives. I appreciate his strong leadership in our continued joint efforts in this and many other areas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of this exchange program is to demonstrate to the youth of the United States and Poland the benefits of friendly cooperation between the U.S. and Poland based on common political and cultural values. I have long been an active supporter of the Congress-Bundestag Exchange program and am hopeful that this new endeavor will make similarly important lasting contributions to the U.S.-Polish relationship.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a Rhodes Scholar, I had the opportunity to discover international education at Pembroke College--my first trip outside of the United States. The parameters of my imagination expanded enormously during this time, as I gained a sense of how large the world was, how many talented people there were, and how many opportunities one could embrace. Student exchange programs do more than benefit individual scholars and advance human knowledge. Such programs expand ties between nations, improve international  commerce, encourage cooperative solutions to global problems, prevent war, and give participants a chance to develop a sense of global service and responsibility.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Funding a great foreign exchange program is a sign of both national pride and national humility. Implicit in such a program is the view that people from other nations view one's country and educational system as a beacon of knowledge--as a place where international scholars would want to study and live. But it is also an admission that a nation does not have all the answers--that our national understanding of the world is incomplete. It is an admission that we are just a part of a much larger  world that has intellectual, scientific, and moral wisdom that we need to learn.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The United States and Poland have enjoyed close bilateral relations since the end of the Cold War. Most recently, Poland has been a strong supporter of efforts led by the United States to combat global terrorism, and has contributed troops to and led coalitions in both Afghanistan and Iraq. Poland also cooperates closely with the United States on such issues as democratization, human rights, regional cooperation in Eastern Europe, and reform of the United Nations. As a member of the North Atlantic  Treaty Organization (NATO) and the European Union (EU), Poland has demonstrated its commitment to democratic values and is a role model in its region.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe that it is important to invest in the youth of the United States and Poland in order to strengthen long-lasting ties between both societies. After receiving for many years international and U.S. financial assistance, Poland is now determined to invest its own resources toward funding a U.S.-Poland exchange program. To this end the Polish Foreign Minister unambiguously stated that Poland welcomed the opportunity to be an equal partner in funding important efforts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last year the Senate approved a similar version of this legislation by unanimous consent. I ask my colleagues to again support this resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="Introducing S. 378. A bill to amend title 18, United States Code, to protect judges, prosecutors, witnesses, victims, and their family members, and for other purposes; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="378">S. 378</bill>] Mr. President, I was disappointed at the end of last Congress that, like so much other urgent business of the American people left unattended, we did not pass a measure to improve court security. We made some progress on this important issue when the Senate passed a consensus bipartisan court security bill. Unfortunately we were unable to cross the finish line because the House Republican leadership did not take up this bill. And so that still eaves our Nation's judges and their families  without the vital protections that bill would have provided.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, I join with other Senators on both sides of the aisle to try again. Along with the Majority Leader Senator REID; the Judiciary Committee's Ranking Member, Senator SPECTER; the Majority Whip, Senator DURBIN; and Senators KENNEDY, SCHUMER, CORNYN, HATCH and COLLINS, I introduce the Court Security Improvement Act of 2007, a consensus measure with bipartisan support nearly identical to the bill we passed in the Senate last December. House Judiciary Chairman</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is an important issue, and one I plan to make a priority this Congress. I hope that we can have quick action on this bill to bring to fruition our efforts to provide increased security, an effort that gained new urgency after the tragedy that befell Judge Joan Lefkow of Chicago. She is the Federal judge whose mother and husband were murdered in their home. As we heard in her courageous testimony in May 2005 before the Judiciary Committee, this tragedy provided a terrible reminder not only  of the vulnerable position of our judges and their families, but of the critical importance of protecting judges both where they work and where they and their families live. The shooting last summer of a State judge in Nevada provided another terrible reminder of the vulnerable position of our Nation's State and Federal judges. We cannot tolerate or excuse or justify violence or the threat of violence against judges.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In a speech last year, Justice Sandra Day O'Connor criticized the uncivil tone of attacks on the courts, noting that they pose a danger to the very independence of the Federal judiciary. It is most unfortunate that some in this country have chosen to use dangerous and irresponsible rhetoric when talking about judges, comparing judges to terrorists and threatening judges with punishment for decisions they do not like. This rhetoric can only foster unacceptable violence against judges and it must  stop, for the sake of our judges and the independence of the judiciary. Judicial fairness and independence are essential if we are to maintain our freedoms. Our independent judiciary is the envy of the rest of the world and a great source of our national strength and resilience. Let no one say things that might bring about further threats against our judges. We ought to be protecting them physically and institutionally.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When I last chaired the Judiciary Committee, one of my first efforts was pushing for passage of the Judicial Protection Act, which toughened criminal penalties for assaults against judges and their families. In order to meet the continuing challenges of keeping the Federal judiciary safe, in the last Congress Chairman SPECTER and I introduced <bill type="s" number="1968">S. 1968</bill>, the Court Security Improvement Act of 2005.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill we are introducing today in the Senate and House is a consensus bipartisan bill. I hope that quick action and passage of this bill can serve as a model for what we can achieve with bipartisan cooperation in the 110th Congress. Its core provisions, which previously passed the Senate not only last December, but also in June as part of the managers' package of the "John Warner National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2007," <bill type="s" number="2766">S. 2766</bill>, come the Court Security Improvement Act of  2005.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill responds to the needs expressed by the Federal judiciary for a  greater voice in working with the United States Marshals Service to determine their security needs. It enacts new criminal penalties for the misuse of restricted personal information to harm or threaten to harm Federal judges, their families or other individuals performing official duties. It enacts criminal penalties for threatening Federal judges and Federal law enforcement officials  by the malicious filing of false liens, and provides increased protections for witnesses. The bill also contains provisions making available to States new resources to improve security for State and local court systems as well as providing additional protections for law enforcement officers. I am pleased that the bill includes an extension of life insurance benefits to bankruptcy, magistrate and territorial judges.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, the bill contains provisions that have passed the Senate several times extending and expanding to family members the authority of the Judicial Conference to redact certain information from a Federal judge's mandatory financial disclosure. This expired redaction authority was used in circumstances in which the release of the information could endanger the filer or the filer's family. I hope that we can reinstate and expand this much needed redaction authority.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These protections are crucial to the preservation of the independence of our Federal judiciary so that it can continue to serve as a bulwark protecting individual rights and liberty. Our Nation's Founders knew that without an independent judiciary to protect individual rights from the political branches of government, those rights and privileges would amount to nothing. It is the ultimate check and balance in our system of government in times of heated political rhetoric.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We owe it to our judges to better protect them and their families from violence and to ensure that they have the peace of mind necessary to do their vital and difficult jobs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="Introducing S. 378. A bill to amend title 18, United States Code, to protect judges, prosecutors, witnesses, victims, and their family members, and for other purposes; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>An independent judiciary is essential to the proper administration of justice. In order to maintain an independent judiciary, it is imperative that judges be protected from the threat of reprisal, so that fear does not influence their decisionmaking. This bill, which I am proud to cosponsor, is an opportunity to protect our judges and help guarantee their independence, and also protect the many other dedicated men and women who serve our judiciary and their families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In recent years, the need for increased judicial security has been highlighted by a number of attacks. After an unfavorable trademark ruling in Chicago, a disgruntled litigant murdered a Federal judge's husband and mother in the judge's home. Two weeks later a State judge, a court reporter, and a sheriff's deputy were killed in an Atlanta courthouse. A year after that, death threats were made against U.S. Supreme Court Justices.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These attacks are not isolated incidents. On average, Federal judges receive 700 threats a year; threats that are becoming increasingly serious. As these threats and attacks indicate, judges are not currently safe within the walls of our courts, nor are they safe in their homes. We cannot tolerate violence or the threat of violence against judges, court personnel, or their families. Violence against our judiciary represents an assault on our system of government.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By statute, the U.S. Marshals Service in the Department of Justice has the primary responsibility for the security of the Federal judiciary. Currently, the Marshals Service is underfunded and understaffed. There is a lack of coordination and communication between the Service and the Judicial Conference of the United States, the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, and the Federal Protective Service in the Department of Homeland Security. As a result, the Marshals Service struggles  to keep up with the security needs of the judiciary in this new high-risk age. There is no reason the system should continue to be so vulnerable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation we are introducing will enhance judicial security in several respects. First, it would require the Marshals Service to cooperate and coordinate with the Judicial Conference on judicial security on a continuing basis. This provision will give the judiciary a needed voice in assessing their security needs. The Marshals Service will receive additional funds to meet its responsibilities. It will have the ability to accurately assess threats in a timely manner, collect and share intelligence  on threats among districts and representatives of the FBI, and achieve appropriate staffing levels.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, the legislation punishes those who intrude into the personal lives of the judiciary and their families. It punishes those attempting to humiliate the judiciary or their families by recording a false lien or encumbrance against real or personal property and those who post personal information about public officials or their families with the intent to harm.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Equally important, the bill authorizes Federal grants to improve security for State and local court systems. The problem of judicial security is shared by all courts, State and Federal alike, and all courts deserve the best possible security protections.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To maintain our freedoms as a democratic society, judicial fairness and independence are essential. Threats and acts of violence against the judiciary are unacceptable. Its members must be fully protected. This bipartisan and bicameral bill aids in that protection, and I am honored to join my colleagues in urging that it be passed quickly by Congress and signed by the President.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300056" topic="Introducing S. 381. A bill to establish a fact-finding Commission to extend the study of a prior Commission to investigate and determine facts and circumstances surrounding the relocation, internment, and deportation to Axis countries of Latin Americans of Japanese descent from December 1941 through February 1948, and the impact of those actions by the United States, and to recommend appropriate remedies, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="381">S. 381</bill>] Mr. President, I rise to speak in support of the Commission on Wartime Relocation and Internment of Latin Americans of Japanese Descent Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The story of U.S. citizens taken from their homes on the west coast and confined in camps is a story that was made known after a fact-finding study by a Commission that Congress authorized in 1980. That study was followed by a formal apology by President Reagan and a bill for reparations. Far less known, and indeed, I myself did not initially know, is the story of Latin Americans of Japanese descent taken from their homes in Latin America, stripped of their passports, brought to the U.S., and  interned in American camps.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a story about the U.S. government's act of reaching its arm across international borders, into a community that did not pose an immediate threat to our Nation, in order to use them, devoid of passports or any other proof of citizenship, for hostage exchange with Japan. Between the years 1941 and 1945, our government, with the  help of Latin American officials, arbitrarily arrested persons of Japanese descent from streets, homes, and workplaces.  Approximately 2,300 undocumented persons were brought to camp sites in the U.S., where they were held under armed watch, and then held in reserve for prisoner exchange. Those used in an exchange were sent to Japan, a foreign country that many had never set foot on since their ancestors' immigration to Latin America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Despite their involuntary arrival, Latin American internees of Japanese descent were considered by the Immigration and Naturalization Service as illegal entrants. By the end of the war, some Japanese Latin Americans had been sent to Japan. Those who were not used in a prisoner exchange were cast out into a new and English-speaking country, and subject to deportation proceedings. Some returned to Latin America. Others remained in the U.S., where their Latin American country of origin refused their  re-entry because they were unable to present a passport.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When I first learned of the wartime experiences of Japanese Latin Americans, it seemed unbelievable, but indeed, it happened. It is a part of our national history, and it is a part of the living histories of the many families whose lives are forever tied to internment camps in our country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The outline of this story was sketched out in a book published by the Commission on Wartime Relocation and Internment of Civilians formed in 1980. This Commission had set out to learn about Japanese Americans. Towards the close of their investigations, the Commissioners stumbled upon this extraordinary effort by the U.S. government to relocate, intern, and deport Japanese persons formerly living in Latin America. Because this finding surfaced late in its study, the Commission was unable to fully  uncover the facts, but found them significant enough to include in its published study, urging a deeper investigation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I rise today to introduce the Commission on Wartime Relocation and Internment of Latin Americans of Japanese Descent Act, which would establish a fact-finding Commission to extend the study of the 1980 Commission. This Commission's task would be to determine facts surrounding the U.S. government's actions in regards to Japanese Latin Americans subject to a program of relocation, interment, and deportation. I believe that examining this extraordinary program would give finality to, and complete  the account of Federal actions to detain and intern civilians of Japanese ancestry.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the text of my bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="Introducing S. 382. A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to establish a State family support grant program to end the practice of parents giving legal custody of their seriously emotionally disturbed children to State agencies for the purpose of obtaining mental health services for those children; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="382">S. 382</bill>] Mr. President, I am pleased to join my colleagues, Senators Harkin, Kennedy, Coleman, Pryor, Cantwell, Durbin, Mikulski, Bingaman, Lautenberg and Kerry, in introducing the "Keeping Families Together Act." This legislation is intended to reduce the barriers to care for children with serious mental illness so that their parents are no longer forced to give up custody solely for the purpose of  securing mental health treatment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Serious mental illness afflicts millions of our Nation's children and adolescents. It is estimated that as many as 20 percent of American children under the age of 17 suffer from a mental, emotional or behavioral illness. What I find most disturbing, however, is the fact that two-thirds of all young people who need mental health treatment are not getting it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Behind each of these statistics is a family that is struggling to do the best it can to help a son or daughter with serious mental health needs to be just like every other kid--to develop friendships, to do well in school, and to get along with their siblings and other family members. These children are almost always involved with more than one social service agency, including the mental health, special education, child welfare, and juvenile justice systems. Yet no one agency, at either the State  or the Federal level, is clearly responsible or accountable for helping these children and their families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My interest in this issue was triggered by a compelling series of stories by Barbara Walsh in the Portland Press Herald which detailed the obstacles that many Maine families have faced in getting desperately needed mental health services for their children. Too many families in Maine and elsewhere have been forced to make wrenching decisions when they have been advised that the only way to get the care that their children so desperately need is to relinquish custody and place them in either the  child welfare or juvenile justice system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When a child has a serious physical health problem like diabetes or a heart condition, the family turns to their doctor. When the family includes a child with a serious mental illness, it is often forced to go to the child welfare or juvenile justice system to secure treatment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Yet neither system is intended to serve children with serious mental illness. Child welfare systems are designed to protect children who have been abused or neglected. Juvenile justice systems are designed to rehabilitate children who have committed criminal or delinquent acts. While neither of these systems is equipped to care for a child with a serious mental illness, in far too many cases, there is nowhere else for the family to turn.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In some extreme cases, families feel forced to file charges against their child or to declare that they have abused or neglected them in order to get the care that they need. As one family advocate observed, "Beat `em up, lock `em up, or give `em up," characterizes the choices that some families face in their efforts to get help for their children's mental illness.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 2003, the Government Accountability Office (GAO) issued a report that I requested with Representatives Pete Stark and Patrick Kennedy that found that, in 2001, parents placed more than 12,700 children into the child welfare or juvenile justice systems so that these children could receive mental health services. This likely is just the tip of the iceberg, since 32 States--including five States with the largest populations of children--did not provide the GAO with any data.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Other studies indicate that the problem is even more pervasive. A 1999 survey by the National Alliance on Mental Illness found that 23 percent--or one in four of the parents surveyed--had been told by public officials that they needed to relinquish custody of their children to get care, and that one in five of these families had done so.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Some States have passed laws to limit custody or prohibit custody relinquishment. Simply banning the practice is not a solution, however, since it can leave children with mental illness and their families without services and care. Custody relinquishment is merely a symptom of the much larger problem, which is the lack of available, affordable and appropriate mental health services and support systems for these children and their families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 2003 and 2004, I chaired a series of hearings in the Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee to examine this issue further. We heard compelling testimony from mothers who told us that they were advised that the only way to get the intensive care and services that their children needed was to relinquish custody and place them in the child welfare or juvenile justice system. This is a wrenching decision that no family should be forced to make. No parent should have to give up custody  of his or her child just to get the services that the child needs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The mothers also described the barriers they faced in getting care for their children. They told us about the limitations in both public and private insurance coverage. They also talked about the lack of coordination and communication among the various agencies and programs that service children with mental health needs. One parent, desperate for help for her twin boys, searched for two years until she finally located a program--which she characterized as "the best kept secret in Illinois"--that  was able to help.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Parents should not be bounced from agency to agency, knocking on every door they come to, in the hope that they will happen upon someone who has an answer. It simply should not be such a struggle for parents to get services and treatment for their children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We also need to question what happens to these children when they are turned over to the child welfare or juvenile justice authorities. I released a report in 2004 with Congressman Henry Waxman that found that all too often they are simply left to languish in juvenile detention centers, which are ill-equipped to meet their needs, while they wait for scarce mental health services.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our report, which was based on a national survey of juvenile detention centers, found that the use of juvenile detention facilities to "warehouse" children with mental disorders is a serious national problem. It found that, over a six month period, nearly 15,000 young people--roughly seven percent of all of the children in the  centers surveyed--were detained solely because they were waiting for mental health services outside the juvenile justice system. Many were held without any charges pending against them, and the young people incarcerated unnecessarily while waiting for treatment were as young as seven years old. Finally, the report estimated that juvenile detention facilities are spending an estimated $100 million of the taxpayers' money each year simply to warehouse children and teenagers while they are waiting  for mental health services.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Keeping Families Together Act, which we are introducing today, will help to improve access to mental health services and assist states in eliminating the practice of parents relinquishing custody of their children solely for the purpose of securing treatment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation authorizes $100 million over six years for competitive grants to states to create an infrastructure to support and sustain statewide systems of care to serve children who are in custody or at risk of entering custody of the State for the purpose of receiving mental health services. States already dedicate significant dollars to serve children in state custody. These Family Support Grants would help states to serve children more effectively and efficiently, while keeping them at  home with their families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, the legislation calls for the creation of a federal interagency task force to examine mental health issues in the child welfare and juvenile justice systems and the role of those agencies in promoting access by children and youth to needed mental health services. The task force would also be charged with monitoring the Family Support grants, making recommendations to Congress on how to improve mental health services, and fostering interagency cooperation and removing interagency  barriers that contribute to the problem of custody relinquishment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Keeping Families Together Act takes a critical step forward to meeting the needs of children with serious mental or emotional disorders. Our legislation has been endorsed by a broad coalition of mental health and children's groups, including the National Alliance on Mental Illness, the Bazelon Center for Mental Health Law, Mental Health America, the American Psychological Association, and the American Psychiatric Association. I ask unanimous consent that letters from these organizations endorsing  the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Keeping Families Together Act will help to reduce the barriers to care for children with serious mental illness, and I urge our colleagues to join us as cosponsors.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the materials were ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="NATIONAL ALLIANCE ON">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I am honored to join with the distinguished junior Senator from Maine, Ms. Collins, in introducing the Keeping Families Together Act. As a long-time advocate for people with disabilities, I believe that this legislation represents an important step forward in ensuring the health and wellbeing of our children, in particular those with mental illness.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One in five children has a diagnosable mental disorder, and one in ten children has a mental disorder serious enough to hinder their functioning at school, at the home, and in their communities. Regrettably, two-thirds of children in this latter group do not receive the treatment they need. Without treatment, mental illness negatively affects all areas of children's lives, and it can have dire consequences for their future, including their ability to become productive members of society. Children  with mental health problems are at higher risk of chronic illness, academic difficulties and school discipline problems, delinquency, incarceration, and suicide.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The good news is that 90 percent of all mental health disorders are treatable by therapy and medication. Yet parents face a multitude of obstacles and challenges in finding appropriate services for a child with serious mental illness. Often, they find that their private insurance will not pay for necessary mental health services, or that they do not qualify for Medicaid. In their efforts to secure effective treatment, many parents exhaust their own financial resources and find that they have  nowhere else to turn. Tragically, many dedicated, loving parents reach the point where they believe that they have no other option but to relinquish custody of their child to the State in order to access appropriate services. These out-of-home placements can be traumatic for children, and profoundly disruptive and heart-breaking for families that are already in crisis.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Making matters worse, state systems are often poorly equipped to serve the needs of these children. Many children end up being placed in expensive residential institutions, rather than less  costly home- and community-based services. Our juvenile justice system is overwhelmed by young people in need of mental health services. A congressional report authored by Senator Collins and Representative HENRY WAXMAN of California suggests that,  every night, nearly 2,000 youths are placed in juvenile detention facilities not because they are criminals but because they do not have access to necessary mental health services. This results in a $100 million bill to the taxpayers. Not only is this a serious misuse of public funds, it is a tragic injustice to the children and families involved. We simply cannot allow children to languish in detention facilities when they are really in need of mental health treatment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Keeping Families Together Act lays a foundation for securing better access to mental health services for children. Consistent with recommendations by the President's New Freedom Commission on Mental Health, this legislation encourages interagency coordination in the provision of mental health services for children. The bill gives States incentives to remedy the fragmentation that now exists among child welfare, education, juvenile justice, and mental health agencies responsible for helping  children. It ensures that States will improve access to mental health services and eliminate the practice of parents' relinquishing custody of their children solely for the purpose of securing mental health treatment. Our bill also promotes sustainable financing by requiring States to provide graduated matching funds.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In sum, by providing a sustainable, coordinated system of mental health care, children will be able to receive needed services within a stable, loving home environment. Families will be able to stay together.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In a decent, humane society, every family should have access to appropriate mental health services for their children. Parents should not have to surrender a child to the State as the price for obtaining access to mental health treatment. The Keeping Families Together Act offers a better way. It allows children with mental disorders to stay where they belong--in the custody and care of their loving family. I join with Senator Collins in urging our colleagues to support this urgent and  important legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="Introducing S. 383. A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to extend the period of eligibility for health care for combat service in the Persian Gulf War or future hostilities from 2 years to 5 years after discharge or release; to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="383">S. 383</bill>] Mr. President, I today introduce legislation that, if enacted, will help ensure that returning servicemembers receive the care they need from VA in the 5 years immediately following detachment or deactivation, without having to meet strict eligibility rules. The changes this legislation would make will contribute to the "seamless" transition of military personnel from active duty to veteran status. This legislation is identical to the bill I introduced last Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, any active duty servicemember who is discharged or separated from active duty following deployment to a theater of combat--including Reservists or Guard who stand down but remain on reserve duty--is eligible for VA health care for a 2-year period. In my view, it is vital that this period be extended to 5 years to provide a more appropriate window of time for servicemembers to access VA care. Since the start of OEF and OIF, an average of 157,800 servicemembers have been discharged  or deactivated per year. This legislation will help the existing 315,600 veterans who have been inactive for more than 2 years but fewer than 5, and thousands more in the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Following the first Persian Gulf War, and partially in response to the unexplained illnesses among those who served, Congress enacted the Veterans Programs Enhancement Act of 1998. This law gave 2 years of priority eligibility for health care to any veteran who served in a theater of combat following discharge or deactivation from active duty. The original intent was to ensure health care for servicemembers after their active duty health care benefits ended. It is now clear this the 2 year  window of eligibility is insufficient.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are two primary reasons to amend the law to allow a greater period of eligibility: protection from budget cuts and access to care for conditions, including mental health conditions, that may not be readily apparent when a servicemember first leaves active duty. In recent years, funding for VA health care has been delayed or cut by the legislative and appropriations processes, leading to delayed or denied care to those veterans with lower priority for VA care. Those veterans who have  served in a theater of combat operations deserve to have their health care guaranteed for at least the first 5 years immediately following their discharge or detachment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With regard to mental health, 2 years is often insufficient time for symptoms related to PTSD and other mental illnesses to manifest. In many cases, it takes years for such symptoms to present themselves, and many servicemembers do not immediately seek care. Experts predict that up to 30 percent of OEF/OIF servicemembers will need some type of readjustment services. Five years would provide a bigger window to address these risks. We face a growing group of recently discharged veterans,  and this legislation will help smooth their transition to civilian life.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One final reason, that I believe this legislation is necessary, is that extending the window of eligibility for VA health care services may also serve to prevent homelessness among veterans. We all know that veterans represent a disproportionate segment of the homeless population, and that is a national tragedy. While we continue to battle homelessness among older veterans from Vietnam and other conflicts, we must do all we can to ensure that none of the new veterans returning from Iraq and Afghanistan  fall through the cracks. Providing more time for them to access VA's services is a key part of that effort.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this legislation, as I believe it is truly a way to honor the service of our men and women in uniform.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300063" topic="Introducing S. 384. A bill to provide pay protection for members of the Reserve and the National Guard, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="384">S. 384</bill>] Mr. President, today there are 91,555 members of the National Guard and our Reserve armed forces serving bravely in Iraq, Afghanistan, and any other part of the world our country calls them to serve. The President is sending an additional 21,500 troops to Iraq in one final push to bring stability to that country. Regardless of what we think about this plan, Americans stand by our troops. They have the best equipment and training for their mission and we would never deny them the  support they need. But back at home, there is still a great deal that we can do to support our guard and reserves families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When guardsmen and reservists are deployed they leave their families, their jobs, and their communities behind, causing tremendous stress on the home front and in the workplace. Families often lose the main bread winner when a citizen soldier gets deployed. They may have trouble paying bills, the rent, the mortgage, or buying medicine for their children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The reason these families cannot make ends meet is because for Guardsmen and Reservists military pay is often less than civilian pay. We call that the "pay gap." According to the most recent Status Forces Survey of Reserve Components, 51 percent of our citizen soldiers take a pay cut when they get deployed and 11 percent of them lose more than $2,500 per month.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To help provide relief from the pay gap for our Guard and Reserve, I am pleased to introduce, along with Senators DURBIN, GRAHAM and KERRY, the Helping Our Patriotic Employers at Helping our Military Employees Act of 2007. I call the bill by its nickname: HOPE at HOME. Our guard and reserve families have enough to worry about when a loved one gets called away, the least we can do is relieve some of their financial worry by encouraging employers to make up the pay gap. Let me describe  for my colleagues how this legislation works.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>HOPE at HOME will give a 50 percent tax credit to the thousands of employers around the country who have taken the patriotic step of continuing to pay the salary of their guard and reservists employees who have been called to active duty. There are literally thousands of employers out there who already take this noble step--they do it voluntarily, selflessly and at great sacrifice. The HOPE at HOME Act honors that sacrifice.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>HOPE at HOME will also give companies that cannot afford to make up the pay-gap an incentive to do so. One survey found that only 173 of the Fortune 500 companies make up the pay gap. If the wealthiest companies cannot afford to help their active duty employees, imagine how difficult this is for smaller companies. HOPE at HOME will allow companies large and small to do the patriotic thing and reward those employees who are serving to keep us all free.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>HOPE at HOME will also give small patriotic employers additional tax relief if they need to hire a worker to temporarily replace the active duty Guardsmen or Reservist. In addition, the  bill clarifies the tax treatment of any pay-gap payments to make income tax filing easier for our Guard and Reservists.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I mentioned that thousands of employers make up the pay-gap for their employees. There is one employer, however, and it happens to be the Nation's largest, that does not make up the pay gap: Uncle Sam. The Federal Government, which should set the bar for patriotism in our country, does not do its part to help our citizen soldiers. We cannot ask the private sector to do more than they are doing if the Federal government is not willing to step up and do its part for our military men and women.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today our Nation relies on the Guard and Reserve to meet our armed forces needs more than at any other time in our history. At times in the war on terror, 40 percent of our troops in Iraq and Afghanistan were citizen soldiers, if not more. Many of them performed multiple tours of duty or found their duties extended.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>All of the experts tell us that our need for our Guard and Reserve troops will only get greater. During the Cold War, end strength of the U.S. military force never dropped below 2.0 million personnel and peaked at over 3.5 million during the Korean and Vietnam Wars. From 1989 to 1999, end strength dropped steadily from 2.1 million to 1.4 million, where it has remained. Our ground forces are stretched thin and the number of deployments has increased by over 300 percent. The Guard and Reserve have  made it possible to meet these challenges. We still find ourselves stretched thin, but without the Guard and Reserve we would never be able to meet our obligation as guardians of freedom in the World.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But this over-reliance on the Guard and Reserve is starting to have a toll on our ability to recruit and retain these men and women. The top reasons for leaving the Guard and Reserve, according to the Status of Forces Survey of Reserve Components, are family stress, the number and lengths of deployments, income loss, and conflict with civilian employment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>HOPE at HOME recognizes that a soldier who is worrying about how his or her family is paying the bills is not focusing on the mission at hand. A soldier who is worrying about whether the family is paying the rent, is not going to reenlist. And every time one of our soldiers leaves, our nation loses the experience and service of a highly trained, capable professional. We need to make every effort to keep our citizen soldiers in service to their country. HOPE at HOME is a first step to addressing  our military's larger recruitment and retention issues.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>During the Cold War we built our strength on having the biggest, best equipped standing army in the World. Now our military gathers its strength from a large reserve of qualified men and women in the Guard and Reserve who are ready to fight at a moment's call. We will lose that strength if we do not give our guardsmen and Reservists and their families HOPE at HOME.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I hope my colleagues will join me in giving our Guard and Reserve HOPE at HOME Act.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300056" topic="Introducing S. 385. A bill to improve the interoperability of emergency communications equipment; to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="385">S. 385</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to call attention to an important issue that the Congress has not adequately addressed since the painful events of September 11, 2001.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That issue is the inability of our first responders to speak to each other, a problem especially troubling during an emergency, when the ability to quickly and effectively communicate saves lives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is why I, with the cosponsorship of my colleagues, Senators STEVENS, KERRY, SMITH AND SNOWE, are introducing the Interoperable Emergency Communications Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After September 11, 2001, we heard heartbreaking stories of firefighters and police officers who went into harm's way because they lacked adequate information. These brave men and women were unable to reach victims because their systems could not communicate with one another.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At that time, the Congress began devoting greater attention to why many of our first responders lacked this ability to communicate with each other in the field. We asked what it would take to ensure communications equipment and facilities could withstand a natural disaster. We asked which equipment would be worthy of our investment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Then Hurricane Katrina struck in August, 2006, and we found that our first responders faced the same communications failures. This is an unnecessary frustration that prevents our first responders from effectively doing their jobs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our bill provides needed direction to the National Telecommunications and Information Administration (NTIA) regarding its administration of the $1 billion grant program for interoperable communications systems for first responders, which was created by the Senate Commerce Committee early last year. It will be funded by money from the Digital Transition and Public Safety Fund and administered by the NTIA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill designates grants for regional or statewide communications systems that will allow first responders to talk to one another during an emergency. It also sets aside funding for a technology reserve for immediate deployment of communications equipment in the event of an emergency or disaster.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To ensure a fair distribution of funds, the money will be distributed in accordance with guidelines outlined in the Patriot Act to ensure a fair distribution of funds, and grant allocations will be prioritized based on an "all hazards" approach that will take into account threat and risk factors associated with natural disasters--such as hurricanes, tsunamis, earthquakes, and tornadoes--as well as risks associated with terrorist attacks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Every day we hear about potential threats against our Nation and it will not be long until we are again in the midst of hurricane season. I hope that history will not repeat itself and that the Congress can act quickly in directing the NTIA to give our first responders the tools they need to effectively do their jobs. I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD. </paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300021" topic="Introducing S. 385. A bill to improve the interoperability of emergency communications equipment; to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today to discuss the connection between energy production and agriculture. Agriculture and energy policy are converging and unlike anytime in the past, farmers and ranchers are producing food, fiber, and fuel. As the country recognizes the danger of relying on imported oil, we need to develop an energy policy that is aggressive while at the same time thoughtful. Renewable fuels like ethanol and biodiesel are not the total solution to our problems, but they  can help reduce our dependence on imported oil from unstable regions of the world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 2005, the Congress passed, and President Bush signed, the Energy Policy Act that established the Renewable Fuel Standard, RFS. The RFS requires minimum volumes of renewable fuels be used in America's motor fuels market annually, from 4 billion gallons in 2006 to 7.5 billion in 2012. On January 1, 2006, the Renewable Fuel Standard went into effect and since then, the United States has used more than 5 billion gallons of ethanol, outpacing RFS requirements by more than 25 percent. According  to the Renewable Fuels Association, in the next 18 months the industry will add nearly 6 billion gallons of new production capacity. In short, in 2008, new capacity will exceed the minimum level as called for in the RFS.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This progress is astounding. However, the expansion has not come without some cost to the rest of the agriculture sector. For the first time in memory corn prices increased during the 2006 harvest season and exceeded a critical threshold of $4 per bushel on the Chicago Board of Trade and continue to do so.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If corn prices continue to set new highs over the next year, the broiler industry in my home State of Georgia and across the Southeast will come under increasing pressure. I fear continued price spikes will force some producers out of business. This is not unique to the poultry industry, but will also impact swine and cattle operations across the country as ethanol outbids livestock for corn.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We find ourselves in the position of encouraging an industry that directly competes with another that is important in all our States, and I hope the end result is not policy that encourages livestock operators to further integrate and consolidate. We need to continue to support the biofuels sector, but also do it in a way that has the least disruption on existing markets as possible.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For this reason, I am introducing the Cellulosic Ethanol Incentive Act of 2007. This act builds upon the success of the RFS and increases the target from 7.5 billion gallons in 2012 to 30 billion gallons in 2030. Central to the bill is a set-aside that will help commercialize cellulosic ethanol much faster than under current law. This is important in order to ensure Federal policy does not erode the profitability of the U.S. livestock sector by encouraging additional competition for available  corn. The bill meets the challenge set forth by President Bush last night and mirrors the renewable fuel targets in his proposal.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Furthermore, the legislation promotes regional diversity in the production of biofuels. This is important in order to spread the benefits of renewable energy policy more evenly across all regions of the country. By recommending a minimum level of consumption within a particular region, we will provide a needed economic boost to rural areas, a new income stream for farmers and ranchers and a further acceleration in the production of cellulosic ethanol from a diverse resource base ranging from  wood chips in the Southeast to wheat straw on the Great Plains.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ever since the founding of our great country, farmers and ranchers have been an integral part in growing the safest, most affordable food supply in the world. Now we can build upon their success and we ask them to help grow an abundant source of energy. I am confident they are up to the task and the Cellulosic Ethanol Incentive Act is an important step to help promote this goal.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to join me in supporting the bill and I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
</record>
