<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1176912003" ordinal="10" title="PRESERVING COMPETITION WITHIN MEDICARE">
  <speaking speaker="300062" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to speak for a few minutes on the bill on which we will be voting in approximately an hour, as the majority leader just said. I would like to speak directly to the point he attempted to make, which was why should there be a problem with allowing the Federal Government to negotiate for drug prices for Medicare by repealing Medicare's so-called noninterference provision?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nobody doesn't support negotiation. Negotiation is at the heart of the Medicare prescription drug benefit. I was there when it was written in the conference committee and there was a conscientious decision to ensure that there would be competition for lowering prices by specifically designating pharmacy benefit managers to do negotiating with the drug companies to bring the prices down. So the first myth is that Medicare somehow does not involve negotiations. It involves extensive negotiations.  What it does not do is allow the Federal Government to interfere in those negotiations and, in effect, put itself in between patients and doctors and the drugs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Medicare Fair Prescription Drug Price Act of 2007, on which we will be voting cloture, turns this law upside-down and basically inserts the Government into this process under these decisions. The purpose may sound simple--the Government, using its negotiating clout, forcing drug companies to give seniors deep discounts--but if you take a closer look and peel away the layers, you realize it is nothing more than a promise running on empty, void of details and muddled by political rhetoric rather  than sustained by the facts. Let's look at the facts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First of all, Medicare Part D is working. When Congress crafted the bill, we heard from our constituents loudly and clearly. They wanted a prescription drug benefit that guaranteed access to affordable drugs and offered a choice of plans. They didn't want to be packed into a one-size-fits-all, Government-run plan that didn't fit their needs, and in fact they asked us to model the benefit after the plan that is available to Members of Congress. We did that. We chose access over restrictions, choice  over Government control, and competition over price control. As a result, Medicare Part D is exceeding everyone's expectations. Approximately 90 percent of Medicare beneficiaries have some form of prescription drug coverage. The average premium was $22, in 2007, which is 42 percent lower than the Government projected initially. On average, seniors saved $1,200 on their prescription drug costs last year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Eight out of ten Part D enrollees report they are satisfied with their current coverage, and the Congressional Budget Office estimates that the drug benefit will cost the taxpayers 30 percent less, $265 billion in savings over the next 10 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To sum it up, we have 90 percent Medicare beneficiaries with coverage, 80 percent satisfaction rate, and it costs 30 percent less than originally estimated. If it "ain't" broke, don't fix it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The second fact, drug negotiation is at the heart of the Medicare bill. For the first time in history, health insurance plans and pharmaceutical companies and these benefit managers whom I mentioned are required to negotiate better prices for seniors, just like they do for Members of Congress. The noninterference provision, which first appeared in democratically sponsored legislation, prevents the Federal Government from interfering in those negotiations. It is a basic economic principle. In  competitive markets, supply and demand interact, determining the price of the good or service. How do you get a good price? These pharmacy benefit managers I mentioned have significant market power.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Consider this fact: The three largest PBMs have nearly 200 million members, compared to Medicare's 44 million. So when you talk about the Government using its considerable bargaining clout because it would represent 44 million, appreciate that these pharmacy benefit managers represent 200 million. They insure all of these people--Americans in the private sector, as well as Americans who have Government insurance. So the private drug negotiators already enjoy a significant competitive advantage.  They use that power to negotiate lower prices and, as I pointed out, that negotiation has worked.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Third, the secretarial negotiation cannot achieve any lower price without rationing choice in access. That was the testimony before the Senate Finance Committee, and I think every one of us appreciates that we should be very careful about anything which could restrict access to care for our seniors. When the Finance Committee marked up this bill last week, I looked forward to getting some clarity on exactly how Members contemplated this secretarial negotiation, how it would work.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To my disappointment, no one could explain exactly how it would work. In fact, my colleagues openly and candidly admitted they had no plan or any specifics. What they said was that the Secretary would have to use his imagination and that it could take a number of different forms.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So what we are buying, in effect, is a pig in a poke. Nobody knows what the  Secretary would or could do in order to try to bring prices down; he would have to use his imagination.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think it is appropriate for us to ask this kind of question before we buy into legislation that could so dramatically and negatively impact health care for our seniors. Restricting access could theoretically reduce lower prices if they were raised with some other program. That is the other downside to this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>During the Finance Committee noninterference hearing, we heard testimony from Dr. Fiona Scott Morton, who is a Professor of Economics at the Yale School of Management. She made a couple of critical points. Individuals eligible to participate in Medicare Part D generate approximately 40 percent of prescription drug spending in the United States. The Secretary cannot negotiate a lower average price for such a large population; Medicare is the average.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So if it were somehow theoretically possible to reduce prices, they would have to go up somewhere else. That is the other point we established as well. There are many different organizations, including veterans organizations, that urged us to oppose this legislation because they understand that if you are somehow able to lower the prices for Medicare, they necessarily, arithmetically, have to go up somewhere else. The Veterans' Administration is one of those areas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me quote from two letters, one received from the American Legion, which asks us to consider, and I quote:</paragraph>
    <paragraph> ..... the serious collateral damage that would result from repealing the noninterference provision.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The VA is a health care provider, whereas Medicare is a health insurer. Any possible Medicare savings would likely result in a reciprocal cost to the VA. Compromising the noninterference provision by striking this section is not in the best interest of America's veterans and their families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The American Legion is not alone. The Military Order of the Purple Heart sent a similar letter to the Hill. Bottom line here: Cost savings are the result of true efficiencies. Repealing the noninterference provision is just another way to shift costs at the expense of other consumers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In conclusion, during this markup of this bill in the committee, I offered three amendments, each of which ensured important safeguards: No. 1, to prohibit cost shifting, as I mentioned, to entities such as Medicaid or veterans or the uninsured; No. 2, to require a certification of cost savings to Medicare beneficiaries if these negotiations were to occur; No. 3, a certification of four beneficiary protections: One, individual choice of a prescription drug plan; two, access to prescription drugs  by prohibiting a government formulary or other tool to restrict drug access; three, guaranteed access to local pharmacies; and, four, no cost shifting to other payors, such as Medicaid, veterans or the uninsured. All three of these amendments were rejected.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Repealing this noninterference provision would put the Government, not the individual in charge, and put seniors one step closer to a single Government-run designed formulary.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I appreciate and respect the goals of my colleagues. We all want to improve access to affordable health coverage. But with all due respect, they are wrong. A great deal of expert testimony and experience with Medicare Part D by millions of Americans has demonstrated they are wrong. So I urge my colleagues, when considering how to vote on this motion for cloture, to appreciate the fact that, first of all, there is a great benefit that is producing savings and is well appreciated by the American  people; that there are organizations that are very much opposed to this, such as the VA, and that we would be very foolish, it seems to me, to adopt a piece of legislation such as this about which there is no consensus as to how the Secretary would utilize his authority to negotiate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent to have printed at this point in the Record an editorial from the Wall Street Journal of today, April 18, 2007, which further amplifies the points I have made this morning.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300062" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Michigan is recognized.</chair>
</record>
