<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1216828802" ordinal="19" title="HOUSING AND ECONOMIC RECOVERY ACT OF 2008">
  <narrative>HOUSING AND ECONOMIC RECOVERY ACT OF 2008 -- (Senate - July 23, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="7130">S7130</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask the Chair to lay before the Senate a message from the House with respect to <bill type="h" number="3221">H.R. 3221</bill>, which is the housing legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The PRESIDING OFFICER laid before the Senate the following message:</narrative>
  <narrative>Resolved, That the House agree to the amendment of the Senate to the amendments of the House to the amendment of the Senate to the bill (<bill type="h" number="3221">H.R. 3221</bill>) entitled "An Act moving the United States toward greater energy independence and security, developing innovative new technologies, reducing carbon emissions, creating green jobs, protecting consumers, increasing clean renewable energy production, and modernizing our energy infrastructure, and to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to  provide tax incentives for the production of renewable energy and energy conservation", with an amendment.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I move to concur with the amendment of the House to the Senate amendment to <bill type="h" number="3221">H.R. 3221</bill>, and I send a cloture motion to the desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The cloture motion having been presented under rule XXII, the Chair directs the clerk to report the cloture motion.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>Cloture Motion</narrative>
  <narrative>We, the undersigned Senators, in accordance with the provisions of rule XXII of the Standing Rules of the Senate, hereby move to bring to a close debate on the motion to concur in the House amendment to the Senate amendment to the House amendments to the Senate amendment to <bill type="h" number="3221">H.R. 3221</bill>, the Foreclosure Prevention Act.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>I ask the mandatory quorum call be waived.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="MOTION TO CONCUR">
    <paragraph>I now move to concur in the amendment of the House to the Senate amendment to <bill type="h" number="3221">H.R. 3221</bill>, with an amendment which is at the desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>The Senator from Nevada [Mr. REID] moves to concur in the amendment of the House to the Senate amendment to <bill type="h" number="3221">H.R. 3221</bill>, with an amendment numbered 5103.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent the reading of the amendment be dispensed with.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The amendment is as follows:</chair>
  <chair>At the end of the amendment add the following:</chair>
  <chair>The provisions of this act shall become effective 2 days after enactment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask for the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there a sufficient second? There appears to be a sufficient second.</chair>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I have a second-degree amendment at the desk. I ask for its consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>The Senator from Nevada [Mr. REID] proposes an amendment numbered 5104 to amendment No. 5103.</narrative>
  <narrative>The amendment is as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>In the amendment, strike "2" and insert "1".</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask that no motion to refer be in order during the pendency of this message.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="">
    <paragraph>Reserving the right to object, if I might ask the leader a question, the filing of the cloture motion on the housing bill at this point means there will be a Saturday vote?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I say to my friend, you are the one who pretty well determines when we vote on these things. It will probably be--it will be Friday.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="">
    <paragraph>Friday, if all the time is used. I would like to make the Senator aware that I believe we could arrange a unanimous consent to shorten the time, if you would allow one amendment that would prohibit Fannie May and Freddie Mack or organizations from lobbying during this time of taxpayer-secured funding. So we are prepared to shorten the time, if you are willing to allow that unanimous consent.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I say to my friend, the Senator from South Carolina, that this bill is so important. We have filed--I kind of lost track, but because of your side we have had to have four cloture motions. This will be the fifth on this most important piece of legislation, a piece of legislation that has been promoted and the administration has prodded us to get this done weeks ago.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Of course, if your amendment is made part of what we are going to do here and this legislation is changed, it goes back to the House again. Then we have a process that seems never ending.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have no problem with the intent of the Senator from South Carolina. I think there would be, perhaps, support on both sides of the aisle for your amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That being the case, I think it would be a real travesty at this time. I don't know if there is a day that has gone by this week--it is only Wednesday, so probably not--a day that has gone by this week that I haven't received a call from someone in the White House, including on several occasions the Secretary of Treasury, saying please do not hold this up at all. This has to be done.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I say to my friend again, in no way denigrating the intent of the offer because I think the intent is sincere, I hope you would not force us to do this.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Speaking on behalf of President Bush--and I don't do that very often--I don't think we should do this. I don't think we should send this back to the House. I think we should complete it here.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I will be happy to consider joining the Senator in a letter to the two entities regarding some way to make sure they are transparent in any lobbying they do. I would be happy to do something on this. But I feel constrained not to slow this very important legislation, which is well over a month overdue at this time. Every day that we do not do something--every day there are 8,500 people who get foreclosure notices; 8,500.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It may not seem like much, but if we send this back to the House, we would complete it sometime late next week. During that period of time, we would probably have about 45,000 people who would have entered foreclosure proceedings, when this legislation will allow, some say, up to 1 million people to be able to save their homes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I hope the Senator would not press us on that. I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <chair>The legislative clerk proceeded to call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I offered a unanimous consent request, the last one I offered, and my friend from South Carolina reserved the right to object, so I withdraw that.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
