<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1201626002" ordinal="25" title="ORDER OF PROCEDURE">
  <narrative>ORDER OF PROCEDURE -- (Senate - January 29, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="423">S423</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300055" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, there is confusion as to the order of the speakers. I ask unanimous consent that the junior Senator from Pennsylvania, Mr. Casey, be recognized for up to 15 minutes, in morning business, to be followed by me, to be recognized for up to 35 minutes in morning business.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412246" topic="">
    <paragraph>Reserving the right to object.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412246" topic="">
    <paragraph>Will the Senator modify his request to add Senator Webb to that lineup to be the next Democratic speaker?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300055" topic="">
    <paragraph>May I ask how long Mr. Webb, the junior Senator from Virginia, wishes to speak?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="412246" topic="">
    <paragraph>Ten minutes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300055" topic="">
    <paragraph>I amend my request that it be, first, Senator Casey for 15 minutes, Senator Webb for 10 minutes, and myself for 35 minutes in morning business.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is the new request: I ask unanimous consent that the junior Senator from Pennsylvania, Mr. Casey, be recognized for up to 15 minutes, after which I will be recognized for up to 35 minutes, and then the Senator from Virginia, Mr. Webb, will be recognized for up to 10 minutes in morning business.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The Senator from Pennsylvania is recognized for up to 15 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412246" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I thank the Senator from Oklahoma for working through that unanimous consent agreement.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
