<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1182355236" ordinal="51" title="SUPPORTING GOALS AND IDEALS OF NATIONAL CLEAN BEACHES WEEK">
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate now proceed to the consideration of <bill type="sr" number="243">S. Res. 243</bill>, submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table, and that any statements relating thereto be printed in the Record, without intervening action or debate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="243">S. Res. 243</bill>) was agreed to.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The preamble was agreed to.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>
      <bill type="sr" number="243">S. Res. 243</bill>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>Whereas coastal areas produce 85 percent of all United States tourism dollars and are the leading tourism destination in America;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas over 50 percent of the population of the United States lives in coastal counties;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the beaches in these coastal counties provide recreational opportunities for numerous Americans and their families who, together with international tourists, make almost 2,000,000,000 trips to the beach each year to fish, sunbathe, boat, swim, surf, and bird-watch;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas beaches are a critical driver of the American economy and its competitiveness in the global economy;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas beaches represent a critical part of our natural heritage and a beautiful part of the American landscape;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas beaches are sensitive ecosystems, susceptible to degradation and alteration from natural forces, sea level rise, pollution, untreated sewage, and improper use;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas members of the Government, the private sector, and nongovernmental organizations, along with citizen volunteers, have worked diligently to clean up and protect our beaches over the years;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas great strides have been made in understanding the science of watersheds and the connections between inland areas and coastal waters;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Federal Government should develop science-based policies that are commensurate with that knowledge; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas a 7-day week, commencing in June and including July 5, will be observed as National Clean Beaches Week: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) supports the goals and ideals of National Clean Beaches Week;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) recognizes the value of beaches to the American way of life and the important contributions of beaches to the economy, recreation, and natural environment of the United States; and</paragraph>
    <paragraph> (3) encourages Americans to work to keep beaches safe and clean for the continued enjoyment of the public and to engage in activities during National Clean Beaches Week that foster stewardship, healthy living, and volunteerism along our coastlines.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
