<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1216310404" ordinal="45" title="TRIBUTE TO PHIL ROBBINS">
  <narrative>TRIBUTE TO PHIL ROBBINS -- (Senate - July 17, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="6934">S6934</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300094" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I wish to remember the life of Philip Austin Robbins III, of Kodiak, AK.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Phil was born on June 28, 1943, in Anacortes, WA, where he spent his youth. After graduating from high school, he set out on an adventure that would take him around the globe. With little money, Phil hitchhiked, took odd jobs, slept where he could find shelter, enjoyed the hospitality of strangers, and made many new friends, as he traveled through Europe, the Middle East, and Asia.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Upon returning home, Phil was drafted into service during the Vietnam war. As fate would have it, though, he was not sent to Vietnam but instead stationed in Heidelberg, Germany, where he worked as a code-breaker in the U.S. Army.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After serving in the Army, Phil lived for a few years in Makaha, HI. He attended the University of Hawaii in Honolulu, and married Lisa Gayle Tatsumi.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Not long after this, Phil would embark on another adventure, moving with his wife and newborn son to Kodiak Island in Alaska. Here, the young family would live in a log cabin in the woods of Island Lake, and Phil would pursue a career as a commercial fisherman. It was a career that would span 40 years. During this time, Phil would see firsthand the boom and bust of the lucrative Kodiak king crab industry from the 1960s to the early 1980s as well as the recordbreaking salmon prices of the late  1980s. He would participate in the cleanup efforts that followed the disastrous Exxon Valdez oil spill of 1989 and the frantic derby-style halibut seasons that were phased out in the 1990s. Phil was one of the pioneers of the potcod fishery in Kodiak. Cod fishing</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Phil had a tireless work ethic, a great sense of humor, and a warm heart. He was a modest man and the last to expect his life story would be told on the floor of the U.S. Senate. His bold spirit is emblematic of that of many Alaskans who come to our State with big dreams and a taste for adventure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Phil lost his battle to cancer earlier this month at the age of 65. He is survived by his loving wife Lisa and proud sons Philip Junior and Mark. Philip Junior is a computer engineer and Mark, a member of my staff.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>May you find calm seas and beautiful new horizons, Phil. You will be missed.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
