<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1222531203" ordinal="14" title="CONSOLIDATED SECURITY, DISASTER ASSISTANCE, AND CONTINUING APPROPRIATIONS ACT, 2009--Continued">
  <narrative>CONSOLIDATED SECURITY, DISASTER ASSISTANCE, AND CONTINUING APPROPRIATIONS ACT, 2009--Continued -- (Senate - September 27, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="9901">S9901</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300063" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I wish to proceed to the hour that I have asked the leader to set aside for the purpose of discussing, in my view, a grave oversight that can be corrected if there is enough political will to do so. So the purpose of this hour is to try to lay out a case so that we can build, over the course of the next few days and weeks, the will necessary to take action that if not taken could literally result in the bankruptcy of thousands of people and individuals in rural communities  throughout Louisiana and the Nation who, through no fault of their own, have been caught up in the disasters of the last few weeks and months.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The disasters I speak of are not like the manmade disaster that is happening on Wall Street as we speak. It is not the purpose for which a group of Senators, both Republicans and Democrats, have been meeting around the clock for hours. They are disasters of nature's making--hurricanes, strong winds, and heavy rains that no one could prevent, but we most certainly can stop the economic downturn in the aftermath that will occur.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am here today because it looks to me and several of my colleagues as though this Congress intends to leave without taking any action whatsoever, to give even hope to people, thousands of hard-working taxpayers who are in this situation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I will speak for an hour, but this cartoon says it all. This was in the USA TODAY newspaper yesterday. I don't think it needs any explanation. I represent the lower ninth ward. I am proud to represent the ninth ward and the lower ninth ward. I also represent St. Bernard Parish and Plaquemines Parish and Terrebonne Parish and others that were devastated and basically have been abandoned in large measure by aspects of this Government that did not come to their aid. This cartoon says we have been  building a levee for the last several weeks--or trying to build a levee--around Wall Street. Meanwhile, the rest of the country--whatever.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Out there in the rest of the country--whatever--which is what I represent--are thousands of farmers. This is what their fields look like. They are completely underwater, not because they left the hose on too long or failed to do the proper irrigation techniques but because we had Hurricane Gustav, Hurricane Ike, and Hurricane Fay, which did not hit just Florida, but that storm, as the Presiding Officer will remember, dropped significant rains throughout large parts of the country right before  harvest time. Then, a few weeks later--because the farmers in many districts who watch the weather, of course, every day, made the decision to wait until these rains were done, they would then go into their fields and harvest the thousands of acres that were planted in Louisiana in cotton, soybean, rice, sugarcane, sweet potatoes, and our beautiful pecan</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The State I represent, as people will know their geography, is the State that basically drains, through the Mississippi River, the Arkansas, the Missouri River, comes down through the Mississippi River to Louisiana. There was simply nowhere for the water to go. It broke levees everywhere. The  levees in New Orleans held because of the work I have been, in large measure, fighting for with others to help build. But levees have broken all over Louisiana,  including Federal levees and non-Federal levees. We are a strong State but not always strong enough to hold in the water from the whole Nation. Although we have tried on many occasions to build the kind of levee system we need, we are 20 or 30 years behind.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I got here 12 years ago and have worked every day to accelerate that, and I am going to stay here for as long as it takes to get the job done. Nonetheless, we are not there yet.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So the water came into these fields. The farmers cannot harvest their crops. They cannot get into the fields to try to save what is left. This is a farmer who has farmed profitably with his family for probably over 50 years. He is from Chaneyville. This is what the rice fields look like if you grow rice in water, but it can't grow in salt water. So the salt water and the tidal surge came in, ruining the rice crop. Then, the cotton crop, which looked so beautiful just a couple of weeks ago--8  weeks ago--the farmers throughout the South were celebrating what a beautiful crop they may have. It has been a very tough year, as the Presiding Officer knows, with high fuel prices and the financial markets being unsettled, which has not just been going on the last few weeks. Farmers</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This Congress, Democrats and Republicans, is about ready to leave, having done nothing--nothing--not even a lifeline, not even a telegraph, not even a message to say: We hear you.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Right now everyone is--many people--downstairs in a room talking about how we can build a levee around Wall Street. I understand that something has to be done about the financial situation. I am not sure I am in a position to be able to say exactly what should happen. But I can tell my colleagues that while everybody has been meeting for weeks about building a levee on Wall Street, the levees have already broken at home. They have already broken at home; not just in Louisiana but in Texas and  in Arkansas and in Missouri and in Kansas and throughout the heartland. People who never even heard about a subprime loan, never, ever looked at an application for a subprime loan, never went to a bank to inquire about a subprime loan, and most certainly never knowingly bought one, their levees have already broken.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, I would not have kept my colleagues here. I am known up here as tenacious but a team player. I fight hard, but I fight fair. I most certainly would not have asked 100 Members, for whom I have the greatest respect and with whom it has been my honor to work with, each of them, to have great difficulty in their plans for the weekend. I understand one-third are up for reelection. There are Senators who came to me to say they have taken the first--tried to take the first vacation with their child  in 6 months. Other Senators have said they have had these plans. I understand that. I have two young children at home myself. But I could not leave without at least making a 1-hour pitch--and I am going to be here after the vote for several hours. I asked to speak for 1 hour before this vote because I wanted to be able to lay this case down. But I will be here for the rest of the day speaking about this and through the evening if the Senate stays in. As long as the Senate is in, I am</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I wish to read from the terrific statement that our commissioner from Louisiana, Mike Strain, who has been leading this effort--not only for us but nationally--I wish to say something so people understand how strongly I feel about this issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mike Strain is not a Democrat; he is a Republican. I actually didn't even support him in his election. I supported someone else. But he is the agriculture commissioner now, and it is my job to stand with him and to do what I can to help our rural communities. So I asked him to testify before the committee that I chair this week to try to get something on the record in Congress to help.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is what our commissioner says, who is, by the way, a farmer himself. He is a veterinarian. He is very  knowledgeable. He is a tenacious fighter. He came up and has spent days here trying to sound the alarm. He says:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Louisiana agriculture faces unprecedented losses from Hurricanes Gustav and Ike. This is the largest natural disaster affecting agriculture, aquaculture, forestry, and fisheries in Louisiana history.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, that statement did get my attention. I have only been here 12 years, but for a commissioner who is knowledgeable, who is trained, who has been in the business, who has been elected by the people of my State, to make such a statement before a committee, I thought it might be worth it to bring that statement to the full floor of the Senate. He goes on:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>No parish or commodity was spared by these storms. From the cattle rancher and the oyster fisherman in the southernmost tip of Plaquemines Parish, to cotton farmers in the delta of East Carol Parish all were severely impacted. Combined with the timing of these storms, just prior to harvest, and the devastation caused by the wind (110 miles per hour), in Terrebonne Parish, the flooding (24 inches), in Franklin Parish, and the tidal surge (12 feet) in Cameron Parish, our agriculture community is  in peril.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He has held 11 meetings across the State with farmers and ranchers. I have been to several of them with him. There are several reasons our situation is so grave: One, the inadequacy of the crop insurance program we have in place, but the regulations aren't written yet, and there is no availability for our farmers to access; insufficient disaster provisions of the farm bill, which I just described; farmers who have contracts with elevators and cannot deliver the commodity; bank liens against partially  filled commodity contracts; and deterioration of rain and cotton quality, which I have demonstrated with my pictures earlier.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I wish to go on to read his statement to explain these in some detail:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Higher input cost--Fuel and fertilizer costs have more than doubled since the start of the current crop.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I don't know what the prices are in the Presiding Officer's State, but in the last year, gasoline prices and diesel prices have been on the rise. As the Presiding Officer knows, several of us have been in negotiations on bills trying to contain those costs. We have not yet been successful. But the price of gasoline and diesel over the last 12 to 15 months has doubled. Fertilizer prices have gone up 300 percent, and potash, which is a commonly used substance for our agriculture base, the farmers  were faced with almost a 600-percent increase with no explanation. So their input costs were higher this year than almost any previous year. That is how the year started. Yet farmers absorbed it. They got their crops in the field and were ready for a good harvest, but that was a problem on the front end.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many farmers did not borrow enough money to cover these exorbitant costs. Some of them were totally unexpected. They used all their available credit. Since the storms occurred just prior to harvest, as I said, many of the farmers have incurred all the costs of the crop except harvesting and now will not be able to repay lenders and suppliers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I wish to say, they will not be able to repay lenders and suppliers. That is what the Wall Street bailout is all about. People unable--banks, holding companies, financiers unable to meet their debts, and this Congress could not scramble fast enough to try to build them a levee. But to the farmers who can't pay their notes: You are on your own.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He goes on to explain the inadequacy of the crop insurance program:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The farm bill was signed late. Had producers known they would have had a disaster program included that was based on their crop insurance coverage levels, they may have made different coverage decisions. But in order to be eligible for the SURE program--</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Which is the new program--</paragraph>
    <paragraph>USDA requires farmers to purchase catastrophic insurance or to participate in the noninsured assistance program. Due to thin margins and high costs of buyout coverage levels, crop insurance protection participation is relatively low in Louisiana and other southern States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is not that we don't want insurance. It is not that we don't believe in insurance. But the insurance programs that have been crafted by this Congress do not meet the needs of southern farmers. Every region of the country is very different, and the crop insurance programs that exist today have never been adequate for southern farmers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although a farmer may have only harvested a portion of his crop, he may have already surpassed the yield threshold. A cotton farmer reported to me that he met with his insurance agent and based on preliminary calculations, even though he has more than 1,000 acres of cotton and is facing a 50 percent crop loss, he will only receive only $3,300 in insurance proceeds.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, $3,300 is not going to keep the farming community in this farmer's hometown moving forward in a strong position.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The disaster provisions of the farm bill--I wish to read from his testimony and why it is inadequate:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many of our crops will not qualify for assistance under the current disaster provisions. All of the rules and regulations of the new 2008 Farm Bill had not been written.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I repeat that for the record. The opponents of what I am trying to do--and they are unidentifiable by name, but obviously there is some opposition or we would have been able to get this amendment moving--say: Senator, you are making a mountain out of a molehill because your farmers can get help through the 2008 disaster farm bill. We passed a farm bill. There is a disaster provision to try to help your farmers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I want to read this into the RECORD:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>All of the rules and regulations--</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Of that bill that is supposed to be a help for us--</paragraph>
    <paragraph>..... have not yet been written; and payments may not be available until October or November of 2009.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our farmers cannot wait until November of 2009 for assistance. They need it now. The only people who can give them assistance is us. So I am filing a bill today on behalf of myself, Senator Hutchison, Senator Lincoln, Senator Pryor, and Senator Wicker. On behalf of these Senators, I am introducing this bill today, and I urge other colleagues to look at this bill to see if they will join us in our efforts to put before this Congress at the earliest possible  time a bill that will at least provide a glimmer of hope for these farmers and rural communities throughout America. I send the bill to the desk.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, the reason this bill has to be introduced and the reason this speech had to be given today, and the reason this Congress must act before we leave--we are going to, it looks like, take a break for a day or two, come back for a couple of days next week, and it looks like there is going to be some bailout package for Wall Street. It might be a $700 billion package, it might be a $300 billion package, it could be a $400 billion package. By the time they finish negotiating, maybe it is only  a $200 billion package. Right now, I am leaning against voting for that package, no matter how it is structured, without certain provisions in it. This bill asks for $1 billion--$1 billion of--which at least will help all the rest of the farming communities in this part of the country while we are working on bailing out the financial community.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, $1 billion. And maybe that is not sufficient. I introduce the bill at this level because our needs in Louisiana are $700 million. I know we might not be able to get every penny that our commissioner has testified we desperately need and most certainly can justify. I am most certainly willing for this $1 billion to be shared by the other States that can put forth their documents and put forth their requirements. Maybe this $1 billion is not sufficient. But I could not in good conscience  leave here without putting something down with my colleagues. And this is a bipartisan effort.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am so grateful this morning that I was able to secure, by the motions that were provided this morning on the calendar, the support of Senator Hutchison of Texas. She cannot even get into some places in Texas to do the assessment because the water and damage is so high. But she has cosponsored this bill with me.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am very proud as well to have Senator Lincoln and Senator Pryor as cosponsors. I am going to yield to both of them in a moment. I see Senator Conrad is in the Chamber. I wish to give each of them 5 minutes to speak because they are quite knowledgeable about this situation--I must say more knowledgeable than I am about farm programs. Senator Lincoln is on the committee. Senator Conrad was the chief sponsor and designer of the farm disaster program.  He helped to write it. Having his testimony and him speaking today about why the program that he wrote, with all good intentions, is not necessarily going to help us and why we need special assistance will give a lot of support to my arguments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield to my good friend from Arkansas for whatever she might require. I thank her for being a cosponsor of the bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Arkansas.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300068" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I come to the floor today to say an enormous thanks to my good friend and neighbor, Senator Landrieu. When you grow up in small communities in middle America, one of the things you understand the most is that it is important to be a good neighbor and it is very important to have good neighbors. Through the last several years, we in Arkansas and the folks in Louisiana have come to understand that. We have housed most or a tremendous number of the evacuees  from both Katrina and Rita, and then Gustav sent us more evacuees. We have worked in tandem with our neighbors to try to figure out how we can be there for one another.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With our proximity to Louisiana and Texas, sitting right above those two States, we say thanks to our colleagues who are allowing us to join them in speaking out on behalf of a tremendously important constituency that we represent, and that is production agriculture.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator Landrieu has brought up so many good points. Again, I wish to reiterate that our growers across this country, these hard-working farm families, get up early every morning. They go into the fields, into their livestock arenas, and work hard to ensure that we can have the safest, most abundant, and affordable food supply in the world. They provide us a food supply, food and fiber per capita that is less than any other developed nation in the world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Yet in this body and throughout the Congress, it is hard to get attention if your issue is not glamorous. If it is not glamourous and it is not on the front page of People magazine or on the front page of these papers, people don't want to talk about it and they don't want to put the work into it that is required to get the results that are needed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These hard-working farm families are doing a tremendous job. As Senator Landrieu has mentioned, so often we forget these are folks who are absorbing tremendous costs--the increased cost of fuel and utilities, the needs they have in terms of chemical application, fertilizers, and other products, and the fluctuation of the price and value of commodities that are going crazy as well in many of those markets. So it is so important that we as a government create an environment where they  can continue to do the fine job they do in ensuring that all of us--not just in this country but globally--can enjoy that safe and abundant supply of food.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator Landrieu is exactly correct. Every year they go through this unbelievable anguish of figuring out how they are going to pay to keep their jobs. They go to their lenders in December and January to start a new crop year. This year they are going to go to that lender and they are going to say: We have had unbelievable disaster, whether it has been a hurricane, floods, tornadoes, which we suffered drastically this spring. We had one tornado that hit the ground and stayed on the ground  for 120 miles. We have seen floods that are 50-, 90-year floods. We had those in the spring, to be followed by a tremendous amount of water that was sent up from Louisiana or Texas after Gustav and Ike which put all of our crops that had been planted late because of spring floods under water, as Senator Landrieu has mentioned.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>They go in to their lenders, having suffered these unbelievable disasters,  they are faced with unbelievable  increases in their input costs, and the lender says: Your house is probably worth less because of the mortgage crisis and your 401(k) might not be so solid because of whatever else is going on. They get hit from absolutely every direction. Yet to be able to get back into the field, they have to have the support of those lenders. Without having the Government behind them, the Government to say, We are going to stand with you in whatever it is that you meet up against, they are not going to be  able to continue to do that tremendous job.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As Senator Landrieu mentioned--and I know Senator Conrad has worked tirelessly in terms of crop insurance--she is exactly right. Crop insurance doesn't fit us like it does the rest of the country. We grow capital-intensive crops and to insure ourselves against that kind of liability and that kind of risk, it is not cost effective, nor is the payout what it needs to be when we hit those disasters. So it is critically important that we recognize the disaster program that is intended  to be there for those farmers crop insurance cannot fully protect.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We worked in this farm bill to come up with that program. Again, as Senator Landrieu has mentioned, USDA has failed to give us the rules. So these growers, who are caught between a rock and a hard spot, know they have a 2008 farm bill, there are no rules that apply, and they are not going to understand or even know what they can count on in terms of disaster payments until the spring. It is too late by April or May to have gotten their assistance, their financing, their ability to know  what they are going to be able to plant and start for a 2009 crop year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank my good friend and my good neighbor because we understand how important it is to be and to have good neighbors. I am very grateful she is standing up for our farm families and allowing those of us who want to stand with her to say: It may not be a glamorous issue, it may not be one that people are going to jump up and rise to the occasion to try to solve. But I tell you one thing, when people look around and realize that it is not just stock markets, it is not just home mortgages, but  it is actually the ability to feed your family, then they will figure out that it is absolutely appropriate that we stand here today and ask our Government to help us move forward with the kind of environment that our growers need to put seed in the ground, to produce, as well as to be competitive in a global marketplace so we can continue to allow them to produce unbelievably safe and abundant food and fiber for this Nation and for the entire world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thanks to my good friend and neighbor, Senator Landrieu. I am proud to be here with her to fight on behalf of America's growers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank the Senator for yielding.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300063" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I thank the Senator from Arkansas for her remarks. As you can see, she is one of the experts in farming policy of this country. We are very grateful.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I now yield 5 minutes to the Senator from North Dakota.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from North Dakota.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300026" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I thank Senator Landrieu, the Senator from Louisiana, for her leadership. Senator Lincoln, who is a valuable member of the Agriculture Committee and the Finance Committee, played such an important role in writing a new farm bill, and Senator Pryor, as well, from Arkansas, who is here.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>They are fighting for farmers who have been devastated by disasters, farmers who are down and out through no fault of their own.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We hear some saying: Wait, there is a disaster program that has just passed that is in the farm bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Indeed, that is true. In fact, I am the author of that legislation, very proud of it. The problem is, we don't yet have the regulations from the U.S. Department of Agriculture as to how that program will be administered. So these farmers who have been hit by one hurricane after another don't know the rules of the road. They can't know. So they are there wondering if there is any help for them. And what do they see? They see Congress rushing to help Wall Street and understanding that if credit  in this country locks up, it is not just going to be Wall Street. The Chairman of the Federal Reserve has told us that if the credit lockup continues, 3 to 4 million Americans will lose their jobs in the next 6 months. So we all understand there is much more at risk than Wall Street. Main Street is on the line.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But what about these farm families? What about them? Apparently, there is no place in this package for them. And the excuse? Well, we have a disaster program in the farm bill. But the problem is, it is not in effect and no one knows the rules of the road because USDA hasn't written them. Talk about a catch-22. These farmers, these constituents of Senator Landrieu, these constituents of Senator Lincoln, these constituents of Senator Pryor are out there in limbo land.  They are being told: Oh, yes, there is a disaster program for you. But nobody can tell them what it is because the rules and regulations have not yet been drafted. But it is there, so don't you worry. And they are thinking: Well, wait a minute, where is the help? What am I going to do about planting decisions for next year</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What Senator Landrieu is asking for here is exactly what needs to be done; that is, a bridge program to deal with the current emergency until the disaster program that is part of the farm bill is in effect. So, Mr. President, I would hope our colleagues in the House and the Senate and representatives of the administration would help find a way to deal with this crisis because these farm families are in every bit as much a crisis as the families who are being affected by the fiscal crisis,  and these farm families deserve our help as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank Senator Landrieu for her leadership. She has been persistent. She has gone from colleague to colleague. She has talked to the House and the Senate, trying to persuade them that these farm families should not be abandoned at their time of need. What an irony it would be if the Congress moved in the next few days to react to a fiscal crisis in the country but left part of the country out and said to those farm families in Arkansas, in Louisiana, and in Texas, and, yes, in Mississippi:  Tough luck for you. We have $700 billion for other parts of the country, but we don't have $1 billion for you. Mr. President, that can't be the result.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank the Chair, and I thank Senator Landrieu for the time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300063" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I thank the Senator from North Dakota. I couldn't say it better myself, and I most certainly don't know it as well as he does, but I wish to read to the Senator, before he leaves the floor, something that I think will make him even more concerned.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to say to the Senator that, in anticipation--because I was getting nowhere with my conversations, except with good people such as yourself, and of course Senator Harkin was very interested, Senator Lincoln, and Senator Hutchison, but others didn't seem to have a real understanding of this situation despite the fact that we kept talking. So I wrote a letter to HUD, because in the disaster package which we are voting on now, the Senator may know that there  is $22 billion of special disaster relief, and in that there is $6.5 billion of community development block grant money, for which we are grateful. That is money for Louisiana, Texas, Mississippi, and, frankly, the whole part of the country that got hit by the storms. But Houston alone--the</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So people would tell me: Senator, you don't have a problem. Just go get some money from the community development block grant. Maybe you all can come up with a plan to help your farmers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I thought: Well, let me scurry over and find out if that could be possible.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I wrote a letter as quickly as I could, and I said:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Gustav and Ike caused an estimated $700 million in damage in agricultural damage in Louisiana alone. Regulations have still not been written ..... will not be available through this program until 2009, which is much too long to wait. Can CDBG funds be used to provide grants and loans to individual farmers, ranchers, and fishermen, as well as agricultural lending institutions and processing facilities?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I was hoping that maybe I could get a glimmer of hope. But I want to read for the record what they wrote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is probably an eligible activity under the CDBG disaster recovery program. CDBG funds may be used to assist businesses to create or retain low- and moderate-income jobs, and the CDBG disaster recovery program allows the State to make grants and loans directly rather than working through local governments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But here is the kicker:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The only issue that may arise is that Circular OMB A-87 does not allow one Federal program to be used for costs allocable to another program and these costs may be allocable to the USDA SURE Program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And here is the last sentence:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If the CDBG activity is designed to only cover costs USDA will not allow, then it could work.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I tell my friend from North Dakota, if I go home and try to read this paragraph of gobbledygook to my farmers, I wouldn't blame them for trying to find another Senator. I mean, I cannot even understand it myself, yet I am supposed to go home and tell the people whom I represent that this is the paragraph I have left Washington with?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I didn't think this was sufficient, and so I make no apologies to my colleagues, but as a way of explanation, the reason I am standing here for this 1 hour is to just testify that this paragraph is not sufficient. The program is not sufficient.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As I speak, I know the powers that be in this Chamber, on both sides, and in the White House have been in meeting after meeting trying to bail out Wall Street. Could somebody spend 1 hour or 2 hours figuring out how to bail out our farmers throughout the entire midpart of our country? Because this paragraph isn't going to do it.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300026" topic="">
    <paragraph>Will the Senator yield?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300063" topic="">
    <paragraph>I will yield.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300026" topic="">
    <paragraph>I have been in the Senate for 22 years, and I have gotten letters like that in the past. I know exactly what they mean. It means "not eligible." They say "probably it is," with this one little problem, and the little problem is that because there is another program--the disaster program in the farm bill--CDBG cannot be used for that purpose. They can write all the fancy legal language they want to try to make somebody feel better, but we know at the end of the day how much money  it is going to result in for these farmers who have been hit by a disaster--zero, goose egg, nothing. That is what is going to happen.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, the catch-22 your farmers face and farmers all across America face is we have a disaster bill that was passed as part of the farm bill, but USDA has not written the regulations--the rules of the road. So, in effect, there is no program available currently, yet the disaster is now. These farmers have been hit now. The question is, Is there going to be any help for them now?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Here we have the prospect of a massive rescue package for the entire country to prevent 3 or 4 million people from losing their jobs in the next 6 months, and yet we have a need that is now. It is immediate. It is not 6 months from now, it is right now.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senator is doing the Lord's work, and I hope very much that we can find a way to get a resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300063" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the Senator from North Dakota. Again, because I was able to introduce this bill this morning, I wanted very much for it to be introduced with the support of both Republican and Democratic leaders, and I was able to secure that. As I said, the senior Senator from Texas is a cosponsor of this bill, and I am certain that sometime before the next few days she will speak on behalf of the farmers of Texas because I myself am aware, having flown over many parts of southwest Louisiana,  what the agricultural situation in Texas looks like. It is not quite as bad per capita as Louisiana--and, of course, Texas has Galveston, Bridge City, Houston, and so many other areas affected--but the agricultural hit to Texas is going to be significant.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>May I inquire of the Chair how many minutes I have remaining?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator has 18 minutes remaining.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300063" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the Chair.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I think this says it all. I most certainly am not trying, again, to grandstand here because I do understand the significance of what happens on Wall Street and in Manhattan and in many of the financial centers of this country, of which New Orleans, whether it is a small city--Merrill Lynch actually started in New Orleans many years ago. So I am not unaware of the significance of cities such as Boston and Manhattan and New Orleans and San Francisco and Chicago and the well-being  of our financial sector and our country to operate. I am not unaware of the importance of this financial system needing to be secure not just for our people or our institutions and our taxpayers but for the world. Our economy is so large, and so much of the rest of the world's finances, in large measure, now are so interconnected. So I am not here complaining about the time and effort that has gone into trying to figure this situation out.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What I am complaining about is that in all of these discussions, no one seems to understand that there is a financial crisis right now in the heartland that is not being relieved by this disaster bill we are getting ready to vote on, nor, to date, have I heard one sentence, one phrase, one section, one paragraph that might bring any hope to the thousands of farmers and ranchers who never even saw a subprime loan, who have never filled out an application for a subprime loan, yet whose crops in  the field are rotting, are unharvestable--not one single word about them. So I thought it was worth at least 1 hour of this Congress's time to hear that word from me and to hear that word from Senator Lincoln and to hear that word from Senator Conrad and to hear that word from Senator Pryor and to hear that word from Senator Wicker and Senator Hutchison, who have joined in this effort.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am going to ask the other Senators to join with us. Many of them are reading the document now. Senator Harkin has it under consideration. Senator SAXBY CHAMBLISS has it under consideration. I have expressed to both of them, with respect, as leaders of the Agriculture Committee--should they see anything in this bill that they think should be modified or increased or decreased or written in a different way, the Senator from Louisiana is most certainly willing to take any amendments  that they would think necessary to make this work. I am not even asking for this, again, to be for Louisiana. This is for the whole country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have to spend an hour saying $700 billion for Wall Street and zero for farmers? It could be said a different way: $700 billion for financiers, zero for farmers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If you want to know why people in America are upset with this bailout, I could give you several reasons. Let me try one big one. The regular people out there, who put boots on in the morning and go to work, direct traffic, run the daycare centers, teach our kids in school, get on the fire trucks in the morning, shine shoes, open the grocery store--they don't think anyone is listening to them. And they are right. No one is listening to them. Everyone is listening to the people who have a lot of  money--money, money, money.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>People who work hard every day and actually put in 14-hour days and maybe make--not farmers, because they usually make more than this--but $8 or $10 an hour, they work hard, they never heard about a quick buck--there are no quick bucks in the life they live. They don't make $500 million an hour. They don't make $1 million a minute. They are lucky if they make $1 million in a lifetime. I have to go home and tell them not only I wasn't able to do anything to help them but no one in the whole Congress  could come up with a plan to help them. I am not going home with that. I am not going home with it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am not going home with gobbledegook. I want to read it again in the last 5 minutes. This was the response I got. Senator, we can't do anything for you, we can't amend the bill, we can't give you a vote on the floor, we can't put it in the bailout package, we can't put it in the disaster package, we can't have a committee meeting, we can't do anything. We can't do anything. That is what I was told all week.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is the sheet of paper I am going to submit for the Record. This is $6.5 billion. I hope the cameras could see it. I wish I had it blown up; $6.5 billion. That is what we are taking home for all the disasters including Houston, Galveston, everything else. I was told if I needed help for my farmers, I could do this:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dear Senator, your request to help farmers, this is probably an eligible activity under the Community Development Block Grant Disaster Recovery Program. These funds may be used to assist businesses to create or retain low- and moderate-income jobs and the CBDG Disaster Recovery Program allows the States to make grants or loans directly rather than through local governments. The only issue that may arise is that circular OMB 8-87 [may?] does not allow one Federal program to be used for costs allocable  to another program and these costs may be allocable to the USDA shore program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If the CDBG is designed to only cover costs USDA would not allow, then it would work.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I don't have time to explain this to my farmers because it doesn't make any sense. The only thing--actually nothing makes sense to them. I went home last weekend--and I am going to wrap up. I have about a minute left.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I went home last weekend and told them I would be there, and hundreds of them came out of the fields with dirt on their hands, of course, filthy dirt. These are men who had been farming for decades, who said: Senator, I left my sons in the field to come meet you. These are the farmers I met with. They said: Senator, what is going on in Washington? Between the weather reports we have to read and working hard in our fields all day, we are having a hard time understanding about this bailout. Who  are we bailing out? Why are we bailing them out? And does anybody know that our crops are under water, that we have had the worst disaster?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This disaster for us, may I remind everyone, comes 3 years after Katrina hit our State and it was the worst natural disaster and manmade disaster. Let me give you some numbers to illustrate this. When Hurricane Andrew hit, the per capita was $58. After the attacks on the World Trade Center, the per capita equaled $1,050. But after Katrina and Rita hit, the per capita damage shot up to $4,366. And that number will only increase after all the damage left by Gustav and Ike has been assessed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me repeat that. No disaster in the history of the country ever exceeded the mark that Katrina and Rita have left Louisiana, including 9/11 or anything. Our disaster in Katrina and Rita, from Mississippi and Louisiana, exceeded $4,000 per capita.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I know about disasters. I have been through the worst one in the history of the country. We are just recovering. We are grateful for the aid. We are still struggling. We have communities that are still destroyed, neighborhoods with houses that are worth $600,000 as well as $50,000, still struggling. The gulf coast is not back. And then we get hit by this and then I have to go home and tell my farmers that we are going to do $700 billion for financiers, and nothing for them? I have to go home  and tell them I don't know what is going on in this bailout passage, all I can tell you is it looks as though the financiers are going to win and you are going to lose again.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thought before I did that, if at least they could see that I was fighting for them and they could see an actual bill we introduced, that might be helpful.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I see my good friend, the Senator from Mississippi, here. I would be happy to yield a minute if he wanted to speak on this, or two?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300023" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I asked the distinguished Senator to yield to me because I want to commend her for the strong argument she has made, the attention she has brought to the issue of agricultural disaster both in her State and Texas in particular. But this also affects my State, Mississippi.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Listening to her a little while ago, from my office, over the television, made me think: We do need to address this issue, and why not put language in this bill that would help ensure that consideration was given?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I wish to be listed, if the Senator will permit me, as a cosponsor to her bill. I am pleased to support it and I hope it is helpful.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I don't know whether we have the votes. I don't know what would happen in conference. I don't know what will happen when the administration sees it. But I think you have made some excellent points and they need to be acknowledged by those in charge of our programs so ways can be found to help these farmers.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300063" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the Senator from Mississippi.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>How much time do I have remaining?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Six minutes remain.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300063" topic="">
    <paragraph>I am going to wrap up now in 1 minute and yield the rest of my time because I know the Senators are anxious for a vote. I couldn't think of a better way to end than with an endorsement from the senior Senator from Mississippi. He and I and his colleague before him, Trent Lott, have been through the mill, as they say at home, with these storms. Well fought, shoulder to shoulder, side by side. We have had disagreements, but we continue to work on behalf of the people of Mississippi  and Louisiana, the gulf coast. We have said often--he and I have come to the floor to say this is America's working coast. We are America's energy coast. We are a breadbasket in our farming community for the rice, cotton, sugarcane, and corn. I appreciate his support.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I will be pleased to add him as a cosponsor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300063" topic="">
    <paragraph>Again, I want the Senator to understand I would not have taken this time--and I do not take it lightly. I am not here complaining about something that only affects Louisiana, although that would be meritorious enough. But I am here saying we cannot talk about a bailout of $700 billion for Wall Street and zero for the rest of America, particularly our farmers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300058" topic="COOPERATIVE DEVELOPMENT PROGRAM">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to ask the Senator from Vermont, the chairman of the State and Foreign Operations Subcommittee, if he would enter into a colloquy with me about the Cooperative Development Program which is funded in his bill?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="COOPERATIVE DEVELOPMENT PROGRAM">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would be pleased to enter into a colloquy with the Senator from South Dakota, Mr. Johnson.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300058" topic="COOPERATIVE DEVELOPMENT PROGRAM">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, I would like to commend your committee and all the work it has done to promote responsible international development. As you know, our Nation's cooperatives have played a significant role in our international development efforts for over 40 years. Mr. Chairman, your committee has been very supportive of the Cooperative Development Programs, and I applaud you for it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am, however, concerned that the program may suffer due to the continuing resolution. The request for applications for the 5-year competitively bid Cooperative Development Program is set to be reissued this fall. For a number of years, you and the committee have worked to encourage the U.S. Agency for International Development to continue the program's successes by providing needed increased funding. As currently configured, this small program provides funding for eight grants that are on average  less than $700,000 per year. I am concerned that under the continuing resolution, the new grants under this program will not be able to grow in accordance with intent of the State and Foreign Operations Subcommittee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Cooperatives have had a long and beneficial impact on the economy of my State, and I strongly support the Cooperative Development Program as it supports the growth of cooperatives as a means of spreading inclusive businesses in the developing world. This small but effective program enables U.S. cooperative development organizations to expand the use of this practical and beneficial development tool in our foreign assistance portfolio, and I hope that you can provide some insight on this issue.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="COOPERATIVE DEVELOPMENT PROGRAM">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I thank the Senator from South Dakota for his continued interest in international development and in the Cooperative Development Program. I assure him that the State and Foreign Operations Subcommittee intends to continue our strong support of the Cooperative Development Program in the fiscal year 2009 State and Foreign Operations appropriations bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300058" topic="COOPERATIVE DEVELOPMENT PROGRAM">
    <paragraph>I thank the chairman for his support and leadership on this issue.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="DDG--1000 ZUMWALT DESTROYER PROGRAM">
    <paragraph>Mr Chairman, I would like to clarify language included in the fiscal year 2009 Defense Appropriations bill that addresses the Navy's DDG-1000 Zumwalt destroyer program.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300056" topic="DDG--1000 ZUMWALT DESTROYER PROGRAM">
    <paragraph>The bill supports the Navy's DDG-1000 program, which incrementally funds the third ship, directs that a construction contract consistent with the ship's current acquisition schedule be awarded, and directs that the remaining funds necessary to complete the third ship be included in the fiscal year 2010 budget.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="DDG--1000 ZUMWALT DESTROYER PROGRAM">
    <paragraph>Mr. Chairman, the language also identifies a requirement for the Navy to have future shipbuilding requirements reviewed by the Joint Requirements Oversight Council, or JROC, before moving forward with any modifications to the existing Navy shipbuilding program of record and before any funds can be obligated for surface combatants. I understand that this requirement is a result of significant instability in the Navy's surface combatant shipbuilding program; however, I would like to  be clear that the intent of the bill is to award a contract for a third DDG-1000 in fiscal year 2009 that would be split funded between fiscal year 2009 an fiscal year 2010.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300056" topic="DDG--1000 ZUMWALT DESTROYER PROGRAM">
    <paragraph>That is correct. I fully expect the Joint Requirements Oversight Council to review future Navy surface combatant requirements so that the results of this review will be available as the Department considers future shipbuilding plans and any adjustments to the program that may be required in future budget submissions.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="DDG--1000 ZUMWALT DESTROYER PROGRAM">
    <paragraph>Thank you, Mr Chairman. Your support of the Zumwalt program is appreciated.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="DDG--1000 ZUMWALT DESTROYER PROGRAM">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the following disclosure of earmarks be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>Following is a list of congressional earmarks and congressionally directed spending items (as defined in clause 9 of rule XXI of the Rules of the House of Representatives and rule XLIV of the Standing Rules of the Senate, respectively) included in the bill or this explanatory statement, along with the name of each Senator, House Member, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner who submitted a request to the Committee of jurisdiction for each item so identified. Neither the bill nor the explanatory  statement contains any limited tax benefits or limited tariff benefits as defined in the applicable House and Senate rules.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="DISCLOSURE OF EARMARKS AND CONGRESSIONALLY DIRECTED SPENDING ITEMS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I wanted to take a moment to highlight a provision in this continuing resolution that is before us to provide mandatory funding for the Advanced Technology Vehicles Manufacturing Incentive Program, which we passed in last year's energy bill, EISA. As one of the principal authors of the provision, I am happy to see the program moving forward and particularly pleased to see the guidance in the resolution that will press the Department of Energy to move forward quickly  to get the program up and running. There is great potential in bringing these new advanced technology vehicles to market and we can't let difficulties in obtaining financing for manufacturing facilities derail our efforts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As we conferred on the program almost a year ago, it was clear there were credit problems for both the large manufacturers and the smaller start-ups and component suppliers, particularly as it related to getting financing for the most cutting edge technologies such as batteries for electric-drive vehicles. Now that credit markets have tightened further, the need is even more acute. I hope that with this funding the Department can move quickly to produce regulations to implement the program and  particularly to move forward with loans to component manufacturers, including battery manufacturers such as A123 Systems and other key suppliers that will be imperative to bringing forward plug-in vehicles in the coming years. Several of these smaller, important component suppliers have been participating in the Department loan guarantee program but have yet to complete their journey through that</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, I have been told there may be some confusion about the terms of the loans as the provision creating the loan program references the "activities" that are the subject of a grant program also authorized in the same section of EISA. The grant program is limited to 30 percent of the costs of a facility. This is a fairly typical cost share for grant programs. Some have raised a question as to whether this 30 percent cap should also apply to the loan program. That is not the way I read the  language of the law and was certainly not our intent in writing the provision. Moreover, I would argue that it would dramatically limit the effectiveness of the program as it would require companies to go to tight credit markets for 70 percent of their financing, precisely the problem we were seeking to remedy</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300042" topic="DISCLOSURE OF EARMARKS AND CONGRESSIONALLY DIRECTED SPENDING ITEMS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I will vote against <bill type="h" number="2638">H.R. 2638</bill>, the continuing resolution for fiscal year 2009. Congress needs to provide funding to keep the Federal Government operating, and this bill includes funding for a number of programs I support. I am particularly pleased that this resolution includes money to help Wisconsinites recover from the serious flooding the Midwest experienced earlier this year. I joined a number of my colleagues in asking appropriators to include this disaster relief,  which will help Wisconsin families and communities still dealing with the aftermath.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But wrapping three separate appropriations bills into one package, with no opportunity for amendments, is irresponsible and unacceptable. Moreover, this bill provides funding to continue the war in Iraq, when we should be bringing that war to a close. And it allows Members of Congress to receive a hefty $4700 pay raise, despite the massive deficits we are running and the economic pain so many of our constituents are feeling.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="DISCLOSURE OF EARMARKS AND CONGRESSIONALLY DIRECTED SPENDING ITEMS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, we are about to vote on the continuing resolution to enable the Federal Government to continue functioning until March 6, 2009.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I had hoped, as I know Chairman Byrd and Senator Cochran had, that we would have been permitted to debate and vote on the individual appropriations bills that the Appropriations Committee has reported.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That was not to be, due to President Bush's insistence that he would veto bills that exceed his arbitrary spending cap and to certain Republican Senators who have made it virtually impossible to pass anything here without the necessary 60 votes to overcome a filibuster.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A continuing resolution will result in hardship for many Federal agencies, and those hardships will be felt by the American people. But as long as some here would prefer to be obstructionists rather than legislators, this is the only course available to us.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Having said that, I commend Chairman Byrd and Senator Cochran for what they have done because it is a bipartisan bill that reflects the constructive efforts of the leaders of both parties to do their best under difficult circumstances.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are several items within the jurisdiction of the State and Foreign Operations Subcommittee in this bill. Senator Gregg and I, working with Congresswoman Lowey and Congressman Wolf, have ensured that vital programs continue and that necessary adjustments are made.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For example, we have lifted the cap on administrative expenses for the State Department's refugee and migration assistance programs. We have reauthorized the Overseas Private Investment Corporation, and we have provided authority to the Treasury Department to contribute up to $5 million to help Liberia extinguish its commercial debt.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also includes supplemental aid for Georgia, and it specifically prohibits the administration from transferring funds from other vulnerable former Soviet and Eastern European countries. We also provide funds to ensure continued Voice of America and Radio Free Europe broadcasting to Georgia, Russia, and the region during this time of heightened tensions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We provide additional funding to ensure the continued operations of the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction. And we provide emergency assistance for Haiti and other Caribbean countries that were severely damaged by the recent hurricanes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are all painfully aware that the 2008 hurricane season caused much loss of life and destruction of property in communities along the gulf coast of the United States. And while the Federal Government is trying to help the victims of those disasters, including with additional appropriations for disaster relief for victims of Hurricane Ike in this bill, we sometimes forget that Haiti, Cuba, Jamaica, the Dominican Republic, and other Caribbean  countries  suffered catastrophic destruction from Hurricanes Fay, Gustav, Hanna, and Ike.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In Haiti, the U.N. has reported that over 400 people have died due to the storms or storm-related causes, over 800,000 were severely affected, and some 150,000 were left homeless. Cuba reportedly suffered damage estimated at $5 billion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The U.S. Government has provided $30 million in emergency humanitarian aid to Haiti, but no additional assistance was requested by the administration. That was inexplicable, and I am pleased that the Congress did not likewise decide to ignore that impoverished nation in which we have already invested so much. This bill includes $100 million in emergency supplemental aid for hurricane relief and reconstruction for Haiti and other Caribbean countries.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This assistance was included to address both the short and longer term needs that Haiti and its neighbors face. We not only want to respond to immediate needs like potable water, food, shelter, and medical care, we also want to rebuild infrastructure and stabilize hillsides to avoid future washouts and mudslides that have caused so much loss of life. The U.S. Agency for International Development should use a portion of these funds to significantly enhance its efforts to address environmental  vulnerabilities in key Haitian watersheds.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We know that next year there will be more hurricanes. For once, let us look beyond the immediate needs and help Haiti and its neighbors strengthen basic infrastructure bridges and roads and help with reforestation, so that damage from future storms is less severe.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We also know that Haiti was a destitute country before these latest hurricanes. Its Government is fragile; its economy is in shambles. These devastating storms are capable of reversing whatever economic and social progress has been made in recent years and could trigger chaos and panic and a repeat of the flotillas of fleeing desperate people that we saw a few years ago.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Cuba also suffered widespread damage from the hurricanes, and I am disappointed that the Cuban Government has not been willing to accept offers of humanitarian aid from the United States. I also regret that the administration's ill-conceived embargo against Cuba prevents the American people from helping the Cuban people in this time of need. This is an opportunity to cooperate with the Cuban Government for a purely humanitarian purpose. We are long overdue for a new policy toward Cuba, as this  disaster so graphically illustrates.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also want to mention the Reid-Byrd stimulus bill we voted on yesterday, which would have provided urgently needed funding for a wide range of domestic programs to help bolster this Nation's ailing economy. These programs address critical needs of urban and rural working class people across America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Despite all the finger pointing and angry talk about how Washington is broken often by those who did their utmost to game the system or who have themselves been in Government for decades this is exactly what the Congress should be doing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I commend Chairman Byrd and Senator Reid for this initiative. After inheriting the largest surplus in this Nation's history, President Bush will leave a legacy of fiscal mismanagement and mile high deficits that dwarf anything in my 34 years in the Senate. For an administration that came into office piously claiming to be the guardians of responsible fiscal conservatism, when it comes to the economic security of middle class Americans this White House has proven to be incompetent,  unprincipled and unaccountable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This administration's economic policies have been disastrous for the people of this country who are most dependent on Federal funding for schools, hospitals, police and fire departments, farms and businesses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The stimulus items in <bill type="s" number="3604">S. 3604</bill>, none of which were requested by the White House and which most of our Republican friends voted to defeat, would have helped prevent an already precarious economic situation that threatens the livelihoods and retirements of millions of Americans, from becoming worse.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300058" topic="DISCLOSURE OF EARMARKS AND CONGRESSIONALLY DIRECTED SPENDING ITEMS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I am pleased that the appropriations package which the Senate is now considering incorporates a trio of security-related funding measures, including the fiscal year 2009 Military Construction, Veterans Affairs and Related Agencies Appropriations bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill is important to the Nation's military forces and their families and to the military veterans who have served their country so valiantly. By passing this legislation, we will fulfill the promise we have made to support our veterans and military families by providing historic levels of funding for military construction and the Department of Veterans Affairs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Military Construction and Veterans Affairs bill totals a record $119.6 billion dollars, of which $72.8 billion is discretionary funding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For the Department of Veterans Affairs, discretionary funding totals $47.6 billion, $2.8 billion over the President's request and $4 billion above the fiscal year 2008 enacted level. This is a landmark level of funding which will greatly enhance the VA's ability to deliver veterans' benefits in a timely manner and to provide first-rate medical care in first-class medical facilities to veterans throughout the country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Within the VA budget, the funding for veterans health care also set a new benchmark at nearly $41 billion, almost $2 billion above the President's request. A key focus of this funding is medical research. Not only does this bill flatly reject the cuts in research funding proposed by the President, but it also provides a healthy increase over last year's funding level. This is crucial to ensure that the VA is on the forefront in providing innovative treatment for service-related diseases and complex  combat injuries, such as traumatic brain injury, polytrauma injuries, and post-traumatic stress disorder.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am also pleased that the bill establishes a $250 million rural health initiative targeted toward meeting the unique needs of veterans who live in remote and rural areas. South Dakota is a prime example of the need for this type of initiative. Many veterans in South Dakota are scattered in sparsely populated rural areas, and many others live on Native American reservations. These veterans must drive long distances in many cases hundreds of miles--to access medical care.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Through the rural health care initiative, the VA can greatly expand its current rural health outreach and devote more resources to such programs as mobile clinics, telemedicine, community clinics, and shared health care services. Significantly, the Department will be able to implement targeted health care for rural areas without having to compete for funding with urban hospitals and clinics.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For military construction, the bill provides $25 billion. This funding will provide for the most critical construction needs of our Nation's military, improving safety and security on our military bases in the United States and abroad, and enhancing the living conditions of our soldiers and their families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, it is vitally important that the Senate act quickly on this spending package and see it signed into law before the end of the fiscal year so that we may speed this funding to the many programs that are essential to the health and well-being of our military forces, their families, and our Nation's veterans.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="DISCLOSURE OF EARMARKS AND CONGRESSIONALLY DIRECTED SPENDING ITEMS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, as our colleagues know, my State of Iowa and other States across the Midwest were hit by devastating tornadoes, floods, and heavy rains this past spring. These were natural disasters of historic proportions, and they left tremendous damage and destruction in their wake.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Three and a half months later, Iowans are making progress toward recovery. But the harsh reality is that many flood victims are still living in trailers or with relatives. Many businesses can't get the low-interest Small Business Administration loans they need to rebuild and recover. Cities are waiting for funding to restore damaged infrastructure. We still face billions of dollars in unmet needs across Iowa.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Within weeks of the flooding, Congress acted promptly to provide assistance, passing a $2.65 billion disaster assistance bill. This was intended to be only an initial injection of Federal aid--a downpayment on the long recovery ahead.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am very pleased that, in this continuing resolution before us today, we have the second installment on disaster assistance. The bill includes $23 billion in disaster aid, with a significant share of those dollars destined for Iowa and other Midwestern states hit by floods and tornadoes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a senior member of the Senate Appropriations Committee, I have been working with other members of the committee, and with the House Appropriations Committee; with other Senators from the disaster-impacted States; as well as the Iowa House delegation for months to secure these urgently needed funds. I am both gratified and grateful that my colleagues on the Appropriation Committees recognized the disaster recovery needs in my State of Iowa as a national priority.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The $23 billion provided in this bill is allocated in several areas. The largest segment is $8 billion to replenish FEMA's available funding, which is crucial. However, the amount that local governments and individuals receive from FEMA is set by existing law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One of the most important functions is mitigation funding equal to 20 percent of most of what FEMA spends in a State. Those funds are used to reduce the chance of damage from future disasters. I am proud that, in 1993, I was the chief sponsor of legislation that sharply expanded this program, similar to what it is today. We need not only to recover from past disasters, but work to limit damage in the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The most significant component of relief funding in this bill is $6.5 billion for community development block grants. State and local governments have considerable flexibility and leeway in how they use these grants. They can be used for home repairs and buyouts, assistance to businesses, repair of damaged public facilities, and additional mitigation efforts to reduce damage from future disasters.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The amount of CDBG funding varies from time to time, as do the specific rules. The language in this continuing resolution provides more flexibility than has often been provided in the past.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since passage of the initial flood relief in late June, the Department of Housing and Urban Development has been very slow to actually get CDBG funding out the door and to the people who need it. There has been endless redtape and chronic delays. And this is unacceptable at a time when so many people are hurting and so many businesses are struggling to put people back to work.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To prevent a repeat of this poor performance, a provision was included, which I proposed, requiring that HUD allocate at least one-third of the CDBG money in this bill within 60 days of it being signed. This will give us confidence that, by about December 1, a significant portion of this CDBG money will be in the hands of individuals and businesses that urgently need it. Needless to say, this "one third" requirement is a minimum. I hope that HUD will do better than that and will release this  new CDBG funding as expeditiously as possible.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This new disaster-relief package includes several other major components.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It includes $7.9 billion for FEMA disaster relief, which helps pay individuals affected by disasters nationally.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It includes $600 million for the social services block grant program to provide urgently needed services to people in areas hit by disasters. This funding can be used to purchase food, shelter, and clothing, as well as health care and mental health services. States may also use these funds for vital public health activities, such as surveillance of water-borne or mosquito-borne diseases. Funds may also be used to repair damaged health care and social services facilities, such as child care centers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, the package includes $182 million for construction of the new Cedar Rapids Courthouse. As many of my colleagues know, the city of Cedar Rapids was devastated by the flooding in June. The Cedar River crested at nearly 32 feet, inundating nearly 400 city blocks--more than 9 square miles. The construction of this new Federal courthouse will be an important symbol of the rebirth and rebuilding of this proud city.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The package also includes important disaster relief for rural areas. It includes: $59 million for the U.S. Department of Agriculture to help rebuild and repair single and multifamily homes in rural areas; $40 million for USDA to rebuild and repair rural community facilities, including nonprofit facilities, everything from hospitals to day care centers, in towns with populations under 20,000; $26 million for rural utilities including water and wastewater, rural electric cooperatives, electric  and telephone repair, and reconstruction; $100 million for the USDA Emergency Watershed Program for recovery from floods, storms, and other natural disasters; $115 million for the USDA Emergency Conservation Program; $850 million is made available for the repair of State highways damaged by the storms across the country;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to the relief provisions in the continuing resolution, I want to mention the good work of my senior colleague, Senator GRASSLEY, who played a lead role in moving a number of important tax provisions in the separate tax extender bill that passed the Senate earlier this week--tax provisions that will be of significant benefit to those recovering from disasters. I was pleased to be the lead Democratic sponsor of his disaster tax bill in this area that includes important assistance  for homeowners, for the building of new housing, and assistance to rebuild and revitalize business.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The funding in the continuing resolution will bring a second infusion of urgently needed resources to people in Iowa and across the Midwest.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>No question, people in my State have suffered terrible damage, and the road back is going to be long and difficult. But as I have witnessed in recent months, Iowans are a tough, resilient people. And they are also a generous people, pitching in to help neighbors and strangers alike.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As I learned in the Navy, there are two responses to a disaster. It's either "every man for himself, abandon ship," or it's "all hands on deck, save the ship." Well, Iowans are an "all hands on deck" kind of people. We will endure--and we will prevail.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, let me say that the disaster funding in this bill is another important, positive step on the path to full recovery. But additional assistance will be needed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The reality is that the funding levels for the disaster package were set with only minimal information on the level of damage suffered by Hurricanes Gustav and Ike. When that data is set, I believe it will be clear that additional assistance will be necessary for those accounts that are allocated by the level of damage in each State or region compared to all of the disaster areas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Hopefully, early next year, by which time we should have a nearly complete assessment of damages and needs, I will work with my colleagues on the Appropriations Committee to include a third installment of disaster relief on the omnibus appropriations bill for fiscal year 2009.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am grateful to my colleagues for providing this generous assistance to people and businesses in Iowa and across the Midwest. And I urge their support for this continuing resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300056" topic="DISCLOSURE OF EARMARKS AND CONGRESSIONALLY DIRECTED SPENDING ITEMS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today the Senate is considering the Defense Appropriations Act for fiscal year 2009, along with a 6 month continuing resolution and other matters. In regards to the Defense portion of this bill, the Appropriations Committee examined the President's request of $491.7 billion for funding under the jurisdiction of the Defense Subcommittee. The amount that is contained in this measure for the Department of Defense is $487.7 billion, $4 billion below the request and equal  to the subcommittee's 302(b) allocation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over the past 9 months the Appropriations Committee received testimony from the leaders of the Department of Defense and intelligence community, on all of the critical programs requested by the Administration for the coming fiscal year. These hearings were augmented by countless meetings and detailed review by the committee staff. Senator Cochran, Senator Stevens, and I together worked in formulating the recommendations that were  reviewed  and approved by the Defense Subcommittee on September 10. Those recommendations form the basis of the bill which is before the Senate today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The highest priority for our committee is to support our men and women in uniform. That means we strongly support and fully fund programs to provide for the pay and allowances of our forces, to take care of their families, and preserve the readiness of the force. In this bill, our families are protected. Additional funds are provided to fix hospitals and barracks, to serve our families through the Family Advocacy Program, and to enhance our Defense Health Program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To ensure our forces are prepared to serve in harm's way, the recommendation provides for the purchase of essential equipment and support to meet their needs. The measure approves and, in some cases, increases funding above the budget request for key programs such as the Future Combat System, unmanned aerial vehicles, F-18 aircraft, UH-60, MH-60, and CH-47 helicopters among many others.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The recommendation includes funds to purchase 14 F-35 aircraft and includes advance procurement to preserve the industrial base for the F-22 aircraft and DDG-51 destroyer programs. It provides a $120 million increase for our near-term missile defense programs and support for all the major missile systems in the budget request. It includes $750 million in additional funds to support our National Guard and Reserve equipment needs and $750 million to enhance our Nation's intelligence, surveillance  and reconnaissance capabilities to support our warfighters today. In addition, the needs of the intelligence community are addressed in this measure and summarized in a classified annex.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill before the Senate, which was passed by the House on Wednesday by a vote of 370 to 58, represents a compromise between the views of the Senate and House Defense Subcommittees. Additional funding above the amounts approved by the Senate Defense Subcommittee is included for several initiatives including a down payment on the next LPD-17 amphibious ship. It provides more funding for C-130 aircraft than we had recommended and a higher level of funding for the Presidential helicopter program.  It also includes a cut of 5 percent in funding to scale back contracting out in the Defense Department.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On balance we believe this is a very good bill. The budget allocation requires us to make some difficult choices curtailing funding for programs which are of interest to certain members, outside interest groups, or the military departments. But the funds that are reduced are for programs which are behind schedule or not sufficiently justified. In reallocating funding from these programs, this bill provides for the critical unmet needs of the military and intelligence community albeit at a lower  overall funding level.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today is September 25. The fiscal year is rapidly coming to a close. The Senate is using an unusual procedure to consider this bill. It is not one that any of us is particularly pleased with, and some are likely to be critical of it, but it is a procedure and probably the only procedure which will allow for passage of this very important measure before the end of the fiscal year. I can assure my colleagues that we have worked closely with the House on a bipartisan basis to ensure that the bill  which has come before the Senate represents what is needed for our Nation's defense and for the men, women, and their families who serve her. I thank all my colleagues, and in particular Senator Cochran and Senator Stevens, for their efforts in putting this bill together. I urge my colleagues to join with me today and vote to pass this measure.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300029" topic="DISCLOSURE OF EARMARKS AND CONGRESSIONALLY DIRECTED SPENDING ITEMS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today at a time of significant financial crisis in our Nation to discuss a program within this continuing resolution that, in my opinion, is the wrong priority at the wrong time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over the last 2 years, the chairman of the Senate Veterans' Affairs Committee has brought before the Committee and this Senate legislation to authorize bonus payments for Filipino veterans who fought in World War II. Like my colleague and good friend, Senator Akaka, I respect and honor the sacrifice of the Filipinos in that war, and I respect his tenacity to pass what he believes is a remedy to a wrong.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is where I unfortunately part with the Senator. After World War II, the Philippines were not left destitute, with America turning a blind eye to their sacrifice and efforts in the war. In fact, the United States has spent millions upon millions of dollars on infrastructure in the Philippines.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, there are some who think that is not enough. There are some who believe that Filipino veterans deserve to have all the benefits and entitlements that American veterans are afforded. I disagree.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At a time when we have soldiers coming home broken from combat, this bill would designate as an "emergency" $198 million to provide a lump-sum payment of $9,000 to Filipino veterans currently living in the Philippines and $15,000 for those Filipino veterans living in the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, let me say that again: this would designate the funding I just spoke of as an "emergency."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, I know how things work around here. Someone's emergency doesn't always seem to be too urgent to other folks. But please, I would like somebody to come to this floor and explain to me how giving Filipino veterans a check for $9,000 or $15,000 can be seen as an emergency. Not when we are debating landmark legislation to shore up our economy, which is suffering so greatly. Not when we have Senators coming to this floor repeatedly arguing that we have so badly underfunded the VA that we need  supplemental spending every year just to keep up. Not when there are towns in Texas still cleaning up from the ravages of Hurricane Ike. And not when we have a Forest Service that is broke and must borrow and steal from other agencies to ensure that we can fight against wildfires threatening thousands of people's homes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I could go on for days talking about true emergencies in our Nation. However, designating a fund for Filipino veterans as an "emergency" just doesn't pass the smell test. And this is not an insignificant amount of money, Mr. President: we are talking about almost $200 million that could be used for items that truly deserve to be considered emergencies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I know that we will pass this continuing resolution, and I praise the work that was done on most of this bill. There are a lot of good programs that will get funded because of this bill and the work that was done on it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, I could not stay silent when I saw that almost $200 million, designated as emergency spending, was going to be spent on non-American veterans for actions taken in the 1940s.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I hope that my colleagues today will take a serious look at the authorization that will come before this Senate in the future to allow this funding to be spent. It is my serious belief, as I hope I spelled out clearly here today, that this funding should not be spent for its intended purpose. Instead, Senators should look at this funding as a way to pay for priorities, either within the VA or other agencies that have been underfunded, that are true emergencies.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="DISCLOSURE OF EARMARKS AND CONGRESSIONALLY DIRECTED SPENDING ITEMS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, this consolidated appropriations bill includes three important Fiscal Year 2009 appropriations bills, the Homeland Security appropriations bill, the Military Construction and Veterans appropriations bill, and the Defense appropriations bill. In addition, this bill includes funding for a number of other important programs, including nutrition and home energy assistance programs to ensure those most vulnerable who rely on these programs do not lose access to them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today many families are hurting from the current economic downturn and the rising food and energy costs. This bill includes additional funding for both the Nutrition for Women, Infants and Children, WIC, program and the Commodity Supplemental Food Program, CSFP, which provide assistance to children, low-income working families, and seniors. It is of vital importance that we continue these food programs for our Nation's least fortunate and most vulnerable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am pleased that the bill contains significant additional funding for the Low Income Home Energy Assistance Program, or LIHEAP. This bill includes a total of $5.1 billion for LIHEAP, which is double the amount of funding provided in fiscal year 2008  and will serve an additional 2 million households and increase the average amount available per household. LIHEAP is a critically important program that was created to help low-income families, elderly individuals  on a fixed income, and the unemployed pay their energy bills.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Even before recent and projected increases in energy prices, Michigan--like other States--started off with less funding in the current fiscal year than was required to meet the need. There have been significant efforts over the last couple of years to provide full funding for the LIHEAP program--consistent with that authorized by the Energy Policy Act of 2005--but these efforts have been thwarted by an administration unwilling to support this program at the necessary level. Therefore, I am particularly  pleased today that the administration finally has joined the Congress in supporting this vital lifeline for many Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This additional funding for LIHEAP is critically needed particularly as we head into the winter months. These funds need to be put quickly and directly into the hands of individuals who need them the most, which will both provide a vital safety net to these families and seniors and provide a benefit to the economy. Studies have shown that every LIHEAP dollar distributed generates up to 5 dollars of economic activity, thus helping to stimulate the economy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am also pleased that this legislation includes a significant increase in funding for the Department of Energy's weatherization assistance programs, providing close to $500 million for this program in fiscal year 2009. The Bush administration has consistently reduced funding for weatherization assistance in previous years and even proposed to eliminate it completely this year. But instead of decimating the program as proposed by the administration with, the increase provided in this bill, Congress  will more than double the assistance provided by the Federal Government and help to weatherize an additional 100,000 homes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress has changed eligibility rules under the Pell Grant Program in order to afford more students larger grants. As a result, the Pell Grant Program will require a funding boost from this year's funding to ensure each student's 2009-2010 Pell grant award level. The bill includes $2.5 billion above 2008 to prevent cuts in the Pell Grant award to students midway through the year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am particularly pleased that this appropriations bill includes funding to support up to $25 billion for loans to auto manufacturers and suppliers for retooling of facilities to produce advanced technology vehicles and their component parts. These loans were authorized as part of the 2007 Energy bill to assist companies in moving swiftly toward advanced technology. Since that time, the need for access to capital has become increasingly urgent due to the state of the economy and significantly  changed market conditions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the midst of all the economic dark clouds that are in the sky, this is a significant bright spot that will help domestic manufacturers in moving forward with the advanced technology that we all want to see. The U.S. automotive manufacturing industry is facing huge challenges. They face a sputtering global economy, the economic downturn here at home, the credit crisis here at home, and the challenge of meeting new fuel economy standards that Congress enacted last year. The future viability  of the auto industry depends on whether they are able to produce advanced technology vehicles that will reduce our consumption of oil and greenhouse gas emissions, be affordable for the average American, and ultimately save consumers money at the gas pump.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The funding that is part of this legislation will support loans that will be fully repaid with interest to the Federal Government and will not cost the taxpayers anything beyond the administrative costs. The benefit to the American people is that it will help to bring these advanced vehicle technologies more quickly into the marketplace and it will ensure that these vehicles and components continue to be manufactured in the United States by American workers for many years to come. In the near  term, the availability of these loans for auto manufacturers and suppliers in my home State of Michigan and other auto manufacturing States will help ensure that we maintain existing auto and supplier jobs and stem the decline in American manufacturing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Success in the area of advanced technology vehicles--such as hybrids, clean diesel, and plug-in hybrids--is critical to the future of Michigan-based auto manufacturers and suppliers and those in many other States. Most of these technologies were invented by our companies here in the United States, and we need to keep manufacturing them here and continue to lead the world in automotive innovation. These loans will help our companies stay competitive in the global marketplace. It is important to  note that the loan program is open to all automakers and suppliers to retool their facilities to produce these vehicles and components. Some may be more in need than others--but it is open to everyone with a qualified technology. I want also to emphasize that these loans are available to suppliers and component</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is a significant accomplishment to have funding for these loans included in this appropriations bill. The next step in this process is for the Department of Energy to establish regulations to implement this program, and it is essential that it happen quickly. We need these regulations completed expeditiously in order to get money out the door to the manufacturers that need it to move forward with advanced technology vehicles and components.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation significantly increases resources for border security, including $30 million for border interoperability demonstration projects. In 2007, I authored the legislation that established the International Border Community Interoperable Communications Demonstration Projects on the northern and southern borders. These projects will address the interoperable communications needs of police officers, firefighters, emergency medical technicians, National Guard, and other emergency response  providers at our borders.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also provides valuable funding for our first responders, rail and transit security FIRE Act grants, and SAFER grants.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Defense appropriations section of the bill supports the operational needs of our troops in Iraq and Afghanistan and the ongoing transformation of the military. Small and large businesses and universities across State play a critical role in ensuring that our Armed Forces are equipped to meet the challenges of the 21st century. Especially in the areas of vehicle technologies, robotics, energy and manufacturing research and development, Michigan continues to lead the way.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill includes approximately $354.1 million for Army research on combat vehicle and automotive technologies. This includes work on systems to protect Army vehicles against rocket-propelled grenades, improvised explosive devices and explosively formed projectiles; advanced materials for combat and tactical vehicle armor; more efficient engines; fuel cell and hybrid electric vehicles; unmanned ground vehicles; computer simulations for vehicle design and training of Army personnel; and technology  partnerships with the automotive industry. This research is performed and managed by the Army Tank and Automotive Research, Development and Engineering Command, TARDEC, and its National Automotive Center, NAC, both located in Warren, MI. TARDEC is the leading laboratory for research and development of advanced military vehicle technologies for the Department of Defense, DOD.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also includes funding for the programs of the Army's TACOM Life Cycle Management Command, LCMC, in Warren. TACOM LCMC is the Army's lead organization for the development and acquisition of ground vehicle combat, automotive and armaments technologies and systems. TACOM LCMC-managed systems include the Abrams main battle tank, Bradley Fighting Vehicle, Stryker Armored Vehicle, Mine Resistant Ambush Protected Vehicle, and all Army tactical vehicles, such as the HMMWV,  &lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page:  <bill type="s" number="9963">S9963</bill>]&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/center&gt;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are nine military construction projects included in the MILCONN/VA division of the bill for Michigan, including $68.5 million for the Detroit Arsenal in Warren.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These funds are crucial for the needed construction and renovations necessary to accommodate the more than 1,000 personnel who will be transferred to the Detroit Arsenal. This bill will also provide much needed improvements at Camp Grayling, the Army Reserve Center in Saginaw, and Selfridge Air National Guard Base.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300061" topic="DISCLOSURE OF EARMARKS AND CONGRESSIONALLY DIRECTED SPENDING ITEMS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I know none of my colleagues is happy that today the Senate was forced to pass a continuing resolution. Continuing resolutions are a sign that we failed to get our work done in a timely manner. As a result, many departments will be frozen at last year's funding levels and unable to begin new initiatives until next spring.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress was able to complete 3 of the 12 appropriations bills, however, and those bills are the vehicle for the continuing resolution before us. I am pleased that Congress was able to come together and move the legislation most critical to our national defense including the Defense, Military Construction, and Homeland Security appropriations bills.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, one of the bills that is left behind is the Agriculture appropriations bill, the bill I have responsibility for. However, there are parts of the CR that deal with the Agriculture Department, and I think it is important to spend a few moments going over the details within my jurisdiction as chairman of the Subcommittee on Agriculture Appropriations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My staff worked diligently with their House counterparts to find a responsible way to move forward under difficult circumstances. The continuing resolution includes an addition of $150 million for the Food and Drug Administration. The FDA has enormous responsibilities and I have consistently been pressing for more rigorous work on food safety. These additional funds will contribute to that effort.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The continuing resolution also includes resources to aid recovery from recent hurricanes and flooding in the Midwest. An additional $100 million is provided for the Emergency Watershed Program. The Emergency Conservation Program is slated for an increase of $115 million. Both of these programs provide basic, essential support for storm cleanup.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The continuing resolution also includes substantial resources--$188 million for Rural Development. $38 million of these funds are specifically set aside to continue recovery from hurricanes Katrina and Rita. The balance of $150 million is aimed at aiding recovery from natural disasters that occurred in 2008. They will augment efforts to maintain rural housing for low income and elderly Americans affected by these disasters. Without them, many needy Americans face very grim housing circumstances.  The funds will also help restore community facilities, rural utilities and small businesses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The CR also address some other priorities of mine. I am pleased that this continuing resolution includes an addition of $2.5 billion for the Pell Grant program, which is the largest grant program available to help low-income families afford the rising cost of a college degree. Pell grants are critical to ensure that all Americans can pursue a higher education, and during these tough economic times, such grants have become even more important to families. With college students seeking financial  aid in record numbers, the Department of Education recently announced that the Pell Grant program could face a shortfall of nearly $6 billion next year if more federal funds are not made available. The additional funds provided in this bill are a crucial first step toward ensuring the continued sustainability of the Pell Grant program, and I am glad to see that this Congress continues to make college affordability a top priority.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The continuing resolution also includes low-interest loans for U.S. automakers. These loans will provide needed financing to allow GM, Ford and Chrysler to retool their factories to produce fuel efficient cars and trucks. In June of this year, GM announced it was closing its Janesville, Wisconsin, plant because demand for the SUVs built there was down. With these low-interest loans on the way, I am hopeful that GM retools the Janesville plant. With a highly skilled workforce, the Janesville plant  stands ready to meet consumer demands for fuel efficient vehicles that will keep good paying jobs in Wisconsin and reduce our dependence on foreign oil.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Passing a continuing resolution instead of finishing our work is never something to be proud of, but this CR makes the best of a bad situation. I look forward to finishing the appropriations bills next year and putting our government on a more sustainable funding path.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="DISCLOSURE OF EARMARKS AND CONGRESSIONALLY DIRECTED SPENDING ITEMS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today to discuss a matter of critical importance to the security of our borders and our Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is estimated that at least 15 million people enter the United States through the visa waiver program each year. Thousands of these people overstay their authorized visit, and many just simply disappear into the shadows.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This country cannot afford to continue this trend. The Department of Homeland Security and its partners must have the tools they need to protect Americans by tracking the millions who enter our country, including some who may wish on us grievous harm and injury.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A biometric system is one of the best tools we have to protect us from the use of fraudulent and stolen passports and other international documents. We need to make sure people are who they claim to be.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Between January 2002 and June 2004, 28 foreign governments, including visa waiver countries, reported 56,943 stolen blank foreign passports to the State Department. And just this summer, a security van in London was hijacked, resulting in the loss of 3,000 blank British passports and visas that were destined for overseas embassies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Clearly, DHS cannot continue to add new countries into the visa waiver program without properly mitigating the security risks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is why Congress passed a provision in the 9/11 Commission Recommendations Act just last year requiring the Department of Homeland Security to implement a biometric air exit system. This biometric system is required to be in place by June 30, 2009.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The intent of Congress was and remains clear: There must be in place a fully operational biometric air exit system, or else the Secretary of Homeland Security cannot admit new countries into the visa waiver program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Therefore, if such a biometric system is not implemented by June 30, 2009, the Secretary's authority to admit new countries with visa refusal rates above 3 percent shall be suspended until a biometric exit system is fully operational.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is critical to ensuring the ability to track the arrivals and departures of foreign nationals--not just through a paper trail, but through fingerprints, photographs, and other fraud-proof biometric identifiers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill that we are considering today cuts off funding for the biometric air exit system until reports are received by Congress on pilot tests of the air exit solution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We simply cannot afford to delay the execution of the biometric exit system. Congress should not be restricting DHS's ability to protect our borders and our people.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, if the biometric system is delayed and the Department of Homeland Security is unable to meet the statutory deadline of June 30, 2009, the visa waiver program should not be expanded.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is the intent of the authorizing language and that is what's best to protect the security of our Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The biometric air exit system was mandated as a result of the horrific events of 9/11. We are a different country today and we must learn the lessons of September 11 and implement the recommendations of the 9/11 Commission. We cannot afford to go backwards as a country and Congress must do all that it can to protect our Nation and prevent another tragedy like 9/11.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400272" topic="DISCLOSURE OF EARMARKS AND CONGRESSIONALLY DIRECTED SPENDING ITEMS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today to express my support for the 2009 Consolidated Security, Disaster Assistance, and Continuing Appropriations Act, a bill better known as the continuing resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Keeping the government running, particularly as so many Americans are  struggling in these tough economic times, is vital. Besides ensuring that basic services continue to be provided, we are also providing some additional measures of assistance that will benefit millions of middle class and working Americans. Now more than ever, we can't simply tell Americans who are having a rough go of it, "Tough luck, you're on your own." It is important to responsibly  offer a helping hand where we can and help spur the economy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As families face increasing energy bills that have stretched their budgets thin, and as we head toward cold winter days and nights, we are providing some relief. This resolution contains substantial low-income energy assistance and weatherization assistance--programs that are essential for seniors and low income families this upcoming winter.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The CR will also provide much-needed resources for families struggling to keep up with increasing grocery bills and rising college tuition fees. It will provide urgently needed disaster assistance to those hit by recent hurricanes, substantial funding or veteran's health care, and an important investment in Pell grants and emergency food assistance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As the author of the COAST Act, I am adamantly opposed to expanded coastline drilling along eastern and western seaboards of the United States, especially the Jersey shore. I want to continue the moratorium that has protected our Outer Continental Shelf for over two decades. Expanded OCS drilling is bad energy policy, bad environmental policy, and it will do nothing to lower the prices at the pump, now or ever.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This country deserves a serious debate about energy and not just election year posturing. Though this resolution does not extend the moratorium on coastline drilling, it allows us to revisit this issue in March, when we can have a serious policy discussion. In the meantime, drilling would not commence between now and then--or for years into the future--anyway. With a new Congress and a new administration I will continue to stand up for the development of a real, comprehensive energy policy that  achieves our goals without endangering the Jersey shore.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With this action today, we have avoided a shutdown of the Federal Government, provided much-needed relief to middle-class and working Americans struggling in this economy and allowed Congress to focus on finding a bipartisan solution to the urgent financial crisis.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="DISCLOSURE OF EARMARKS AND CONGRESSIONALLY DIRECTED SPENDING ITEMS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, it is encouraging that Congress today passed the Wartime Enforcement of Fraud Act of 2008 as part of the Consolidated Security, Disaster Assistance and Continuing Appropriations Act. This is a modest but important commonsense measure that will help restore accountability and deter fraud in the many billions of dollars worth of contracts in connection with the two wars we continue to fight.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The failed legacy of the Bush administration is clearer today than ever before, as our Nation faces unprecedented crises at home and abroad. The financial markets are in turmoil as a result of mismanagement of the economy and neglect of the regulatory process that helps maintain confidence in the market. Americans are losing their homes to foreclosure at record rates. Our country remains mired in Iraq, fighting a war that President Bush should never has started, that continues to cost too many  lives and billions of dollars each month, with no end in sight.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As part of this legacy, the Bush administration has further failed to meet one of its most important obligations during wartime--to protect American taxpayers from losses due to fraud and corruption in war contracting. Fraud and corruption in contracting are all too common in times of war, and these problems have been particularly pervasive in Iraq.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>New reports just this week have confirmed that corruption and fraud have robbed billions from the American taxpayers during the Iraq war. The former chief investigator of the Iraqi Commission on Public Integrity, Salam Adhoob, testified before Congress this week that $9 billion in U.S. taxpayer funds have been lost to corruption and fraud in Iraq.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Adhoob described how senior Iraqi defense officials set up fraudulent front companies that were supposed to buy airplanes, armored vehicles, and guns with $1.7 billion in U.S. funds. But these companies failed to deliver most of the military equipment, and what they did provide was mostly junk, including defective ammunition and unsafe bulletproof vests. These companies also overcharged for military helicopters and aircraft, delivering useless decades-old equipment. Most of the money ended  up in German bank accounts controlled by these Iraqi defense officials.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Iraqi chief investigator prepared a full report based on this investigation, and thousands of others, and submitted the documentation to the Iraqi government, as well as to U.S. investigators. Yet so far, neither the Bush administration nor the Iraqi government has taken action in these cases. Instead, the Iraqi government has passed laws giving immunity to many of its corrupt officials, and the U.S. investigators have too often stalled trying to find witnesses and review documents in the  midst of a war zone.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These examples of fraud and corruption are not isolated, or new. Over the past 2 years, I have chaired hearings in the Appropriations and Judiciary Committees focused on the billions of dollars that have been lost to contracting fraud, waste, and abuse during this war. The testimony at those hearings has also exposed the Bush administration's failure to take aggressive action to enforce and punish wartime fraud. These hearings have shown how difficult it can be for investigators to uncover and  prosecute fraud amidst the chaotic environment of war.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These persistent problems have been made worse by the Bush administration's use of "no-bid" and "cost-plus" contracts that have been awarded with little, if any, oversight or accountability. Billions in cash--physical, paper money--have been flown to Iraq and handed out in paper bags, often without records of who received what, and when. Billion-dollar contracts for training services cannot be audited because the records are incomplete, lost, or in disarray. As a result, time and time again,  the government has paid for services that were never needed or never provided and for equipment that was too often substandard or actually defective.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But as we found again this week, too often we do not learn about wartime fraud and corruption until years after the fact. What we do know is that billions of dollars are unaccounted for, and likely lost to war profiteers and corrupt officials. Fraud investigators from the offices of several inspectors general, as well as the Special Inspector General for Iraq Reconstruction and the Federal Bureau of Investigation, are working to figure out where the money has gone and who has taken it. But they  have told us it will take a long time, in some cases years, to figure out exactly what has happened with the billions of dollars in fraud related to war contracts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the meantime, the statute of limitations that bars Federal fraud prosecutions after 5 years threatens to make this work meaningless and essentially immunize those who are responsible. The wars in Iraq and Afghanistan have gone on for far more than five years, and with each passing day, we are losing the authority to prosecute fraud committed early on in the wars. As time passes, we are effectively granting immunity to these criminals and letting them get away with taxpayers' money.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I introduced the Wartime Enforcement of Fraud Act of 2008 to correct this problem once and for all. Passage of this legislation today is an important step forward to make sure all those who have committed fraud will be held to account. Put simply, this bill will give the government more time to continue investigating these massive wartime frauds and, in time, this provision should save American taxpayers untold millions and help punish those responsible for the fraud.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our country has faced this same problem in past wars and taken similar action. During World War II, President Franklin Delano Roosevelt spoke out against "war millionaires" who made excessive profits exploiting the calamity of war. President Harry Truman, when he served in the Senate, held historic public hearings to expose gross fraud and waste by military contractors during the war.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1942, President Roosevelt signed the Wartime Suspension of Limitations  Act, which made it possible for criminal fraud offenses against the United States to be prosecuted after the war was over. President Truman made that law permanent in 1948.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Everyone understood then that it was unrealistic to believe that all wartime fraud could be tracked down immediately in the midst of a war. The law provided an extension of the statute of limitations until the war was over. Congress supported this law overwhelmingly, as they had with a similar provision during World War I. President Roosevelt wrote:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The crisis of war should not be used as a means of avoiding just penalties for wrongdoing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, this Roosevelt-era law does not appear to apply to the ongoing conflicts in Iraq and Afghanistan. Current law only applies "when the United States is at war," but the military operations in Iraq and Afghanistan were undertaken without formal declarations of war. As a result, this law technically does not apply to these ongoing conflicts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill simply amends current law to make clear that extending the statute of limitations during wartime applies to the wars in Iraq and Afghanistan. In doing so, we will give investigators and auditors the time necessary to continue their efforts to uncover the wartime frauds and prosecute those who are responsible. Without this bill, fraudulent conduct by war contractors and corrupt officials will go unpunished, and the government will have no ability to recover taxpayer money lost to these  criminals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The statute of limitations is an important check on the proper use of government power, and we should suspend it only in extraordinary circumstances. Wars provide exactly such circumstances, as Congress and Presidents have recognized in the past. It would be wrong to exempt the wars in Iraq and Afghanistan from this common sense law, and passage of this bill will close that loophole for the Iraq and Afghanistan wars, as well as any future wars.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With passage of this bill today, Congress has taken action, as it has in the past, to protect the American taxpayer and make sure the money spent to support the troops is not wasted through fraud and corruption. The President should now sign this bill to show the American people that we will do all we can to investigate and prosecute those who would undermine our troops and steal from the taxpayer during times of war.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is all time yielded back?</chair>
  <chair>If all time is yielded back, the question is now on agreeing to the motion to concur.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300063" topic="DISCLOSURE OF EARMARKS AND CONGRESSIONALLY DIRECTED SPENDING ITEMS">
    <paragraph>I ask for the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there a sufficient second?</chair>
  <chair>There appears to be a sufficient second.</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will call the roll.</narrative>
  <narrative>The assistant legislative clerk called the roll.</narrative>
  <narrative>Mr. BURR (When his name was called). On this vote, Senator Clinton is absent. If she were present and voting, she would have voted "yea." If I were at liberty to vote, I would vote "nay." Therefore, I withhold my vote.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="DISCLOSURE OF EARMARKS AND CONGRESSIONALLY DIRECTED SPENDING ITEMS">
    <paragraph>I announce that the Senator from Delaware (Mr. Biden), the Senator from California (Mrs. Boxer), the Senator from California (Mrs. Feinstein), the Senator from Massachusetts (Mr. Kennedy), the Senator from Missouri (Mrs. McCaskill), the Senator from Washington (Mrs. Murray), and the Senator from Illinois (Mr. Obama) are necessarily absent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I further announce that, if present and voting, the Senator from California (Mrs. Feinstein) would vote "aye."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300062" topic="DISCLOSURE OF EARMARKS AND CONGRESSIONALLY DIRECTED SPENDING ITEMS">
    <paragraph>The following Senator is necessarily absent. The Senator from Arizona (Mr. McCain).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Are there any other Senators in the Chamber desiring to vote?</chair>
  <narrative>The result was announced--yeas 78, nays 12, as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>[Rollcall Vote No. 208 Leg.]</narrative>
  <narrative>Akaka</narrative>
  <narrative>Barrasso</narrative>
  <narrative>Baucus</narrative>
  <narrative>Bayh</narrative>
  <narrative>Bennett</narrative>
  <narrative>Bingaman</narrative>
  <narrative>Bond</narrative>
  <narrative>Brown</narrative>
  <narrative>Brownback</narrative>
  <narrative>Byrd</narrative>
  <narrative>Cantwell</narrative>
  <narrative>Cardin</narrative>
  <narrative>Carper</narrative>
  <narrative>Casey</narrative>
  <narrative>Chambliss</narrative>
  <narrative>Cochran</narrative>
  <narrative>Coleman</narrative>
  <narrative>Collins</narrative>
  <narrative>Conrad</narrative>
  <narrative>Corker</narrative>
  <narrative>Cornyn</narrative>
  <narrative>Craig</narrative>
  <narrative>Dodd</narrative>
  <narrative>Dole</narrative>
  <narrative>Domenici</narrative>
  <narrative>Dorgan</narrative>
  <narrative>Durbin</narrative>
  <narrative>Enzi</narrative>
  <narrative>Grassley</narrative>
  <narrative>Gregg</narrative>
  <narrative>Hagel</narrative>
  <narrative>Harkin</narrative>
  <narrative>Hatch</narrative>
  <narrative>Hutchison</narrative>
  <narrative>Inhofe</narrative>
  <narrative>Inouye</narrative>
  <narrative>Isakson</narrative>
  <narrative>Johnson</narrative>
  <narrative>Kerry</narrative>
  <narrative>Klobuchar</narrative>
  <narrative>Kohl</narrative>
  <narrative>Landrieu</narrative>
  <narrative>Lautenberg</narrative>
  <narrative>Leahy</narrative>
  <narrative>Levin</narrative>
  <narrative>Lieberman</narrative>
  <narrative>Lincoln</narrative>
  <narrative>Lugar</narrative>
  <narrative>Martinez</narrative>
  <narrative>McConnell</narrative>
  <narrative>Menendez</narrative>
  <narrative>Mikulski</narrative>
  <narrative>Murkowski</narrative>
  <narrative>Nelson (FL)</narrative>
  <narrative>Nelson (NE)</narrative>
  <narrative>Pryor</narrative>
  <narrative>Reed</narrative>
  <narrative>Reid</narrative>
  <narrative>Roberts</narrative>
  <narrative>Rockefeller</narrative>
  <narrative>Salazar</narrative>
  <narrative>Sanders</narrative>
  <narrative>Schumer</narrative>
  <narrative>Smith</narrative>
  <narrative>Snowe</narrative>
  <narrative>Specter</narrative>
  <narrative>Stabenow</narrative>
  <narrative>Stevens</narrative>
  <narrative>Sununu</narrative>
  <narrative>Tester</narrative>
  <narrative>Thune</narrative>
  <narrative>Vitter</narrative>
  <narrative>Voinovich</narrative>
  <narrative>Warner</narrative>
  <narrative>Webb</narrative>
  <narrative>Whitehouse</narrative>
  <narrative>Wicker</narrative>
  <narrative>Wyden</narrative>
  <narrative>Alexander</narrative>
  <narrative>Allard</narrative>
  <narrative>Bunning</narrative>
  <narrative>Coburn</narrative>
  <narrative>Crapo</narrative>
  <narrative>DeMint</narrative>
  <narrative>Ensign</narrative>
  <narrative>Feingold</narrative>
  <narrative>Graham</narrative>
  <narrative>Kyl</narrative>
  <narrative>Sessions</narrative>
  <narrative>Shelby</narrative>
  <narrative/>
  <narrative>Burr, against</narrative>
  <narrative/>
  <narrative/>
  <narrative/>
  <narrative>Biden</narrative>
  <narrative>Boxer</narrative>
  <narrative>Clinton</narrative>
  <narrative>Feinstein</narrative>
  <narrative>Kennedy</narrative>
  <narrative>McCain</narrative>
  <narrative>McCaskill</narrative>
  <narrative>Murray</narrative>
  <narrative>Obama</narrative>
  <narrative/>
  <narrative>The motion was agreed to.</narrative>
  <chair> The majority leader.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="NOT VOTING--9">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, this is a great accomplishment for this Congress. Of course, we have battled our way through a lot of things, but this is an excellent piece of legislation. We funded the troops in more ways than one. Not only have we done the Defense appropriations bill, but we have done VA-HUD and Homeland Security. I wish we could have done all the appropriations bills, but we haven't done that. But we have funded the Government until March 6. I appreciate the cooperation of the distinguished  Republican leader and all Senators because it took all Senators to get to the point where we are. I appreciate it very much.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are going to have no more votes today. We will let everyone know as soon as we can as to what we are going to do on Monday. We are going to be in session on Monday. The question is, What are we going to do on Monday? We may have to have a vote on the Defense authorization bill. We may have to have a vote on the Amtrak bill. I failed to mention one thing to the Republican leader. I told him we had two things that were absolutely necessary. I forgot to mention one of them. We have to do, of  course, the Defense authorization bill. We have to do Amtrak. We have to do the nuclear treaty with India. I have indicated to them we have a lands bill we are taking a look at, a package of bills. Each one of these is something we could complete next week.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For people who are concerned about the Indian nuclear agreement--and there are several Senators who have concerns--all we would be doing is running out the statutory time. At the end of that time, Senators have 10 hours of debate time. Then we vote. So there are very few hurdles we have to jump through on that other than running out the 30 days. We can do that the easy way or the hard way. Time started running on September 8. Those are legislative days we are in session.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Those are the things we have to do before we leave. Of course, I haven't mentioned the big one, which is the financial rescue plan. As I said this morning, staff worked until early this morning. I had a briefing an hour ago from my staff. Progress is still being made. They only have a handful of issues, literally, maybe a handful and a half, left that the Members of Congress who are part of this negotiation will finalize, and they will bring them to the respective floor leaders. Hopefully, we  can bring it to the floor at a very early time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As I indicated this morning, one of the things we want to do is have an outline of an agreement by 6 o'clock on Sunday because that would give recognition to the Asian markets opening. That is an important message. We have to make sure the markets aren't volatile.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We tend to look at the Dow Jones, but as we have learned--as I have learned--there are a lot of other financial indicators that are extremely important, and this week they have been in big trouble. As we have said, and will say, this is more than just a concern to Wall Street. A lot of these things would have a dramatic, fast impact on Main Street. That is what the negotiators are working on.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So no more votes today. We will let everyone know as soon as we can what votes there will be on Monday. If we have a vote on Monday, it is a very narrow window because of the holiday that starts at sundown on Monday night. That vote would be between 11:30 and 12:30.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Republican leader is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300072" topic="NOT VOTING--9">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I did not hear all of my good friend's, the majority leader's, remarks, but I did hear the end of them, and I do want to underscore that he is entirely correct, that this crisis we face in the financial markets is about Main Street.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A good example of that is a community of mine that wanted to issue municipal revenue bonds the other day. These were highly rated bonds. There was no buyer. This is going on all across the country. It underscores the need to act responsibly and quickly, which we anticipate doing on Monday.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
