<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1203008401" ordinal="13" title="COMMENDING SENATOR DANIEL K. INOUYE">
  <narrative>COMMENDING SENATOR DANIEL K. INOUYE -- (Senate - February 14, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="1049">S1049</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, with great pleasure I extend my most heartfelt congratulations to our esteemed colleague, the senior Senator from Hawaii, Daniel K. Inouye, for casting his 15,000 vote in the Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many times on this floor I have referred to Senator Inouye as my "No. 1 hero," and he is. Few have ever served our country more bravely and with more loyalty and determination than has Senator Inouye.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Daniel Inouye was a member of the famed 442nd Infantry Regimental Combat Team of World War II, the most decorated Army unit in U.S. history. During one bloody battle, Platoon Leader Inouye led an assault on a heavily defended Nazi position. Although gravely wounded, he still managed to destroy three Nazi machine gun nests. Anyone who is not familiar with the details of this amazing display of heroism should make it a point to become so.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For his incredible heroism, Dan Inouye was awarded the Distinguished Service Cross, the Bronze Star, the Purple Heart, and the Congressional Medal of Honor, making him one of only seven Senators to have achieved our Nation's highest military honor. Senator Inouye is the Senate's only Congressional Medal of Honor recipient from World War II.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1963, he became the first Japanese American to serve in the U.S. Senate, where he continues to represent his State and our country with great distinction and dedication. This man of incredible integrity has worked tirelessly in the Senate on behalf of his constituents and our country. Senator Inouye served on the Select Committee on Presidential Campaign Activities--Watergate Committee--the Select Committee on Secret Military Assistance to Iran, and the Nicaraguan Opposition, Iran-Contra.  He is the next in line on the Democratic side to chair the Senate Appropriations Committee and is currently the chairman of the Appropriations Subcommittee on Defense. He also served as Secretary of the Democratic Conference from 1977 to 1989. I have always respected Danny's deep loyalty to the Senate. I will always appreciate his loyalty to me when I was the Senate Democratic leader and I relied on his sage advice.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator Inouye is now the fourth longest serving U.S. Senator in history.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With today's vote, he is now the fourth U.S. Senator in history to have cast 15,000 votes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I again congratulate my good friend, my outstanding colleague, and my "No. 1 hero" for another important milestone in his outstanding life:</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
