<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1177084810" ordinal="38" title="NATIONAL SHAKEN BABY SYNDROME AWARENESS WEEK">
  <speaking speaker="300078" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of <bill type="sr" number="163">S. Res. 163</bill>, submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300034" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, along with Senators ALEXANDER, BAYH, BENNETT, BOXER, CANTWELL, CLINTON, COLEMAN, DOMENICI, DURBIN, HATCH, LEVIN, LIEBERMAN, SALAZAR, and SCHUMER, I am in support of our resolution to proclaim the third week of April of 2007 as "National Shaken Baby Syndrome Awareness Week." The Senate has passed similar resolutions each year since 2001, and we strongly support continued awareness of one of the most devastating forms of child abuse in this country, abuse  that results in the severe injury, lifelong disability, or death of hundreds of children each year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In recognition of the need to eliminate child abuse and to raise awareness about the issue, the month of April has again been designated "National Child Abuse Prevention Month," an annual tradition that was initiated in 1979 by former President Jimmy Carter. As we focus on child abuse prevention this month, awareness and prevention of Shaken Baby Syndrome is an important component of these efforts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to recognize the many groups, including those formed by parents and relatives who have been killed or injured by shaking, who support this effort to increase awareness of one of the most devastating forms of child abuse. These supporters include the American Academy of Pediatrics, the American Association of Neurological Surgeons, the American Psychological Association, The Arc of the United States, the Association of Maternal and Child Health Programs, the Association of University  Centers on Disabilities, the Brain Injury Association of America, the Center for Child Protection and Family Support, the Child Welfare League of America, Children's Healthcare is a Legal Duty, the Congress of Neurological Surgeons, the Cynthia Gibbs Foundation, Don't Shake Jake, Easter Seals, Epilepsy Foundation of America, Family Voices, the Hannah Rose Foundation, the Kierra Harrison Foundation, the National Association of Children's Hospitals, the National Association of Child Care Resource &amp; Referral Agencies,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge the Senate to adopt this resolution designating the third week of April 2007 as "National Shaken Baby Syndrome Awareness Week," and to take part in the many local and national activities and events recognizing the month of April as National Child Abuse Prevention Month.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300078" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table, and that any statements relating thereto be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
