<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1192723202" ordinal="54" title="SUPPORTING &quot;LIGHTS ON AFTERSCHOOL&quot;">
  <narrative>SUPPORTING "LIGHTS ON AFTERSCHOOL" -- (Senate - October 18, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="13132">S13132</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate now proceed to the immediate consideration of <bill type="sc" number="51">S. Con. Res. 51</bill>, submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the concurrent resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A concurrent resolution (<bill type="sc" number="51">S. Con. Res. 51</bill>) supporting "Lights on Afterschool!", a national celebration of after school programs.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the concurrent resolution.</narrative>
  <narrative>(At the request of Mr. Reid, the following statement was ordered to be printed in the Record)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300034" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today Senator Ensign and I, along with 29 cosponsors, are submitting a concurrent resolution with the House of Representatives designating October 18, 2007 as Lights On Afterschool Day. Lights on Afterschool brings students, parents, educators, lawmakers, and community and business leaders together to celebrate afterschool programs. This year, more than 1 million Americans are expected to attend about 7,500 events designed to raise awareness and support for  these much needed programs. In addition, Lights On Afterschool 2007 marks the 10th anniversary of 21st Century Community Learning Centers, the primary Federal initiative supporting afterschool programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Approximately 90 percent of parents say that having a safe, positive place where their child can go after school will improve their child's well-being. However, 14 million school-age children--or 25 percent of all school-age children--are left unsupervised after school and miss the opportunity to attend a safe, positive place that supports their growth and well-being.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Quality afterschool programs benefit youth, families, and communities. Students enrolled in afterschool programs are more likely to be engaged and go farther in education. They are also more likely to avoid risky behavior and criminal activity. Afterschool programs help parents successfully balance their work and home-life. In addition, these programs promote adult involvement with youth, which helps to create more cohesive communities invested in the future of our children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In our work on the Senate Afterschool Caucus, Senator Ensign and I have been working for more than three years to impress upon our colleagues the importance of afterschool and are proud to say that 35 of our colleagues have joined the Caucus. We hope that they, along with other Members of the Congress, will join us on October 18 to celebrate the importance of afterschool programs in their communities back home.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the concurrent resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table en bloc, and that any statements relating thereto be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The concurrent resolution (<bill type="sc" number="51">S. Con. Res. 51</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The concurrent resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sc" number="51">S. Con. Res. 51</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas high quality after school programs provide safe, challenging, engaging, and fun learning experiences to help children and youth develop their social, emotional, physical, cultural, and academic skills;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas high quality after school programs support working families by ensuring that the children in such families are safe and productive after the regular school day ends;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas high quality after school programs build stronger communities by involving the Nation's students, parents, business leaders, and adult volunteers in the lives of the Nation's youth, thereby promoting positive relationships among children, youth, families, and adults;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas high quality after school programs engage families, schools, and diverse community partners in advancing the well-being of the Nation's children;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas "Lights On Afterschool!", a national celebration of after school programs held on October 18, 2007, promotes the critical importance of high quality after school programs in the lives of children, their families, and their communities;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas more than 28,000,000 children in the United States have parents who work outside the home and 14,300,000 children in the United States have no place to go after school; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas many after school programs across the United States are struggling to keep their doors open and their lights on: Now, therefore, be it</chair>
  <chair> Resolved by the Senate (the House of Representatives concurring), That Congress supports the goals and ideals of "Lights On Afterschool!" a national celebration of after school programs.&lt;ul&gt;</chair>
</record>
