<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1207238402" ordinal="27" title="35TH ANNIVERSARY OF THE CENTER FOR DISABILITIES">
  <narrative>35TH ANNIVERSARY OF THE CENTER FOR DISABILITIES -- (Senate - April 03, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="2433">S2433</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300058" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today I congratulate the University of South Dakota School of Medicine and Health Sciences Center for Disabilities in Vermillion, SD, which will celebrate its 35th anniversary in 2008.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Started in September of 1973 as the Developmental Disabilities Evaluation Center, the Center for Disabilities has a long and distinguished history of providing training, service, information, and research not only to South Dakota but to the entire region. My wife Barbara worked on the DDEC staff during those initial years. Thirty-five years later, the school continues to serve those needs of South Dakota through current projects, such as the Autism and Related Disorders Program, Birth to 3 Connections,  Cheyenne River Reservation Rural Health Outreach Project, Deaf-Blind Program, Dietetic Internship, the Upper Midwest Public Health Training Center, and the Pine Ridge Developmental Clinic, which was established in 2008. The Center for Disabilities is also working with other States to provide service in projects such as the Four-State Consortium on Studies in the Prevention of Fetal Alcohol Syndrome/Fetal Alcohol Effect and the Upper Midwest Public Health Training Center.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over the last 35 years, the University of South Dakota School of Medicine and Health Sciences Center for Disabilities has provided quality services to the people of South Dakota. Their goal, to help those with disabilities live without limitations, has been demonstrated through the citizens with whom they have worked. Those ideals have also been carried out by the students who have graduated and gone on to excel in their careers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Not only has this center encouraged learning and research, but the University of South Dakota School of Medicine and Health Sciences Center for Disabilities also strives to bring together communities. Indeed, one of the core functions of the center is community education. The center works to provide training and assistance, not only to individuals with disabilities and their families, but also to professionals, paraprofessionals, policymakers, students, and any member of the community who chooses  to get involved.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am proud to honor the University of South Dakota School of Medicine and Health Sciences Center for Disabilities for its 35 years of outstanding service. It is an honor for me to share with my colleagues the exemplary leadership and strong commitment to education and research the University of South Dakota School of Medicine and Health Sciences Center for Disabilities has provided. I strongly commend their years of hard work and dedication, and I am very pleased that their substantial efforts  are being publicly honored and celebrated.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
