<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1193760002" ordinal="59" title="ANDREW LAROCHELLE GOD, FAMILY AND COUNTRY ACT OF 2007">
  <narrative>ANDREW LAROCHELLE GOD, FAMILY AND COUNTRY ACT OF 2007 -- (Senate - October 30, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="13587">S13587</bill>]</narrative>
  <chair> Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of Calendar No. 430, <bill type="s" number="2198">S. 2198</bill>.</chair>
  <chair> The clerk will report the bill by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A bill (<bill type="s" number="2198">S. 2198</bill>) to require the Architect of the Capitol to permit acknowledgment of God on flag certificates.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the bill.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent the bill be read a third time and passed, the motion to reconsider be laid on the table, and any statements be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The bill (<bill type="s" number="2198">S. 2198</bill>) was ordered to be engrossed for a third reading, was read the third time and passed, as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="s" number="2198">S. 2198</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "The Andrew Larochelle God, Family, and Country Act of 2007".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. FLAG CERTIFICATES ISSUED BY THE ARCHITECT OF THE CAPITOL.</chair>
  <chair> The Architect of the Capitol shall permit the acknowledgment of God on flag certificates that are issued at the request of a Member of the United States House of Representatives or of the United States Senate.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
