<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1185422400" ordinal="19" title="SMALL BUSINESS TAX RELIEF ACT OF 2007--MOTION TO PROCEED">
  <narrative>SMALL BUSINESS TAX RELIEF ACT OF 2007--MOTION TO PROCEED -- (Senate - July 26, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="10117">S10117</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that on Monday, July 30, following a period of morning business, the Senate proceed to calendar No. 58, <bill type="h" number="976">H.R. 976</bill>, and that once the bill is reported, Senator Baucus be recognized to offer an amendment, which would be the text of the children's health legislation, also known as SCHIP, reported by the Senate Finance Committee.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400576" topic="">
    <paragraph>I object.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>In view of the objection, I now move to proceed to calendar No. 58, <bill type="h" number="976">H.R. 976</bill>, and I send a cloture motion to the desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The cloture motion having been presented under rule XXII, the Chair directs the clerk to read the motion.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>Cloture Motion</narrative>
  <narrative>We, the undersigned Senators, in accordance with the provisions of rule XXII of the Standing rules of the Senate, hereby move to bring to a close debate on the motion to proceed to Calendar No. 58, <bill type="h" number="976">H.R. 976</bill>, the Small Business Tax Relief Act of 2007.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the mandatory quorum be waived.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, finally, I hope that Monday, after the Republicans have a chance to study this legislation, we can move without a vote to this most important legislation. I had indications from the other side that that may be the case. If that is not the case, we will try to invoke cloture on this matter.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I appreciate everybody's hard work today. I now withdraw the motion.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The motion is withdrawn.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>I thank the Chair.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Connecticut is recognized.</chair>
</record>
