<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1190044802" ordinal="12" title="220TH ANNIVERSARY OF THE UNITED STATES CONSTITUTION">
  <narrative>220TH ANNIVERSARY OF THE UNITED STATES CONSTITUTION -- (Senate - September 17, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="11538">S11538</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today, September 17, in this year of Our Lord, 2007, marks the 220th anniversary of the signing of the Constitution of the United States. Praise God.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Across the Nation, many students, teachers, and historians are spending at least part of their time today reviewing, learning about, and, most of all, appreciating the U.S. Constitution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although not as flashy looking as the American flag on Flag Day, or as bedecked in sparklers and fireworks as the celebration of the Declaration of Independence on the Fourth of July, the workhorse that is our Constitution truly merits a day of appreciation by all citizens.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Constitution is a living, breathing document, still as full of passion, patriotism, jealousy, and intrigue after 220 years as the star of any long-running soap opera. Perhaps it is because the Constitution, similar to soap operas, deals with the relations between human beings in society.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Constitution, in its articles and amendments, lays out the roles for its actors: the executive, the legislature, the judiciary, the States, and the rights of individuals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The script is pretty basic: Run a country and ensure the welfare of its citizens. But being human, people never seem content with playing out their own roles as written. James Madison aptly observed that:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>[T]he essence of Government is power; and power, lodged as it must be in human hands, will ever be liable to abuse.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>History is replete with examples of governmental actors who have improvised, seeking to expand their own role and put their name in bigger lights at the expense of the other players.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Fortunately, history is also full of examples in which the grasping star's excesses are checked by the concerted actions of the rest of the cast. It is a fascinating read, and well worth one's time. Federal versus States rights, the freedoms of individuals versus the need for order in society, protection from tyranny pitted against a strong executive, declarations of war and peaceful diplomacy--these are some of the great themes, the high dramas written into the Constitution and played out over  the course of our Nation's history. Our Founding Fathers truly knew what they were doing when they crafted a document that hoped for the best, most noble instincts in men but guarded against the worst.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As James Madison famously observed, "If men were angels, no government would be necessary." At the same time, however, he also noted that "All men having power ought to be mistrusted," so the foundation of all the checks and balances in the Constitution is the premise that "ambition must be made to counteract ambition." As a result, the Constitution has found itself in a constantly shifting political landscape created by the ebb and flow of Executive power, legislative control, judicial  counterbalancing, Federal expansion, and individualism. These great themes are all played out in many smaller scenes each year, from each nomination through each budget submission, authorization, and appropriations bill, and each Supreme Court case.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have always found this historical drama more stimulating and absorbing than any television reality show. Perhaps it is because the constitutional drama has played such a large role in my own long life. In the 220-year history of this Nation's Constitution, there have been only 1,896 individuals fortunate enough to serve as Senators. I am number 1,579 out of 1,896. I have served in the Senate for one-quarter of the Senate's history--not quite an original cast member but pretty close. Amen. You  better believe it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But whether each citizen has an active role in our Constitution drama or is merely a spectator, the Constitution  plays a large role in the life of every citizen. I encourage everyone, every citizen to read the Constitution--read the Constitution--read the Constitution and to read the Federalist Papers as well as other writings by our Founding Fathers. Read deeply in history; with all thy volumes vast hath but one page. Read deeply in history and biography,  and read the newspapers and follow what is happening in Washington.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Do not believe everything you see, do not believe everything you hear, but view it through the prism of the Constitution--the Constitution--the Constitution. Be your own Supreme Court and decide if the arguments put forth by the White House, the Congress, the press, and the pundits are in accordance with the Constitution and with the intent of the immortal Framers. Then and only then will you become the most valuable of all things: a true defender of liberty, an informed citizen.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I close with a poem--a great poem--by Henry Wadsworth Longfellow entitled "O Ship of State." Our Constitution is our ship, the heart and soul of our Nation, and the stalwart vessel that will carry our Nation's liberty into the future. Long, long, long may it live.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I note the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <chair>The assistant legislative clerk proceeded to call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300072" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
