<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1209052802" ordinal="67" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <narrative>AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET -- (Senate - April 24, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="3410">S3410</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="COMMITTEE ON ARMED SERVICES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, April 24, 2008, at 9:30 a.m., in closed session to receive a briefing on a sensitive intelligence matter.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="COMMITTEE ON BANKING, HOUSING, AND URBAN AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on April 24, 2008, at 10 a.m., to conduct a committee hearing entitled "Turmoil in U.S. Credit Markets: Examining the U.S. Regulatory Framework Assessing Sovereign Investments."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold an Executive Session during the session of the Senate on Thursday, April 24, 2008, at 10:30 a.m., in Room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold an Executive Session during the session of the Senate on Thursday, April 24, 2008, at 2:30 p.m., in Room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="COMMITTEE ON FINANCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Finance be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, April 24, 2008, at 10 a.m., in Room 215 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building, to hear testimony on "Tax Aspects of a Cap-and-Trade System."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, April 24, 2008, at 9:30 a.m. to hold a hearing on implementing smart power: setting an agenda for national security reform.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, April 24, 2008, at 2 p.m. to hold a hearing on international debt relief.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, April 24, 2008, at 4:45 p.m. to hold a briefing on a classified matter.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="COMMITTEE ON HEALTH, EDUCATION, LABOR, AND PENSIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions be authorized to meet, during the session of the Senate, in order to conduct a hearing entitled "Restoring FDA's Ability to Keep America's Families Safe" on Thursday, April 24, 2008. The hearing will commence at 9:30 a.m. in Room 106 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="COMMITTEE ON INDIAN AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Indian Affairs be authorized  to meet on Thursday, April 24, at 9 a.m. in Room 562 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building to conduct a business meeting on pending issues to be followed immediately by an oversight hearing on "Recommendations for Improving the Federal Acknowledgment Process."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate, to conduct an executive business meeting on Thursday, April 24, 2008, at 10 a.m. in Room SD-226 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="SELECT COMMITTEE ON INTELLIGENCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Select Committee on Intelligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on April 24, 2008, at 2:30 p.m. to hold a closed hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON FEDERAL FINANCIAL MANAGEMENT, GOVERNMENT INFORMATION, FEDERAL SERVICES, AND INTERNATIONAL SECURITY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs' Subcommittee on Federal Financial Management, Government Information, Federal Services, and International Security be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, April 24, 2008, at 9:30 a.m. in order to conduct a hearing entitled, "Addressing Iran's Nuclear Ambitions."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON OVERSIGHT OF GOVERNMENT MANAGEMENT, THE FEDERAL WORKFORCE, AND THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs' Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, April 24, 2008, at 2 p.m. in order to conduct a hearing entitled, "Beyond Control: Reforming Export Licensing Agencies for National Security and Economic Interests."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON ANTITRUST, COMPETITION POLICY AND CONSUMER RIGHTS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate Committee on the Judiciary, Subcommittee on Antitrust, Competition Policy and Consumer Rights, be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate, in order to conduct a hearing entitled "An Examination of the Delta-Northwest Merger" on Thursday, April 24, 2008, at 2 p.m., in Room SD-226 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building. The witness list is not yet available.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON WATER AND POWER">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on Water and Power be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate in order to conduct a hearing on Thursday, April 24, 2008, at 2:15 p.m., in Room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
