<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1193414402" ordinal="30" title="EXECUTIVE SESSION">
  <narrative>EXECUTIVE SESSION -- (Senate - October 26, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="13492">S13492</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="EXECUTIVE CALENDAR">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to executive session to consider the following nominations: Calendar Nos. 336 through 356; that the nominations be confirmed, the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table, the President be immediately notified of the Senate's action, and the Senate then return to legislative session.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The nominations considered and confirmed are as followed:</chair>
  <chair>George E. Pataki, of New York, to be a Representative of the United States of America to the Sixty-second Session of the General Assembly of the United Nations.</chair>
  <chair>Kelly G. Knight, of Kentucky, to be an Alternate Representative of the United States of America to the Sixty-second Session of the General Assembly of the United Nations.</chair>
  <chair>Rodger D. Young, of Michigan, to be an Alternate Representative of the United States of America to the Sixty-second Session of the General Assembly of the United Nations.</chair>
  <chair>William H. Frist, of Tennessee, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the Millennium Challenge Corporation for a term of three years.</chair>
  <chair>Kenneth Francis Hackett, of Maryland, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the Millennium Challenge Corporation for a term of two years. (Reappointment)</chair>
  <chair>David T. Johnson, of Georgia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be an Assistant Secretary of State (International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs).</chair>
  <chair>Robin Renee Sanders, of New York, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Federal Republic of Nigeria.</chair>
  <chair>Barry Leon Wells, of Ohio, a Career Member of the Senior Executive Service, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of The Gambia.</chair>
  <chair>Mark M. Boulware, of Texas, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Islamic Republic of Mauritania.</chair>
  <chair>James D. McGee, of Florida, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Zimbabwe.</chair>
  <chair>Ronald K. McMullen, of Iowa, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the State of Eritrea.</chair>
  <chair>P. Robert Fannin, of Arizona, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Dominican Republic.</chair>
  <chair>Christopher Egan, of Massachusetts, to be Representative of the United States of America to the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development, with the rank of Ambassador.</chair>
  <chair>Louis John Nigro, Jr., of Florida, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Chad.</chair>
  <chair>Paul E. Simons, of Virginia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Chile.</chair>
  <chair>Gail Dennise Mathieu, of New Jersey, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Namibia.</chair>
  <chair>Dan Mozena, of Iowa, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Angola.</chair>
  <chair>Eunice S. Reddick, of New York, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Gabonese Republic, and to serve concurrently and without additional compensation as Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Democratic Republic of Sao Tome and Principe.</chair>
  <chair>Daniel V. Speckhard, of Wisconsin, a Career Member of the Senior Executive Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to Greece.</chair>
  <chair>Thomas F. Stephenson, of California, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Portuguese Republic.</chair>
  <chair>Vincent Obsitnik, of Virginia, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Slovak Republic.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="DEPARTMENT OF STATE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, one of the nominations we approved is Dr. William H. Frist to be a member of the board of directors of the Millennium Challenge Corporation for a term of 3 years. This is Bill Frist who worked with us in the Senate for 12 years, who was majority leader and somebody with whom I worked very closely. He is a very fine man, a great reputation. He entered public service for the right reason. He was a prominent surgeon. He is  a man  who was one of the pioneers in transplant surgery.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have such fond memories of working with him. We had our battles, but he was always a gentleman. I wish him well with his job. I know he will do a very good job.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
