<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1204131603" ordinal="25" title="INDIAN HEALTH CARE IMPROVEMENT ACT">
  <narrative>INDIAN HEALTH CARE IMPROVEMENT ACT -- (Senate - February 27, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="1264">S1264</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300060" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I welcome the Senate passage of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act. The bill is a long overdue response to a health crisis for our country's American Indians and would at last strengthen and expand health services to those who need it most and those to whom promises were made but far too few promises have been kept. The last comprehensive reauthorization of IHCIA took place in 1992--and since then, progress has been ground to a halt in the Senate while health disparities  for American Indians have dramatically widened.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The situation is dire. Today, American Indians suffer from disproportionately higher rates of diabetes, heart disease, suicide, and several types of cancer than all other groups in the United States: 2.6 times more likely to be diagnosed with diabetes; 630 percent more likely to die from alcoholism; and a life expectancy nearly 6 years shorter than the rest of the U.S. population. The gap between the needs of this community and the resources dedicated to addressing them is stark: fewer mental  health professionals available to treat Indians than the rest of the U.S. population; health care expenditures for Indians less than half of what America spends for Federal prisoners.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It goes without saying that we should invest the necessary funds in improving health coverage and care for American Indians, which is why it is so important that the Indian Health Care Improvement Act modernizes Indian health care services and helps ensure at least that money is no longer the biggest impediment to quality health care in Indian Country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In my home State, the status of Indian health care is particularly daunting: inadequate health facilities, mental health services and assisted living care for the elderly; the percentage  of American Indians with poor emotional health is on average 2.1 times higher than the adult Massachusetts population; an obesity rate twice as high as the rate for Massachusetts adults in general. Moreover, the percentage of Mashpee Wampanoag adults with diabetes is  nearly two times higher than the rest of the adult population in our State. During the 5 years between 1999 and 2004, American Indian mothers were over three times more likely to smoke during pregnancy than all mothers giving birth in Massachusetts. American Indian students have much higher percentages of smoking, drinking alcohol before age</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill can mark a new day of at last addressing the health care needs of Indian Country programs to increase the outreach and enrollment of Indians in Medicaid and CHIP and improve the ability for tribes to participate in managed care health plans. The Indian Health Care Improvement Act brings greater access to health care services, improved medical insurance coverage, and education of disease prevention and healthy lifestyles.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senate came together across partisan lines to take a step forward with Indian Country, and I look forward to the quick passage of the bill and ultimately to seeing it signed into law by President Bush. This must be the beginning, not the end, of a new compact with Indian Country--and a renewed commitment to making sure that no American's health suffers because they are born on a farm, in a city, or on a reservation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
