<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1221753612" ordinal="85" title="MEASURES READ THE FIRST TIME--S. 3526, H.R. 6842, AND H.R. 6899">
  <narrative>MEASURES READ THE FIRST TIME--S. 3526, <bill type="h" number="6842">H.R. 6842</bill>, AND <bill type="h" number="6899">H.R. 6899</bill> -- (Senate - September 18, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="9167">S9167</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412246" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I understand there are three bills at the desk, and I ask for their first reading en bloc.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the bills by title for the first time.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A bill (<bill type="s" number="3526">S. 3526</bill>) to enhance drug trafficking interdiction by creating a Federal felony relating to operating or embarking in a submersible or semi-submersible vessel without nationality and on an international voyage.</narrative>
  <narrative>A bill (<bill type="h" number="6842">H.R. 6842</bill>) to restore Second Amendment rights in the District of Columbia.</narrative>
  <narrative>A bill (<bill type="h" number="6899">H.R. 6899</bill>) to advance the national security interests of the United States by reducing its dependency on oil through renewable and clean, alternative fuel technologies while building a bridge to the future through expanded access to Federal oil and natural gas resources, revising the relationship between the oil and gas industry and the consumers who own those resources and deserve a fair return from the development of publicly owned oil and gas, ending tax subsidies for large oil and  gas companies, and facilitating energy efficiencies in the building, housing, and transportation sectors, and for other purposes.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412246" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I now ask for their second reading en bloc, and I object to my own request en bloc.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Objection is heard. The bills will be read for the second time on the next legislative day.</chair>
</record>
