<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1169053202" ordinal="34" title="STATEMENTS ON INTRODUCED BILLS AND JOINT RESOLUTIONS">
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="Introducing S. 310. A bill to express the policy of the United States regarding the United States relationship with Native Hawaiians and to provide a process for the recognition by the United States of the Native Hawaiian governing entity; to the Committee on Indian Affairs.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="310">S. 310</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today with the senior Senator from Hawaii to introduce the Native Hawaiian Government Reorganization Act of 2007. This bill, which is of great importance to the people of Hawaii, establishes a process to extend the Federal policy of self-governance and self-determination to Hawaii's indigenous people. The bill provides parity in Federal policies that empower our country's other indigenous people--merican Indians and Alaska Natives--to participate in a government-to-government  relationship with the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>January 17, 2007, commemorates the 114th anniversary of Hawaii's beloved Queen Liliuokalani being deposed. Although this event may seem like a distant memory, it is a poignant event that expedited the decline of a proud and self-governing people. The overthrow facilitated Native Hawaiians being disenfranchised from not only their culture and land, but from their way of life. Native Hawaiians had to endure the forced imprisonment of their Queen and witness the deterioration and near eradication  of their culture and tradition in their own homeland, at the hands of foreigners committed exclusively to propagating Western values and conventions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While Congress has traditionally treated Native Hawaiians in a manner parallel to American Indians and Alaska Natives, the Federal policy of self-governance and self-determination has not been formally extended to Native Hawaiians. The bill itself does not extend Federal recognition--it authorizes the process for Federal recognition.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Native Hawaiian Government Reorganization Act of 2007 does three things: (1) It authorizes an office in the Department of the Interior to serve as a liaison between Native Hawaiians and the United States; (2) It forms an interagency coordinating group composed of officials from Federal agencies who currently administer programs and services impacting Native Hawaiians; and (3) It authorizes a process for the reorganization of the Native Hawaiian governing entity for the purposes of a federally  recognized government-to-government relationship.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Once the Native Hawaiian governing entity is recognized, the bill establishes an inclusive, democratic negotiations process representing both Native Hawaiians and non-Native Hawaiians. Negotiations between the Native Hawaiian entity and the Federal and State governments may address issues such as the transfer of lands, assets, and natural resources and jurisdiction over such lands, assets, and natural resources, as well as other longstanding issues resulting from the overthrow of the Kingdom  of Hawaii. Any transfers of governmental authority or power will require implementing legislation at the State and Federal levels.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Hawaii congressional delegation has devoted much time and careful consideration into crafting this legislation. When I first started this process in 1999, our congressional delegation created five working groups to assist with the drafting of this legislation. The working groups were composed of individuals from the Native Hawaiian community, the State of Hawaii, Federal Government, Indian country, Members of Congress, and experts in constitutional law. Collectively, more than 100 people  worked together on the initial draft of this legislation. The meetings held with the Native Hawaiian community were open to the public and a number of individuals who had differing views attended the meetings and provided their alternative views on the legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In August 2000, the Senate Committee on Indian Affairs and the House Committee on Resources held joint field hearings on the legislation in Hawaii for 5 days. While the bill passed the U.S. House of Representatives in the 106th Congress, the Senate failed to take action. The bill was subsequently considered by the 107th, l08th, and 109th Congresses. In each Congress, the bill has been favorably reported by the Senate Committee on Indian Affairs and its companion measure has been favorably reported  by the House Committee on Resources in the 106th through the 108th Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Most recently in the 109th Congress clarifications were made to the bill. I want to inform my colleagues to the fact that this bill is identical to legislative language negotiated between Senator INOUYE and myself, and officials from the Department of Justice, Office of Management and Budget, and the White House. The language satisfactorily addresses concerns expressed in July 2005 by the Bush administration regarding the liability of the United States in land claims, the impact of the  bill on military readiness, gaming, and civil and criminal jurisdiction in Hawaii.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With respect to liability of the United States as it relates to land claims, as the author of the Apology Resolution, P.L. 103-150, as well as the Native Hawaiian Government Reorganization Act, I have always maintained that this legislation is not intended to serve as a settlement of any claims nor as a cause of action for any claims. The negotiated language makes clear that any grievances regarding historical wrongs committed against Native Hawaiians by the United States or by the State of Hawaii  are to be addressed in the negotiations process between the Native Hawaiian governing entity and Federal and State governments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a senior member of the Senate Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, as well as the incoming Chairman on the Subcommittee on Readiness and Management of the Senate Committee on Armed Services, military readiness for our Armed Forces is of great importance to me. Due to concerns raised by the Department of Defense to the consultation requirements expected to be facilitated by the Office of Native Hawaiian Relations in the Department of the Interior and the Native Hawaiian  Interagency Coordinating Group; negotiated language exempts the Department from these consultation requirements. However, these exemptions do not alter nor terminate requirements of the DoD to consult with Native Hawaiians under the Native Graves Protection and Repatriation Act, NAGPRA, National Historic Preservation Act, NHPA, and other existing statutes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill does not authorize gaming by the Native Hawaiian governing entity. Negotiated language clarifies that gaming may not be conducted by Native Hawaiians or the</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Native Hawaiian governing entity as a matter of  claimed inherent authority or under the authority of any Federal laws or regulations promulgated by the Secretary of the Interior or the National Indian Gaming Commission. The bill also makes clear that the prohibition applies to any efforts to establish gaming by Native Hawaiians and the Native Hawaiian governing entity in Hawaii and in any other State or Territory. This language only applies to efforts  to establish gaming operations as a matter of inherent authority as indigenous peoples or under federal laws pertaining to gaming by native peoples.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill makes clear that civil and criminal jurisdiction currently held by the Federal and State governments will remain with the Federal and State governments unless otherwise negotiated and implementing legislation is enacted.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have described the clarifications that have been made so my colleagues know that our negotiations with the administration have been successful. This language has been publicly available since September 2005 and has been widely distributed. Although such clarifications have been made, I am proud to report that the bill remains true to its intent and purpose--to clarify the existing legal and political relationship between Hawaii's indigenous people, Native Hawaiians and the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Along with our efforts to work with the Bush administration, during the past 4 years, we have worked closely with Hawaii's first Republican governor in 40 years, Governor Linda Lingle to enact this legislation. We have also worked closely with the Hawaii State legislature which has passed three resolutions unanimously in support of federal recognition for Native Hawaiians. I am pleased to announce today that I am again joined by members from both sides of the aisle to introduce this important  measure. I mention this, to underscore the fact that this is bipartisan legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to its widespread support by both Native Hawaiians and non-Native Hawaiians in Hawaii, in resolutions adopted by the oldest and largest national Indian organization, the National Congress of American Indians, and the largest organization representing the Native people of Alaska, the Alaska Federation of Natives, the members of both groups have consistently expressed their strong support for enactment of a bill to provide for recognition by the United States of a Native Hawaiian governing  entity. Organizations such as the American Bar Association, Japanese American Citizen League, and the National Indian Education Association have also passed resolutions in support of federal recognition for Hawaii's indigenous peoples.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today I provide my colleagues with a framework to understand the need for this legislation by briefly reviewing (1) Hawaii's past, ancient Hawaiian society prior to Western contact, (2) Hawaii's present, the far reaching consequences of the overthrow, and (3) Hawaii's future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Hawaii was originally settled by Polynesian voyagers arriving as early as 300 A.D, 1200 years before Europe's great explorers Magellan and Columbus. The Hawaiians braved immense distances guided by their extensive knowledge of navigation and understanding of the marine environment. Isolation followed the era of long voyages, enabling Native Hawaiians to develop distinct political, economic, and social structures which were mutually supportive. As stewards of the land and sea, Native Hawaiians  were intimately linked to the environment and they developed innovative methods of agriculture, aquaculture, navigation and irrigation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With an influx of foreigners into Hawaii, Native Hawaiian populations plummeted due to death from common Western diseases. Those that survived witnessed foreign interest and involvement in their government grow until Queen Liliuokalani was forced by American citizens to abdicate her right to the throne. This devastated the Native Hawaiian people, forever tainting the waters of their identity and tattering the very fabric of their society. For some this injustice, this wound has never healed,  manifesting itself in a sense of inferiority and hopelessness leaving many Native Hawaiians at the lowest levels of achievement by all social and economic measures.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, 14 years ago the United States enacted the Apology Resolution, 103-150, which acknowledged the 100th anniversary of the overthrow of the Kingdom of Hawaii in which the United States offered an apology to Native Hawaiians and declared its policy to support reconciliation efforts. This is a landmark declaration for it recognizes not only are Native Hawaiians the indigenous people of Hawaii, but of the urgent need for the U.S. to actively engage in reconciliation efforts. This acknowledgment  played a crucial role in initiating a healing process and although progress has been made, the path ahead is uncertain.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Frustration has led to anger and festered in the hearts of Hawaii's younger generations, with each child that is taught about this period of Hawaiian history, a loss is relived. It is a burden that Native Hawaiians since the overthrow continue to carry, to know that they were violated in their own homeland and their governance was ripped away unjustly. Despite the perceived harmony, it is the generation of my grandchildren that is growing impatient and frustrated with the lack of progress being  made. Influenced by a deep sadness and growing intolerance, an active minority within this generation seeks independence from the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is for this generation that I work to enact this bill so that there is the structured process to deal with these emotional issues. It is important that discussions are held and that there is a  framework to guide appropriate action. For Hawaii is the homeland of the Native Hawaiian people.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A lack of action by the U.S. will only incite and fuel us down a path to a divided Hawaii. A Hawaii where lines and boundaries are drawn and unity severed. However, the legislation I introduce today seeks to build upon the foundation of reconciliation. It provides a structured process to bring together the people of Hawaii, along a path of healing to a Hawaii where its indigenous people are respected and culture is embraced.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Respecting the rights of America's first people--American Indians, Alaska Natives, and Native Hawaiians is not un-American. Through enactment of this legislation, we have the opportunity to demonstrate that our country does not just preach its ideas, but lives according to its founding principles. That the United States will admit when it has trespassed against a people and remain resolute to make amends. We demonstrate our character to ourselves and to the world by respecting the rights of our  country's indigenous people. As it has for America's other indigenous peoples, I believe the United States must fulfill its responsibility to Native Hawaiians.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am proud of the fact that this bill respects the rights of Hawaii's indigenous peoples through a process that is consistent with Federal law, and it provides the structured process for the people of Hawaii to address the longstanding issues which have plagued both Native Hawaiians and non-Native Hawaiians since the overthrow of the Kingdom of Hawaii. We have an established record of the United States' commitment to the reconciliation with Native Hawaiians. This legislation is another step building  upon that foundation and honoring that commitment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask my colleagues to join me in enacting this legislation which is of great importance to all the people of Hawaii.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the text of this measure be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300056" topic="Introducing S. 310. A bill to express the policy of the United States regarding the United States relationship with Native Hawaiians and to provide a process for the recognition by the United States of the Native Hawaiian governing entity; to the Committee on Indian Affairs.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I am pleased to join my colleague, Senator Akaka, as a cosponsor of the Native Hawaiian Government Reorganization Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>During the 109th Congress, the Administration expressed concerns with this legislation that stem from its experience with Indian tribes. The history of the Native Hawaiians and their treatment by the United States is similar to that of Indian tribes and Alaska Natives. I want to commend the Administration for devoting staff to work with us to achieve consensus on mutually agreeable language. I am confident that this measure not only addresses the Administration's concerns but also the concerns  of some of our colleagues.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Having served on the Indian Affairs Committee for the past 28 years, I know that most of our colleagues are more familiar with conditions and circumstances in Indian country, and naturally, they bring their experience with Indian country to bear in considering this measure, which has been pending in the Senate for the past eight years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Accordingly, I believe it is important that our colleagues understand what this bill seeks to accomplish as well as how it differs from legislation affecting Indian country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is a little known fact that beginning in 1910 and since that time, the Congress has passed and the President has signed into law over 160 Federal laws designed to address the conditions of Native Hawaiians.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thus, Federal laws which authorize the provision of health care, education, housing, and job training and employment services, as well as programs to provide for the preservation of the Native Hawaiian language, Native language immersion, Native cultural and grave protections and repatriation of Native sacred objects have been in place for decades.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Native Hawaiian programs do not draw upon funding that is appropriated for American Indians or Alaska Natives--there are separate authorizations for programs that are administered by different Federal agencies--not the Bureau of Indian Affairs or the Indian Health Service, for instance--and the Native Hawaiian program funds are not drawn from the Interior Appropriations Subcommittee account. Thus, they have no impact on the funding that is provided for the other indigenous, native people  of the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, unlike the native people residing on the mainland, Native Hawaiians have not been able to exercise their rights as Native people to self-determination or self-governance because their government was overthrown on January 17, 1893.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill would provide a process for the reorganization of the Native Hawaiian government and the resumption of a political and legal relationship between that government and the government of the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because the Native Hawaiian government is not an Indian tribe, the body of Federal Indian law that would otherwise customarily apply when the United States extends Federal recognition to an Indian tribal group does not apply.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thus, the bill provides authority for a process of negotiations amongst the United States, the State of Hawaii, and the reorganized Native Hawaiian government to address such matters as the exercise of civil and criminal jurisdiction by the respective governments, the transfer of land and natural resources and other assets, and the exercise of governmental authority over those lands, natural resources and other assets.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Upon reaching agreement, the U.S. Congress and the legislature of the State of Hawaii would have to enact legislation implementing the agreements of the three governments, including amendments that will necessarily have to be made to existing Federal law, such as the Hawaii Admissions Act and the Hawaiian Homes Commission Act, and to State law, including amendments to the Hawaii State Constitution, before any of the new governmental relationships and authorities can take effect.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is why concerns which are premised on the manner in which Federal Indian law provides for the respective governmental authorities of the State governments and Indian tribal governments simply do not apply in Hawaii.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have every confidence that consistent with the Federal policy for over 35 years, the restoration of the rights to self-determination and self-governance will enable the Native Hawaiian people, as the direct, lineal descendants of the aboriginal, indigenous native people of what has become our nation's fiftieth state, to take their rightful place in the family of governments that makes up our constitutional system of governance.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300099" topic="Introducing S. 315. A bill to establish a digital and wireless network technology program, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="315">S. 315</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to reintroduce the Minority Serving Institution Digital and Wireless Technology Opportunity Act. This legislation, which was crafted by Senator Allen and I in years past, will provide vital resources to address the technology gap that exists at many Minority Serving Institutions, MSIs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the past, Senator Allen took the role of lead sponsor on this important bill. With his leadership, this exact legislation has passed twice unanimously. Unfortunately, the 109th Congress adjourned before the House of Representatives considered the bill. Accordingly, today I am privileged to serve as the lead sponsor of this legislation in the 110th Congress. I am pleased to have my Virginia colleague Senator JIM WEBB as an original cosponsor of this bill. I hope this important bill will  soon become law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over 60 percent of all jobs require information technology skills. Jobs in the information technology field pay significantly higher salaries than jobs in non-information technology fields. At the same time, many of our Minority Serving Institutions lack the capital to offer assistance to their students to bridge the "Digital Divide" between students who are able to develop the skills necessary to succeed in  a technology based economy and those who  are not.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation will establish a grant program for these institutions of higher education to bring increased access to computers, technology, and the Internet to their student populations. Specifically, this legislation authorizes $250 million in Federal grants for Minority Serving Institutions to acquire equipment, instrumentation, networking capability, hardware and software, digital network technology and wireless technology and infrastructure to develop and provide educational services.  In addition, the grants could be used for such activities as campus wiring, equipment upgrades, and technology training. Finally, Minority Serving Institutions could use these funds to offer their students universal access to campus networks, increase connectivity rates, or make infrastructure improvements.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am proud to say that Virginia is home to five Historically Black Colleges and Universities, HBCUs--Norfolk State University, St. Paul's College, Virginia Union University, Hampton University, and Virginia State University--that are eligible for these technology grants. There are over 200 Hispanic Serving Institutions, over 100 Historically Black Colleges and Universities and over 30 Tribal Colleges throughout the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, in 2005, this bill passed in the Senate by unanimous consent. In 2003, this bill passed in the Senate with a roll call vote of 97-0. I am pleased to support this legislation, as I have done in the past, and I look forward to strengthening the technology provided to students at Minority Serving Institutions.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300061" topic="Introducing S. 316. A bill to prohibit brand name drug companies from compensating generic drug companies to delay the entry of a generic drug into the market; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="316">S. 316</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to introduce the Preserve Access to Affordable Generics Act. This legislation will stop one of the most egregious tactics used by the brand-name pharmaceutical industry to keep generic competitors off the market, leaving consumers with unnecessary high drug prices.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The way it is done is simple--a drug company that holds a patent on a blockbuster brand-name drug, pays a generic drug maker off to delay the sale of a competing generic product that might dip into their profits. The brand name company profits so much by delaying competition that it can easily afford to pay off the generic company, leaving consumers the big losers who continue to pay unnecessarily high drug prices.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last year, the Supreme Court refused to consider an appeal by the Federal Trade Commission to reinstate anti-trust charges against a brand-name drugs maker. Since the recent court decisions allowing these backroom deals, there has been a sharp rise in the number of settlements in which brand-name companies pay off generic competitors to keep their cheaper drugs off the market. In a report issued last year, the FTC found that more than two-thirds of the 10 settlement agreements made in 2006 included  a pay-off from the brand in exchange for a promise by the generic company to delay entry into the market.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The decision by the Supreme Court is a blow to consumers who save billions of dollars on generics every year. When brand, name drugs lose patent rights, this opens the door for consumers, employers, third-party payers, and other purchasers to save billions--63 percent on average--by using generic versions of these drugs. A recent study released earlier this year by Pharmaceutical Care Management Association, showed that health plans and consumers could save $26.4 billion over the next 5 years  by using the generic versions of 14 popular drugs that are scheduled to lose their patent protections before 2010.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last year, I was successful in including an additional $10 million in the fiscal year 07 Agriculture Appropriations bill for the Food and Drug Administration's Office of Generic Drugs, an effort to help reduce the growing backlog of generic drug applications. The FDA Office of Generic Drugs has reported a backlog of more than 800 generic drug applications with more applications for new generics being received than ever before.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But even approval by the FDA doesn't always guarantee that consumers will have access to these affordable drugs. Brand-name pharmaceutical manufacturers have learned to circumvent the Drug Price Competition and Patent Term Restoration Act, commonly referred to as Hatch-Waxman, using litigation and other means to extend the life of patents and keep generics from entering the market Of the six approved first generics for LA popular brand-name drugs taken by seniors over the last year, only two  have actually reached the market, while the others are being kept of the shelves by patent disputes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We cannot profess to care about the high cost of prescription drugs while turning a blind eye to anticompetitive backroom deals between brand and generic drug companies. It's time to stop these drug company pay-offs that only serve the companies involved and deny consumers to affordable generic drugs. I urge my colleagues to join me in this effort.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="Introducing S. 316. A bill to prohibit brand name drug companies from compensating generic drug companies to delay the entry of a generic drug into the market; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I am pleased to join Senators Kohl, Feingold, Grassley and Schumer in introducing the Preserve Access to Affordable Generics Act of 2007. This legislation is a continuation of a longstanding, bipartisan effort to provide consumers with more choices for medications at lower costs. Better access to affordable prescription medication is of vital importance to seniors, families, and consumers across the Nation who are struggling to keep  up with the ever increasing costs of health care.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation builds on the Drug Competition Act, which I authored in 2001 and which became law in 2003 in the Medicare Modernization Act. Recently, two Federal courts undermined the intent of this law; the legislation we introduce today will address that problem. The Preserve Access to Affordable Generics Act will result in lower prescription drug costs for all Americans by preventing a pernicious practice in which brand-name pharmaceutical companies pay other drug companies not to produce  and market generic drugs--which can be 80 percent less expensive than their brand-name counterparts--as part of private patent settlement agreements.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Hatch-Waxman Act was intended to facilitate the entry of lower-cost generic drugs into the market, making medication more affordable, while protecting patent rights to foster innovation. It created a process, known as the Abbreviated New Drug Application, ANDA, to speed approval of generics. Under ANDA, an applicant can receive expedited approval from the FDA to market a generic product. An applicant using ANDA may certify that the manufacturing of its new drug will either not infringe on  a previously patented drug on which it is based, or that the existing patent is invalid. After certifying an ANDA, the generic applicant must give notice to the patent-holder, at which point the patent-holder has 45 days to file a patent infringement against the applicant.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>More times than not, disputes over an ANDA are resolved through private settlements. Unfortunately, the  underpinnings of these private settlements are becoming more and more questionable; drug companies are abusing Hatch-Waxman provisions, and using settlement opportunities to limit consumer choices and keep consumer prices artificially high. The FTC had been policing these deals to ensure they were not anticompetitive until two recent appellate court  decisions limited it's role.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Hatch-Waxman created a good framework for promoting innovation while speeding the market entry of affordable drugs. The trend of anticompetitive agreements between brand-name pharmaceutical companies and generic companies to delay entry into the market is a troubling abuse of that good law. Some drug firms have colluded to pad their profits by forcing consumers to pay higher prices than they would pay for lower-cost generics. Congress never intended for brand-name drug companies to be able to  grease the palms of generic companies by paying them not to produce generic medicines.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rarely do we have such a clear-cut opportunity as this to remove obvious impediments that prevent the marketplace from working as it should--to the benefit of consumers. Congress should seize this opportunity and enact legislation that plainly makes anticompetitive deals, such as those I have outlined, illegal.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Preserve Access to Affordable Generics Act will accomplish this goal. I look forward to working with my colleagues on both sides of the aisle to pass this timely and needed legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="Introducing S. 317. A bill to amend the Clean Air Act to establish a program to regulate the emission of greenhouse gases from electric utilities; to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="317">S. 317</bill>] Mr. President, I am pleased to join with Senator Carper to introduce the Electric Utility Cap and Trade Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, we are introducing the first of five bills to address the number one environmental issue facing this planet--global warming.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill establishes a national cap and trade system over the electricity sector. It will reduce emissions from this sector by 25 percent by 2020.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What distinguishes this bill is that it has the support of 6 major energy companies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Together, these companies operate in 42 States and produce approximately 150,000 megawatts of energy. This is greater than 15 percent of the U.S. electricity market.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These companies include, first, Pacific Gas &amp; Electric (PG&amp;E) Corporation, which is the parent of Pacific Gas and Electric Company. PG&amp;E is California's largest utility and serves approximately 1 in every 20 Americans. PG&amp;E Corporation currently owns approximately 6,500 megawatts of generation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second, Calpine, which operates in 20 States and Canada, generating 26,000 megawatts of energy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Third, Florida Power &amp; Light, which operates in 26 States, generating more than 30,000 megawatts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Fourth, Entergy, which operates in Arkansas, Louisiana, Mississippi, and Texas, generating approximately 30,000 megawatts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Fifth, Exelon, which operates in Illinois and Pennsylvania, generating 38,000 megawatts of energy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sixth, Public Service Enterprise Group, which is the largest provider of energy in New Jersey, generating approximately 15,000 megawatts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These companies' support is greatly appreciated, and I think it signals a new willingness in the energy industry to seriously tackle global warming.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill is just the beginning of a major program. Over the next weeks and months, we will also be introducing a cap and trade bill for the industrial sector; a bill that increases fuel economy standards by ten miles per gallon over the next ten years; a bill to promote bio-diesel and E-85; and other low carbon fuels and an energy efficiency bill modeled after California's program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is an ambitious agenda, but I believe it is the right way to go if we are to slow global warming.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A great debate has raged in the halls of Congress, in academia, and in the field over the past two decades.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At issue were three fundamental questions: First, is the earth warming? Second, if so, is the warming caused by human activity? And third, can it be stopped?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over the past few years, a consensus has been forged. An overwhelming body of evidence has been gathered. And, an inescapable conclusion has been reached: The earth is warming. The warming is caused by human activity, namely the combustion of fossil fuels.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It cannot be stopped, because carbon dioxide does not dissipate. It stays in the atmosphere for 30, 40, or 50 years or more.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When we pick up the newspaper each day we see the results. We read about ice sheets the size of small nations breaking off the ice shelves in the Arctic and Antarctic. We read about polar bears committing acts of cannibalism, something unknown in recent memory. We read about species disappearing, seas rising, coral reefs dying, and glaciers melting.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But, all this dire news does not mean we should throw up our hands and do nothing. If we act now, and if we act with purpose, the most serious consequences can be averted. Global warming can be contained to 1-2 degrees Fahrenheit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But if we do not act, and temperatures spike by 5 degrees or more, the world around us will change forever. There's no going back.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The question becomes what can we do? I've spent the last year trying to answer this question. And the conclusion I've reached is that there is no single answer, no silver bullet, no one thing to turn the tide. But rather, we need many answers in many different areas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And more importantly, we need people of common purpose, working together, to find innovative solutions. And that's why we're here today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As I was searching for answers, I picked up the phone and called PG&amp;E Corporation's CEO, Peter Darbee. I said, "Peter, would you help me out on Global Warming legislation?"</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To his immense credit, Peter went back, studied the issue, and said "You're right. Something must be done." And he's been terrific. He's helped at every step of the way.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It means so much to me that PG&amp;E, Calpine, Florida Power and Light, and all the companies that comprise the Clean Energy Group's Clean Air Policy Initiative have endorsed the legislation we are introducing today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is the most aggressive global warming bill that industry has supported to date. And I want to thank the CEOs of these companies today for their courage and leadership in taking this step.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Here's what the bill would do. The bill would establish a cap and trade program for the electricity sector, which is the single largest piece of the global warming puzzle, accounting for 33 percent of all U.S. emissions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, the bill would a cap at 2006 levels in 2011--a 6 percent reduction from anticipated levels of greenhouse gases from the electric sector.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 2015, it would ratchet the cap down to 2001 levels--a 16 percent reduction from anticipated levels.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 2016, the bill would reduce the cap further to 1 percent below 2001 levels. And, from 2017 to 2019 it would require additional annual 1 percent reductions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By 2020, emissions would be reduced 25 percent below anticipated levels.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And after that, emissions will be reduced even further--by an additional 1.5 percent a year and potentially more, if the EPA, based on scientific evidence, believes that more needs to be done to avert the most dire consequences of global warming.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That's the cap.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The trade part of the bill gives companies flexibility to embrace new technologies, encourage innovation, and promote green practices--not just in this area, but across the economy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As I said, this bill is only one part of the answer. One piece of the puzzle.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress has a window of opportunity to act. If we act boldly and quickly, then perhaps we can make a difference.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But if we resort to the feuding which has characterized past Congresses, our world will be the poorer for it. I think there is but one choice.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to join me in supporting this legislation and I ask unanimous consent that the text of the legislation be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="Introducing S. 320. A bill to provide for the protection of paleontological resources on Federal lands, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="320">S. 320</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today along with my distinguished colleagues, Senator Wyden, Senator Bunning, Senator Inouye, and Senator Durbin, to introduce the Paleontological Resources Preservation Act in order to protect and preserve the Nation's important fossil record for the benefit of our citizens. Vertebrate fossils are rare and important natural resources that have become increasingly endangered due to an increase in the illegal collection of fossil  specimens for commercial sale. However, at this time there is no unified policy regarding the treatment of fossils by Federal land management agencies which would help protect and conserve fossil specimens. Consequently, we risk the deterioration or loss of these valuable scientific resources. This Act will correct that omission by providing uniformity to the patchwork of statutes and regulations that currently exist. By creating a comprehensive national policy for preserving and managing paleontological</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would also mention that this bill is exactly the same bill that I introduced  in the 109th Congress. This bill was heard and marked up by the Senate Energy and Natural Resources Committee, and was passed by the Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a senior member of the Senate Energy and Natural Resources Committee and Chair of the Subcommittee on National Parks, I am very concerned about the preservation of fossils as records of earth's past upheavals and struggles. While I recognize the value of amateur collecting--and casual collecting--of fossils is protected in this bill--fossil theft has become an increasing problem. New fossil fields and insights into the earth's past are discovered nearly every month. Paleontological resources  can be sold on the market for a hefty price. For example, the complete skeleton of a T-Rex was sold for $8.6 million at auction to the Field Museum of Chicago. Consequently, they are being stolen from public lands without regard to science and education. The protections I offer in this Act are not new. Federal and management agencies have individual regulations</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>
      <bill type="s" number="320">S. 320</bill>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "Paleontological Resources Preservation Act".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. DEFINITIONS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; As used in this Act:</paragraph>
    <paragraph> (1) CASUAL COLLECTING.--The term "casual collecting" means the collecting of a reasonable amount of common invertebrate and plant paleontological resources for non-commercial personal use, either by surface collection or the use of non-powered hand tools resulting in only negligible disturbance to the Earth's surface and other resources. As used in this paragraph, the terms "reasonable amount", "common invertebrate and plant paleontological resources" and "negligible disturbance"  shall be determined by the Secretary.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) FEDERAL LANDS.--The term "Federal lands" means--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) lands controlled or administered by the Secretary of the Interior, except Indian lands; or&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) National Forest System lands controlled or administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) INDIAN LANDS.--The term "Indian Land" means lands of Indian tribes, or Indian individuals, which are either held in trust by the United States or subject to a restriction against alienation imposed by the United States.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) PALEONTOLOGICAL RESOURCE.--The term "paleontological resource" means any fossilized remains, traces, or imprints of organisms, preserved in or on the earth's crust, that are of paleontological interest and that provide information about the history of life on earth, except that the term does not include--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) any materials associated with an archaeological resource (as defined in section 3(1) of the Archaeological Resources Protection Act of 1979 (16 U.S.C. 470bb(1)); or&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) any cultural item (as defined in section 2 of the Native American Graves Protection and Repatriation Act (25 U.S.C. 3001)).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) SECRETARY.--The term "Secretary" means the Secretary of the Interior with respect to lands controlled or administered by the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture with respect to National Forest System Lands controlled or administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (6) STATE.--The term "State" means the fifty States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and any other territory or possession of the United States.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 3. MANAGEMENT.</paragraph>
    <paragraph> (a) In General.--The Secretary shall manage and protect paleontological resources on Federal lands using scientific principles and expertise. The Secretary shall develop appropriate plans for inventory, monitoring, and the scientific and educational use of paleontological resources, in accordance with applicable agency laws, regulations, and policies. These plans shall emphasize interagency coordination and collaborative efforts where possible with non-Federal partners, the scientific  community, and the general public.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Coordination.--To the extent possible, the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall coordinate in the implementation of this Act.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 4. PUBLIC AWARENESS AND EDUCATION PROGRAM.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; The Secretary shall establish a program to increase public awareness about the significance of paleontological resources.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 5. COLLECTION OF PALEONTOLOGICAL RESOURCES.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Permit Requirement.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) IN GENERAL.--Except as provided in this Act, a paleontological resource may not be collected from Federal lands without a permit issued under this Act by the Secretary.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) CASUAL COLLECTING EXCEPTION.--The Secretary may allow casual collecting without a permit on Federal lands controlled or administered by the Bureau of Land Management, the Bureau of Reclamation, and the Forest Service, where such collection is consistent with the laws governing the management of those Federal lands and this Act.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) PREVIOUS PERMIT EXCEPTION.--Nothing in this section shall affect a valid permit issued prior to the date of enactment of this Act.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Criteria for Issuance of a Permit.--The Secretary may issue a permit for the collection of a paleontological resource pursuant to an application if the Secretary determines that--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) the applicant is qualified to carry out the permitted activity;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) the permitted activity is undertaken for the purpose of furthering paleontological knowledge or for public education;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) the permitted activity is consistent with any management plan applicable to the Federal lands concerned; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) the proposed methods of collecting will not threaten significant natural or cultural resources.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Permit Specifications.--A permit for the collection of a paleontological resource issued under this section shall contain such terms and conditions as the Secretary deems necessary to carry out the purposes of this Act. Every permit shall include requirements that--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) the paleontological resource that is collected from Federal lands under the permit will remain the property of the United States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) the paleontological resource and copies of associated records will be preserved for the public in an approved repository, to be made available for scientific research and public education; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) specific locality data will not be released by the permittee or repository without the written permission of the Secretary.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (d) Modification, Suspension, and Revocation of Permits.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) The Secretary may modify, suspend, or revoke a permit issued under this section--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) for resource, safety, or other management considerations; or&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) when there is a violation of term or condition of a permit issued pursuant to this section.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) The permit shall be revoked if any person working under the authority of the permit is convicted under section 7 or is assessed a civil penalty under section 8.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (e) Area Closures.--In order to protect paleontological or other resources and to provide for public safety, the Secretary may restrict access to or close areas under the Secretary's jurisdiction to the collection of paleontological resources.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 6. CURATION OF RESOURCES.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Any paleontological resource, and any data and records associated with the resource, collected under a permit, shall be deposited in an approved repository. The Secretary may enter into agreements with non-Federal repositories regarding the curation of these resources, data, and records.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 7. PROHIBITED ACTS; CRIMINAL PENALTIES.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) In General.--A person may not--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) excavate, remove, damage, or otherwise alter or deface or attempt to excavate, remove, damage, or otherwise alter or deface any paleontological resources located on Federal lands unless such activity is conducted in accordance with this Act;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) exchange, transport, export, receive, or offer to exchange, transport, export, or receive any paleontological resource if, in the exercise of due care, the person knew or should have known such resource to have been excavated or removed from Federal lands in violation of any provisions, rule, regulation, law, ordinance, or permit in effect under Federal law, including this Act; or&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) sell or purchase or offer to sell or purchase any paleontological resource if, in the exercise of due care, the person knew or should have known such resource to have been excavated, removed, sold, purchased, exchanged, transported, or received from Federal lands.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) False Labeling Offenses.--A person may not make or submit any false record, account, or label for, or any false identification of, any paleontological resource excavated or removed from Federal lands.</paragraph>
    <paragraph> (c) Penalties.--A person who knowingly violates or counsels, procures, solicits, or employs another person to violate subsection (a) or (b) shall, upon conviction, be fined in accordance with title 18, United States Code, or imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both; but if the sum of the commercial and paleontological value of the paleontological resources involved and the cost of restoration and repair of such resources does not exceed $500, such person shall be fined in accordance  with title 18, United States Code, or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (d) General Exception.--Nothing in subsection (a) shall apply to any person with respect to any paleontological resource which  was in the lawful possession of such person prior to the date of the enactment of this Act.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 8. CIVIL PENALTIES.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) In General.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) HEARING.--A person who violates any prohibition contained in an applicable regulation or permit issued under this Act may be assessed a penalty by the Secretary after the person is given notice and opportunity for a hearing with respect to the violation. Each violation shall be considered a separate offense for purposes of this section.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) AMOUNT OF PENALTY.--The amount of such penalty assessed under paragraph (1) shall be determined under regulations promulgated pursuant to this Act, taking into account the following factors:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) The scientific or fair market value, whichever is greater, of the paleontological resource involved, as determined by the Secretary.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) The cost of response, restoration, and repair of the resource and the paleontological site involved.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) Any other factors considered relevant by the Secretary assessing the penalty.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) MULTIPLE OFFENSES.--In the case of a second or subsequent violation by the same person, the amount of a penalty assessed under paragraph (2) may be doubled.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) LIMITATION.--The amount of any penalty assessed under this subsection for any one violation shall not exceed an amount equal to double the cost of response, restoration, and repair of resources and paleontological site damage plus double the scientific or fair market value of resources destroyed or not recovered.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Petition for Judicial Review; Collection of Unpaid Assessments.--</paragraph>
    <paragraph> (1) JUDICIAL REVIEW.--Any person against whom an order is issued assessing a penalty under subsection (a) may file a petition for judicial review of the order in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia or in the district in which the violation is alleged to have occurred within the 30-day period beginning on the date the order making the assessment was issued. Upon notice of such filing, the Secretary shall promptly file such a certified copy of the record on which  the order was issued. The court shall hear the action on the record made before the Secretary and shall sustain the action if it is supported by substantial evidence on the record considered as a whole.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) FAILURE TO PAY.--If any person fails to pay a penalty under this section within 30 days--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) after the order making assessment has become final and the person has not filed a petition for judicial review of the order in accordance with paragraph (1); or</paragraph>
    <paragraph> (B) after a court in an action brought in paragraph (1) has entered a final judgment upholding the assessment of the penalty, the Secretary may request the Attorney General to institute a civil action in a district court of the United States for any district in which the person if found, resides, or transacts business, to collect the penalty (plus interest at currently prevailing rates from the date of the final order or the date of the final judgment, as the case may be). The district court  shall have jurisdiction to hear and decide any such action. In such action, the validity, amount, and appropriateness of such penalty shall not be subject to review. Any person who fails to pay on a timely basis the amount of an assessment of a civil penalty as described in the first sentence of this paragraph shall be required to pay, in addition to such amount and interest, attorneys fees and costs for collection proceedings.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Hearings.--Hearings held during proceedings instituted under subsection (a) shall be conducted in accordance with section 554 of title 5, United States Code.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (d) Use of Recovered Amounts.--Penalties collected under this section shall be available to the Secretary and without further appropriation may be used only as follows:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) To protect, restore, or repair the paleontological resources and sites which were the subject of the action, or to acquire sites with equivalent resources, and to protect, monitor, and study the resources and sites. Any acquisition shall be subject to any limitations contained in the organic legislation for such Federal lands.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) To provide educational materials to the public about paleontological resources and sites.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) To provide for the payment of rewards as provided in section 9.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 9. REWARDS AND FORFEITURE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) Rewards.--The Secretary may pay from penalties collected under section 7 or 8--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) consistent with amounts established in regulations by the Secretary; or</paragraph>
    <paragraph> (2) if no such regulation exists, an amount equal to the lesser of one-half of the penalty or $500, to any person who furnishes information which leads to the finding of a civil violation, or the conviction of criminal violation, with respect to which the penalty was paid. If several persons provided the information, the amount shall be divided among the persons. No officer or employee of the United States or of any State or local government who furnishes information or renders service in the  performance of his official duties shall be eligible for payment under this subsection.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Forfeiture.--All paleontological resources with respect to which a violation under section 7 or 8 occurred and which are in the possession of any person, and all vehicles and equipment of any person that were used in connection with the violation, shall be subject to civil forfeiture, or upon conviction, to criminal forfeiture. All provisions of law relating to the seizure, forfeiture, and condemnation of property for a violation of this Act, the disposition of such property or  the proceeds from the sale thereof, and remission or mitigation of such forfeiture, as well as the procedural provisions of chapter 46 of title 18, United States Code, shall apply to the seizures and forfeitures incurred or alleged to have incurred under the provisions of this Act.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Transfer of Seized Resources.--The Secretary may transfer administration of seized paleontological resources to Federal or non-Federal educational institutions to be used for scientific or educational purposes.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 10. CONFIDENTIALITY.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Information concerning the nature and specific location of a paleontological resource the collection of which requires a permit under this Act or under any other provision of Federal law shall be exempt from disclosure under section 552 of title 5, United States Code, and any other law unless the Secretary determines that disclosure would--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) further the purposes of this Act;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) not create risk of harm to or theft or destruction of the resource or the site containing the resource; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) be in accordance with other applicable laws.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 11. REGULATIONS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; As soon as practical after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue such regulations as are appropriate to carry out this Act, providing opportunities for public notice and comment.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 12. SAVINGS PROVISIONS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Nothing in this Act shall be construed to--</paragraph>
    <paragraph> (1) invalidate, modify, or impose any additional restrictions or permitting requirements on any activities permitted at any time under the general mining laws, the mineral or geothermal leasing laws, laws providing for minerals materials disposal, or laws providing for the management or regulation of the activities authorized by the aforementioned laws including but not limited to the Federal Land Policy Management Act (43 U.S.C. 1701-1784), Public Law 94-429 (commonly known as the "Mining  in the Parks Act") (16 U.S.C. 1901 et seq.), the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 (30 U.S.C. 1201-1358), and the Organic Administration Act (16 U.S.C. 478, 482, 551);&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) invalidate, modify, or impose any additional restrictions or permitting requirements on any activities permitted at any time under existing laws and authorities relating to reclamation and multiple uses of Federal lands;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) apply to, or require a permit for, casual collecting of a rock, mineral, or invertebrate or plant fossil that is not protected under this Act;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) affect any lands other than Federal lands or affect the lawful recovery, collection, or sale of paleontological resources from lands other than Federal lands;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) alter or diminish the authority of a Federal agency under any other law to provide protection for paleontological resources on Federal lands in addition to the protection provided under this Act; or&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (6) create any right, privilege, benefit, or entitlement for any person who is not an officer or employee of the United States acting in that capacity. No person who is not an officer or employee of the United States acting in that capacity shall have standing to file any civil action in a court of the United States to enforce any provision or amendment made by this Act.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 13. AUTHORIZATION OF APPROPRIATIONS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this Act.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300037" topic="Introducing S. 322. A bill to establish an Indian youth telemental health demonstration project; to the Committee on Indian Affairs.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="322">S. 322</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to re-introduce legislation which would provide a first important step in dealing with the crisis of youth suicide in Indian Country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation I am introducing today is almost identical to legislation that the Senate passed in May, 2006, to establish an Indian youth telemental health demonstration project. The Indian Youth Telemental Health Demonstration Project Act of 2007 would authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to carry out a 4-year demonstration project under which five tribes and tribal organizations with telehealth capabilities could use telemental health services in youth suicide prevention,  intervention, and treatment. Demonstration project grantees would provide services through telemental health for such purposes as counseling of Indian youth; providing medical advice and other assistance to frontline tribal health providers; training for community members,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Committee on Indian Affairs held three hearings during the 109th Congress on the issue of Indian youth suicide, including one hearing that I convened in Bismarck, ND. Although on the Indian reservations of the northern Great Plains, the rate of Indian youth suicide is 10 times higher than it is anywhere else in the country, this tragic issue is not limited to these locations. The committee has heard testimony from people from tribal communities in Arizona, Oregon, Washington, Alaska, New  Mexico, and Wyoming, as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>According to 2004 statistics from the National Center for Injury Prevention and Control, suicide is the second leading cause of death, behind unintentional injury, for American Indian and Alaska Native young adults 15 to 24 years old, of both sexes--a statistic that has sadly been true for the past 20 years. For North Dakota Indian girls 15 to 24 years old in 2004, suicide was the number one leading cause of death.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am grateful for the efforts of the Indian Health Service and the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, in particular, both of which have, in a host of ways, sought to address the reservation youth suicide crisis. SAMHSA is providing a 4-year grant to the Standing Rock Sioux Tribe of North and South Dakota--a tribe that had 12 Indian youth die by suicide over a 6-month period--to provide mental health outreach workers. In addition, across the country, tribal leaders, tribal  health professionals, and service providers and family members are working together to implement early intervention plans, improve access to prevention programs, promote community training and awareness, and reinstate traditional tribal practices and culture-based interventions to address Native youth suicides.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many Indian reservations and Native villages in Alaska are remote and isolated, and everyone who lives in those communities experiences much more limited access to mental health services than in our Nation's metropolitan areas. The testimony received by the Indian Affairs Committee indicates that it is particularly in these remote Native communities that there is a crisis among the youth. I believe that the use of telemedicine--or, for purposes of this legislation, telemental health--will prove  a useful resource for the several tribes or tribal organizations that will participate in this demonstration project in assisting their youth.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to introducing this legislation, I will include authorization of this Indian Youth Telemental Health Demonstration Project in legislation to reauthorize and amend the Indian Health Care Improvement Act, which I intend to introduce soon.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank my colleagues who have joined me in sponsoring this legislation and in being willing to talk and think hard about an issue that many believe should be kept hidden. We must find ways to prevent the needless loss of young Native American boys and girls whose whole lives lie ahead of them, and from whom their tribal communities and all of this country stand to benefit as these youth blossom in to their potential as adults. I look forward to continuing our efforts to address this sensitive  and very important issue. I urge my colleagues to support this legislation. I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="Introducing S. 323. A bill to require persons seeking approval for a liquefied natural gas facility to identify employees and agents engaged in activities to persuade communities of the benefits of the approval; to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="323">S. 323</bill>] Mr. President, I rise to discuss liquified natural gas projects in California. As of August of last year, there are five potential liquified natural gas projects in California. The projects include the Cabrillo Deepwater Port LNG Facility, Clearwater Port LNG Project, Long Beach LNG Facility, Ocean Way LNG Terminal, and the Pacific Gateway LNG Facility.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>LNG is natural gas in its liquid form. When natural gas is cooled to minus 259 degrees Fahrenheit, it becomes a clear, colorless, odorless liquid. Natural gas is transferred into LNG to transport it more easily.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although there is a need for natural gas, there are potential safety concerns with the siting of new LNG facilities. According to the California Energy Commission, "LNG hazards result from three of its properties: cryogenic temperatures, dispersion characteristics, and flammability characteristics. The extremely cold LNG can directly cause injury or damage. A vapor cloud, formed by an LNG spill, could drift downwind into populated areas. It can ignite if the concentration of natural gas is between  five and 15 percent in air and it encounters an ignition source. An LNG fire gives off a tremendous amount of heat."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is why many people who live near a potential LNG facility have safety concerns. As a result, many companies try to "sell" the projects to communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is why today I am introducing this common sense bill. This bill is identical to legislation that I introduced in the 109th Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It would require any company seeking Federal Government approval to submit, as part or its application, the names of employees and business agents who are trying to persuade communities of the benefits of the LNG facility.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill does not stop anyone from reaching out to local communities. What this bill says is that if you are trying to get approval for an LNG facility, whether on- or off-shore, you have to be public about it. Today, if someone lobbies the federal government, he or she needs to register so their affiliation and interests before the government are publicly known. We should do the same for these projects. As I said, it is common sense.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this bill. I ask unanimous consent that the text of my bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300036" topic="Introducing S. 324. A bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a study of water resources in the State of New Mexico; to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="324">S. 324</bill>] Mr. President, above-average rainfall in New Mexico last summer and recent snow fall have led many to turn a blind eye to the grim water situation faced by our State only months ago. New Mexico was fast approaching a disaster due to drought. Many of our municipalities' wells were running dry and reservoirs were at dangerously low levels. Providence intervened, narrowly averting a crisis resulting from water scarcity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The development of the centrifugal pump was an event of great significance in the history of the West. Windmill driven pumps provided enough water for a family and several livestock. The centrifugal pump, on the other hand, was capable of pumping eight hundred gallons of water a minute, making possible the habitation of what was previously barren desert. To a large extent, this invention provided the water for growing towns and agricultural industry. However, it also resulted in a great dependence  on groundwater. As such, we need to fully understand the nature and extent of our groundwater resources. This bill will provide us with the information necessary to ensure that the water on which we have come to rely is available for years to come.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>During times of drought, when surface water is scarce, we must be able to reliably turn to groundwater reserves. Approximately 90 percent of New Mexicans depend on groundwater for drinking water and 77 percent of New Mexicans obtain water exclusively from groundwater sources. While groundwater supplies throughout the State are coming under increasing competition, not enough is known about these resources in order to make sound decisions regarding their use.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nearly 40 percent of the State's population resides in the Middle Rio Grande Basin. Once thought to contain vast quantities of water, we are now faced with the reality the Middle Rio Grande Basin contains far less water than originally thought. Between 1995 and 2001, the United States Geological Survey undertook a study of the Basin which added greatly to our knowledge regarding the primary source of water for our largest population center. Had we proceeded with our water planning without the  information provided by this study, I have little doubt that we would ultimately find ourselves in a dire situation. However, there is much more to be learned about this Basin.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Roughly 65 percent of the State's population lives along the Rio Grande. Also located along the river are the four largest cities in New Mexico: Santa Fe, Albuquerque, Rio Rancho and Las Cruces. While the completion of the San Juan-Chama Diversion by the Albuquerque Bernalillo County Water Utility Authority will allow the County of Bernalillo and City of Albuquerque to take advantage of their allocation of San JuanChama water, the remainder of the cities and counties located along the Rio Grande  will continue to receive the majority of their water from aquifers beneath the Rio Grande. Aside from the Middle Rio Grande Basin, we have limited knowledge of the amount of water contained in the aquifers below the Rio Grande, the rate at which they recharge, aquifer contamination, and the interaction between surface flows and ground water.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Elsewhere in the State, even less is understood regarding groundwater resources. While there is limited unallocated surface water in the State, there are significant quantities of untapped underground water in the Tularosa and Salt Basins. The Tularosa Basin is approximately 60 miles wide and 200 miles long. Making the conservative estimate that 10 percent of the water contained in that aquifer is available for use through desalination, it would provide 100 years of water for a city the size  of Albuquerque. With the development of desalination technology, I anticipate that even a greater amount of the brackish water contained in the Tularosa Basin will be available for human use.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Another untapped water supply is the Salt Basin located in southern New Mexico. The Basin lies in a geologically complex area and our understanding of the total resource is incomplete. However, initial estimates predict sustainable withdrawals on the order of 100,000 acre-feet per year of potable water from the New Mexico portion of the aquifer. This is enough water to support a city the size of our largest municipal area. Additional brackish resources in that Basin are highly likely. Because  the Basin is located near expanding metropolitan areas near the U.S.-Mexico Border, it is a resource of critical importance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill I introduce today would direct the United States Geological Survey, in collaboration with the State of New Mexico, to undertake a groundwater resources study in the State of New Mexico. A comprehensive study of the State's water resources is critical to effective water planning. Absent such a study, I fear that there is a significant likelihood that we may be depleting aquifers at an unsustainable rate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank Senator BINGAMAN for being an original co-sponsor of this legislation. I look forward to working with him to ensure the bill's passage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="Introducing S. 325. A bill to provide for innovation in heath care through State initiatives that expand coverage and access and improve quality and efficiency in the health care system; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="325">S. 325</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to introduce bipartisan legislation with Senator VOINOVICH entitled the "Health Partnership Act of 2007," which along with a companion House bill introduced by Representatives TAMMY BALDWIN, JOHN TIERNEY, and TOM PRICE, intends to set us on a path toward affordable, quality health care for all Americans. The Health Partnership Act creates partnerships between the Federal Government, State and local governments, tribes and tribal  organizations, private payers, and health care providers to seek innovation in health care systems.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under this Act, States, local governments, and tribes and tribal governments would be invited to submit applications to the Federal Government for funding to implement expansion and improvements to current health programs for review by a bipartisan "State Health Innovation Commission." Based on funding available through the Federal budget process, the Commission would approve a variety of reform options and innovative approaches.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This federalist approach to health reform would encourage a broad array of reform options subject to monitoring, to determine what is and is not successful. As Supreme Court Justice Louis D. Brandeis wrote in 1932, "It is one of the happy incidents of the federal system that a single courageous State may, if its citizens choose, serve as a laboratory; and try novel social and economic experiments without risk to the rest of the country."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our bipartisan legislation, the "Health Partnership Act," encourages  this type of State-based innovation and will help the Nation better address both the policy and the politics of health care reform. Currently, we do not have a "one-size-fits-all" model of reform, so encouraging States, local governments, and tribes to adopt a variety of approaches will help us better understand what may or may not work.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Inaction on the growing and related problems of the uninsured and increasing health care costs is unacceptable and unconscionable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In fact, while spending on health care in our country has reached $2 trillion annually, the number of uninsured has increased to nearly 47 million people, seven million more than in 2000. The consequences are staggering, as uninsured citizens get about half the medical care they need compared to those with health insurance and, according to the Institute of Medicine, about 18,000 unnecessary deaths occur each year in the U.S. because of lack of health insurance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While gridlock continues to permeate Washington, DC, in regards to this issue, a number of States and local governments are moving ahead with health reform. The "Health Partnership Act" would provide support, in the form of grants, to States, groups of States, local governments, and Indian tribes and tribal organizations to carry out any of a broad range of strategies intended to reduce the number of uninsured, reduce costs, and improve the quality of care.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Responding to urgent needs, State and local governments have not been able to wait for Federal action. We observed this in the early 1990s as States such as New Mexico, Massachusetts, Pennsylvania, Florida, Rhode Island, Hawaii, Maryland, Tennessee, Vermont, and Washington led the way to expanding coverage to children through the enactment of a variety of health reforms. Evaluation proved that some of these programs worked better than others, so the Federal Government took note and responded  in 1997 with passage of the "State Children's Health Insurance Program" or SCHIP. This legislation, built upon experiences of the States, enjoyed broad bipartisan support. SCHIP is a popular and successful State-based model that covers millions of children and continues to have broad-based bipartisan support across this Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, why not use that successful model and build upon it? In fact, State and local governments are already taking up that challenge and the Federal Government should, through the enactment of the "Health Partnership Act," do what it can to be helpful with those efforts. For example--</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On November 15, 2005, Illinois Governor Rod Blagojevich signed into law the "Covering All Kids Health Insurance Act" which, beginning in July 2006, intended to make insurance coverage available to all uninsured children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In April, Massachusetts Governor Mitt Romney signed into law legislation that requires all Bay State residents to have health insurance. Their State experiment involves partnerships between the State Medicaid, employer groups, and insurance companies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now California's Governor Schwarzenegger proposes health reform to include health promotion and wellness services for all, insurance coverage, and cost containment measures.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Other States, including New Mexico, Vermont, Tennessee, Maine, West Virginia, Oklahoma, and New York have enacted other health reforms that have had mixed success.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>All of these efforts add importantly to our knowledge base, and can then lead to a national solution to our uninsured and affordability crisis. We can learn from each and every one of these efforts, including those which failed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Commonwealth Fund President Karen Davis said it well by noting that State-based reforms, such as that passed in Massachusetts, are very good news. As she notes, "First, any substantive effort to expand access to coverage is worthwhile, given the growing number of uninsured in this country and the large body of evidence showing the dangerous health implications of lacking coverage."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>She adds, "But something more important is at work here. While we urgently need a national solution so that all Americans have insurance, it doesn't appear that we'll be getting one at the Federal level any time soon. So what Massachusetts has done potentially holds lessons for every State." I would add that it holds lessons for the Federal Government as well and not just for the mechanics of implementing health reform policy but also to the politics of health reform.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As she concludes, "One particularly cogent lesson is the manner in which the measure was crafted--via a civil process that successfully brought together numerous players from across the political business, health care delivery, and policy sectors."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator VOINOVICH and I have worked together and reached out to like minded colleagues in the House of Representatives via a process much like that described by Karen Davis. The legislation stems from past legislative efforts by Senators such as Bob Graham, Mark Hatfield, and Paul Wellstone, but also from work across ideological lines by Henry Aaron of the Brookings Institution and Stuart Butler of the Heritage Foundation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation also benefits from advice and support from health care providers. Dr. Tim Garson who, as Dean of the University of Virginia, brought a much needed provider perspective, ensuring support from the House of Medicine. Supporters include the American Medical Association, the American Academy of Pediatrics, the American College of Physicians, the American College of Cardiology, American Gastroenterological Association, the Visiting Nurses Association, the National Association of Community  Health Centers, and from state-based health providers such as the New Mexico Medical Society and Ohio Association of Community Health Centers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Health Partnership Act supports providers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Health Partnership Act received much comment and support from consumer-based groups advocating for national health reform, including that by Dr. Ken Frisof of the Universal Health Care Action Network, Bill Vaughan at Consumers Union, and from numerous health care advocates in New Mexico, including Community Action New Mexico, Health Action New Mexico, Health Care for All Campaign of New Mexico, New Mexico Center on Law and Poverty, New Mexico Health Choices Initiative, New Mexico POZ Coalition,  New Mexico Public Health Association, New Mexico Religious Coalition for Reproductive Choice, New Mexico Progressive Alliance for Community Empowerment, and the Health Security for New Mexicans Campaign, which includes 115 State-based organizations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Health Partnership Act supports consumers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Support from stakeholders throughout our Nation's health care system has been sought and I would like to thank the many organizations from New Mexico for their support and input to this legislation. There is great urgency in New Mexico because our State, like all of those along the U.S.-Mexico border, faces a severe health care crisis. Over one in five New Mexicans does not have insurance coverage. In fact, only one State, Texas, has more uninsured. New Mexico is also the only State in the country  with greater than half of its population covered by State or federally funded health programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A rather shocking statistic, which also continues to worsen, is that one out of every three Hispanic citizens are uninsured. In fact, less than 41 percent of the Hispanic population now has employer-based coverage nationwide, which is in sharp comparison to the 66 percent of non-Hispanic whites who have employer-based coverage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because so few New Mexicans have employer-based health insurance, the State of New Mexico has enacted its own health reform plan called the State Coverage Initiative, or SCI, in July 2005. SCI is a public/private partnership intended to expand employer-sponsored insurance, developed in part with grant funding from the Robert Wood Johnson Foundation. As of December 2006, there were 4,256 people covered by this initiative and there are efforts to expand this effort to cover over 20,000 individuals.  With Federal support for my State, the hope would be to further expand coverage to as many New Mexicans as possible.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Health Partnership Act encourages reforms at both the state and local levels of government. Senator VOINOVICH, as former mayor of Cleveland, suggested language that would capture community-based efforts as well. Illinois, Georgia, Michigan, and  Oregon have all initiated efforts at the local level for reform, including so-called "three-share" programs in Illinois and Michigan. Under these initiatives, employers, employees, and the community  each pick up about one-third of the cost of programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Jeaneane Smith, deputy administrator in the Office of Oregon Health Policy and Research was recently quoted by an Academy Health publication stating, "In recent years it has become apparent that there is a need to consider both state- and community-level approaches to improved access. We want to learn how best to support communities as they play an integral part in addressing the gaps in coverage."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Health Partnership Act supports communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our hope is to spawn innovation. Brookings Institution senior health fellow Henry Aaron and Heritage Foundation vice president Stuart Butler wrote a Health Affairs article in March 2004 that lays out the foundation for this legislative effort. They argue that while we remain unable to reconcile how best to expand coverage at the Federal level, we can agree to support states in their efforts to try widely differing solutions to health coverage, cost containment, and quality improvement. As they  write, "this approach offers both a way to improve knowledge about how to reform health care and a practical way to initiate a process of reform. Such a pluralist approach respects the real, abiding differences in politics, preferences, traditions, and institutions</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to Dr. Garson, Mr. Aaron, Mr. Butler, and Dr. Frisof, I would like to express my appreciation to Dan Hawkins at the National Association of Community Health Centers, Bill Vaughan at Consumers Union, and both Jack Meyer and Stan Dorn at ESRI for their counsel and guidance on health reform and this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would also like to commend the American College of Physicians, or ACP, for their outstanding leadership on the issue of the uninsured and for their willingness to support a variety of efforts to expand health coverage. ACP has been a longstanding advocate for expanding health coverage and has authored landmark reports on the important role that health insurance has in reducing people's morbidity and mortality. In fact, to cite the conclusion of one of those studies, "Lack of insurance contributes  to the endangerment of the health of each uninsured American as well as the collective health of the Nation."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And finally, I would also thank the many people at the Robert Wood Johnson Foundation on their forethought and knowledge on all the issues confronting the uninsured. Their efforts to continue the dialogue on the uninsured has successfully kept the issue alive for many years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to break the gridlock and support this legislation, which offers financial support to states, communities, providers, and consumers, as they adopt important innovations in healthcare coverage and expansion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300098" topic="Introducing S. 325. A bill to provide for innovation in heath care through State initiatives that expand coverage and access and improve quality and efficiency in the health care system; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise to speak about a bill my colleague Senator BINGAMAN and I introduced today, the Health Care Partnership Act. For too many years, I have listened to my colleagues on both sides of the aisle talk about the rising cost of health care and the growing number of uninsured Americans. Yet, at the Federal level we have made little progress toward a solution for improving access to quality, affordable health care. I believe it is the greatest domestic challenge  facing our Nation. In fact, the rising cost of health care is a major part of what is hurting our competitiveness in the global marketplace.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While surveys have indicated that health insurance premiums have stabilized--a 9.2 percent increase in 2006 the same increase as in 2005 and compared with; 12.3 percent in 2004; 14.7 percent in 2003 and 15.2 percent in 2002--health insurance costs continue to be a significant factor impacting American competitiveness. In addition, the share of costs that individuals have paid for employer sponsored insurance has risen roughly 2 percent each year, from 31.4 percent of health care costs in 2001  to 38.4 percent this year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In fact, spending on health care in the United States reached $2 trillion in 2005--16 percent of our GDP--the largest share ever.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Yet, despite all the spending some 45 million Americans--15 percent of the population--had no health insurance at some point last year. This number has increased steadily. In 2000, that number was 39.8 million. In 2002 it was 43.6 million.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These statistics are startling, and it is beyond time that we do something about them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill Senator BINGAMAN and I are introducing today aims to break the log-jam here in Washington and allows States to experiment the way we did with welfare reform when I was Governor of Ohio. This bill would support State-based efforts to reduce the uninsured, reduce costs, improve quality, improve access to care, and expand information technology.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have been in this situation before. As Governor of Ohio, I had to work creatively to expand coverage and deal with increasing health care costs for a growing number of uninsured Ohioans. I am happy to report that we were able to make some progress toward reducing the number of uninsured during my time as the head of the State by negotiating with the State unions to move to managed care; by controlling Medicaid costs to the point where from 1995 to 1998, due to good stewardship and management,  Ohio ended up under-spending on Medicaid without harming families; and implementing the S-CHIP program to provide coverage for uninsured children. In fact, I recently learned from the Cuyahoga Commissioners that in our county, 98 percent of eligible children are currently enrolled in this program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Like we did in Ohio, a number of States are already actively pursuing efforts to reduce the number of their residents who lack adequate health care coverage. This bill will build on the goals of States like Massachusetts, California and others, while providing a mechanism to analyze results and make recommendations for future action on the Federal level.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under the Health Partnership Act, Congress would authorize grants to individual States, groups of States, and Indian tribes and organizations to carry out any of a broad range of strategies to improve our Nation's health  care delivery. The bill creates a mechanism for States to apply for grants to a bipartisan "State Health Innovation Commission" housed at the Department of Health and Human Services, HHS. After reviewing the State proposals, the Commission  would submit to Congress a list of recommended State applications. The Commission would also recommend the amount of Federal grant money each State should receive to carry out the actions described in their plan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Most importantly, at the end of the 5-year period, the Commission would be required to report to Congress whether the States are meeting the goals of the act and recommend future action Congress should take concerning overall reform, including whether or not to extend the program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe it is important that we pass this legislation and provide a platform from which we can have a thoughtful conversation about health care reform at the Federal level.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since I have been in the Senate, Congress has made some progress toward improving health care, most notably for our 43 million seniors with the passage of the Medicare Modernization Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Yet, we have been at this too long here in Washington without comprehensive, meaningful results. It is my hope that we will have bipartisan support for this very bipartisan comprehensive bill that I hope will move us closer toward a solution to the uninsured.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300068" topic="Introducing S. 326. A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a special period of limitation when uniformed services retirement pay is reduced as result of award of disability compensation; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="326">S. 326</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today with my colleague, Senator CRAIG THOMAS, to introduce the Disabled Veterans Tax Fairness Act of 2007. This much-needed legislation would protect disabled veterans from being unfairly taxed on the benefits to which they are entitled, simply because their disability claims were not processed in a timely manner. This legislation is supported by the Military Coalition, a group representing more than 5.5 million members of the uniformed services and  their families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While the Department of Veterans Affairs, VA, resolves most of its filed disability claims in less than a year, there are also instances of lost paperwork, administrative errors, and appeals of rejected claims that often delay thousands of disability awards for years on end. When this occurs, disability compensation is awarded retroactively and for tax purposes, a disabled veteran's previously received taxable military retiree pay is re-designated as nontaxable disability compensation. Thereby,  the disabled veteran is entitled to a refund of taxes paid and must file an amended tax return for each applicable year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, under current law the IRS Code bars the filing of amended returns beyond the last 3 tax years. As a result, many of our disabled veterans are denied the opportunity to file a claim for repayment of additional years of back taxes already paid--through no fault of their own--even though the IRS owes them a refund for the taxes that were originally paid on their retiree pay.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Disabled Veterans Tax Fairness Act of 2007 would add an exception to the IRS statute of limitations for amending returns. This exception would allow disabled veterans whose disability claims have been pending for more than 3 years to receive refunds on previous taxes paid for up to 5 years--the length of time the IRS keeps these records. Affected veterans would have 1 year from the date the VA determination is issued to go back and amend previous years' tax returns.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My father and grandfather both served our Nation in uniform and they taught me from an early age about the sacrifices our troops and their families have made to keep our Nation free. This is particularly true for our disabled veterans. During a time when a grateful nation should be doing everything it can to honor those who have sacrificed so greatly on our behalf, the very least it can do is ensure they and their families are not unjustly penalized simply because of bureaucratic inefficiencies  or administrative delays which are beyond their control. This situation is unacceptable and our veterans deserve better.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is why I am proud to reintroduce this legislation today to provide relief to our Nation's veterans. It is the least we can do for those whom we owe so much, and it is the least we can do to reassure future generations that a grateful nation will not forget them when their military service is complete.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300071" topic="Introducing S. 327. A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a special resource study of sites associated with the life of Cesar Estrada Chavez and the farm labor movement; to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="327">S. 327</bill>] Mr. President, I am pleased to be joined today by Senator Salazar in reintroducing the Cesar Estrada Chavez Study Act. A similar version of this bill was introduced by Congresswoman Hilda Solis last week. This legislation, which is identical to the bill we introduced in the 109th Congress and passed the Senate by unanimous consent during the 108th Congress, would authorize the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a special resource study of sites associated with  the life of Cesar Chavez. The bill would direct the Secretary of the Interior to determine whether any of the sites significant to Chavez's life meet the criteria for being listed on the National Register of Historic Landmarks. The goal of this legislation is to establish a foundation for future legislation that would then designate land for the appropriate sites to become historic landmarks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Chavez's legacy is an inspiration to us all and he will be remembered for helping Americans to transcend distinctions of experience and share equally in the rights and responsibilities of freedom. It is important that we honor his struggle and do what we can to preserve appropriate landmarks that are significant to his life. This legislation has received an overwhelming positive response, not only from my fellow Arizonans, but from Americans all across the Nation. It has also received an  endorsement from the Congressional Hispanic Caucus.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Cesar Chavez, an Arizonan born in Yuma, was the son of migrant farm workers. While his formal education ended in the eighth grade, his insatiable intellectual curiosity and determination helped make him known as one of the great American leaders for his successes in ensuring migrant farm workers were treated fairly and honestly. His efforts on behalf of some of the most oppressed individuals in our society is an inspiration, and through his work he made America a bigger and better nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While Chavez and his family migrated across the southwest looking for farm work, he evolved into a advocate of migrant farm workers. He founded the National Farm Workers Association in 1962, which later became the United Farm Workers of America. He gave a voice to those who had no voice. In his words, "We cannot seek achievement for ourselves and forget about progress and prosperity for our community ..... our ambitions must be broad enough to include the aspirations and needs of others, for  their sakes and for our own."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Cesar Chavez was a humble man of deep conviction who understood what it meant to serve and sacrifice for others. His motto in life "It Can Be Done," epitomizes his life's work and continues to be a positive influence on so many of us. Honoring the places of his life will enable his legacy to inspire and serve as an example for our future leaders.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
