<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1185336000" ordinal="42" title="NOTICES OF HEARINGS">
  <narrative>NOTICES OF HEARINGS -- (Senate - July 25, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="9982">S9982</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300060" topic="COMMITTEE ON SMALL BUSINESS AND ENTREPRENEURSHIP">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to inform the Members that the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship will hold a staff-led public roundtable entitled "Reauthorization of the Small Business Innovation Research Programs: National Academies' Findings and Recommendations," on August 1, 2007, at 10 a.m. in room 428A of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON WATER AND POWER">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to announce for the information of the Senate and the public that a hearing has been scheduled before the Subcommittee on Water and Power of the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. The hearing will be held on August 1, 2007, at 2:30 p.m., in room 366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building in Washington, DC.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the hearing is to receive testimony on the following bills: <bill type="s" number="1054">S. 1054</bill> and <bill type="h" number="122">H.R. 122</bill>, to amend the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to participate in the Inland Empire regional recycling project and in the Cucamonga Valley Water District recycling project; <bill type="s" number="1472">S. 1472</bill>, to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to create a Bureau of Reclamation partnership with the North Bay Water Reuse Authority and other regional  partners to achieve objectives relating to water supply, water quality, and environmental restoration; <bill type="s" number="1475">S. 1475</bill> and <bill type="h" number="1526">H.R. 1526</bill>, to amend the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Bay Area Regional Water Recycling Program, and for other purposes; <bill type="h" number="30">H.R. 30</bill>, to amend the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act  to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to participate in the Eastern Municipal Water District</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of the limited time available for the hearing, witnesses may testify by invitation only. However, those wishing to submit written testimony for the hearing record should send it to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, United States Senate, Washington, DC 20510-6150, or by email to: Gina Weinstock@energy.senate.gov.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For further information, please contact Michael Connor at (202) 224-5479 or Gina Weinstock at (202) 224-5684.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
