<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1202749203" ordinal="15" title="FISA AMENDMENTS ACT OF 2007--Continued">
  <narrative>FISA AMENDMENTS ACT OF 2007--Continued -- (Senate - February 11, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="845">S845</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate resume consideration of <bill type="s" number="2248">S. 2248</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I just finished a conference with the distinguished Republican leader, and we both believe this is the best way to go. We will, at some time, finish the intelligence conference report one way or the other, and following that, we will likely move to the Indian health bill to try to complete that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have had a productive day. It is my understanding there are only two speakers left on the FISA legislation, and that is Senator Dodd and Senator Specter. If there are others, they should notify the cloakroom forthwith.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have eight votes we are going to do tomorrow, and staff is working on a consent to get to those votes. If we finish them, regardless, it would be better if we do this by consent. We are going to start the votes early in the morning. There will be no morning business tomorrow. We have eight votes to do tomorrow and complete a lot of talk on this bill, and that way we can send it to the House very quickly and they will come back and tell us something, we hope, by the end of the week.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We all hope it is not necessary that we have an extension, but time will tell.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <chair>The legislative clerk proceeded to call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that when the Senate resumes <bill type="s" number="2248">S. 2248</bill> on Tuesday morning, February 12, the sequence of votes on remaining amendments occur in the following order: Whitehouse 3920, subject to a 60-vote threshold; Feinstein 3910, subject to a 60-vote threshold; Feingold 3979; Dodd 3907; Feingold 3912; Bond-Rockefeller 3938, as modified; Specter-Whitehouse 3927; Feinstein 3919, with a 60-vote threshold; and that each leader control a total of 10 minutes of debate  time to be used prior to any of the votes; that the provisions of the previous order governing debate limitations and vote limitations remain in effect.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are going to do as many of these as we can before the weekly party conferences. With a little bit of luck, we can finish all of them.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <chair>The legislative clerk proceeded to call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
