<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1222444802" ordinal="50" title="NATIONAL BIBLE WEEK 2008">
  <narrative>NATIONAL BIBLE WEEK 2008 -- (Senate - September 26, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="9620">S9620</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today to celebrate one of the most significant books in human history, the Bible. As Senate cochair of National Bible Week 2008, it is my honor to join the National Bible Association in promoting the nationwide recognition of the Bible's importance in our daily lives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One of the many important verses in the Bible that applies to us as leaders is found in Proverbs 21, verse 1:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The king's heart is in the hand of the Lord. Like the rivers of water, He turns it wherever He wishes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our Nation has always recognized the power of an unseen hand guiding our fortunes and destiny, and during this important and critical crossroads, our Nation will do well to turn once again to the Bible for strength.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This year, from November 23 to November 30, communities, churches, and leaders across America will celebrate National Bible Week by reading and reflecting on the Bible's teachings and how it can help us lead better lives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is our responsibility as leaders to remind all Americans of the importance of the Bible to individuals and to our history, life, and the culture of our Nation. We gain much inspiration from the Scriptures, and the light of God will shine through us if we hold fast to the Bible's principles and apply them to our daily lives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I join my voice with my fellow National Bible Week cochair, Todd Akin, and the National Bible Week chairman, J. Willard Marriott, Jr., in urging all Americans to celebrate National Bible Week 2008.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300021" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I join with my colleague from Hawaii in celebrating National Bible Week. I get together every Wednesday morning with a group of our colleagues for our weekly prayer breakfast, and he is always such an inspiration. He is our song leader while we do, except for he and the Chaplain, some of the worst singing that can be done. He is a great inspiration for all of us, and I commend him for bringing this resolution forward.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
