<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1193846401" ordinal="29" title="RECOGNIZING MAJOR GENERAL HARRY B. BURCHSTEAD, JR.">
  <narrative>RECOGNIZING MAJOR GENERAL HARRY B. BURCHSTEAD, JR. -- (Senate - October 31, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="13622">S13622</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300047" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today I ask the Senate to join me in recognizing Major General Harry B. Burchstead, Jr. on the occasion of his retirement from the South Carolina Army National Guard. Since entering the United States Army as a commissioned officer through the ROTC program at Clemson University, General Burchstead has remained a dedicated serviceman for his entire career. Immediately after his graduation from Clemson, General Burchstead loyally answered his call of duty and deployed  for combat service in the Vietnam War.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After leaving active duty in 1971, General Burchstead went on to pursue his law degree at the University of South Carolina. While in law school, General Burchstead continued his military service by joining the South Carolina Army National Guard in 1972. For the next thirty-five years, General Burchstead proudly served the State of South Carolina as a traditional citizen soldier through many levels of military service.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1997, General Burchstead was appointed to serve as the Deputy Adjutant General of South Carolina. In this capacity, he was critical in advising the Adjutant General's oversight of the South Carolina Army and Air National Guard. For six years, General Burchstead's strategic and diligent counsel was integral to the effective military operations of our state's full-time servicemen and women.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a distinguished leader, General Burchstead was selected to command the 263rd Army Air and Missile Defense Command in 2003. In his role as Commander, General Burchstead led Joint Task Force Cobra in its execution of the Juniper-Cobra Missile Defense Exercise in Israel. Additionally, General Burchstead was successful in commanding the Joint Project Optical Windmill Air and Missile Defense Exercise in Europe, as well as the U.S.-Russian Federation Missile Defense Exercise at Fort Bliss, Texas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A dedicated patriot, General Burchstead formally retired from the South Carolina Army National Guard on September 30th, 2007. Over his thirty-five years of service General Burchstead has amassed numerous awards and decorations including the Legion of Merit, the Bronze Star Medal with two oak leaf clusters, the Purple Heart, the U.S. Meritorious Service Medal and the Army Commendation Medal. His military career will be forever marked by his selfless devotion and sacrifice to both our country and  the State of South Carolina. I wish General Burchstead the very best in his retirement and ask that the United States Senate join me in thanking him for his lifelong career of service.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
