<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1204131603" ordinal="46" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <narrative>AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET -- (Senate - February 27, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="1273">S1273</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="COMMITTEE ON ARMED SERVICES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, February 27, 2008, at 9:30 a.m., in open session, and possibly closed session, to receive testimony on the current and future worldwide threats to the national security of the United States.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, February 27, 2008, at 2:30 p.m., in room 253 of the Russell  Senate Office Building, in order to conduct a hearing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The hearing will focus on the National Aeronautics and Space Administration's fiscal year 2009 budget proposal.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND NATURAL RESOURCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate in order to conduct a hearing on Wednesday, February 27, 2008, at 9:45 a.m., in room SD366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building. At this hearing, the Committee will hear testimony to consider two nominations: Stanley C. Suboleski, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Secretary of Energy (Fossil Energy), vice Jeffrey D. Jarrett, resigned; and,  J. Gregory Copeland, of Texas, to be General Counsel of the Department of Energy, vice David R. Hill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENVIRONMENT AND PUBLIC WORKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Environment and Public Works be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, February 27, 2008 at 10:00 a.m. in room 406 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building in order to conduct a hearing entitled, "Hearing on the President's Proposed EPA Budget for FY 2009."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="COMMITTEE ON HEALTH, EDUCATION, LABOR, AND PENSIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions be authorized to meet in executive session during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, February 27, 2008 at 10 a.m. in SD-430.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="579">S. 579</bill>, Breast Cancer and Environmental Research Act of 2007; <bill type="s" number="1810">S. 1810</bill>, Prenatally and Postnatally Diagnosed Conditions Awareness Act; <bill type="s" number="999">S. 999</bill>, Stroke Treatment and Ongoing Prevention Act of 2007; <bill type="s" number="1760">S. 1760</bill>, Healthy Start Reauthorization Act of 2007; <bill type="h" number="20">H.R. 20</bill>, Melanie Blocker-Stokes Postpartum Depression Research and Care Act; and <bill type="s" number="1042">S. 1042</bill>, Consistency, Accuracy, Responsibility, and Excellence in Medical Imaging and Radiation Therapy Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>National Board for Education Sciences: Jonathan Baron, Frank Handy, Sally Shaywitz.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>National Foundation on the Arts and Humanities: Jamsheed Choksy, Gary Glenn, David Hertz, Marvin Scott, Carol Swain.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>National Museum and Library Science Board: Julia Bland, Jan Cellucci, William Hagenah, Mark Herring,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Truman Scholarship Foundation: Javaid Anwar, and Assistant Secretary of Labor ODEP: Neil Romano.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="COMMITTEE ON HOMELAND SECURITY AND GOVERNMENTAL AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, February 27, 2008, at 10 a.m. in order to conduct a hearing entitled "An Uneasy Relationship: U.S. Reliance on Private Security Firms in Overseas Operations."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="COMMITTEE ON INDIAN AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Indian Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, February 27, at 9:30 a.m. in room 485 of the Russell Senate Office Building in order to conduct a hearing on <bill type="s" number="2232">S. 2232</bill>, the Foreign Aid Lessons for Domestic Economic Assistance Act of 2007.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate, in order to conduct a hearing entitled "The False Claims Act Correction Act (<bill type="s" number="2041">S. 2041</bill>): Strengthening the Government's Most Effective Tool Against Fraud for the 21st Century" on Wednesday, February 27, 2008 at 10 a.m. in room SD-226 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Michael F. Hertz, Deputy Assistant Attorney General, Civil Division, U.S. Department of Justice, Washington, DC.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Panel II: Tina M. Gonter, Jacksonville, FL; The Honorable John E. Clark, Of Counsel, Goode, Casseb, Jones, Riklin, Choate &amp; Watson, P.C., San Antonio, TX; John T. Boese, Partner, Fried, Frank, Harris, Shriver &amp; Jacobson LLP, Washington, DC; and Pamela H. Bucy, Bainbridge Professor of Law, University of Alabama School of Law, Tuscaloosa, AL.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="COMMITTEE ON RULES AND ADMINISTRATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Rules and Administration be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, February 27, 2008, at 10:00 a.m., in order to hear testimony on Protecting Voters at Home and at the Polls: Limiting Abusive Robocalls and Vote Caging Practices.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="COMMITTEE ON SMALL BUSINESS AND ENTREPRENEURSHIP">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate in order to conduct a hearing entitled "The President's FY2009 Budget Request for the Small Business Administration on Wednesday, February 27, 2008, beginning at 10:00 a.m., in room 428A of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="COMMITTEE ON VETERANS' AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent for the Committee on Veterans' Affairs to be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, February 27, 2008, in order to conduct an oversight hearing entitled "Review of Veterans' Disability Compensation: Expert Reports on PTSD and other issues." The Committee will meet in room 216 of the Hart Senate Office Building, at 9:30 a.m.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="PERSONNEL SUBCOMMITTEE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Personnel Subcommittee of the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, February 27, 2008, at 3:00 p.m., in open session to receive testimony on active component, reserve component, and civilian personnel programs in review of the defense authorization request for Fiscal Year 2009 and the Future Years Defense Program.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair> SELECT COMMITTEE ON INTELLIGENCE</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="PERSONNEL SUBCOMMITTEE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Select Committee on Intelligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on February 27, 2008, at 2:30 p.m. in order to hold a closed business meeting.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair> SUBCOMMITTEE ON CRIME AND DRUGS</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="PERSONNEL SUBCOMMITTEE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate Committee on the Judiciary, Subcommittee on Crime and Drugs, be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate, in order to conduct a hearing entitled "Supporting the Front Line in the Fight Against Crime: Restoring Federal Funding for State and Local Law Enforcement" on Wednesday, February 27, 2008 at 2 p.m. in the Dirksen Senate Office Building, Room 226.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair> SUBCOMMITTEE ON PUBLIC LANDS AND FORESTS</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="PERSONNEL SUBCOMMITTEE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests of the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources be authorized to  meet during the session of the Senate in order to conduct a hearing on Wednesday, February 27, 2008, at 2:30 p.m., in room SD366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building. At this hearing, the Committee will hear testimony regarding the following legislation:</paragraph>
    <paragraph> <bill type="s" number="832">S. 832</bill>, to provide for the sale of approximately 25 acres of public land to the Turnabout Ranch, Escalante, Utah, at fair market value;</paragraph>
    <paragraph> <bill type="s" number="2229">S. 2229</bill>, to withdraw certain Federal land in the Wyoming Range from leasing and provide an opportunity to retire certain leases in the Wyoming Range;</paragraph>
    <paragraph> <bill type="s" number="2379">S. 2379</bill>, to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to cancel certain grazing leases on land in Cascade-Siskiyou National Monument that are voluntarily waived by the lessees, to provide for the exchange of certain Monument land in exchange for private land, to designate certain Monument land as wilderness, and for other purposes;</paragraph>
    <paragraph> <bill type="s" number="2508">S. 2508</bill> and <bill type="h" number="903">H.R. 903</bill>, to provide for a study of options for protecting the open space characteristics of certain lands in and adjacent to the Arapaho and Roosevelt National Forests in Colorado, and for other purposes;</paragraph>
    <paragraph> <bill type="s" number="2601">S. 2601</bill> and <bill type="h" number="1285">H.R. 1285</bill>, to provide for the conveyance of a parcel of National Forest System land in Kittitas County, Washington, to facilitate the construction of a new fire and rescue station, and for other purposes;</paragraph>
    <paragraph> <bill type="h" number="523">H.R. 523</bill>, to require the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain. public land located wholly or partially within the boundaries of the Wells Hydroelectric Project of Public Utility District No. 1 of Douglas County, Washington, to the utility district;</paragraph>
    <paragraph> <bill type="h" number="838">H.R. 838</bill>, to provide for the conveyance of the Bureau of Land Management parcels known as the White Acre and Gambel Oak properties and related real property to Park City, Utah, and for other purposes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="SPECIAL COMMITTEE ON AGING">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Special Committee on Aging be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, February 27, 2008 from 10:30 a.m.-12:30 p.m. In Dirksen 628 for the purpose of conducting a hearing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph> The PRESIDING, OFFICER. Without objection, it is so ordered.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
