<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1183132832" ordinal="29" title="SUBMITTED RESOLUTIONS">
  <speaking speaker="300021" topic="SENATE RESOLUTION 262--DESIGNATING JULY 2007 AS &quot;NATIONAL WATERMELON MONTH&quot;">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today to introduce a resolution that will recognize July 2007 as "National Watermelon Month." Watermelon production is a vital part of our Nation's agricultural sector and this resolution recognizes that fact.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>According to statistics released by the National Agricultural Statistics Service of the U.S. Department of Agriculture in January 2006, the United States produces 4,200,000,000 pounds of watermelon annually. This amount of annual production is remarkable when you consider the number of actual watermelons it represents. Watermelon varieties range in size from 5 pounds to over 40 pounds, so the number produced, consumed, and exported each year is truly amazing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Research has shown that the inclusion of fruits and vegetables in our diets is vitally important for a healthy lifestyle. Evidence indicates that eating between 2 1/2  and 5 cups of fruits and vegetables everyday will improve health and protect against many of the diseases, especially those influenced by diet, that afflict our Nation. Watermelon provides many of the vitamins, fiber and nutrients which help prevent many of these diseases. Watermelon is also a good source of lycopene, an antioxidant  that has been shown to reduce the risk of certain cancers. The health benefits associated with watermelon are so outstanding that the American Heart Association has certified watermelon as a heart-healthy food, thereby qualifying it for the heart-check certification mark.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I cannot address this body without mentioning the importance of the watermelon to my home State of Georgia. The University of Georgia College of Agricultural and Environmental Sciences Center for Agribusiness and  Economic Development recently released its 2006 Georgia Farm Gate Value Report. Watermelon ranked 16th among all Georgia commodities with a farm gate value of a little over $111 million from almost 24,000 acres of watermelon. I am also proud  to represent Cordele, Georgia, which is known as the, "Watermelon Capital of the World."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Recognizing July as "National Watermelon Month" will provide the watermelon industry with many avenues to not only market their product but also educate the public about the health benefits associated with consuming watermelon through different watermelon related programs and activities. Watermelon enjoys a long history as one of our Nation's favorite foods. As Mark Twain once said, "When one has tasted watermelon he knows what the angels eat." I encourage my colleagues to join me in acknowledging  the wisdom of Mark Twain by supporting this resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
