<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1172595604" ordinal="25" title="TRIBUTE TO W. DON NELSON">
  <speaking speaker="300077" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today to express my best wishes and appreciation to a staff member who is leaving my office after many years of public service.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>W. Don Nelson has served with distinction as my State director in Lincoln, NE, since I was elected in 2000, which is no small job in a State that stretches 500 miles.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although we share the same last name, we do not share a family relationship. We do share a passion for public service. W. Don, as he is known throughout Nebraska, has a long history of bipartisan government service at the highest levels.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Nelson worked for former Congressman Douglas Bereuter when he was director of the Nebraska State Office of Planning and Programming. He also served as a chief policy adviser for former Nebraska Governors Norbert Tiemann, Jim Exon, and former Wyoming Governor Ed Herschler and was chief of staff for Nebraska Governor Bob Kerrey. Before Don became my State director he was in the private sector serving as managing director for the Nebraska office of a major national securities firm.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To say that W. Don Nelson was an important and vital part of the staff for those of us whom he served is an understatement. His background as a lawyer and investment banker made him invaluable in government service but his abilities stretched far beyond that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>W. Don Nelson is one of the most fiercely loyal and completely trustworthy individuals I have ever had the privilege to know. His intellect and depth of knowledge on virtually any issue is uncanny. He has the courage to confront adversaries at the highest levels and the compassion to help those who are less fortunate. He is a gracious host and gentleman to friends, and a devoted father and husband to a loving family.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>W. Don may be retiring but not to a rocking chair. The W. Don Nelson that so many Nebraskans know will never sit back and rest on his laurels. His so-called retirement will be in front of a computer screen and stalking the halls of government buildings visiting with elected and appointed officials from the other side of the desk, as a reporter.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After answering questions from reporters for much of his career, he will be asking the questions. He is crossing over to start his own newspaper, called Prairie Fire, in Lincoln, NE. Its objective is to be the progressive voice of the Great Plains offering thoughtful, bipartisan public discourse about all matters relating to politics and the arts and, I imagine, Don's passion, the environment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>All of us will miss Don, his quirky sense of humor, his vintage neckties, his sports cars, and even his outward display of pride in Cornhusker Country for his alma maters, the University of Florida and Florida State University.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We wish him every success in his new role as editor, publisher, and writer.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
