<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1191513602" ordinal="31" title="BUDGET SCOREKEEPING REPORT">
  <narrative>BUDGET SCOREKEEPING REPORT -- (Senate - October 04, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="12765">S12765</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300026" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I wish to submit to the Senate the budget scorekeeping report for fiscal year 2007 prepared by the Congressional Budget Office pursuant to section 308(b) and in aid of section 311 of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974, as amended. This is my final report for fiscal year 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This report shows the effects of Congressional action through October 1, 2007. Since my last report, dated July 26, 2007, the Congress has cleared and the President has signed Public Law 110-84, the Higher Education Access Act of 2007. The estimates of budget authority, outlays, and revenues used in this report are consistent with the technical and economic assumptions of <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>, the 2008 budget resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The estimates show that current level spending equals the budget resolution for both budget authority and outlays while current level revenues exceed the budget resolution by $4.2 billion. I want to commend the Congress for not exceeding the limits set in the 2008 budget resolution for fiscal year 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the letter and accompanying tables from CBO be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>CONGRESSIONAL BUDGET OFFICE,</narrative>
  <narrative>U.S. CONGRESS,</narrative>
  <narrative>Washington, DC, October 3, 2007.</narrative>
  <narrative>DEAR MR. CHAIRMAN: The enclosed report shows the effects of Congressional action on the fiscal year 2007 budget and is current through October 1, 2007. This report is submitted under section 308(b) and in aid of section 311 of the Congressional Budget Act, as amended.</narrative>
  <narrative>The estimates of budget authority, outlays, and revenues are consistent with the technical and economic assumptions of <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>, the Concurrent Resolution on the Budget for Fiscal Year 2008, as approved by the Senate and the House of Representatives.</narrative>
  <narrative>Pursuant to section 204(a) of <bill type="sc" number="21">S. Con. Res. 21</bill>, provisions designated as emergency requirements are exempt from enforcement of the budget resolution. As a result, the enclosed current level report excludes these amounts (see footnote 1 of Table 2 of the report).</narrative>
  <narrative>Since my last letter, dated July 26, 2007, the Congress has cleared and the President has signed the Higher Education Access Act of 2007 (Public Law 110-84), which affects budget authority and outlays.</narrative>
  <narrative>The effects of that action are detailed on Table 2.</narrative>
  <narrative>Sincerely,</narrative>
  <narrative>Peter R. Orszag,</narrative>
</record>
