<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1222444802" ordinal="131" title="AUTHORIZING THE PRINTING OF A REVISED EDITION OF THE SENATE RULES AND MANUAL">
  <narrative>AUTHORIZING THE PRINTING OF A REVISED EDITION OF THE SENATE RULES AND MANUAL -- (Senate - September 26, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="9867">S9867</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412247" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of <bill type="sr" number="689">S. Res. 689</bill> which was submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="689">S. Res. 689</bill>) to authorize the printing of a revised edition of the Senate Rules and Manual.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412247" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table, and that any statements related to this item be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="689">S. Res. 689</bill>) was agreed to, as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="689">S. Res. 689</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair> Resolved, That--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) the Committee on Rules and Administration shall prepare a revised edition of the Senate Rules and Manual for the use of the 110th Congress;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) the manual shall be printed as a Senate document; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) in addition to the usual number of documents, 1,500 additional copies of the manual shall be bound, of which--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) 500 paperbound copies shall be for the use of the Senate; and</chair>
  <chair> (B) 1,000 copies shall be bound (550 paperbound; 250 nontabbed black skiver; 200 tabbed black skiver) and delivered as may be directed by the Committee on Rules and Administration.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
