<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1176393602" ordinal="21" title="DECEPTIVE FOOD PACKAGING">
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today I call attention to a development within the U.S. Food and Drug Administration, FDA, that has resulted in the sale of carbon-monoxide-treated meat to American consumers. Allowing this can deceive American consumers and raises serious public health concerns since the consumers can no longer rely on the way the meat looks to indicate its freshness.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The use of carbon monoxide turns beef a shade of red that mimics very fresh red meat. Mixing carbon monoxide into the pre-packaged, air-tight packaging of beef allows it to retain its red color long after the expiration date on the package.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The meatpacking industry argues that beef is actually safe up to 20 days when refrigerated and much longer if it is frozen. They also argue that because untreated meat can begin to turn brown before its expiration date, it is  not a true indication of the meat's freshness and consumers should not be relying on the color of the meat, but the expiration date on the package.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is a theoretical argument that fails in the real world. Consumers do rely on meat color and the industry knows that the only purpose of using carbon monoxide is to maintain the red color. Experiments with treated and untreated packages of beef compared how they age under refrigeration. After the expiration date, untreated meat begins to turn brown, while meat was still rosy pink if treated with carbon monoxide. Even though the treated beef looked fresh, it was in fact contaminated with E.  coli bacterium and salmonella.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The FDA has had longstanding rules against color alteration of meats but, inexplicably, the FDA has allowed carbon-monoxide-treated packaging to move forward. I asked the Food and Drug Administration for an explanation of this change. In their response, the FDA claims that adding carbon monoxide to the packaging meets their standard of "generally recognized as safe," and no further FDA approval is required.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Relying on the procedures for substances that are "generally recognized as safe" is inappropriate for color additives and surely that should include any substance added to food whose purpose is to change its color. Under the Federal Food, Drug and Cosmetic Act, the FDA is required to issue, through notice and comment rulemaking, the permissible conditions of use in regulations "listing" the color additive. The color additive "listing" procedure is a transparent process in which the public  is engaged. Consumers have the opportunity to comment on the safety and deception risks that are presented. For the FDA to allow the use of carbon monoxide for color alteration under the "generally recognized as safe" notification procedure ignores the well established listing requirements for public engagement in the policy development process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since there are currently no requirements for the meatpacking industry to label which meats have been packed in carbon monoxide and which have not, it is especially important for consumers to look for the expiration date printed on all meat package labels and not just at the color of the beef. Even if the meat is purchased before the expiration date, consumers still need to be aware that beef packaged in carbon monoxide can spoil at home yet still look fresh. If consumers judge the freshness  of beef by its red color without checking the expiration date on the package, they risk their health.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Prepackaged beef should not be treated with carbon monoxide, but at a minimum, meat that has been treated with carbon monoxide should be clearly labeled so that consumers know what they are buying.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Six consumer groups recently sent a letter to Senators asking that Congress take action on this important health issue. I ask unanimous consent that this letter be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
</record>
