<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1185940800" ordinal="44" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <narrative>AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET -- (Senate - August 01, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="10658">S10658</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="COMMITTEE ON BANKING, HOUSING, AND URBAN AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on August 1, 2007, at 9:30 a.m., to mark up <bill type="s" number="1677">S. 1677</bill>, the Currency Reform and Financial Markets Access Act of 2007; <bill type="s" number="1518">S. 1518</bill>, the Community Partnership to End Homelessness Act of 2007; an original bill entitled the FHA Modernization Act of 2007; an original bill entitled the Housing Assistance Authorization Act of 2007; an original bill  entitled the Private Student Loan Transparency and Improvement Act of 2007; and an original bill entitled the Commission on National Catastrophe Risk Management and Insurance Act of 2007.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, August 1, 2007, at 2:30 p.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The U.S. Department of Commerce and its component bureaus are responsible for the stewardship, protection, and scientific understanding of our ocean environment and its resources, effective use and growth of the Nation's technological resources, and promoting U.S. trade and tourism. The oversight hearing will examine the Department's effectiveness in implementing these goals.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND NATURAL RESOURCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, August 1, 2007, at 9:30 a.m. in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of this hearing is to receive testimony on recent advances in clean coal technology, including the prospects for deploying these technologies at a commercial scale in the near future.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, August 1, 2007, at 9:30 a.m. to hold a hearing on Africa.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="COMMITTEE ON HEALTH, EDUCATION, LABOR, AND PENSIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions be authorized to meet in executive session during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, August 1, 2007 at 10 a.m. in the LBJ Room, S-211, of the Capitol building. We will be considering the following:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>1. <bill type="s" number="625">S. 625</bill>, Family Smoking Prevention and Tobacco Control Act</paragraph>
    <paragraph>2. <bill type="s" number="1183">S. 1183</bill>, Christopher and Dana Reeve Paralysis Act</paragraph>
    <paragraph>3. <bill type="s" number="579">S. 579</bill>, Breast Cancer and Environmental Research Act of 2007</paragraph>
    <paragraph>4. <bill type="s" number="898">S. 898</bill>, Alzheimer's Breakthrough Act of 2007</paragraph>
    <paragraph>5. <bill type="s" number="1858">S. 1858</bill>, Newborn Screening Saves Lives Act of 2007</paragraph>
    <paragraph>6. The Following Nominations: Diane Auer Jones, of Maryland, to be Assistant Secretary for Postsecondary Education, Department of Education; David C. Geary, of Missouri, to be a member of the Board of Directors of the National Board for Education Sciences; Miguel Campaneria, of Puerto Rico, to be a member of the National Council on the Arts; and any nominations ready for action.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE HOMELAND SECURITY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs be authorized to meet on Wednesday, August 1, 2007, at 10 a.m. in order to conduct business meeting to consider pending committee business.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nominations: The Honorable James A. Nussle to be Director, Office of Management and Budget; Dennis R. Schrader to be Deputy Administrator for National Preparedness, Federal Emergency Management Agency, U.S. Department of Homeland Security.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Legislation: <bill type="s" number="680">S. 680</bill>, Accountability in Government Contracting Act of 2007; <bill type="h" number="1254">H.R. 1254</bill>, Presidential Library Donation Reform Act of 2007; S.  __, an original bill to provide for the flexibility of certain disaster relief funds, and for improved evacuation and sheltering during disasters and catastrophes; <bill type="s" number="1000">S. 1000</bill>, Telework Enhancement Act of 2007; <bill type="s" number="1446">S. 1446</bill>, National Capital Transportation Amendments Act of 2007; <bill type="s" number="547">S. 547</bill>, Effective Homeland Security Management Act of 2007; <bill type="s" number="1245">S. 1245</bill>, a bill to reform mutual aid agreements for the National Capital Region; <bill type="s" number="597">S. 597</bill>, a bill to extend the special postage stamp for breast cancer research for 2 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Post Office Naming Bills: <bill type="h" number="2570">H.R. 2570</bill>/S. 1732, a bill to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 301 Boardwalk Drive in Fort Collins, Colorado, as the "Dr. Karl E. Carson Post Office Building"; <bill type="s" number="1772">S. 1772</bill>, a bill to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 127 South Elm Street in Gardner, Kansas, as the "Private First Class Shane R. Austin Post Office"; <bill type="s" number="1781">S. 1781</bill>, a bill to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located  at 118 Minner Avenue in Bakersfield, California, as the "Buck Owens Post Office"; <bill type="h" number="2127">H.R. 2127</bill>, a bill to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 408 West 6th Street in Chelsea, Oklahoma, as the "Clem Rogers McSpadden Post Office Building"; <bill type="h" number="2563">H.R. 2563</bill>/S. 1539, a bill to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 309 East Linn Street in Marshalltown, Iowa, as the "Major Scott Nisely Post Office"; <bill type="s" number="1596">S. 1596</bill>, a bill to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 103 South Getty Street in Uvalde, Texas, as the "Dolph S. Briscoe, Jr., Post Office Building"; <bill type="h" number="1722">H.R. 1722</bill>, a bill to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 601 Banyan Trail in Boca Raton, Florida, as the "Leonard W. Herman Post Office"; <bill type="h" number="1425">H.R. 1425</bill>, a bill to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 4551 East 52nd Street in Odessa, Texas, as the "Staff Sergeant Marvin `Rex' Young Post Office Building"; <bill type="h" number="2078">H.R. 2078</bill>, a bill to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 14536 State Route 136 in Cherry Fork, Ohio, as the "Staff</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="COMMITTEE ON SMALL BUSINESS AND ENTREPRENEURSHIP">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate in order to conduct a roundtable entitled "Reauthorization of the Small Business Innovation Research Programs: National Academies' Findings and Recommendations," on August 1, 2007, at 10 a.m. in room 428A of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="SELECT COMMITTEE ON INTELLIGENCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Select Committee on Intelligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on August 1, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. to hold an open hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="COMMITTEE ON OVERSIGHT OF GOVERNMENT MANAGEMENT, THE FEDERAL WORKFORCE, AND THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Homeland Security and Government Affairs' Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia be authorized to meet on Wednesday, August 1, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. in order to conduct a hearing entitled Building a Stronger American Diplomatic.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON WATER AND POWER">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on Water and Power of the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, August 1, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the hearing is to receive testimony on the following bills: <bill type="s" number="1054">S. 1054</bill> and <bill type="h" number="122">H.R. 122</bill>, to amend the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to participate in the Inland Empire regional recycling project and in the Cucamonga Valley Water District recycling project; <bill type="s" number="1472">S. 1472</bill>, to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to create a Bureau of Reclamation partnership with the North Bay Water Reuse Authority and other regional  partners to achieve objectives relating to water supply, water quality, and environmental restoration; <bill type="s" number="1475">S. 1475</bill> and <bill type="h" number="1526">H.R. 1526</bill>, to amend the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Bay Area Regional Water Recycling Program, and for other purposes; <bill type="h" number="30">H.R. 30</bill>, to amend the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to participate in the Eastern Municipal Water District Recycled Water  System</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
