<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1192809602" ordinal="14" title="DEPARTMENTS OF LABOR, HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES, AND EDUCATION APPROPRIATIONS ACT, 2008--Continued">
  <narrative>DEPARTMENTS OF LABOR, HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES, AND EDUCATION APPROPRIATIONS ACT, 2008--Continued -- (Senate - October 19, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="13147">S13147</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I send a modification to the desk of amendment No. 3374 and ask for its consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report.</chair>
  <chair>The assistant legislative clerk read as follows:</chair>
  <chair>The Senator from Iowa [Mr. Harkin], for Ms. Collins, for herself, Mr. Feingold, Mr. Bingaman, Mr. Cardin, and Ms. Snowe, proposes an amendment numbered 3374, as modified, to amendment No. 3325.</chair>
  <chair>The amendment, as modified, is as follows:</chair>
  <chair> On page 64, line 5, insert before the period the following: ": Provided further, That $2,000,000 of the amounts appropriated under this heading shall be made available to carry out dental workforce programs under section 340G of the Public Health Service Act (42 U.S.C. 256g)".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;AMENDMENTS NOS. 3353, 3333, 3354, AND 3374, AS MODIFIED, TO AMENDMENT NO. 3325 EN BLOC</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I have four amendments that have been cleared on both sides, and I ask unanimous consent to call them up and have them considered en bloc. The amendments are amendment No. 3353, amendment No. 3333, amendment No. 3354, and amendment No. 3374, for which the modification was sent to the desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the four amendments will be considered en bloc and agreed to en bloc.</chair>
  <chair>The amendments were agreed to, as follows:</chair>
  <chair>AMENDMENT NO. 3353&lt;center&gt;(Purpose: To provide funding for the ADAM Act)&lt;/center&gt;</chair>
  <chair> At the appropriate place in title II, insert the following:</chair>
  <chair> Sec. __.  Of the funds made available in this Act for subtitle B of title IV of the Cardiac Arrest Survival Act of 2000 (Public Law 106-505), $200,000 shall be used to carry out section 312(c)(6) of the Public Health Service Act.</chair>
  <chair>AMENDMENT NO. 3354&lt;center&gt;(Purpose: To provide for a Government Accountability Office report concerning State health care reform initiatives)&lt;/center&gt;</chair>
  <chair> At the appropriate place, insert the following:</chair>
  <chair> Sec. __. (a)  Not later than November 30, 2008, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report concerning State health care reform initiatives.</chair>
  <chair>  (b) The report required under subsection (a) shall include the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) An assessment of State efforts to reexamine health care delivery and health insurance systems and to expand the access of residents to health insurance and health care services, including the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) An overview of State approaches to reexamining health care delivery and insurance.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) A description of whether and to what extent State health care initiatives have resulted in improved access to health care and insurance.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) A description of the extent to which public and private cooperation has occurred in State health care initiatives.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (D) A description of the outcomes of State insurance coverage mandates.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (E) A description of the effects of increased health care costs on State fiscal choices.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (F) A description of the effects of Federal law and funding on State health care initiatives and fiscal choices.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (G) A description of outcomes of State efforts to increase health care quality and control costs.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) Recommendations regarding the potential role of Congress in supporting State-based reform efforts, including the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) Enacting changes in Federal law that would facilitate State-based health reform and expansion efforts.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) Creating new or realigning existing Federal funding mechanisms to support State-based reform and expansion efforts.</chair>
  <chair> (C) Expanding existing Federal health insurance programs and increasing other sources of Federal health care funding to support State-based health reform and expansion efforts.&lt;p&gt;</chair>
  <chair>The amendment (No. 3333) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The amendment (No. 3374), as modified, was agreed to.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I don't think there is any further consideration to be had on these amendments. Are the amendments agreed to en bloc?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> That is correct.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the Presiding Officer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are waiting for a Senator to come to the floor to speak on an amendment. I know of no other speakers yet today. Again, I would remind people that we will be here Monday, and we will be voting--I don't know if the time has been determined yet but probably around 5:30 or somewhere around there. We will probably be in late voting on Monday. We will have a whole lot of amendments on Monday night. The agreement was struck yesterday that we would finish this bill by noon on Tuesday and to get there,  with all the amendments we have pending, there will probably be a number of votes on Monday night.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So with that, I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <chair>The assistant legislative clerk proceeded to call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, we have another amendment that has been agreed to on both sides, so I call up amendment No. 3399 and ask for its immediate consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Amendment No. 3399 is pending.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I call up that amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> It was previously proposed.</chair>
  <chair>Is there further debate on the amendment?</chair>
  <chair>If not, without objection, the amendment is agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The amendment (No. 3399) was agreed to</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the Presiding Officer. I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <chair>The assistant legislative clerk proceeded to call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300027" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>AMENDMENT NO. 3381&lt;center&gt;(Purpose: To provide for the continuing review of unauthorized, Federal programs and agencies and to establish a bipartisan commission for the purpose of improving oversight and eliminating wasteful Government spending)&lt;/center&gt;</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300027" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I have conferred with the bill managers.  I ask unanimous consent to call up amendment No. 3381 and to set aside any pending amendments.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will report.</narrative>
  <narrative>The assistant legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>The Senator from Texas (Mr. CORNYN), for himself, Mr. Voinovich, and Mr. Chambliss, proposes an amendment numbered 3381.</narrative>
  <narrative>(The amendment is printed in today's Record under "Text of Amendments.")</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300027" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, first, I thank Senator Harkin and Senator Specter for working with us on this bill, this important piece of legislation, and for the opportunity to offer this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is my intention, at the end of my remarks, to seek to withdraw the amendment because there are some procedural objections under rule XVI of the Senate rules.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think this is an important amendment and an important matter for us to consider at the appropriate time. I hope my colleagues will work with me, as well as Senator Voinovich and Senator Chambliss, who are cosponsors of the amendment, to find a way to address the urgent matters contained within the scope of the amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Specifically, we ought to be good stewards of the taxpayers' money. Unfortunately, due to the size and scope of the Federal budget, there seems to be precious little attention given to ways to make sure that we spend the taxpayers' money efficiently. While we debate the necessity of appropriations, and we should continue to try to cut back on the unnecessary expenditures wherever possible, I think it is imperative that Congress do the appropriate oversight on existing Federal programs and appropriations  and ways to look for both cost savings and efficiencies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think we ought to ask the fundamental question every time we are asked to appropriate money for a particular agency--we ought to ask this question: Is this agency or program still needed?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What has led me to offer this amendment arises out of some good work being done by the OMB. As a matter of fact, they have published this brochure called: "Expect More." You could go on line to expectmore.gov on the Internet and see what I am talking about. Specifically, they have a tool called "the program assessment rating tool," which helps the Office of Management and Budget assess whether a particular Government program is working.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Office of Management and Budget has recently reviewed over a thousand programs. As this chart indicates, upon a review of 1,016 Federal Government programs, they have concluded that 22 percent of those programs rated either as ineffective or they are unable to determine whether they are effective. In other words, they are unable to find evidence that they are effective. They have not conclusively determined them as ineffective, but they have concluded that 22 percent of the Federal Government  programs are either ineffective or the results are not demonstrated. Anybody who is interested anywhere in the world--certainly in the United States--can look at the information on this expectmore.gov Web site and inform themselves, as I am sure they would want to, about what the Federal Government is doing and not doing on their behalf.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As part of the review, the OMB looked at 35 programs within the Department of Labor, totaling almost $15 billion. They identified $2 billion that could be saved out of that $15 billion on programs that are not meeting expectations and are not effective. Some of these programs include the Office of Disability Employment Policy, Trade Adjustment Assistance, and part of the Workforce Investment Act. Certainly, these programs have the potential to help people and strengthen our country. But my hope  is we will look at these programs and not necessarily decide they are not necessary--because they may be--but, rather, give the appropriate oversight and come back and try to do what is necessary to make them effective or, if they simply cannot be rehabilitated or made effective, we ought to eliminate them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The fact is we can look to our State governments and State laws for mechanisms that we could use to make sure we spend the taxpayers' dollars only on needed programs and in the most efficient ways possible.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I look to my State of Texas. Since 1971, we have had something called the Sunset Commission, which periodically--about every 10 years--reviews State programs and State spending to decide what the answer to the question is that I posed earlier: Is this agency or this program still needed? Is the money being spent effectively?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Here in Washington, we could learn from the State sunset commission process, which I know happened in Texas and which also is reflected in the laws of many of our State governments but which we do not have here at the Federal level.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A study by the Congressional Budget Office found that Congress spent almost $160 billion in 2006 on agencies and programs that were not, in fact, authorized. In other words, while the authorizing committees had previously authorized it, those authorizations had lapsed, indicating a lack of continued oversight and authorization by Congress. Yet money was continuing to be appropriated and spent on these programs. This list includes hundreds of accounts, both big ones and small ones, ranging from  the Coast Guard, $8 billion, to the Administration on Aging, $1.5 billion, to section 8 tenant-based housing, $15.6 billion, to the foreign relations programs, which is $9.5 billion. Many of these programs and agencies, perhaps most, deserve reauthorization. I am not saying they do not. But reauthorization</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My amendment would take what I think is a great experiment, which has shown tremendous success on the State level in places such as Texas, and create a bipartisan Federal sunset commission to review the efficiency of all Federal programs but will focus their work on ineffective and unauthorized programs and will make recommendations to Congress about how to improve them, if they can be improved, or whether we should just eliminate them altogether.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To me, this is a shocking figure, when our own Federal Government concludes--the executive branch, the Office of Management and Budget--that almost 25 percent of Federal programs are not delivering for the American taxpayers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My amendment would create, as I said, a bipartisan U.S. authorization and sunset commission that would be composed of four Members of the House and four Members of the Senate. The commission would issue a schedule-and-review proposal to Congress at least once every 10 years, as well as issue reports on the way to improve the effectiveness and efficiency of Government programs and agencies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The schedule-and-review proposal is where the commission would review and analyze at least 25 percent of unauthorized Federal programs and 25 percent of the ineffective programs as identified by OMB and would do so on a rolling or ongoing basis. In other words, we have to start somewhere, and that is where they would start, but we would continue until all Federal agencies and programs would be subject to this sort of scrutiny and review.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unlike most commissions, Congress cannot simply ignore the commission's work under my amendment. Rather, the amendment would provide an expedited procedure that would force Congress to consider and debate the commission's work and then vote up or down on whether to accept it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Simply put, this commission would help Congress do what we should already be doing; that is, providing the necessary oversight to make sure every dollar of the taxpayers' money is being spent wisely. The commission will help Congress answer the simple but powerful question I posed at the outset, and that is: Is an agency or program still needed? It seems like common sense to me.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I know some will argue this is why we have authorizing committees, but I believe the commission would add greater focus to the budget and appropriations process on saving taxpayers money as opposed to how can we come up with new ways to spend more money, which tends to dominate the appropriations process, and how can we  improve Government accountability and provide for greater openness and transparency in Government decisionmaking?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This concept, as I said, is not new or even revolutionary. My home State of Texas has had a sunset commission in place for 30 years, in which time it is estimated the Texas taxpayers have been saved more than $700 million by eliminating ineffective or unnecessary programs, starting with a zero-based budget during the sunset commission reviewing process and justifying each and every dollar that is added to pay for that program if reauthorized.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The tendency in Washington, unfortunately, is to take an existing program and see it grow incrementally each year. Indeed, once a Government program is created, it tends to create a constituency that will come to Congress and argue that it should not be eliminated--not only should it not be eliminated, it should grow by a certain percentage each year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As this and other appropriations bills come before the Senate, I ask my colleagues to keep in mind the extent of waste we already see in Government programs. Rather than allowing these programs to continue endlessly with no real purpose and no real means of accomplishing their goals, it is time we took a closer look at and acted on our responsibility to eliminate wasteful Washington spending. Before we raise taxes and before we mindlessly appropriate money for another batch of potentially ineffective  and outdated programs, we should take a hard look in the mirror on how we spend the hard-earned money of the beleaguered American taxpayers. No one wants higher taxes, and our first defense against higher taxes ought to be greater efficiency and money savings by eliminating wasteful programs. Our primary means of ensuring this efficiency would be through this bipartisan sunset commission.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I hope all of our colleagues will seriously consider this proposal for a Federal sunset commission. It is important, before we look at raising taxes and growing the size of Government, that we look at ways to eliminate waste and unnecessary programs, and that is exactly what this amendment would do.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I understand this particular amendment, being legislation on an appropriations bill, will be subject to a point of order. Rather than pursue that issue and require the procedural ruling on that decision, I now ask unanimous consent to withdraw my amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300027" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I thank the bill managers and my colleagues for indulging me on this point. This is not an issue that is going to go away. I am not going to go away when it comes to urging greater efficiency and elimination of wasteful Washington spending.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have a tremendous responsibility, those of us who have been sent to Congress to represent our States and our districts, the least of which ought to be being good stewards of the taxpayers' money. It is time to take the Federal budget off autopilot, to see the Government grow and grow and grow without any real oversight, particularly when it comes to these programs which have been demonstrated either as ineffective or where it is impossible for the Federal Government to conclude that the evidence  justifies the continued existence of these programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam President, in America, there are over 10,000 children like 11-year-old Nate Newton of San Antonio and 7-year-old triplets Zoe, Emma, and Sophie Dunn of Houston, who are both deaf and blind. The increase in the number of deafblind children in America is fueling a growing demand for qualified teachers to work with deafblind children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Texas Tech University is one of the few universities in the United States that offer graduate training in deafblind education. To date, the Department of Education has provided funding from the special education national activities account to train teachers with deafblind children in their classes on how to educate and include these children in daily classroom activities. Yet Federal funding for this program has remained level at $12.8 million for nearly the past 20 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The House-passed version of the Labor-HHS appropriations bill includes a modest increase of $2 million in funding for deafblind services. I think this is a reasonable increase and would request that the conference committee accept the higher level of funding.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="FUNDING FOR DEAFBLIND SERVICES">
    <paragraph>I appreciate the Senator raising this issue and will do what I can to ensure that we accept the higher number when we go to conference on this bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300092" topic="FUNDING FOR DEAFBLIND SERVICES">
    <paragraph>There are over 300 deafblind children in Pennsylvania, so this is an issue that also affects a number of families in my State. I thank Senator CORNYN for calling this issue to our attention. I will do what I can when we go to conference to try to keep the funding for deafblind services at the higher level.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>1945 TRINITY TEST</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="FUNDING FOR DEAFBLIND SERVICES">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I rise to discuss a matter of great importance to my State with the chairman of the subcommittee, Senator Harkin. As he is aware, New Mexico was host to the Nation first test of a nuclear weapon on July 16, 1945--the "Trinity" test. At the time, this test, like the entire Manhattan Project, was classified, with a public cover story of an ammunition magazine exploding at Alamogordo Air Force Base some 40 miles to the south of the test. The surrounding  communities were not told that this was a nuclear weapons test until after the detonation of the "fat man" bomb over Nagasaki nearly 1 month later. In fact, the decision was knowingly made by the Army not to give any advance warning or evacuate any of the surrounding communities. The radioactive fallout from this test traveled northeast for at least 100 miles, and the effects were felt all around my State and beyond. Communities 96 miles north in Vaughn, NM, were affected; windows in Silver City, 120 miles west, were shattered. For 4 or 5 days after the test, the surrounding communities northeast to the test reported a "white substance like flour settled on everything." Cattle that grazed on Chupadera Mesa suffered beta radiation burns and loss of hair, indicating levels of radiation exceeding today's permissible dose by factors of several thousand. The government made</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="FUNDING FOR DEAFBLIND SERVICES">
    <paragraph>I am well aware of the problem of compensating workers affected by radiation from my efforts to secure a special exposure cohort under the Energy Employees Occupational Illness Compensation Program at the Iowa Army Ammunition Plant. Have these local communities received any sort of compensation to date?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="FUNDING FOR DEAFBLIND SERVICES">
    <paragraph>No. While the local communities surrounding the test in my State have talked of illnesses such as thyroid cancer for years, the recent CDC study is the first technical compilation of historical documents in the technical files of Los Alamos National Laboratory. Detailed technical dose reconstructions must first be attempted to take place to show the probable cause of the illnesses. I would like to request that the managers of this bill work in conference to insert the strongest  possible language to have the National Cancer Institute undertake a study that estimates the number of fatal and nonfatal radiogenic illnesses compared to a baseline of what would be expected to occur naturally. This analysis must be completed by the National Cancer Institute with the utmost urgency given that, as the chairman knows well from the Iowa Army Ammunition Plant, many of the affected population are reaching an advanced age.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="FUNDING FOR DEAFBLIND SERVICES">
    <paragraph>I will work with my colleague Senator Specter, the ranking member of the subcommittee, to urge the National Cancer Institute to make this matter a high priority. Does the Senator agree?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300092" topic="FUNDING FOR DEAFBLIND SERVICES">
    <paragraph>Yes, I will support that effort.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="FUNDING FOR DEAFBLIND SERVICES">
    <paragraph>I thank both managers of this bill for their willingness to work with me on this important issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank the Chair. I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <chair>The assistant legislative clerk proceeded to call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="FUNDING FOR DEAFBLIND SERVICES">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
