<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1176220802" ordinal="52" title="MSU SPARTAN HOCKEY NCAA CHAMPIONSHIP">
  <speaking speaker="300093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today to commend the Michigan State University Spartans on winning the 2007 Men's National Collegiate Hockey Championship.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On Saturday, April 7, 2007, the Michigan State University Men's Hockey Team won the 2007 Men's Hockey National Collegiate Athletic Association Championship by defeating Boston College by a score of 3 to 1.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In a hard-fought game, and going into the final period with a one-goal deficit, the Spartans charged ahead to tie the game, and then triumphantly scored a game-winning goal with only 18.9 seconds remaining of play.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This victory constituted MSU Hockey's third national championship, and the first since 1986. Each member of the MSU Hockey organization made essential contributions to the team's success.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>MSU Spartans' Head Coach Rick Comley has become only the third coach in college hockey history to win national titles at two institutions, and has earned over 700 career wins.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A record crowd of over 19,000 people attended the Frozen Four Championship game in St. Louis, and the enthusiasm shown by the people of Michigan and the students of MSU demonstrate Michigan's strong support for the MSU Hockey organization.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I know how important the families and friends of the team have been in providing unwavering support and always cheering on their Spartans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the final weeks of the season, with an uncertain forecast of their playoff position, the Spartans rallied together with unrivaled team character and focus, and starting with the 1st round playoffs in Grand Rapids, MI, they went on undefeated to clinch the championship.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Michigan State University has always stood as a center for excellence in both athletics and scholarship, especially with the guidance of University President Lou Anna K. Simon, and athletic director and renowned former MSU Hockey coach, Ron Mason.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am a proud MSU alumnus myself, and was beyond delighted to see this great team win the national championship.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The MSU Spartans displayed unparalleled team camaraderie, and have shown their ability to unite both on and off the ice has led them to well-fought victories.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Spartan Hockey Team demonstrated superior strength, skill, perseverance and determination and has made Michigan State University and the entire State of Michigan proud.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I congratulate the MSU Spartan Hockey Team on winning the 2007 NCAA Championship and recognize all the players, coaches, staff, fans, and others who were instrumental in this great achievement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, this is a wonderful day for Michigan State University. We are very proud of our hockey members and particularly proud of a member of my staff, Jeff Muich, whose brother Steve is a member of that team. So with pride we congratulate Michigan State University on this wonderful achievement.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table, and that any statements relating to the resolution be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
