<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1207756802" ordinal="41" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <narrative>AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET -- (Senate - April 09, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="2825">S2825</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400357" topic="COMMITTEE ON ARMED SERVICES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, April 9, 2008, at 9:30 a.m., in open session to receive testimony on the situation in Iraq and progress made by the Government of Iraq in meeting benchmarks and achieving reconciliation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400357" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, April 9, 2008, at 2:30 p.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400357" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENVIRONMENT AND PUBLIC WORKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Environment and Public Works be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, April 9, 2008, at 10 a.m. in room 406 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building to hold a hearing entitled, "Legislative Hearing on <bill type="s" number="1870">S. 1870</bill>, the Clean Water Restoration Act of 2007."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400357" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, April 9, 2008, at 9:30 a.m. to hold a hearing on sexual assault in combat environments.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400357" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, April 9, 2008, at 3:15 p.m. to hold a nomination hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400357" topic="COMMITTEE ON VETERAN'S AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent for the Committee on Veterans' Affairs to be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, April 9, 2008, to conduct an oversight hearing on Making the VA the Workplace of Choice for Health Care Providers. The committee will meet in room 418 of the Russell Senate Office Building, at 9:30 a.m.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without a objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400357" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON AIRLAND">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on Airland of the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, April 9, 2008, at 2 p.m., in open session to receive testimony on Air Force and Navy aviation programs in review of the Defense authorization request for fiscal year 2009 and the Future Years Defense Program.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400357" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON HEALTH CARE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Finance Subcommittee on Health Care be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, April 9, 2008, at 2:30 p.m., in room 215 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building, to conduct a hearing entitled "Covering Uninsured Children: The Impact of the August 17 CHIP Directive."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400357" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON NATIONAL PARKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on National Parks be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate to conduct a hearing on Wednesday, April 9, 2008, at 2:30 p.m., in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
