<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1171688400" ordinal="32" title="RECOGNIZING THE 45TH ANNIVERSARY OF JOHN HERSHEL GLENN, JR.'S HISTORIC ACHIEVEMENT">
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Judiciary Committee be discharged from further consideration of <bill type="sr" number="81">S. Res. 81</bill> and the Senate then proceed to its consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered. The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I know the time is late and a lot of people want to go a lot of different places, but I have to say that John Glenn is one of the most amazing people I have ever known, to think that I had the opportunity to serve with him in this body, a man who was an ace in World War II, knocking down enemy aircraft in his marine vehicle. He was an ace in the Korean war and, of course, America's most famous astronaut.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I will just say in passing, when I first came here as a Senator, at our Tuesday luncheon, Senator Glenn said: Does anybody want to go with me? I am going to go out on the USS Kennedy, which is an aircraft carrier. He said: I am going to watch some landings. I said: Well, gee, John Glenn, aircraft carrier, which I have never been on. I said: I will try that. And I did.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It was interesting. We flew out in an airplane. It was stopped very quickly because a hook grabbed the airplane. Then I watched these new pilots, who had never landed on an aircraft carrier, coming in, wings wobbling. They would wave some off: "Dirty, dirty"--that is the word they used to get this thing out of there. Lots of them landed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Then John Glenn got in one of those planes and was catapulted off the aircraft carrier and came in on a landing himself. He is an amazing man.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have one final story about John Glenn. My office was in the Hart Building. Nevada had the champions in double Dutch jump-roping. They were out in the atrium of the Hart Building showing me what they could do. It is amazing--several people jumping at the same time. They asked me to do it. I made--I wouldn't say a fool of myself, but I couldn't do it. I didn't realize John Glenn was standing watching this. Here is a man, at the time had to be 70 years old, and he walked over and said: Can I try  that? He was like one of the kids. An amazing man.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a resolution recognizing the 45th anniversary of his historic achievement. Becoming the first U.S. astronaut to orbit the Earth is only one of the achievements this great man did--and he is still healthy and strong--with his wonderful wife Annie.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table, and that any statements relating to the measure be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
