<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1227200405" ordinal="96" title="HONORING THE FIREFIGHTERS AND EMERGENCY WORKERS IN CALIFORNIA IN 2008">
  <narrative>HONORING THE FIREFIGHTERS AND EMERGENCY WORKERS IN CALIFORNIA IN 2008 -- (Senate - November 20, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="10775">S10775</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300037" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of <bill type="sr" number="714">S. Res. 714</bill>, which was submitted earlier today by Senator Boxer.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="714">S. Res. 714</bill>) honoring the firefighters and emergency workers who courageously fought fires in California in 2008.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300037" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table, with no intervening action or debate, and that any statements related to the resolution be printed in the Record at the appropriate place as if read.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="714">S. Res. 714</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="714">S. Res. 714</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas, in 2008, there have been more than 10,000 wildfires in California started by natural causes and human activity;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas more than 1,440,000 acres of Federal, State, and local land in California burned in 2008;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, in June 2008, fires started by lightning strikes burned approximately 1,200,000 acres of Federal, State, and local land in California, making the June fires the largest single wildfire event in California's recorded history;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas 41 counties across California were impacted by wildfires in 2008;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas more than 1,400 homes were destroyed by fires in California in 2008;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas State and local firefighters have been called to duty for increasingly long fire seasons, working on the front lines of these fires for weeks;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas firefighters have risked their lives and endured great hardship to protect lives, property, and the environment in California;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas many firefighters were injured and 14 firefighters tragically lost their lives in California in 2008;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas 25,000 firefighters and emergency response personnel from California, 41 other States, and other nations worked side-by-side to fight the wildfires;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas members of the National Guard from California and other States provided essential support to the firefighting effort; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the people of California and the United States recognize the steadfast dedication of the firefighters throughout the ongoing fire suppression and subsequent repair and rebuilding efforts: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) commends the firefighters and emergency workers from California, 41 other States, and other nations for their courageous actions and sacrifices in fighting wildfires in California;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) supports the continued work of firefighters to protect National Forest System land, other public lands, and private property from further damage;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) praises the people of California for their great courage in the face of the fires; and</chair>
  <chair> (4) extends heartfelt sympathy to the people who have lost loved ones, homes, and businesses in the wildfires.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
