<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1191513602" ordinal="14" title="PROVIDING FOR A CONDITIONAL ADJOURNMENT OR RECESS OF THE SENATE">
  <narrative>PROVIDING FOR A CONDITIONAL ADJOURNMENT OR RECESS OF THE SENATE -- (Senate - October 04, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="12702">S12702</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of <bill type="sc" number="49">S. Con. Res. 49</bill>, the adjournment resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the concurrent resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A concurrent resolution (<bill type="sc" number="49">S. Con. Res. 49</bill>) providing for a conditional adjournment or recess of the Senate.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the concurrent resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to and the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The concurrent resolution (<bill type="sc" number="49">S. Con. Res. 49</bill>) was agreed to, as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sc" number="49">S. Con. Res. 49</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Resolved by the Senate (the House of Representatives concurring), That when the Senate recesses or adjourns on Thursday, October 4, 2007, or Friday, October 5, 2007, on a motion offered pursuant to this concurrent resolution by its Majority Leader or his designee, it stand recessed or adjourned until 12 noon on Monday, October 15, 2007, or such other time on that day as may be specified by its Majority Leader or his designee in the motion to recess or adjourn, or until the time of any  reassembly pursuant to section 2 of this concurrent resolution, whichever occurs first.</chair>
  <chair>SEC. 2. The Majority Leader of the Senate, after consultation with the Minority Leader of the Senate, shall notify the Members of the Senate to reassemble at such place and time as he may designate if, in his opinion, the public interest shall warrant it.</chair>
</record>
