<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1222444802" ordinal="53" title="CONSOLIDATED SECURITY, DISASTER ASSISTANCE, AND CONTINUING APPROPRIATIONS ACT, 2009">
  <narrative>CONSOLIDATED SECURITY, DISASTER ASSISTANCE, AND CONTINUING APPROPRIATIONS ACT, 2009 -- (Senate - September 26, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="9621">S9621</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Chair lay before the Senate a message from the  House with respect to <bill type="h" number="2638">H.R. 2638</bill>, the Consolidated Security, Disaster Assistance, and Continuing Appropriations Act.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Presiding Officer laid before the Senate the following message from the House of Representatives:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="h" number="2638">H.R. 2638</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative>Resolved, That the House agree to the amendment of the Senate to the bill (<bill type="h" number="2638">H.R. 2638</bill>) entitled "An Act making appropriations for the Department of Homeland Security for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2008, and for other purposes." with an amendment to the Senate amendment.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I move to concur in the amendment of the House to the Senate amendment to <bill type="h" number="2638">H.R. 2638</bill> with an amendment at the desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>The Senator from Nevada [Mr. Reid] moves to concur in the House amendment to the Senate amendment with an amendment numbered 5660.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that reading of the amendment be dispensed with.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The amendment is as follows:</chair>
  <chair>At the end, add the following: The provisions of this Act shall become effective 2 days after enactment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask for the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there a sufficient second?</chair>
  <chair>There appears to be a sufficient second.</chair>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I have a second-degree amendment that I ask to be considered at this time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report.</chair>
  <chair>The Senator from Nevada [Mr. Reid] proposes an amendment numbered 5661 to amendment No. 5660.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that reading of the amendment be dispensed with.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The amendment is as follows:</chair>
  <chair>In the Amendment, strike "2" and insert "1".</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>I now send a cloture motion to the desk on the motion to concur.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The cloture motion having been presented under rule XXII, the clerk will report the motion to invoke cloture.</chair>
  <chair>The assistant legislative clerk read as follows:</chair>
  <chair>Cloture Motion</chair>
  <chair>We, the undersigned Senators, in accordance with the provisions of rule XXII of the Standing Rules of the Senate, hereby move to bring to a close debate on the motion to concur in the House amendment with an amendment No. 5660 to <bill type="h" number="2638">H.R. 2638</bill>, the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act/Continuing Resolution for fiscal year 2009.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>I now ask that no motion to refer be in order during the pendency of the message.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
