<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1201021201" ordinal="73" title="COMMENDING MARTIN P. PAONE">
  <narrative>COMMENDING MARTIN P. PAONE -- (Senate - January 22, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="155">S155</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412246" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I have a resolution at the desk, and I ask for its immediate consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="420">S. Res. 420</bill>) commending Martin P. Paone.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412246" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution and preamble be agreed to, en bloc, and that the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="420">S. Res. 420</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The premble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>Senate Resolution 420</chair>
  <chair>Whereas Marty Paone has faithfully served the Congress in various capacities over the past 32 years, twenty-eight of which were spent in service to the Senate;</chair>
  <chair>Whereas Marty Paone is the first person to rise through the ranks of various positions--including Vehicular Placement Specialist--to finally serve with distinction as Secretary for the Minority, and concluding his Senate service as Secretary for the Majority;</chair>
  <chair>Whereas Marty Paone has at all times discharged the important duties and responsibilities of his office with great efficiency, dedication and diligence;</chair>
  <chair>Whereas his dedication, good humor, and exceptional service have earned him the respect and admiration of Democratic and Republican Senators, as well as their staffs; Now therefore be it</chair>
  <chair>Resolved, That the Senate expresses its appreciation to Marty Paone and commends him for his lengthy, faithful and outstanding service to the Senate.</chair>
  <chair>The Secretary of the Senate shall transmit a copy of this resolution to Martin P. Paone.</chair>
</record>
