<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1173974406" ordinal="17" title="ORDER OF PROCEDURE">
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the motion to proceed to <bill type="sj" number="9">S.J. Res. 9</bill> be agreed to and that the Senate now begin debate en bloc on the following: <bill type="sj" number="9">S.J. Res. 9</bill>, <bill type="sr" number="107">S. Res. 107</bill>, and <bill type="sc" number="20">S. Con. Res. 20</bill> by Senator Gregg; that there now be 4 hours for debate on the above items equally divided between the two leaders or their designees; that no amendments or motions be in order to any of the above; that at the conclusion or yielding back of that time, the Senate vote on each  of the above in the above order; and that the preceding all occur without intervening action or debate; further, that there be 2 minutes for debate equally divided between each vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300072" topic="">
    <paragraph>I object.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, since a filibuster is any Member's prerogative, I renew my consent with 60 votes required to pass each measure; and that if any measure fails to get 60 votes, the vote on passage be vitiated and the item be returned to its previous status.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection? Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, let me also say, when we complete these votes, we are going to move to three judges, one circuit court judge and two district court judges. So Senators should be alerted that we could have six votes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I note the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
