<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1184644800" ordinal="7" title="DEBATE TIME ON IRAQ WAR POLICY">
  <narrative>DEBATE TIME ON IRAQ WAR POLICY -- (Senate - July 17, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="9294">S9294</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300072" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, listening to my good friend from Illinois, the majority whip, discussing the 60-vote threshold reminds me of what the majority leader said back on January 30, 2007:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sixty votes are required for just about everything. I have talked with Senator McConnell about this. You know we have to come up with a number of resolutions that require 60 votes because, as you know in the Senate, a lot of times 60 votes are required for just about everything.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, that is life in the Senate. On the Defense authorization bill, we had two amendments last year, the Kennedy and Enzi amendments, and both required 60 votes. We are happy to have this debate tonight. It is my understanding the other side last evening agreed to accept the Cornyn amendment to the Defense authorization bill. As we indicated, we have a request for a rollcall vote on that amendment. However, we will be happy to schedule that vote at a reasonable time today. I am told--and we heard  again--that we plan to be here this evening leading up to the cloture vote on the Levin amendment, and we would be happy to have that vote today. There is no particular reason to have the Levin-Reed vote tomorrow; we could have it today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But look, it is perfectly fine with us to stay here today and this evening to discuss this very important issue. I couldn't agree with my friend from Illinois more that it is the significant issue in the country at this particular juncture. We will be prepared to work with the majority whip and the majority leader to work out a floor schedule that allows us to rotate back and forth on a regular basis throughout the afternoon and the evening, and we look forward to working that out in a way that  is fair to both sides and gives us ample opportunity for a vigorous debate about this extremely important issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
