<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1168966803" ordinal="35" title="STATEMENTS ON INTRODUCED BILLS AND JOINT RESOLUTIONS">
  <speaking speaker="300064" topic="Introducing S. 294. A bill to reauthorize Amtrak, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="294">S. 294</bill>] Mr. President, together with my good friend--the new Minority Whip--Senator TRENT LOTT I rise to introduce <bill type="s" number="294">S. 294</bill>, the Passenger Rail Investment and Improvement Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After several gloomy years, the future of America's passenger railroad is bright. This legislation will provide the necessary resources to bring Amtrak up to speed as a real alternative to taking a plane or driving a car.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As we did in the past, we have joined forces to strengthen Amtrak and intercity passenger rail services for all Americans. But today, we introduce an updated version of last Congress's Amtrak reauthorization and passenger rail expansion bill. <bill type="s" number="1516">S. 1516</bill>, the Passenger Rail Investment and Improvement (PRIIA) Act of 2005.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I co-authored this legislation with Senator LOTT, then Chairman of the Commerce Committee's Surface Transportation and Merchant Marine Subcommittee, so that we could finally provide Amtrak with the funding and support it needs to thrive. The Commerce Committee favorably reported this bill, and Senator LOTT and I added it to last Congress's Budget Reconciliation package, where it was adopted by an overwhelming vote of 93 to 6. Despite the bipartisan support, the House failed to act,  so Amtrak was left without a necessary reauthorization.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, in the new Congress, I am the chair of the Commerce Committee's Surface Transportation and Merchant Marine Subcommittee. Working with Senator LOTT, and our bipartisan group of cosponsors, we are going to get our Amtrak bill through the Senate. This time, I believe the House will be ready, willing, and able to match our efforts, so that we can send a bill to the President for his signature.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Every year, Amtrak is forced to fight for Federal funding--funding that has been insufficient at best. But as air and highway congestion continue to worsen, and concerns over our dependence on foreign oil remain, we must expand the capacity and improve the quality of our passenger rail system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One needs only to look to Europe and Asia to see the benefits that a modern  passenger rail system can bring to a nation. Germany, which invested nine billion dollars in its rail system 2003 alone, has a modern, high-speed rail system that reduces pollution, eases congestion and improves mobility for all of its citizens. The benefits of their world class system are obvious to anyone who travels there. We need the same world class system in our country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The era of the free and easy interstate and quick, hassle-free flights has come and gone, and time for us to make real investments in our passenger rail system has come. If we do not invest in Amtrak now, I fear for our country's economy and quality of life over the coming years. We simply cannot afford to rely solely on air travel or automobiles if we are going to keep this country moving.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The terror and tragedy we experienced on 9/11 taught us that we cannot rely solely on our aviation system. Last fall, Hurricane Katrina highlighted the role that passenger rail could play in evacuating residents who do not own automobiles. Hurricane Rita demonstrated the limits of our highway system, as evacuees' vehicles crawled to a stop in bumper-to-bumper traffic. Each one of these disasters reminded us that our Nation needs Amtrak and better train service to provide options for the traveling  public--in good times and in bad.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill we introduce today is the most comprehensive reauthorization of Amtrak ever attempted by this body. We have worked with Amtrak, freight railroads, the States and rail labor to draft strong and comprehensive legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our bill authorizes nearly $12 billion in Federal support to expand partnerships for passenger rail with the States, improve the Northeast Corridor and provide real rail security for the Nation. Additionally, Senator LOTT and I filed an amendment today to this bill which would add $7.8 billion in bonding authority for States and Amtrak to develop rail infrastructure. This bonding authority would augment the appropriated funds authorized by this bill and provide Amtrak and the States with  a reliable, multi-year source of capital for major projects. We look forward to working with the Finance Committee to consider this proposal.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our bill also requires significant reforms of Amtrak: The system's supporters and detractors alike agree that it is time to reauthorize the Corporation so that Amtrak has congressional guidance on how to proceed with important reform initiatives needed to improve service, grow revenues, and cut costs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>People in New Jersey rely on Amtrak and want to be sure that the system will be there for them in the future. With this plan, it will.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last year, 93 Senators voted for this plan. I ask that my colleagues, once again, join Senator LOTT and myself in supporting this important bill that will bring America's passenger rail system into the 21st Century.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300069" topic="Introducing S. 294. A bill to reauthorize Amtrak, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I just want to take a few moments to talk about Amtrak and inter-city passenger rail.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the last Congress, I worked with Senators Stevens, Inouye, and Lautenberg--and other members of the Commerce Committee--to develop <bill type="s" number="1516">S. 1516</bill>, the Passenger Rail Investment and Improvement Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last year during the Senate's consideration of the reconciliation bill I offered an amendment to add the text of <bill type="s" number="1516">S. 1516</bill>. The amendment passed by a vote of 93 to 6. So I know there is widespread support for this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today we are introducing the same bipartisan legislation in hopes of gaining the same level of support as we did in the last Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill was developed with input from the Administration, the Department of Transportation's Inspector General, States, Amtrak Board members, and many others.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill makes a number of important reforms to Amtrak, and has three major themes: Amtrak Reform and Accountability; cost cutting; and, creating funding options for States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By increasing executive branch oversight over Amtrak, this bill ensures that the taxpayers' money is used more effectively. Under its past President, David Gunn, Amtrak has made some improvements in its management. However, much remains to be done. Amtrak must be run more like a business. This bill requires Amtrak to develop better financial systems and to evaluate its operations objectively. It forces Amtrak to improve the efficiency of long distance train service. The bill reduces Amtrak's  operating subsidy by 40 percent by 2011 by requiring Amtrak to use its funding more effectively,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill promotes a greater role for the private sector by allowing private companies to bid on operating Amtrak routes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also creates a new rail capital grant program that States can use to start new inter-city passenger rail service. This will be the first time that States will have a Federal program they can use for passenger rail, putting intercity passenger rail on a similar footing to highways, transit, and airports, all of which have Federal assistance programs for infrastructure. States won't have to rely only on Amtrak for intercity passenger rail service.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I look forward to working with my colleagues on both sides of the aisle to get this bipartisan legislation signed into law this year</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300063" topic="Introducing S. 295. A bill to establish a servitude and emancipation archival research clearinghouse in the National Archives; to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="295">S. 295</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to reintroduce the Servitude and Emancipation Archival Research Clearing House, SEARCH, Act of 2007, a bill that will establish a national database consisting of historic records of servitude and emancipation in the United States to assist African Americans in researching their genealogy. Additionally, Congressman ELIJAH CUMMINGS is reintroducing a companion to this bill on the House side because we both believe in its importance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is a very human instinct for people to want to understand who they are from the lenses of who are their ancestors and where are they from. This is the very reason I stand before you today to reintroduce this piece of very important legislation. Unfortunately, African Americans who attempt to trace their genealogy encounter huge hurdles in reclaiming the usual documentary history that allows most Americans to piece together their heritage. W.E.B. Dubois once said that, "There is in this world  no such force as the force of a person determined to rise, for the human soul cannot be permanently chained." The Servitude and Emancipation Archival Research ClearingHouse, SEARCH, Act of 2007 gives African Americans the tools they need to rise above the unique challenges and hardships they face in order to</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Traditionally, someone researching their genealogy would try looking up wills and land deeds; however, enslaved African Americans were prohibited from owning property. In fact, African Americans, must frequently rely on the records of slave owners--most of which are in private hands--in hope that they had kept records containing birth and death information. Even if records do exist, many African Americans in the past did not have formal last names, thus compounding the difficulty of tracing their  lives. The omission of surnames also precludes use of the most popular and major source of genealogical research, the United States Census. Furthermore, letters, diaries, and other first-person records used by most genealogical researchers are scarcely available for slaves, owing to the fact that they could not legally learn to read or write.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Even after the Emancipation Proclamation was given in 1865, we would think that African Americans could begin using traditional genealogical records like voter registrations and school records. However, African Americans did not immediately begin to participate in many of the privileges of citizenship, including voting and attending school. Discrimination meant that African Americans were barred from sitting on juries or owning businesses. Segregation meant segregated neighborhoods, schools,  churches, clubs, and fraternal organizations, and thus segregated societies maintained segregated records. For example, some telephone directories in South Carolina did not include African Americans in the regular alphabetical listing, but rather at the end of the book. An African American must maneuver these distinctive nuances</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Abraham Lincoln said, "a man who cares nothing about his past can care little about his future." By providing $5 million for the National Historical Publications and Records Commission to establish and maintain a national database, the SEARCH Act has the potential to significantly reduce the time and painstaking efforts of those African Americans who truly care about their American past to contribute to the American future. This bill also seeks to authorize $5 million for States, colleges,  and universities to preserve, catalogue, and index records locally.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In a democracy, records matter. The mission of NARA is to ensure that anyone can have access to the records that matter to them. The SEARCH Act of 2007 seeks to fulfill that mission by helping African Americans navigate genealogical research sources and negotiate the unique challenges that confront them in this process. No longer should any American have to wait to learn information, which in itself can offer such freedom.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I don't believe there is a more appropriate time than now to pass this piece of legislation, on the day before we honor the legacy of a man who spent his life as an advocate of freedom, Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. Dr. King once said, "Our lives begin to end the day we become silent about things that matter." Mr. President, this piece of legislation does matter and I ask my colleagues to join me in passing the SEARCH Act of 2007.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300075" topic="Introducing S. 298. A bill to provide incentives for renewable energy production, to increase fuel economy standards for automobiles, and to provide tax incentives for renewable energy production; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="298">S. 298</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to introduce a significant bill to improve energy efficiency in this Nation and reduce greenhouse gas emissions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill I am introducing will promote the development of additional forms of renewable energy and also pave the way for improved fuel consumption by vehicles. I rise to introduce the Renewable Energy, Fuel Reduction, and Economic Stabilization and Enhancement Act of 2007, or the REFRESH Act, for short.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I consider this a balanced measure, a companion to a bill introduced recently by Alaska's Senior Senator TED STEVENS who proposed to raise the fuel efficiency of automobiles to 40 miles per gallon within a decade, a bill I am proud to be a cosponsor of. This bill will promote alternative energy by providing grants and tax credits to promote development of geothermal power, all forms of ocean energy and small hydro electric development.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also seeks to reduce American fossil fuel consumption by nearly 5 million barrels of oil a day by 2025 by not only supporting an increase in the Corporate Average Fuel Efficiency Standard, CAFE, for automobiles, as  proposed by Senator STEVENS, but by also requiring a study of whether to mandate that a CAFE standard to be imposed on commercial trucks. The bill also requires an improvement in the efficiency of replacement tires for all passenger  cars, provides grants to States and local communities to encourage a reduction in traffic congestion by helping States to set up telecommuting and flexible-work programs to keep motorists off roadways during rush hours, and extends and removes a cap on tax credits to encourage the purchase of hybrid and advanced fuel efficient lean-burn vehicles. The bill also authorizes $100 million in additional research assistance for plug-in hybrid and battery storage technology development.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also includes a truth in advertising provision requiring that the CAFE standards for vehicles be based on the actual fuel economy that the vehicles will achieve under real-world driving conditions, where acceleration, the use of air conditioning and stop and go driving is considered rather than on a three-decades old testing formula.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill will reduce carbon dioxide emissions from fossil fuel usage by about 530 million metric tons in the United States by 2025--a 7 percent cut over what emissions otherwise are predicted to be that year. Coming from Alaska where there is no question but that warming temperatures have been in place in recent years, it only makes sense that we take common sense steps now to improve fuel efficiency, to promote the development of a wider range of alternative energy technologies and to encourage  Americans to buy more fuel efficient vehicles, as long as their ability to drive safe and affordable vehicles of their own choosing is protected.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill is a careful balance of steps we can take to reduce fuel usage and thus greenhouse gas emissions, but also of provisions that are economic for Americans to undertake, and will pay for themselves in reduced fuel costs, sometimes in very short order. It will be good insurance for the environment, but also good for the pocketbooks of Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Americans understand that we are in a current warming trend. Just this week, our government reported that 2006 was the warmest year worldwide in over a century. There are dozens of examples of the effects on the environment that the warming climate of the past three decades has caused. While I believe the ultimate cause of the climate change we are seeing is not yet certain, it is our responsibility to take affordable steps now to reduce fuel consumption, increase the use of alternative, non-fossil-fuel  technologies, and to reduce carbon dioxide and other greenhouse gas emissions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill, paired with previous legislation by my colleague Senator Ted Stevens that specifically raises the CAFE standard by 2017, <bill type="s" number="183">S. 183</bill>, will require automobile makers, if it is technologically feasible, to improve fuel efficiency. I am proud to be a supporter of that measure. The two bills will have a host of policy and economic advantages. They will make us less dependent on imported oil, improving our national security and reducing the money we spend overseas to buy imported crude  oil. And they will produce more jobs in America through the development of new alternative-fuel industries.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill I introduce today, for example, will require all tire manufacturers to make and sell only low, rolling, resistance tires for replacement tire purposes within five years--the same tires found on new cars today. The tires, while they will add on average $20 to the cost of a set of two replacement tires, will improve fuel efficiency by 1.5 to 4.5 percent. Thus if the price of gasoline is only $2 a gallon, drivers will save from $87 to $260 a year in fuel costs per year, the change saving  the typical driver money within the first year, according to estimates by the National Commission on Energy Policy that recommended the change in a 2005 report.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also will require the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA) to study the savings that would result and the costs of imposing a CAFE standard on commercial trucks, a key requirement before Congress can actually impose such a standard. Commercial trucks consume between 1.5 and 2 million barrels of oil a day in fuel. According to estimates by the Department of Energy's 21st Century Truck Program and by Argonne National Laboratory, fuel economy for tractor-trailers should  be able to improve by 30 to 60 percent by 2015 through use of a CAFE standard. While such improvements might increase the cost of a tractor-trailer by $7,000 at time of purchase, it would save some $11,000 in fuel costs over the life of the vehicle, achieving payback for the typical truck owner in less than three years. Imposing such a CAFE on trucks was proposed by the Energy Security Leadership Council in a report just last month.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The $50 million in grants to reduce traffic congestion could pay for themselves nearly immediately, since the National Commission on Energy Policy estimated that American motorists consume between 65,000 and 260,000 barrels of oil a day in wasted fuel because of urban traffic congestion, costing the Nation up to $13 million a day at current fuel prices.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And the tax credit provisions, making all forms of ocean energy: wave, current, tidal and thermal, and small hydro electric power qualified to receive the Federal Production Tax Credit that currently reduces the cost of wind, solar and biomass energy by 1.9 cents per kilowatt hour generated, would help to increase renewable energy production nationwide. Geothermal energy is already covered by the PTC, as are wind, solar and biomass projects.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress two years ago in the Energy Policy Act of 2005, which I helped formulate, provided both grant and the tax assistance to encourage the development of wind, solar and biomass energy. But when you consider that large portions of the country, including 70 percent of Alaska, may contain geothermal resources, that there are thousands of lakes and small rivers and creeks that can power small-scale hydro electric development without requiring dams or affecting fisheries or the environment in  the least, and that thousands of miles of U.S. coastlines and river systems can generate electricity from emerging ocean energy systems, it only makes sense to expand the scope of Federal assistance to encourage wider development and use of these other renewable technologies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Electric Power Research Institute has estimated that wave energy off U.S. coasts alone could conservatively generate 252 million megawatt hours of electricity, 6.5 percent of all energy now produced in America. Alaska has nearly 80 coastal and river communities that could benefit greatly by development of ocean energy systems. To facilitate ocean and geothermal development, the bill authorizes $100 million in Federal research and development grant assistance to both types of development.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill is not a cure all for all of our energy woes. I recently co-sponsored legislation by Senators JIM BUNNING and BARACK OBAMA that will provide additional incentives to develop fuel from coal and that will encourage the sequestration of carbon from coal processed in fuel-to-liquid plants. I will support additional assistance to promote wind, solar and biomass alternative energy development. I have supported and will continue to support development of the next generation of  nuclear power that can produce energy without any greenhouse gas emissions. And I will continue to support research and development of biofuels, such as ethanol, especially celluosic ethanol, and of development of hydrogen-fueled vehicles and fuel distribution systems for the new fuels.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also will support production of more domestic energy from conventional sources, whether it be more oil and natural gas from the ground onshore and from under some of our seas offshore where it can be done in an environmentally friendly way, or more novel forms of fossil fuels, be they from oil shales, oil sands, coal or from gas hydrate deposits. In my view we need to do everything we can to find economic forms of the energy we will need during the remainder of the 21st Century.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill only represents one piece of a balanced plan to improve this Nation's energy outlook. But it is an important piece. This bill has the ability to restore and refresh our environment  by reducing greenhouse gas emissions. It will encourage development of more renewable energy. We can't afford not to find the funds to pay for its provisions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300024" topic="Introducing S. 299. A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to extend increased expensing for small businesses; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="299">S. 299</bill>] Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the text of my legislation to extend increased expensing for small businesses be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300062" topic="Introducing S. 300. A bill to authorize appropriations for the Bureau of Reclamation to carry out the Lower Colorado River Multi-Species Conservation Program in the States of Arizona, California, and Nevada, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="300">S. 300</bill>] Mr. President, today I am pleased to join with Senators Ensign, Feinstein and Reid to introduce the Lower Colorado River Multi-Species Conservation Program Act. This bipartisan legislation is designed to protect and maintain wildlife habitat on the lower Colorado River and to provide assurances to the affected water and power agencies of Arizona, California, and Nevada that their river operations may continue upon compliance with the underlying program. This  bill is nearly identical to legislation I introduced late last year with Senators Ensign, Feinstein, and Reid.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Lower Colorado River Multi-Species Conservation Program, otherwise known as the MSCP, is a comprehensive, cooperative effort among 50 Federal and non-Federal entities in Arizona, California, and Nevada whose purposes are to 1. protect the lower Colorado River environment while ensuring the certainty of existing river water and power operations; 2. protect threatened endangered wildlife under the Endangered Species Act; and 3. prevent the listing of additional species on the lower Colorado  River.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To accomplish these goals, the MSCP will create more than 8,100 acres of riparian, marsh, and backwater habitat and implement additional measures to protect 26 endangered, threatened and sensitive species. The program covers approximately 400 miles, including the full-pool elevations of Lake Mead to the United States-Mexico Southerly International Boundary.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The program costs will be spread over 50 years, and split 50-50 between the Federal Government and the non-Federal entities covered by MSCP. Arizona and Nevada will each bear 25 percent of the non-Federal costs and California will bear 50 percent of the non-federal costs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although implementation of the program began in April 2005 under the U.S. Department of the Interior's existing authority, legislation is needed to protect the substantial financial commitments that the non-Federal parties are making to species protection . To that end, the bill 1. expressly authorizes appropriations to cover the Federal share of the program costs; 2. directs the Secretary of the Interior to manage and implement the MSCP in accordance with the underlying program documents; and  3. provides a waiver of sovereign immunity to allow the non-Federal parties to enforce, if necessary, the underlying program documents. The waiver, however, does not allow an action to be brought against the United States for money damages.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Late in 2006, the House Committee on Resources, Subcommittee on Water and Power held a comprehensive field hearing in Arizona on the MSCP Act. The hearing highlighted the significance of the program to Colorado River users in Arizona, California, and Nevada and demonstrated the strong support for the legislation. Unfortunately, Congress adjourned before it could take action on the bill. We hope for its swift passage in the 110th Congress.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300022" topic="Introducing S. 301. A bill to provide higher education assistance for nontraditional students, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="301">S. 301</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to introduce legislation to meet the needs of non-traditional college students. If enacted, The Non-Traditional Student Success Act would expand services that promote retention and graduation for non-traditional students.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The number of non-traditional students has been increasing dramatically on college campuses all across America. These students face unique challenges to completing their degree that include affording their education, balancing work, school, and family responsibilities, overcoming inadequate academic preparation, and navigating the college environment. Unfortunately, many of our current higher education policies make it harder, not easier for these students to complete their degree.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In fact, among students seeking a bachelor's degree, nearly half of non-traditional students leave college within the first 3 years before completing their studies, compared with 12 percent of traditional students. Similarly, among those seeking an associate's degree, 62 percent of non-traditional students left without any degree, compared with 19 percent of traditional students. This trend has a disproportionate impact on minority communities especially when considering over 80 percent of both  black and Hispanic undergraduate students are non-traditional in some way. This trend must end if we are to ensure that all students are awarded an equal opportunity to compete for jobs in today's marketplace.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We must take a step forward with a positive agenda in the 110th Congress to ensure that all students are able to successfully acquire a college education as doing so is essential to our economic prosperity. That is why I have introduced the Non-Traditional Student Success Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Non-Traditional Student Success Act will tear down the financial barriers many non-traditional students face when financing their college education. By allowing students access to their Federal Pell grants year-round while increasing the maximum Pell grant award to $12,600 over the next 5 years, this bill will not only help students pay for college but also allow them the opportunity to complete programs more quickly. This legislation also creates a pilot program to provide more financial  aid--grants and loans--to students enrolled in a degree program less than half-time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation will also expand services that promote retention and graduation for non-traditional students. The Non-Traditional Student Success Act will increase funding for Student Support Service programs, GEAR-UP, mentoring, tutoring and other services to help non-traditional students succeed. While spending for remediation among U.S. colleges and universities approaches the $1 billion mark, this bill create incentives for institutions to customize their courses to help students more successfully  complete remedial work and graduate into academic programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am happy to report that two of the provisions from the previously introduced Nontraditional Student Success Act were enacted into law through the Deficit Reduction Act of 2005. These provisions, expanding the use of Pell grants for less than half-time students and a provision to reduce the work penalty for independent students, will provide more options to non-traditional students in financing their college education.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The fact is, three out of four undergraduate students--75 percent--are non-traditional in some way. My bill will increase access to a higher education and improve the graduate rates for the millions of non-traditional students.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The start of a new Congress brings an opportunity to provide critical changes in higher education and offer assistance to non-traditional students. This proposal is endorsed by the Commission on Independent Colleges and Universities, The Center for Law and Social Policy, Career Colleges Association, and the American Association of Community Colleges.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am hopeful that my Senate colleagues from both sides of the aisle will join in support of this bill and move this legislation to the floor without delay.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300098" topic="Introducing S. 304. A bill to establish a commission to develop legislation designed to reform tax policy and entitlement benefit programs and to ensure a sound fiscal future for the United States, and  for other purposes; to the Committee on the Budget.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="304">S. 304</bill>] Mr. President, a fiscal crisis looms on the horizon. As the Nation's demographic tide begins to shift, a fiscal tidal wave threatens to overwhelm our economy if we do not act now. Our irresponsible fiscal policies have created a grave situation that more and more people--Republicans and Democrats--are coming to recognize. We can no longer sit back and hope things will work themselves out. A potential national disaster threatens to devastate our way of life, and we have a moral  responsibility to do something about it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the simplest of terms, the Federal Government continues to spend more than it brings in. But, running the credit card for today's needs and leaving the bill for future generations should not be the policy of this Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An historical perspective helps to highlight the gravity of our current situation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Fiscal Year 2006 budget deficit was $248 billion--the seventh largest deficit in our Nation's history. However, if we don't include the money we're borrowing from the Social Security Trust Fund, the Fiscal Year 2006 budget deficit was $434 billion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I arrived in Washington in 1999, and in the 8 short years since, our national debt has increased by over 50 percent from $5.6 trillion to a staggering $8.6 trillion. It represents 67 percent of the GDP--the worst number in 50 years. This means that each man, woman, and child in the United States owes $29,000 of the Federal Government's debt.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And yet, these numbers pale in comparison with the budget problems looming in our future as the Baby Boom generation begins to retire less than a year from now, on January 1, 2008. Our long-term fiscal imbalance is $50 trillion. That's hard to even grasp, but it translates into $440,000 of future government debt for every American household--up from a mere $175,000 per household just 6 years ago.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If we do not sharply curb entitlement spending, the continual growth of these programs--especially in healthcare--will crowd out all our other spending obligations and collide with historic, long-term level of taxes. To put it in perspective, balancing the budget without reforming entitlement programs will require raising taxes to European levels. And, that would cripple our ingenuity and economy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, what must be done?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress must view our tax code, entitlement programs, and budget process as the three components--or pillars--of the nation's fiscal foundation, and not as separate entities. Each is intricately linked to the other two pillars. We must reform all three areas to raise the necessary revenue to ensure effective and responsible behavior by Congress and federal agencies, to keep our obligations to future generations, and to keep our nation strong.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, we need fundamental tax reform to help make the tax code simple, fair, transparent, and economically efficient. According to the President's tax panel and the Mack-Breaux report, only 13 percent of taxpayers file without the help of either a tax preparer or computer software program--a function of the complexity of the system. Since enacting the Tax Reform Act of 1986--legislation intended to simplify the filing process for taxpayers--15,000 additions have been made to the Internal Revenue  Code.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We cannot consider tax reform, however, without reforming our growing entitlement programs. Our already massive debt will spike yet higher as entitlements such as Social Security, Medicare, and Medicaid witness a surge of beneficiaries in the form of retiring Baby Boomers. This mounting debt will soon become a burden our children cannot bear, dragging down our standard of living and our standing in the world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, we must restore the third pillar of our fiscal foundation--the budget process. Together we can streamline the system to help lock in long term tax and entitlement reforms. In the past, every major deficit reduction package has included a series of budget process reforms and enforcement mechanisms designed to prevent Congress from undoing tough choices in future years. By transforming the budget process, we can fight back against the all-too-common practice of gaming the system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While some of our colleagues claim we need tax reform, others claim we need entitlement reform. The bill I am introducing today, however, is the only bill that does it all--because you can't reform one without the other, or it's doomed to fail.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Securing America's Future Economy Commission Act establishes a national, bipartisan commission to examine these broken systems and to present solutions to place the nation on a fiscally sustainable course and ensure the solvency of entitlement programs for future generations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Commission will be comprised of 16 voting members--an equal number of members from each party, with some seats reserved for sitting members of Congress. The Treasury Secretary and the OMB Director will be members, and the other 14 will be appointed by congressional leaders.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Commission will hold town hall meetings throughout the country to determine the scope of the problem and consider possible policy options. The Commission will present a report--and, if a three-fourths majority of the Commission agrees, they will present actual legislation to Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The administration and Congress will each have 90 days to review the proposal and develop an alternative package of reforms if they believe it's necessary. The most important point is that this legislation uses a fast-track procedure to guarantee a vote in Congress on the Commission's legislation and the congressional and presidential alternatives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Outside groups across the political spectrum have shown support for our efforts, as have business executives--who view our efforts as an economic necessity--and religious leaders--who view our efforts as a moral necessity. And, when you look at the numbers, it is clear why. We have a moral obligation to improve the fiscal health of our Nation. Otherwise, our children and grandchildren are going to celebrate America's past and the good old days, rather than the future and the good new days.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Restoring our Nation's fiscal health will require hard, bipartisan work and tough decisions. That work, however, must begin immediately. We cannot afford to put it off any longer.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="Introducing S. 305. A bill to amend the Packers and Stockyards Act, 1921, to make it unlawful for a packer to own, feed, or control livestock intended for slaughter; to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="305">S. 305</bill>] Mr. President, Congress will be working on a rewrite of the current farm bill during the 110th Congress and I will be looking for ways to improve the economic condition of America's farmers. However, one of the many shortcomings of the 2002 farm bill is that it failed to protect family farmers and independent livestock producers from vertical integration in the livestock industry. This is one reason why I voted against the final conference report.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over the years, family farmers from across Iowa have contacted me to express their fears about the threat they feel from concentration in the livestock industry. They fear that if the trend toward increased concentration continues, they may be unable to compete effectively and will not be able to get a fair price for their livestock in the marketplace.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill I am introducing would prevent meat packers from assuming complete control of the meat supply by preventing packers from owning livestock.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill would make it unlawful for a packer to own or feed livestock intended for slaughter. Single pack entities and packs too small to participate in the Mandatory Price Reporting program would be excluded from the limitation. In addition, farmer cooperatives in which the members own, feed, or control the livestock themselves would be exempt under this new bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a similar version I successfully offered on the floor during the debate on the 2002 farm bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It's important for our colleagues to remember that family farmers ultimately derive their income from the agricultural marketplace, not the farm bill. Family farmers have unfortunately been in a position of weakness  in selling their product to large processors and in buying their inputs from large suppliers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, the position of the family farmer has become weaker as consolidation in agribusiness has reached all time highs. Farmers have fewer buyers and suppliers than ever before. The result is an increasing loss of family farms and the smallest farm share of the consumer dollar in history.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One hundred years ago, this Nation reacted appropriately to citizen concerns about large, powerful companies by establishing rules constraining such businesses when they achieved a level of market power that harmed, or risked harming, the public interest, trade and commerce. The United States Congress enacted the first competition laws in the world to make commerce more free and fair. These competition laws include the Sherman Act, Clayton Act, Federal Trade Commission Act and Packers &amp; Stockyards  Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since that time, many countries in the world have followed this U.S. example to constrain undue market power in their domestic economies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, competition policy has been severely weakened in this country, especially in agriculture, due to Federal case law, underfunded enforcement, and unfounded reliance on efficiency claims. The result has been a significant degradation of the domestic agricultural market infrastructure. The current situation reflects a tremendous mis-allocation of resources across the food chain. Congress must strengthen competition policy within the farm sector to reclaim a properly operating marketplace.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While this legislation does not accomplish all that we need to do in this area, it's an important first step toward remedying the biggest problem facing farmers today, the problem of concentration.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thank you Mr. President; I ask unanimous consent the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300034" topic="Introducing S. 308. A bill to prohibit an escalation in United States military forces in Iraq without prior authorization by Congress; to the Committee on Foreign Relations.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="308">S. 308</bill>] Mr. President, last week President Bush announced a plan to escalate U.S. military involvement in Iraq, the continuation of his failed policy in Iraq. I am strongly opposed to this course.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is why I have introduced legislation today that will prohibit the number of troops in Iraq from exceeding the current force levels without an explicit authorization from Congress. As of January 16, 2007, United States Central Command reports 130,500 American service-members operating within the borders of Iraq.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is my hope that Congress can begin debate on my proposal and others that may be forthcoming before the week is out. It is imperative that we in Congress act swiftly on this crucial issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let's be very clear, my bill does not prohibit additional funding for American troops who are currently in harms way. I will continue to do everything that I can to support our troops so long as they are stationed in Iraq. My bill would prohibit President Bush from increasing the number of U.S. service-members in Iraq without prior authorization from Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The President's decision to escalate U.S. military involvement is a true disservice to American troops who have shown nothing but professionalism and courage, and who should not be asked to risk their lives to become cannon fodder in a civil war rife with ethnic cleansing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Moreover, I do not believe that the authorization provided by Congress in 2002 gives the President unlimited authority to send additional troops to Iraq for a mission which is completely different from the one the President himself articulated in March 2002, shortly after committing U.S. forces to Iraq. On March 22, 2002, the President of the United States said that our goal in invading Iraq was "to disarm Iraq of weapons of mass destruction, to end Saddam Hussein's support for terrorism, and  to free the Iraqi people."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We all now know that there were no weapons of mass destruction in Iraq to be disarmed. So we can no longer justify an additional troop presence on the grounds of WMDs. Saddam Hussein is no longer in a position to support terrorism, or anything else for that matter. As for freeing the Iraqi people--Iraq's dictator is dead and the Iraqi people have duly elected their own leaders to govern them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nothing in the 2002 resolution, or in the President's articulation of his goals for Iraq prior to that resolution suggested that the United States would, could, or should be engaged in trying to referee a civil war.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So Congress is confronted with two choices--do nothing; or respond decisively in opposition to staying the course--a course that is sure to produce an even more violent, less stable political and security climate in Iraq.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To me, that choice is clear. Leadership demands that those of us who think the President is on the wrong track, not simply stand up and say so, but act to stop this escalation from going forward.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I know that enacting legislation to stop the President from the course he has chosen will not be easy. But that doesn't mean that the Congress shouldn't debate it and vote on it--that is exactly what the American people sent us to Congress to do.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have arrived at a moment of choice. The President and this Administration have chosen escalation--more bloodshed, more chaos, and more violence. If the President wants to escalate our military commitment to Iraq, and if the President wants to send more troops into the center of a civil war, then the President must make that case to the United States Congress and let the full Congress vote on the merits of such a plan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The President has stated that he believes that as Commander-in-Chief he has the authority to order troops to Iraq in the face of Congressional opposition. We are a Nation of laws. The President is not above those laws. If Congress passes legislation to limit the deployment of troops to Iraq, the President will no longer have the luxury of ignoring the views of the Congress, a co-equal branch of government. And the time for a blank check is over.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400357" topic="Introducing S. 309. A bill to amend the Clean Air Act to reduce emissions of carbon dioxide, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="309">S. 309</bill>] Mr. President, today I am introducing the Global Warming Pollution Reduction Act of 2007. There are many critically important issues that we face, including education, health care, the growing and inexcusable economic inequality in this country, and the situation in Iraq. Among these issues has to be the threat faced by the earth itself due to global warming and that is why this legislation is the first bill that I am introducing as a U.S. Senator.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Global Warming Pollution Reduction Act, the full text of which I ask be included in the RECORD following my remarks, was initially introduced last year by the Senator whose seat I currently hold, Senator Jim Jeffords. Jim's leadership in offering a forwardthinking global warming bill is known by all in this chamber and I am honored to continue his efforts by introducing this tremendously-important legislation today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill, is being cosponsored by many of my esteemed colleagues and I would like to recognize them this morning: Senator Boxer, chairman of the Environment and Public Works Committee; the Senior Senator from the great state of Vermont, Mr. Leahy; both Senators from New Jersey, Mr. Lautenberg and Mr. Menendez; Senators Reed and Whitehouse, both from Rhode Island; the Senate delegation from the State of Hawaii, Senators Inouye and</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am also proud that the Global Warming Pollution Reduction Act has the support of numerous national groups, including the Earth Day Network, Earthjustice, Environmental Defense, Environmental &amp; Energy Study Institute, Friends of the Earth, Greenpeace, League of Conservation Voters, National Audubon Society, National Environmental Trust, National Wildlife Federation, Natural Resources Defense Council, Physicians for Social Responsibility, Public Citizen, Sierra Club, Union of Concerned Scientists,  and US PIRG.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Global Warming Pollution Reduction Act is based on the scientific evidence and consensus that global warming poses a significant threat to the United States and the world. In fact, with our national security, our economy, our public health and welfare, and our global environment at stake, we must do nothing short of taking bold action. To that end, I am proud that last week the Vermont state legislature began 3 weeks of hearings on global warming. Like Americans across the country, they want  action to fight global warming and they wish their Federal Government would step up and provide leadership commensurate with the magnitude of the threat. Well, Mr President this bill answers those pleas for leadership.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Grassroots support for action on global warming is clear. Over 300 mayors have committed their cities to meeting the standards described in the Kyoto Protocol. In fact, with over 54 million citizens represented, the U.S. Mayors Climate Protection Agreement provides clear evidence that everyday citizens--unlike some large corporations who have continually misrepresented the science of global warming--want to see movement on this issue. Additionally, a group of northeast States, including Maine,  Connecticut, Delaware, New Hampshire, New Jersey, New York, and Vermont, have already implemented a regional effort to reduce greenhouse gas emissions and other northeastern States, such as Maryland and Massachusetts, are likely to join this group soon. And, we all know that the State of California has recognized the need to act on global warming and is moving forward with a tremendous program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Despite the increasing calls for action, for years, the Bush administration has turned a deaf ear as the scientific community warned us of the problem of global warming and the disastrous impact it will have on our planet. Sadly, many of these predictions are now becoming a reality.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Global concentrations of greenhouse gases are incredibly high. In fact, the atmospheric concentration of greenhouse gases has risen to 378 parts per million--a level unseen during anytime over the past 400,000 years. Additionally, on a global scale, 8 of the 10 years between 1996 and the end of 2005 are among the warmest 10 years on record and experts at the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration have just logged 2006 as the hottest year on record for the U.S. Also, the National Center  for Atmospheric Research suggests that the majority of the ice caps of the Arctic Ocean will melt by the summer of 2040--decades earlier than previously expected. And, the situation has become so dramatic that the Department of the Interior recently suggested listing polar bears on the endangered species list because their habitat is quite literally</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The good news is that we know how to stop continued global warming--we simply need the political will to make it happen. The time is now for bold action that will move our country away from fossil fuels such as coal, gas, and oil towards efficient, sustainable energy sources like wind, solar, bio-mass and hydrogen. The bill I introduce today recognizes the urgency of our circumstances and sets targets for reduction of U.S. emissions to help stabilize global atmospheric concentrations of greenhouse  gases below 450 parts per million, a critical level as recognized by leading climate scientists. More specifically, this legislation calls for an 80 percent decrease--compared to 1990 levels--in global warming pollutants by 2050 by enacting a combination of mandatory reduction targets and incentives that will help develop clean alternative energies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The concept is simple. By putting our minds to it, we can usher in a new era of nonpolluting, renewable energy sources. And, what makes this proposal even more exciting  is its potential to reshape our economy and make the United States a leader in clean and efficient energy technologies--creating millions of good paying jobs in the process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In fact, it is a lack of bold vision that will financially cost us. In October of 2006, Sir Nicholas Stern, a former chief economist of the World Bank, turned the old economic arguments against taking action on climate change on their head. In a report to the British government, he writes that bold action to combat the threat of global warming will in fact save industrial nations money and that inaction could cost between 5 to 20 percent of global gross domestic product. Speaking to the issue  in no uncertain terms, the report states, "If no action is taken we will be faced with the kind of downturn that has not been seen since the great depression and the two world wars."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To be quite frank, the time for talk is over. It is time for action and introduction of this bill signals my commitment to pushing for such action.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While I ask unanimous consent that Senator Jeffords' full statement from last year on this important bill be included following my remarks, I want to read two excerpts from those remarks:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Global warming is real and it is already happening. Its effects are being felt across the globe and the longer we delay, the more severe these effects will be.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He went on to say,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In my final year in the Senate, I have often asked myself, "What lasting actions can I take to make the world a better place?" I hope that by proposing real action on climate change, and passing the torch to a new generation of those committed to protecting the environment, that I can help make a difference for us all.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I couldn't be more honored to carry on Senator Jeffords' vision on behalf of Vermonters and all Americans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In closing, a country that represents only 6 percent of the world's population but produces 25 percent of its  greenhouse gas emissions, the United States has a moral obligation to lead the way toward reducing these emissions. For the sake of our children and grandchildren, we must meet that obligation. This legislation will put us on the right path to do so.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the material be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
</record>
