<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1169571615" ordinal="6" title="SCHEDULE">
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, this morning, we will be in a period of morning business for 60 minutes. The first half of the time will be under the control of the Republicans and the second half of the time will be under the control of the Democrats.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Following morning business, we will resume consideration of <bill type="h" number="2">H.R. 2</bill>, the minimum wage bill. We will be in recess today from 12:30 to 2:15 for the party luncheons. As I indicated, we have two cloture motions that have been filed. The first vote, on line-item veto, will take place tomorrow. If cloture is not invoked, we will then proceed to a vote on the underlying bill, which is <bill type="s" number="2">S. 2</bill>.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There have been a number of amendments filed and that is very good. We are looking at a number of them closely to see if we can schedule a vote on one of them sometime this morning.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Looking at the schedule, we are going to have a couple of votes Friday morning, and everyone should understand that. The only way I can see that we will not have votes Friday morning is if we can figure out a way to finish minimum wage on Thursday. That is certainly possible. I am impressed with the seriousness of the amendments that have been offered. To this point, five amendments have been offered, and we certainly could complete this bill this week if we put our minds to it. I hope we can  do that. If we cannot, it will spill over into next week. I am not sure that is good; we have so many things that we have to do. I have had a number of conversations with the Republican leader and we are going to have debate on Iraq. We are going to make that as meaningful as possible. We are going to work together to see if we can limit the subject matter of the debate on Iraq. We hope we can do that. We also have other things that are facing us down the road, not the</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think we are at a point where we have a pretty good idea of the subject matter of the CR. There will be no earmarks, zero, not a single earmark on the CR. That is what we have agreed upon. Senator McConnell agrees with that, as I do, and the two appropriating bodies agree with that. So we are going to move forward on the CR. It is not going to be fun. I have been an appropriator here for many years, as has Senator McConnell. We like to do the regular process, but in my opinion  we cannot get to that unless we get the CR out of the way and work on the budget and get the appropriations bills done.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is my goal to work very hard to get the appropriations bills done this year. It has been done before and we can do it again. It has been done under Republican leadership and under Democratic leadership in the Senate. We have been working on it on a bipartisan basis. I think we can get it done.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a reminder, first-degree amendments must be filed at the desk by 2:30 p.m. this afternoon.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
