<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1192636802" ordinal="23" title="ANNA POLITKOVSKAYA">
  <narrative>ANNA POLITKOVSKAYA -- (Senate - October 17, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="12980">S12980</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400064" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, the Russian Federation is, in many respects, a democratic state. Elections are held at regular intervals, local and national elective bodies meet and pass legislation. Referenda may be held on major issues, both at the national and local level, although this exercise may be reduced in the near future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But there is another consideration, in which the Russian Federation falls short in its democratic characterization.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Freedom of the press is vital to the existence of a stable democratic state. Journalists must be able to openly report on all issues without fear of physical harassment or economic pressures. It is no accident that Napoleon said that four newspapers were more effective than a thousand bayonets.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Therefore, it is regrettable that a number of Russian journalists have recently been murdered while reporting on subjects sensitive to the Russian government. Other have been beaten or otherwise prevented from doing their job. One recent victim was involuntarily incarcerated in a psychiatric hospital.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Among those Russian journalists who have given their lives for their profession was Anna Politkovskaya, who reported extensively on the brutal war in Russia's secessionist region of Chechnya. Last week, friends, colleagues, and supporters of this courageous woman marked the one-year anniversary of her assassination.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Politkovskaya was fearless in her efforts to bring correct and unbiased information on the Chechen war to her readers. This was a hard-earned counterpoint to the propaganda that much of the electronic media turned out daily on the conflict ..... when there was any mention of it at all. While other journalists reported on the conflict from afar, she routinely traveled to troublesome areas to view and describe first-hand the problems and issues in the war-torn region. She was one of few Russian  reporters to actively engage the Chechen people in open dialogue, and she presented her findings in a fair and balanced manner. Her resume included a long list of awards and commendations for her investigative skills and professional competence.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On October 7th, 2006, Ms. Politkovskaya was carrying groceries up to her Moscow apartment when, according to authorities, a gunman clad in black fired twice, shooting her once in the head. The murderer left the weapon at her side, a brazen gesture indicating, or meant to indicate, the commission of a contract murder. The Moscow newspaper Novaya Gazeta, where Ms. Politikovskaya worked, suggested the assassin or assassins had been following her closely and probably for a long time. Indeed, she  was used to being watched and harassed. Numerous threats had already been made on her life, and at one point in 2001 she was forced to flee to Vienna.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As Co-chairman of the Helsinki Commission, I would also note that Anna Politkovksya delivered memorable and compelling testimony on the conflict in Chechnya at Commission hearings on Capitol Hill in September 2003, and she was awarded the OSCE Parliamentary Assembly's annual Prize for Journalism and Democracy in that year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Recently, several suspects were arrested in connection with the murder. However, there are disturbing reports that the investigation has been marked  by irregularities and apparent political considerations. For instance, Russian officials have been quick to assert that certain individuals and factions outside of the Russian Federation must have ordered the killing, although they have presented no credible proof. The fact is that Politkovskaya's work  was extremely critical of corrupt and incompetent officials in the Russian government. At the time of her death, she had been working on a story about the torture of detainees in the jails of the pro-Moscow Chechen authorities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The true instigator of this murder might well reside in Moscow, London, Grozny, or Murmansk. In any event, Russian President Vladimir Putin stated during a visit last week to Germany that the investigation is "on the right track." Let us hope that he is correct.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And let us also remember the sacrifice and the journalistic integrity of Anna Politkovskaya and her colleagues in Russia and throughout the world, who risk life and limb every day to discern the truth and bring it to their fellow citizens.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to comment on the status of the alternative minimum tax, AMT.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is some good news regarding the need to do a patch to protect 19 million families. If you look back over the last few months, I have come to the floor several times to urge my friends in the Democratic leadership in both bodies to focus on this problem and get legislation ready. Earlier today, I urged the House to begin work on an AMT patch bill. I urged them to send it to the Senate so that Chairman Baucus and I will have a vehicle to deal with this pressing problem.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have a few weeks to act before the IRS forms are finalized. After that time, there could be big problems for taxpayers and the Internal Revenue Service.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I was pleased to read in this afternoon's press reports that Chairman Rangel is going to process an AMT patch bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also want to commend our Finance chairman, my friend, Senator Baucus, for convening an informal meeting of the Finance Committee to discuss this pressing matter. I hope the Democratic leadership provides Chairman Baucus floor time to take up a committee bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On a related point, at a press event earlier today, in answer to a reporter's question, I indicated that we could look at measures to insure that certain high-income taxpayers who pay no regular income tax or AMT pay some tax. I would like to elaborate on that comment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have referred many times to the IRS statistic of high income taxpayers who pay no regular income tax or AMT. The statistic is that, for the tax year 2004, IRS Statistics of Income reported that 2,833 taxpayers with incomes over $200,000 paid no income tax. That same group paid no AMT as well. I will ask to have inserted in the Record a copy of that statistic.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The reason this group does not pay tax is defects in the AMT. What I was saying is that the AMT is defective in its original purpose. That is, to make sure that all high-income taxpayers pay some tax. I was not arguing for a tax increase on high-income taxpayers who are paying either regular income tax or AMT. I was arguing that, if anything, if the AMT's original purpose is to be served, then insure that those not paying ANY tax, pay it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Presdient, I ask unanimous consent to have a copy of the statistic to which I referred printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
</record>
