<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1192636802" ordinal="52" title="MEASURES READ THE FIRST TIME--S. 2179, S. 2180, S. 2184, S. 2185, H.R. 2102, AND H.R. 3678 EN BLOC">
  <narrative>MEASURES READ THE FIRST TIME--S. 2179, <bill type="s" number="2180">S. 2180</bill>, <bill type="s" number="2184">S. 2184</bill>, <bill type="s" number="2185">S. 2185</bill>, <bill type="h" number="2102">H.R. 2102</bill>, AND <bill type="h" number="3678">H.R. 3678</bill> EN BLOC -- (Senate - October 17, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="13025">S13025</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I understand there are six bills at the desk. I ask for their first reading en bloc.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the clerk will report the bills by title for the first time.</chair>
  <chair>The assistant legislative clerk read as follows:</chair>
  <chair>A bill (<bill type="s" number="2179">S. 2179</bill>) to authorize certain programs and activities in the Forest Service, the Department of the Interior, and the Department of Energy, and for other purposes.</chair>
  <chair>A bill (<bill type="s" number="2180">S. 2180</bill>) to authorize certain programs and activities in the Department of the Interior, the Forest Service, and the Department of Energy, and to amend the Compact of Free Association Amendments Act of 2003, and for other purposes.</chair>
  <chair>A bill (<bill type="s" number="2184">S. 2184</bill>) to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to permanently allow penalty-free withdrawals from retirement plans for individuals called to active duty for at least 179 days.</chair>
  <chair>A bill (<bill type="s" number="2185">S. 2185</bill>) to permanently extend the current marginal tax rates.</chair>
  <chair>A bill (<bill type="h" number="2102">H.R. 2102</bill>) to maintain the free flow of information to the public by providing conditions for the federally compelled disclosure of information by certain persons connected with the news media.</chair>
  <chair>A bill (<bill type="h" number="3678">H.R. 3678</bill>) to amend the Internet Tax Freedom Act to extend the moratorium on certain taxes relating to the Internet and to electronic commerce.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I now ask for their second reading en bloc, but I object to my own request en bloc.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Objection is heard. The bills will be read for the second time on the next legislative day.</chair>
  <chair><bill type="s" number="2179">S. 2179</bill> AND <bill type="s" number="2180">S. 2180</bill></chair>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources has reported over 70 individual bills and resolutions this Congress. Most of these bills are authorizations for specific projects and activities in the Department of the Interior, although we have also reported several measures involving National Forest lands under the jurisdiction of the Department of Agriculture, as well as a few authorizations related to the Department of Energy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Typically these bills would be considered in the Senate under a unanimous consent procedure. Unfortunately, although all of these bills are noncontroversial and all were reported unanimously by the Energy and Natural Resources Committee, we have been unable to get consent to pass these bills.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In an effort to facilitate passage of these bills, today I am introducing two bills which contain the individual measures reported by the committee. The first bill, the National Forests, Parks, Public Land, and Reclamation Projects Authorization Act of 2007, includes the text of 25 bills and 1 resolution which have been passed by the House of Representatives and which were reported, or their Senate companion measure was reported, without substantive amendment by the committee. If considered as  individual bills, upon passage in the Senate, these bills would have been cleared for the President. Since they will now be included as part of this comprehensive bill, it will require additional action by the House of Representatives, but I am hopeful that because all of the measures included in this bill were previously approved by the other body that they will be able to approve this bill expeditiously.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The second bill, the Natural Resource Projects and Programs Authorization Act of 2007, includes the text of 44 bills which originated in the Senate, or which passed the House of Representatives and were substantively amended in committee. Like the previous bill, all of the individual bills were reported unanimously by the Energy and Natural Resources Committee. While the House of Representatives has not previously acted on all of the individual components of this new bill, I believe these bills  are non-controversial, and I hope that the House will be able to consider this bill in a timely manner as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I have prepared a table identifying the individual measures that are included in both comprehensive bills, including references to the corresponding calendar numbers. I ask unanimous consent to have printed in the Record the table to which I just referred.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
</record>
