<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1202144402" ordinal="38" title="COMMEMORATING THE LIFE OF A. LEON HIGGINBOTHAM, JR.">
  <narrative>COMMEMORATING THE LIFE OF A. LEON HIGGINBOTHAM, JR. -- (Senate - February 04, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="611">S611</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400357" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of <bill type="sr" number="442">S. Res. 442</bill>, which was submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="442">S. Res. 442</bill>) commemorating the life of A. Leon Higginbotham, Jr.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400357" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table, with no intervening action or debate, and that any statements relating to this measure be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="442">S. Res. 442</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="442">S. Res. 442</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas the late A. Leon Higginbotham, Jr., dedicated his life to eliminating racial barriers in the society of the United States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, having grown up during the Great Depression and the era of Jim Crow laws, A. Leon Higginbotham, Jr., overcame a childhood marked by economic hardship and segregation;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, having personally experienced the effects of racism, A. Leon Higginbotham, Jr., sought an education and career in law during which he fought institutionalized racism in the United States judicial system;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas A. Leon Higginbotham, Jr., began his legal career as a law clerk to Justice Curtis Bok of the Superior Court of Pennsylvania and soon became the youngest and first African-American Assistant District Attorney in the city of Philadelphia;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, in 1954, when African Americans were largely excluded from professional opportunities, A. Leon Higginbotham, Jr., became a founding member of Norris, Schmidt, Green, Harris, &amp; Higginbotham, the first African-American law firm in Philadelphia;</chair>
  <chair>Whereas, while still in private practice, A. Leon Higginbotham, Jr., served as Special Deputy Attorney General for the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, Special Hearing Officer in the Department of Justice, President of the Philadelphia chapter of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, a member of the Executive Board of the Governor's Committee of One Hundred for Better Education, Commissioner of the Pennsylvania Fair Employment Practices Commission, Commissioner of the Pennsylvania  Human Rights Commission, and a member of the board of directors for various legal, political, and nonprofit organizations within Pennsylvania;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, having been appointed by President John Fitzgerald Kennedy to the Federal Trade Commission in 1962, A. Leon Higginbotham, Jr., became not only the first African American to serve on a Federal regulatory commission but also the youngest person to be named as a Commissioner of the Federal Trade Commission;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, having recognized A. Leon Higginbotham, Jr.'s gifts as both a lawyer and a public servant, both President Kennedy and President Lyndon Baines Johnson nominated A. Leon Higginbotham, Jr., as a Federal judge on the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Pennsylvania;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, upon confirmation as a Federal judge at the age of 35, A. Leon Higginbotham, Jr., became the youngest person appointed to the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Pennsylvania and one of the youngest ever appointed to a Federal bench;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, in his role as a Federal judge, A. Leon Higginbotham, Jr., served as a mentor to numerous young attorneys, affording them the opportunity to gain critical exposure to the legal profession;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas A. Leon Higginbotham, Jr., played an extraordinary role in the civil rights movement as an advisor to President Johnson after the tragic assassination of Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr., and as a member of the National Commission on Causes and Prevention of Violence;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, as the first African-American member of the Yale University Board of Trustees, A. Leon Higginbotham, Jr., successfully fought to allow women to enroll as undergraduates in Yale College;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, in 1977, President Jimmy Carter acknowledged A. Leon Higginbotham Jr.'s work as both a judge and a scholar and appointed him to the United States Court of Appeals for the Third Circuit;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas A. Leon Higginbotham, Jr,. sat on the Court of Appeals for 16 years and served as Chief Judge from 1989 until 1991 and as Senior Judge through the completion of his public career in 1993;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, through his rulings and subsequent writing, A. Leon Higginbotham, Jr., vigorously fought racial bias and prejudice;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, upon retirement from the bench, A. Leon Higginbotham, Jr., became the Public Service Jurisprudence Professor at Harvard University, dedicating the remainder of his life to educating and empowering future generations to continue the pursuit of equal justice under the law;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, A. Leon Higginbotham, Jr., served as the chairman of an American Bar Association panel that in 1993 issued the landmark report "America's Children at Risk: A National Agenda for Legal Action", studying the status of children in the society and legal system of the United States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, in 1993, A. Leon Higginbotham, Jr., served as counsel to the law firm of Paul, Weiss, Rifkind, Wharton, &amp; Garrison, where he litigated a host of pro bono matters, including voting rights in Louisiana, and advocated free elections in South Africa;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, A. Leon Higginbotham, Jr., brought his passion for equal justice into the international arena as a consultant to the President of South Africa, Nelson Mandela, on the formation of the Constitution of South Africa, and as an advocate for grass roots democracy education in South Africa;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, in 1995, A. Leon Higginbotham, Jr., continued his commitment to public service when appointed by President William Jefferson Clinton to the United States Commission on Civil Rights;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, as an author and contributor to more than 100 publications and academic works, A. Leon Higginbotham, Jr., left a legacy as a renowned scholar of racial and social justice issues in the United States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, A. Leon Higginbotham, Jr.'s critically acclaimed historical works, including "In the Matter of Color: The Colonial Period", published in 1978, and "Shades of Freedom: Racial Politics and Presumptions in the American Legal Process", published in 1996, continue to provide invaluable insight into the history of race relations in the United States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, as a sought-after public speaker, after his retirement A. Leon Higginbotham, Jr., delivered more than 100 speeches annually to motivate the next generation of people in the United States to continue the fight for racial justice;</chair>
  <chair>Whereas A. Leon Higginbotham, Jr., received numerous honors and awards during his lifetime, including the Presidential Medal of Freedom, the Raoul Wallenberg Humanitarian Award, the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People Spingarn Medal, the American Civil Liberties Union Medal, the Lifetime Achievement Award from the Philadelphia Bar Association, the Silver Gavel Award from the American Bar Association, America's Ten Outstanding Young Men of 1963 from the United States Junior  Chamber of Commerce, and honorary degrees from more than 60 universities; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas A. Leon Higginbotham, Jr.'s work as an esteemed jurist, scholar, and public servant helped transform the Nation's perception of race: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) commemorates the life of the late A. Leon Higginbotham, Jr.;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) salutes the lasting legacy of A. Leon Higginbotham, Jr.'s achievements; and</chair>
  <chair> (3) encourages the continued pursuit of A. Leon Higginbotham, Jr.'s vision of eliminating racial prejudice from all aspects of our society.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
