<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1173801604" ordinal="32" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, March 13, 2007, at 3 p.m. to hold a nominations hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="COMMITTEE ON HEALTH, EDUCATION, LABOR, AND PENSIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions and House Committee on Education and Labor be authorized to meet for a joint hearing on the No Child Left Behind Act during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, March 13, 2007 at 10 a.m. in room 2175 of the Rayburn House Office Building.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet to conduct a hearing on "Judicial Nominations" on Tuesday, March 13, 2007 at 10 a.m. in Dirksen Senate Office Building, Room 226.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Panel I: The Honorable THAD COCHRAN, United States Senator, R-MS and The Honorable TRENT LOTT, United States Senator, R-MS.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Panel II: Halil Suleyman Ozerden to be U.S. District Judge for the Southern District of Mississippi; Benjamin Hale Settle to be U.S. District Judge for the Western District of Washington; and Frederick J. Kapala to be U.S. District Judge for the Northern District of Illinois.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="SELECT COMMITTEE ON INTELLIGENCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Select  Committee on Intelligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on March 13, 2007 at 2:30 p.m. to hold a closed hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON OVERSIGHT TO GOVERNMENT MANAGEMENT, THE FEDERAL WORKFORCE, AND THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia be authorized to meet on Tuesday, March 13, 2007 at 2:30 p.m. for a hearing entitled, A Review of U.S. International Efforts to Secure Radiological Materials.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
