<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1176912003" ordinal="40" title="STATEMENTS ON INTRODUCED BILLS AND JOINT RESOLUTIONS">
  <speaking speaker="300070" topic="Introducing S. 1138. A bill to enhance nuclear safeguards and to provide assurances of nuclear fuel supply to countries that forgo certain fuel cycle activities; to the Committee on Foreign Relations.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1138">S. 1138</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today with my colleague from Indiana, Senator Bayh, to introduce the Nuclear Safeguards and Supply Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The future of the Nuclear Non-Proliferation Treaty and the larger nonproliferation system it supports is in doubt. The existing safeguards regime used by the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) has succeeded in forestalling nuclear weapons programs in the world's advanced industrial states, several of which were weighing the nuclear option 40 years ago. Unfortunately, this regime has failed to keep pace with the increase in the global availability of nuclear weapons technology, especially  the technology and equipment for uranium enrichment and spent nuclear reactor fuel reprocessing, which can produce fissile material for weapons. Now the road to nuclear weapons can be traveled by determined countries with only a minimal industrial base.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The construction of facilities for the enrichment of uranium and reprocessing of spent nuclear fuel in new states, even for ostensibly peaceful purposes, poses an unacceptable long-term risk to the national security of the United States. The enrichment technology intended to produce fuel for reactors can also be used to create highly-enriched uranium for a nuclear weapon, and the plutonium that is produced from reprocessing spent fuel is also suitable for nuclear weapons and susceptible to diversion  to terrorists. The spread of enrichment and reprocessing capabilities will dangerously increase the chances that new nations will develop nuclear weapons and that terrorists might obtain fissile or radiological materials for crude devices. It is therefore incumbent on the United States to lead an international effort to halt the expansion of enrichment and reprocessing to new countries.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We know President Bush shares our assessment of this situation. On February 11, 2004, he stated, "The world's leading nuclear exporters should ensure that states have reliable access at reasonable cost to fuel for civilian reactors, so long as those states renounce enrichment and reprocessing. Enrichment and reprocessing are not necessary for nations seeking to harness nuclear energy for peaceful purposes."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The threats posed by new nuclear fuel cycle facilities in new states are made worse by the fact that the use of nuclear power is likely to increase, both in developed and developing countries. As energy costs have soared in recent years, many states are reexamining nuclear power as a potential source of electricity. Importantly, however, the expansion of nuclear power does not require--either technically or economically--the construction of enrichment or reprocessing facilities in countries that  do not currently have them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator Bayh and I believe the United States should adopt as a basic nonproliferation principle that countries who give up their own enrichment and reprocessing programs have an assurance, either bilateral or multilateral or both, of nuclear reactor fuel at reasonable prices. Today, the market provides the basic framework for commerce in and access to nuclear fuel, and should not be interrupted by government action, but the exchange of nuclear fuel and fuel services for enrichment and  reprocessing capabilities is not currently explicit. This would also require that states agreeing to accept fuel services and leasing of fuel, in return for giving up joining the group of states possessing reprocessing and enrichment capabilities, would also consent to wide access and</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, as the world looks to increase the number of civilian nuclear power plants, the IAEA, charged with ensuring that energy programs do not stray into weapons efforts through the verification of safeguards agreements, operates on a shortsighted budget with old equipment. This situation threatens the institution, and to some degree the nuclear stability that the IAEA's safeguards verification mandate supports. The IAEA is responsible for verifying that states do not violate their obligations  under the Nuclear Nonproliferation Treaty (NPT). The IAEA monitors states' nuclear</paragraph>
    <paragraph>programs through safeguards agreements and additional protocols to ensure that nuclear material, equipment, and technology are used for declared, peaceful purposes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last November, I visited the IAEA and its Safeguards Analytical Laboratory (SAL), located just outside Vienna, Austria. Samples collected by IAEA inspectors during inspections are brought to the SAL to verify that safeguards obligations are being met and that there are no undeclared materials and activities. Unfortunately the laboratory's aging equipment and dangerous working conditions will hamper the important work done there, particularly as more samples arrive there and as more states expand  their nuclear power infrastructure. Such a situation could, in the future, shut down a critical nonproliferation facility. The IAEA's nuclear materials analysis capability is vulnerable to a single point of failure given the situation at SAL. Laboratory staff is also severely limited in the time they can spend analyzing evidence in the "hot" or nuclear</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Absent refurbishment of SAL, or the construction of a new IAEA facility with modem equipment, President Ronald Reagan's charge "trust but verify" will be abandoned because we have not taken action.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The SAL helped to discover the inconsistencies in Iran's cover-up of its nuclear weapons program. The analysis and questioning by inspectors prompted stonewalling by Tehran. The Iranian failure to provide information and access led the IAEA Board of Governors to refer the matter to the United Nations Security Council. While I wish this might have happened more quickly, the fact is that SAL, the network of laboratories in other Member States, and the IAEA's inspectors provided the evidence necessary  to build consensus on Iranian violations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Lugar-Bayh legislation works to create both bilateral and multilateral assurances of nuclear fuel supply by specifically authorizing the President to pursue such mechanisms. Importantly, our legislation takes note of the fact that merely ensuring fuel supply is not enough to truly deal with the potential proliferation that could arise as a result of many more nuclear reactors being built around the world. Proliferation of fuel cycle technologies may continue, regardless of the ability of  our Nation and others to craft layers of assurance in fuel supply. Our bill makes an important point--that fuel supply for new nuclear power is as important as the safeguards applied to nuclear power.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Lugar-Bayh legislation makes it the policy of the United States to discourage the development of enrichment and reprocessing capabilities in additional countries, and to encourage the creation of bilateral and multilateral assurances of nuclear fuel supply,  and ensure that all supply mechanisms operate in strict accordance with the IAEA safeguards system and do not result in any additional unmet verification burdens for the system. To ensure that  SAL does not cease to function, we authorize an additional $10,000,000 for the refurbishment or possible replacement of the IAEA Safeguards Analytical Laboratory. We also authorize the Secretary of State, in cooperation with the Secretary of Energy and the Directors of the National Laboratories, and in consultation with the Secretary of Defense and the Director of National Intelligence, to pursue a program that will improve nuclear safeguards technology development.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With regard to fuel supply, our bill authorizes the President to create, consistent with existing law, bilateral and multilateral mechanisms to provide a reliable supply of nuclear fuel to those countries and groups of countries that adhere to policies designed to prevent the proliferation of nuclear weapons and that decide to forgo a national uranium enrichment program and spent nuclear fuel reprocessing facilities. Such mechanisms must confront the challenges of international politics, thus  the authority contained in the bill is designed to provide a flexible framework, rather than a final set of requirements, for such mechanisms. The bill embraces both bilateral and multilateral fuel supply mechanisms, and calls for a report on the establishment of an International Nuclear Fuel Authority.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The United States cannot fix the IAEA's problems alone, but we must lead. An international diplomatic effort is required to raise the funds necessary to ensure that the IAEA has the resources and leadership it needs to continue its important mission. But the IAEA, its Member States and Board of Governors must also act. The Board must review and revise SAL staffing policies as they apply to professional staff working at SAL to ensure that it attracts and retains key personnel. Current policies  are self-defeating and force experts out just as they are accumulating the level of experience and expertise necessary to succeed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Not only is the existing IAEA infrastructure in desperate need of modernization, but a global nuclear power expansion will require a commensurate increase in IAEA capability. We must strengthen the organization to ensure that multiplying nuclear power facilities are not diverted to weapons work. This can and should be accompanied by better support to our own efforts in verification activities and technologies, such as through the Key Assets Verification Fund at the Department of State and the  U.S. Program of Technical Assistance to IAEA Safeguards or POTAS.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If the world is at the dawn of a new nuclear power age, then there will be more facilities and materials for the IAEA to inspect and verify. The IAEA is not prepared for such a future, but there is still time to put the necessary investments in place to ensure that it continues its important role. The United States and other Member States have the ability to plan and make decisions now that will ensure a safer nuclear power option in the future. It is incumbent upon the United States to assist  in the construction of the best possible safeguards system to provide for international peace and security. Peaceful uses of nuclear energy are only as good as the means to verify them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The current budget of the IAEA cannot sustain further stress, nor can the world afford to allow another state to develop nuclear weapons in secret. The IAEA is underfunded to perform its current tasks and would be required to do much more should nuclear energy become more widespread. The Bush Administration must significantly increase funding to the IAEA to improve its ability to exercise its rights and meet its obligations. We hope this legislation will begin that process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I look forward to working with my colleagues on the Committee on Foreign Relations on these important matters. I thank Senator Bayh for his partnership in this endeavor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="Introducing S. 1139. A bill to establish the National Landscape Conservation System; to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1139">S. 1139</bill>] Mr. President, together with Senators Salazar, Cantwell, and SANDERS, I am pleased today to introduce legislation to codify the National Landscape Conservation System, the collection of national monuments, national conservation areas, wilderness areas, wild and scenic rivers and other remarkable landscapes on our public lands administered by the Bureau of Land Management.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The National Landscape Conservation System was established administratively by the Department of the Interior in 2000 and consists of all areas the BLM administers for conservation purposes. The concept behind grouping all of these areas into one system was to increase public awareness of the importance of these lands and to highlight the BLM's conservation of these areas and their cultural, historical, scientific, and ecological significance to the Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Within my own State of New Mexico, the National Landscape Conservation System encompasses several nationally significant areas, including the rugged lava flows of El Malpais National Conservation Area, the unique cone-shaped rock formations of the Kasha-Katuwe Tent Rocks National Monument, the Rio Grande Wild and Scenic River, the Continental Divide National Scenic Trail and the El Camino Real de Tierra Adentro and Old Spanish Trail National Historic Trails, as well as over one million acres  of wilderness and wilderness study areas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, because the NLCS was established administratively, it does not have the permanence that it would have if enacted legislatively. In addition, legislative enactment of the NLCS will help increase the attention to these important, congressionally protected areas, and hopefully will help ensure that the system remains a high priority within the BLM and the Department of the Interior. The bill does not create any new management authority and does not change the authorities for any of the  previously designated areas within the system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Given the broad public support for these areas, I expect this bill to be non-controversial and it is my hope that it will be able to move quickly through the Congress and enactment into law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300049" topic="Introducing S. 1142. A bill to authorize the acquisition of interests in undeveloped coastal areas in order better to ensure their protection from development; to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1142">S. 1142</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today along with Senator Lautenberg to introduce the Coastal and Estuarine Land Protection Act. We are introducing this much needed coastal protection act along with Senators Cochran, Warner, Wyden, Kennedy, Lieberman, Snowe, Boxer, Kerry, Menendez, Cantwell, Feinstein, Reed, Murray, Collins, and Sununu. In addition, this legislation is supported by the Trust for Public Land, The Nature Conservancy, Association of Fish and Wildlife Agencies,  the Land Trust Alliance, The Conservation Fund, Restore America's Estuaries, The Ocean Conservancy, American Fly Fishing Trade Association, Society for the Protection of New Hampshire Forests, National Estuarine Research Reserve Association, Association of National Estuary Programs, Coastal States Organization, New Jersey Audubon Society, and the NY/NJ Baykeeper.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Coastal and Estuarine Land Protection Act promotes coordinated land acquisition and protection efforts in coastal and estuarine areas by fostering partnerships between non-governmental organizations and Federal, State, and local governments. As clearly outlined by the U.S. Commission of Ocean Policy, these efforts are urgently needed. With Americans rapidly moving to the coast, pressures to develop critical coastal ecosystems are increasing. There are fewer and fewer undeveloped and pristine  areas left in the Nation's coastal and estuarine watersheds. These areas provide important nursery habitat for two-thirds of the Nation's commercial fish and shellfish, provide nesting and foraging habitat for coastal birds, harbor significant natural plant communities, and serve to facilitate coastal flood control and pollutant filtration.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Coastal and Estuarine Land Protection Act pairs willing sellers through community-based initiatives with sources of federal funds to enhance environmental protection. Lands can be acquired in full or through easements, and none of the lands purchased through this program would be held by the Federal Government. This bill puts land conservation initiatives in the hands of State and local communities. This new program, administered by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, would  provide Federal matching funds to states with approved coastal management programs or to National Estuarine Research Reserves through a competitive grant process. Federal matching funds may not exceed 75 percent of the cost of a project under this program, and non-Federal sources may count in-kind support toward their portion of the cost share.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This coastal land protection program provides much needed support for local coastal conservation initiatives throughout the country. In New Hampshire, we have worked collaborative1y with local communities, environmental groups, willing sellers, and the State to conserve lands around Great Bay, Sagamore Creek, Massacre Marsh, Hurd Farm, Moose Mountain, Winnicut Headwaters, Marden Woods, Sleeper Wetlands, and the Piscassic River Greenway. These lands are home to a wide variety of plants and animal  species that are</paragraph>
    <paragraph>particularly threatened by encroaching development and environmental pollutants. By working with local communities to purchase lands or easements on these valuable parcels of land, New Hampshire has been able to successfully conserve the natural and scenic heritage of this vital estuary.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Programs like the Coastal and Estuarine Land Protection program will further enable other states to participate in these community-based conservation efforts in coastal areas. This program was modeled after the U.S. Department of Agriculture's successful Forest Legacy Program, which has conserved millions of acres of productive and ecologically significant forest land around the country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I welcome the opportunity to offer this important legislation, with my good friend from New Jersey, Senator Lautenberg. I am thankful for his leadership on this issue, and look forward to working with him to make the vision for this legislation a reality, and to successfully conserve our coastal lands for their ecological, historical, recreational, and aesthetic values.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300064" topic="Introducing S. 1142. A bill to authorize the acquisition of interests in undeveloped coastal areas in order better to ensure their protection from development; to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today to join Senator GREGG in our introduction of legislation that would help protect and preserve the valuable coastal and estuarine lands of our Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Development of the Nation's coastal and estuarine areas poses an increasing threat to water quality, wildlife habitat, flood protection, and recreational opportunities. The U.S. Commission on Ocean Policy emphasized that intact coastal lands are vital to ensuring the ecological and economic health of coastal communities. However, as these areas are fragmented and disappear, so do the benefits they provide. The Coastal and Estuarine Land Protection Act (CELP) would authorize the National Oceanic  and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) as the lead Federal agency supporting State, local or private acquisition of land or conservation easements in undeveloped coastal areas in order to ensure their protection from development. The Joint Ocean Commission Initiative has identified enactment of the Coastal and Estuarine Land Protection Act as a high priority for improving our coastal</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The CELCP complements private, Federal and State conservation programs. This program is based on the highly successful Forest Legacy program which is a Federal-State partnership program that supports efforts to protect environmentally sensitive forest lands. Permanent protection of lands in the coastal zone is also necessary to maintain and enhance coastal and estuarine areas for the benefit of the Nation, including protecting water quality, keeping public beachfront accessible, conserving wildlife  habitat, and sustaining sport and commercial fisheries.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Coastal and estuarine areas are some of the most productive ecosystems on earth. They are home to countless plants, animals, birds, and fish. These are complex ecosystems that provide a foundation for marine life as well as protection of inland areas from storm damage. Over the last 150 years the national system of estuaries has decreased in size because of our growing coastal populations and short-sighted land-use planning. Today our coastal areas are home to over 150 million Americans, about  53 percent of the U.S. population, and over 180 million people visit the coasts each year. Due to the increasing pressures from development in low-lying areas, NOAA has estimated 80 percent of our Nations' coastal waters are impaired for human use and marine life.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The National Estuarine Research Reserve System (NERRS) established under the Coastal Zone Management Act is a network of 27 protected estuaries throughout the United States, including the Jacques Cousteau NERRS site in New Jersey. These are pristine areas that provide public education and conservation awareness, and serve as living laboratories for scientific research. The funds provided through the CELP program established by our legislation would  promote the expansion of these estuarine areas and assist in keeping coastal ecosystems healthy and productive.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Federal funds help make New Jersey conservation possible. New Jersey's treasured natural resources--from the Meadowlands to the marshlands of Barnegat Bay--have substantially benefited from Federal support. The existing CELCP has aided in securing protection for over a thousand acres in New Jersey including lands for Gunning Island, Tuckerton Creek, and the Harbor Herons project. This week there will be a formal dedication of a 115-acre property, acquired with the aid of CELCP, on Potter Creek  in Berkeley Township for public use and recreation. Lands have been protected in the Manahawkin Marsh, for wildlife habitat, including migratory birds along the Atlantic Flyway. In Ocean County, the CELCP helped secure the acquisition of 800 acres on Tuckerton Creek in Little Egg Harbor which is vital to protecting Atlantic white cedar stands and improving the water quality of the Barnegat Bay. These projects have successfully protected our coasts while sustaining human activity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The coastal zone is essential to our country's prosperity and well-being. The coastal and estuarine lands are areas of national importance and they are vulnerable to human activities. From 2002 through 2006 twenty-five States have benefited from the CELCP. Now is the time for Congress to authorize this program to conserve lands that are vital to our Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill Senator GREGG and I are introducing today, the Coastal and Estuarine Land Protection Act, will ensure an ongoing partnership between Federal, State, and local governments to support the economic and natural resource base of communities through the acquisition of coastal and estuarine lands. This legislation offers the opportunity for States to protect coastal and estuarine areas that have significant conservation, recreation, ecological, historical, or aesthetic values and are  threatened by conversion to other uses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The organizations supporting this legislation include The Trust for Public Land, The American Littoral Society, NY/NJ Baykeeper, Association of Fish and Wildlife Agencies, Land Trust Alliance, Restore America's Estuaries, American Fly Fishing Trade Association, Society for the Protection of New Hampshire's Forests, National Estuarine Research Reserve Association, Association of National Estuary Programs, The Ocean Conservancy, Coastal States Organization, The Conservation Fund, The Nature Conservancy,  and the New Jersey Audubon Society. I ask unanimous consent that a letter of support from these groups be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to thank Senator GREGG for his long-time leadership on this issue. I would also like to thank Senator MIKULSKI for her many years of support for this legislation. I look forward to continuing to work with Senator GREGG and my colleagues in the Senate to ensure its passage so that we can fill this vital need for coastal and estuarine protection.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the letter was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300078" topic="Introducing S. 1143. A bill to designate the Jupiter Inlet Lighthouse and the surrounding Federal land in the State of Florida as an Outstanding Natural Area and as a unit of the National Landscape System, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1143">S. 1143</bill>] Mr. President, today I am introducing a bill designating the Jupiter Inlet Lighthouse and the 126 surrounding acres in Jupiter, Florida, as an "Outstanding Natural Area." The Jupiter Lighthouse is a local and regional icon, full of rich history and home to many endangered plant and animal species. Designating the lighthouse as an "Outstanding Natural Area" will preserve the rich cultural heritage and important ecological value of the site. This designation would give  the Jupiter Inlet the distinction of being the sole East Coast representative of the National Landscape Conservation System--the eastern counterpart to the Yaquina Head Lighthouse in Oregon.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill is the product of the hard work and cooperation of many people in Florida, including the Town of Jupiter Island, the Town of Jupiter, the Board of County Commissioners of Palm Beach County, the Loxahatchee River Historical Society, and numerous others. I am also pleased that Representative TIM MAHONEY is introducing similar legislation in the House of Representatives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300091" topic="Introducing S. 1144. A bill to provide for an assessment of the achievements by the Government of Iraq of benchmarks for  political settlement and national reconciliation in Iraq; to the Committee on Foreign Relations.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1144">S. 1144</bill>] Mr. President, I rise to speak to the monumental and consequential matter regarding the future course of the United States and our courageous men and women in uniform in Iraq.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, we are at a profoundly challenging moment in time, and at a critical crossroads with respect to our direction in this war. I know that none of us arrive at this question lightly. In my 28-year tenure in Congress, I have witnessed and participated in debates on such vital matters as Lebanon, Panama, the Persian Gulf, Somalia, Bosnia, and Kosovo. And indisputably, myriad, deeply-held beliefs and arguments were expressed on those pivotal matters--some in concert, some complementary, some  in conflict. Yet, without question, all were rooted in mutual concern for--and love of--our great Nation. And there was--and should not be today--no question about our support for our brave and extraordinary troops.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is therefore with the utmost respect for our troops that I today introduce a bill which allows them the ability to complete the mission they have selflessly undertaken, while assuring them that their valor shall not be unconditionally expended upon an Iraqi government which fails to respond in kind. This amendment requires that government to actually achieve previously agreed political and security benchmarks while the Baghdad Security Plan--commonly referred to as the "surge"--is in effect,  or face the redeployment of those U.S. troops dedicated to that plan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Specifically, this legislation would require that, 120 days after enactment--a point in time at which our military commanders have stated that they should know whether the surge will succeed--the Commander of Multi-National Forces, Iraq would report to Congress as to whether the Iraqi government has met each of six political and security-related benchmarks which it has already agreed to meet by that time. These six benchmarks are:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Iraqi assumption of control of its military .....</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enactment of a Militia Law to disarm and demobilize militias and to ensure that such security forces are accountable only to the central government and loyal to the constitution of Iraq .....</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Completion of the constitutional review and a referendum held on special amendments to the Iraqi Constitution that ensure equitable participation in the government of Iraq without regard to religious sect or ethnicity .....</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Completion of provincial election law and preparation for the conduct of provincial elections that ensures equitable constitution of provincial representative bodies without regard to religious sect or ethnicity .....</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enactment and implementation of legislation to ensure that the energy resources of Iraq benefit Sunni Arabs, Shia Arabs, Kurds, and other Iraqi citizens in an equitable manner; and</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enactment and implementation of legislation that equitably reforms the de-Ba'athification process in Iraq.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Iraqi Government must know that any opportunity gained from our increased troop levels in Baghdad is a window that we will soon close if it fails to take urgent action and show tangible results in tandem. If, at the end of 120 days, the Commander of Multi-National Forces, Iraq reports the Iraqi Government has not met the benchmarks, then the Commander should plan for the phased redeployment of the troops we provided for the Baghdad Security Plan, period.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is why, under this amendment, after 120 days, should the Commander report that the Iraqi Government has failed to meet the benchmarks listed, he will then be required to present a plan for the phased redeployment of those combat troops sent to Iraq in support of the Baghdad Security Plan and to provide plans detailing the transition of the mission of the U.S. forces remaining in Iraq to one of logistical support, training, force protection, and targeted counter-terrorism operations--i.e.,  those functions set forth in the Iraq Study Group Report. As General Petraeus stated in March, "I have an obligation to the young men and women in uniform out here, that if I think it's not going to happen, to tell them that it's not going to happen, and there needs to be a change."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The message must be loud and clear--the Iraqi government must understand in no uncertain terms that our presence is neither open-ended nor unconditional, and I support setting conditions for a phased withdrawal. My concern with the supplemental appropriations bill stems from the fact that it mandates a specific date for troop withdrawal by requiring it to occur within 120 days of passage. This arbitrary timeline would telegraph a precise and immediate departure date to our enemies that I believe  would jeopardize the security of our men and women remaining on the ground.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Moreover, this mandated, 120-day timetable does not place the necessary pressure and conditions on the Iraqi government to implement national reconciliation and solidify their own security. Rather, we should require that the Iraqi government complete work within 120 days on the specific, concrete benchmarks they have already agreed to that would lead to national reconciliation. If the Iraqis cannot meet these benchmarks within this 120-day period, our commanders should begin planning for the  phased redeployment of the troops we deployed for the Baghdad Security Plan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My colleagues may recall that I opposed the surge because I did not--and still do not--believe that additional troops are a substitute for political will and capacity. General Petraeus said last month that a political resolution is crucial because that is what will determine in the long run the success of this effort. I could not agree more. The fact is, America and the world require more than Iraq's commitment to  accomplishing the benchmarks that will lead to a true national reconciliation--we must see actual results. The Iraqi Government must find the will to ensure that it represents and protects the rights of every Iraqi.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After our four-year commitment, Iraq's Government should not doubt that we must observe more than incremental steps toward political reconciliation we require demonstrable changes. While limited progress has been made on necessary legislative initiatives such as the Hydrocarbon Law, it is in fact a sheaf of laws and not just a single measure that must pass to ensure that all Iraqis have a share and stake in their government. Chief among these are constitutional amendments which will permit Iraqis  of all ethnicities and confessions to be represented at the local level of government. Yet, so far, the review committee has yet to even finish drafts of these critical amendments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe we were all encouraged by the recent Ambassadorial meetings in Baghdad and the follow-on ministerial conference called at the Iraqi government's request. These talks are vital to securing Iraq's border, reversing the flow of refugees, and stemming the foreign interference which exacerbates sectarian divisions. But we also look for the Iraqi government's leadership in dismantling the militias and strengthening the National Army so that it is truly a national institution that can provide  the security so desperately desired by all Iraqis in every province.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are now three months into the surge, and our troops have made gains in reducing the still horrific levels of violence on Baghdad through their heroic efforts. Yet it is deeply concerning to me that--mirroring the slowness with which the Iraqi government has moved on political reforms--their sacrifice remains by and largely unmatched by their Iraqi counterparts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Two weeks ago, Leon Panetta, a member of the Iraq Study Group, wrote the following in a New York Times Op-Ed, ". . . every military commander we talked to felt that the absence of national reconciliation was the fundamental cause of violence in Iraq. As one American general told us, `if the Iraqi government does not make political progress on reforms, all the troops in the world will not provide security.' " He went on to enumerate the progress or, more to the point, the lack of progress toward  the agreed upon benchmarks and concluded that `unless the United States finds new ways to bring strong pressure on the Iraqis, things are not likely to pick up any time soon."'</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In fact, over the past few months, many have come to the realization that political action by the Iraqi government is a paramount precursor to  national reconciliation and stability and, without it, the Baghdad Security Plan is only a temporary, tactical fix for one specific location. And while we are hearing about incremental successes, I agree with Thomas Friedman who said recently in an interview, "there's only one metric for the surge working, and  that is whether we're seeing a negotiation among Iraqis to share power, to stabilize the political situation in Iraq, which only they can do ..... telling me that the violence is down 10 percent or 8 percent here or 12 percent there, I don't really think that's the metric at all."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To this day, the public looks to the United States Senate to temper the passions of politics and to bridge divides. And if ever there were a moment when Americans are imploring us to live up to the moniker of "world's greatest deliberative body," that moment is upon us.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If I had a son or daughter or other family member serving in Iraq, I would want at least the assurance that someone was speaking up to tell the Iraqi government--and frankly our government as well--that my family's sacrifice must be matched by action and sacrifice on the part of the Iraqi government. I would want to know that the most profound of all issues was fully debated by those who are elected to provide leadership. For those of us who seek success in Iraq, and believe that a strategy predicated  on political and diplomatic solutions--not merely increased troop levels--presents the strongest opportunity to reach that goal, let us coalesce around this bill, which will allow us to speak as one voice strong ..... together ..... and united in service to a purpose we believe to be right.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="Introducing S. 1145. A bill to amend title 35, United States Code, to provide for patent reform; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1145">S. 1145</bill>] Mr. President, our patent system is grounded in the Constitution. Among the specifically enumerated powers of Congress in Article I, Section 8, stands the command to "promote the progress of science and the useful arts, by securing for limited times to authors and inventors the exclusive right to their respective discoveries." Those discoveries have, since the founding of our Nation, made us the envy of the world. Our inventors, our research institutions, and the many companies that  commercialize those discoveries have brought a wealth of new products and processes to our society; we have all been the beneficiaries of that creativity and hard work.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Vermont has long played an important role in bringing such inventions to the public, combining `Yankee ingenuity' with lots of sweat equity. In fact, the very first U.S. patent was granted to Samuel Hopkins, a farmer in Pittsford, VT, who discovered a process for making potash. That ethic continues to the present day; just last year, inventors in IBM's Essex Junction plant received 360 patents 10 percent of IBM's total U.S. patents.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Vermont is special, of course, but not unique in this regard. American inventors are in every community, every company and school. They are individuals tinkering on the weekends in their garages. They are teams of PhDs in our largest corporations. They are scientists training students in laboratories at our colleges and universities. Our patent laws should support and reward all American innovators--independent inventors, small businesses, venture capitalists, academic researchers, and large  corporations. To do so, we must update our patent laws. Crafted for an earlier time, when smokestacks rather than microchips were the emblems of industry, those laws have served well but need some refinements.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator Hatch and I introduced an earlier version of this bill, <bill type="s" number="3818">S. 3818</bill>, last August. At that time, I said we had taken the first step down a road to real, constructive patent reform, which could reduce the unnecessary burdens of litigation in the patent system and enhance the quality of patents granted by the Patent and Trademark Office. Senator Hatch wisely noted that we would have to have continuing conversations about issues that remained unresolved. We have spent the time  since then hearing from all manner of interested parties, and indeed we have learned as much since we introduced <bill type="s" number="3818">S. 3818</bill> as we had in the two years prior to its introduction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In this Congress, the partnership is not only bipartisan but bicameral. We have reached not only across the aisle but across the Hill to work out a bill that joins the Senate and the House, Democrats and Republicans, so that today we are introducing a Leahy-Hatch bill in the Senate that mirrors a Berman-Smith bill in the House. The message is both strong and clear: We have a unified and resolute approach to improving the nation's patent system. We will all have time to focus on the bill's many  provisions in the weeks to come, but I would highlight three significant changes we have made since last summer, aided by the many stakeholders in this process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, the Patent Reform Act of 2007 now includes a pure "first-to-file" system, which will inject needed clarity and certainty into the system. The United States stands alone among nations that grant patents in giving priority for a patent to the first inventor, as opposed to the first to file a patent application for a claimed invention. The result is a lack of international consistency, and a complex and costly system in the United States to determine inventors' rights. At the same time,  our legislation provides important protections for inventors at universities, by permitting them to discuss publicly their work without losing priority for their inventions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second, poor patent quality has been identified as a key element of the law that needs attention. After a patent is issued, a party seeking to challenge the validity and enforceability of the patent has two avenues under current law: by reexamination proceeding at the USPTO or by litigation in federal district court. The former is used sparingly and some see it as ineffective; the latter, district court litigation, can be unwieldy and expensive. <bill type="s" number="3818">S. 3818</bill> had created a new, post-grant review to  provide an effective and efficient system for considering challenges to the validity of patents. The Patent Reform Act of 2007 has improved that system, and in particular, we have addressed concerns about misuse of the procedure. Post-grant review will include</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Third, we are keenly aware that a sound patent system needs fair and equitable remedies. As products have become more complex, often involving hundreds or even thousands of patented aspects, litigation has not reliably produced damages awards in infringement cases that correspond to the value of the infringed patent. Our bill last summer was our first effort to ensure that damages awards accurately reflected the harm caused by infringement. Subsequent conversations with many affected parties  have led us to language that, we believe, better serves that purpose and avoids potential pitfalls.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Patent Reform Act of 2007 is also significant for what is not included. <bill type="s" number="3818">S. 3818</bill> would have made three considerable changes to the patent laws that, upon further consideration and after listening to the affected parties, we have decided not to make in this year's legislation. First is the requirement that patent applicants not intentionally misrepresent a material fact or fail to disclose material information to the PTO. Candor and truthfulness are the backbone of the patent application system,  and are protected by the inequitable conduct doctrine. <bill type="s" number="3818">S. 3818</bill> would have weakened that doctrine, but it is preserved this year. Second, we maintain the traditional rule on attorneys' fees, instead of shifting fees and other expenses to the non-prevailing party as was proposed in <bill type="s" number="3818">S. 3818</bill>. Finally, we do not inject Congress into the ongoing</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If we are to maintain our position at the forefront of the world's economy, if  we are to continue to lead the globe in innovation and production, if we are to continue to enjoy the fruits of the most creative citizens, then we must have a patent system that produces high quality patents, that limits counterproductive litigation over those patents, and that makes the entire system more streamlined and efficient. This bill is an important step towards  that goal. I look forward to immediate and intense debate that will inform both the Members of Congress and the public about these improvements, that will allow us to further refine our legislation, and that will lead us to consideration on the Senate floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300052" topic="Introducing S. 1145. A bill to amend title 35, United States Code, to provide for patent reform; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today to introduce with Senate Judiciary Committee Chairman Patrick Leahy the Patent Reform Act of 2007, <bill type="s" number="1145">S. 1145</bill>. <bill type="s" number="1145">S. 1145</bill> represents years of careful negotiation and input from a wide-spectrum of stake holders. In fact, the 2006 Hatch-Leahy bill has served as a blueprint for this year's legislation and contains substantially similar language. Chairman Leahy's desire to have a piece of legislation that is both bipartisan and bicameral is a great  undertaking and represents a tremendous commitment by Congress to move forward in streamlining and strengthening our patent system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The patent system is the bedrock of innovation, especially in today's global economy. Last year, more than 440,000 patent applications were filed at the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO). The sheer volume of patent applications reflects the vibrant, innovative spirit that has made America a world-wide leader in science, engineering, and technology. Because America's ingenuity continues to fund our economy, we must protect new ideas and investments in innovation and creativity.  Patents encourage technological advancement by providing incentives to invent, invest in, and disclose new technology. Now, more than ever, it is important to ensure efficiency and increased quality in the issuance of patents. This in turn creates an environment that fosters entrepreneurship</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Additionally, the concentration of college graduates in Utah is contributing to the State's technological friendliness, attracting growth companies to Utah and creating new ones. There is a large, young adult population in Utah attending not only the two world-class research universities of the University of Utah and Utah State University, but also Brigham Young University, Utah Valley State College and Weber State University. These universities and colleges are strong economic drivers that encourage  technology industry growth in my State.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For years, Chairman Leahy and I have been working together to craft meaningful patent reform to address problems that have been identified through a series of hearings and discussions with stake holders. This bill addresses many of the problems with the substantive, procedural, and administrative aspects of the patent system, which governs how entities here in the United States apply for, receive, and eventually make use of patents.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Patent Reform Act of 2007 includes provisions to improve patent quality. Many complaints about the current patent system deal with the number of suspect and over-broad patents that are issued. Because bad patents are generally of little value to productive companies, in many cases their value is maximized by using them as a basis for infringement suits against deep-pocket defendants. This bill institutes a robust post-grant review process so that third parties can challenge suspect patents  in an administrative process, rather than through costly litigation. In the bill we introduced today, Section 6 has been tightened by including an anti-harassment provision to discourage companies from colluding and perpetually harassing one company. I am hopeful this will serve as a deterrent to those who seek to abuse post-grant review process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, <bill type="s" number="1145">S. 1145</bill> is designed to harmonize U.S. law with the law of other countries by instituting a first-to-file system. The United States is the only significant country following the first-to-invent system, in which the right of the patent lies with the first inventor, rather than the first inventor to file for a patent. The Patent Reform Act of 2007 provides greater certainty because the filing date of an application can very rarely be challenged.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="1145">S. 1145</bill> also seeks to provide fair and equitable remedies. Some claim that courts have allowed damages for infringement to be based on the market for an entire product when all that was infringed is a minor component of the product. The bill's language preserves the current rule that mandates that a damages award shall not be less than a reasonable royalty for the infringed patent, and further requires the court to conduct an analysis to ensure that when a reasonable royalty is the award, it  reflects only the economic value of the patent's specific contribution over the prior art.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are a few provisions I believe need further discussion. I was disappointed that the inequitable conduct provision from last year's bill was removed. Attorneys well know that the inequitable conduct defense has been overpleaded and has become a drag on the litigation process. I think last year's language struck the correct balance by focusing on the patentability of the claims in dispute and properly prevented parties from asserting the defense frivolously. Let me hasten to add that I do  believe there should be consequences for misconduct. I believe that reforms to the inequitable conduct defense should focus on the nature  of the misconduct and not permit the unenforceability of a perfectly valid patent on a meritorious invention. And, sanctions should be commensurate with the misconduct.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Moreover, establishing inequitable conduct is supposed to require independent proof that: (1) the information at issue was material; and (2) the person who failed to disclose it or made the misrepresentation had the specific intention of misleading the USPTO. The two elements have become linked, and courts often discount the intent requirement by finding that the information is "highly material." In fact, the materiality standard has become so inclusive that virtually anything now is portrayed  as material. Information should only be considered material when it causes the USPTO to improperly grant patent claims. Using a standard of whether USPTO examiners would reject the claims is a good approximation of materiality because of the prima facie standard they use to determine whether the claims meet the requirements for patentability. Unfortunately, this bill preserves the status quo.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A provision that would provide attorneys' fees and costs to a prevailing party was also left out of this bill. I included this provision in last year's bill to discourage weak cases from clogging the already-burdened judicial system. This is not a new concept in the realm of intellectual property. In fact, I note, Section 505 of the Copyright Act clearly provides courts the discretion to award attorneys' fees and costs. It seems logical that we would provide the same discretion in <bill type="s" number="1145">S. 1145</bill> and  I look forward to discussing this issue with Chairman Leahy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We opted this year not to include a provision that would repeal Section 271(f) of Title 35, pending a Supreme Court decision that is expected soon. Section 271(f) creates a cause of action for infringement due to foreign sales when a component of a patented invention is supplied from this country, knowing that a component will be combined in an infringing manner outside the United States. In the event of an unfavorable ruling, Chairman Leahy and I are committed to addressing this issue  using the legislative process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Patent law is vital to our Nation's ability to compete in the global economy. <bill type="s" number="1145">S. 1145</bill> is designed to ensure that the United States remains at the forefront of developing and translating new ideas into tangible goods and services through an effective patent review and protection system</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill represents a commitment from Congress to move forward in streamlining and strengthening our patent system. I am hopeful that further refinements will be made to this bill during the legislative process. I am committed to moving this legislation forward and hope that we can join efforts to refine and enact this important bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400619" topic="Introducing S. 1146. A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to improve health care for veterans who live in rural areas, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1146">S. 1146</bill>] Mr. President, today I am introducing the Rural Veterans Healthcare Improvement Act of 2007, with my colleague from South Dakota, Senator Thune, and my colleague from Montana, Senator Tester. We are pleased to be joined by Senators Burr, Murray, Grassley, Wyden, Collins, Pryor, Enzi, Lincoln, Snowe, Kerry, Bingaman, Smith, Baucus, and Dorgan.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over the last two years my colleagues have heard me speak repeatedly about the challenges that are facing rural America. In the America where I grew up--the America of farmers, ranchers, small business owners, and generations of close-knit families--it is getting more difficult to make a living, to access affordable healthcare, and to provide opportunities for kids to learn and grow.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The challenges facing veterans in rural communities are particularly grave. For generations, men and women from rural America have devoted themselves to the cause of freedom without hesitation and in numbers greatly beyond their proportion of the U.S. population. Yet we consistently overlook the unique challenges these men and women face after they return home to their families and friends in the heartland of America. When it comes to the VA healthcare system, we fail our Nation's rural veterans  by not doing more to ensure they can access the high-quality health care they have earned. We owe them much better.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over and over, I hear from veterans in my state about obstacles to care. In northwest Colorado, veterans must brave three and four hour drives on winding mountain roads to reach the VA hospital in Grand Junction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In northeast Colorado I have heard from a veteran who must travel 500 miles round trip just to get a simple blood test at a VA hospital. I think most of my colleagues would agree with me that this is ludicrous.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I wish I could say these are isolated circumstances. Unfortunately, they are not. Because of gaps in the network of VA hospitals and clinics, we hear stories like this all the time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Every day, veterans from rural communities throughout the country are forced to put off crucial treatment because they live too far from VA facilities and can't get the care they need. As a result, rural veterans die younger and suffer from more debilitating illnesses--all because our system is not equipped to address their needs and provide care accordingly. A 2004 study of over 750,000 veterans conducted by Dr. Jonathan Perlin, the Under Secretary for Health at the VA, consistently found that  veterans living in rural areas are in poorer health than their urban counterparts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last year, we took an important first step in improving care for rural veterans. Thanks to the bipartisan efforts of my colleagues on the Veterans' Affairs Committee, we were able to create the Office of Rural Health within the VA. The Office of Rural Health is charged with working to reduce the wide disparities between care for rural and non-rural veterans by developing and refining policies and programs to improve care and services for rural veterans. Because nearly one in every four veterans  is from a rural area, the creation of this Office of Rural Health is crucial if we are to live up to our promise to provide all of our Nation's veterans with high-quality services.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill we are introducing today, the Rural Veterans Healthcare and Improvement Act of 2007, builds on last year's work by giving direction and resources to the Office of Rural Health and by making healthcare more accessible to veterans in rural areas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill tasks the Office of Rural Health with developing demonstration projects that would expand care in rural areas through partnerships between the VA, Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services, and the Department of Health and Human Services at critical access hospitals and community health centers. The bill also instructs the Director of the Office of Rural Health to carry out demonstration projects in partnership with the Indian Health Service to improve healthcare for Native American  veterans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, the Rural Veterans Healthcare Improvement Act of 2007 establishes centers of excellence to research ways to improve care for rural veterans. The centers would be based at VA medical centers with strong academic connections. The Office of Rural Health would establish between one and five centers across the country with the advice of an advisory panel.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Rural Veterans Healthcare Improvement Act includes two key provisions that will help veterans in rural areas reach healthcare facilities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, the bill establishes the VetsRide grant program to provide innovative transportation options to veterans in remote rural areas. The bill tasks the Director of the Office of Rural Health to create a program that would provide grants of up to $50,000 to veterans' service organizations and State veterans' service officers to assist veterans with travel to VA medical  centers and to improve healthcare access in remote rural areas. The bill authorizes</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Secondly, the bill increases the reimbursement rates for veterans for their travel expenses related to VA medical care so that they are compensated at the same rate paid to federal employees.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, our bill requires the VA to report to Congress on the assessment it is conducting of its fee-based healthcare policies. We need to improve the VA's fee-based healthcare policies to be more equitable and efficient in helping veterans in rural areas get the care they deserve.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With almost one-quarter of our Nation's veterans living in rural communities, and with the obstacles they face in accessing high-quality care, it is evident that we need to do a better job of making sure they receive the care they deserve. The creation of the Office of Rural Veterans Healthcare was a first step, and this legislation will move us further down the path toward improved care.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to again thank my colleague from South Dakota, Senator Thune, and my colleague from Montana, Senator Tester, for their efforts on this bill. We have a strong group of 17 Senators from both sides of the aisle behind this bill so far.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I know that each and every one of my colleagues deals with veterans' issues and feels a deep sense of gratitude towards the brave men and women who have fought for our freedom. I hope we can join together to move this legislation through Congress and send it to the President for his signature.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="Introducing S. 1147. A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, To terminate the administrative freeze on the enrollment into the health care system of the Department of Veterans Affairs of veterans in the lowest priority category for enrollment (referred to as &quot;Priority 8&quot;); to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1147">S. 1147</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to introduce the Honor Our Commitment to Veterans Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>More than four years ago, the Bush Administration cut off enrollment of Priority 8 veterans in the VA healthcare system. Priority 8 veterans are those veterans without service-connected disabilities whose income is above a means tested level that varies across the country. Many of these so-called "high-income veterans" have annual incomes as low as $26,902.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When the Administration announced its intention to suspend healthcare enrollment for new Priority 8 veterans, they said that they were doing so in order to reduce the backlog and alleviate a longstanding funding crisis within the VA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is no doubt that the VA has problems. Nearly five years into this war, our veterans are facing lengthy waits just to get in the door to see a primary care physician. They are having trouble accessing critical mental health services, and some are waiting up to two years for benefits claims to be processed. These are real problems facing real people, and they deserve real solutions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But instead of cutting off enrollment to veterans of modest means four years ago, the Bush Administration should have asked Congress for the resources necessary to address its shortcomings and increase access to this high quality health care system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is absolutely unacceptable that veterans in need of care are being prohibited from enrolling in the system that is supposed to serve them. Veterans who have fought hard to secure our freedoms shouldn't have to fight for access to health care at home. Our veterans deserve better.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is why I am introducing the Honor Our Commitment to Veterans Act today, which would permit new Priority 8 veterans to enroll in the VA healthcare system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>According to a recent Congressional Research Service report, the VA estimates that if the enrollment freeze was lifted, approximately 273,000 Priority 8 veterans would have been eligible to receive medical care from VA in FY2006, and 242,000 Priority 8 veterans would be eligible in FY2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation, which has been introduced in the House by Congressman Steve Rothman of New Jersey, would correct the injustice perpetrated in 2003 by allowing all new Priority 8 veterans to enroll in the VA healthcare system.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300061" topic="Introducing S. 1149. A bill to amend the Federal Meat Inspection Act and the Poultry Products Inspection Act to authorize the interstate distribution of State-inspected meat and poultry if the Secretary of Agriculture determines that the State inspection requirements are at least equal to Federal inspection requirements and to require the Secretary to reimburse State agencies for part of the costs of the inspections; to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1149">S. 1149</bill>] Mr. President, I am today introducing with Senators Baucus and Conrad a bill that will eliminate the prohibition on interstate commerce in State-inspected meat and poultry products. Senator Hatch is also introducing a State meat inspection measure and I congratulate him on his bill. We are working together and in collaboration with the National Association of State Departments of Agriculture and a coalition of national, State, and local agricultural organizations  on this effort. I expect our coalition to grow over time. Together, we intend to push for changes that will protect public health and safety and at the same time help state-inspected meat and poultry processors compete in new markets.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Removing the current prohibition will help level the playing field for small businesses and spur additional competition in the marketplace. It will help main street businesses--who often specialize in local, organic, grass-fed or artisinal products--meet emerging markets. And it will help livestock producers who want more options for marketing their livestock.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For too long, processors with State-inspected facilities have been unfairly constrained to selling only within their home States. Meanwhile, foreign-processed meat can be shipped anywhere in the United States so long as the originating Nation's inspection program is deemed equivalent to U.S. Federal standards. We want our State-inspected processors to be treated at least as well. This is an effort to give main street businesses the same opportunity our Government confers on foreign processors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I look forward to working with Senators Hatch, Baucus and Conrad and a number of our House colleagues on this topic in the months to come.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300091" topic="Introducing S. 1153. A bill to require assessment of the impact on small business concerns of rules relating to internal controls, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1153">S. 1153</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today with my colleague Senator Coleman, to introduce the "Small Business Regulatory Review Act." This is a targeted, non-controversial measure. It would ensure that the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) and the Public Company Accounting Oversight Board (PCAOB) fully consider the impacts of their final rules mandating how small public companies must comply with the internal control requirements of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our Nation's small stock companies are the cornerstone of our entrepreneurial economy, and it is essential that we carefully address the regulatory barriers that impede their growth.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Sarbanes-Oxley Act was essential in restoring investor confidence after accounting fraud and massive company deceptions shook the public's trust in U.S. markets. The horrendous debacle of corporate greed from companies like Enron and Worldcom forced not only thousands of employees to lose their jobs, but also wiped out the life savings of many retirees. Now, as we refine Sarbanes-Oxley's regulations, we must carefully preserve investor protections and ensure company transparency and accountability.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In my home State of Maine, small publicly-traded companies are indispensable to the strength and renewal of our economy. However, the fact is that many of these small stock companies are struggling mightily with the cost and regulatory burden imposed by Sarbanes-Oxley compliance, regardless of  their industry. Whether it's a utility company, a dairy pharmaceutical company that makes large animal vaccines, or a community bank that fears being smothered  by the combined weight of Sarbanes-Oxley and banking regulations, it is crucial that Maine's home grown companies focus their energies on developing new products, entering new markets, and creating jobs--not on compliance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is why I rise today, with Senator Coleman, to introduce the "Small Business Regulatory Review Act of 2007." Our bill would require the SEC to conduct a small business analysis, consistent with the Regulatory Flexibility Act (RFA), before the SEC publishes its final rules on small business internal controls compliance. This non-controversial provision simply restates existing law, ensuring that the SEC conducts a final RFA analysis. As the SEC should already be conducting this  analysis as part of its final rulemaking process, this bill will impose no additional delay.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our bill would also require the SEC to publish a small business compliance guide, consistent with the Small Business Regulatory Enforcement Fairness Act (SBREFA). This compliance guide would explain, in plain language, the small business requirements under the rule. The SEC should publish this small businesses compliance guide when it publishes its final rule, so that small business understand the new requirements. As this non-controversial provision also restates existing law, this measure would  impose no additional delay on the SEC's rulemaking process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Regulations disproportionately affect small businesses and significantly hinder their competitiveness. In 2004, Senator Enzi and I jointly requested that the Government Accountability Office (GAO) study the effects of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act on small public companies' access to capital. The study found that the costs for complying with Sarbanes-Oxley were nine times greater for smaller companies than for large stock companies. We must reduce the burden imposed by Sarbanes-Oxley so that  our small stocks in Maine, Minnesota, and across the country can continue to be some of the world's fastest growing and most innovative companies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, to address this disproportionate regulatory burden on small businesses, our bill would require that the GAO re-analyze the impact of these rules on small public companies two years after final rules are published. The GAO's report would include an assessment of the costs and time commitments the SEC and PCAOB requirements impose on small businesses and whether these costs are expected to decrease or increase in the future. Additionally, the final report would include recommendations,  and regulatory alternatives, on how to simplify or improve the process of complying with SEC and PCAOB small company stock requirements. This provision simply ensures that the rules do not impose unintended, undue burdens on small businesses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The "Small Business Regulatory Review Act of 2007" will help to ensure that small stock companies do not suffer from additional unintended consequences which harm their ability to compete, innovate, and grow--and, most importantly, create jobs.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300037" topic="Introducing S. 1155. A bill to treat payments under the Conservation Reserve Program as rentals from real estate; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1155">S. 1155</bill>] Mr. President, today I am joined by Senator Brownback and ten of our colleagues in introducing the Conservation Reserve Program Tax Fairness Act of 2007. This legislation clarifies once and for all that Conservation Reserve Program (CRP) payments received by active or retired farmers, or other landowners for that matter will be treated for Federal tax purposes as rental payments that are not subject to self-employment taxes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me take a moment to describe this problem. For many years now, the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) has been taking the erroneous position that CRP payments received by farmers are self-employment income derived from a trade or business and therefore are subject to Self-Employment Contributions Act (SECA) taxes. Regrettably, the IRS and the Treasury Department proposed a new ruling late last year that not only requires active farmers to pay SECA taxes on CRP payments but expands similar tax  treatment to CRP payments received by retired farmers and other landowners.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This latest ruling proposed by the IRS would impose a significant financial hardship on family farmers and others who have voluntarily agreed to take environmentally-sensitive lands out of farm production and place them in the Conservation Reserve Program in return for an annual rental payment from the Commodity Credit Corporation of the U.S. Department of Agriculture.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, North Dakota has some 3.4 million acres with about $112 million in rental payments in the CRP program. Left intact, the IRS's ruling would mean that farmers in North Dakota may owe an additional $16 million in Federal taxes this coming year. A typical North Dakota farmer with 160 acres of CRP would owe nearly $750 in new self-employment taxes because of the agency's ill-advised position.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If the IRS decides to pursue back taxes on returns filed by farmers in past years, the amount of taxes owed by individual farmers for CRP payments could amount to thousands of dollars. That would be devastating to many farmers and others who depend on CRP rental payments to make ends meet. As a result, the proposed change in our bill applies to CRP payments made in open tax years before, on, or after the date of its enactment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We believe the IRS's position on the tax treatment of CRP payments is dead wrong. In our judgment, forcing CRP recipients to pay self-employment taxes on CRP payments is not what Congress intended, nor is it supportable in law. The U.S. Tax Court, the Federal court with the most expertise on tax issues, shares our view that the IRS position is improper. In fact, the U.S. Tax Court ruled in the late 1990's that CRP payments are properly treated by farmers as rental payments and, thus, not subject  to self-employment taxes. Unfortunately, the IRS challenged the Tax Court decision and the Tax Court was later reversed by a Federal appellate court.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In February, IRS Commissioner Mark Everson sent a letter to me and a number of our colleagues who are concerned about this issue. In his letter, Commissioner Everson made clear that the IRS would not change its position that CRP payments are subject to self-employment tax as income derived from a trade or business--absent new statutory language passed by the Congress and enacted into law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With the legislation we are introducing today, Congress will send a clear message to the IRS that its misguided effort to subject CRP payments to self-employment taxes is inappropriate and will not be allowed to stand. Our bill also makes sure that Federal trust funds that would have received SECA revenues but for the enactment of our bill are held harmless through the use of revenue transfers from the Treasury general fund.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator Brownback and I ask our colleagues to support this much-needed tax relief for family farmers and other CRP recipients by cosponsoring the Conservation Reserve Program Tax Fairness Act. And we hope you will work with us to get this legislation enacted into law without delay.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300034" topic="Introducing S. 1156. A bill to amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to reauthorize the Best Pharmaceuticals for Children program; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1156">S. 1156</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to introduce the Best Pharmaceuticals for Children Amendments of 2007, which is a bill to reauthorize the Best Pharmaceuticals for Children Act--BPCA. If Congress doesn't act, this successful program will expire on October I, 2007. I thank my colleagues Senators KENNEDY, HARKIN, BINGAMAN, MURRAY, CLINTON and BROWN who are joining me as original cosponsors of this important legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am pleased that Senators KENNEDY and ENZI, the distinguished chairman and ranking member of the Health Education Labor, and Pensions--HELP--Committee, have included this bill in the chairman's mark for <bill type="s" number="1082">S. 1082</bill>, which is expected to be voted on today in the HELP Committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would also like to recognize the contributions and leadership of former Senator Mike De Wine, a friend and colleague, who always fought to ensure children would not be treated as second-class citizens when it came to drug and device development. He was a champion of BPCA along with me even when it wasn't popular to hold that view.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The story of the Best Pharmaceuticals for Children Act is one of huge success for children and their families. Children with a wide range of diseases such as HIV/AIDS, cancer, allergies, asthma, neurological and psychiatric disorders, and obesity can now lead healthier, more productive lives as a result of new information about the safety and efficacy of drugs they use to treat and manage their diseases where previously there was none.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Children are not simply little adults and results of the drug studies conducted under the BPCA have shown us that they should not be treated as such. Pediatric drug studies conducted. under the BPCA showed that children may have been exposed to ineffective drugs, ineffective dosing, overdosing, or side effects that were previously unknown.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since the BPCA's passage in 1997 and its reauthorization in 2002, FDA has requested nearly 800 studies involving more than 45,000 children in clinical trials. Useful new pediatric information is now part of product labeling for 119 drugs. By comparison, in the 7 years prior to the BPCA's passage, only 11 studies of marketed drugs were completed. In the past 10 years, there has been a twentyfold increase in the number of drugs studied in infants, children, and adolescents since BPCA was enacted.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Labeling changes resulting from clinical studies under the BPCA have informed physicians of the proper dosing in the examples of Viracept, a protease inhibitor used in a combination therapy for the treatment of HIV, and Neurontin, a pain relief medication used to treat children with chronic pain. For children with epilepsy, the BPCA studies informed physicians that the drugs Keppra and Trileptal could be used safely and effectively at an even earlier age than previously known. Studies of Imitrex  as a result of the BPCA showed no better results than placebo for the treatment of migraine headaches in adolescents. These same studies also showed serious adverse events due to Imitrex in pediatric populations and therefore the drug is not recommended to treat migraines in anyone less than 18 years of age.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Recent studies of the BPCA by the Government Accountability Office--GAO--and by several authors from Duke University in an article which appeared in the Journal of the American Medical Association--JAMA--have demonstrated that the program is a success and have identified opportunities to strengthen the program. Authors of the recent JAMA article found that outside of the BPCA, the FDA is limited in the number and scope of studies for which it can require pediatric data for existing products on  the market.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Data from this article showed that only a minority of drugs studied under the BPC, about 20 percent, had more than $1 billion in annual sales. In fact, the median drug granted exclusivity was a small-market drug with annual sales of $180 million and 30 percent of drugs studied had sales less than $200 million. This article went on to say that a universal reduction in the length of pediatric exclusivity from 6 to 3 months would mean that products with small profit margins may not be submitted  for pediatric testing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The BPCA has always tried to strike the right balance between cost to consumers and benefits to children. I believe there is an ongoing need to evaluate the cost of the incentive as it relates to reaching the goal of having medications properly studied and labeled for children. In fact, that is why I strongly support a 5-year sunset of the BPCA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After 10 years, experience and data has shown us that for a small number of drugs, pediatric exclusivity has far exceeded the "carrot" it was intended to provide for manufacturers. As the authors of the recent JAMA article noted, "our study shows that the Pediatric Exclusivity Program overcompensates blockbuster products for performing clinical trials in children, while other products have more modest returns on investment under this program."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill I am introducing today contains a reasonable, workable proposal to address cost concerns without jeopardizing the extraordinary success of BPCA. I have worked closely with the chairman and ranking member of the HELP Committee to craft this proposal into the form it appears in this legislation and in the bipartisan chairman's mark which is expected to be voted on in the HELP Committee today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On March 27, the HELP Committee held a hearing, which I chaired, entitled "Ensuring Safe Medicines and Medical Devices for Children." We learned from pediatricians and a parent of five children, four of whom are HIV-positive, Mrs. Susan Belfiore, about the tremendous impact BPCA has had on the quality of life for countless numbers of children and their families. We received testimony with many suggestions for improvements to BPCA which I believe are reflected in this bill. I would also add  that in the month since I circulated this bill as a draft, I received comments from several pharmaceutical companies. Some have been strongly supportive of this effort and many of their ideas and suggestions are incorporated in this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The success of the BPCA has transformed the drug development process for children. It is my hope that we will achieve similar success with another piece of legislation I recently introduced called the Pediatric Medical Device Safety and Improvement Act. It is also contained within the chairman's mark to <bill type="s" number="1082">S. 1082</bill> and I thank Chairman KENNEDY and Ranking Member ENZI for working with me to ensure that medical devices used in children are safe and are designed specifically for their  use.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The BPCA has had a long history of bipartisan support and it has been my longstanding hope that this initiative will continue to be bipartisan as the chairman's mark to <bill type="s" number="1082">S. 1082</bill> moves to the Senate floor. The safety of our Nation's children is not a partisan issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As the parent of two young children, I know that it is essential that products used in children's growing bodies, whether they be drugs or devices, are appropriately tested and designed specifically for their use. We must continue the tremendous success of BPCA and its complementary program, the Pediatric Research Improvement Act, of which I am an original cosponsor, by strengthening both programs through the reauthorization process this year. It is essential that we use the past experience of  both programs to ensure they will continue to thrive in the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
</record>
