<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1221667203" ordinal="31" title="UNANIMOUS CONSENT AGREEMENT--S. 3001">
  <narrative>UNANIMOUS CONSENT AGREEMENT--S. 3001 -- (Senate - September 17, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="8929">S8929</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="">
    <paragraph>Given that objection to our going to conference, I now ask unanimous consent that at 6:30 p.m., morning business be closed; that after the bill is reported, all postcloture time be yielded back, the first- and second-degree amendment be withdrawn, the bill be then read a third time, and the Senate proceed to vote on passage of the bill; that upon passage, it then be in order for the Senate to consider en bloc the following calendar items: Nos. 733, 734, and 735; that all after the  enacting clause of each bill be stricken and the following divisions of <bill type="s" number="3001">S. 3001</bill> as passed by the Senate be inserted as follows: Division A, <bill type="s" number="3002">S. 3002</bill>; Division B, <bill type="s" number="3003">S. 3003</bill>; and Division C, <bill type="s" number="3004">S. 3004</bill>; that these bills be read a third time, passed, and the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table en bloc; further, that the consideration of these items appear separately in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300099" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I join in making that request. There is no objection on this side.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="">
    <paragraph>I will again thank my friend for all of his efforts on this bill. He has been, as always, a highly constructive force. We could not even be this far without his great support. I am indebted to him and the Senate is indebted to him, I hope, and the Nation again is indebted to Senator Warner.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, I thank our good friend from Louisiana. We have interrupted her for a little longer than I promised.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300099" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, if I might just add, I thank my distinguished colleague and friend for the 30 years we have been together. I am certain this institution will carry on just as well without me--and perhaps even a little bit better. But I have enjoyed our working together these many years. I stop to think, you and I having been here the same number of years, we have served with 273 different Senators in that period of time. I have enjoyed it. I don't know of any relationship, either  professional or even simply friendship, that I have enjoyed and profited from more than working with you, Senator. I wish you well as you carry on with this committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam President, I do want to thank the staff of the Senate Armed Services Committee. I have here with me Michael Kostiw, William Caniano, David Morriss, David Collins, Sandy Luff of my personal staff, Marie Dickinson, Paul Hutton, Gergory Kiley, Lucian Niemeyer, Christopher Paul, Lynn Rusten, Robert Soofer, Diana Tabler, and Richard Walsh.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I know my staff would want me to say--and I say it--we have enjoyed working with the majority staff.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Louisiana is recognized.</chair>
</record>
