<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1169744418" ordinal="34" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <speaking speaker="300093" topic="COMMITTEE ON ARMED SERVICES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, January 25, 2007, at 9:30 a.m., in open session to receive testimony on the current situation in Iraq on the Administration's recently announced strategy for continued United States assistance to the Iraqi Government and for an increased United States mlitary presence in Iraq.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300093" topic="COMMITTEE ON BANKING, HOUSING, AND URBAN AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on January 25, 2007, at 9:30 a.m., to vote on committee organizational matters for the 110th Congress; immediately following the executive session the committee will meet to conduct a hearing on "Examining the Billing, Marketing, and Disclosure Practices of the Credit Card Industry, and Their Impact on Consumers."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300093" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND NATURAL RESOURCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Thursday, January 25, 2007, at 9:30 a.m. in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the hearing is to receive testimony on oil and gas resources on the Outer Continental Shelf and areas available for leasing in the Gulf of Mexico.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300093" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, January 25, 2007, at 9:15 a.m. to hold a hearing on Iraq.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection. it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300093" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, January 25, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. to hold a hearing on Iraq.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300093" topic="COMMITTEE ON INDIAN AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to announce that the Committee on Indian Affairs will meet on Thursday, January 25, 2007, at 9:30 a.m. in room 485 of the Russell Senate Office Building to conduct a business meeting to consider changes to the committee rules and a funding resolution for the committee budget for the 110th Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Those wishing additional information may contact the Indian Affairs Committee at 224-2251.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300093" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet to conduct a markup on Thursday, January 25, 2007, at 10 a.m. in Dirksen room 226.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Agenda</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Committee Rules for the 110th Congress; Subcommittees for the 110th Congress; Funding Resolution for the 110th Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Lisa Godbey Wood to be U.S. District Judge for the Southern District of Georgia; Philip S. Gutierrez to be U.S. District Judge for the Central District of California; Valerie L. Baker to be U.S. District Judge for the Central District of California; Lawrence Joseph O'Neill to be U.S. District Judge for the Eastern District of California; and Gregory Kent Frizzell to be U.S. District Judge for the Northern District of Oklahoma.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="188">S. 188</bill>, To Revise the Short Title of the Voting Rights Act Reauthorization and Amendments Act of 2006, Salazar.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="214">S. 214</bill>, To Amend Chapter 35 of Title 28, To Preserve the Independence of U.S. Attorneys, Feinstein.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="sr" number="21">S. Res. 21</bill>, Recognizing the Uncommon Valor of Wesley Autry, Clinton, Schumer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="sr" number="24">S. Res. 24</bill>, Designating January as "National Stalking Awareness Month", Biden.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="sr" number="29">S. Res. 29</bill>, Expressing the Sense of the Senate Regarding Martin Luther King, Jr. Day, Stabenow, Leahy, Kennedy, Biden, Kohl, Feinstein, Feingold, Schumer, Durbin, Cardin, Whitehouse, Specter.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300093" topic="SELECT COMMITTEE ON INTELLIGENCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Select Committee on Intelligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on January 25, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. to hold a hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300093" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON OVERSIGHT OF GOVERNMENT MANAGEMENT, THE FEDERAL WORKFORCE, AND THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce and the District of Columbia be authorized to meet on Thursday, January 25, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. for a hearing entitled, "Lost in Translation: A Review of the Federal Government's Efforts to Develop a Foreign Language Strategy."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
