<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1177387200" ordinal="30" title="DISCUSSING PRESSING ISSUES FACING THE NATION">
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, on April 27-29, more than 800 of the foremost scientists, humanists and leaders in business and public affairs will gather here in Washington when the Nation's two oldest learned societies--the American Academy of Arts and Sciences and the American Philosophical Society--meet jointly for the first time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Both organizations predate the birth of the Nation, and among their founders were Benjamin Franklin, John Adams, James Bowdoin, and John Hancock.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The two organizations were established to help advance "useful knowledge" in the colonies by promoting enlightened leaders and an engaged citizenry, and they have remained faithful to their original missions to the present day. Their current membership includes more than 170 Nobel laureates and more than 50 Pulitzer Prize winners.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This joint meeting, entitled "The Public Good: Knowledge as the Foundation for a Democratic Society" will bring together academics and practitioners for a series of panel discussions, conversations and dinner programs on many of the most pressing issues facing the Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Joining them for the unprecedented 2 1/2 -day meeting will be members of these congressionally chartered National Academies--the National Academy of Sciences, the National Academy of Engineering, and the Institute of Medicine.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At the opening of their meeting next week, the presidents of all five organizations will issue a joint statement affirming the importance of knowledge as the foundation for sound policymaking for the public good, and I ask unanimous consent that their unprecedented joint statement be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
</record>
