<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1209052802" ordinal="72" title="NATIONAL CYSTIC FIBROSIS AWARENESS MONTH">
  <narrative>NATIONAL CYSTIC FIBROSIS AWARENESS MONTH -- (Senate - April 24, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="3412">S3412</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions be discharged from further consideration of <bill type="sr" number="510">S. Res. 510</bill> and the Senate proceed to its consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will report the resolution by title.</narrative>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="510">S. Res. 510</bill>) supporting the goals and ideals of National Cystic Fibrosis Awareness Month.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, the motions to reconsider be laid on the table, there be no intervening action or debate, and all statements relating to this matter be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="510">S. Res. 510</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preambles, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>Whereas cystic fibrosis is one of the most common life-threatening genetic diseases in the United States and one for which there is no known cure;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the average life expectancy of an individual with cystic fibrosis is 37 years, an improvement from a life expectancy in the 1960s where children did not live long enough to attend elementary school, but still unacceptably short;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas approximately 30,000 people in the United States have cystic fibrosis, more than half of them children;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas 1 of every 3,500 babies born in the United States is born with cystic fibrosis;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas more than 10,000,000 Americans are unknowing, symptom-free carriers of the cystic fibrosis gene;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention recommend that all States consider newborn screening for cystic fibrosis;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Cystic Fibrosis Foundation urges all States to implement newborn screening for cystic fibrosis to facilitate early diagnosis and treatment which improves health and life expectancy;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas prompt, aggressive treatment of the symptoms of cystic fibrosis can extend the lives of people who have the disease;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas recent advances in cystic fibrosis research have produced promising leads in gene, protein, and drug therapies beneficial to people who have the disease;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas innovative research is progressing faster and is being conducted more aggressively than ever before, due, in part, to the Cystic Fibrosis Foundation's establishment of a model clinical trials network;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, although the Cystic Fibrosis Foundation continues to fund a research pipeline for more than 30 potential therapies and funds a nationwide network of care centers that extend the length and quality of life for people with cystic fibrosis, lives continue to be lost to this disease every day;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas education of the public about cystic fibrosis, including the symptoms of the disease, increases knowledge and understanding of cystic fibrosis and promotes early diagnosis; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Cystic Fibrosis Foundation will conduct activities to honor National Cystic Fibrosis Awareness Month in May 2008: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) honors the goals and ideals of National Cystic Fibrosis Awareness Month;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) supports the promotion of further public awareness and understanding of cystic fibrosis;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) encourages early diagnosis and access to quality care for people with cystic fibrosis to improve the quality of their lives; and</chair>
  <chair> (4) supports research to find a cure for cystic fibrosis by fostering an enhanced research program through a strong Federal commitment and expanded public-private partnerships.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
