<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1197306002" ordinal="30" title="HONORING THE LATE JOE NUXHALL">
  <narrative>HONORING THE LATE JOE NUXHALL -- (Senate - December 10, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="15081">S15081</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400619" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of <bill type="sr" number="398">S. Res. 398</bill> submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="398">S. Res. 398</bill>) honoring the life and recognizing the accomplishments of Joe Nuxhall, broadcaster for the Cincinnati Reds.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400619" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table, and that any statements be printed in the Record without intervening action or debate.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="398">S. Res. 398</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="398">S. Res. 398</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas Joe Nuxhall was born on July 30th, 1928 in Hamilton, Ohio.</chair>
  <chair>Whereas on June 10th, 1944 at the age of 15 years, 10 months, and 11 days Joe Nuxhall became the youngest player in the modern era to appear in a major league baseball game.</chair>
  <chair>Whereas Joe Nuxhall earned over 100 victories in his sixteen year major league career and was elected into the Cincinnati Reds Hall of Fame.</chair>
  <chair>Whereas Joe Nuxhall began a radio broadcasting career in 1967 and went on to call over 6,000 games for the Cincinnati Reds.</chair>
  <chair>Whereas Joe Nuxhall had a career spanning over sixty years with the Cincinnati Reds.</chair>
  <chair>Whereas Joe Nuxhall will be remembered for his signature signoff, "This is the Ol' Lefthander rounding third and heading for home."</chair>
  <chair>Whereas Joe Nuxhall whose voice was synonymous with baseball and the summer for generations of fans across the country.</chair>
  <chair>Whereas Joe Nuxhall was a beloved community leader, philanthropist, husband, father, and advocate for children, public schools, and the elderly.</chair>
  <chair>Whereas Ohio has lost a beloved son and baseball one of its most distinctive voices with the passing of Joe Nuxhall on November 15, 2007.</chair>
  <chair>Resolved, That the Senate honors the life of Joe Nuxhall, baseball legend, dedicated family man, and civic-minded leader.</chair>
</record>
