<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1191427202" ordinal="29" title="TRIBUTE TO MARTHA ANNE DOW">
  <narrative>TRIBUTE TO MARTHA ANNE DOW -- (Senate - October 03, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="12529">S12529</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300090" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, famed educator Henry Adams once said, "a teacher affects eternity. They never know where their influence will stop." I wish to pay tribute to Dr. Martha Anne Dow, who passed away on September 29 after a courageous battle with breast cancer. Martha Anne had served for the past 9 years as president of the Oregon Institute of Technology in Klamath Falls, OR. In that position--and throughout her career--she had a positive impact on countless lives. Her influence will  truly continue for generations and generations to come.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Martha Anne came to the Oregon Institute of Technology after teaching for more than a quarter century in the fields of biology, microbiology, environmental science, and water quality. She served for 6 years as provost and vice president for Academic Affairs at OIT and moved into the president's office in May of 1998.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I had the privilege of meeting President Dow on several occasions and was always impressed with her intelligence, enthusiasm, and vision for OIT. Her leadership transformed the institute, expanding the engineering, computer science, and renewable energy programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>President Dow's greatest passion was, perhaps, for the health care field. She realized the shortage of health care professionals in Oregon and across our country, and she believed that OIT could help.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Through her leadership, OIT expanded their health care training programs with the goal of doubling the number of students in training for health care professions. Included in this expansion was the construction of a new center showcasing the most modern, technologically advanced equipment available. The first wing of the new facility opened on September 12 in Klamath Falls. In her honor, the building was officially named the "Martha Anne Dow Oregon Center for Health Professions."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As she battled breast cancer, President Dow would often ask medical technicians providing her treatment where they had received their training. She was very proud to hear that many had been trained at OIT, in the very programs she helped to expand.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Those professionals, and countless more to follow, are Martha Anne Dow's legacy. And I am proud to say her legacy will truly affect eternity.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
