<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1168534804" ordinal="41" title="STATEMENTS ON INTRODUCED BILLS AND JOINT RESOLUTIONS">
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="Introducing S. 256. A bill to harmonize rate setting standards for copyright licenses under section 112 and 114 of title 17, United States Code, and for other purposes; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="256">S. 256</bill>] Mr. President, today I am pleased to introduce the Platform Equality and Remedies for Rights-holders in Music Act along with Senators Graham, Biden, and Alexander.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The need to protect creative works has been an important principle recognized in our country since the time when our Constitution was first drafted.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, the founding fathers could not have predicted the path innovation would eventually lead us down, nor the amazing new technologies that we now take for granted.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While many of us still enjoy traditional radio, this too is rapidly changing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Recently, radio stations have begun advertising for a national campaign to switch to High Definition, or HD, radio. This new platform is changing the way music is transmitted and, according to its promoters, "radio has never sounded better."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, we can now have music radio programs provided not just in our cars, or on traditional home stereos, but radio programs have expanded to be available through Internet, cable, and satellite music stations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And radio services are looking to use the new digital transmissions and new technologies to change how music is delivered so that the audience can not only listen but also record, manipulate, collect and create individual music play lists.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thus, what was once a passive listening experience has turned into a forum where consumers can create their own personalized music libraries.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As the modes of distribution change and the technologies change, so must our laws change.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The government granted a compulsory license for radio-like services by Internet, cable, and satellite providers in order to encourage competition and the creation of new products.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, as new innovations alter these services from a performance to a distribution, the law must respond.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, as the changing technology evolves the distinctions between the services become less and less, and the differences in how they are treated under the statutory license make less and less sense.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Therefore, I am introducing a bill that will begin to fix the inequities currently in the statute and open the door to further debate about additional issues that need to be addressed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, the bill I am introducing today, the PERFORM Act, would create rate parity. All companies covered by the government license created in section 114 of title 17 would be required to pay a "fair market value" for use of music libraries rather than having different rate standards apply based on what medium is being used to transmit the music.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill would also establish content protection. All companies would be required to use reasonably available, technologically feasible, and economically reasonable means to prevent music theft. In addition, a company may not provide a recording device to a customer that would allow him or her to create their own personalized music library that can be manipulated and maintained without paying a reproduction royalty.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This does not mean such devices cannot be made or distributed. It simply means that the business must negotiate the payment for the music outside of the statutory license.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also contains language to make sure that consumers' current recording habits are not inhibited. Therefore, any recording the consumer chooses to do manually will still be allowed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, if the device allows the consumer to manipulate music by program, channel, or time period that would still be permitted under the statutory license.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For example, if a listener chooses to automatically record a news station every morning at 9:00 a.m.; a jazz station every afternoon at 2:00 p.m., a blues station every Friday at 3:00 p.m., and a talk radio show every Saturday at 4:00 p.m., that would be allowable. In addition, that listener could then use their recording device to move these programs so that each program of the same genre would be back to back.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What a listener cannot do is set a recording device to find all the Frank Sinatra songs being played on the radio-service and only record those songs. By making these distinctions this bill supports new business models and technologies without harming the songwriters and performers in the process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, this bill was unable to move last Congress primarily because of misinformation about what the bill does and does not do.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, there were also some questions that were raised, not about problems with the bill, but about ways to expand its reach. For example, currently the bill does not apply to traditional radio distributed by the broadcasters. This legislation only covers businesses that are under the section 114 license: Internet, cable, and satellite. Yet, some of my Republican colleagues argued that the bill should apply the same recording limitations to over-the-air broadcasters as are applied to Internet,  cable, and satellite. While this change has not been made in the version of the bill I am introducing today, I believe it is an issue we should look at in the 110th Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Also, the bill as introduced does not address the other conditions applied to Internet, cable, and satellite services in order for them to get the benefit of the statutory license. The one that I am most concerned with is interactivity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think there is real confusion about what is and what is not allowed under the current statute: how much personalization and customization may these new services offer?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Currently, licensing rates are higher for interactive services. However, there are clear disagreements as to what constitutes an "interactive" service. I tried to have the parties meet to negotiate a solution to this issue so that we could include new language in this bill; however, the parties were so far apart that a solution could not be reached.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Despite this, I still believe this is an important issue that must be addressed. As introduced, the bill calls for the Copyright Office to make recommendations to Congress, but I am hopeful that through the process of moving this bill through the Senate we can develop a solution sooner rather than rely on a study.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, some have raised concerns that applying content protection to all providers is unfair. They argue that if there is no connection between the distributor of the music and the technology provider that allows for copying and manipulating of performances then they should not be required to protect the music that they broadcast. In general, I do not agree. We know that there are websites out there now that provide so-called stream-ripping services that allow an individual to steal music off  an Internet webcast.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is not enough to turn a blind eye to this type of piracy and do nothing simply because there is no formal connection between the businesses. At the same time, I am sympathetic to the concerns that if the type of technology a company uses is inadequate or ineffective, through no fault of their own, they should not be saddled with huge mandatory penalties.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am interested in looking at this issue more closely to see if there is some way to address this concern and find a compromise solution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To be clear, I see this as the beginning of the process. I think this legislation is a good step forward in addressing a real problem that is occurring in the music industry. Changes or additions may be necessary as the bill moves forward, but I believe to wait and do nothing does a disservice to all involved.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Music is an invaluable part of all of our lives. The new technologies and changing delivery systems provide exciting new options for all consumers. As we continue to move forward into new frontiers we must ensure that our laws can stand the test of time.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I look forward to working with my colleagues to pass this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="Introducing S. 259. A bill to authorize the establishment of the Henry Kuualoha Giugni Kupuna Memorial Archives at the University of Hawaii; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="259">S. 259</bill>] Mr. President, I am introducing with my dear friend, the senior Senator from Hawaii, DAN INOUYE, and several of our colleagues from both sides of the aisle, a bill paying tribute to one of this body's most loyal servants. The Henry Kuualoha Giugni Kupuna Memorial Archives bill honors Henry K. Giugni, our former Sergeant-at-Arms of the U.S. Senate, through the establishment of cultural and historical digital archives. Mr. Giugni would have turned 82 today, if he were still alive.  These archives will enable the sharing and perpetuation of the culture, collective memory, and history of peoples Mr. Giugni so dearly loved.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As many of my colleagues are aware, Henry was a man full of life and loyalty who served our country with distinction. He enlisted in the U.S. Army at the age of 16 after the attack on Pearl Harbor. During World War II he served in combat at the battle of Guadalcanal. Following World War II, he continued to serve the State of Hawaii and our Nation by working as a police officer and firefighter. After nearly a decade of service with Senator INOUYE in the Hawaii territorial legislature, he  came to Washington, DC, as the senior Senator's senior executive assistant and then chief of staff for more than 20 years. Mr. Giugni was appointed in 1987 to serve as Sergeant-at-Arms of our revered body--a position that each of my colleagues and I know as crucial to the running of the Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Henry also sought to tear down barriers in society. In 1965 it was Mr. Giugni who represented Senator INOUYE's office, and thus the people of Hawaii, in the famous 1965 Selma to Montgomery civil rights march led by Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. As Senator INOUYE's chief of staff, Mr. Giugni served as a vital link between the Senator's office and minority groups. He was the first person of color and the first Native Hawaiian to be appointed Senate Sergeant-at-Arms. In this influential  position, he sought out capable minorities and women for promotion to ensure that our workforce reflects America. He appointed the first minority, an African-American, to lead the Service Department, and was the first to assign women to the Capitol Police plainclothes</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Further in his capacity as Sergeant-at-Arms, Henry was the chief law enforcement officer of the U.S. Senate and an able manager of a majority of the Senate's support services. He oversaw a budget of nearly $120 million and approximately 2,000 employees. As Sergeant-at-Arms, Mr. Giugni presided over the inauguration of President George H.W. Bush, and escorted numerous dignitaries on their visits to the U.S. Capitol, including Nelson Mandela, Margaret Thatcher, and Vaclav Havel.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Establishing the Henry Kuualoha Giugni Memorial Archives would be a poignant and appropriate way to honor our loyal friend, colleague, and fellow American, as well as his dear wife Lani, who recently followed him to the great beyond. Henry lived a life full of rich experiences, and along the way he accumulated a wealth of wisdom. His memory and spirit live on, but it is essential we perpetuate his wisdom and  experiences, and those of others like him,  so what was learned and accomplished will not be lost to future generations. This is the primary</paragraph>
    <paragraph>impetus behind creating these archives. There is a dearth of physical archives, museums, or libraries devoted to preserving and perpetuating the history, culture, achievements and collective narratives of indigenous peoples. As one generation passes, a wealth of traditional knowledge could be lost forever. Establishing these archives to perpetuate the traditional knowledge of indigenous peoples such as Henry will ensure that future generations have access to that widsom and, in a sense, will  be able to learn from the original sources themselves.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The development of the Internet in managing knowledge in electronic format has enabled the most pervasive storing and sharing of information the world has ever seen. Electronic, digital archives would facilitate the sharing, preservation and perpetuation of the unique native culture, language, tradition and history. These archives will be a source of enduring knowledge, accessible to all. It will help to ensure that the children of today and tomorrow will not be deprived of the rich culture,  history and collective knowledge of indigenous peoples. These archives will help to guarantee that the experiences, wisdom and knowledge of kupuna, or elders such as Henry, will not be lost to future generations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The first section of the Henry Kuualoha Giugni Memorial Archives bill authorizes a grant awarded to the University of Hawaii's Academy for Creative Media for the establishment, maintenance and update of the archives which are to be located at the University of Hawaii. These funds would be used to enable a statewide archival effort which will include the acquisition of a secure, web-accessible repository that will house significant historical and cultural information. This information may include  oral histories, collective narratives, photographs, video files, journals, creative works and documentation of practices and customs such as traditional dance and traditional music that were used to convey historical and cultural knowledge in the absence of</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The second section of this bill authorizes the use of these grant funds for several different educational activities, many of which are intended to magnify the resourcefulness of these archives and benefit the student populations who will likely access the archives the most. This includes the development of educational materials from the archives that can be used in teaching indigenous students. Despite their focus, these materials are meant to enhance the education of all students, even students  from non-native backgrounds. This also includes developing outreach initiatives to introduce the archives to elementary and secondary schools, and as enabling schools to access the archives through the computer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Grant funds would also be available to help make a college education possible for students who otherwise could not independently afford such an education through scholarship awards. Additionally, funds can be used to address the problem of cultural incongruence in teaching, an issue that impedes effective learning in our Nation's classrooms. Such a lack of congruence exists in a wide range of situations, from rural and underserved communities in remote areas to well-populated urban centers, from  my State of Hawaii to areas on the eastern seaboard. The dynamic I am describing exists along lines of race and ethnicity, socioeconomic strata, age, and many other vectors, which can muddy the effective transmission of knowledge. Many of us, especially those from rural, indigenous, or ethnic minority backgrounds, including Henry Giugni, have experienced</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, as financial illiteracy is a growing problem, especially among college age youth who are exposed to a variety of financial products, funds can be used to increase the economic and financial literacy of college students. This will be accomplished through the propagation of proven best practices that have resulted in positive behavioral change in regards to improved debt and credit management, and economic decision making. Such activities can help to ensure that students stay in school,  graduate in a better financial position, and remain disciplined in effectively managing their finances throughout their working and retirement years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Henry K. Giugni served among us with distinction and honor. I am very grateful to have known him and his family. I encourage all of my colleagues to perpetuate his memory by supporting the Henry Kuualoha Giugni Memorial Archives bill. These archives are the most fitting way we can honor and remember our friend and dear public servant, Henry Kuualoha Giugni.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD and that support letters from University of Hawaii President David McClain and Academy for Creative Media Director Christopher Lee also be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300056" topic="Introducing S. 259. A bill to authorize the establishment of the Henry Kuualoha Giugni Kupuna Memorial Archives at the University of Hawaii; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today I join my partner from Hawaii, Senator AKAKA, and other esteemed colleagues, in lending my support to the Henry Kuualoha Giugni Kupuna Memorial Archives Bill. I offer my support today, on this, the eleventh day of January, Henry's birthday, to herald the significant role that the establishment of these archives will play in shaping the future of a new generation of Americans, just as Henry did during his remarkable tenure as the 30th Sergeant-at-Arms of  the United States Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to creating a digital archive and preserving the traditions and culture of Native Hawaiians, this bill will support initiatives critical to the development of Web-based media projects and the creation of educational materials that will richly enhance the educational experience for countless students.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is my hope that the establishment of these archives will inspire greater academic achievement of indigenous students by sharing with them the stories and histories of accomplished individuals with indigenous backgrounds, such as Henry.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300036" topic="Introducing S. 260. A bill to establish the Fort Stanton-Snowy River Cave National Conservation Area; to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="260">S. 260</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to introduce legislation to protect a natural wonder in my home State of New Mexico. A passage within the Fort Stanton Cave contains what can only be described as a magnificent white river of calcite. I am pleased to be joined in this effort again this year by my colleague from New Mexico, Senator Bingaman.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many locals are familiar with the Fort Stanton Cave in Lincoln County, NM. Exploration of the cave dates back to at least the 1850s, when troops stationed in the area began visiting the network of caverns. Exploration continued over the years and in 2001 BLM volunteers discovered a two-mile long continuous calcite formation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have not found a formation of this size anywhere else in New Mexico or perhaps even in the United States. Because of the beauty and distinct appearance of this discovery, I continue to be excited about the scientific and educational opportunities associated with the find. This large, continuous stretch of calcite may yield valuable research opportunities relating to hydrology, geology, and microbiology. In fact, there may be no limits to what we can learn from this snow white cave passage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is not often that we find something so striking and so significant. I believe this find is worthy of study and our most thoughtful management and conservation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My legislation does the following: (1) creates a Fort Stanton-Snowy River Cave Conservation Area to protect, secure and conserve the natural and unique features of the Snowy River Cave; (2) instructs the BLM to prepare a map and legal description of the Snowy River cave, and to develop a comprehensive, long-term management plan for the cave area; (3) authorizes the conservation of the unique features and environs in the cave for scientific, educational and other public uses deemed safe and appropriate  under the management plan; (4) authorizes the BLM to work with State and other institutions and to cooperate with Lincoln County to address the historical involvement of the local community; (5) protects the caves from mineral and mining leasing operations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As the people of my home State of New Mexico know, we have many natural wonders, and I am proud to play a role in the protection of this recent unique discovery. I hope my colleagues will join with me in approving the Fort Stanton-Snowy River National Cave Conservation Area Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300018" topic="Introducing S. 261. A bill to amend title 18, United States Code, to strengthen prohibitions against animal fighting, and for other purposes; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="261">S. 261</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to join with my colleagues, Senators SPECTER and ENSIGN, in reintroducing the Animal Fighting Prohibition Enforcement Act of 2007. This legislation has won the unanimous approval of the Senate several times, but unfortunately has not yet reached the finish line. I look forward to working with my colleagues to see this important bill finally become the law of the land.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is no doubt, animal fighting is terribly cruel. Dogs and roosters are drugged to make them hyper-aggressive and forced to keep fighting even after suffering severe injuries such as punctured eyes and pierced lungs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It's all done for "entertainment" and illegal gambling. Children are sometimes brought to these spectacles, and the fights are frequently accompanied by illegal drug trafficking and acts of human violence. In 2006, nine murders related to animal fighting occurred across the country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Some dogfighters steal pets to use as bait for training their dogs, while others allow trained fighting dogs to roam neighborhoods and endanger the public.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Animal Fighting Prohibition Enforcement Act will strengthen current law by making the interstate transport of animals for the purpose of fighting a felony and increase the punishment to three years of jail time. This is necessary because the current misdemeanor penalty has proven ineffective--considered a "cost of doing business" by those in the animal fighting industry which continues unabated nationwide. These enterprises depend on interstate commerce, as I evidenced by the animal fighting  magazines that advertise and promote them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our bill also makes it a felony to move cockfighting implements in interstate or foreign commerce. These are razor-sharp knives known as "slashers" and ice pick-like gaffs designed exclusively for cockfights and attached to the birds' legs for fighting. Cockfighting magazines I and websites contain hundreds of advertisements for mail-order knives and gaffs, revealing a thriving interstate market for the weapons used in cockfights.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is long overdue legislation. Both the Senate and House approved felony animal fighting provisions in their Farm Bills in 2001, but they were stripped out in conference. The Senate included felony animal fighting provisions in the 2003 Health Forest Bill, but they were again dropped in conference. In September 2004, the Animal Fighting Prohibition Enforcement Act was approved by the House Judiciary Committee, but did not reach the floor. In April 2005, the Senate passed a bill nearly identical  to the one we are introducing today, when it unanimously approved <bill type="s" number="382">S. 382</bill>. In May 2006, the House Crime, Terrorism and Homeland Security Subcommittee held a comprehensive hearing on the House companion bill, <bill type="h" number="817">H.R. 817</bill>, which garnered 324 cosponsors but was not considered on the House floor. The legislative history of this animal fighting felony legislation shows it has broad bipartisan support of more than half the Senate, and it has won unanimous approval on the floor time and time again.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It's time to get this felony animal fighting language enacted. With the bird flu threat looming, we can't afford to wait any longer. The economic consequences are staggering--the World Bank projects worldwide losses of $1.5 to $2 trillion. We must be able to say we did all we could to prevent such a pandemic, and this is an obvious, easy and necessary step.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Interstate and international transport of birds for cockfighting is known to have contributed to the spread of avian influenza in Asia and poses a threat to poultry and public health in the United States. According to the World Health Organization and local news reports, at least nine confirmed human fatalities from avian influenza in Thailand and Vietnam may have been contracted through cockfighting activity since the beginning of 2004. Several children are among those who are reported to have  died from avian influenza as a result of exposure through cockfighting, including 4-year-old, 6-year-old, and 18-year-old boys in Thailand and a 6-year-old girl in Vietnam.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There have been many news stories focusing on the connection between bird flu and cockfighting. For example, an MSNBC report headlined, "Cock-fights blamed for Thailand bird flu spread." A World Health Organization Asia regional spokesperson interviewed recently on the CBS Evening News described the risk of spreading disease through cockfighting with infected animals as a "total disaster waiting to happen."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because human handling of fighting roosters is a regular occurrence, the opportunity of disease transmission from fighting birds to people is substantial. Fighting-bird handlers come into frequent, sustained contact with their birds during training and during organized fights. It is common practice for handlers to suck saliva and blood from roosters' beaks to help clear their airways and enable them to keep fighting.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Cockfighters frequently move birds across State and foreign borders, bringing them to fight in different locations and risking the spread of infectious diseases. Communications in national  cockfighting magazines and websites have shown that U.S. cockfighters regularly transport their birds to and from other parts of the world, including Asia.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA), in endorsing the Animal Fighting Prohibition Enforcement Act, noted that strengthening current Federal law on the inhumane practice of animal fighting would enhance the agency's ability to safeguard the health of U.S. poultry against deadly diseases such as avian influenza and exotic Newcastle disease (END). The USDA has stated that cockfighting was implicated in an outbreak of END that spread through California and the Southwest in 2002 and 2003. That  outbreak cost U.S. taxpayers nearly $200 million to eradicate and cost the U.S. poultry industry many millions more in lost export markets. The costs of an avian influenza outbreak in this country could be much higher--with the Congressional Budget Office estimating losses between 1.5 and 5 percent of GDP ($185 billion to $618 billion).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The National Chicken Council, which represents 95 percent of all U.S. poultry producers and processors, has also endorsed the Animal Fighting Prohibition Enforcement Act, expressing concern that avian influenza and other diseases can be spread by the movement of game birds and that the commercial chicken industry remains under considerable threat because it operates amidst a national network of game bird operations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Avian influenza has not yet crossed the species barrier in this country, as it has in Asia. But we must do all we can to minimize this risk. Establishing a more meaningful deterrent to illegal interstate and foreign movement of animals for fighting purposes is an obvious step we can take to reduce this risk.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Besides those associated with the poultry industry, this legislation has been endorsed by a number of other organization including the Humane Society of the United States, the American Veterinary Medical Association, the National Coalition Against Gambling Expansion, the League of United Latin American Citizens, the National Sheriffs' Association, and more than 400 individual sheriffs and police departments covering every State in the country. Those law enforcement agencies recognize that animal  fighting often involves the movement of animals across State and foreign borders, so they can't do the job on their own. They need the Federal Government to do its part to help curb this dangerous activity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our legislation does not expand the federal government's reach into a new area, but simply aims to make current law more effective. It is explicitly limited to interstate and foreign commerce, so it protects States' rights in the two States where cockfighting is still allowed, and it protects States' rights the other 48 States--and all 50, for dogfighting--where weak Federal law is compromising their ability to keep animal fighting outside their borders.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill we introduce today is identical to <bill type="s" number="382">S. 382</bill>, which passed the Senate unanimously in the last Congress, except for one change. The new bill provides for up to three years' jail time, compared to two in <bill type="s" number="382">S. 382</bill>, in order to bring this more in line with penalties for other federal animal cruelty-related felonies. For example, in 1999, Congress authorized imprisonment of up to 5 years for interstate commerce in videos depicting animal cruelty, including animal fighting, P.L. 106-152, and mandatory  jail time of up to 10 years for willfully harming or killing a federal police dog or horse (P.L. 106-254).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With every week, there are new reports of animal fighting busts, as local and state law enforcement struggle to rein in this thriving industry. In my own State of Washington, police arrested 5 people on Christmas Day at a cockfight in Brewster, and about 50 people ran off, according to recent news accounts. Three days later, six more were arrested in Okanogan for promoting cockfighting. And nine people were arrested in Tacoma last spring, where investigators seized methamphetamines, marijuana,  weapons, thousands of dollars, and fighting roosters.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It's time for Congress to strengthen the federal law so that it can provide as a meaningful deterrent against animal fighting. State and local law enforcement will have a tough law on the books necessary to help them crack down on this interstate industry. I thank my colleagues for their support, and look forward to working with them to finally enacting this common-sense measure into law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By Mr. BINGAMAN (for himself, Mr. Smith, Mr. Reid, Mrs. Feinstein, Mrs. Boxer, Mr. Baucus, Mrs. Murray, and Ms. Cantwell)</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="267">S. 267</bill>. A bill to amend the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to clarify that territories and Indian tribes are eligible to receive grants for confronting the use of methamphetamine; to the Committee on the Judiciary.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="Introducing S. 261. A bill to amend title 18, United States Code, to strengthen prohibitions against animal fighting, and for other purposes; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today to introduce the Native American Methamphetamine Enforcement and Treatment Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, when Congress passed the Combat Methamphetamine Epidemic Act, tribes were unintentionally left out as eligible applicants in some of the newly-authorized grant programs. The bill I am introducing today, along with Senators SMITH, REID, BAUCUS, FEINSTEIN, BOXER, FEINGOLD, CANTWELL, and MURRAY, would simply ensure that tribes are able to apply for these funds and give Native American communities the resources they need to fight scourge of methamphetamine use.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The recently-enacted Combat Methamphetamine Epidemic Act of 2005 authorized new funding for three grant programs. The Act authorized $99 million in new funding for the COPS Hot Spots program, which helps local law enforcement agencies obtain the tools they need to reduce the production, distribution, and use of meth. Funding may also be used to clean up meth labs, support health and environmental agencies, and to purchase equipment and support systems.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Act also authorized $20 million for a Drug-Endangered Children grant program to provide comprehensive services to assist children who live in a home in which meth has been used, manufactured, or sold. Under this program, law enforcement agencies, prosecutors, child protective services, social services, and health care services, work together to ensure that these children get the help they need.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, the Combat Meth Act authorized grants to be made to address the use of meth among pregnant and parenting women offenders. The Pregnant and Parenting Offenders program is aimed at facilitating collaboration between the criminal justice, child welfare, and State substance abuse systems in order to reduce the use of drugs by pregnant women and those with dependent children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although Tribes are eligible applicants under the Pregnant and Parenting Offenders program, they were not included as eligible applicants under either the Hot Spots program or the Drug-Endangered Children program. I see no reason why tribes should not be able to access all of these funds.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Meth use has had a devastating impact in communities throughout the country, and Indian Country is no exception. According to NCAI, Native Americans have the highest meth abuse rate among any ethnic group and 70 percent of law enforcement rate meth as their greatest challenge--indeed, a FBI survey found that an estimated 40 percent of violent crime in Indian Country was related to meth use. And last year there was an article in the Gallup Independent newspaper about a Navajo grandmother, her  daughter, and granddaughter, who were all arrested for selling meth. There was also a one-year-old child in the home when police executed the arrest warrant. It is absolutely disheartening to hear about cases such as this, with three generations of a family destroyed by meth.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I strongly believe that we need to do everything we can to assist communities as they struggle to deal with the consequences of meth, and ensuring that Native American communities are able to access these funds is an important first step. I hope my colleagues will join me in supporting this important measure.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300091" topic="Introducing S. 271. A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a shorter recovery period for the depreciation of certain improvements to retail space; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="271">S. 271</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to introduce a series of proposals that, once enacted, will reduce not only the amount of taxes that small businesses pay, but also the administrative burdens which saddle small companies trying to comply with the tax laws. Small businesses are the engine that drives our Nation's economy and I believe these proposals strengthen their ability to lead the way. I am pleased to be joined by colleagues from both sides of the aisle as we work to move these important  initiatives for small businesses from legislation to law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A top priority I hear from small businesses across Maine is the need for tax relief. Despite the fact that small businesses are the real job-creators for Maine's and our Nation's economy, the current tax system is placing an entirely unreasonable burden on them when trying to satisfy their tax obligations. The current tax code imposes a large, and expensive, burden on all taxpayers in terms of satisfying their reporting and record-keeping obligations. The problem, though, is that small companies  are disadvantaged most in terms of the money and time spent in satisfying their tax obligation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For example, according to the Small Business Administration's Office of Advocacy, small businesses spend an astounding 8 billion hours each year complying with government reports. They also spend more than 80 percent of this time on completing tax forms. What's even more troubling is that companies that employ fewer than 20 employees spend nearly $1,304 per employee in tax compliance costs; an amount that is nearly 67 percent more than larger firms.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For that reason, I am introducing a package of proposals that will provide not only targeted, affordable tax relief to small business owners, but also simpler rules under the tax code. By simplifying the tax code, small business owners will be able to satisfy their tax obligation in a cheaper, more efficient manner, allowing them to be able to devote more time and resources to their business.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am introducing legislation today in response to the repeated requests from small businesses in Maine and from across the nation to allow them to expense more of their investments, like the purchase of essential new equipment. My bill modifies the Internal Revenue Code by doubling the amount a small business can expense from $100,000 to $200,000, and make the provision permanent as President Bush proposed this change in his fiscal year 2007 tax proposals. With small businesses representing 99  percent of all employers, creating 75 percent new jobs and contributing 51 percent of private-sector output, their size is the only `small' aspect about them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By doubling and making permanent the current expensing limit and indexing these amounts for inflation, this bill will achieve two important objectives. First, qualifying businesses will be able to write off more of the equipment purchases today, instead of waiting five, seven or more years to recover their costs through depreciation. That represents substantial savings both in dollars and in the time small businesses would otherwise have to spend complying with complex and confusing depreciation  rules. Moreover, new equipment will contribute to continued productivity growth in the business community, which economic experts have repeatedly stressed is essential to the long-term vitality of our economy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second, as a result of this bill, more businesses will qualify for this benefit because the phase-out limit will be increased to $800,000 in new assets purchases. At the same time, small business capital investment will be pumping more money into the economy. This is a win-win for small business and the economy as a whole and I am please to have Senators Lott, Isakson, Chambliss, and Collins join me as cosponsors of this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Another proposal that I am introducing with Senator LINCOLN, the Small Business Tax Flexibility Act of 2007, will permit start-up small business owners to use a taxable year other than the calendar year if they generally earn fewer than $5 million during the tax year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Specifically, the Small Business Tax Flexibility Act of 2007 will permit more taxpayers to use the taxable year most suitable to their business cycle. Until 1986, businesses could elect the taxable year-end that made the most economic sense for the business. In 1986, Congress passed legislation requiring partnerships and S corporations, many of which are small businesses, to adopt a December 31 year-end. The tax code does provide alternatives to the calendar year for small businesses, but the  compliance costs and administrative burdens associated with these alternatives prove to be too high for most small businesses to utilize.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Meanwhile, C corporations, as large corporations often are, receive much more flexibility in their choice of taxable year. A C corporation can adopt either a calendar year or any fiscal year for tax purposes, as along as it keeps its books on that basis. This creates the unfair result of allowing larger businesses with greater resources greater flexibility in choosing a taxable year than smaller firms with fewer resources. This simply does not make sense to me. My bill changes these existing  rules so that more small businesses will be able to use the taxable year that best suits their business.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To provide relief and equity to our nation's 1.5 million retail establishments, most of which have less than five employees, I am introducing a bill with Senators Lincoln, Hutchison, and Kerry that reduces from 39 to 15 years the depreciable life of improvements that are made to retail stores that are owned by the retailer. Under current law, only retailers that lease their property are allowed this accelerated depreciation, which means it excludes retailers that also  own the property in which they operate. My bill simply seeks to provide equal treatment to all retailers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Specifically, this bill will simply conform the tax codes to the realities that retailers on Main Street face. Studies conducted by the Treasury Department, Congressional Research Service and private economists have all found that the 39-year depreciation life for buildings is too long and that the 39-year depreciation life for building improvements is even worse. Retailers generally remodel their stores every five to seven years to reflect changes in customer base and compete with newer stores.  Moreover, many improvements such as interior partitions, ceiling tiles, restroom accessories, and paint, may only last a few years before requiring replacement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This package of proposals are a tremendous opportunity to help small enterprises succeed by providing an incentive for reinvestment and leaving them more of their earnings to do just that. I urge my colleagues to join me in supporting these proposals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the the text of these bills be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the texts of the bills were ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300024" topic="Introducing S. 272. A bill to amend Public Law 87-383 to reauthorize appropriations to promote the conservation of migratory waterfowl and to offset or prevent the serious loss of important wetland and other waterfowl habitat essential to the preservation of migratory waterfowl, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="272">S. 272</bill>] Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill I introduce today--to amend Public Law 87-383 to reauthorize appropriations to promote the conservation of migratory waterfowl and to offset or prevent the serious loss of important wetland and other waterfowl habitat essential to preservation of migratory waterfowl, and for other purposes--be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300092" topic="Introducing S. 273. A bill to amend part D of title XVIII of the Social Security Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to negotiate for lower prices for Medicare prescription drugs; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="273">S. 273</bill>] Mr. President, I have sought recognition today to introduce the Prescription Drug and Health Improvement Act of 2007 to reduce the high prices of prescription drugs for Medicare beneficiaries. I introduced a similar version of this bill in the 108th and the 109th Congress, <bill type="s" number="2766">S. 2766</bill> and <bill type="s" number="813">S. 813</bill>, respectively.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Americans, specifically senior citizens, pay the highest prices in the world for brand-name prescription drugs. With 46.6 million uninsured Americans and many more senior citizens without an adequate prescription drug benefit, filling a doctor's prescription is unaffordable for many people in this country. The United States has the greatest health care system in the world; however, too many seniors are forced to make difficult choices between life-sustaining prescription drugs and daily necessities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services report that in 2005, per capita spending on prescription drugs rose approximately 7 percent, with a similar rate of growth expected for this year. Much of the increase in drug spending is due to higher utilization and the shift from older, lower cost drugs to newer, higher cost drugs. However, rapidly increasing drug prices are a critical component.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>High drug prices, combined with the surging older population, are also taking a toll on State budgets and private sector health insurance benefits. Medicaid spending on prescription drugs rose by 7.5 percent between 2004 and 2005. Until lower priced drugs are available, pressures will continue to squeeze public programs at both the State and Federal level.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To address these problems, my legislation would reduce the high prices of prescription drugs to seniors by repealing the prohibition against interference by the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) with negotiations between drug manufacturers, pharmacies, and prescription drug plan sponsors and instead authorize the Secretary to negotiate contracts with manufacturers of covered prescription drugs. It will allow the Secretary to use Medicare's large beneficiary population to leverage bargaining  power to obtain lower prescription drug prices for Medicare beneficiaries.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Price negotiations between the Secretary of HHS and prescription drug manufacturers would be analogous to the ability of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to negotiate prescription drug prices with manufacturers. This bargaining power enables veterans to receive prescription drugs at a significant cost savings. According to the National Association of Chain Drug Stores, the average "cash cost" of a prescription in 2005 was $51.89. The average cost in the Veterans Affairs (VA) health care system  in fiscal year 2006 was $28.61.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the 108th Congress, in my capacity as chairman of the Veterans' Affairs Committee, I introduced the Veterans Prescription Drugs Assistance Act, <bill type="s" number="1153">S. 1153</bill>, which was reported out of committee, but was not considered before the full Senate. In the 109th Congress, I again introduced the Veterans Prescription Drugs Assistance Act, <bill type="s" number="614">S. 614</bill>, which was not reported out of committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation will broaden the ability of veterans to access the Veterans Affairs' Prescription Drug Program. Under my bill, all Medicare-eligible veterans will be able to purchase medications at a tremendous price reduction through the Veterans Affairs' Prescription Drug Program. In many cases, this will save veterans who are Medicare beneficiaries up to 50 percent on the cost of prescribed medications, a significant savings for veterans. Similar savings may be available to America's seniors  from the savings achieved using the HHS bargaining power, like the Veterans Affairs bargaining power for the benefit of veterans. These savings may provide America's seniors with fiscal relief from the increasing costs of prescription drugs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe this bill can provide desperately needed access to inexpensive, effective prescription drugs for America's seniors. The time has come for concerted action in this arena. I urge my colleagues to move this legislation forward promptly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="Introducing S. 273. A bill to amend part D of title XVIII of the Social Security Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to negotiate for lower prices for Medicare prescription drugs; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today I rise to reintroduce the Federal Employee Protection of Disclosures Act, which will make much needed changes to the Whistleblower Protection Act, WPA. I am pleased once again to be  joined in this effort by Senators Collins, Grassley, Levin, Lieberman, Leahy, Voinovich, Carper, Durbin, Pryor, and Lautenberg.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator Levin and I first introduced this legislation in 2000. In the House, Representatives Henry Waxman and Tom Davis, the chairman and ranking member of the House Government Reform Committee, and Representative Todd Platts, who has sponsored companion legislation since 2003, have been working to enact strong whistleblower protections.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over the years, we've worked to educate our colleagues on the need to strengthen the WPA and build consensus for the legislation. I'm especially pleased that last year our bill passed the Senate by unanimous consent as an amendment to the fiscal year 2007 Defense Authorization Act. While the measure was removed with other non-defense specific material in conference, I believe the Senate's action will provide the momentum to make a real difference for Federal whistleblowers in the 110th Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We agree that to ensure the success of any government program there must be appropriate checks in place to weed out mismanagement and wasteful spending. A strong and vibrant WPA is a critical tool in saving taxpayer money and ensuring an open government.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Federal Employee Protection of Disclosures Act addresses many court decisions that have eroded protections for Federal employees and have ignored congressional intent. Our legislation ensures that Federal whistleblowers are protected from retaliatory action when notifying the public and government leaders of waste, fraud, and abuse. If we fail to protect whistleblowers, then our efforts to improve government management, protect the public, and secure the nation will also fail.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation: clarifies congressional intent that Federal employees are protected for any disclosure of waste, fraud, or abuse--including those made as part of an employee's job duties; provides an independent determination as to whether the loss or denial of a security clearance is retaliation against a whistleblower; and suspends the Federal Circuit Court of Appeals' sole jurisdiction over Federal employee whistleblower cases for 5 years, which would ensure a fuller review of a whistleblower's  claim.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Given that the United States will be fighting the war on terror for years to come and that funding such operations requires significant resources, it is imperative that government funds are spent wisely. That is why Federal employees must be confident that they can disclose government waste, fraud, and abuse without fear of retaliation. Restoring credibility to the WPA is no less than a necessity. I look forward to working with my colleagues to pass this critical legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the legislation be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="Introducing S. 275. A bill to establish the Prehistoric Trackways National Monument in the State of New Mexico; to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="275">S. 275</bill>] Mr. President, I'm pleased to reintroduce today with Senator DOMENICI a bill we introduced last Congress. The Prehistoric Trackways National Monument Establishment Act would protect a site of worldwide scientific significance in the Robledo Mountains in my State. The bill would create a national monument to preserve and allow for the continuing scientific investigation of this remarkable "megatracksite" of 280,000,000 year-old fossils. The Energy Committee held a hearing  last year where the Bureau of Land Management testified in support; in addition the bill has the support of the local community. I appreciate Senator DOMENICI's support on this measure and hope that with the progress we made last Congress we can look forward to moving the bill quickly through the Senate this year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The vast tidal mudflats that made up much of modern New Mexico 60 million years before the dinosaurs preserved the marks of some of the earliest life on our planet to make its way out of the ocean. The fossil record of this time is scattered throughout New Mexico but, until this discovery, there were few places where the range of life and their interactions with each other could be studied.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Las Cruces resident Jerry MacDonald first brought the find to light in 1988 when he revealed that there was far more to be found in the Robledos than the occasional fossil that local residents had been seeing for years. The trackways he hauled out on his back, some over 20 feet long, showed that there was a great deal of useful information buried in the rock there. These trackways help complete the puzzle of how these ancient creatures lived in a way that we cannot understand from only studying  their fossilized bones.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator DOMENICI and Representative Skeen joined me in creating legislation, passed in 1990, to protect the area and study its scientific value. In 1994, scientists from the New Mexico Museum of Natural History and Science, the University of Colorado, and the Smithsonian Institution completed their study and documented the significant scientific value of the find. Particularly owing to the quality of the specimens and the wide range of animals that had left their imprint there the study  found that the site was of immense scientific value. The study concluded, in part, "[t]he diversity, abundance and quality of the tracks in the Robledo Mountains is far greater than at any other known tracksite or aggregation of tracksites. Because of this, the Robledo tracks allow a wide</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to permanently protecting the fossils for the scientific community the bill would make it a priority that local residents get the opportunity to see these unique specimens and participate in their curation. This should provide a unique scientific and educational opportunity to Las Cruces and the surrounding community.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I look forward to working with my colleagues to protect these important resources and allow for their continuing contribution to our understanding of life on the ancient earth.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300036" topic="Introducing S. 275. A bill to establish the Prehistoric Trackways National Monument in the State of New Mexico; to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, the fossilized trackways near Las Cruces, New Mexico, in Dona Ana County came to my attention in the early 1990's. During the 101st Congress, I cosponsored Senator Bingaman's legislation that directed the Bureau of Land Management to study and report on the significance of the prehistoric sites near the Robledo Mountains.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe our Federal lands are truly national treasures, and I understand the challenges we face in managing our public lands in a responsible and environmentally sensitive manner. Local leaders, special interest groups, multiple users, New Mexico State University, and the Bureau of Land Management, BLM, have identified many land issues in the Las Cruces area that need to be addressed. The trackways are but one of these issues that can and should be addressed in the context of a broader lands  bill. I continue to believe that introduction of comprehensive or omnibus legislation is a preferable approach, rather than the introduction of individual bills to deal with each separate issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The trackways are a remarkable resource that need and deserve protection, and I support the intent of this bill. While I am very supportive of the overall goal to protect these prehistoric trackway sites, there are several particulars in this bill that I do not fully embrace and on which I want to continue to work with Senator Bingaman, such as ensuring that we authorize all uses in the area that are not inconsistent with the purposes of the bill, and reworking the section regarding  BLM authority with respect to hunting activities. As we work through the legislative process, I look forward to working with Senator Bingaman to accomplish the objective of protecting the prehistoric trackway sites, while at the same time addressing some of the broader Federal land issues in Dona Ana County.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="Introducing S. 276. A bill to strengthen the consequences of the fraudulent use of United States or foreign passports and for other purposes; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="276">S. 276</bill>] Mr. President, Senator Sessions and I are introducing legislation today that will enhance our national security by expanding and strengthening the current passport and visa fraud laws.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Passport and Visa Security Act bill adds much needed law to punish trafficking in passports and visas and clarifies the current criminal law. It also punishes those who engage in schemes to defraud immigrants based on changes in the immigration law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill is an improved version of a bill Senator Sessions and I introduced in the 109th Congress. We both have long been concerned about the need to strengthen our national security by strengthening our document fraud laws.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In fact, we introduced our passport fraud bill well before the comprehensive immigration reform bill was passed in the Senate last Spring.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For that reason, I was pleased that the comprehensive immigration reform bill contained important document fraud provisions. This bill builds on those provisions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The evidence has shown repeatedly that false immigration documents provide a gateway for organized crime and terrorism. The need to take action against this crime is clear.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For too long, the Federal Government has moved too slowly--or not at all--to enhance our border security. According to the 9/11 National Commission Staff Report on Terrorist Travel, prior to September 11, 2001, no agency of the U.S. government thought of border security as a tool in the counterterrorism arsenal.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Still today, over five years since the tragic attacks on September 11, the Federal Government has failed to devote sufficient time, technology, personnel and resources to make border security a cornerstone of our national security policy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last year, Congress passed a law to build a border fence. I believe this law was an important first step, but a fence alone cannot sufficiently protect our vulnerable borders.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In fact, as the 9/11 Commission report demonstrates, individuals with fraudulent documents can pose a far greater threat to our national security than those traveling with no documents at all.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Fraudulent documents give criminals free reign to create a new identity and to plan and carry out attacks in the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We know, for example, that at least two of the 9/11 hijackers used passports that were altered when they entered this country and as many as 15 of the 19 hijackers could have been intercepted by border officials, based in part on their travel documents.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The 9/11 Commission Report detailed the way the terrorist operatives carefully selected the documents they used for travel--most often relying on fraudulent ones.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The terrorists altered passports by substituting photographs, adding false visas, bleaching stamps, and by substituting pages.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The terrorists devoted extensive resources to acquiring and manipulating passports--all to avoid detection of their nefarious activities and objectives.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, over five years later, Interpol reports that they have records of more than 12 million stolen and lost travel documents from 113 different countries. These are only the ones we know about.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Interpol estimates that 30 to 40 million travel documents have been stolen worldwide.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We know that over the past few years, passport and visa forgery has become even easier thanks to home computers, digital photography, scanners and color laser printing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>News articles document that passport and visa fraud has become so lucrative that gangs are offering franchises in the multimillion-dollar scam to forgers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, it's not only foreign passports that can be forged. Forged and fraudulent United States passports can be the most dangerous when in the wrong hands.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With a U.S. passport, criminals can establish American citizenship and have unlimited access to virtually every country in the world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It's no surprise, then, that passport and visa fraud are often linked to other, very serious crimes in the United States and abroad: narcotics trafficking, organized crimes, money laundering, human trafficking, and identity theft.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For example, this past December, the son of former Liberian President Charles Taylor, Charles McArthur Emmanuel, who headed a violent paramilitary unit in his father's government, was sentenced in Miami for passport fraud.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A day later, a Federal grand jury indicted him on charges of torture and conspiracy involving acts committed in Liberia in 2002.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Emmanuel, also known as Charles "Chuckie" Taylor and Roy Belfast Jr., was on Interpol's Most Wanted list and the United Nations travel watch list.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nevertheless, he escaped detection by falsifying his passport application, ultimately gaining easy entry and exit from the United States while he perpetrated his crimes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Despite evidence that these crimes are widespread and that millions of travel documents are on the black market, in 2004, the State Department's Diplomatic Security Service reports that it made about 500 arrests for passport fraud, with only 300 convictions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For these reasons, Senator SESSIONS and I are introducing a bill today to strengthen current passport and visa laws in a number of key ways.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, this bill adds two new laws with strong penalties to punish those who traffic in fraudulent travel documents. The current law makes no distinction between those caught with multiple false travel documents--the very worst offenders who are often part of organized crime rings--and those with only one false document. Our bill would change that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also updates the current travel document fraud laws--using plain language advocated for by the practitioners that passed the Senate as part of the comprehensive immigration reform bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thirdly, the bill adds provisions to the current passport and visa fraud laws to ensure that conspiracies and attempts to commit these crimes are investigated and prosecuted just as vigorously as the completed crime.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Fourth--the bill makes explicit that there is extraterritorial jurisdiction over these offenses, so that individuals who counterfeit travel documents while abroad but are caught trying to enter the United States are still subject to prosecution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also directs the U.S. Sentencing Guidelines Commissions to reconsider the relatively low sentencing guidelines to reflect the potential seriousness of these crimes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Currently, offenders who engage in passport or visa fraud generally serve less than a year imprisonment, providing little incentive for U.S. Attorney's Offices to expend scarce resources in prosecuting these crimes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, the bill creates a law to punish sham attorneys who cheat immigrants out of thousands of dollars by preying on their fears that they could be forced to leave the country. We know that when Congress discusses changing the immigration law, scam artists target and exploit these vulnerable populations. These crimes should not go unpunished.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill provides much needed reform. It strengthens the security of documents used to illegally gain entry to this country and empowers the agents and prosecutors who enforce our borders to take swift and strong action against these criminals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask my colleagues to join Senator Sessions and me in supporting this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that a bill summary and the text of this bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the materials were ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300088" topic="TITLE II--OTHER REFORMS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I want to thank my colleague Senator Feinstein for her hard work on document security issues. She currently serves as the Chair of the Judiciary Committee's Terrorism Subcommittee, Senator Kyl is Ranking Member, and I am looking forward to working with her on the document security that issues I am sure our subcommittee will address this Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This year will mark the 3rd year Senator Feinstein and I have worked together on legislation aimed at making it easier to prosecute people trying to enter the U.S. with fraudulent documents.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One of the most dangerous document security issues we face is how to keep passports and visas out of the hands of the people we don't want to have them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a 2004 U.S. News and World Report article rightly stated, "When it comes to terrorists' most valuable weapons, passports and visas probably rank higher than bullets and bombs." A 2004 study done by the Department of Homeland Security Office of Inspector General titled "A Review of the Use of Stolen Passports From Visa Waiver Countries to Enter the United States," found that "[there are] over 10 million lost or stolen passports that might be in circulation." As background for the report,  the Forensics Documents Laboratory informed the Office of the Inspector General that "criminals consider a passport" from a Visa Waiver Country "a very valuable commodity."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To keep out terrorists and others we do not want to allow into the United States, we must be able to identify and effectively prosecute people who lie or give us fraudulent information to obtain a U.S. visa or a passport.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Additionally, we must be able to identify and effectively prosecute people trying to enter the U.S. with a passport or visa that belongs to someone else.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Perhaps most importantly, we must effectively prosecute those possessing multiple passports and visas they intend to distribute to others. We must be able to take these "career" document traffickers, those caught with more than 10 fraudulent passports or visas, off the streets.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under current law, violators are not being prosecuted effectively because there is no statute that specifically makes trafficking in multiple (10 or more) documents its own crime. This bill will add that new crime--punishable by 20 years in jail--to the passport and visa fraud sections of the criminal code.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to creating a new crime to penalize trafficking in 10 or more fraudulent immigration documents, 20 year maximum sentence, Title I of the bill simplifies the language of several of the current passport fraud provisions of the criminal code and changes the maximum penalties for these offenses from 10 years for the first offense and 15 years for subsequent offenses, to simply 15 years for each offense.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also includes a new protection for immigrants. Anyone who engages in a scheme to defraud them in connection with matters under Federal immigration law, or who pretends to be an immigration lawyer, will be charged under a new crime that carries a maximum penalty of 15 years. Although this provision is not strictly related to passport fraud, it will protect immigrants from sham attorneys and legal "experts" who cheat them out of their money by pretending to offer them immigration benefits  or legitimate documents.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many of the bill's provisions simply clean up sections of the criminal code. For example--one section modifies the alternative sentencing penalties to make sure the penalties for severe passport fraud offenses (such as those used to facilitate a drug trafficking crime or an act of international terrorism) are consistent throughout the code.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Other provisions codify common law principles needed for effective prosecution of document fraud offenses. For example--one section makes needed clarifications on venue. Currently, false statements or documents are often included in the application which is mailed from one location but processed in another location. This section makes clear that the offense is perpetrated both at the location of the mailing and at the location of the adjudication. If the application containing false statements  is prepared overseas, this section clarifies that the offense is still punishable in the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In March of 2004, Mark Zuckerman, Assistant U.S. Attorney for New Hampshire, testified before the United States Sentencing Commission. New Hampshire's National Passport Center processed 2 million of the 7 million passports issued in 2003. The National Passport Center also receives nearly all of the applications for passport renewals filed with the State Department. New Hampshire conducted a passport fraud initiative in its U.S. Attorney's Office as part of its anti-terrorism effort. Zuckerman's  testimony provides some insight into the problems that arose during the initiative.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Though the passport applications were processed in New Hampshire, cases of passport fraud resulting from those applications were not being handled in New Hampshire. Typically, they were sent back to the district from which they were mailed. Once returned, they were often declined for prosecution by their local U.S. Attorney's office.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One of the reasons frequently given by the regional U.S. Attorney's Offices for declining passport fraud cases was: "The sentencing guidelines do not treat passport fraud as a serious offense for which a period of incarceration is likely."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would reiterate what Mr. Zuckerman so astutely pointed out in his testimony. Under the current Criminal Code, the most common forms of passport fraud--unless they constitute terrorism or drug trafficking--are just class C felonies. When the defendant has no criminal history, the court is simply required to incarcerate the defendant for 0-6 months. This is the lowest and least consequential sentencing range that can be assigned to any felony under the U.S.  Code.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The 9/11 Commission also recognized the lack of routine prosecutions for passport fraud offenses. Page 386 of their report noted:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Fraudulent travel documents, for instance, are usually returned to travelers who are denied entry without further examination for terrorist trademarks, investigation into their source, or legal process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Importantly, the bill we are introducing today directs the Sentencing Commission to reevaluate the current low sentencing guidelines for passport and visa fraud offenses to reflect the potential seriousness of these crimes and the changes made by our bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Additionally, we will require the Sentencing Commission to report back to the Congress on the rationale behind their decision to change (or not change) the sentencing guidelines as a result of this direction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Majority Leader HARRY REID has repeatedly stated that one of the items at the top of the Democratic agenda early this</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress is the implementation of the recommendations of the 9/11 Commission. In addition to their comments on the lack of prosecutions, the 9/11 Commission had a lot more say about the use of fraudulent and altered passports and visas in the Commission of the 9/11 terrorist attacks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>"[W]e endeavor to dispel the myth that their [the hijackers'] entry into the United States was `clean and legal'. It was not....... two [hijackers] carried passports manipulated in a fraudulent manner. It is likely that several more hijackers carried passports with similar fraudulent manipulation. Two hijackers lied on their visa applications" Preface, 9/11 Commission staff report.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>"To avoid detection of their activities and objectives while engaging in travel that necessitates using a passport, terrorists devote extensive resources to acquiring and manipulating passports, entry and exits stamps, and visas. The al Qaeda terrorist organization was no exception. High-level members of Al Qaeda were expert document forgers . . ." Page 1. 9/11 Commission staff report.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>"Travel history, however, is still recorded in passports with entry-exit stamps called cachets, which al Qaeda has trained its operatives to forge and use to conceal their terrorist activities". Page 403, 9/11 Commission report.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>"[C]ertain al Qaeda members were charged with organizing passport collection schemes to keep the pipelines of fraudulent documents flowing." Page 186., ibid</paragraph>
    <paragraph>"For terrorists, travel documents are as important as weapons. They must travel clandestinely to meet, train, plan, case targets, and gain access to attack ..... In their travels, terrorists use evasive measures, such as altered and counterfeit passports and visas ....." Page 384. ibid.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I hope that Senator Reid plans to include the Feinstein/Sessions Passport and Visa Fraud Bill in his 9/11 Commission Recommendations Implementation Package.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
