<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1196874002" ordinal="17" title="EXTENSION OF MORNING BUSINESS">
  <narrative>EXTENSION OF MORNING BUSINESS -- (Senate - December 05, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="14759">S14759</bill>]</narrative>
  <chair> The Senator's time under morning business has expired.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask for 4 additional minutes to finish my statement.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300027" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I was going to use the occasion to ask unanimous consent that following the Senator from Washington speaking, I would like to be recognized for up to 10 minutes in morning business.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, we have a number of Senators on our side seeking recognition. Perhaps we can put that together fairly quickly.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Chair notes that at this time, there is 5 minutes left in morning business for the Republican side. The Democratic side has used all of its time in morning business.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that morning business be extended to include 4 minutes for myself, the Senator from Washington----</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300027" topic="">
    <paragraph>I would like 10 minutes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="">
    <paragraph>Ten minutes to the Senator from Texas, 5 minutes to the Senator from Montana, 10 minutes to the Senator from Illinois.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300037" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I assumed we were going to go off morning business and onto the calendar. I was going to speak for 20 minutes, so I will speak in line of appearance on the floor for 20 minutes at whatever appropriate time that is.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="">
    <paragraph>I add that to the consent request, that if there are Republican Senators who would like intervening times, in between, we include those as well in the unanimous consent request.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Texas.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300027" topic="">
    <paragraph>Reserving the right to object, and I will not object, I express my appreciation to the Senator from Washington for allowing Republican Senators to intervene and the extent to which Democratic Members speak, I would like to make sure we have equivalent time on our side. I think we can work that out.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="">
    <paragraph>That is included in my request. I ask additionally that Senator Menendez be allowed 10 minutes as well as the end of that unanimous subsequent request.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection? The Senator from Montana.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask that my 5 minutes be expanded to 10 minutes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Does the Senator so modify her request?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="">
    <paragraph>I do.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The request is so modified. Is there objection to the existing unanimous consent request? Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
