<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1202230801" ordinal="39" title="STATEMENTS ON INTRODUCED BILLS AND JOINT RESOLUTIONS">
  <narrative>STATEMENTS ON INTRODUCED BILLS AND JOINT RESOLUTIONS -- (Senate - February 05, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="659">S659</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="Introducing S. 2593. A bill to establish a program at the Forest Service and the Department of the Interior to carry out collaborative ecological restoration treatments for priority forest landscapes on public land, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="2593">S. 2593</bill>] Mr. President, today, I am introducing the Forest Landscape Restoration Act. I developed this bill with Senators Domenici and Feinstein, and I am pleased they have joined as cosponsors. The bill also is cosponsored by Senators Allard, Wyden, Salazar, Cantwell, Craig, Akaka, and Crapo. I also am pleased that Chairman Grijalva will be introducing a companion bill in the House of Representatives, and I look forward to working with him as  his subcommittee in the Natural Resources Committee moves forward with the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill establishes a program to select and fund projects that restore forests at a landscape scale through a  process that encourages collaboration, relies on the best available science, facilitates local economic development, and leverages local funds with national and private funding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As many of my colleagues know, we are facing serious forest health and wildfire challenges in many of our National Forests. A century of over-aggressive fire suppression, logging, and other land uses have significantly deteriorated entire landscapes. These conditions have played an important role in the extraordinary wildfires and insect-caused mortality we have seen on millions of acres of National Forest and other lands. To address these problems, it is critical to begin trying to restore our  forests at a landscape scale.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Landscape-scale restoration is important because, first, it is key to controlling wildfire suppression costs, which is one of the issues that is emphasized in our bill. Wildland fire appropriations have more than tripled in the last decade, and we are now spending billions every year trying to suppress fires. We will not be able to get control of the ballooning costs of fire suppression until we can allow more fires to play their natural, beneficial role in restoring and maintaining healthy,  fire-resilient forests. But that will not be possible until we can reduce hazardous fuels and the risk of unnaturally intense fire on a landscape scale.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, our bill will help to reduce wildfire suppression costs through forest restoration.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second, landscape-scale restoration is an important component of successful economic development, another issue we have emphasized in our bill. In many cases, forest restoration will not be fiscally viable unless we can put the byproducts of restoration to economic use. Large-scale forest restoration efforts can help to provide economies of scale, and long-term efforts can help to provide entrepreneurs with the confidence that encourages investment and initiative.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, our bill will help to make the restoration economy a reality by facilitating the use of restoration byproducts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Third, landscape restoration is necessary for the health of many of our forest ecosystems, which also is emphasized in our bill. We need healthy landscapes for a clean, abundant, and controlled water supply. We need them for clean air and carbon sequestration. We need them to support fish and wildlife. And we need healthy forest ecosystems if they are to have a chance to survive the pressures of climate change. Fire suppression and other land uses have caused entire forest landscapes to deteriorate,  and we cannot reverse that deterioration without landscape-level restoration.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So, our bill provides a unique program to conduct comprehensive ecosystem restoration through landscape-scale treatments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our bill also builds upon the existing successes in forest restoration by requiring collaboration and the best available science to form the foundation for landscape restoration.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Despite the importance of landscape-scale restoration, neither the National Fire Plan, nor the Healthy Forests Restoration Act, nor any of our other efforts have been very successful in facilitating restoration and hazardous fuels reduction on landscape scales. A lack of sufficient funding is one of the primary reasons. Restoring landscapes takes a significant amount of funding over a significant period of time. That has proven to be beyond the capacity of the local and regional agency budgets.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To address this problem, the Forest Landscape Restoration Act authorizes $40 million per year for 10 years to be paid into a national pool. Eligible landscape restoration projects from around the country would compete for a portion of that money. Forty million dollars is not nearly enough money to fund landscape-scale treatments in all of the forest landscapes in need of restoration, but it is a realistic amount of funding, and it is enough to make landscape-scale restoration a reality.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of funding and other challenges, landscape-scale restoration remains largely theoretical. As a result, this legislation is designed to be both practical and experimental. It does not redirect existing efforts. It instead adds to existing efforts by creating a program that will make planning, funding, and carrying out at least a handful of landscape-scale forest restoration projects possible. If it is successful--and I think it will be--we can expand it in the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would again like to thank Senators Domenici and Feinstein and the other cosponsors of the bill. I appreciate the stakeholders who have written to support this bill, including the Nature Conservancy--which has been very supportive of our effort--American Forests, the Forest Guild, Sustainable Northwest, the Watershed Research and Training Center, and Conservation Northwest. I look forward to working with them and the many other stakeholders as we move forward with the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>
    <bill type="s" number="2593">S. 2593</bill>
  </narrative>
  <narrative> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "Forest Landscape Restoration Act of 2008".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. PURPOSE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; The purpose of this Act is to encourage the collaborative, science-based ecosystem restoration of priority forest landscapes through a process that--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) encourages ecological, economic, and social sustainability;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) leverages local resources with national and private resources;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) facilitates the reduction of wildfire management costs, including through reestablishing natural fire regimes and reducing the risk of uncharacteristic wildfire; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) demonstrates the degree to which--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) various ecological restoration techniques--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) achieve ecological health objectives; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) affect wildfire activity and management costs; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) the use of forest restoration byproducts can offset treatment costs while benefitting rural economies and improving forest health.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 3. DEFINITIONS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; In this Act:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) FUND.--The term "Fund" means the Collaborative Forest Landscape Restoration Fund established by section 4(f).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) PLAN.--The term "Plan" means the plan entitled the "10 Year Comprehensive Strategy Implementation Plan" and dated December 2006.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) PROGRAM.--The term "program" means the Collaborative Forest Landscape Restoration Program established under section 4(a).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) SECRETARY.--The term "Secretary" means the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 4. COLLABORATIVE FOREST LANDSCAPE RESTORATION PROGRAM.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (a) In General.--The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, shall establish a Collaborative Forest Landscape Restoration Program to select and fund ecological restoration treatments for priority forest landscapes in accordance with applicable law.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (b) Eligibility Criteria.--To be eligible for nomination under subsection (c), a collaborative forest landscape restoration proposal shall--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) be based on a landscape restoration strategy that--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) is complete or substantially complete;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) identifies and prioritizes ecological restoration treatments for a 10-year period across a landscape that is--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) at least 50,000 acres;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) comprised primarily of forested National Forest System land, but may also include other Federal, State, tribal, or private land;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (iii) in need of active ecosystem restoration; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (iv) accessible by existing or proposed wood-processing infrastructure at an appropriate scale to use woody biomass and small-diameter wood removed in ecological restoration treatments;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) incorporates--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) the best available science and scientific application tools in ecological restoration strategies; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) the requirements for old-growth maintenance, restoration, and management direction of paragraphs (2), (3), and (4) of subsection (e) and the requirements for large-tree retention of subsection (f) of section 102 of the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 (16 U.S.C. 6512); and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (D) does not include the establishment of permanent roads;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) be developed and implemented through a collaborative process that--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) includes multiple stakeholders representing diverse interests;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B)(i) is transparent and nonexclusive; or&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) meets the requirements for a resource advisory committee under section 205 of the Secure Rural Schools and Community Self-Determination Act of 2000 (16 U.S.C. 500 note; Public Law 106-393); and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) has an established record of successful planning and implementation of ecological restoration projects on National Forest System land;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) describe plans to--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) use fire for ecological restoration and maintenance, where appropriate; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) improve fish and wildlife habitat, including for endangered, threatened, and sensitive species;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) maintain or improve water quality;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (D) prevent, remediate, or control invasions of exotic species;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (E) maintain or decommission roads;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (F) use woody biomass and small-diameter trees produced from projects implementing the landscape restoration strategy;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (G) report annually on performance, including through performance measures from the Plan;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (H) develop small business incubators and provide employment and training opportunities to people in rural communities, including contracts for monitoring activities, through--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) local private, nonprofit, or cooperative entities;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) Youth Conservation Corps crews or related partnerships, with State, local, and non-profit youth groups;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (iii) small or micro-businesses; or&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (iv) other entities that will hire or train a significant percentage of local people to complete such contracts; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (I) take into account any applicable community wildfire protection plan (as defined in section 101 of the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 (16 U.S.C. 6511));&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) analyze the anticipated cost savings resulting from--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) reduced wildfire management costs; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) a decrease in the unit costs of implementing ecological restoration treatments over time;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) estimate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) the annual Federal funding necessary to implement the proposal; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) the amount of new non-Federal investment for carrying out the proposal that would be leveraged by Federal funding for ecological restoration treatments; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (6) be subject to any other requirements that the Secretary determines to be necessary for the efficient and effective administration of the program.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (c) Nomination Process.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) SUBMISSION.--Collaborative forest landscape restoration proposals shall be submitted to the appropriate Regional Forester for consideration.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) NOMINATION.--A Regional Forester may nominate collaborative forest landscape restoration proposals for selection by the Secretary.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) DOCUMENTATION.--With respect to each collaborative forest landscape restoration proposal that is nominated under paragraph (2)--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) the appropriate Regional Forester shall--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) include a proposal to use Federal funds allocated to the region to fund those costs of planning and carrying out ecological restoration treatments on National Forest land consistent with the landscape restoration strategy that would not be covered by amounts transferred to the Secretary from the Fund; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) provide evidence that amounts proposed to be transferred to the Secretary from the Fund during the first 2 years following selection would be used to carry out ecological restoration treatments consistent with the landscape restoration strategy during the same fiscal year in which the funds are transferred to the Secretary;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) if actions under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior are proposed, the nomination shall require--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) the concurrence of the appropriate official of the Department of the Interior; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) a proposal to fund ecological restoration treatments consistent with the landscape restoration strategy that would be carried out by the Secretary of the Interior; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) if actions on land not under the jurisdiction of the Secretary or the Secretary of the Interior are proposed, the appropriate Regional Forester shall provide evidence that the landowner intends to participate in, and provide appropriate funding to carry out, the actions.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (d) Selection Process.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) IN GENERAL.--After consulting with any scientific and technical advisory panels established under subsection (e), the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, shall, subject to paragraph (2), select the best collaborative forest landscape restoration proposals that--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) have been nominated under subsection (c)(2); and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) meet the eligibility criteria established by subsection (b).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) CRITERIA.--In selecting collaborative forest landscape restoration proposals under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall give special consideration to--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) the strength of the ecological case of the proposal for landscape restoration and the proposed restoration strategies;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) the strength of the collaborative process;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) whether the proposal would reduce the relative costs of carrying out treatments as a result of the use of woody biomass and small-diameter trees;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (D) whether the proposal is likely to achieve reductions in long-term wildfire management costs;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (E) the strength of the landscape restoration proposal and strategy; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (F) whether an appropriate level of non-Federal investment would be leveraged in carrying out the proposal.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) LIMITATION.--The Secretary may select not more than--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) 10 collaborative forest landscape restoration proposals to be funded during any given year; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) 2 collaborative forest landscape restoration proposals in any 1 region of the National Forest System to be funded during any given year.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (e) Advisory Panels.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) SCIENTIFIC ADVISORY PANEL.--The Secretary shall establish a scientific advisory panel comprised of not more than 12 experts in ecological forest restoration and fire ecology to evaluate, and provide recommendations on, any proposal that has been nominated under subsection (c)(2) and meets the eligibility criteria established by subsection (b) with respect to--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) the strength of the ecological case of the proposal for landscape restoration and the proposed restoration strategies; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) whether the proposal is likely to achieve reductions in long-term wildfire management costs.</narrative>
  <narrative> (2) TECHNICAL ADVISORY PANEL.--The Secretary may establish a technical advisory panel comprised of experts in rural business development and the use of woody biomass and small-diameter trees to evaluate, and provide recommendations on, any proposal that has been nominated under subsection (c)(2) and meets the eligibility criteria established by subsection (b) with respect to whether the proposal is likely to reduce the relative costs of carrying out treatments as a result of the use of  woody biomass and small-diameter trees and provide local economic benefit.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (f) Collaborative Forest Landscape Restoration Fund.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) ESTABLISHMENT.--There is established in the Treasury of the United States a fund, to be known as the "Collaborative Forest Landscape Restoration Fund", to be used to pay up to 50 percent of the cost of carrying out ecological restoration treatments on National Forest System land for each collaborative forest landscape restoration proposal selected to be carried out under subsection (d), consisting of--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) such amounts as are appropriated to the Fund under paragraph (5); and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) any interest earned on investment of amounts in the Fund under paragraph (3).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) EXPENDITURES FROM FUND.--On request by the Secretary, the Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer from the Fund to the Secretary of Agriculture such amounts as the Secretary of Agriculture determines are necessary to carry out ecological restoration treatments under paragraph (1).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) INVESTMENT OF AMOUNTS.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) IN GENERAL.--The Secretary of the Treasury shall invest such portion of the Fund as is not, in the judgment of the Secretary of the Treasury, after consulting with the Secretary, required to meet current withdrawals.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) INTEREST-BEARING OBLIGATIONS.--Investments may be made only in interest-bearing obligations of the United States.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) ACQUISITION OF OBLIGATIONS.--For the purpose of investments under subparagraph (A), obligations may be acquired--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) on original issue at the issue price; or&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) by purchase of outstanding obligations at the market price.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (D) SALE OF OBLIGATIONS.--Any obligation acquired by the Fund may be sold by the Secretary of the Treasury at the market price.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (E) CREDITS TO FUND.--The interest on, and the proceeds from the sale or redemption of, any obligations held in the Fund shall be credited to and form a part of the Fund.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) ACCOUNTING AND REPORTING SYSTEM.--The Secretary shall establish an accounting and reporting system for the Fund.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) AUTHORIZATION OF APPROPRIATIONS.--There is authorized to be appropriated to the Fund $40,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2008 through 2018, to remain available until expended.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (g) Program Implementation and Monitoring.--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) WORK PLAN.--Not later than 180 days after the date on which a collaborative forest landscape restoration proposal is selected to be carried out, the Secretary shall create, in collaboration with the interested stakeholders, an implementation work plan and budget to implement the collaborative forest landscape restoration proposal that includes--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) a description of the manner in which the proposal would be implemented to achieve ecological and community economic benefit, including capacity building to accomplish restoration;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) a business plan that addresses--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) the anticipated unit treatment cost reductions over 10 years;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) the anticipated costs for infrastructure needed for the proposal;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (iii) the projected sustainability of the supply of woody biomass and small-diameter trees removed in ecological restoration treatments; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (iv) the projected local economic benefits of the proposal; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) documentation of the non-Federal investment in the priority landscape, including the sources and uses of the investments.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) PROJECT IMPLEMENTATION.--Amounts transferred to the Secretary from the Fund shall be used to carry out ecological restoration treatments that are--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) consistent with the landscape restoration proposal and strategy; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) identified through the collaborative process described in subsection (b)(2).&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) ANNUAL REPORT.--Annually, the Secretary, in collaboration with the Secretary  of the Interior and interested stakeholders, shall prepare a report on the accomplishments of each selected collaborative forest landscape restoration proposal that includes--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) a description of all acres (or other appropriate unit) treated and restored through projects implementing the landscape restoration strategy;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) an evaluation of progress, including performance measures and how prior year evaluations have contributed to improved project performance;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (C) a description of community benefits achieved, including any local economic benefits;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (D) the results of the multiparty monitoring, evaluation, and accountability process under paragraph (4); and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (E) a summary of the costs of--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (i) treatments; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (ii) relevant fire management activities.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) MULTIPARTY MONITORING.--The Secretary shall, in collaboration with the Secretary of the Interior and interested stakeholders, use a multiparty monitoring, evaluation, and accountability process to assess the positive or negative ecological, social, and economic effects of each project implementing a selected collaborative forest landscape restoration proposal for not less than 15 years after project implementation commences.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (h) Report.--Not later than 5 years after the first fiscal year in which funding is made available to carry out ecological restoration projects under the program, and every 5 years thereafter, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, shall submit a report on the program, including an assessment of whether, and to what extent, the program is fulfilling the purposes of this Act, to--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives; and</narrative>
  <narrative> (4) the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives. &lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</narrative>
</record>
