<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1204822801" ordinal="43" title="CONGRATULATING IOWA STATE UNIVERSITY OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY">
  <narrative>CONGRATULATING IOWA STATE UNIVERSITY OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY -- (Senate - March 06, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="1716">S1716</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the consideration of <bill type="sr" number="475">S. Res. 475</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="475">S. Res. 475</bill>) congratulating Iowa State University of Science and Technology on its 150 years of leadership and service to the United States and the world as Iowa's land-grant university.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today to speak on behalf of my alma mater, Iowa Sate University, and recognize it upon its 150 years of leadership and service to the United States and the world as Iowa's land-grant university.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Iowa State has a colorful and progressive history. The university was founded under the Morrill Land Grant College Act of 1862. Representative Justin Smith Morrill, who wrote the bill, and Abraham Lincoln, who signed the act into law in the midst of the Civil War, had the vision to establish a public institution that provided and still provides a top flight, affordable education for people of all walks of life.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Iowa was the first State to accept the terms of the Morrill land grant and pioneered all three parts of its mission. The act calls for schools that provide "access to all, regardless of race, gender, or class." The act also limits funding to only schools that conduct "Practical Research." Finally, the Morrill Land Grant Act calls for the schools provided for to serve significant "outreach" in the surrounding community.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Iowa State has certainly lived up to those lofty words of the Morrill Act. Iowa State University has been home to some of the most important technological and agricultural advances in history. Professor John Atanasoff and graduate student Clifford Berry of ISU have been credited with the invention of the electronic digital computer in  the late 1930s. When they constructed the Atanasoff-Berry computer, they were the first to incorporate the seven basic  principles of modern computing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Professor Henry Gilman laid the foundation for the modern plastics industry with his research in polyethylene materials. In the 1920s, ISU was home to the development of hybrid seed corn. Professor Orland Sweeney conducted pioneering work on soybean oil extraction and producing ethanol from corn and other plant materials in the 1930s.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Iowa State has produced such esteemed graduates as George Washington Carver, a man who shattered the glass ceiling for minority inventors, women's rights activist Carrie Chapman Catt, and astronaut Clayton Anderson, just to name a few.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>John Garang, who earned a Ph.D. in economics from Iowa State, not only went on to serve as vice president of Sudan, but in his role as leader of the Sudanese Peoples Liberation Army worked to end his country's violent civil war.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One cannot forget to mention that Mildred Day, the inventor of Rice Krispies treats, also graduated from Iowa State. In addition to Mildred, former CEOs of Boeing, Dow Corning, 3-M, and Lockheed Martin have all claimed Iowa State University as their alma mater, as do I.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I attended ISU on a Naval ROTC scholarship. The program covered my books and tuition, as well as $50 a month to cover extra expenses. I was well taken care of at ISU. With NROTC and a loan from the National Defense Scholarship Program, started under President Eisenhower, I was able to make it through college and flourish.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is my honor today to stand in support of my resolution honoring Iowa State for its long and storied history of graduating men and women who are creative, productive, and innovative. As the ISU fight song goes, "Loyal sons forever true, and we will fight the battle through. And when we hit that line we'll hit it hard ev'ry yard for I.S.U."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today I support this resolution to honor the service and leadership of Iowa State University. I am cosponsoring this resolution because I know firsthand the substantial contributions that Iowa State has made to both Iowa and the Nation as a whole. In fact, as one of the first land-grant universities, it has led the way in technology advancement and outreach.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Iowa State University will celebrate 150 years of service to the United States this month. The university is a leader in agricultural, engineering, and computer science technologies. They have been pioneers in the education of minorities and women. Because of these advancements, Iowa State University is recognized throughout the world as a standard for excellence in education, practical research, and outreach through extension.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Iowa State is a great representative for the people of our State and will continue to leave an important legacy for our Nation. It is with great respect that I introduce this resolution in honor of Iowa State University's 150th year anniversary.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table, with no intervening action or debate, and that any statements relating to the resolution be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="475">S. Res. 475</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="475">S. Res. 475</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas Iowa State University of Science and Technology was established by the Iowa General Assembly on March 22, 1858, as the Iowa Agricultural College and Model Farm in response to the State of Iowa's desire to provide higher education opportunities to farm families and working classes in Iowa, predating the passage of the Federal Morrill Act by 4 years;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas on September 3, 1862, Iowa became the first State in the Nation to accept the terms and conditions of the Morrill Act creating the land-grant system of colleges and universities;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Iowa Agricultural College and Model Farm, known today as Iowa State University of Science and Technology (Iowa State), received Iowa's land-grant charter on March 29, 1864, making it one of the first land-grant institutions in the Nation;</chair>
  <chair>Whereas Iowa State was a pioneer in all 3 parts of the land-grant mission, including--(1) access to all, regardless of race, gender or social class, being the first land-grant institution to be coeducational from its opening, with 16 women in its first class and later students including future suffragist Carrie Chapman Catt, an 1880 graduate, and George Washington Carver, the first African American student, who earned a bachelor's degree in 1894 and a master's degree in 1896, and was also the  institution's first African American faculty member; (2) practical research, establishing the Nation's first Engineering Experiment Station and domestic economy experimental kitchen, and one of the first agriculture experiment stations; and (3) outreach, including some of the earliest land-grant</chair>
  <chair> (2) thanks the State of Iowa for its visionary leadership in the beginning of the land-grant movement in the United States of America.  &lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
