<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1212422402" ordinal="13" title="ORDER OF PROCEDURE">
  <narrative>ORDER OF PROCEDURE -- (Senate - June 02, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="4866">S4866</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300055" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, it is my understanding that the junior Senator from California is going to want to yield back the morning business time, I suppose, and get on with the bill; is that correct?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the remaining morning business time be yielded back, and under the previous order, the Chair will report the motion to proceed to <bill type="s" number="3036">S. 3036</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300055" topic="">
    <paragraph>Will the Senator yield for a question?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="">
    <paragraph>Sure.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300055" topic="">
    <paragraph>I assume the Senator has an opening statement to make, and I do, too, on this legislation we are going to be going to. If you have an opening statement, Senator Specter would like to follow you and I would follow him. Is that an order that would be acceptable to the Senator?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="">
    <paragraph>I have to check because I have a number of Democratic Senators who wish to partake if we go to this. How much time will we have on this?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The time until 5:30 will be equally divided.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="">
    <paragraph>If the Senators could put a time certain on it, and I will be happy to put a time certain on my time?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300092" topic="">
    <paragraph>Five minutes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="">
    <paragraph>Five minutes? Great.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300055" topic="">
    <paragraph>Twenty-five minutes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="">
    <paragraph>I would have 25 minutes, to be followed by Senator Specter for 5, then followed by Senator Inhofe for 25, to be followed by Senator Lieberman for 20.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I make that as a unanimous consent request.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection? Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
