<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1222444802" ordinal="20" title="UNANIMOUS CONSENT AGREEMENT--S. 3604">
  <narrative>UNANIMOUS CONSENT AGREEMENT--S. 3604 -- (Senate - September 26, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="9574">S9574</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent the motion to proceed to <bill type="s" number="3297">S. 3297</bill> be set aside and that it be in order for the majority leader to move to proceed to a bill relating to the stimulus initiative that was introduced earlier today and that is at the desk; that the motion be considered as having been made, there be debate by Senator Allard for up to 3 minutes, and that there be an opportunity for Senator DeMint to offer a unanimous consent request, and that upon completion  of that time the Senate proceed to vote on the motion to proceed and the motion be subject to an affirmative 60-vote threshold; that if the motion receives 60 affirmative votes, then it be as if cloture had been invoked on the motion and postcloture time would be in effect; that if the motion does not receive an affirmative 60-vote threshold, then it be withdrawn, and the motion to proceed to <bill type="s" number="3297">S. 3297</bill> recur, with the above occurring with no intervening action or debate.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="">
    <paragraph>Reserving the right to object, I understand the majority leader has added into this so-called stimulus package an extension of the ban on oil shale development. I ask consent that his request be modified to include an amendment, which is at the desk, that would authorize and expedite offshore and oil shale exploration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I say to my good friend, you should quit while you are ahead. I object.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <chair>Is there an objection to the majority leader's request?</chair>
  <chair>Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
