<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1210176002" ordinal="7" title="SCHEDULE">
  <narrative>SCHEDULE -- (Senate - May 07, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="3839">S3839</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412246" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today there will be a period of morning business for up to 1 hour, with the time equally divided and controlled between the two leaders or their designees, with the majority controlling the first half and the Republicans will control the final half.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Following morning business, the Senate will resume consideration of the motion to proceed to <bill type="s" number="2284">S. 2284</bill>, a bill to restore the financial solvency of the National Flood Insurance Fund.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a reminder, the Senate will recess from 12:30 until 2:15 today for the weekly caucus luncheons.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask for a couple moments of personal privilege.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Monsignor Joseph Quinn offered our prayer. I wish to say how proud I am to be here this morning to witness that. He is a very dear friend and someone who has, for many years, ministered to my family and to families throughout northeastern Pennsylvania in good times and bad.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are grateful for his presence today. We are grateful he was able to offer the prayer. I will submit for the Record a fuller statement of some background material on his life. But he has been so much a part of the fabric of northeastern Pennsylvania.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>He has often said that in large families, the joys are multiplied and sorrows are divided. We are grateful for his leadership as a priest, and now as a monsignor, but in a very personal way, for what he has meant to so many families in northeastern Pennsylvania. I am honored to be here to share a couple minutes with him and am grateful for his presence today in the Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Washington State.</chair>
</record>
