<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1193241604" ordinal="48" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <narrative>AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET -- (Senate - October 24, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="13369">S13369</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="COMMITTEE ON AGRICULTURE, NUTRITION, AND FORESTRY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition and Forestry be authorized to meet in executive session during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, October 24, 2007, at 10 a.m. in SR-328A. The committee will be considering the 2007 farm bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="COMMITTEE ON BANKING, HOUSING, AND URBAN AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on October 24, 2007, at 2 p.m., in order to conduct a hearing entitled "International Accounting Standards: Opportunities, Challenges, and Global Convergence Issues."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, Transportation be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, October 24, 2007, at 10 a.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At this hearing, committee members will assess the state of innovation and competition in the radio market.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, October 24, 2007, at 9:30 a.m., in order to hold a hearing on the Great Lakes region of Africa.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, October 24, 2007, at 1:45 p.m., in order to hold a business meeting.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="COMMITTEE ON HOMELAND SECURITY AND GOVERNMENTAL AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, October 24, 2007, at 10 a.m., in order  to conduct a hearing entitled "Watching the Watch List: Building an Effective Terrorist Screening System."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet, during the session of the Senate, in order to conduct a hearing entitled "Nominations" on Wednesday, October 24, 2007. The meeting will commence at 10 a.m. in room 226 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Panel I: Ronald Jay Tenpas to be Assistant Attorney General for the Environment and Natural Resources Division, Department of Justice.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Panel II: Joseph N. Laplante to be United States District Judge for the District of New Hampshire; Reed Charles O'Connor to be United States District Judge for the Northern District of Texas, Dallas Division; Thomas D. Schroeder to be United States District Judge for the Middle District of North Carolina; Amul R. Thapar to be United States District Judge for the Eastern District of Kentucky.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet, during the session of the Senate, in order to conduct a hearing entitled "The Role of Federally-Funded University Research in the Patent System" on Wednesday, October 24, 2007. The meeting will commence at 1:30 p.m. in room 226 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Arti K. Rai, Professor of Law, Duke University School of Law, Durham, NC; Elizabeth Hoffman, Executive Vice President and Provost, Iowa State University, Ames, IA; Robert Weissman, Director, Essential Action, Washington, DC; Dr. Charles Louis, Vice Chancellor for Research, University of California, Riverside, Riverside, CA.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="COMMITTEE ON VETERANS' AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent for the Committee on Veterans' Affairs to be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, October 24, 2007, in order to conduct a hearing on pending legislation. The committee will meet in room 562 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building, at 9:30 a.m.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="SPECIAL COMMITTEE ON AGING">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Special Committee on Aging be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, October 24, 2007, from 10:30 a.m.-12:30 p.m. in room 628 of the Dirkson Senate Office Building for the purpose of conducting a hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON PRIVATE SECTOR AND CONSUMER SOLUTIONS TO GLOBAL WARMING AND WILDLIFE PROTECTION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Environment and Public Works, Subcommittee on Private Sector and Consumer Solutions to Global Warming and Wildlife Protection, be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, October 24, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. in room 406 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building in order to hold a hearing entitled, "A hearing to examine America's Climate Security Act of 2007.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
