<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1202749203" ordinal="22" title="TRIBUTE TO REVEREND WEBSTER TWO HAWK">
  <narrative>TRIBUTE TO REVEREND WEBSTER TWO HAWK -- (Senate - February 11, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="847">S847</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300058" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, it is my pleasure to speak today to recognize an outstanding lifelong resident of South Dakota, Rev. Webster Two Hawk.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Recently, Reverend Two Hawk marked 50 years of service to his church and his faith. His congregation is the St. Peter's Episcopal Church in Fort Pierre, SD, where he has been a volunteer priest for the last 27 years. Reverend Two Hawk, now retired, has a long list of accomplishments throughout his lifetime.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Reverend Two Hawk was born and lived near White River, SD, until going to schools in Todd County. Upon completion of high school in Mission, SD, now Todd County High School, he attended the University of South Dakota, my alma mater, where he graduated in 1952 with a degree in business administration. Upon leaving college, Two Hawk enlisted in the U.S. Army to serve in the Korean war. Upon his return from service, he attended Kenyon College in Ohio where he graduated  with  a master's degree in divinity and was ordained at St. Peter's Church in Lake Andes on the Yankton Sioux Reservation. He served there 6 years as priest before moving to the Standing Rock Sioux Reservation for another 6 years and ultimately returning home to the Rosebud Sioux Reservation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>His return home led him down a different path of service he was elected chairman of the Rosebud Sioux Tribe. He had many accomplishments during his tenure as leader of the tribe; most notably was the opening of Sinte Gleska University in 1971. His desire to serve also led him to work for the Aberdeen Area Indian Health Service and was also appointed by former Gov Bill Janklow as the commissioner for the South Dakota Tribal Government Relations Office from 1996 until 2003. As well, he serves on  the board of directors for the Wakpa Sica Reconciliation Place.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Currently, Reverend Two Hawk is working to rebuild the congregation in his hometown of White River, SD. I take this opportunity to commend Rev. Webster Two Hawk for his lifetime of service to his congregation and to his tribe. Both are certainly thankful for his efforts.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
