<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1179871463" ordinal="43" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="AIRLAND SUBCOMMITTEE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Airland Subcommittee of the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, May 22, 2007 at 12:30 p.m. in closed session to mark up the airland programs and provisions contained in the National Defense Authorization Act for fiscal year 2008.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, May 22, 2007, at 10 a.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building. The purpose of the hearing is to discuss reauthorization of the Federal rail safety program.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND NATURAL RESOURCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, May 22, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. in  room 366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building in Washington, DC.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the hearing is to receive testimony on <bill type="s" number="645">S. 645</bill>, a bill to amend the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to provide an alternate sulfur dioxide removal measurement for certain coal gasification project goals; <bill type="s" number="838">S. 838</bill>, a bill to authorize funding joint ventures between United States and Israeli businesses and academic persons; <bill type="s" number="1089">S. 1089</bill>, a bill to amend the Alaska Natural Gas Pipeline Act to follow the Federal Coordinator for Alaska Natural Gas Transportation projects to hire employees more efficiently,  and for other purposes; <bill type="s" number="1203">S. 1203</bill>, a bill to enhance the management of electricity programs at the Department of Energy; <bill type="h" number="85">H.R. 85</bill>, a bill to provide for the establishment of centers to encourage demonstration and commercial application of advanced energy methods and technologies; and <bill type="h" number="1126">H.R. 1126</bill>, a bill to reauthorize the Steel and Aluminum Energy Conservation and Technology Competitiveness Act of 1988.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENVIRONMENT AND PUBLIC WORKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Environment and Public Works be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, May 22, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. in room 406 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building for a hearing entitled "Examining the Case for the California Waiver."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, May 22, 2007, at 10 a.m. to hold a nomination hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="COMMITTEE ON HOMELAND SECURITY AND GOVERNMENTAL AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs be authorized to meet on Tuesday, May 22, 2007, at 3 p.m. for a hearing titled "Implementing FEMA Reform: Are We Prepared for the 2007 Hurricane Season?"</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet to conduct a hearing on "Restoring Habeas Corpus: Protecting American Values and the Great Writ" for Tuesday, May 22, 2007, at 10 a.m. in Dirksen Senate Office Building room 226.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Witness list: RADM Donald Guter, USN (ret.), Dean, Duquesne University School of Law, Pittsburgh, PA; William Howard Taft IV, Of Counsel Fried, Frank, Harris, Shriver &amp; Jacobson LLP, Washington, DC; Mariano-Florentino Cuellar, Professor, Stanford Law School, Stanford, CA; David B. Rivkin, Jr., Partner, Baker &amp; Hostetler LLP, Washington, DC; and Orin Kerr, Professor, George Washington University Law School, Washington, DC.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="COMMITTEE ON SMALL BUSINESS AND ENTREPRENEURSHIP">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate for a hearing entitled "Minority Entrepreneurship: Assessing the Effectiveness of SBA's Programs for the Minority Business Community," on Tuesday, May 22, 2007, beginning at 10 a.m. in room 428A of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="COMMITTEE ON VETERANS' AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Veterans' Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, May 22, 2007, after the first rollcall vote of the day in the reception room adjacent to the Floor, to conduct a vote on the nomination of Dr. Michael J. Kussman to be Under Secretary for Health at the Department of Veterans Affairs.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="EMERGING THREATS AND CAPABILITIES SUBCOMMITTEE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Emerging Threats and Capabilities Subcommittee of the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, May 22, 2007 at 5:30 p.m. in closed session to mark up the Emerging Threats and Capabilities Programs and Provisions contained in the National Defense Authorization Act for fiscal year 2008.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="PERSONNEL SUBCOMMITTEE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Personnel Subcommittee of the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, May 22, 2007 at 10 a.m. in closed session to mark up the Personnel Programs and Provisions contained in the National Defense Authorization Act for fiscal year 2008.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="READINESS AND MANAGEMENT SUPPORT SUBCOMMITTEE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Readiness and Management Support Subcommittee of the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, May 22, 2007 at 4 p.m. in closed session to mark up the Readiness and Management Support Programs and Provisions contained in the National Defense Authorization Act for fiscal year 2008.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.  seapower subcommittee</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="READINESS AND MANAGEMENT SUPPORT SUBCOMMITTEE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Seapower Subcommittee of the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, May 22, 2007 at 9 a.m. in closed session to mark up the Seapower Programs and Provisions contained in the National Defense Authorization Act for fiscal year 2008.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON EMPLOYMENT AND WORKPLACE SAFETY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions, Subcommittee on Employment and Workplace Safety, be authorized to hold a hearing on the MINER Act during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, May 22, 2007 at 10 a.m. in room 628 of the Senate Dirksen office building.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON OVERSIGHT OF GOVERNMENT MANAGEMENT, THE FEDERAL WORKFORCE, AND THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs' Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia be authorized to meet on Tuesday, May 22, 2007, at 10 a.m. to conduct a joint hearing entitled "GAO Personnel Reform: Does it meet expectations?"</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The joint hearing will take place in conjunction with the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and the House Subcommittee of Federal Workforce, Postal Service, and the District of Columbia.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
