<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1203094801" ordinal="3" title="NATIONAL DRUG PREVENTION AND EDUCATION WEEK">
  <narrative>NATIONAL DRUG PREVENTION AND EDUCATION WEEK -- (Senate - February 15, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="1087">S1087</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300058" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I speak today in recognition of National Drug Prevention and Education Week. One of the most serious issues facing our youth in rural America and throughout the United States is drug use and abuse. Drug abuse and addiction is a problem that never seems to go away and prevention and education are two of the most important steps that we can take to ensure the welfare of our next generation while preserving our current generation. As a nation, we cannot sit idly by  and watch the trend of substance abuse grow.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We, as a community, must continue fighting the challenges imposed by drugs on our communities. We have to face the fact that cocaine, marijuana, and heroin remain a constant threat. We cannot ignore the rapidly increasing use of meth or the abuse of prescription drugs in our rural communities across South Dakota and throughout the Nation. I will continue to seek funding for organizations and programs like South Dakota's Glory House Methamphetamine Addiction Treatment Center and Martin Addiction  Recovery Center to help those addicted to drugs and alcohol. We cannot afford to let these and other programs disappear from lack of funding. As we all know, the devastating effects of drug addition do not just affect those who are addicted, but everyone</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Education and prevention are the first steps in this fight against substance abuse. For that reason, the Senate passed <bill type="sr" number="434">S. Res. 434</bill>, a resolution designating this week as National Drug Prevention and Education Week. We urge local communities, schools, friends, youths and parents to carry out drug education and drug prevention activities not only throughout this designated week, but throughout the year so we can continue to beat back the horrible tide of drug use and abuse to preserve the health  of our Nation for years to come.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
