<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1174924955" ordinal="36" title="STATEMENTS ON INTRODUCED BILLS AND JOINT RESOLUTIONS">
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="Introducing S. 986. A bill to expand eligibility for Combat-Related Special Compensation paid by the uniformed services in order to permit certain additional retired members who have a service-connected disability to receive both disability compensation from the Department of Veterans Affairs for that disability and Combat-Related Special Compensation by reason of that disability; to the Committee on Armed Services.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="986">S. 986</bill>] Mr. President, before I introduce my legislation, The Combat Related Special Compensation Act of 2007, I would like to briefly talk about the unfair treatment and the deplorable health care conditions found at the Walter Reed Army Medical Center. I feel that the current situation there has some bearing on my legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Walter Reed is one of the Army's best-known and premier medical facilities for wounded service members in the country. Numerous reports by the Government Accounting Office and transcripts of congressional testimony  indicate that many of our military facilities for wounded outpatients are in disarray. These facilities are plagued by mold, mice, stained carpets, and a system ill equipped to handle another generation of psychologically scarred veterans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nearly 4,000 outpatients are currently in the military's Medical Holding companies, which oversee the wounded. Soldiers and veterans across the country report bureaucratic neglect similar to Walter Reed's: untrained staff; misplaced paperwork; lost computer generated medical appointments; and long waits for consultations. These serious problems have resulted from bureaucratic red tape and substandard health care conditions. This situation is unacceptable. We have not fulfilled our covenant, nor  have we kept our promise to take care of our troops.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our dedicated service members took an oath to serve our Nation. We as policy makers have a moral obligation to take care of these dedicated service men and women that have shown heroic patriotism in Afghanistan and Iraq.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>"As described in the Washington Post", It is not just a problem at Walter Reed: others describe depressing living conditions for outpatients at military bases throughout the country. Let me share with you the comments of a 70-year-old soldier, Mr. Oliva, who is worried about the military health care our wounded will receive. He described his own troubling experiences at the VA hospital in Livermore, CA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>"It is not just Walter Reed," Mr. Oliva states. "The VA hospitals are not good either except for the staff members who work so hard. It brings tears to my eyes when I see my brothers and sisters having to deal with these conditions."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. Oliva is but one voice in a vast outpouring of emotion and anger about the treatment of wounded outpatients at Walter Reed. Stories of neglect and substandard care have flooded in from soldiers, their family members, veterans, doctors and nurses working inside the system. This is appalling and an embarrassment to our Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am particularly concerned that some of the highest ranking officials were aware of the problem for almost two years, but took no action to correct the situation. While we have  seen some positive signs from the fallout over the scandal, such as the firing of the head of Walter Reed and the establishment of a bipartisan commission, more must be done.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our soldiers receive first class care in combat, and they should receive the same level of care in our own country. Congress must lead the way in this effort. We must continue our efforts and pass legislation that will improve the quality of life for all of America's heroes, including providing them with the benefits they have earned.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, I join with many of my Senate colleagues to fight and end the ban on current receipt so that disabled veterans can get the fair benefits they deserve. We have made some progress over the last few years, but as everyone knows, we still have a lot of work to do.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation I am introducing today--the Combat-Related Special Compensation Act of 2007, would continue to chip away at this unfair policy, by giving pro-rated retirement benefits to our service men and women who are forced into early retirement because of their combat-related injuries.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our veterans on a day-to-day basis sacrifice their life for our country. As public servants, we Americans owe it to our dedicated service men and women to end this inequity. We must support our troops; we must ensure that those who serve us with dignity and valor receive these deserving benefits. They have earned it and they deserve it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My legislation will take care of soldiers who had hoped to make the military a career, but were discharged prematurely for an injury sustained in combat and forced to retire medically before attaining 20 years of service.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Like many of you, I have visited military hospitals on several occasions and have seen first hand the injuries sustained by our military personnel. Many of the members have reached the 10-, 12-, 14-year marks of their military careers and have been forced to retire medically before they meet the 20-year requirement to receive full benefits. Right now, these soldiers receive combat-related disability benefits, but are not eligible to receive retirement benefits because they cannot fulfill the  20-year service requirement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a travesty to treat our dedicated service men and women inequitably. It's wrong.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We should not penalize veterans because they incurred a combat-related injury while serving their country. This legislation will ensure they will receive both their prorated military retirement pay, along with their disability compensation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me point out that this legislation is especially important given the injuries sustained by these troops that are currently serving in Afghanistan, Iraq, and other theaters throughout the world. This legislation is essential for the more than 23,000 injured personnel who are returning from war. The widespread use of improvised explosive devices (IED) has created numerous amputees and therefore, result in an increase in medically discharged veterans. As described in stories reported by the  Washington Post, a 25-year-old soldier got to close to an IED in Iraq and was sent to Walter Reed, where doctors did all they could before shipping the soldier to the VA for the remainder of his life. Will this young soldier be one of the victims of war that do not receive disability compensation and military retirement pay?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, ensuring our veterans receive retirement benefits they have earned is the right thing to do, especially in light of recent issues surrounding the treatment of patients at Walter Reed. We must never forget the sacrifices our service men and women have made to protect our freedom. They serve because they love this great country. Taking care of our veterans is not only the right thing to do; it is also important for our efforts to win the war on terror. In our all-volunteer military,  it is critical to attract and retain professional and dedicated soldiers. In turn, they expect that we will honor our commitments to provide health care and other primary benefits for them and their families.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By ending this unfair policy, we now have an opportunity to show our gratitude to our veterans. If we are to truly honor the sacrifices of our veterans, we need to ensure that those who were injured in defense of our Nation receive these well deserved benefits.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While our Nation is at war, there is no better honor we could bestow upon them than to pass this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the text of this legislation be printed in the Record. </paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking-unknown-id title="Mr." name="MENDENEZ" of="">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="987">S. 987</bill>] Mr. President, today, all across America, organized criminal gangs plague our communities, destroying the lives of thousands of young children and adults each and every year. Unfortunately, this plague is currently not being treated effectively, and as a result has grown in size and power in almost every State in the Nation. In order to effectively counter this growing threat, we cannot continue to believe it is only a State and local issue that predominantly occurs in highly urbanized  areas. Instead, we must recognize that it has escalated into a national issue--reaching small rural towns, suburban areas, and big cities alike--and affecting our country as a whole.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In light of this, it is clear that we must recalibrate our efforts and--in addition to our local initiatives--comprehensively confront gang violence at the national level. That is why I rise today, along with my colleague, Senator Lautenberg, to introduce the Fighting Gangs and Empowering Youth Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Combining the efforts of Federal, State, and local agencies, this legislation would utilize a multi-pronged approach in order to comprehensively deal with all aspects of gang violence. From rigorously enforcing and appropriately sentencing criminal acts, to exposing and eliminating the root causes of gang pervasiveness, this bill would simultaneously deter gang violence while proactively targeting the sources that have led to its expanding prevalence.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Like most of the problems we face as a society, gang violence can most effectively be handled by addressing its root causes. In order to grow in size and power, gangs need a large, self-replenishing pool of recruits to draw upon. They prey on areas that suffer from high dropout rates, crippling poverty, and rampant unemployment--areas where hope is often in short supply. All  too often children who live in these areas are caught in a tragic web of gang  violence simply because they can envision no other alternative.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is in these circumstances, where a 15-year-old child sees life in a gang as not just their best option, but often their only option--that gang membership thrives. It is in these circumstances, where children do not anticipate living to celebrate their 30th birthday--that gangs flourish. Not only does this environment destroy the life of the individual recruited--it also serves to strengthen the gang, further reinforcing a vicious cycle.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thus, any effort undertaken to combat gang violence must address the environment that transforms promising, young adolescents into ruthless tools of a criminal enterprise. While we will probably never be able to completely eliminate all acts of violence from our society, there is much we can do to instill in our children the skills they need to pursue a law abiding life. To this end, my legislation would authorize funds for afterschool and community-based programs designed to economically empower  young people. Disadvantaged students will be given the opportunity to realize their potential, through tutoring, mentoring, and job training programs as well as college preparation classes and tuition assistance. Additionally, millions of dollars would be authorized to enhance and expand anti-gang and anti-violence programs</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill would also attack one of the roots of gang violence--gang recruiters, who seek out young, economically disadvantaged, at-risk youth and pressure them to join. Currently, there is no Federal law specifically forbidding gang recruitment. This legislation would change that--making it illegal for a gang member to solicit or recruit others into a gang--and would incarcerate an offender for up to 10 years if the person being recruited was 18 or older, or up to 20 years if the individual was  under the age of 18. This provision would effectively target the kingpins of gangs, who cowardly order younger members to do their violent bidding, callously sacrificing their lives like pawns on a chessboard.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For those who have made wrong choices in life, but are still capable of rehabilitation, this bill would expand adult and juvenile offender reentry demonstration projects to help with post-release and transitional housing, while promoting programs that hire former prisoners, and establish reentry planning procedures within communities. To be eligible for early release, prisoners with drug addictions would be required to participate in treatment programs both while they are imprisoned as well as  during their transition period back into society. All offenders would be encouraged to participate in educational initiatives such as job training, GED preparation, and a myriad of other programs designed to provide offenders with the skills necessary to become legally employed when they are released from prison. By providing such individuals with an alternative choice to a life of crime, lives can be transformed and recidivism rates amongst ex-convicts will be reduced.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to programs focused on gang violence prevention, we must provide law enforcement officials at every level of government with all of the tools and resources necessary for them to safely and effectively protect and serve their communities. All too often these heroic officers are caught in the crossfire of gang violence, and all too often they make the ultimate sacrifice so that others may live.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One tragic example involves the late Detective Kiernan Shields from East Orange, New Jersey. Detective Shields was a rising star in the East Orange Police Department, living his lifelong dream of serving his community as an officer of the peace. He was a devoted, loving husband and proud father of three children, who was remembered by his peers and colleagues not just as a multi-talented person with a great sense of humor, but as the epitome of a role model in an area that desperately needed  one. Unfortunately, New Jersey lost one of its bravest and finest sons on the evening of August 7, 2006, when Detective Shields was ruthlessly shot-gunned to death by a reputed member of the Bloods</paragraph>
    <paragraph>gang, as he valiantly ran toward the sound of echoing gunfire--Ran toward the gunfire.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This single act of heroism is consistent with the way police officers across this Nation live their daily lives. These are the people who are fighting day in and day out to keep our communities safe. The best way to honor the victims of gang violence and those who are still fighting it is to fully commit ourselves to eradicating this cancer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To assist our frontline warriors in their daily struggle against gang violence, my proposal would provide law enforcement officials on every level of government with the resources and information they need to accurately track and effectively neutralize criminal gangs. Specifically, this legislation would establish a program similar to the current Community Oriented Policing Services (COPS) program to augment the number of police officers combating gangs in our local communities, and would authorize</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As is true with almost all problems, a better understanding of how gangs operate translates into a better understanding of how best to counter them. That is why this bill would authorize additional funding for the National Youth Gang Survey to increase the number of law enforcement agencies whose data is collected and included in the annual survey and provide money to upgrade technology to better identify gang members and include them in the National Gang Database. Additionally, this legislation  would expand the Uniform Crime Reports (UCRs) to include local gang and other crime statistics from the municipal level, while also requiring the Attorney General to distinguish those crimes committed by juveniles. The bill also requires consolidation and standardization of criminal databases, enabling law enforcement all across the country to better share information.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For those who still choose a life of crime, this proposal would increase the penalties for crimes committed in the furtherance of a gang. Gangs are dependent on committing crimes such as witness intimidation, illegal firearm possession, and drug trafficking--implementing these violent instruments to augment their power. Subsequently, when these crimes are committed in the furtherance of gang activity, they can be more detrimental to society than if they were committed in isolation. Thus, these  tougher sentencing requirements for crimes committed in the furtherance of a gang are not only appropriate, but necessary to deter gang violence and shield society from its most dangerous and unremorseful criminals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Taken together, the provisions of this bill develop a comprehensive approach to gang violence by focusing on prevention, deterrence, and enforcement. Failure to address all of these gang violence catalysts in their entirety would leave us with an incomprehensive approach that would do little to quell the scourge of gang violence. Therefore, I urge my colleagues to support the Fighting Gangs and Empowering Youth Act, and by doing so, give law enforcement and our communities the means to thoroughly  and comprehensively counter the growing specter of gang violence that afflicts our great Nation.</paragraph>
  </speaking-unknown-id>
</record>
