<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1192809602" ordinal="31" title="EXECUTIVE SESSION">
  <narrative>EXECUTIVE SESSION -- (Senate - October 19, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="13167">S13167</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="PROTOCOL TO TREATY OF FRIENDSHIP, COMMERCE, AND NAVIGATION WITH DENMARK">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to executive session to consider Executive Calendar No. 1, the Protocol Treaty of Friendship Commerce, and Navigation with Denmark; that the protocol be advanced through its various parliamentary stages up to and including the presentation of ratification, and that there now be a division vote on the resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>A division has been requested.</chair>
  <chair>Senators in favor of the resolution of ratification will rise and stand until counted.</chair>
  <chair>Those opposed will rise and stand until counted.</chair>
  <chair>On a division, two-thirds of the Senators present having voted in the affirmative, the resolution of ratification is agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution of ratification agreed to is as follows:</chair>
  <chair>Resolution of Advice and Consent to Ratification</chair>
  <chair>Resolved (two-thirds of the Senators present concurring therein), the Senate advises and consents to the ratification of the Protocol between the United States of America and the Kingdom of Denmark to the Treaty of Friendship, Commerce and Navigation of October 1, 1951, signed at Copenhagen on May 2, 2001 (Treaty Doc. 108-8).</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="PROTOCOL TO TREATY OF FRIENDSHIP, COMMERCE, AND NAVIGATION WITH DENMARK">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the motion to reconsider be laid on the table, the President be immediately notified of the Senate's action, and the Senate now return to legislative session.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
