<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1215446403" ordinal="24" title="TRIBUTE TO MAJOR GENERAL MELISSA A. RANK">
  <narrative>TRIBUTE TO MAJOR GENERAL MELISSA A. RANK -- (Senate - July 07, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="6359">S6359</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300073" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I join Senator Inouye in recognizing a great American and true military heroine who has honorably served our country for 30 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Major General Rank was born in Frostburg, MD, and entered the Air Force Nurse Corps in 1978. She earned her BSN from the University of Maryland at Baltimore in 1975, and worked for Baltimore City Hospitals, Johns Hopkins Medical Institutions, and Center for Disease Control prior to entering the Air Force. She also completed a master's in nursing administration from University of Texas in 1990, and a master's in strategic studies from Air War College in Alabama in 1999.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Major General Rank's military education includes the Air War College; the Air Command and Staff College, Squadron Officer School, Flight Nurse School, and Nursing Service Management.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Major General Rank became the Assistant Air Force Surgeon General for Medical Force Development and Assistant Air Force Surgeon General, Nursing Services in 2005. She established policy for 34,000 active-duty and enlisted medical personnel. She also created nursing policy for 19,000 active-duty, Guard, and Reserve personnel.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Major General Rank's past military assignments include serving in the Office of the Surgeon General as executive management fellow for services, chief of plans, policies and programs for nursing services in the directorate of work force management, and deputy assistant surgeon general for health care operations. She also served as United States Air Force Surgeon Chair to Air University and has commanded an aeromedical evacuation squadron in Southwest Asia and a medical operations squadron and  two medical groups.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Throughout her career Major General Rank has served with valor and profoundly impacted the entire Air Force Medical Department. Her performance reflects exceptionally on herself, the United States Air Force, the Department of Defense, and the United States of America. We extend our deepest appreciation to Major General Rank on behalf of a grateful nation for her more than 30 years of dedicated military service.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
