<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1178208007" ordinal="23" title="STATEMENTS ON INTRODUCED BILLS AND JOINT RESOLUTIONS">
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="Introducing S. 1276. A bill to establish a grant program to facilitate the creation of methamphetamine precursor electronic logbook systems, and for other purposes; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1276">S. 1276</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to introduce the bipartisan Methamphetamine Production Prevention Act of 2007. I am pleased to have the support and cosponsorship of Senator Grassley for this important legislation, and I look forward to working closely with Chairman Leahy and Ranking Member Specter to advance the bill through the judiciary Committee and to secure its enactment into law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Methamphetamine Production Prevention Act will take the next step toward wiping out the domestic production of methamphetamine, or "meth." The bill will make it easier to use electronic logbook systems in order to monitor sales of meth precursor drugs and notify enforcement agencies when individuals illegally stockpile these precursors by traveling from pharmacy to pharmacy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation is endorsed by the National Alliance of State Drug Enforcement Agencies, the National Narcotics Officers' Associations' Coalition, the National Criminal Justice Association, the National Sheriffs' Association, the Major County Sheriffs' Association, the National Troopers Coalition, the National District Attorneys Association, the National Association of Counties, and the Community Anti-Drug Coalitions of America. I also want to commend and thank Illinois Attorney General Lisa  Madigan and her staff for their assistance in preparing this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For years, the manufacture and use of methamphetamine have plagued communities in Illinois and throughout the Nation. Meth is unique among illegal drugs in that its harms stem not only from its distribution and use, but also from the clandestine manufacturing labs that meth "cooks" use to make meth. These labs pose serious dangers to those who live nearby and to the surrounding environment. Law enforcement agencies in Illinois and elsewhere are forced to devote a significant percentage of their  time to locating, busting, and cleaning up meth labs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Combat Methamphetamine Epidemic Act, "Combat Meth Act," enacted in 2006, took several important steps to reduce domestic meth manufacturing. These steps included limiting the amount of meth precursor drug products that a purchaser can buy, such as pseudoephedrine, and requiring pharmacies to keep written or electronic logbooks recording each precursor purchase. The Combat Meth Act has led to a drop in the number of meth labs discovered in many States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, domestic meth cooks have begun adapting to the Combat Meth Act. They have figured out how to circumvent the act's restrictions by "smurfing," or purchasing illegal amounts of meth precursor drugs by traveling to multiple pharmacies that keep written logbooks and buying legal quantities at each one. According to Illinois law enforcement authorities, smurfing now accounts for at least 90 percent of the pseudoephedrine used to make meth in Illinois.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The next step in combating domestic meth production is to promote the use of effective electronic logbook systems. Law enforcement experts agree that if pharmacies maintain electronic logbook information and share that information with appropriate law enforcement and regulatory agencies, this information can be used to prevent the sale of meth precursor drugs in excess of legal limits, and to identify and prosecute "smurfs" and meth cooks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation, the Methamphetamine Production Prevention Act, facilitates and encourages the use of meth precursor electronic logbook systems in several ways.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, the bill revises the technical logbook requirements in the Combat Meth Act. While the Combat Meth Act provides for the use of electronic logbook systems, several of the act's requirements are not tailored for logbooks kept in electronic form. For example, under the act, a prospective purchaser must "enter[] into the logbook his or her name, address, and the date and time of the sale." This requirement is unwieldy for retailers who use electronic logbook systems, because many purchasers  cannot type quickly or accurately. The Methamphetamine Production Prevention Act would permit retailers' employees to type the name and address of a purchaser into an electronic logbook system, and would allow retailers to use software programs that automatically record the date and time of each sale. Under the bill, a retail employee would have to ensure that the name the employee types into the system matches the name on the ID that the purchaser is currently required to present.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Also, the Combat Meth Act requires purchasers to sign a logbook at the time of sale, regardless of whether the seller uses a paper or electronic logbook. Collecting and retaining electronic signatures requires a large amount of computer memory, and the transmission of these electronic signature files to law enforcement agencies does not provide a significant law enforcement benefit. Sellers who use electronic logbook systems should be given the option of collecting signatures on paper, as long  as those signatures are stored for the requisite 2-year retention period, and as long as the signatures are clearly linked to the electronically-captured sale information.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Methamphetamine Production Prevention Act would permit a seller who uses an electronic logbook to collect purchaser signatures through any of three different methods: (1) having the purchaser sign an electronic signature device; (2) having the purchaser sigh a bound paper book in which the signature is placed adjacent to a unique identifier number, or a printed sticker that clearly links the signature to the purchaser's logbook information; or (3) having the purchaser sign a document that  the seller prints out at the time of sale that displays the required logbook information and contains a signature line. These options ensure that each purchaser's signature will be collected, but they give sellers flexibility in developing cost-effective electronic logbook systems.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Methamphetamine Production Prevention Act would also create a small but important Federal grant program to help States plan, create or enhance electronic logbook systems. Several States, including Oklahoma, Arkansas, West Virginia and Kentucky, have already begun developing electronic logbook systems, and many other States are  considering them. The Methamphetamine Production Prevention Act authorizes $3 million in grants  to States and localities, with grants capped at a maximum of $300,000. The bill imposes a 25-percent State matching requirement, to ensure that States have, invested in their logbook systems and have a stake in ensuring the successful operation of these systems.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Instead of mandating how States design their electronic logbook systems, the bill provides incentives for States to design effective logbook systems. Because meth smurfs frequently travel across State lines to stockpile meth precursors, State efforts to develop electronic logbook systems will be more successful if those efforts are coordinated with the activities of other states. The bill would therefore give priority to grant applicants whose logbook systems are developed in consultation with  a working group of key Federal, State and private stakeholders spearheaded by the National Alliance for Model State Drug Laws. This working group will advise States on best practices in developing logbook systems and will help States develop logbook systems that are compatible and interoperable with other systems across the country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also gives a grantmaking preference to applicants whose logbook systems are statewide, are capable of sharing information in real time, and are designed to share information across jurisdictional boundaries. At the same time, the bill preserves the privacy safeguards currently established under the Combat Meth Act and State law. To promote accountability, the bill requires the Attorney General to provide an annual report to Congress that evaluates the grant program and its effectiveness  in curtailing meth production.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Methamphetamine Production Prevention Act does not mandate the use of electronic logbook systems, nor does it mandate the features that an electronic logbook system must possess. The bill respects the fact that States have enacted various types of anti-meth restrictions above the Federal Combat Meth Act baseline, and that pharmacies and retailers in different States have different capabilities with regard to electronic tracking. At the same time, we want to encourage States to coordinate  their development of methamphetamine precursor electronic logbook systems so that smurfs will not be able to supply their meth labs by hopping across State lines. Our bill aims to strike a balance by coordinating the various State efforts, while still allowing States the flexibility to innovate and to respond to their specific State needs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are many actions besides promoting electronic logbook systems that we must take to address the scourge of methamphetamine. For example, we must provide for the prevention and treatment of meth use, and we must also prevent the illegal distribution of meth and its precursors over the Internet and from other countries. However, law enforcement experts agree that electronic logbook systems are an important tool in our effort to combat meth, particularly domestic meth labs. We can, and should,  do more to help make these logbook systems work.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>By facilitating and encouraging the use of electronic logbook systems, the Methamphetamine Production Prevention Act will help wipe out domestic meth labs and the environmental and social harms they cause. The bill will also help free up law enforcement resources from meth lab busts and cleanup, allowing our law enforcement agencies to focus on other crime prevention and enforcement efforts. The production of methamphetamine has plagued our communities for far too long, and this legislation takes  a critical step to stop it. I urge the Senate to pass this important bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="Introducing S. 1276. A bill to establish a grant program to facilitate the creation of methamphetamine precursor electronic logbook systems, and for other purposes; to the Committee on the Judiciary.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I am pleased to join my colleague, Senator DURBIN, in introducing the Methamphetamine Production Prevention Act of 2007. Together we offer this important legislation in an effort to strengthen existing law by providing some necessary changes and updates.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>During my time in the Senate, I have come to the floor many times to speak about methamphetamine and how it has destroyed individuals, families, and  communities across the country. The Midwest was hit especially hard by meth and the impacts of this drug were devastating to rural areas. As opposed to other illegal drugs, meth is often times home cooked and made in rural areas using ingredients that are largely available over the counter. I am proud to  say that Congress has taken action to attack this problem head on by working to cut off access to these over the counter products that form the basis of the drug.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Legislation such as the Combat Methamphetamine Act of 2005, Combat Meth Act of 2005, which was included into the USA Patriot Act Reauthorization in 2005 immediately impacted the production of home cooked meth. Just a week ago when I joined with Senator FEINSTEIN in introducing two other separate bills, the Saving Kids from Dangerous Drugs Act and the Drug Endangered Children Act, I noted that because of the efforts of Congress in passing the Combat Meth Act, the number of clandestine meth  lab seizures has dropped across the country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Combat Meth Act was a tremendous step in the right direction limiting access to psuedoephedrine, PSE, the main ingredient in methamphetamine. The Combat Meth Act required this product to be removed from store shelves and placed behind the counter at pharmacies across the country. It also limited the number of products containing PSE a person could buy at once. Further, it required a logbook system be kept by pharmacies containing information regarding the individuals that purchased products  containing PSE.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Despite these successes, ever determined meth cooks and users have learned how to game this system and continue to produce home grown meth.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The preferred method of these meth cooks is to "smurf" between different pharmacies for PSE products. Smurfing occurs when a person visits a number of different locations buying the legal maximum amount of PSE product at each site. The result is an amount of PSE sufficient to produce home cooked meth. Smurfing occurs because the Combat Meth Act only required that retailers keep a logbook which could be kept on paper or electronically. It did not require interoperability or electronic transmission  of data. As a result, these unscrupulous individuals have learned that if they provide false information or visit multiple stores, tracking and arresting these individuals is more difficult and time consuming for law enforcement. This is especially true in metropolitan communities that</paragraph>
    <paragraph>share a common border, one such example is the Quad Cities on the Iowa/Illinois border.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Recently, the Quad City Times highlighted the successes of the Combat Meth Act in an article titled, The Next Step in Meth War. This article detailed the efforts of a Scott County Deputy and his dedication in fighting the meth war. One noteworthy portion of this article raised a question about the lengths that were required for this deputy to do his job in combating mom and pop meth labs. The article stated, "Now we're stuck with this image of a detective in each Iowa county sorting through  thousands of paper forms." It read further, "He must call county to county to find out if those purchasing the limit in Scott County might be doing so elsewhere as well." This statement gets right to the heart of our bill. We can't effectively combat meth if we don't close the smurfing loophole.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To address this loophole, Senator DURBIN and I have introduced the Methamphetamine Production Prevention Act of 2007. This legislation would revise the technical requirements of the Combat Meth Act to allow for electronic logbook systems. The bill would also create a Federal grant program for states looking to create or enhance existing electronic logbook systems. Finally, this bill would prioritize these Federal grants to states that design and implement the most effective systems for  sharing information via an electronic logbook system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation will take a big step forward in closing this loophole that home grown meth cooks abuse. Additionally, it does so without creating burdensome mandates upon states to meet requirements. This bill facilitates innovation and growth by offering financial assistance to states looking to create an electronic logbook system. By avoiding mandates, this legislation seeks to promote innovation and growth of electronic logbook systems.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill has broad support from the law enforcement community and has been endorsed by the National Sheriffs' Association, the National Narcotics Officers' Associations' Coalition, National Alliance of State Drug Enforcement Agencies, the National Criminal Justice Association, the National Troopers Coalition, the National District Attorneys Association, the National Association of Counties, and the Community Anti-Drug Coalitions of America among others.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As you can see, this legislation has a broad base of support. Working together, state and local governments can use this legislation and grant program to create interoperable networks that will reduce the illegal smurfing of PSE products and lead us to the goal of ending domestic production of meth. I urge my colleagues, join us in support of this important legislation and pass the Methamphetamine Production Prevention Act of 2007 and help wipe out domestic production of meth.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the aforementioned article be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400064" topic="Introducing S. 1282. A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for the exclusion from gross income of certain wages of a certified master teacher, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1282">S. 1282</bill>] Mr. President, as you know, teachers are the most valuable resource when it comes to educating our Nation's children. Under the No Child Left Behind Act, (NCLB), States are required to recruit highly qualified teachers, yet schools in rural or high poverty areas have trouble attracting and retaining these teachers. It is for this reason that Senator Snowe and I have joined together to introduce The Master Teacher Act of 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have an education problem in America. The schools that most need  experienced educators simply do not have the resources to attract and keep the best teachers. We must give our schools the tools they need to prepare our students to succeed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As currently designated by NCLB, 100 percent of our Nation's schools must meet Adequate Yearly Progress, AYP, in reading/language arts and mathematics by the 2013/2014 school year. To date, almost 26 percent of schools in the U.S. are not making the grade. According to a report released by the National Education Association last year, fewer schools met AYP in the 2004/2005 school year than the prior school year. In my home State of Maryland, 311 out of 1,429 schools, or almost 22 percent, did  not make Adequate Yearly Progress, as defined by the No Child Left Behind Act and the State targets. During the 2005-2006 school year, 79 schools, or about 6 percent of Maryland's elementary and secondary schools had missed Adequate Yearly Progress toward State achievement targets for 5 or more</paragraph>
    <paragraph>consecutive years. As a result they were placed in restructuring and were subject to a variety of major school-wide reform strategies. A large majority of these restructuring schools are urban schools, and more than half are in the Baltimore City Public School System.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>According to research, teacher quality is the schooling factor with the most profound effect on student achievement. Good teachers can make up to a full year's difference in learning growth for students and overwhelm the impact of any other educational investment, including smaller class sizes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, our educational system pairs the children most behind with teachers who, on average, have less experience, less education, and less skill than those who teach other children. Certainly, there are exceptions, excellent and experienced teachers who have devoted their lives to at-risk students. But the overall patterns are clear.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Despite evidence that teachers become more effective after several years experience, students in high-poverty and high-minority schools are assigned to novice teachers almost twice as often as children in low-poverty schools. Classes in high-poverty and high-minority schools are much more likely to be taught by teachers without a major or minor in the subject they teach. Certainly, there are excellent first-year teachers and ineffective veterans. Indeed, mastery of a subject matter does not necessarily  translate into effective teaching. But these proxies for teacher effectiveness are backed by substantial bodies of research. Studies of effective teachers reveal they are distributed among our Nation's schools in a manner that actually enlarges achievement gaps.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We will only close student achievement gaps when we improve teacher quality and experience. We must make obtaining advanced training and experience in teaching more accessible and teaching at-risk students more desirable. In short, we must establish a class of "master teachers" with extensive experience and training who are willing to teach for an extended period of time in the schools that need them the most.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Fortunately, research also shows even modest monetary incentives lower teacher attrition, especially in high-risk school districts. Our legislation will reward master teachers with a 25 percent Federal tax exemption on their salary for four years if they agree to teach in a school that is not meeting AYP. A master teacher is a teacher that has at least 5 years of teaching experience in a public elementary or secondary school, holds a master's degree, meets the definition of highly qualified as  defined by the NCLB, and has obtained advanced certification in their state licensing system. Each State would have a cap of 10 percent of public school teachers eligible to receive master teacher tax treatment at a time. This program would go into effect in 2007 and end with the 2013/2014 school year, when NCLB requires that 100 percent of students perform at the proficient level.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Good teachers are essential to a successful education system; they are the profession charged with educating our future work force. The Master Teacher Act of 2007 will provide our children access to the best possible teachers and our teachers much needed financial support.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300021" topic="Introducing S. 1283. A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to improve the management of medical care, personnel actions, and quality of life issues for members of the Armed Forces who are receiving medical care in an outpatient status, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Armed Services.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1283">S. 1283</bill>] Mr. President, I rise today to join my colleague and my good friend, the Senator from Arkansas, Mr. Pryor, in introducing legislation to ensure that the medical needs of wounded service men and women are properly met and that the military bureaucracy does not interfere with their recovery progress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have watched with embarrassment and compassion as the unacceptable conditions of some of our military medical care facilities and housing facilities were revealed and shown to the public. Clearly, we owe our wounded military personnel the best treatment and care that can be offered. This bill we are introducing today will help provide that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me say, first of all, I have recently had the opportunity to visit the Eisenhower Medical Center at Fort Gordon, GA, as well as the medical facility at Fort Benning, GA, and I am reminded once again that medical care given to our military men and women is truly second to none. Are there exceptions? Sure. There are problems that arise from time to time in the delivery of health care services to our military men and women. Our purpose today is to try to make some of the bureaucracy go away  and to try to help make sure our medical suppliers at all of our military facilities around the country and around the world have the ability to deliver the very best medical care to our men and women.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our bill, <bill type="s" number="1283">S. 1283</bill>, the Wounded Warrior Assistance Act of 2007, will improve the access to and quality of the health care our military personnel receive by requiring that case managers for personnel in medical holdover status handle no more than 17 cases and review each case once a week.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our bill will also create a system of patient advocates who can help personnel navigate the cumbersome medical board and review process, as well as add necessary funding to hire additional physicians.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our bill increases training for health care professionals, medical case managers, and patient advocates, with an emphasis on identifying and treating difficult-to-diagnose and complex conditions, such as post-traumatic stress disorder and traumatic brain injury.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our bill establishes a toll-free hotline for patients and their families to report problems with medical facilities or patient care and creates an independent advocate to counsel servicemembers appearing before medical evaluation boards.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our bill creates a wounded warrior battalion, which will be an Army pilot program to improve the transition from military to civilian life for wounded combat veterans, as well as track and assist members of the Armed Forces who are in outpatient status and in need of medical treatment. More than 24,900 soldiers have been wounded in Iraq. We owe it to them and their loved ones to have a responsive health care system in place, in addition to the very best medical care available.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation increases the resources available to our veterans in order to allow them to focus on their recovery rather than redtape. Heroes such as these need and deserve the best medical care and attention we can offer them, and this bill will help provide that. They do not need to be disadvantaged by an outdated, bureaucratic process that adds more stress to their recovery process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our legislation is a step in the right direction to reform and modernize the outpatient treatment process and will increase the morale and welfare of our recovering servicemembers. They deserve our fullest support, and we are committed to meeting their needs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill mirrors <bill type="h" number="1538">H.R. 1538</bill>, which was passed by the House of Representatives by a vote of 426 to 0 on March 28 of this year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank Senator Pryor for the chance to work together with him on this important legislation. He and I have had the opportunity to work on any number of measures during our now going on 5 years in the Senate. He is a true champion of not just our wounded but all of our military personnel, and it has been a pleasure to work with him.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I commend this bill to all of my colleagues. I hope we can move to a swift passage of the bill so we can present it to the President for his signature. I urge my colleagues to support it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Arkansas is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300080" topic="Introducing S. 1283. A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to improve the management of medical care, personnel actions, and quality of life issues for members of the Armed Forces who are receiving medical care in an outpatient status, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Armed Services.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I thank the Senator from Georgia for his kind remarks. Of course, everybody in the Senate knows what a friend to the men and women in uniform Senator Chambliss has been since he has been in the Senate. I am sure that also relates back to his House days. He has really been a fabulous leader for our soldiers, and it is an honor for me to ask him to join me in the Wounded Warrior Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last Friday, I had the chance to go to Walter Reed and see three Arkansans who were injured in various ways in Iraq. It is always a sobering experience to go see our soldiers whom we are so proud of. We are proud of the people who put on the uniform and put their lives in jeopardy for the principles of this country. And we have other facilities, not just Walter Reed. I know that is the one that gets the most publicity nationally. Obviously, every State or region has a lot of facilities. In Little  Rock, there is the John McClellan Veterans Hospital, which I visited not too long ago, and we have at least a couple of other very good facilities in our State. They offer, generally speaking, great care. We know that sometimes people fall through the cracks, but we are very proud of our VA presence in the State of Arkansas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I must say that in my office in Little Rock--and the one here, for that matter--we have people on staff who deal and work with soldiers virtually on a daily basis--people who are in the VA system who, for some reason, have run into some bureaucratic roadblock or a file gets lost or a record gets lost or some box doesn't get checked or whatever the case may be. We, more or less, like many colleagues here, have full-time staff who do that on virtually a full-time basis. We are honored to help the  citizens of our State in any way we can, but we also would like to say that we can help the VA system run better and provide better health care with less bureaucracy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Arkansas has had about 40 soldiers killed in Iraq. It has been a very hard circumstance for our State to go through. It impacts every community in the State and almost every family in the State. In addition to those 40, which obviously are going to get more notice and publicity and discussion, as they should, there are 369 Arkansans who have been injured in Iraq. Those numbers track fairly well what the national numbers are.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Across this Nation, there have been 11,215 soldiers, at last count, who have been wounded in Iraq so severely that they have not been able to return to duty. So it is critical that we have legislation such as the Wounded Warrior Assistance Act. It will require case managers for outpatients to handle no more than 17 cases. They will have to review each case weekly. It creates a system of patient advocates within our health care system. It increases training for health care professionals, medical  case managers, and patient advocates, with an emphasis on identifying and treating post-traumatic stress disorder and traumatic brain injuries. It establishes a toll-free hotline for patients and families to report problems with medical facilities or patient care. It creates an independent advocate to counsel servicemembers appearing before medical evaluation boards. We think all of those are healthy, positive, and constructive reforms. We think the time has come for this to happen.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator Chambliss, a few moments ago, mentioned that the House passed this legislation 426 to 0. They did that late last month. It is the Senate's turn to weigh in and be on record for helping our wounded warriors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Wounded Warrior Assistance Act allows them to focus on healing and not be frustrated by redtape. It improves the access and quality of care our veterans receive. It puts an advocate on their side. We know that with any large organization, there will be  some bureaucracy and files will be lost and information gets misplaced. We understand that. But, hopefully, what this will do is streamline the process and make the system work a lot better for those  who have been willing to make the sacrifice for this country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I think this is important legislation because it does good things, but it is also symbolic legislation. It shows our members of the military that we are willing--their Government and the people of this country--to stand behind them during and after their Active-Duty service.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask that my colleagues give this legislation their strong consideration. The House passed it overwhelmingly. I hope we will have broad-based, bipartisan support in this body. It is an honor for me to offer it with my lead cosponsor, Senator Chambliss of Georgia.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300037" topic="Introducing S. 1284. A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for the taxation of income of controlled foreign corporations attributable to imported property; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1284">S. 1284</bill>] Mr. President, today I am joined by Senators Mikulski, Durbin, Stabenow, Rockefeller, Levin, Feinstein, Johnson, Harkin, Feingold, Leahy, Kohl, and Kennedy in introducing legislation to close an insidious loophole in the U.S. Tax Code that actually rewards U.S. companies that move American manufacturing jobs overseas. Some may think this is a belated April Fools' Day joke; regrettably,  it is not. Let me explain how this perverse tax break for these companies works.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When a U.S. company closes down a U.S. manufacturing plant, fires its American workers, and moves those good-paying jobs to China or other locations abroad, U.S. tax laws allow these firms to defer paying any U.S. income taxes on the earnings from those now foreign-manufactured products until those profits are returned, if ever, to this country. This tax break is not available to American companies that make the very same products here on American soil. So the U.S. company that decides to stay  at home suffers a competitive disadvantage, a disadvantage that our tax laws have helped to create. Multinational companies ought to pay the same taxes that domestic companies pay. At a minimum, U.S. companies that keep their jobs here should not be put at a competitive disadvantage by Federal tax policy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The notion that granting large tax breaks to companies that move their manufacturing operations offshore is good for this country is utter nonsense. Among other things, those who support this half-cocked fiscal policy claim that shutting down U.S. manufacturing operations and moving them abroad will result in more U.S. jobs and increase our exports.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, this assertion is not supported by the facts. According to the latest available data, the number of foreign manufacturing affiliates has grown from 7,420 to 8,490, up some 14 percent since 1993. From 1993 though 2004, U.S. companies moved 1 million manufacturing jobs offshore to their foreign affiliates.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Throughout this entire period, this perverse deferral break has been in effect. Has it resulted in new U.S. manufacturing jobs? No. We have lost some 3.2 million U.S. manufacturing jobs since 2000 alone. Has this misguided tax subsidy resulted in higher exports from U.S. companies to their foreign affiliates as the proponents of this tax subsidy suggest? No. In fact, imports into the United States from the foreign subsidiaries of U.S. companies more than doubled from $92 billion in 1993 to $203  billion in 2004. And the balance of trade with foreign affiliates of U.S. firms plummeted to a $72 billion deficit in 2004 as compared to $3.4 billion in 1997.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have been working to end this wrong-headed Federal tax break for many years. Senator Mikulski and I have forced the Senate to vote to repeal this tax subsidy several times. I have described stories on the Senate floor about a number of American companies that have moved production overseas, companies like Huffy bicycles and Radio Flyer little red wagons to China; Samsonite, which went to Mexico and then China; Levi's, which are now made all over the world, everywhere except in the  very country that invented them; Maytag, which now makes appliances in Mexico and Korea; and Fruit of the Loom, which moved to Mexico. And I would point out, once again, that this tax deferral break given to companies like Radio Flyer or formerly to Huffy bicycles is not available to American companies that make the very same products on U.S. main streets.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But we have run into stiff opposition from many U.S. multinational companies, their lobbyists, and some policymakers who claim our proposal would impede the ability of U.S. firms to compete and grow in the global economy. That is hogwash. This proposal does nothing to hinder U.S. multinationals that produce abroad from competing with foreign firms in foreign markets. The legislation we are introducing today is carefully targeted; it ends the deferral tax break only where U.S. multinationals produce  goods abroad and ship those products back to the U.S. market. In more technical language, this legislation would end tax deferral for the "imported property" income of controlled foreign corporations. The proposal also adds a new separate foreign tax credit basket for imported property income. The separate foreign tax credit</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The tax experts with the Joint Committee on Taxation estimate that this pernicious tax break will costs U.S. taxpayers some $15.5 billion over the next decade. It is no wonder that the powerful lobby for the largest U.S. multinational firms has fought to keep this tax loophole fully intact. But as I have told my colleagues on the Senate floor a number of times, I intend to offer this proposal again and again until this tax subsidy is finally repealed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I understand that some U.S. companies will still choose, with or without this tax subsidy, to dislocate thousands of workers in America in search of cheaper labor, lax regulation, and greater profits abroad at whatever the cost. They will be free to do so. But at least U.S. taxpayers will not be asked to provide billions of dollars in tax subsidies for those who do.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge all of my colleagues in the Senate, Democrats and Republicans alike, to take a fresh look at this issue and help us do what Congress should have done many years ago; that is, repeal this ill-conceived tax break once and for all.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="Introducing S. 1285. A bill to reform the financing of Senate elections, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Rules and Administration.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1285">S. 1285</bill>] Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300090" topic="Introducing S. 1288. A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to increase the retirement security of women and small business owners, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1288">S. 1288</bill>] Mr. President, today I am introducing the Women's Retirement Security Act of 2007. This measure has the potential to make a significantly positive impact on the ability of Americans to save for their retirement years. This is a truly bi-partisan bill and I am pleased to be joined today in introducing this important legislation with Senators CONRAD, KERRY, BINGAMAN and SNOWE.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Preparing for retirement and achieving financial security are daunting tasks for all Americans; however, women face many unique challenges. Women are more likely to work part-time or work in industries where employers are less likely to offer retirement benefits. And many women have significant gaps in their work histories due to caring for children or elderly parents.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a result, women receive substantially less income during retirement than men. What makes this trend even more disturbing is the fact that women generally live longer. So if anything, women should be entering retirement with more income.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Women's Retirement Security Act of 2007 works to narrow the retirement income gap between men and women. For example, because women are more likely than men to work part-time, the bill will require employers to allow long-term, part-time employees to make elective deferrals to their 40l(k) plans. In addition, the bill expands the Saver's Credit, which is a tax credit for certain low and moderate-income individuals, so that more Americans will benefit.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill also creates automatic IRAs. Over 75 million Americans work for an employer that does not sponsor a retirement plan. This is almost half of all working Americans. The Women's Retirement Security Act will allow those employees not covered by a qualified retirement plan to save for retirement through automatic payroll deposits to IRAs. Under the bill, employers with more than 10 employees that don't sponsor a retirement plan would be required to offer an option for their employees to make  regular payroll deposits to IRAs. This concept is very similar to direct deposit of paychecks to employees' bank accounts, which many employers already do.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Another key component provides incentives for lifetime payments. Since women generally live longer than men, they must be particularly concerned with protecting against the risk of exhausting their retirement income. Life annuities help ensure that older Americans will not outlive their retirement savings, adding stability and security in retirement years. The Women's Retirement Security Act encourages annuitization by allowing individuals to exclude from taxation a portion of payments from qualified  or nonqualified annuities that last a lifetime.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I look forward to working with my colleagues to narrow the pension gap between men and women by enacting the important reforms in this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that a copy of this legislation be printed in the RECORD. I also ask unanimous consent that my statement be included in the RECORD next to the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thank you.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300060" topic="Introducing S. 1288. A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to increase the retirement security of women and small business owners, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I am pleased to join my colleagues Senators SMITH, CONRAD, SNOWE, and BINGAMAN in introducing the Women's Retirement Security Act of 2007. This legislation comes on the heels of the passage of the Pension Protection Act of 2006, which makes improvements to the defined benefit pension plan system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation that we are introducing today builds upon that legislation and focuses on defined contribution plans. Our pension system has shifted away from defined benefit plans to defined contribution plans. We should make it easier for employers to offer defined contribution plans and for individuals to participate in these plans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At a time when we have a negative savings rate that is the lowest since the Great Depression, we should provide appropriate incentives to help individuals save for retirement. In an effort to achieve this, the Women's Retirement Security Act of 2007 focuses on increasing retirement savings, the preservation of income, equity in divorce, improving financial literacy, and encouraging small businesses to enter and remain in the employer retirement plan system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation increases savings by allowing employees to contribute a portion of their paycheck to an individual retirement account (IRA) if their employer does not offer a pension plan. Automatic IRAs will help the 71 million workers that do not have employer-sponsored plans. It is a low-cost, sensible solution that provides a stepping stone toward employer-sponsored retirement plans. More workers are likely to contribute to an IRA if the contribution is deducted from their payroll. Automatic  IRAs will help combat the inertia that is a factor in our low savings rate. The bill also provides a tax credit to help small businesses with the cost of implementation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Pension Protection Act of 2006 increase made the tax credit for contributions to qualified pension plans permanent, commonly referred to as the saver's credit, permanent. Our legislation builds upon this provision by making this credit refundable and making it 50 percent of the contribution for all eligible taxpayers. The annual contribution eligible for this credit is $2,000. In 2005, five million households benefited from this provision. These changes will help many more benefit from this  important credit. Making the credit refundable will help those who are struggling and do not have enough income to save.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Women are often placed at a disadvantage in our retirement system because they cycle in and out of the work force. The Women's Retirement Security Act of 2007 addresses this issue by requiring employers that offer defined contribution plans to cover part-time employees that meet specific requirements.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Pension coverage needs to improve, particularly for small businesses. In  2004, only 26 percent of workers at firms with fewer than 25 employees participated in pension plans. Progress has been made on providing coverage to small businesses. Currently, more than 19 million workers are covered by small business retirement plans, but more than 36 million Americans work for firms with less than 25 employees.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Women's Retirement Security Act of 2007 provides a start-up credit for new small business retirement contributions. In addition, it removes rules that discourage small employers from adopting deferral only plans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I look forward to continuing to work with my colleagues to help improve the retirement of mothers, sisters, daughters, and wives. We should work together to provide incentives that encourage participation in retirement plans and remove barriers preventing employers from offering them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thank you.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300029" topic="Introducing S. 1289. A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to modify the salary and terms of judges of the United States Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims, to modify authorities for the recall of retired judges of such court, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1289">S. 1289</bill>] Mr. President, I have sought recognition today to comment on a bill I am introducing to help ensure the long-term ability of the United States Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims to promptly dispense justice in all veterans cases.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1988, Congress created this court to hear appeals from decisions of the Department of Veterans Affairs, most commonly on veterans' claims for disability compensation based on injuries or diseases they suffered during service. As was discussed at a hearing I called last year while serving as chairman of the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, the CAVC is facing some serious challenges, which may impede its ability to consistently provide timely decisions to our Nation's veterans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In fact, between 2004 and 2006 the court experienced something akin to a "perfect storm." The last four of the original judges, who were appointed when the court was created, all retired, taking 60 years of experience with them; the court's incoming caseload experienced a dramatic 67-percent increase; and the court was left with a single judge who had at least 2 years of experience deciding these often complex cases. As a consequence, the court received 30 percent more cases than it decided  during that time and the number of pending cases doubled in less than 2 years. With over 6,000 cases still pending, almost 4,000 more than a decade ago, and with the court continuing to receive record levels of incoming cases, veterans seeking justice from the court may feel the effects of this "perfect storm" for many years to come, as the court struggles to eliminate the existing backlog and to keep up with new appeals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For the men and women who have served, sacrificed, and suffered for our Nation, I believe we must take steps to ensure that they will receive timely decisions on their appeals, not just today but for many years to come. That is why I am introducing this bill to help the court deal with its existing caseload and to help ensure that, in the long term, the court will not face such a devastating combination of events.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As one means of helping with the current caseload, the bill would modify the rules that govern the recall of retired judges. Under current law, a retiring judge may opt to be recall eligible, which means the judge may be involuntarily called back to work for up to 90 days per year when needed and may voluntarily serve up to 180 days per year. For this court, like other Federal courts, the option of receiving help from retired judges can be an extremely important resource. In fact, last year,  after the court began recalling retired judges to help with its caseload, the court's productivity rose over 19 percent in 3 months.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In view of the obvious value of having experienced retired judges continue to decide veterans' cases and the fact that they currently receive the same salary as active judges regardless of how much, if any, service they provide in a year, it would be a win-win situation for veterans, the court, and taxpayers if a retired judge opted to return to the bench more frequently or for longer periods than current law permits. To allow for that possibility, the bill would eliminate the 180-day cap and  permit a retired judge to voluntarily serve in recall status as many days during a year as he or she wishes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Also, because the court may need an unprecedented level of service from retired judges in the next several years to help deal with its caseload, the bill would provide an incentive for the current complement of recall-eligible judges to provide as much service as practical during that time. Specifically, the bill would provide that, once a recall-eligible judge has served an aggregate of 5 years of recall service, the judge will no longer be subject to involuntarily recall and will continue to  receive the same salary, that of an active judge.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To put that into perspective, if a retired judge were to be recalled for 90 days each year, as current law permits, it would take 20 years to provide the equivalent of 5 years of recall service. In addition to allowing judges to accelerate their service into fewer years, at a time when it may be most beneficial to veterans, this change may also encourage retired judges to serve in recall status for longer periods of time. This should help minimize concerns expressed by the Chief Judge in recent  years about how much retired judges would be able to accomplish in the limited 90 day recall period. With these changes, the court should have the judicial resources it needs to handle its caseload in the near term.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, this bill would take steps to ensure that the court, in the long run, is not faced with a difficult transition like the one it experienced in recent years. By way of background, the original judges, except for one who died, all retired between 2000 and 2005, with four of those retirements occurring within a single 12-month period. Given the delays inherent in the appointment and confirmation process, this left the CAVC without a full complement of active judges for much of that 5-year  period. As the Chief Judge testified in 2006, functioning with less than seven judges "led to a backlog" of cases at the court.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Perhaps more significantly, this cluster of retirements meant that, as of August 2005, the court had only one judge, the new Chief Judge, who had at least 2 years of experience on the bench. In the words of that Chief Judge, "no other Federal court would be faced with the transition that we were faced with as of August 2005. Where else in the Federal judiciary system could I, the junior judge . . . suddenly become the senior judge, and have all of the experience of the court departing?" The  Chief Judge also opined that "[t]his turnover on the Court has had great significance, particularly in the short term, on the Court's case management."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The effects of this turnover may have been magnified by the fact that this court deals with a very specialized area of law, which by all accounts has become increasingly complex in recent years. In fact, the Veterans of Foreign Wars of the United States recently described veterans' law as "a complex thicket of court decisions and statutory requirements."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To further complicate the situation, the court experienced a dramatic rise in the number of incoming cases in recent years. In fact, in 2005 the court received 37 percent more cases than it had received in any prior year and, then, in 2006 the court received an even higher level of incoming cases. As I indicated earlier, the combined effect of these factors led the court to be "in the red" for several years, taking in almost 3,000 more cases than it decided.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although some factors that have contributed to the court's challenges cannot be controlled, it seems clear that multiple retirements of experienced judges within a relatively short period of time can have a profound impact on the court's ability to decide veterans' cases. It is worth noting that Congress previously attempted to stagger the retirement dates of the judges by temporarily expanding the size of the court and by shortening the length of two judges' terms. Despite those efforts, it  is possible that 6 of the 7 judges now on the bench will retire within a 4-year window, an even shorter period than the disruptive turnover between 2000 and 2005.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is why I believe we need to try a completely new approach to help ensure that experienced judges will stay  on the bench for as long as practicable and will not retire in clusters  as their terms expire. To that end, this bill would eliminate the term limits for any new judges appointed to the court and would provide those judges with full pay-of-the-office only when serving as an active judge or when providing service as a recalled retired judge. The combined effect of those provisions should encourage judges to stay on the bench longer before they retire and to regularly volunteer for recall service after they retire.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Yes, this represents a significant departure from the traditional model for article I courts. But as experience has shown, the current model is not adequate to consistently provide veterans with timely decisions on their claims and we simply cannot allow further disruptions in service to our Nation's heroes each time the court turns over. Once judges gain years of valuable experience in this complex, specialized area of law, we should not force them, and their experience, into retirement. Rather,  we should take steps, as this bill would do, to permit veterans and the court to receive the maximum possible benefit from their years on the bench.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To avoid "changing the rules" on those judges who have already been appointed and confirmed, these changes would be prospective, applying only to judges appointed to the court on or after the date of enactment of this bill. In the meantime, I hope the changes to the current recall provisions that I mentioned earlier will help avoid a difficult transition when the current sitting judges retire.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to these changes to the term limits and recall rules, the bill would require the Chief Judge, in conjunction with the court's stakeholders, to set guidelines for when recall would be appropriate, taking into account such factors as the number of active judges, temporary or prolonged increases or decreases in caseload, and the complexity of the caseload. It would also require the court to submit annual performance reports to Congress including information on the court's workload during  the prior year, as well as an analysis of whether the standards for recalling judges were met and what service, if any, was performed by retired judges. Such guidelines should aid the court, retired judges, and Congress in planning for periods when recall will likely be used and when it will not.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>More importantly, the number of recall-eligible judges and their level of activity are important factors that must be considered in determining whether the court has sufficient judicial resources. If current caseload trends continue and the court, even fully utilizing the services of recalled judges, is unable to provide veterans with the level of service they deserve, the addition of judgeships may need to be considered. These guidelines and reports will allow Congress to closely monitor that  situation to ensure that the court has the necessary capacity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, the bill would recognize the critical and increasingly demanding role of the Chief Judge by allowing the salary of the Chief Judge to be increased by $7,000 per year, and the bill would direct the General Services Administration to provide Congress with a report as to the feasibility and desirability of converting the court's current location into a dedicated Veterans Courthouse and Justice Center.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is my sincere hope that the fundamental changes in this bill will help ensure that the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims is able to consistently provide veterans with timely decisions, now and for many years to come. I ask my colleagues to support this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300029" topic="Introducing S. 1290. A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to provide additional discretion to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs in contracting with State approving agencies, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1290">S. 1290</bill>] Mr. President, I have sought recognition today to comment on a bill I am introducing to ensure that veterans and their families have access to educational assistance benefits unimpeded by layers of bureaucracy and inflexible legal requirements.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Each year, the Department of Veterans Affairs provides educational assistance benefits to veterans, servicemembers, reservists, and their families to pursue a wide array of educational opportunities, including traditional college degrees, vocational training, apprenticeships, and on-the-job training programs. VA contracts with entities called "State approving agencies," SAAs, to assess whether schools and training programs are of sufficient quality for individuals to receive VA education benefits  while pursuing their programs. That SAA approval process was originally instituted after World War II to help stem abuses of veterans' education benefits, such as scam vocational and business schools profiting from those education benefits and then not providing veterans with an education of any value.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, unlike 60 years ago, schools and educational programs of all types may be scrutinized by a number of different entities, including the Department of Education, the Department of Labor, various national and regional accrediting bodies, and state licensing agencies. In fact, in 1995 the Government Accountability Office found that a substantial portion of the approval activities performed by SAAs overlapped with work done by others. Several years later, the Commission on Servicemembers  and Veterans Transition Assistance concluded that veterans should be "the primary judge of the appropriateness of accredited courses to their plans for the future" and that "[a]pproval of institutions accredited by accrediting bodies recognized by the Department of Education should suffice for veterans' training approval."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the years since those findings, Congress has altered the responsibilities of SAAs by requiring them to perform additional functions, such as promoting the development of apprenticeships and on-the-job training programs, conducting outreach services, and approving licensing tests. However, the traditional approval functions performed by SAAs, which are specifically required by statute, have not been significantly modified.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last year, in order to assess whether veterans face unnecessary or inefficient barriers in accessing VA education benefits under the current system, I asked GAO to evaluate the extent to which SAA approval activities currently overlap with functions performed by the Departments of Labor and Education and what value is added by the services performed by SAAs. Let me give you a few examples of GAO's recent findings:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many education and training programs approved by SAAs have also been approved by the Departments of Education or Labor and VA and SAAs have taken few steps to coordinate approval activities with those Departments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To streamline approval processes, VA should collaborate with other agencies but, according to VA, that may be difficult because of the specific approval requirements in law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>VA does not require SAAs to track the amount of resources they spend on specific duties and functions, including those that may be performed by other agencies, and thus does not have all relevant information to make resource allocation decisions or to determine whether it is spending federal funds efficiently and effectively.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is difficult to assess the effectiveness and progress of SAAs because VA does not have outcome-oriented performance measures in place to fully evaluate their performance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although I have no doubts about the dedication and sincerity of SAA personnel in the field, I believe GAO's findings demonstrate that we do not have a systematic or objective way to determine whether the current mix of services provided by SAAs, which are mandated by statute, are either necessary or beneficial to the veterans and their families who participate in VA's education programs. That is why I believe we should overhaul the entire statutory scheme regarding SAAs, as this bill would do,  to help eliminate redundant administrative procedures, increase VA's flexibility in determining the nature and extent of services that should be performed by SAAs, and improve accountability for any activities they undertake.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Specifically, this bill would strike statutory provisions that mandate what activities SAAs must perform, how those functions must be carried out, and how VA must pay for them. Instead, VA would have authority to contract with SAAs for services that it deems valuable and to determine how those services should be performed, evaluated, and compensated. The bill would also require VA to coordinate approval activities performed by State approving agencies, the Department of Labor, the Department  of Education, and other entities to reduce overlapping and unnecessary layers of bureaucracy. To ensure that VA, Congress, and other stakeholders will be able to objectively assess the effectiveness of any functions performed by SAAs, VA would be required to establish outcome-oriented performance measures and SAAs would be required to track and report information on the resources expended on all activities they perform.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, the bill includes a provision, similar to legislation that the Senate passed last year, that would provide a $19 million spending authorization for SAAs effective at the start of the upcoming fiscal year and would allow, for the first time, SAA funding to be drawn from both mandatory spending accounts and discretionary accounts. By way of background, since 1988 VA payment for the services of SAAs has been made only out of funds available for "readjustment benefits", a VA account funded  through mandatory appropriations, and has been subject to annual funding caps.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For the current fiscal year, SAA funding from this entitlement account is capped at $19 million, but under current law there will be a $6 million reduction in authorized spending, to $13 million, for every fiscal year thereafter. Although the provisions of this bill would maintain a $19 million funding level in future years, it is important to note that that level is a ceiling, not a floor. As with any private-sector business or good-government business model, budgeting and funding decisions  should be linked to performance and VA should contract only for those services that are necessary and valuable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In sum, this bill would provide VA with the flexibility to streamline approval processes, eliminate redundant bureaucratic procedures, focus resources on services that will meet the current needs of education program participants, and ensure that veterans and their families will not confront layers of bureaucracy and inflexible legal requirements in accessing their educational assistance benefits. I ask my colleagues to support this measure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300029" topic="Introducing S. 1293. A bill to amend titles 10 and 38, United States Code, to improve educational assistance for members and former members of the Armed Forces, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1293">S. 1293</bill>] Mr. President, I have sought recognition today to comment on a bill I am introducing to enhance educational assistance benefits provided to active duty servicemembers, veterans, members of the Guard and Reserve, and their survivors and dependents by the Department of Veterans Affairs, VA, and the Department of Defense.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In recent years, many veterans' organizations, members of Congress, and others have highlighted the need to modernize these education programs to support emerging and alternative education opportunities and to recognize that the role of Guard and Reserve members has been transformed since September 11, 2001. This bill would take significant steps in that direction by providing greater flexibility in the use of these education benefits, revising eligibility criteria to reflect current mobilization  strategies for Guard and Reserve units, and enhancing the education program for our "citizen soldiers" who have been called up to serve in the war on terror.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, this bill would provide veterans, Guard and Reserve members, and their spouses and dependents with additional flexibility in using existing education benefits. Traditionally, educational assistance benefits have been paid in equal monthly allotments throughout a semester or term. For veterans, the maximum basic rate is now $1,075 per month, which means a veteran may receive at least $9,675 over the course of an average school year and almost $39,000 during a 4-year college program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This system works well for veterans attending a traditional four-year college. But, as the Commission on Servicemembers and Veterans Transition Assistance reported in 1999, the existing payment structure "constrains veterans and servicemembers desiring to enroll in short-term career-focused technical courses," a problem that is "especially acute if the cost of the course dramatically exceeds the benefits payable for the few months' duration of the course."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is why in 2001 I cosponsored legislation to establish an "accelerated" payment option for veterans' education benefits. With that program now in place, a veteran may receive an up-front, lump-sum payment of up to 60 percent of the cost of certain high-tech, high-cost programs. Since that option was made available, many veterans have used that additional flexibility to train for jobs in high technology sectors of the economy, such as the computer and telecommunications industry, the aerospace  industry, and the electronics industry.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Then last year, as chairman of the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, I supported legislation that would have expanded this option to allow accelerated payments for short-term, high-cost education programs leading to jobs in any high growth sectors of the economy. Although VA also supported that legislation, VA testified that "implementation would be challenging" and that "[i]t would be cleaner and more direct if the bill simply stated that all high-cost short-term courses were eligible for accelerated  payments."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Having taken those concerns into account, this bill would allow veterans to receive accelerated payments for any short-term, high-cost education programs, and it would authorize VA to spend up to $3 million for those payments in each fiscal year from 2009 to 2012. Not only would this provide veterans with the flexibility to pursue nontraditional or technical educational opportunities, but it may help veterans quickly obtain job skills that currently are in high demand.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For example, the trucking industry is now experiencing a critical shortage of trained drivers, but the GI Bill, as currently structured, may pay only a fraction of the cost for a veteran to take the 6 to 8 week training course, about $2,000 of a total $6,000 bill. With the availability of accelerated payments for those and other short-term, high-cost training programs, veterans may be able to obtain the skills needed  to thrive in sectors of the economy  that, today, are growing rapidly and can provide them with lucrative, rewarding career opportunities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, the bill would, for the first time, provide Guard and Reserve members with the option of receiving accelerated payment of their education benefits. They, too, would be eligible to receive up-front, lump-sum payments of up to 60 percent of the cost of any short-term, high-cost education program. For fiscal years 2009 to 2012, the bill would authorize $2 million per year for the Montgomery GI bill, Selected Reserve program and $1 million per year for the smaller Reserve Educational  Assistance Program to make these payments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To ensure that the families of veterans also have flexibility in the use of their education benefits, the bill would extend the same accelerated payment option to participants in the Survivors' and Dependents' Educational Assistance program. It would authorize VA to spend up to $1 million per year for those payments in fiscal years 2009 to 2012.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The second principal goal of the bill is to update and enhance the education program for members of the Guard and Reserve who are called to active duty. In 2004, recognizing the increased sacrifices being made by our "citizen soldiers" who are fighting in the War on Terror, Congress created the Reserve Educational Assistance Program for Guard and Reserve members who are activated for at least 90 days after September 11, 2001. This program was a significant step in the right direction, providing  a maximum benefit of $860 per month for 36 months, a total possible benefit of over $30,000.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>However, the maximum monthly benefit requires a deployment of 2 continuous years or more of active duty, and the Secretary of Defense has recently announced that "from this point forward, members of the Reserves will be involuntarily mobilized for a maximum of one year at any one time, in contrast to the current practice of sixteen to twenty-four months." To bring those eligibility criteria in line with current practice, this bill would allow members of the Guard or Reserve to receive the maximum  benefits if they are deployed for an aggregate period of 3 or more years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, the bill would provide these "citizen soldiers" with access to a valuable option now available only under the Montgomery GI bill program for active duty servicemembers. Specifically, it would allow members of the Guard or Reserve to contribute up to $600 in order to receive an additional $150 per month in education benefits, which amounts to an additional $5,400 in benefits over the course of 36 months. Under this bill, Guard and Reserve members would, for the first time, have access  to this valuable opportunity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With these modifications, we can take significant strides towards ensuring that current education programs are up-to-date and flexible and that they provide members of the Guard and Reserve with benefits commensurate with the level of service they are now performing on behalf of the entire Nation. I urge my colleagues to support this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="Introducing S. 1294. A bill to strengthen national security by encouraging and assisting in the expansion and improvement of educational programs in order to meet critical needs at the elementary, secondary, and higher education levels, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1294">S. 1294</bill>] Mr. President, I urge my colleagues to support the Homeland Security Education Act. This bill encourages initiatives to increase the number of Americans trained in science, technology, engineering, math, and foreign languages.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>More than a century ago, Henry Ford revolutionized transportation and industry with the creation of the Model T. This car and the process designed to create it were so innovative that it was copied by every other company. The Model T became the base model for all cars that followed. This is a classic American story. Some of the most important scientific breakthroughs in modern history have occurred in the labs, workshops, and classrooms of America. We take pride in our Nation's ability to meet  any challenge and solve any problem with innovation and discovery. But we are falling behind. Today's innovations in the auto industry come not from Detroit but from Japan. Engineers in Asia are designing tomorrow's hybrid car while Henry Ford's company and other American companies are just trying to keep up.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>America's colleges and universities can play an important role in reversing the decline in American innovation. The United States graduates some of the world's best engineers, scientists, and mathematicians, but a far higher proportion of the students in China, India, South Korea, and Japan are focusing on these fields. The National Academies of Science reports that in 2004, only 32 percent of the undergraduate degrees awarded in the United States were in science or engineering compared to 59  percent in China and 66 percent in Japan. If we do not address this crisis soon, China, India, and Japan will become the new centers for scientific and technological innovation, while American workers scramble to keep up. We must act now to ensure that America remains the world's economic, scientific, and technological leader.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>American workers are also increasingly finding themselves at a disadvantage in a multilingual global community. In our increasingly global economy and with a heightened concern for security in the post-911 world, we need Americans who can speak a foreign language. Only 9 percent of American students enroll in a foreign language course in college. We especially need to focus on less commonly taught languages, including Arabic, Farsi, Chinese, and Korean, and other languages that are of particular  value in the world today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The best place to address both of these concerns is in the classroom. We must adapt our educational system by providing the teachers and resources needed to encourage students to study science, technology, engineering, mathematics, and foreign languages. The Homeland Security Education Act is an important step in the right direction.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill would encourage students to pursue math, science, technology, engineering, and critical foreign languages by providing them with $5,000 scholarships. Scientists, engineers, technology professionals, and those fluent in foreign languages would be encouraged to return to the classroom and use their career experiences to inspire students in high-need or low-income schools. New grant programs would encourage educational institutions, public entities, and businesses to enter into partnerships  that improve math and science curricula, establish programs that promote students' foreign language proficiency along with their science and technological knowledge, and create and establish foreign language pathways from elementary school through college. Finally, the bill would fund a student loan repayment program for qualified individuals trained in science, technology, engineering, math, and foreign languages who join the Federal workforce.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our country is quickly approaching a crisis of competitiveness. To avoid falling behind our international competitors in science and innovation, we must confront this problem immediately in our schools. We need to strengthen our students' proficiency in science, technology, engineering, math, and foreign languages and provide them with the incentives necessary to pursue careers in those fields. Today's students are tomorrow's innovators, scientists, and technology leaders, and we can't afford  not to invest in them. I encourage my colleagues to join me in cosponsoring the Homeland Security Education Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="Introducing S. 1294. A bill to strengthen national security by encouraging and assisting in the expansion and improvement of educational programs in order to meet critical needs at the elementary, secondary, and higher education levels, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today, along with my friends Senators DURBIN and COCHRAN, to reintroduce legislation that will provide students much needed educational opportunities in foreign languages and science, technology engineering and mathematics, STEM.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The future economic health and security of our Nation depends on programs such as those called for in our legislation. This country's national security depends upon having a workforce with the necessary science, technology, engineering, math, and foreign language skills to rapidly and efficiently adapt to the challenges of globalization. Yet, we are falling behind.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>According to a study conducted by the Committee on Economic Development, the Federal Bureau of Investigation and other Federal Government agencies do not have a sufficient number of personnel trained in critical languages to translate intelligence information in a timely manner. Similarly, a GAO report issued August 4, 2006, GAO-06-894 noted that the State Department was still suffering from gaps in language proficiency which could adversely impact its ability to communicate with foreign audiences  and execute critical duties.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We all know that we live in a global marketplace. The United States, which has the world's largest economy, is the engine for global economic growth. However, this also means that American workers must compete with others in the global market for skilled labor. The signs have long been clear that we are failing to develop the next generation of workers. As a recent study by the National Center for Public Policy and Higher Education observes, in the United States "about one-quarter of 15-year-olds  fall into the lowest proficiency level on assessments of skills and knowledge." The United States ranks 16th among 27 countries in the number of students who earn a college degree or certificate. We can delay no longer in taking the steps to train students to compete and thrive in a multi-lingual and technologically complex environment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our bill the Homeland Security Education Act, provides schools with the framework they need to prepare our Nation's youth for the future. Its enactment is a critical step in reenergizing and reinvigorating our education system to meet the needs of our Nation. It will increase students' proficiency in foreign languages and encourage them to become scientists and engineers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Homeland Security Education Act provides schools with the equipment and materials necessary to teach STEM and foreign language courses by encouraging public private partnerships to improve science and math curricular--upgrade laboratory facilities; provide scholarships for students to study math, science, or engineering at the university level; and Establish internship and mentoring opportunities for students in grades K-12; developing cultural awareness and immersion programs in colleges  and universities that combine science, technology, and engineering instruction with foreign language to expand international understanding and scientific collaboration; and creating language learning pathways to facilitate proficiency in critical foreign languages from kindergarten through graduate school.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, this act addresses the shortage of STEM and foreign language teachers. Our Nation needs mathematicians, scientists, and linguists in order to compete in a global mart. Accordingly, our bill awards scholarships in the amount of $15,000 to language proficient individuals and to practicing scientists and engineers to encourage them to become certified to teach these critical skills to students in high-need, low-income schools. The bill would also allow National Security Education Program  scholarship and fellowship recipients to meet their service requirements by teaching in critical areas if they cannot find a national security position in the Federal service. In addition, a key provision awards grants to build professional development programs, summer workshops or institutes, and foreign language distance learning programs for elementary and secondary school teachers in order to facilitate partnerships between 12 schools and institutions of higher education.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Not only do we need to encourage individuals and professionals to become teachers in these critical need areas, we also need to encourage students to study languages, science, technology, engineering, and math by underscoring the importance of these subjects to our country's security and economic well-being. As Secretary of Education Margaret Spellings noted in January 2006, only 44 percent of this country's high school students are studying any foreign language, while learning a second or even  a third language is compulsory for students in the European Union, China, Thailand, and many other nations. Only 32 percent of undergraduates in the United States receive their degrees in science and engineering compared to 59 percent in China and 66 percent in Japan. Our children deserve better</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, education is the foundation of our Nation's long-term security. In order to fulfill our role as a world leader, this Nation needs Americans who are well educated and can communicate and compete in a global environment. The bill we are introducing today will help us meet this essential goal.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300060" topic="Introducing S. 1298. A bill to amend the Social Security Act to establish a Federal Reinsurance Program for Catastrophic Health Care Costs; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1298">S. 1298</bill>] Mr. President, States like my home state of Massachusetts are setting an example for the rest of the country by taking bold steps to provide quality health coverage for everyone. Now it is time for Washington to do the same by bringing meaningful, affordable healthcare to the uninsured, in Massachusetts and across America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In Massachusetts there is still a major obstacle in the overall goal of universal coverage: cost. The fact is the problem of the uninsured can't be solved unless the issue of skyrocketing health costs to families and businesses is also tackled. And fully reforming the healthcare system will require that the Federal Government begin shouldering some of the burden to help alleviate costs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Healthcare costs are highly concentrated in this country. The very few who suffer from catastrophic illness or injury drive costs up for everyone. One percent of patients account for 25 percent of healthcare costs, and 20 percent of patients account for 80 percent of costs. To make healthcare more affordable, we must find a better way to share the immense burden of insuring the chronically ill and seriously injured.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Part of the reason that businesses and health plans today fail to cover  their workers is an aversion to risk, a fear that they will be saddled with a sick employee whose high premiums will bankrupt them. And patients who are catastrophically ill or injured often face the tragic combination of failing health and financial peril. But there's a way to combat these costs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress should make employers and healthcare plans an offer they can't refuse. It's called "reinsurance." Reinsurance provides a backstop for the high costs of healthcare. The Federal Government will reimburse a percentage of the highest cost cases if employers agree to offer a substantive insurance benefit to all full time employees, including preventative care and health promotion benefits that are proven to make care affordable. This means lower costs and lower premiums for both employers  and employees. If the Federal Government can help small and large businesses bear the burden of cost in the most expensive cases, we'll dramatically improve the health of everyone.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today I am introducing the Healthy Businesses, Healthy Workers Reinsurance Act, a bill that will make Government a partner in helping businesses with the heavy financial burden of those catastrophic cases: those that use over $50,000 in a single year in healthcare costs. Healthy Businesses, Healthy Workers will protect business owners from skyrocketing premiums, and provide more working families affordable, quality healthcare. With reinsurance, health insurance premiums for all of us will go  down, by up to 10 percent under this plan. This plan does have a cost associated with it, but the benefits will outweigh the costs. We spend hundreds of billions of dollars each year on inefficient and wasteful health expenditures. We need to make sure that these funds are being spent wisely to ensure that we can lower health care costs and improve coverage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe that even in today's sharply divided Washington, this plan is feasible. There is a growing bipartisan consensus that the Federal Government has a responsibility to help the catastrophically ill. Consider the Medicare prescription drug program: Despite its flaws, the bill did cover 95 percent of the cost of prescription drugs once seniors passed through the disastrous "doughnut hole" in their coverage. The same approach has been used to protect the insurance market from going under  in case of another catastrophic act of terrorism.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As we take the next steps toward alleviating our Nation's healthcare crisis, a commonsense partnership between employers, families, and the government to share the costs of the sickest among us will lay the groundwork for achieving our ultimate goal: healthcare coverage for every single American.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask for unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the text of the bill was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300081" topic="Introducing S. 1298. A bill to amend the Social Security Act to establish a Federal Reinsurance Program for Catastrophic Health Care Costs; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I join my colleague, Senator Kerry, in introducing the Reinsure America's Businesses Act of 2007. This legislation represents a critical step forward in bringing affordable health care to the uninsured and lowering the ever increasing costs of health care for families and businesses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill that we are introducing today proposes that the Federal Government assume responsibility for the most burdensome risk for employers, and in doing so helps to provide greater access to lower priced health care. Under our legislation, the Federal Government will reimburse employers for a significant portion of the costs of their most ill employees--75 percent of medical bills in excess of $50,000. In exchange, employers agree to offer all of their workers preventative care and quality  coverage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At the heart of this bill lies the fact that 1 percent of patients account for 25 percent of health care costs, and 20 percent of the population that is catastrophically ill accounts for 80 percent of the costs. Planning for the unfortunate chance that one falls into one of these categories is precisely why individuals have health insurance. Yet it is also the primary reason why many employers, particularly small businesses where one critically ill individual can have a tremendous influence on  the  overall cost, do not offer their employees health insurance. Through reinsurance, the Federal Government has an opportunity to absorb a large portion of this risk and encourage more affordable and meaningful employer sponsored health coverage. This legislation also eases the burden on health insurance companies by making rate determinations more predictable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Federal reinsurance is an efficient use of Federal dollars because it spreads the burden across employers, the Federal Government, and employees, thereby lowering costs and increasing access to quality health care. Reinsurance reduces health insurance premiums for everyone; some estimates suggest as much as 10 percent. Actions to decrease the cost of health care and improve access to care are crucial if we are to combat ever-rising health care costs in this country. In Rhode Island, from 2000  to 2006, premiums increased 75 percent while median earnings went up only 23 percent. Uninsured rates have also grown in Rhode Island with more than 13 percent of residents under age 65 with no health insurance, up from 8.1 percent in 1999. Rhode Island</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am pleased to join with my colleague in introducing this important initiative and hope the Senate will give it prompt consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="Introducing S. 1302. A bill to amend title V of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to encourage and support parent, family, and community involvement in schools, to provide needed integrated services and comprehensive supports to children, and to ensure that schools are centers of communities, for the ultimate goal of assisting students to stay in school, become successful learners, and improve academic achievement; to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1302">S. 1302</bill>] Mr. President, I am pleased today to introduce the Keeping Parents and Communities Engaged or Keeping PACE Act, to foster greater involvement of parents in their children's education, engage community partners in supporting the comprehensive learning needs of students in school, as well as to address our Nation's high dropout rate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is clear that engaged parents can make a positive difference in students' achievement. Parents are their children's first teachers, and they have immense influence over their children's attitudes, focus, priorities and goals. Well-informed parents are more likely to be involved, to ask questions, to suggest constructive changes and to make a difference in their child's education. They deserve to know what their children are learning and being tested on, what their children's grades and assessment  scores mean, and how assessment data may be used for improvement. Informed and engaged parents can help turn around struggling schools.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We crafted the No Child Left Behind Act to recognize parents as full partners in their children's education. The Act includes essential requirements to develop parent involvement policies and programs, develop and release school report cards, and to establish a team of parents and community representatives to construct a plan to improve schools if they are identified as struggling. We should build on these important reforms. But in the upcoming reauthorization of the law, we must also explore  new and innovative strategies to engage parents and communities in helping kids succeed in school.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Better coordination among parents, schools, and the community can also help create a network that enables and empowers students to take advantage of every opportunity to learn. That's particularly important for students needing the greatest help and attention in their learning and those who need more challenging schoolwork to keep them engaged and progressing, as well as students at risk of dropping out of school. Today, more than one million students who enter the ninth grade fail to receive  a high school diploma 4 years later and approximately 7,000 students drop out of school every day. We've made great advances in recent years to improve the education of every student, but it remains clear that more must be done to respond to this challenge.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We must support and strengthen our elementary and secondary schools and do more to attend to the learning and nonacademic needs of our most at-risk students, which make such a difference in how well they master their subjects. That means support for community programs to meet children's social, intellectual, emotional, and physical needs. It means making parent involvement a top priority, and offering support to schools to involve parents and families more effectively in their children's education,  including postsecondary education planning.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Keeping PACE Act will address these fundamental issues. This bill amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to encourage and support parent, family, and community involvement in schools, to provide needed supports and services to children, and to ensure that schools are centers of communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Educators recognize, on the basis of abundant research and common experience, that parental involvement is a critical element in children's academic and social development. Unfortunately, as noted in a recent report by Appleseed, too often, schools and districts continue to face challenges that impede efforts to effectively advance parental involvement. My bill enables States to award grants to local education agencies to assist schools in hiring and maintaining Parent and Community Outreach  Coordinators. These coordinators will build critical partnerships among families, schools, and the community. They'll work with school principals, teachers, and staff to encourage parents to become more involved in their child's education and give them the tools necessary to become successful advocates for their children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last year, a Massachusetts pilot initiative placed 17 full-time Family and Community Outreach Coordinators in Boston Public Schools. The Coordinators were responsible for supporting families, teachers, and the community in a common effort to help students excel academically and socially.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Their efforts have worked. The Family and Community Outreach Coordinator at the Condon School in Boston, Massachusetts, has offered workshops for parents on middle school transition and math curriculum; coordinated parent participation on the School Climate Committee, an anti-bullying initiative at the school; helped teachers and parents make connections for parent-teacher conferences; and brought in over 200 parents to participate in the fall open house, where some teachers reported having contact  with over 80 percent of their students' families. The Coordinator has also leveraged donations to the school through the generosity of local businesses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The success of the coordinators led the Boston School Committee to approve its budget for the next school year with the addition of 14 more full-time Family and Community Outreach Coordinators. All together this means that almost 22 percent of Boston Public Schools will have a coordinator by September 2007-2008.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The director of the Harvard Family Research Project notes that many years of research confirm that "now is the time ..... for action. The question we must ask is, in addition to quality schools, what non-school learning resources should we invest in and scale up to  improve educational outcomes, narrow achievement gaps, and equip our children with the knowledge and skills needed to succeed in the complex and global 21st century."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill answers that question and responds directly to these needs by creating new grants for community-based organizations to work in partnership with schools to bring essential comprehensive and integrated services to children in need. These support services may include health care, counseling, social services, enrichment, mentorship, and tutoring, services that can often spell the difference between a dropout and a graduate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Rather than giving teachers, counselors, and principals more to do as they address the non-classroom needs  of students, every school should have a resource they can turn to for help with identifying student needs and leveraging community services to help all students succeed. We know that comprehensive, integrated supportive services increase graduation rates and improve student achievement. In one national report: 82 percent of tracked students improved  their attendance in school; 86 percent of tracked students had fewer behavior incidents; 89 percent of tracked students had fewer suspensions. In addition, 98 percent of tracked students stayed in school and 85 percent of eligible seniors graduated. Students who are identified as needing these services, but do not receive them are more likely to drop out of school.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Lucy Stone School in Boston, Massachusetts, demonstrates the effectiveness of student supports on learning. The once failing school took action and focused on improving core learning skills, a broad array of enrichment activities and health and social supports. Lucy Stone is making strong progress. Students in Grades 3 and 4 are passing the literacy MCAS at rates well above the Boston Public School average percentages, and are approaching State averages. Grade 4 math MCAS passing rates are  approaching Boston and State averages as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In other communities, diverse community partners have played an important role in providing accelerated learning and mentoring opportunities that have made all the difference for students.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For example, a comprehensive evaluation of nine schools in New England found that classroom participation in community service outdoor learning projects increased student engagement and retention of science knowledge. And the "Being Enthusiastic about Math and Science" (BEAMS) enrichment program at the Jefferson National Lab in Virginia, which serves 1,800 inner-city students and their teachers, has resulted in increased achievement and attendance rates, and a better understanding of academic  subjects, careers and applications among participating students.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The National Commission on Service Learning found that mentorships and internships with caring adults in a workplace resulted in higher grade point averages and better attendance than for students who spend less time with adult mentors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is one particular organization that has a demonstrated track record in helping leverage the integrated services and supports that students need to succeed in school. Communities in Schools (CIS) is the Nation's largest dropout prevention organization, and has a nearly 30-year track record of helping connect students, families and schools with supportive services to help them graduate and prepare for life. With affiliates operating in 27 States and the District of Columbia, Communities in  Schools helps about 2 million students every year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Community involvement means real help for children in need, and the evidence shows. For instance:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In Georgia, CIS currently supports graduation coaches directly serving approximately 37,000 high school students who are at risk of dropping out.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the wake of Hurricane Katrina, CIS stepped in to provide morning classes and afternoon activities for students whose parents had lost their social support systems after they were forced to relocate to Houston, Texas.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are also countless individual stories of community-based integrated services making a difference. In Texas, CIS helped 14-year-old Yeana Carbajal, who was born with cerebral palsy, to obtain proper medical attention and social services, enabling her to return to school after hip surgery when her doctors had told her that would be impossible. Yeana is now back in school and thriving academically and socially.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Another student, who at 14 became the primary caregiver of a mother who eventually died with AIDS, overcame homelessness and became the first in her family to graduate high school. A turning point for her came when she participated in a career exploration program coordinated through the community-based program office at her school. She discovered her special talents in the culinary arts, and is now an honor student at Johnson and Wales University.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, a growing body of educational research suggests that student achievement improves in environments where learning is a community value, and where schools have the ability to address a broad range of educational needs. Many school districts have gone even further to respond to this research, by establishing full-service community schools that directly involve parents, families, and the entire community in education.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Keeping PACE Act also responds to this research by providing new avenues to establish and support full-service community schools. These efforts have wide-ranging positive impacts, including "better family functioning and parental involvement, healthy youth development and improved social behavior, improved academic achievement and learning outcomes, and enhanced community life." Two prominent researchers in the field further note, "In community schools ..... schools are transformed into  much more than just a portfolio of programs and services. They become a powerful agent for change in the lives of young people and their families and improve the climate of the entire school."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill enables States to provide incentives to local education agencies that coordinate with mayors, community-based organizations, for-profit organizations and other community partners to re-design and modernize their current school plans and facilities to better link students with community resources. School districts across the country are beginning to recognize the benefits of planning a school not only as an academic center for students, but also as a neighborhood center that serves the  entire community. Designing schools from the onset to leverage integrated services to students helps meet multiple local needs such as educational, health, social service, and recreational needs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It's time for America to make a real commitment, and give real opportunity and real fairness to address the comprehensive learning needs of children and families, guarantee a place for parents and families in schools, and provide real hope to our students most at-risk of dropping out. Engaging parents and communities in the success of students enrolled in our public schools is critical to the future and prosperity of our entire Nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill is supported by 15 organizations representing education communities. I ask unanimous consent that their letters of support be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300071" topic="Introducing S. 1304. A bill to amend the National Trails System Act to designate the Arizona National Scenic Trail; to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1304">S. 1304</bill>] Mr. President, I am pleased to be joined today by Senator Kyl in introducing the Arizona Trail Feasibility National Scenic Trail Act. This bill would designate the Arizona Trail as a National Scenic Trail. A similar bill is being introduced in the House of Representatives by Congresswoman GIFFORDS.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Arizona Trail is a beautifully diverse stretch of public lands, mountains, canyons, deserts, forests, historic sites, and communities. The Trail is approximately 807 miles long and begins at the Coronado National Memorial on the U.S.-Mexico border and ends in the Bureau of Land Management's Arizona Strip District on the Utah border near the Grand Canyon. In between these two points, the trail winds through some of the most rugged, spectacular scenery in the Western United States. The corridor  for the Arizona Trail encompasses the wide range of ecological diversity in the State, and incorporates a host of existing trails into one continuous trail. In fact, the trail route is so topographically diverse that a person can hike from the Sonoran Desert to Alpine forests in 1 day.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For over a decade, more than 16 Federal, State, and local agencies, as well as community and business organizations, have partnered to create, develop, and manage the Arizona Trail. Through their combined efforts, these agencies and the members of the Arizona Trail Association have completed over 90 percent of the longest contiguous land-based trail in the State of Arizona. Designating the Arizona Trail as a National Scenic Trail would help streamline the management of the high-use trail to ensure  that this pristine stretch of diverse land is preserved for future generations to enjoy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since 1968, when the National Trails System Act was established, Congress has designated over 20 National trails. Before a trail receives a national designation, a Federal study is typically required to assess the feasibility of establishing a trail route. The Arizona Trail doesn't require a feasibility study because it's virtually complete with less than 60 miles left to build and sign. All but 1 percent of the trail resides on public land, and the unfinished segments don't involve private property.  The trail meets the criteria to be labeled a National Scenic Trail and already appears on all Arizona State maps. Therefore, the Congress has reason to forego an unnecessary and costly feasibility study and proceed straight to National Scenic Trail designation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Arizona Trail is known throughout the State as boon to outdoor enthusiasts. The Arizona State Parks recently released data showing that two-thirds of Arizonans consider themselves trail users. Millions of visitors also use Arizona's trails each year. In one of the fastest-growing States in the U.S., the designation of the Arizona Trail as a National Scenic Trail would ensure the preservation of a corridor of open space for hikers, mountain bicyclists, cross country skiers, snowshoers, eco-tourists,  equestrians, and joggers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I urge my colleagues to support the passage of this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300062" topic="Introducing S. 1304. A bill to amend the National Trails System Act to designate the Arizona National Scenic Trail; to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today I am pleased to join with Senator McCain in introducing the Arizona National Scenic Trail Act. This bill would amend the National Trails System Act to designate the Arizona Trail as a national scenic trail. In 1968, Congress established the National Trails System to promote the preservation of historical resources and outdoor areas. National scenic and historic trails may be designated only by an act of Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is not a new proposal. Senator McCain and I have been working on legislation relating to the Arizona Trail since the 108th Congress. Past legislation focused on conducting a feasibility study to determine whether the trail is physically possible and financially feasible. A feasibility study is generally the first step toward national trail designation, but such legislation was not successfully enacted. In the meantime the Arizona Trail Association and its State and Federal partners  have continued to develop the trail with national designation in mind. Senator McCain and I believe a feasibility study is not necessary. Let me explain: the Arizona Trail already exists. It extends over 800 continuous miles and is over 90 percent complete--clearly, it is physically possible. It is also financially feasible,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Arizona Trail is highly deserving of national designation. The trail is a roller coaster ride through the wide range of ecological diversity in the State. The trail corridor begins at the Coronado National Memorial on the U.S.-Mexico border and winds some 800 miles, ending on the Bureau of Land Management's Arizona Strip District on the Utah border. Between these two points, it invites recreationists to explore the State's most renowned mountains, canyons, deserts and forests, including the  Grand Canyon and the Sonora Desert. This trail is unique in that it maximizes the incorporation of already existing public trails into one continuous trail to showcase some of the most spectacular scenery in the West.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over 16 Federal, State and local agencies, as well as numerous community and business organizations and countless volunteers, have cooperated to develop and sustain the trail as a recreational resource for future generations. Designating the Arizona Trail  as a national scenic tail will help streamline its management, boost tourism and recreation, and preserve a magnificent natural, cultural, and historical experience of the American West. I urge my colleagues  to enact this legislation at the earliest possible date.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300024" topic="Introducing S. 1307. A bill to Include Medicare provider payments in the Federal Payment Levy Program, to require the Department of Health and Human Services to offset Medicare provider payments by the amount of the provider's delinquent Federal debt, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1307">S. 1307</bill>] Mr. President, I rise to introduce the Medicare Provider Accountability Act on behalf of myself, and my colleagues Senator LEVIN and Senator MCCASKILL. This bill is a direct result of the recent bipartisan investigation by the Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations exposing Medicare physicians and related providers who cheat on their taxes. At our March 20 hearing, entitled "Medicare Doctors Who Cheat On Their Taxes," the Subcommittee presented evidence that more  than 21,000 physicians and other providers received millions of dollars through the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services, CMS, under Medicare Part B, even though they collectively owe more than $1.3 billion in undisputed Federal taxes as of September 30, 2006.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think it is important to note that the vast majority of physicians are working hard to provide services to Medicare beneficiaries. In fact, I know that many doctors struggle with on-going reductions in payments under the so-called Sustainable Growth Rate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The focus of PSI's ongoing investigations has been tax fraud and government contractors. CMS is the only Federal agency of considerable size that has resisted participating in the Federal Payment Levy Program that I will describe later. As we looked into CMS, we found that there were physicians receiving payments from the government while they simultaneously withheld money from the government by cheating on taxes, and failing to pay child support or student loan debts. Through their actions,  these "bad apples" are hurting efforts to promote the longterm sustainability of the Medicare Program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What is disturbing is that the delinquent doctors identified by our investigation were not hardship cases but rather folks living the "good life." This minority of physicians live in multi-million-dollar homes, own luxury vehicles and pleasure boats, and gamble with millions of dollars, yet still cheat the government.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Some of the most egregious examples that GAO discovered include the following:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>An ambulance company received more than $1 million from Medicare in just the first 9 months of 2005, although it owed more than $11 million in back taxes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One doctor has refused to pay Federal income taxes since the 1970s and now owes more than $3 million in unpaid Federal taxes, and more than $1 million to another Federal agency. He was paid approximately $100,000 by Medicare in the first 9 months of 2005. He tried to hide his assets by attempting to transfer property to his children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Another physician who owes more than $1 million, primarily as payroll taxes withheld from his employees, received more than $1 million from Medicare between January and September 2005. He was flaunting his illegally gained windfall with a million-dollar home, 58-foot yacht, and ownership of several night clubs. His recently reported income  is half a million dollars, but the compromise offer he made to the IRS only covers the penalty for nonpayment and not the overdue taxes themselves.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Another physician whose medical license is on probation owes more than $400,000 in unpaid Federal taxes. Despite this debt, he purchased a luxury vehicle predominantly with cash, deposited tens of thousands of dollars in cash in such a way as to avoid mandatory reporting to the IRS, and gambled away millions of dollars. Although he did report more than $600,000 in net profits for 2 recent years, he still managed to fall behind in his child support payments by tens of thousands of dollars and  to default on his installment agreement with the IRS.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unfortunately, the list goes on and on. Worse, as if failing to pay their taxes was not a sufficient insult to American taxpayers, Medicare providers also owed $33 million in child support, $27 million in unpaid student loans, $114 million owed to other Federal agencies, and $22 million in unpaid state income taxes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While these figures and case studies are obviously disturbing, the good news is that the Federal Government has two marvelous programs for recovering Federal debt from Federal payments, the Federal Payment Levy Program, FPLP, for tax debt, and the Treasury Offset Program, TOP, for non-tax debt, such as delinquent student loans, child support, and money owed Federal agencies. The Financial Management Service, FMS, handles both of these programs and matches pending payments from the Federal Government  against outstanding Federal tax debt in the case of FPLP, and against other outstanding federal debt in TOP. If such debt exists, a levy of 15 percent or more is imposed upon each payment made to the delinquent taxpayer until that debt is recovered. FMS currently screens most Federal payments for unpaid taxes, including salaries and payments to contractors and vendors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Government Accountability Office specifically recommended that CMS confer with the IRS and FMS to figure out how to get Medicare payments into the levy program. That recommendation came in six years ago, in 2001, so it is clear that CMS and the other agencies have been "on notice" about this very issue for years. In fact, although CMS has been sending information on payments to Medicare Part C and D providers to FMS for matching in FPLP, it has failed to include the more than $300 billion  in payments to Part A and B providers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a result, the Federal Government has lost countless opportunities to levy Medicare payments made to tax-delinquent doctors and other suppliers. The GAO estimated that, if CMS had participated in the levy program, the government could have recouped anywhere between $50 million and $140 million of unpaid Federal taxes from these Medicare tax-cheats in just the first nine months of 2005 alone. That does not include potential millions recouped for delinquent student loans, unpaid child support,  and back-taxes owed to States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But we are not in the blame business, we are in the problem-solving business. So, the paramount question is how to fix this mess. Make no mistake: these are complex problems, but I am confident that we can fix them. This legislation is a good start.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill, entitled the Medicare Provider Accountability Act, has three prongs to assist the Federal government with the collection of these outstanding debts. It establishes a timetable for CMS to join the Federal Payment Levy Program for all payments to Medicare providers, and expressly authorizes CMS to participate in the Treasury Offset Program to collect nontax debt. Finally, it enables the IRS to begin levying payments earlier in the notice process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, this bill sets a deadline by which CMS must fully participate in the FPLP. Fifty percent of the payments to Part A and B providers must be sent to FMS for matching tax debt under FPLP within 1 year of enactment. Within 2 years of enactment, every Medicare provider payment, regardless of Part, will be checked by FMS under FPLP for outstanding Federal tax debt.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second, this bill gives CMS the authority to submit payments to its providers to TOP, which it had previously been unable to do. CMS and FMS testified at the hearing that CMS cannot legally participate in TOP as a Federal disbursing authority, and that to do so will require a Legislative fix. This bill explicitly includes payments to Medicare providers as disbursements that can be offset, allowing for the recovery of delinquent student loans, overdue child support, debts owed to other federal  agencies and state taxes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, this legislation enables IRS to levy Federal payments to recover delinquent tax debt earlier in the process. Currently, only about half of the $140 billion in tax debt eligible for  matching is "turned on" to allow FMS to begin levying payments through FPLP. This is a result of IRS's current procedure, sending four computer-generated notices followed by a Collection Due Process, CDP, notice. Although the delinquent taxpayer can enter a  payment plan or challenge the amount throughout the process, the formal appeals process begins only after all of those notices are issued. This protracted process allows a delinquent taxpayer to drag out the process and prevent automatic levies anywhere from months to years. An additional problem beyond the delay is that by the time the appeals process concludes, the contractor may no longer</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress has spent much of this session focusing on health care. We all know that we have a crisis looming with Medicare. In order to ensure the long term sustainability of the program, we need to be sure that the money that is going out through this program is being spent efficiently and effectively. We also need to be sure that the money that is coming into this program through our taxes is being collected efficiently and effectively. They are part and parcel of the same problem. As we look  for money to spend on programs to benefit our most vulnerable, this legislation can go a long way to identifying possible sources.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would especially like to thank Chairman Levin for his ongoing support of our efforts to address those who receive Federal payments without paying their taxes. This is truly a bipartisan effort and a bipartisan bill in its writing and its sponsorship.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="Introducing S. 1307. A bill to Include Medicare provider payments in the Federal Payment Levy Program, to require the Department of Health and Human Services to offset Medicare provider payments by the amount of the provider's delinquent Federal debt, and for other purposes; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I join today with my colleagues, Senator Coleman and Senator McCaskill, in introducing the Medicare Provider Accountability Act. This bill targets Medicare, a program which is indispensable to the health of our citizens, because some Medicare service providers are profiting from the program while abusing the federal tax system. The facts show that, while the vast majority of Medicare health care providers are honest, tax-paying citizens, others are  getting paid with taxpayer dollars while, at the same time, failing to pay their taxes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Legislation to stop this abuse is a product of the work of the Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations, on which I serve as Chairman and Senator Coleman serves as the Ranking Member. On March 20, 2007, a Subcommittee hearing presented testimony from the Government Accountability Office (GAO) showing that about 21,000 Medicare Part B health care providers, including doctors, ambulance companies, and medical laboratories, collectively owe more than $1 billion in delinquent taxes. GAO  also determined that, despite this pending tax debt, during the first 9 months of 2005 alone, these health care providers had received payments on Medicare claims totaling around $140 million. In other words, these providers were stuffing taxpayer dollars in their pockets at the same time they were stiffing Uncle Sam by not paying their taxes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Federal programs exist to stop this type of abuse. One key program is the Federal Payment Levy Program, which was established about ten years ago to enable the Federal government to identify federal payments being made to tax delinquents, and authorize the withholding of a portion of those taxpayer dollars to apply to the person's tax debt. That program has successfully collected taxes from federal payments made through the Treasury Department and by agencies like the Defense Department who screen  their own payments to contractors through Treasury's Financial Management Service.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As our March hearing demonstrated, however, despite a legal requirement to do so, The Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS) have never participated in the tax levy program with respect to Medicare Part A and B payments. This failure means that, year after year, as much as $300 billion in Federal Medicare payments have not been screened for unpaid taxes. The first substantive provision of our bill would redress this situation by mandating CMS to bring all Medicare part A and B payments  into the Federal Payment Levy Program over the next two years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The second part of our bill would enable CMS to participate in a similar automated program, known as the Treasury Offset Program, to collect non-tax debt, such as unpaid student loans and child support. GAO has determined that certain Medicare health care providers collectively owe hundreds of millions of dollars in student loans, child support, and unpaid state taxes that could be collected through administrative offsets.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The third and final part of our bill would eliminate a barrier to including a large part of IRS's uncollected tax assessments in the Federal Payment Levy Program for collection from Medicare provider payments, as well as other federal contractor payments. Right now, for a variety of legal and technical reasons, only 45 percent of the tax debt assessed but still uncollected in 2006 was actually made subject to levy under the federal program. In 2006, over half of this assessed tax debt--some $67  billion--was never "turned on" for actual collection under the tax levy program. Now, $67 billion is a big number, even by Washington standards.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One key reason that this tax debt was not "turned on" for collection by levy is that many of the accounts had not reached the stage in their processing where the required notice of intent to levy had been sent to the taxpayer. Until that notice is sent and the taxpayer has exhausted all rights of appeal available under the tax law, the  IRS is currently barred from placing a tax levy on the taxpayer's property. In the case of Medicare providers and  other federal contractors, that means federal dollars continue to go into their pockets, without any withholding, despite their unpaid taxes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While it may be appropriate to delay tax levies on most types of taxpayer property until a taxpayer's appeals are exhausted, it makes no sense to keep sending taxpayer dollars to a tax delinquent Medicare provider or other federal contractor while they are appealing the tax assessment. Withholding should be allowed when it is taxpayer dollars that are being paid to the tax delinquent. That's why our bill would create a special rule for federal payments, allowing a tax levy to be initiated and  continue in effect, while the taxpayer's appeal goes forward. The taxpayer would retain the same due process rights, but a tax levy would be allowed to begin earlier in the administrative process; it would no longer have to wait until all of the taxpayer's appeal rights were exhausted. For property other than federal payments, the bill would maintain the current system, requiring a pre-levy notice and exhausted appeal rights before the property could be levied.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The vast majority of Medicare providers render valuable services to their patients, and they do so while paying their taxes. These honest health care providers are put at a competitive disadvantage by the Medicare tax cheats who reduce their operating costs by failing to pay taxes. Besides hurting honest businesses, this type of tax dodging hurts our country by undermining the fairness of our tax system and by forcing honest taxpayers to make up the shortfall needed to pay for basic federal protections--like  health care. When these tax delinquents also receive large payments of federal funds, it adds insult to injury. We must force these tax dodgers to pay their tax debt, and a key tool is to subject any federal payments they receive to an effective tax levy program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Medicare Providers Accountability Act would target those tax dodgers by strengthening the tax levy program and subjecting additional hundreds of billions of dollars in federal payments each year to screening for unpaid taxes. An improved tax levy program would, in turn, strengthen federal tax enforcement, take a load off the shoulders of honest taxpayers, and reduce the tax gap. I urge my colleagues to join us in supporting the bill's enactment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that my remarks follow those of Senator Coleman in today's Congressional Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300087" topic="Introducing S. 1310. A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for an extension of increased payments for ground ambulance services under the Medicare program; to the Committee on Finance.">
    <paragraph>[Introducing <bill type="s" number="1310">S. 1310</bill>] Mr. President, today I, along with Senators LOTT and CONRAD, introduce the Medicare Ambulance Payment Extension Act. Without this legislation, ambulance service providers stand to lose $306 million in Medicare reimbursement in 2008 and 2009 in addition to the nearly $150 million they will lose this year. Our legislation will restore $341 million in Medicare reimbursement with a 5 percent increase in payments for 2008 and 2009.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ambulance services are a vital component of the health care and emergency response systems of our Nation. Unfortunately, ambulance services providers are being significantly under-funded in providing their critical services to Medicare patients. We need to ensure that our ambulance service providers have the financial resources necessary to provide all Americans with high quality, life-saving services.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Fortunately, in the Medicare Modernization Act of 2003, MMA, Congress implemented several provisions to provide temporary relief to help struggling ambulance service providers. The MMA ambulance provisions provided short-term relief through 1 percent urban and 2 percent rural increases, a mileage rate increase for long trips, a payment boost for ambulance transports in extremely rural areas, and a regional adjustment that helped a majority of providers depending on their state. While the rural  payment boost and long trip increase are temporarily still intact, the 1 percent urban and 2 percent rural increases expired at the end of last year and the regional adjustment has dropped from 80 percent to only 20 percent of payments. If Congress does not act, ambulance service providers will lose over $450 million in relief from 2007 through 2009.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ambulance service providers cannot afford to face decreased reimbursement in the coming years. Ambulances services respond to not only 911 calls and nonemergency requests but also as first responders to natural disasters and acts of terrorism. Medicare patients account for approximately 45 percent of the call volume of an ambulance operation. Ambulance service providers cannot afford to have half of their transports reimbursed at below the cost of providing services.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While all health care providers face reimbursement challenges, ambulance service providers are required by law to respond to a plea for emergency medical care, regardless of whether the provider will recoup the full, if any, cost of the service. This additional responsibility along with the requirement that ambulance service providers accept the Medicare ambulance fee schedule rate as payment in full has further deteriorated the financial stability of ambulance operations. With increased focus  on ensuring that our first responders are prepared in the event of a terrorist attack or national disaster, we should be bolstering, not deteriorating, this health care safety net.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Medicare Ambulance Payment Extension Act will ensure that patients across America will continue to have access to critical ambulance services. We urge our colleagues to support this legislation, and I look forward to its passage this year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the text of the bill be printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
</record>
