<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1180022410" ordinal="50" title="RECOGNIZING LAMOURE, NORTH DAKOTA">
  <speaking speaker="300026" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I am pleased today to recognize a community in North Dakota that will be celebrating its 125th anniversary. On June 22 to 24, the residents of LaMoure will gather to celebrate their community's history and founding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>LaMoure is a small town in southeast North Dakota with a population of roughly 1,000 residents. LaMoure was named in honor of Judson LaMoure, a legislator in the Dakota Territory government. It is the only known community named "LaMoure" in the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>LaMoure has a variety to offer, from its beautiful lake and parks to tours of the Toy Farmer Museum and Hutterian Brethren Colonies. Also in LaMoure, you can tour the County Courthouse, which is on the National Register of Historical Places. The LaMoure County Memorial Park, a short drive from LaMoure, is home to the LaMoure County Summer Musical Theater, which showcases local talent in a series of live performances throughout the summer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For those who call LaMoure home, it is a comfortable place to live, work, and play. The people of LaMoure are enthusiastic about their community and the quality of life it offers. The community has a wonderful celebration weekend planned that includes parades, dances, picnics, games, and much more.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask the Senate to join me in congratulating LaMoure, ND, and its residents on their first 125 years and in wishing them well into the future. By honoring LaMoure and all the other historic small towns of North Dakota, we keep the great pioneering frontier spirit alive for future generations. It is places such as LaMoure that have helped to shape this country into what it is today, which is why this fine community is deserving of our recognition.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>LaMoure has a proud past and a bright future.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
