<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1211299202" ordinal="43" title="CUBAN INDEPENDENCE DAY">
  <narrative>CUBAN INDEPENDENCE DAY -- (Senate - May 20, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="4478">S4478</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300078" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to recognize that today, May 20, is Cuban Independence Day. I am honored to join with Cubans around the world in commemorating this day.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On behalf of the people of Florida and all Americans, I rise to reaffirm our solidarity with the Cuban people as they continue their fight for freedom and self-determination. Dictatorships and tyranny have no place in this hemisphere. The U.S must continue to pressure the Cuban regime, while supporting the Cuban people.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is my great hope, that the people of Cuba, with their passion for liberty and their desire to live in a free and transparent democracy, will soon enjoy the same rights and freedoms that we do. We stand in solidarity with the Cuban people as they continue to fight for democratic change and true independence in their homeland.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thank you and may God bless the Cuban people.</paragraph>
    <paragraph> HONORING SARAH ROZENSKY</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300006" topic="ADDITIONAL STATEMENTS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I today honor Mrs. Sarah Rozensky, who served with excellence in my office for over 6 years. Sarah performed her duties with the utmost distinction and a level of professionalism and virtue rarely seen. I am proud to have this opportunity to recognize Sarah for the tremendous work she has done for the office and my family. My wife, Susan, and my sons, Beau and Nick, will also be eternally grateful for her service.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sarah came to my office with the highest of recommendations from the  White House and proved herself invaluable on a daily basis. Her qualities were contagious in our office; everyone learned and benefited from her presence.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For over 6 years, Sarah's meticulous attention to detail set the standard for those around her, as did her positive attitude and superior work ethic. Her gifts will undoubtedly allow her to excel to new heights in the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Every member of our staff plays an important role in our service in the Senate and to our respective States, but there are always the few who distinguish themselves as invaluable and irreplaceable. For me, Sarah Rozensky is one of those distinguished few. With Sarah's hard work and assistance, I have been better able to represent the people of Indiana in the Senate. Hoosiers all owe Sarah Rozensky a debt of gratitude, but most especially, I do.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am proud today to honor Sarah for her service and commitment to the people of Indiana and the Senate.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
