<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1211472002" ordinal="83" title="NATIONAL HURRICANE PREPAREDNESS WEEK">
  <narrative>NATIONAL HURRICANE PREPAREDNESS WEEK -- (Senate - May 22, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="4847">S4847</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of <bill type="sr" number="579">S. Res. 579</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="579">S. Res. 579</bill>) designating the week beginning May 26, 2008, as "National Hurricane Preparedness Week."</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motions to reconsider be laid on the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="579">S. Res. 579</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="579">S. Res. 579</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas, as hurricane season approaches, National Hurricane Preparedness Week provides an opportunity to raise awareness of steps that can be taken to help protect citizens, their communities, and property;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the official 2008 Atlantic hurricane season occurs in the period beginning June 1, 2008, and ending November 30, 2008;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas hurricanes are among the most powerful forces of nature, causing destructive winds, tornadoes, floods, and storm surges that can result in numerous fatalities and cost billions of dollars in damage;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, in 2005, a record-setting Atlantic hurricane season caused 28 storms, including 15 hurricanes, of which 7 were major hurricanes, including Hurricanes Katrina, Rita, and Wilma;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, for 2008, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration announced that the outlook for the hurricane season was near to above normal, with a 60 to 70 percent chance of 12 to 16 named storms, including 6 to 9 hurricanes and 2 to 5 major hurricanes;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration reports that over 50 percent of the population of the United States lives in coastal counties that are vulnerable to the dangers of hurricanes; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, because the impact from hurricanes extends far beyond coastal areas, it is vital for individuals in hurricane-prone areas to prepare in advance of the hurricane season;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas cooperation between individuals and Federal, State, and local officials can help increase preparedness, save lives, reduce the impact of each hurricane, and provide a more effective response to those storms;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the National Hurricane Center within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration recommends that each at-risk family in the United States develop a family disaster plan, create a disaster supply kit, secure their house, and stay aware of current weather situations to improve preparedness and help save lives, and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the designation of the week beginning May 26, 2008, as "National Hurricane Preparedness Week" will help raise the awareness of the people of the United States to assist them in preparing for the upcoming hurricane season: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) designates the week beginning May 26, 2008, as "National Hurricane Preparedness Week";&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) encourages the people of the United States--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) to be prepared for the upcoming hurricane season; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (B) to promote awareness of the dangers of hurricanes to help save lives and protect communities; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) recognizes--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (A) the threats posed by hurricanes; and</chair>
  <chair> (B) the need for the people of the United States to learn more about preparedness so that they may minimize the impacts of, and provide a more effective response to, hurricanes.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
