<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1197997209" ordinal="21" title="UNANIMOUS CONSENT AGREEMENT--H.R. 2764">
  <narrative>UNANIMOUS CONSENT AGREEMENT--H.R. 2764 -- (Senate - December 18, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="15828">S15828</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that when the Senate begins consideration of the message from the House on <bill type="h" number="2764">H.R. 2764</bill>, the Foreign Operations bill, there be 1 hour for debate equally divided between the two leaders or their designees on invoking cloture on the motion to concur in the House amendments; that the Senate vote on that cloture motion upon the use or yielding back of that time; that the mandatory live quorum be waived; that if cloture is not invoked, the Senate then  proceed to amendment No. 2 of the House; that Senator McConnell be recognized to offer a motion to concur in that amendment, with an amendment; that Senator Feingold then be immediately recognized to offer an amendment to that motion; that there be 1 hour for debate equally divided in the usual form in relation to Senator Feingold's amendment; that if his amendment does not attain 60 votes in the affirmative, it be withdrawn; that upon the disposition of his amendment, Senator Levin be recognized to offer his amendment to the motion; that there be 1 hour for debate equally divided on his amendment prior to a vote on his amendment; that if it does not attain 60 votes, it be withdrawn and the Senate immediately, without any intervening action, vote on Senator McConnell's motion to concur; that if his motion does not attain 60 votes in the</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <chair>The Republican leader.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300072" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, with regard to the 2 hours so designated for the AMT debate, I request the opportunity to modify: that Senator Isakson have 5 minutes, Senator Chambliss have 5 minutes, Senator DeMint have 15 minutes, Senator Enzi have 5 minutes, Senator Grassley have 15 minutes, and Senator Cochran have 15 minutes--that is for the final vote, Mr. President, not the AMT vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to the request, as modified?</chair>
  <chair>Hearing none, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, speaking on behalf of--and Senator McConnell certainly can speak on behalf of himself--I appreciate the cooperation of everyone. These are very difficult issues, and there is a lot of work we have not done. But that is the way it always is at the end of a session like this. So I appreciate everyone's cooperation. I hope no one has been offended with my being a little pushier than usual, but I had a little pushing on my side anyway, pushing me to get this done.  Everyone has a lot to do.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have one Senator who needs to get things done tonight. She has a sick daughter. She has to go home. We have a lot of issues we need to address.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So we will now hear from Senator Reed and Senator Brown, and then we will be on the bill.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Rhode Island.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300081" topic="">
    <paragraph>Thank you, Mr. President. First, let me thank the majority leader for arranging this time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
