<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1228842003" ordinal="39" title="HONORING THE VICTIMS OF THE BOMBING OF PAN AM FLIGHT 103">
  <narrative>HONORING THE VICTIMS OF THE BOMBING OF PAN AM FLIGHT 103 -- (Senate - December 09, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="10837">S10837</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate now proceed to the consideration of <bill type="sr" number="727">S. Res. 727</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="727">S. Res. 727</bill>) honoring the victims of the bombing of Pan Am flight 103 on the twentieth anniversary of the tragedy.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table, that there be no intervening action or debate, and any statements relating to the resolution be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="727">S. Res. 727</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="727">S. Res. 727</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas, on December 21, 1988, 259 passengers and crew members on board Pan American Airways flight 103, and 11 people  on the ground in Lockerbie, Scotland, were killed by a terrorist's bomb;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas 189 people of the United States and nationals from 20 other countries were victims of this heinous attack;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the families and friends of the victims of this tragedy have suffered immeasurable losses;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas people around the world actively have worked to diminish the possibility of future terrorist attacks;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, in 2003, Libya accepted responsibility for Libyan officials' involvement in the bombing of Pan Am flight 103, denounced terrorism, and vowed to abandon its weapons program;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas, on October 31, 2008, almost 20 years after the terrorist attack, Libya completed delivery of long-awaited compensation to the families of the victims of the bombing of Pan Am flight 103; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas nothing can replace the loved ones lost in the attack, and the United States must never forget the victims of this crime: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) designates December 21, 2008, as "Twentieth Anniversary of Remembrance for the Victims of the Bombing of Pan Am Flight 103 Day"; and</chair>
  <chair> (2) conveys the most sincere condolences to the families, friends, and communities of the victims of the attack on Flight 103.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
