<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1170910800" ordinal="63" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="COMMITTEE ON BANKING, HOUSING, AND URBAN AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, February 8, 2007, at 11:30 a.m. to mark up an original bill entitled "Public Transportation Terrorism Prevention Act of 2007."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold a hearing  during the session of the Senate on Thursday, February 8, 2007, at 10 a.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building. The purpose of the hearing is to evaluate the present and future of public safety communications.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND NATURAL RESOURCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Thursday, February 8, 2007, at 9:30 a.m. in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building. The purpose of the hearing is to receive testimony on issues relating to labor, immigration, law enforcement, and economic conditions in the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, February 8, 2007, at 9:15 a.m. to hold a hearing on the fiscal year 2008 budget request for international affairs.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="COMMITTEE ON HEALTH, EDUCATION, LABOR, AND PENSIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Thursday, February 8, 2007 at 10 a.m. in SH-216.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="COMMITTEE ON INDIAN AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Indian Affairs be authorized to meet on Thursday, February 8, 2007, at 9:30 a.m. in Room 485 of the Russell Senate Office Building to conduct a business meeting to consider pending legislative business, to be followed immediately by an oversight hearing on diabetes in Indian Country, with particular focus on the Special Diabetes Program for Indians.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet to conduct a markup on Thursday, February 8, 2007, at 10 a.m. in Dirksen Room 226.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Agenda</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Norman Randy Smith, to be U.S. Circuit Judge for the Ninth Circuit; Marcia Morales Howard, to be U.S. District Judge for the Middle District of Florida; John Alfred Jarvey, to be U.S. District Judge for the Southern District of Iowa.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="188">S. 188</bill>, To revise the short title of the Voting Rights Act Reauthorization and Amendments Act of 2006, Salazar;</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="214">S. 214</bill>, To amend chapter 35 of title 28, To Preserve the Independence of U.S. Attorneys, Feinstein;</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="316">S. 316</bill>, The Preserve Access to Affordable Generics Act, Kohl, Grassley, Leahy, Schumer, Feingold; <bill type="s" number="236">S. 236</bill>, The Federal Agency Data Mining Reporting Act of 2007, Feingold, Sununu, Leahy, Akaka, Kennedy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="sr" number="23">S. Res. 23</bill>, National School Counseling Week, Murray;</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="sr" number="36">S. Res. 36</bill>, Honoring women's health advocate Cynthia Doles Dailard, Snowe;</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="sr" number="37">S. Res. 37</bill>, Designating March 26, 2007 as National Support the Troops Day, Stabenow;</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="sc" number="5">S. Con. Res. 5</bill>, Honoring the life of Percy Lavon Julian, a pioneer in the field of organic chemistry and the first and only African-American chemist to be inducted into the National Academy of Sciences, Obama.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="SELECT COMMITTEE ON INTELLIGENCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Select Committee on Intelligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on February 8, 2007 at 2:30 p.m. to hold a closed hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
