<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1208880002" ordinal="50" title="NATIONAL COMMUNITY HEALTH AIDE, COMMUNITY HEALTH PRACTITIONER, AND DENTAL HEALTH AIDE WEEK">
  <narrative>NATIONAL COMMUNITY HEALTH AIDE, COMMUNITY HEALTH PRACTITIONER, AND DENTAL HEALTH AIDE WEEK -- (Senate - April 22, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="3267">S3267</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate now proceed to <bill type="sr" number="526">S. Res. 526</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <chair>The assistant legislative clerk read as follows:</chair>
  <chair>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="526">S. Res. 526</bill>) designating April 20 through 26, 2008, as "National Community Health Aide, Community Health Practitioner, and Dental Health Aide Week."</chair>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="526">S. Res. 526</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="526">S. Res. 526</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas Alaska experienced one of the most extreme tuberculosis epidemics in recorded history in the 1950s;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Community Health Aide Program in Alaska was created during the 1950s, in response to the unique health care needs of remote Alaskan communities;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Community Health Aide Program, which currently consists of 550 Community Health Aides and Community Health Practitioners and 40 Dental Health Aides, serves 178 isolated Alaskan communities to provide emergency, primary health care, and oral health care;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Community Health Aides, Community Health Practitioners, and Dental Health Aides have proven their dedication to serving Alaskans and their ability to work in some of the most challenging and diverse settings in the world;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Community Health Aide Program is the only program of its kind in the United States, and other countries have modeled their delivery of rural health care after this program;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Community Health Aide Program has proven to be effective, efficient, and essential in improving the health of the inhabitants of rural Alaska;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Community Health Aide Program is a patient's first contact within the network of health care professionals in the Alaska Tribal Health Care System and is one of the most effective means of delivering health care services to Alaskan communities;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Community Health Aide Program was created with a focus on tuberculosis, meningitis, and other infectious diseases, but now successfully cares for other common diseases such as diabetes and heart disease;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Community Health Aide Program also serves the oral health needs of Alaskans, and is in the process of adding services to address the behavioral health needs of rural Alaska; and &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Community Health Aide Program has successfully adapted over the last 50 years to the ever-evolving health care landscape of Alaskan communities: Now, therefore, be it</chair>
  <chair> Resolved, That the Senate designates April 20 through 26, 2008, as "National Community Health Aide, Community Health Practitioner, and Dental Health Aide Week".&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
