<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1215446403" ordinal="43" title="RELATIVE TO THE DEATH OF SENATOR JESSE ALEXANDER HELMS, JR.">
  <narrative>RELATIVE TO THE DEATH OF SENATOR JESSE ALEXANDER HELMS, JR. -- (Senate - July 07, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="6367">S6367</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate now proceed to the consideration of <bill type="sr" number="608">S. Res. 608</bill>, which was submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="608">S. Res. 608</bill>) relative to the death of Jesse Alexander Helms, Jr., former United States Senator for the State of North Carolina.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="608">S. Res. 608</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="608">S. Res. 608</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas Jesse Alexander Helms, Jr., born in Monroe, North Carolina on October 18, 1921, spent a 52-year public career dedicating himself to his country, his family, and his home State, representing North Carolina in the United States Senate for 30 years;</chair>
  <chair>Whereas Jesse Alexander Helms, Jr., served in the United States Navy from 1942 until 1945;</chair>
  <chair>Whereas Jesse Alexander Helms, Jr., was educated in the public schools of Monroe, North Carolina and at Wingate Junior College and Wake Forest College, served as city editor of the Raleigh Times, administrative assistant to United States Senators Willis Smith and Alton Lennon, executive director of the North Carolina Bankers Association, member of the Raleigh City Council, and a television and radio executive;</chair>
  <chair>Whereas Jesse Alexander Helms, Jr., was elected to the United States Senate in 1972, and served as Chairman of the Senate Foreign Relations Committee and the Senate Agriculture Committee, ultimately serving five terms, equal to the longest of any Senator from North Carolina;</chair>
  <chair>Whereas Jesse Alexander Helms, Jr., was a leader against Communism and became the first legislator of any nation to address the United Nations Security Council;</chair>
  <chair>Whereas Jesse Alexander Helms, Jr., was married for 65 years to Dorothy "Dot" Coble Helms, whom he termed his "best friend" and is the father of three children;</chair>
  <chair>Whereas Jesse Alexander Helms, Jr., made invaluable contributions to his community, State, Nation, and the World;</chair>
  <chair>Now, therefore, be it</chair>
  <chair>Resolved, That the Senate has heard with profound sorrow and deep regret the announcement of the death of the Honorable Jesse Alexander Helms, Jr., former Member of the United States Senate.</chair>
  <chair>Resolved, That the Secretary of the Senate communicate these resolutions to the House of Representatives and transmit an enrolled copy thereof to the family of the deceased.</chair>
  <chair>Resolved, That when the Senate adjourns today, it stand in adjournment as a further mark of respect to the memory of the Honorable Jesse Alexander Helms, Jr.</chair>
</record>
