<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1170910800" ordinal="17" title="CONGRATULATING SENATOR THAD COCHRAN ON HIS 10,000TH VOTE">
  <speaking speaker="300078" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I just want to say a word about my friend, Thad Cochran. What a terrific gentleman and fellow legislator he has been over the years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When I have gone to him to work out an appropriations problem, particularly with regard to the 2004 hurricanes we had--and you will recall we had four hurricanes within the span of 6 weeks in Florida, and we so desperately needed that assistance coming in to FEMA--Senator Cochran was there ready to help.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, if I could get Senator Cochran's attention.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator Cochran, I am saying some good things about you, and I just want to say what a gentleman you have been to this Senator, particularly with regard to that time we had such difficulty in Florida during the 2004 hurricanes. When I came to you asking for appropriate help, you were there. And then, lo and behold, the next year is when you had your set of hurricanes, and it was my privilege to try to help return the favor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>You are a real gentleman, and passing the 10,000 vote mark is quite an achievement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I yield the floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300054" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300054" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, let me just say that when the distinguished majority leader is prepared to go forward or the chairman of the Appropriations Committee is ready to proceed to <bill type="hj" number="20">H.J. Res. 20</bill>, I will stand down. But I wish to take this opportunity to also commend my colleague, Senator Cochran.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is truly amazing when someone has been here long enough to cast 10,000 votes. It means they have represented their State well, and it means they are indeed diligent because they are here doing their duty.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have loved working with Senator Cochran. He has been the kind of person who has helped every State when that State needed it. And I hope he has 10,000 more.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
