<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1197997209" ordinal="103" title="CORRECTING THE ENROLLMENT OF H.R. 660">
  <narrative>CORRECTING THE ENROLLMENT OF <bill type="h" number="660">H.R. 660</bill> -- (Senate - December 18, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="15939">S15939</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300080" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of <bill type="sc" number="62">S. Con. Res. 62</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the concurrent resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A concurrent resolution (<bill type="sc" number="62">S. Con. Res. 62</bill>) to correct the enrollment of <bill type="h" number="660">H.R. 660</bill>.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the concurrent resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300080" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the concurrent resolution be agreed to; the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table; and any statements relating thereto be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The concurrent resolution (<bill type="sc" number="62">S. Con. Res. 62</bill>) was agreed to, as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sc" number="62">S. Con. Res. 62</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair> Resolved by the Senate (the House of Representatives concurring), That in the enrollment of <bill type="h" number="660">H.R. 660</bill>, an Act to amend title 18, United States Code, to protect judges, prosecutors, witnesses, victims, and their family members, and for other purposes, the Clerk of the House of Representatives shall strike section 502 of the Act and insert the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;"SEC. 502. MAGISTRATE JUDGES LIFE INSURANCE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(a) In General.--Section 604(a)(5) of title 28, United States Code, is amended by inserting after `hold office during good behavior', the following: `magistrate judges appointed under section 631 of this title,'.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(b) Construction.--For purposes of construing and applying chapter 87 of title 5, United States Code, including any adjustment of insurance rates by regulation or otherwise, the following categories of judicial officers shall be deemed to be judges of the United States as described under section 8701 of title 5, United States Code:&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(1) Magistrate judges appointed under section 631 of title 28, United States Code.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "(2) Magistrate judges retired under section 377 of title 28, United States Code.</chair>
  <chair> "(c) Effective Date.--Subsection (b) and the amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to any payment made on or after the first day of the first applicable pay period beginning on or after the date of enactment of this Act.".&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
