<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1215532805" ordinal="41" title="AMERICAN HOUSING RESCUE AND FORECLOSURE PREVENTION ACT OF 2008">
  <narrative>AMERICAN HOUSING RESCUE AND FORECLOSURE PREVENTION ACT OF 2008 -- (Senate - July 08, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="6448">S6448</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask the Chair to lay before the Senate a message from the House with respect to <bill type="h" number="3221">H.R. 3221</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A message from the House of Representatives to accompany <bill type="h" number="3221">H.R. 3221</bill>, an act to provide needed housing reform, and for other purposes.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I now ask unanimous consent that all postcloture time be considered yielded back, and that the motion to concur be agreed to and the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I move to disagree to the amendments of the House, adding a new title and inserting a new section to the amendment of the Senate to <bill type="h" number="3221">H.R. 3221</bill>, and I send a cloture motion to the desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The cloture motion having been presented under rule XXII, the Chair directs the clerk to read the motion.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>Cloture Motion</narrative>
  <narrative>We, the undersigned Senators, in accordance with the provisions of rule XXII of the Standing Rules of the Senate, hereby move to bring to a close debate on the motion to disagree to the amendments of the House, adding a new title and inserting a new section, to the amendment of the Senate to <bill type="h" number="3221">H.R. 3221</bill>, the Foreclosure Prevention Act.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="CLOTURE MOTION">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the mandatory quorum be waived.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I now move to concur in the amendment of the House adding a new title to the amendment of the Senate to <bill type="h" number="3221">H.R. 3221</bill> with the amendment which is at the desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>The Senator from Nevada [Mr. Reid] proposes an amendment numbered 5067.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the reading of the amendment be dispensed with.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The amendment is as follows:</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask for the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there a sufficient second?</chair>
  <chair>There appears to be a sufficient second.</chair>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I have a second-degree amendment at the desk. I ask for its consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report.</chair>
  <chair>The assistant legislative clerk read as follows:</chair>
  <chair>The Senator from Nevada [Mr. Reid] proposes an amendment numbered 5068 to amendment No. 5067.</chair>
  <chair>The amendment is as follows:</chair>
  <chair>In the amendment, strike "3" and insert "2".</chair>
</record>
