<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1195232402" ordinal="68" title="EXECUTIVE SESSION">
  <narrative>EXECUTIVE SESSION -- (Senate - November 16, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="14654">S14654</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412249" topic="PROTOCOL AMENDING TAX CONVENTION WITH FINLAND">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to executive session to consider Executive Calendar Nos. 3 and 4 en bloc, the Protocol Amending Tax Convention with Denmark and the Protocol Amending Tax Convention with Finland; that the protocols be advanced through their various parliamentary stages up to and including the presentation of the resolutions of ratification, and that there now be a division vote on the resolutions en bloc.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>A division has been requested.</chair>
  <chair>Senators in favor of the resolutions of ratification will rise and stand until counted.</chair>
  <chair>Those opposed will rise and stand until counted.</chair>
  <chair>On a division, two-thirds of the Senators present having voted in the affirmative, the resolutions of ratification are agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolutions of ratification agreed to are as follows:</chair>
  <chair>Resolved, (two-thirds of the Senators present concurring therein),</chair>
  <chair>The Senate advises and consents to the ratification of the Protocol Amending the Convention between the United States of America and the Federal Republic of Germany for the Avoidance of Double Taxation and the Prevention of Fiscal Evasion with Respect to Taxes on Income and Capital and to Certain Other Taxes, signed at Berlin on June 1, 2006 and an Exchange of Notes dated August 17, 2006 (EC-2046) (Treaty Doc. 109-20).</chair>
  <chair>Resolved, (two-thirds of the Senators present concurring therein),</chair>
  <chair>The Senate advises and consents to the ratification of the Protocol Amending the Convention between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of the Republic of Finland for the Avoidance of Double Taxation and the Prevention of Fiscal Evasion with Respect to Taxes on Income and on Capital, signed at Helsinki on May 31, 2006 (Treaty Doc. 109-18).</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412249" topic="PROTOCOL AMENDING TAX CONVENTION WITH FINLAND">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the motions to reconsider be laid on the table, and the President be immediately notified of the Senate's action.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
