<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1182960005" ordinal="14" title="COMPREHENSIVE IMMIGRATION REFORM ACT--Continued">
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="">
    <paragraph>Objection.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="">
    <paragraph>Parliamentary inquiry.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> A parliamentary inquiry is not in order during a quorum call.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400418" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Objection.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will continue with the call of the roll.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400418" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I renew my unanimous consent request that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Objection.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will continue with the call of the roll.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300088" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Objection.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will continue with the call of the roll.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400418" topic="">
    <paragraph>Reserving my right to object.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, he can either object or not object.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400418" topic="">
    <paragraph>I object.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will continue with the call of the roll.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400418" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I remove my objection.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, it is my understanding the distinguished Senator from South Carolina thought they had 5 minutes left; is that right?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would ask unanimous consent that he be allowed to speak, and this would be for debate only. Following the using of 7 minutes, I will take the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to yield my time to other Senators. I will give 1 minute to Senator Vitter and 4 minutes to Senator Sessions.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400418" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, with the majority leader on the floor, I want to use my brief minute to follow up on my inquiries and frustrations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Very soon, we are going to be presented with a brandnew version of this mega-amendment, 400 pages or whatever it is. I would like to be allowed some reasonable opportunity to independently study that mega-amendment without having to depend on other people's summaries, and it is for that reason I made the unanimous consent request that we be in morning business for 5 hours once that brandnew mega-amendment is presented.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>With that explanation and background, given that the distinguished majority leader recognized that right of ours yesterday, when we were allowed to read the old version of the amendment, I would like to make that unanimous consent request.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator has used his 1 minute.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I object. I will use my own time in response to him.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>So as not to use the time of the Senator from South Carolina, Mr. President, there have been a few changes made, but they are very minor. As I indicated to my friend, this is not a new mega-amendment. This is the same amendment which was laid down last night, and people on both sides have had ample opportunity to read this. As I indicated, we would be happy to talk with him and/or his staff, with individual Senators and/or their staff to  indicate where the changes have been made and what the purposes of those were. If that is not sufficient, I don't know how I can be more fair than that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I will now turn it over----</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400418" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent for an additional 30 seconds.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>No, but I just want to make sure it is still under the same time agreement we had before. We add 30 seconds to the time we had given.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400418" topic="">
    <paragraph>I would suggest, through the Chair to the distinguished  majority leader, that I have a real problem with depending on basically the other side's summary of these changes which are being made as we speak. So I would propound a new unanimous consent request, that if we have to do that, if that summary is lacking or inaccurate in any way, that all subsequent votes and actions of the Senate which are agreed to have no effect because we have depended  on the other side's information and it could turn out to have been incomplete or inaccurate.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, again using my time, I object to this, but let me just say that it wasn't a hard piece of reasoning to come up with to object to this.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The reason we are going through this process here is people--mostly on the other side of the aisle because we on this side are satisfied with the bill the way it was written, but mostly on the other side of the aisle and some Democrats--said, OK, if you are going to do this, we will do that. We are doing this to make people happy, so they have an opportunity to talk about this bill some more. This is a process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have really tried to be fair. I have not tried to take advantage of anyone. I have tried to be as candid with people who support the bill as those who oppose the bill, not trying to take advantage of them. The process here in the Senate wasn't invented yesterday; it has been going on for 220 years. I am working my way through the rules, making sure we follow every jot and tittle in these complicated rules, but they are not that complicated. We simply want to work on an issue that is important  to the American people--immigration.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I acknowledge, as has my friend, that the system of immigration in our country is broken. We need to try to fix it, and this is our way of trying to fix it. Perfect? No. Good? Yes. The American people deserve our attention to this problem we have in our country. We have people of good will, Democrats and Republicans, who are trying to do this.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have this occasion, for once in recent memory, where we are working with the President on this side trying to get this done. I have said publicly that I appreciate the President's advocacy on this issue. If we are able to pass this bill, and I hope we can, it will be a shot in the arm for the system, the political system which has been so generous to our country for so many years, and I think people will look and say: You know, those people in Washington who are always yelling and screaming  at each other were able to get something done.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The American people know that whatever we come up with here is not going to solve every problem with immigration, but they also know it will solve many of the problems. The No. 1 problem it is going to solve that the American people want solved is border security. This amendment has $4.4 billion which will go directly to that border.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am, by profession, a trial lawyer, and I know people have the ability to be advocates, as my friend from Louisiana who is speaking--and I see on the floor today my friend from Alabama, whom I have told publicly and privately that I appreciate his advocacy. But my friend from Alabama is a lawyer, just as I am, and we should do everything we can to present our case. Then, when the case is over, we walk out of this shaking hands, as advocates, as Senators, and as friends. So I have no resentment  or ill-will toward anyone who is trying to move this legislation in a way different than I am, but I think the time has come where we have to fish or cut bait, as they say.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I know we still have some speaking time--5 minutes has been allocated.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Under the previous order, the Senator from Alabama is recognized for 4 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300088" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I know Senator Reid has assured people of what is in the bill, but he hasn't read what is in this amendment--neither has any Senator in this body, I suggest. Only a few staffers have, and there have been tremendous errors made already in the previous amendment they offered. And just to say there have been nothing but minor changes is not something I think Senators ought to rely on.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My good friend, Senator Reid, has always been courteous to me, but we disagree on this issue. He said he wants to make people happy. How about making the American people happy? They oppose this bill overwhelmingly, and yet the leadership here continues to use every parliamentary tactic that we have ever used, and new tactics never before used, to limit debate and move this bill to final passage. I object to that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think about our former colleagues, Senator Paul Wellstone and Senator Helms. I wonder how they would feel if it was said: Well, this is unprecedented, we are going to eliminate debate, but I have talked to the leader on the other side, and we two leaders have just decided, since it is bipartisan, we will do that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Make no mistake about what is being done here, Mr. President. There is no dispute whatsoever. Amendments will not be allowed to be voted on that the majority leader does not personally sign off on. The power to control this process is in the majority leader's hands, and he has met with a group of people who are interested in this legislation and they have agreed to control this process. It has never been done like this before in the history of the Senate to eliminate these amendments. It is not  right.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My colleagues, I urge you to understand this is an unprecedented step. It is a step by which the leadership is creating a new tactic that will eliminate the power, the ability of individual Senators to offer amendments and engage in debate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a body of 100. Yes, we have leaders. They have significant authority and we understand that. But that is a limited power and we have always celebrated the great potential of this body that any one Senator can raise an objection, any one Senator can have an amendment voted on.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I tried to offer amendments when the bill was up before. Time and time again they were objected to. Other Senators objected. Why? Because they were able to object to making those amendments pending. Then, when cloture is filed, they are not able to be voted on because they have never been made pending, although they were filed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is not a small matter. I do not think our colleagues understand. I see Senator Specter here. He will stand by himself on an issue in which he believes. There are other Senators here who share those same independent views. We do not need to go down this path. I think it is a big mistake.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would say this: The majority leader said the people want one thing, they want border security. What do we know about this legislation? It does not give us border security. The Congressional Budget Office, our own analysis team, has looked at this bill and concluded in the next 20 years we will have another 8.7 million people in our country illegally. It will only reduce illegal immigration by 13 percent. That is what our own staff, under the majority leader's control, has told us.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Two minutes remain to the Senator from South Carolina.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="">
    <paragraph>I yield the final 2 minutes to Senator Sessions.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Alabama.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300088" topic="">
    <paragraph>I think that is the fundamental thing. I am flabbergasted and amazed our leaders keep telling us this bill is essential to have security. You have to have this amnesty. You have to give up and we will have amnesty. In exchange for that, we will have a legal system that will work in the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But it will not work. That is what they said in 1986. Senator Grassley noted on the floor, people in this body do not even say there will not be another amnesty anymore, as they did in 1986, because they know this bill will not create a legal system. There will be 8.7 million more people in our country illegally and the same group will be here, asking for amnesty again. It is a failed system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let me add one thing. One thing I have learned in this debate, we can make this immigration system lawful and we can make it work. We ought not to be having a 13-percent reduction in illegality, as the Congressional Budget Office says. We can get to 90, 95 percent reduction of illegality. We can create a system of immigration that serves our national interests. It is within our power to do so. This bill will not do it. We must not go forward with it because it will not work.  &lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page:  <bill type="s" number="8534">S8534</bill>]&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/center&gt;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor and reserve the remainder of the time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The majority leader is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I modify my amendment with the changes now at the desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator has that right.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, the amendment is so modified, I understand.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I now ask the amendment be divided as indicated at the desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator has that right and the amendment is divided.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400418" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask for the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from California.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I send an amendment to the desk to division I.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400418" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask for the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the amendment.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent the reading of the amendment be dispensed with.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300054" topic="">
    <paragraph>Parliamentary inquiry.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Let me say, very briefly----</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The majority leader is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I don't want it to go unanswered. This bill, as I mentioned earlier today, is different than what we did before--$4.4 billion goes to the border for security. It is totally different than the last bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Remember, we are at this point because we only got seven Republican votes in the prior vote. Now we have worked together. I was told there were a lot of people on the Republican side, if they had the opportunity to have more amendments, would vote with us. I am confident that will happen. This has worked out extremely well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would say, our work on comprehensive immigration reform has been pretty significant. Due to the man to my right, and Senator Leahy, who is not here, and Senator Kennedy, we have had 36 hearings on immigration since 9/11. That is a lot of hearings. We have had 6 full days of committee action. We have had 59 committee amendments. We have had 21 days of Senate debate since 2006--21 days, not hours. We have had 92 floor amendments. We have worked this thing hard. This is a bill  people should fully understand.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, it is my understanding there is now a unanimous consent in effect that there will be 10 minutes of debate on the first amendment, is that true, equally divided?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from California is not presently under a time limit. However, the Senator from Texas is guaranteed 5 minutes.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>And the Senator from California also 5 minutes?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask I be granted 5 minutes, following the Senator from Texas, to speak on the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Texas.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300054" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I object because the agreement was that Senator Feinstein would speak before me, after which I would have 5 minutes to respond. She would have 5 minutes, I would have 5 minutes to respond.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to that arrangement?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="">
    <paragraph>Reserving the right to object, is it my understanding we will be in morning business or on the amendment?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> We are currently on the measure.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask I be included in the time.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>How much time does the Senator require?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="">
    <paragraph>Five minutes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>We have no objection.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400418" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask for 5 minutes under the same time agreement.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Louisiana.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400418" topic="">
    <paragraph>And for any purposes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="">
    <paragraph>I object.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, shall I proceed?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from California is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I worked with the Senator from Texas, now, 10 years up close. I do not like to oppose her amendment, but in this case I believe I must. This is an issue we debated in many conversations during the process of drafting this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I was opposed to the touchback idea and I am skeptical about it now. However, in the spirit of compromise, we went forward with the touchback that we have in the base bill, specifically in title VI. We included some important safeguards to make sure it is workable.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This amendment from the distinguished Senator from Texas actually does away with this by creating a touchback requirement before people get their full Z visa. What immigrant is going to show up and register for a program if he has to take his chances on leaving the country and coming back in before he gets some kind of immigration status? What immigrant is going to report to deport?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I wager that many, if not most, will simply stay underground and try to keep their heads down for as long as possible. They have built lives here, they have families, they own homes, and they have jobs they want to keep. Very few undocumented immigrants are going to show up for a program that offers no certainty they will actually be able to legalize their status.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What this amendment does is essentially front load the requirement that makes the program unworkable from both an agency and an applicant perspective. Requiring consular officers to steal themselves for a flood of applications, 8 to 10 years down the line, is one thing. Requiring them to gear up for adjudication of this in-person application in the next 2 years following registration is a very different story.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I hope the body will defeat the amendment. Those of us--Senator Craig and I and others--who have worked on the AgJOBS program believe that the agriculture jobs program is the way to go. It is negotiated by farmers, by unions, by growers, and it has a specific requirement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I know the Senator does not touch this specific requirement, but the main problem with the amendment is requiring this touchback so soon, before people have acquired any kind of legal status. They register and then in 2 years, they would have to go and perform this touchback.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We believe it strikes at the heart of the bill and urge a "no" vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Texas.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300054" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I, like my colleague from California, do not remember being on opposite sides on an issue such as this before. But she has brought up a key point that I think it is important for us to address. She says, What immigrant is going to report to deport? What she is asking is, what is the incentive of an illegal immigrant to come forward and say they are illegal and they want to get right with the process to become legal? That is a very important question that many people  in our country have asked. Who is going to do that?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Here is the incentive. First, the secure ID that is provided in the amendment allows exit and reentry. It is a tamperproof ID already, and it does allow the exit to finalize the Z, or Z-A status, and it allows the reentry.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The secure card is issued first. It is temporary until it is finalized because  the final point that is required is that you return home to apply. That is the standardization we must achieve if we are going to avoid the amnesty that would say: Our laws mean nothing. If you come here illegally, eventually you will be able to be regularized without ever going home.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We want to change that whole impression that anyone might have by saying we are going to start today with a process that will apply to every work-eligible adult, and that is you get your secure ID and you have 1 year to do it. Then you must finalize the process outside the country, as everyone will have to, going into the future.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The question is still there: So why wouldn't they stay here and be illegal? Why wouldn't they keep their families and their homes? Here is why. Because when the 3 years is up and the trigger is pulled, because the border security measures have gone into effect--you have the 1 year for people to come forward, say they are illegal, after which they will get their tamperproof card and they must have the "go home" provision then stamped outside the country and they have 2 years to do it. You have  3 years there.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After that 3 years, there is going to be an employer verification system that is going to work. So these people will not be able to go back to their jobs if they have not completed the process. That is the incentive. That is why they will report. That is why they will become legal in the system, because with the employer verification that is a key part of this bill, they will have to have that tamperproof ID stamped that they have been home to apply from outside the country before they come back  in and become regularized and are job eligible.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is going to be the key. The employer verification system will assure that they will not get jobs in this country without that visa that is tamperproof and shows they have been home to do it. It can be done because there is a 3-year period and there will be a constant process to get the people who are illegal working. They will be able to go to the American consulate in their home country. The Secretary can allow exceptions to that for farm workers, if they cannot go home to a faraway place.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is the amendment that will take the amnesty out of this bill and say: Today's standards will be enforced and they will be enforced tomorrow. With this amendment, we can take the amnesty out of this bill and we will have an employer verification system that will assure the incentive is there for people to come forward and know that the law will be enforced.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If we do this, you will not be able to hear people say: There is amnesty in this bill. If my amendment is not passed, then the amnesty tag that has been put on this bill will remain. It is the key issue in the bill for the American people. It is the key issue for the regularization of the 12 million people who are here, and then we will have a guest worker program for new people coming in in the future that will also work with the border security that is established in this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In my opinion, my amendment will make this bill a fully operational bill, because we will then have border security, a tamperproof ID, we will deal with the 12 million, without amnesty but with a regularization process, and it will strengthen the bill for the American people.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The majority leader is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, because of the various activities here on the floor, the Senator from South Carolina and the Senator from Louisiana did not have an opportunity to speak on this amendment. I would be happy to propound a unanimous consent request that they both be allowed to speak for up to 5 minutes each for debate only.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="">
    <paragraph>Reserving the right to object.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Either object or don't object.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="">
    <paragraph>Parliamentary inquiry: Do I not have the right to reserve the right to object? How many rules are we going to change?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The reservation of objection occurs only with the suffrage of the Senate. There is no right to reserve the right to object.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="">
    <paragraph>There are not many rights. I object.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I move to table the amendment and ask for the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there a sufficient second?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>I announce that the Senator from South Dakota (Mr. JOHNSON) is necessarily absent.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300069" topic="">
    <paragraph>The following Senator is necessarily absent: the Senator from Arizona (Mr. MCCAIN).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Are there any other Senators in the Chamber desiring to vote?</chair>
  <narrative>The result was announced--yeas 53, nays 45, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300092" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I sent a second-degree amendment to the desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Clerk will report the amendment.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative Clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that reading of the amendment be dispensed with.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, we are now on division II, which is the amendment offered by Senator Webb, as I understand it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to have everyone have the opportunity to debate this amendment to their heart's content. What I would like to do is ask that we have an hour of time on this admendment equally divided between the proponents and opponents of this admendment, and the debate, of course, would be on this amendment. So I ask unanimous consent that there be an hour of debate on this amendment. As I have indicated, Mr. President, it would be for debate only on this amendment. And I ask that  because it is his amendment Senator Webb, even though he has had an opportunity earlier to speak, would be allowed to speak for up to 10 minutes to start this debate of the 1 hour that I have proposed. So I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to debate this amendment--it will be for debate only--that of the half hour on the majority side, 10 minutes of that be for Senator Webb.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400418" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, reserving my right to object, I would like to ask that my full rights as a Senator be protected with a unanimous consent request also.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, is there an objection to my request?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Regular order is demanded.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400418" topic="">
    <paragraph>There is objection. I would like to propose an alternative unanimous consent request.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, if the present proposal is inadequate, I would be happy to yield for 1 minute to my friend from Louisiana, and I will get the floor when he completes his statement.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400418" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the Majority Leader.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As the majority leader knows, several of us have been continually frustrated about our ability to exercise our rights on the floor of the Senate as duly elected officials. All of our amendments have been shut out. We have not had the opportunity to read this new mega-amendment. The last vote occurred with one copy of that division being at the desk, no copies being on the floor of the Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to protect my rights as an individual Senator and, therefore, I would like to propose a modified UC request incorporating the Senator's suggestions, but offering me 5 minutes within that 1-hour period for any purpose whatsoever.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I appreciate the good faith of my friend, but we cannot do that. I cannot do that. I would have to object to that.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I would be happy to give him whatever amount of time he wishes to debate this amendment. Of course, as he knows, it would be for debate only. He could talk about anything he cared to, but it would be for debate only--5 minutes, 10 minutes, whatever he feels appropriate, within reason, I would be happy to do that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I say to everyone here----</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300088" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, reserving the right to object--</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>As I have said before, I want everyone to have the opportunity to speak. I nor the managers of this legislation are trying to stop people from talking. We have certain rules. They need to be followed, and that is what we are trying to do. So I repeat, I would have no problem with my friend from Louisiana speaking for whatever time he wishes, for debate only, on this amendment. I think that is a reasonable proposal. I would be happy to consider that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. SESSIONS addressed the Chair.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I have the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Nevada.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, does my friend from Louisiana--I thought I heard his voice. Oh, Alabama.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300088" topic="">
    <paragraph>Is the proposal--</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I may have the State wrong, but I had the voice right.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would be happy to yield for a question to my friend--for not a long question--a couple minutes, if he needs that.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Alabama.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300088" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I have a brief question. I thank the majority leader for his courtesy. I had asked, in exchange for agreeing to a process that kept us from working this past weekend, that I would have 2 hours in the debate today set aside. It is in the agreement. But I am hearing that people want to push that into the wee hours of the night, if not into the morning.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask that I have a substantial portion of that before the afternoon is over. What is the status of that negotiation and discussion?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The majority leader is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, what I would say to my friend--and I know he has a lot to say; he has said a lot of things, and I am anxious to hear more--but we would like to be able to dispose of some of these amendments. I would consider if he would like to talk for an hour now--and then I would get the floor after he completes his statement--and it would be for debate only. He can divide the time any way he wants. That is my proposal.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, will the Senator yield for a request?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The majority leader.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="">
    <paragraph>I object.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, here is what we are going to do. I ask unanimous consent that the Senator from Pennsylvania be recognized to make a motion in relation to the Webb amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Following that, I ask unanimous consent that when the vote is completed, Senator Sessions be recognized to speak in morning business until 2:30. He can allocate that time after the vote is concluded until 2:30 any way he sees fit. So I ask unanimous consent. I think it is clear that the time we are spending in morning business be for debate only.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>The final thing: We understand the desire of the Senator from Alabama to be heard. He has, under the terms of the agreement that is already in effect, 2 hours of time. We ask that the time which is going to be used now be counted against the 2 hours he has under the previous order before the Senate.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>The only thing I left out is that at 2:30, when Senator Sessions finishes his remarks, that I be recognized.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask my friends, would it be permissible that my friend from Virginia be recognized for 1 minute prior to the Senator from Pennsylvania?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Before he makes his motion to table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400418" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, reserving the right to object, I would like to ask if my rights on the Senate floor can also be protected in that unanimous consent.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Senator Sessions can do whatever he wants in relation to you because it is for debate only, anyway.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400418" topic="">
    <paragraph>That is not really responding to my request. Again, reserving the right to object, I ask the distinguished majority leader whether my rights as a Senator can also be protected in that unanimous consent request regarding Senator Webb's time by allowing me 1 minute on the floor for any purpose.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>It would have to be for debate only, I say to my friend.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400418" topic="">
    <paragraph>Then I object.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300092" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I move to table the Webb amendment, and I ask for the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there a sufficient second?</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will call the roll.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>I announce that the Senator from New York (Mrs. CLINTON) and the Senator from South Dakota (Mr. JOHNSON) are necessarily absent.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300069" topic="">
    <paragraph>The following Senator is necessarily absent: the Senator from Arizona (Mr. MCCAIN).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Are there any other Senators in the Chamber desiring to vote?</chair>
  <narrative>The result was announced--yeas 79, nays 18, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I move to reconsider the vote and I move to lay that motion on the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The motion to lay on the table was agreed to.</narrative>
</record>
