<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1195059601" ordinal="57" title="RECOGNIZING AND THANKING MILITARY FAMILIES">
  <narrative>RECOGNIZING AND THANKING MILITARY FAMILIES -- (Senate - November 14, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="14418">S14418</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate now proceed to the consideration of <bill type="sr" number="378">S. Res. 378</bill>, which was submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="378">S. Res. 378</bill>) recognizing and thanking all military families for the tremendous sacrifices and contributions they have made to the Nation.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="378">S. Res. 378</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="378">S. Res. 378</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas there are currently more than 3,000,000 immediate family members of individuals serving in the Armed Forces;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas these family members bear the most immediate and profound burden of the absence of their loved ones during the performance of their duties;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas these families have been the bedrock of support and strength for our Nation's Armed Forces for over 230 years;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas military families serve this country with an equal amount of dedication and patriotism as their loved ones who are fighting for the United States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the families of servicemembers--whether in the regular components of the Armed Forces, the Reserve, or the National Guard--feel enormous amounts of pride, love, and trepidation during the absence of their loved ones;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas it is essential that the Nation recognize the contributions made by military families and celebrate their strength; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Senate stands in humble respect of the sacrifice made by our military families: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) honors the families of members of the Armed Forces and recognizes that they too share in the burden of protecting the Nation;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) urges the people of the United States to join with the Senate in thanking military families for their tremendous sacrifice on behalf of the Nation; and</chair>
  <chair> (3) recognizes with great appreciation the contributions made by military families in providing the essential personal support that our Nation's warriors need. &lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
