<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1196787602" ordinal="43" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <narrative>AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET -- (Senate - December 04, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="14745">S14745</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400619" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON STATE, LOCAL, AND PRIVATE SECTOR PREPAREDNESS AND INTEGRATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Ad Hoc Subcommittee on State, Local, and Private Sector Preparedness and Integration of the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, December 4, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. in order to conduct a hearing entitled, "The New Madrid Seismic Zone: Whose Fault Is It Anyway?"</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400619" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, December 4, 2007, at 2:30 p.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building, for the purposes of conducting a hearing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="1581">S. 1581</bill>, Federal Ocean Acidification Research and Monitoring Act of 2007; <bill type="s" number="2307">S. 2307</bill>, Global Change Research Improvement Act of 2007; <bill type="s" number="2355">S. 2355</bill>, Climate Change Adaptation Act of 2007; <bill type="s" number="2332">S. 2332</bill>, Media Ownership Act of 2007; Nominations for Promotion in U.S. Coast Guard (PN 1039 and PN 1055); and Nominations for Promotion in the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Commission Corps (PN 1014).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400619" topic="COMMITTEE ON HEALTH, EDUCATION, LABOR, AND PENSIONS.">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate in order to conduct a hearing entitled "Developing a Comprehensive Response to Food Safety" on Tuesday, December 4, 2007, at 10:30 a.m. in SD-430.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400619" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet during the session of the  Senate, in order to conduct a hearing entitled "Electronic Prescribing of Controlled Substances: Addressing Health Care and Law Enforcement Priorities" on Tuesday, December 4, 2007, at 10 a.m. in room SD-226 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Panel I: Joseph T. Rannazzisi, Deputy Assistant Administrator, Drug Enforcement Administration, Office of Diversion Control, Alexandria, VA and Tony Trenkle, Director, Office of E-Health Standards and Services, Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services, Baltimore, MD;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Panel II: Laura Adams, President and CEO, Rhode Island Quality Institute, Providence, RI; Kevin Hutchinson, CEO, Sure Scripts, Alexandria, VA; David Miller, Chief Security Officer, Covisint, Detroit, MI; and Mike A. Podgurski, R.Ph., Vice President, Pharmacy Services, Rite Aid Corporation, Camp Hill, PA.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400619" topic="PERMANENT SUBCOMMITTEE ON INVESTIGATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations of the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, December 4, 2007, at 9:30 a.m., in order to conduct a hearing entitled, "Credit Card Practices: Unfair Interest Rate Increases."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
