<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1201280402" ordinal="41" title="CONGRATULATING THE UNIVERSITY OF SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA WOMEN'S SOCCER TEAM">
  <narrative>CONGRATULATING THE UNIVERSITY OF SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA WOMEN'S SOCCER TEAM -- (Senate - January 25, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="367">S367</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the consideration of <bill type="sr" number="428">S. Res. 428</bill>, submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="428">S. Res. 428</bill>) congratulating the University of Southern California women's soccer team on winning the 2007 National Collegiate Athletic Association Division I Championship.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412242" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution and preamble be agreed to en bloc, the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table, with no intervention action, and that any statements relating to the resolution be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="428">S. Res. 428</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="428">S. Res. 428</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas the University of Southern California (USC) Trojans won the 2007 National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA) Women's Soccer Championship by a 2-0 victory over the Florida State University Seminoles on December 9, 2007, at the Aggie Soccer Complex in College Station, Texas;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the USC Trojans, in the 2007 season, had a 20-3-2 overall record, with 13 goals allowed, 15 shutouts, and a perfect 6-0 mark in the NCAA Women's Soccer Tournament, including 5 shutouts;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the USC Trojans won a Division I women's soccer title for the first time in school history in 2007;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Marihelen Tomer and Janessa Currier each scored a goal in the championship game;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Amy Rodriguez was named the tournament's Most Outstanding Offensive Player, Kristin Olsen was named the tournament's Most Outstanding Defensive Player, and Marihelen Tomer, Kasey Johnson, and Janessa Currier were named to the All-Tournament Team;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Ashley Nick and Kristin Olsen earned All-American Honors for their exceptional contributions during the 2007 season; and</chair>
  <chair>Whereas the 2007 USC women's soccer team members are players Kristin Olsen, Brittany Massro, Nini Loucks, Alyssa D&#xE1;vila, Laura McKee, Kat Stolpa, Lauren Brown, Shannon Lacy, Ashli Sandoval, Jamie Petrossi, Stacey Strong, Karter Haug, Amy Rodriguez, Kasey Johnson, Jacquelyn Johnston, Janessa Currier, Ashley Nick, Marihelen Tomer, Meagan Holmes, Megan Ohai, Kelley Finch, Briana Ovbude, Amy Massey, Kate Gong, and Monique Gaxiola, and coaches Ali Khosroshahin, Harold Warren, Laura Janke, Alicia  Lloyd, and Rosa Anna Tantillo: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved, That the Senate congratulates the University of Southern California women's soccer team for winning the 2007 National Collegiate Athletic Association Division I Championship. &lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
