<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1194973204" ordinal="58" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <narrative>AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET -- (Senate - November 13, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="14348">S14348</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, November 13, 2007, at 2:30 p.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building, in order to conduct a hearing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At this hearing, the Committee will examine the accuracy of the Federal Trade Commission's tar and nicotine cigarette rating system and the marketing claims of cigarette companies based on these ratings.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND NATURAL RESOURCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, November 13, 2007, at 2:30 p.m., in room  SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building, in order to conduct a hearing entitled "The Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977: Policy Issues Thirty Years Later."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENVIRONMENT AND PUBLIC WORKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Environment and Public Works be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, November 13, 2007, at 11 a.m. in room 406 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building in order to conduct a hearing entitled, "Legislative Hearing on America's Climate Security Act of 2007, <bill type="s" number="2191">S. 2191</bill>."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, November 13, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. in order to conduct a hearing on climate change.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet, during the session of the Senate, in order to conduct a hearing entitled "Exploring the Scope of Public Performance Rights" on Tuesday, November 13, 2007. The hearing will commence at 9:30 a.m. in room 226 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Lyle Lovett, Singer/Songwriter, Nashville, TN; Alice Peacock, Singer/Songwriter, Chicago, IL; Steven W. Newberry, President and CEO, Commonwealth Broadcasting Corporation, Glasgow, KY; and Dan DeVany, Vice President and General Manager, WETA, Arlington, VA.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="COMMITTEE ON SMALL BUSINESS AND ENTREPRENEURSHIP">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate in order to conduct a hearing entitled "SBA Lender Oversight: Preventing Loan Fraud and Improving Regulation of Lenders," on Tuesday, November 13, 2007, beginning at 10 a.m., in room 428A of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="SELECT COMMITTEE ON INTELLIGENCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Select Committee on Intelligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on November 13, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. in order to conduct an open hearing on Congressional oversight.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300001" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON OVERSIGHT OF GOVERNMENT MANAGEMENT, THE FEDERAL WORKFORCE, AND THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs' Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, November 13, 2007, at 10 a.m. in order to conduct a hearing entitled, "Human Capital Needs of the U.S. Customs and Border Protection `One Face at the Border' Initiative."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
