<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1182960005" ordinal="53" title="COMMENDING THE OREGON STATE UNIVERSITY BASEBALL TEAM">
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of <bill type="sr" number="259">S. Res. 259</bill>, submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300100" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, just about a year ago, Senator SMITH and I came down to the floor of the Senate to take a few moments to talk about the Oregon State University baseball team, which had just won its first College World Series national championship out in Omaha, NE.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I can't tell you how happy I am to be standing here on the floor of the Senate 1 year later to applaud the team's defense of that title.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a tough, determined baseball team. When most folks counted them out, they didn't give up. After finishing 6th in the Pac-10, they squeaked their way into the post-season and never looked back.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On the road and at home, the Oregon State squad was virtually unstoppable, winning their last 10 games. In fact, the team trailed in just one of the 45 innings it played in Omaha and it was the first team to ever win 4 College World Series games by 6 or more runs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Beavers are the first back-to-back champions since Louisiana State University accomplished the feat back in 1996-97 and the first "cold-weather" state repeat champions ever.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is a proud day for the players and coaches on the Oregon State team. It is a proud day for the University. And it is a proud day for all Oregonians.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, with Senator SMITH as my cosponsor, I have therefore submitted a resolution commending the Oregon State University baseball team for winning the 2007 College World Series.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table, and any statements be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
