<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1201712403" ordinal="48" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <narrative>AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET -- (Senate - January 30, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="502">S502</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND NATURAL RESOURCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate in order to conduct a business meeting on Wednesday, January 30, 2008, at 11:30 a.m., in room SD366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building. At this mark-up, the Committee will consider pending bills on its shortlist of agenda items.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENVIRONMENT AND PUBLIC WORKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Environment and Public Works be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, January 30, 2008 at 10 a.m., in Room 406 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building in order to hold a hearing entitled, "Examining Threats and Protections for the Polar Bear."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="COMMITTEE ON FINANCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Finance be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, January 30, 2008, at 10 a.m., in room 215 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building, in order to conduct a hearing entitled "Private Fee for Service Plans in Medicare Advantage: A Closer Look."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="COMMITTEE ON FINANCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Finance be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, January 30, 2008, at 2:30 p.m., in room 215 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building, in order to consider an original bill entitled, "The Economic Stimulus Act of 2008"; and to consider changes to the Rules of Procedure of the Committee on Finance.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, January 30, 2008, at 11 a.m. in order to hold a nomination hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, January 30, 2008, at 3:30 p.m. in order to hold an intelligence briefing on Afghanistan.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate, in order to conduct a hearing entitled "Oversight of the U.S. Department of Justice" on Wednesday, January 30, 2008 at 10 a.m. in room SH-216 of the Hart Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Honorable Michael B. Mukasey, Attorney General of the United States, Department of Justice, Washington, DC.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="COMMITTEE ON SMALL BUSINESS AND ENTREPRENEURSHIP">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate in order to conduct a hearing entitled "Holding the Small Business Administration Accountable: Women's Contracting and Lender Oversight," on Wednesday, January 30, 2008, beginning at 10 a.m., in room 428A of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>I suggest the absence of a quorum.</chair>
</record>
