<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1226941203" ordinal="30" title="REMEMBERING DOROTHY GREEN">
  <narrative>REMEMBERING DOROTHY GREEN -- (Senate - November 17, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="10555">S10555</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300011" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I am honored to remember a great American activist, environmental leader, mentor, and woman of service--Dorothy Green, who passed away on October 13, 2008, at the age of 79.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dorothy's career as a leading environmental activist for clean and sound water policy spanned three decades. She was well known for her self-taught expertise on clean oceans and responsible water management. She also founded several well-known organizations that continue to make an impact on California's environment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dorothy Green was born in Detroit to Polish immigrants in 1929. She moved to California where she graduated from the University of California, Berkley, with a degree in music. She married her husband Jacob in 1951. For many years, Dorothy stayed home and took care of her children. In 1962, she began dedicating her life to volunteerism with her involvement in the Exceptional Children's Foundation, committed to helping children with developmental disabilities--like her son, Hershel.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dorothy began advocating for water quality in 1972 when she volunteered in a campaign to establish the California Coastal Commission. From there, Dorothy became president of the Los Angeles League of Conservation Voters, where she focused primarily on sewage treatment. However, Dorothy is best known for forming one of the largest, nonprofit environmental groups in Los Angeles in 1985, Heal the Bay. Heal the Bay has grown to 15,000 members and fights to protect coastal waters, clean up beaches,  and reports on the  water quality conditions of over 500 California beaches through its annual Beach Report Card.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dorothy's work did not stop with Heal the Bay. She went on to found the Los Angeles and San Gabriel Rivers Watershed Council to preserve, restore, and enhance the economic, social, and environmental aspects of the local watersheds. She also went on to help establish the Public Officials for Water and Environmental Reform and the California Water Impact Network--both dedicated to water sustainability.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Even to the very last days of her life, when she was bedridden and under hospice care, Dorothy fought for positive change. She wrote an editorial for the Los Angeles Times, pleading for sensible water policy, and she even provided specific guidance on how to obtain it. Dorothy inspired others to take action on environmental issues through a life of dedicated leadership and service.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Green is survived by three sons, Joshua, Avrom and Herschel; two brothers, Morris and Gerald; and three granddaughters, Jessica, Katherine and Tara. I send my deepest condolences to them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our Nation lost an amazing environmental activist with the passing of Dorothy Green, but her legacy to the State of California and promotion of clean ocean water will live on.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
