<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1168966803" ordinal="39" title="NOTICES OF HEARINGS/MEETINGS">
  <speaking speaker="300060" topic="COMMITTEE ON SMALL BUSINESS AND ENTREPRENEURSHIP">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to inform the Members of the Committee that the Committee will hold an organizational meeting on Thursday, January 18, 2007 at 9 a.m. in Russell 428A.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND NATURAL RESOURCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to announce for the information of the Senate and the public that an oversight hearing has been scheduled before the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The hearing will be held on Wednesday, January 24, 2007 at 9:45 a.m. in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of this hearing is to receive testimony on analysis recently completed by the Energy Information Administration, Energy Market and Economic Impacts of a Proposal to Reduce Greenhouse Gas Intensity with a Cap and Trade System.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of the limited time available for the hearing, witnesses may testify by invitation only. However, those wishing to submit written testimony for the hearing record should send two copies of their testimony to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, United States Senate, Washington, DC 20510-6150.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For further information, please contact Jonathan Black (202) 224-6722 or Amanda Kelly at (202) 224-6836.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to announce for the information of the Senate and the public that an oversight hearing has been scheduled before the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The hearing will be held on Tuesday, January 30, 2007, at 10 a.m. in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the hearing is to consider the status of Federal land management agencies' efforts to contain the costs of their wildfire suppression activities and to consider recent independent reviews of and recommendations for those efforts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of the limited time available for the hearing, witnesses may testify by invitation only. However, those wishing to submit written testimony for the hearing record should send two copies of their testimony to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, United States Senate, Washington, DC 20510-6150.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For further information, please contact Scott Miller at 202-224-5488 or Amanda Kelly at 202-224-6836.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to announce for the information of the Senate and the public that an oversight hearing has been scheduled before the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The hearing will be held on Thursday, February 8, 2007, at 9:30 a.m. in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of this hearing is to receive testimony on issues relating to labor, immigration, law enforcement, and economic conditions in the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana islands.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Because of the limited time available for the hearing, witnesses may testify by invitation only. However, those wishing to submit written testimony for the hearing record should send two copies of their testimony to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, United States Senate, Washington, DC 20510-6150.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For further information, please contact Al Stayman (202) 224-7865 or Amanda Kelly at (202) 224-6836.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
