<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1204909201" ordinal="50" title="TEMPORARILY EXTENDING THE PROGRAMS UNDER THE HIGHER EDUCATION ACT OF 1965">
  <narrative>TEMPORARILY EXTENDING THE PROGRAMS UNDER THE HIGHER EDUCATION ACT OF 1965 -- (Senate - March 07, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="1782">S1782</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I now ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of <bill type="s" number="2733">S. 2733</bill>, introduced earlier today by Senator Kennedy.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the bill by title.</chair>
  <chair>The assistant legislative clerk read as follows:</chair>
  <chair>A bill (<bill type="s" number="2733">S. 2733</bill>) to temporarily extend the programs under the Higher Education Act of 1965.</chair>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the bill.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the bill be read three times and passed, the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table, with no intervening action or debate, and any statements related to the bill be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The bill (<bill type="s" number="2733">S. 2733</bill>) was ordered to be engrossed for a third reading, was read the third time, and passed, as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="s" number="2733">S. 2733</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair> Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This Act may be cited as the "Higher Education Extension Act of 2008".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 2. EXTENSION OF PROGRAMS.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Section 2(a) of the Higher Education Extension Act of 2005 (Public Law 109-81; 20 U.S.C. 1001 note) is amended by striking "March 31, 2008" and inserting "April 30, 2008".&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SEC. 3. RULE OF CONSTRUCTION.</chair>
  <chair> Nothing in this Act, or in the Higher Education Extension Act of 2005 as amended by this Act, shall be construed to limit or otherwise alter the authorizations of appropriations for, or the durations of, programs contained in the amendments made by the Higher Education Reconciliation Act of 2005 (Public Law 109-171) or by the College Cost Reduction and Access Act (Public Law 110-84) to the provisions of the Higher Education Act of 1965 and the Taxpayer-Teacher Protection Act of 2004. &lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
