<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1204218002" ordinal="46" title="STAR PRINT--S. 22">
  <narrative>STAR PRINT--S. 22 -- (Senate - February 28, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="1390">S1390</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412246" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that <bill type="s" number="22">S. 22</bill> be star printed with the changes at the desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair> The Chair, on behalf of the Vice President, pursuant to Public Law 81-754, as amended by Public Law 93-536 and Public Law 100-365, appoints the Senator from Maryland, Mr. Cardin, to the National Historical Publications and Records commission, vice the Senator from Connecticut (Mr. Dodd).</chair>
  <chair>The Chair, on behalf of the Republican leader, pursuant to the provisions of Public Law 110-161, appoints the following individuals to serve as members of the National Commission on Children and Disasters: Ernie Allen of Virginia and Mary Alneta Carlson of Alaska.</chair>
  <chair>The Chair announces, on behalf of the Republican leader, pursuant to the provisions of <bill type="sr" number="105">S. Res. 105</bill>, adopted April 13, 1989, as amended by <bill type="sr" number="149">S. Res. 149</bill>, adopted October 5, 1993, as amended by Public Law 105-275, adopted October 21, 1998, further amended by <bill type="sr" number="75">S. Res. 75</bill>, adopted March 25, 1999, amended by <bill type="sr" number="383">S. Res. 383</bill>, adopted October 27, 2000, and amended by <bill type="sr" number="355">S. Res. 355</bill>, adopted November 13, 2002, and further amended by <bill type="sr" number="480">S. Res. 480</bill>, adopted November 21, 2004, the appointment of the following Senators  as members of the Senate National Security Working Group for the 110th Congress: the Senator from Minnesota, Mr. Coleman, as cochairman and the Senator from Ohio, Mr. Voinovich.</chair>
</record>
