<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1189008002" ordinal="44" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <narrative>AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET -- (Senate - September 05, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="11125">S11125</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300081" topic="COMMITTEE ON FOREIGN RELATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Relations be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, September 5, 2007, at 10 a.m. to hold a nomination hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300081" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet in order to conduct a hearing entitled "The 50th Anniversary of the Civil Rights Act of 1957 and its Continuing Importance" on Wednesday, September 5, 2007, at 10 a.m. in the Dirksen Senate Office Building, room 226.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Panel I: The Honorable John Lewis, United States Representative [D-GA-5th].</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Panel II: Wade Henderson, President and CEO, Leadership Conference on Civil Rights, Washington, DC; Theodore Shaw, Director-Counsel and President, NAACP Legal Defense and Education Fund, Inc., Washington, DC; Peter Zamora, Washington, DC Regional Counsel, Mexican American Legal Defense and Educational Fund [MALDEF], Washington, DC; Gail Heriot, Commissioner, United States Commission on Civil Rights, Professor of Law, University of California at San Diego, San Diego, CA; Robert P. Moses, President  The Algebra Project, Inc., Cambridge, MA; Robert H. Driscoll, Partner, Alston &amp; Bird, Washington, DC.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300081" topic="SPECIAL COMMITTEE ON AGING">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Special Committee on Aging be authorized to meet today Wednesday, September 5, 2007, from 2 p.m.-4 p.m. in SD-628 for the purpose of conducting a hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
