<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1197997209" ordinal="94" title="CONDEMNING THE KIDNAPPING OF THREE UNITED STATES CITIZENS BY THE REVOLUTIONARY ARMED FORCES OF COLOMBIA">
  <narrative>CONDEMNING THE KIDNAPPING OF THREE UNITED STATES CITIZENS BY THE REVOLUTIONARY ARMED FORCES OF COLOMBIA -- (Senate - December 18, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="15936">S15936</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300080" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Foreign Relations Committee be discharged from further consideration of <bill type="sc" number="53">S. Con. Res. 53</bill> and the Senate then proceed to its immediate consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will report the concurrent resolution by title.</narrative>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A concurrent resolution (<bill type="sc" number="53">S. Con. Res. 53</bill>) condemning the kidnapping and hostage-taking of 3 United States citizens for over 4 years by the Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia (FARC), and demanding their immediate and unconditional release.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the concurrent resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300080" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the concurrent resolution be agreed to; the amendment to the preamble be agreed to; the preamble, as amended, be agreed to; the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table en bloc; and any statements relating thereto be printed in the Record without further intervening action or debate.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The concurrent resolution (<bill type="sc" number="53">S. Con. Res. 53</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The amendment (No. 3881) was agreed to, as follows:</chair>
  <chair>Strike "on July 25, 2003" and all that follows in the eighth whereas clause of the preamble and insert "in a videotape seized by the Government of Colombia and aired on November 30, 2007;".</chair>
  <chair>The premable, as amended, was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The concurrent resolution, with its preamble, as amended, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sc" number="53">S. Con. Res. 53</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas the Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia (FARC) is designated as a foreign terrorist organization by the Department of State;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the FARC utilizes kidnappings for ransom, extortion, and the drug trade to finance its activities;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the FARC has consistently committed atrocities against citizens of both Colombia and the United States, kidnapped at least 36 United States citizens since 1980, and killed 10 United States citizens;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas an aircraft carrying United States citizens crashed over territory controlled by the FARC on February 13, 2003;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Keith Stansell, Thomas Howes, and Marc Gonsalves, 3 United States citizens on the aircraft, were taken hostage by the FARC on February 13, 2003;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the FARC murdered Tom Janis, another United States citizen on the downed aircraft;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas 3 United States citizens on a subsequent search mission also lost their lives;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the 3 hostages were last shown alive in a videotape seized by the Government of Colombia and aired on November 30, 2007;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas a police officer from Colombia who escaped from the FARC in April 2007 claims he saw the 3 United States hostages alive in April 2007;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas at least 50 FARC leaders have been indicted in the United States for drug trafficking; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas Ricardo Palmera, the most senior FARC leader to be tried in the United States, was convicted of conspiring to take the United States citizens hostage in Colombia: Now, therefore, be it&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Resolved by the Senate (the House of Representatives concurring), That Congress--&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) condemns the kidnappings of Keith Stansell, Thomas Howes, and Marc Gonsalves by the Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia (FARC) and calls for their immediate and unconditional release;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (2) condemns the FARC for holding these hostages for more than 4 years and demands to know their health and status;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (3) condemns the FARC for the murder of Tom Janis;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (4) condemns the FARC for its use of kidnapping for ransom, extortion, and drug trafficking and for supporting and spreading terror within Colombia;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (5) expresses sympathy to the relatives of the hostages who have been unsure of the fates of their family members for more than 4 years;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (6) reconfirms that the United States Government does not make concessions to terrorists; and</chair>
  <chair> (7) reiterates that the United States Government supports efforts to secure the safe return of the hostages to the United States.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
