<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1173974406" ordinal="48" title="SENATE RESOLUTION 110--EXPRESSING THE SENSE OF THE SENATE REGARDING THE 30TH ANNIVERSARY OF ASEAN-UNITED STATES DIALOGUE AND RELATIONSHIP">
  <speaking speaker="300070" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, since its inception in 1967, the Association of Southeast Asian Nations has been a trusted friend of the United States. The original five-member countries of Indonesia, Malaysia, Philippines, Singapore and Thailand, were joined by Brunei Darussalam in 1984. Beginning in the late 1960s, U.S. officials today continue to interact with ASEAN regarding mutual interests in East and Southeast Asia. Vietnam, Laos, Burma and Cambodia joined ASEAN after 1994.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The level of intersects between ASEAN and the United States is immense, including student exchanges, business and trade, and security cooperation. ASEAN is the third largest export destination of American products.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is important to note that ASEAN is continually changing, with the pursuit of economic integration. As noted by the ASEAN Secretariat, ASEAN officials hope to create "a stable, prosperous and highly competitive ASEAN economic region in which there is a free flow of goods, services and investment and a freer flow of capital, equitable, economic development and reduced poverty and socio-economic disparities in year 2020." Last year alone, there were over 500 meetings of ASEAN officials--it  is a vibrant regional structure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Committed to promoting regional peace and harmony, there has been no armed confrontation among ASEAN member nations, since ASEAN's beginning. An important part of ASEAN's future security lies in the development of a regional energy security strategy. This endeavor is well underway, and the United States looks forward to future dialogue on ways in which meaningful cooperation can occur.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Continued collaboration between ASEAN, the United States and the World Health Organization on addressing major disease challenges, such as Avian influenza is of the essence. All involved must act with vigilance and in a timely way.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While ASEAN and the United States have shared appreciation for the challenges of terrorism, our relationship is far more complex. For the benefit of my colleagues, I point to recent remarks conveyed to me by Singapore's esteemed Ambassador-at-Large, Tommy Koh, who wrote "ASEAN's relationship with the U.S. is its most important relationship. It is a mutually beneficial relationship. However, ASEAN often feels that it has been treated by the U.S. with benign neglect and viewed solely through the  prism of terrorism. We hope, on this 30th anniversary year of the U.S.-ASEAN dialogue relationship, that the U.S. will develop a coherent strategy and policy to engage ASEAN, upgrade our priority and make the U.S. the best friend of ASEAN."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Full implementation of the ASEAN-United States Enhanced Partnership and appointment of the U.S. Ambassador for ASEAN Affairs are important steps in growing this important bilateral relationship.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am pleased to introduce this resolution commemorating the 30th anniversary of the U.S.-ASEAN dialogue. It is a message of reaffirmation and deep appreciation by the United States Senate. We look forward to an even closer future partnership on many fronts, yielding mutual benefit for the people of ASEAN and the United States.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
