<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1209398404" ordinal="32" title="HONORING THE SENIORS' RESOURCE CENTER">
  <narrative>HONORING THE SENIORS' RESOURCE CENTER -- (Senate - April 28, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="3440">S3440</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400619" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I wish to honor the 30th anniversary of the Seniors' Resource Center, SRC, in Jefferson County, CO. For three decades, the SRC has delivered critical services to the aging and disabled communities in the Denver metropolitan area through a variety of innovative programs. I salute Jon Zabawa, president and CEO of SRC, his staff, and the many volunteers who have made the Center what it is today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>From its inception as an extension of the Jefferson County Retired and Senior Volunteer Program, tasked with providing transportation assistance to the elderly, SRC has consistently received awards and acknowledgements for its terrific services. The National Council on Aging has named SRC one of its five Best Practices Organizations. The National Senior Citizen Education and Research Center has recognized SRC for "outstanding performance in the Senior Aide Program and in enrollment, budget management,  and placement." In 2002, SRC was the Colorado Association of Transit Agencies' Mid Transportation System of the Year. In 2004, they were the winners of the Community Transportation Association of America and the Beverly Foundation's "Search for Innovation in Senior Transportation Award." Most recently, the center won the first-ever Non-Profit of the Year Award from the West Chamber of Commerce.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over the last 30 years, SRC has worked to steadily improve and expand its programs. The organization has grown beyond Jefferson County to 10 other metropolitan counties. Today, more than 100,000 Colorado citizens have access to SRC's services, including adult day and respite services, in-home care, transportation, care management, referrals to community partners, and job training programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In the year 2010, there will be more than 770,000 seniors age 60 and over in Colorado, making organizations such as the SRC even more vital to the health of our communities. I am very proud of SRC's work, and I look forward to several more decades of their service to the community.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
