<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1172682003" ordinal="12" title="IMPROVING AMERICA'S SECURITY ACT OF 2007">
  <chair> Under the previous order, the Senate will now proceed to the consideration of <bill type="s" number="4">S. 4</bill>, which the clerk will report.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="TITLE XIII--MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, with the authority of the Homeland Security and the Governmental Affairs Committee--that is, the consent of a majority of the Members--I now withdraw the committee-reported substitute amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator has that right. The amendment is withdrawn.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I send a substitute amendment to the desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the reading of the amendment be dispensed with.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <narrative>(The amendment is printed in today's Record under "Text of Amendments.")</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, the substitute I have just offered encompasses the provisions of <bill type="s" number="4">S. 4</bill>, also legislation on surface transportation security, aviation security, and rail security from the Commerce Committee, as well as transit security legislation from the Banking Committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As I said yesterday, I deeply appreciate, as does the distinguished Republican leader, the work done by the two committee managers. Senator Lieberman and Senator Collins have worked together for a number of years, and they work well together. This is an extremely important piece of legislation, and so we ask Members if there is something about the bill that has just been laid down that they don't like, they should come and try to change it and not wait around because they will  be disappointed. We have to move through this bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have been told there are a number of amendments people have to offer, and we want them to do that. I asked the Democratic manager, Chairman Lieberman, if people offer amendments, to have a reasonable debate. We are not going to mess around here for a long time. With appropriate debate, Senator Lieberman is going to move to table if it is something we don't like, and I think it is important that Members know that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have been told there are a lot of amendments on both sides. It is our goal to finish this legislation as soon as we can next week. That is going to be difficult. We could have some late nights, and as I indicated this morning, we might have to work into Friday sometime. Monday night, I hope we can stack votes so that we have a number of votes. As I have indicated, we will not have votes starting before 5:30, but I hope we can have a number of votes at 5:30 so we can dispose of them that night.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is what we do. We are legislating now, and I look forward to a good piece of legislation when we finish.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300072" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, let me echo the remarks of the majority leader. We have a number of amendments on this side, and we are prepared to offer them in the next few hours. I believe the first amendment is going to come from the Democratic side. Senator Collins is either here or on her way, and she is certainly going to manage the bill on our side, but then we will follow the Democratic amendment with an amendment on our side.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also want to remind everyone that at 2 p.m. this afternoon the Transportation Security Administration will hold an all-Members briefing related to the provisions of <bill type="s" number="4">S. 4</bill>, the bill we are now discussing, which will be pending today. A notice was sent to all offices, and Senators should be made aware that this briefing will be held in <bill type="s" number="407">S407</bill> of the Capitol.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would also say this: We are going to alternate back and forth. If there is not a Democrat here, a Republican will offer two amendments in a row, and vice versa. In other words, we need expedition. There are a number of amendments, and we are not going to wait while somebody is coming from their office to offer an amendment. If somebody is here ahead of someone, then they will proceed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our first amendment, if she is here on time, will be from Senator Feinstein; otherwise, Senator Collins, I understand, has an amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, while the two leaders are here, I want to thank Senator Reid for designating this urgent legislation which would implement the previously unimplemented or inadequately implemented recommendations of the 9/11 Commission. I also thank Senator McConnell, the Republican leader, for his cooperation and consent to moving this forward quickly on the Senate floor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bipartisan cooperation, obviously, is justified by the subject matter, homeland security, and in that regard I want to thank, again, Senator Collins. We switched titles in this session of Congress, but as I said to her when that happened, nothing else will change but our titles. She has been a wonderful partner and coworker on this measure once again, and it is in that spirit that we invite amendments, as Senator Reid said, from our colleagues who may think that, as good  as the bill is, it could be better, and we urge them to come forward quickly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In our committee, only one amendment was divided on a party-line vote. The rest were totally nonpartisan, and I hope that is generally the way things will go on the Senate floor as we consider the amendments brought forth.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Yesterday, to expedite matters, Senator Collins and I both made our opening statements, so we do not have those opening statements now. Therefore, we look forward to the Senator from California coming to the floor as soon as she can to offer an amendment, which I note will concern visa waiver sections of the measure. Senator Collins has another amendment which we will go to if Senator Feinstein does not come soon.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank the Chair and, for the moment, I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, on behalf of the Senator from California, Mrs. Feinstein, I call up amendment No. 271.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the reading of the amendment be dispensed with.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today to voice my concern about the efforts to expand the Visa Waiver Program in the 9/11 commission report bill and to offer an amendment that will cap the unlimited expansion of this program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe the bill as offered on the floor will make us less safe, not more safe with respect to this huge program called Visa Waiver.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill would allow the Department of Homeland Security and the Department of State to expand the Visa Waiver Program without limits. My amendment would limit this discretion based on a 10 percent visa refusal rate or on the actual visa overstay rate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Visa Waiver Program provides an extraordinary exception to our immigration laws. It allows the citizens of 27 nations to visit this country by merely showing up on the day of departure with a passport from their home country. In 2004, the State Department reported that 15.6 million people came to this country as part of this program. I am told that in 2005, unofficially, the number was at least 15.5 million and in 2006, the number was at least 15.6 million.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have no way of knowing how many left because we do not have an exit system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill on the floor today changes the Visa Waiver Program in a number of key ways.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, it adds some good security measures, such as the expedited reporting of lost and stolen travel documents; and the exchange of information on terrorist watchlist. It also authorizes the Department of Homeland Security to develop an electronic travel authorization program so that all persons entering the U.S. will have to apply for clearance to enter the U.S. in advance of their trip. And it requires the Department of Homeland Security to develop a system to track all the foreign visitors  who leave the U.S. via our airports--but not our seaports or land ports. This has been an unmet goal, however, year after year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I welcome and support the enhanced security measures included in the bill. They are long overdue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second--and here is the problem--the bill allows the Department of Homeland Security and the Department of State to fundamentally change the way countries are admitted into the visa waiver program, and thus, who can come into the U.S. without getting a visa.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Under current law, a country is eligible for this program so long as the vast majority--at least 97 percent--of its nationals can get a visa when they apply for one. The percentage of people who are rejected when they apply for a visa is called the "visa refusal rate" and that percentage must be under 3 percent for a country to participate in the program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The rationale is that if the overwhelming majority of visitors satisfy requirements for a U.S. visa when they apply, we should not waste our resources and the time of U.S. consular officers to evaluate every single visa application. The 3 percent rate means that 97 percent of these applicants will return to their home country for one reason or another. They have family and earn a satisfactory living.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But even with a 3 percent rejection rate, the Visa Waiver Program is a security problem.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Convicted terrorist Zacarias Moussaoui from France and "shoe-bomber" Richard Reid from Great Britain both boarded flights to the United States with passports issued by Visa Waiver Program countries.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On August 10 of this past year, British police charged 17 suspects with a terrorist plot to detonate liquid explosives carried on board several airliners traveling from the United Kingdom to the United States. The key suspects were reported to be British-born Muslims, eligible to travel to the U.S. with just a passport in hand.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For that reason, I believe that the current Visa Waiver Program is the soft underbelly of our national security.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But this bill undermines even the scant protection afforded by our current laws in that it allows the administration to admit new countries into the program with complete disregard for how many people were previously rejected when they applied for a U.S. visa. My amendment would provide a meaningful limit to that discretion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This bill does not affect just a handful of countries. It would affect any  and every country whose nationals travel to the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a matter of fact, the "roadmap" countries--or countries that the administration is currently talking to about inclusion in the Visa Waiver Program--total 19. So the Departments of State and Homeland Security are actively talking with 19 countries for acceptance into this Program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A significant number of these 19 countries have visa rejection rates that are well above 3 percent. They are marked with an asterisk, and total 13 of the 19. I ask unanimous consent to have printed in the RECORD a chart showing by country the rejection rates.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today, 544 million people are eligible to travel into the U.S. without a visa as part of the Visa Waiver Program. If we add these "roadmap" countries to the program, we will add 162 million more people who can travel into the United States without a visa--a 30 percent increase.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And if these 19 additional "roadmap" countries can come into the program, what is to preclude any other country from coming into the program? How do we say "no" to India, also a good ally, when its refusal rate--19.5 percent--is lower than 4 of the roadmap--countries? The rejection rate for China--24.5 percent--is lower than those coming from Romania. Indonesia, at 35.1 percent just exceeds Romania. So this bill will likely set up some real conflicts and create additional problems.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The administration has argued that the expansion of the visa waiver countries should be limited to our allies. But what does it mean to be an ally? According to this administration, when we invaded Iraq we counted Colombia with a 33.3 percent visa rejection rate, and Nicaragua, with a 48 percent rejection rate among our allies because they had provided some assistance in war.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Do we, in Congress, really want to give the administration unfettered flexibility to allow nationals from any country to travel to the U.S. without a visa, simply because their governments have cooperated with ours?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Does that mean that those nationals should be allowed to come to the United States with no advance screening?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We can only assume that we will also significantly increase the number of people who will not leave the United States after their visa expires. In this manner, this bill, if enacted into law, will likely add many thousands, if not millions, to the undocumented or illegal population.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Remember, today, 30 to 40 percent of the illegal population are, in fact, visa overstays--people who come with temporary or visitor visas and do not return to their countries.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe we should not expand this program without a good hard look at how it will compromise our national security, law enforcement, and immigration goals and without ensuring that safety measures are in place to make the program strong.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, whenever the United States adds new countries to the program, it increases the demand for, and the availability of, fraudulent travel documents.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The value of lost, stolen or fraudulent Visa Waiver Program documents is enormous. A person carrying a visa waiver country passport has virtually unlimited access into and out of the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>No doubt, the expansion of the program will increase the use of fraudulent border documents which are sold on the black market in the tens of thousands: passports, international driver's licenses, and other forms of identification from new visa waiver countries will flood the market.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>According to the July 2006 GAO report on improving the security of the Visa Waiver Program, visa waiver travel documents have been used by criminals and terrorists seeking to disguise their true identity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 2004, more than 15 million people from 27 countries traveled in and out of the United States with no visa.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>And from January through June 2005--a 6-month period--the Department of Homeland Security reported that it confiscated 298 fraudulent or altered passports issued by Visa Waiver Program countries that travelers were attempting to use to enter the United States. And these are just the ones who got caught.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In fact, Interpol reports that they have records of more than 12 million stolen and lost travel documents in their database, but that there are 30 to 40 million travel documents have been stolen worldwide.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We can extrapolate that tens of thousands of those documents are from visa waiver countries.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As the 9/11 Commission report demonstrates, individuals with fraudulent documents pose a far greater threat to our national security than those traveling with no documents at all.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For that reason, Senator SESSIONS and I have introduced a bill this Congress to crack down on people who traffic in lost and stolen travel documents.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The second problem is that some countries have very weak policies on who can become a citizen--and therefore legally obtain travel documents. Not every country has the same strict controls on who can become a citizen as the U.S. does.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For example, Romania, one of the "road map" countries, extends citizenship to many citizens of Ukraine or Moldova as a matter of course without prior residency requirements. Ukraine and Moldova are not slated to participate in the visa waiver program, and in fact, have visa rejection rates of 38.7 percent and 34.2 percent, respectively. Adding Romania is like adding Ukraine and Moldova. How would their inclusion impact national security?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, this bill does not go far enough to protect U.S. borders.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bill requires the development of an air exit system, but it does nothing to track who comes and goes by way of our land and sea ports.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It also requires the Department of Homeland Security to track how many people overstay their visas, but it does not require them to use this information to determine who can participate in the program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For example, even if we learn that one out of four Lithuanian visitors never returns to Lithuania when their visa expires, Lithuania could still participate in the Visa Waiver Program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, experts estimate that between 30 percent and 40 percent of those undocumented people living in the U.S. today are here because they ignored the time limits on their visa and just never went back home.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At a time when this country is torn about how to handle the 12 million undocumented people currently living here, we must consider who plays by the rules when we talk about who participates in the program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If a high number of travelers from countries overstay their visas, then those countries should not be allowed the benefit of permitting their nationals to enter the U.S. without a background check and a consular interview.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The amendment I am proposing today offers a way to limit the expansion of the Visa Waiver Program in light of our immigration and national security concerns.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The amendment I am offering would increase the visa rejection rate under the current law from 3 percent to 10 percent for countries that agree to these enhanced security measures.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The result is that countries such as South Korea, 3.6 percent, Taiwan, 3.1 percent, Estonia, 7.1 percent, and the Czech Republic, 9.4 percent could be eligible to participate in the program provided they pass the security requirements this bill imposes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Then, once the U.S. has statistics on which foreign nationals regularly overstay their visa, the government should use those statistics to decide who can participate in the program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My amendment would require the Departments of Homeland Security and State, in consultation and with the approval of Congress, to set a meaningful  overstay rate once they have that data. Then countries with a proven track record--those with nationals who go home when they are supposed to go home--could be eligible for the program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The answer is not to entirely remove the visa rejection rate, 3 percent, as this bill does with no suitable replacement, but to enact a fair system across the board that recognizes that the screening of those who wish to come to our country is important, both for the security of the country, as well as to ensure that visitors do what their "visa waiver" provides--and that is to return to their country of origin at the end of the 90-day period.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, there are discussions going on between the Senator from California and others to answer a question or two about the amendment, so for the moment we are going to leave it pending, and I yield for my colleague from Maine.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I have only had a brief time to look at the amendment offered by the Senator from California, but it would, in my judgment, enhance certain provisions in the underlying bill on the visa waiver program. There are discussions going on with key Senators on our side of the aisle, such as Senator Kyl of Arizona, who has also a great interest in this area.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are not prepared on this side to proceed with a full discussion of the amendment at this time or to dispose of it at this time, but I would inform my colleagues that I am optimistic that the discussions will produce a fruitful result. At this time, we cannot proceed to disposing of the amendment, however.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, Parliamentary inquiry: Am I correct that the Feinstein amendment, No. 271, is the pending business?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator is correct.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>I have been informed the questions one Member was raising about the amendment of Senator Feinstein have been resolved. I now urge we adopt the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there further debate? The Senator from Maine.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, to clarify for our colleagues, the objection or the clarification I mentioned earlier has been resolved on this side of the aisle. I know of no objection to adopting the amendment of Senator Feinstein. I believe it strengthens the provisions in the underlying bill and I urge its adoption.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> If there is no further debate on the amendment, the question is on agreeing to the amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I move to reconsider the vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="">
    <paragraph>I move to lay that motion on the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The motion to lay on the table was agreed to.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I send an amendment to the desk and ask for its immediate consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent the reading of the amendment be dispensed with.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today to introduce an amendment to address the growing concern among States regarding the implementation of the REAL ID Act of 2005. This law requires States to meet minimum security standards before citizens can use their driver's licenses for Federal purposes, such as boarding an airplane. I am very pleased to have several cosponsors of this amendment, including Senator Alexander, Senator Carper, Senator Cantwell, Senator Snowe,  and Senator Mikulski. All of them have expressed concerns about the impact on their States. I particularly wish to single out Senator Alexander,  who has long been a leading voice in raising concerns about the costs imposed upon States by the REAL ID Act.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As the deadline for compliance for the REAL ID Act rapidly approaches, States are beginning to send a very clear message that they are deeply concerned they simply will not be able to meet these standards. The amendment I introduce today recognizes those concerns by allowing more time to devise a way to make driver's licenses more secure without unduly burdening State governments and without threatening privacy and civil liberties.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To begin with, perhaps some background information would be useful. The 9/11 Commission's investigation found that all but one of the 9/11 terrorists had acquired some form of U.S. identification--in most cases a State driver's licenses. The Commission recommended that the Federal Government should set standards for the issuance of driver's licenses to make them more secure, to ensure the person was, in fact, entitled to a driver's license, and to make certain the driver's license has certain  security features to ensure the individual is who he or she claims to be.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To implement that recommendation, which was indeed in response to a very real concern identified by the 9/11 Commission, I worked with a bipartisan group of Senators, most notably my colleague, Senator Lieberman, to craft a provision in the 2004 Intelligence Reform Act that would accomplish the goal of the Commission. It called for the creation of a committee of experts from the Federal Government, from State governments, from privacy groups, from technology information organizations,  to come together in a negotiated rulemaking process and to develop a means of providing secure identification, while protecting privacy and civil liberty rights, and also respecting the role of the States, which have always had the primary responsibility in this area.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The language we came up with also provided for some grants that would help the States bear this cost--not the whole cost but to help them out.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This committee was indeed appointed--indeed, at my recommendation, Maine's secretary of state was one of the members--and they began diligently working on this task. Unfortunately, before the committee could complete its work, the House of Representatives attached the REAL ID Act of 2005 to an emergency war supplemental, a bill that was truly urgent. There was not a lot of consideration in the Senate nor debate over this provision.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It was inserted into the emergency war appropriations bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The effect of that was to repeal the negotiated rulemaking provisions that we had worked so hard to craft and to put into the Intelligence Reform Act of 2004. The further effect, therefore, was to halt the very productive and worthwhile progress this committee was making in devising standards to improve security without imposing unnecessary burdens and costs on State governments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Unlike our Intelligence Reform Act, the REAL ID Act of 2005 did not include States and other interested parties, whether privacy advocates or technological experts, in the rulemaking process. Instead, the REAL ID Act simply instructed the Department of Homeland Security to write its own regulations. It has been almost 2 years since the REAL ID Act was passed, and the Department has yet to issue the detailed guidance the States need to comply with the law. We expect these regulations are just  about to be published, that they are about to be issued under the formal notice and comment period later this week.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The problem is, the States are facing this looming May of 2008 deadline for being in full compliance with the REAL ID Act. That is an enormously constricted period for the States to comply, when the regulations have not yet been issued.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As States begin work this year on their 2008 budgets, they still have no idea what the final regulations will require of them, but they do know that the costs are likely to be substantial based on a study released in 2006 by the National Governors Association. The NGA estimated that the costs to States to implement the REAL ID Act could total more than $11 billion over the next 5 years. This is a substantial amount. Perhaps the cost will be less than that, but the point is, we don't know because  the regulations with the detailed guidance have still not been issued, even as we speak.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The State of Maine reports that the costs of implementation of the REAL ID Act could total $158 million. The Secretary of State tells me that is more than six times the normal operating budget of the Maine Bureau of Motor Vehicles.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The result has been an increasing rebellion by States over this unfunded, very difficult mandate. Some States, including my home State of Maine, have passed resolutions that have sent the message to Washington that they cannot and will not implement the REAL ID Act by the May 2008 deadline. So what do we do?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Here is what my amendment proposes. I have had extensive consultations with the National Governors Association, the National Council of State Legislatures, and other experts on this issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My amendment has two primary objectives. The first is to give the Federal Government and States the time and flexibility they need to come up with an effective but practical system to provide secure driver's licenses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second, my amendment would ensure the involvement of experts from the States, from the technology industry, and privacy and civil liberties advocates, by bringing them back to the table and giving them a chance to review these regulations and make them work.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are three major provisions in the amendment we are offering. First, the amendment provides that States would not have to be in full compliance with the REAL ID Act until 2 years after the final regulations are promulgated. That is reasonable. This is a difficult task, and it is important that we get it right. It is important for our security, but it is also important for the States that have been burdened with the task. That means no matter how long it takes for the Department of Homeland  Security to finish these regulations, States will have a full 2 years to implement them. Most likely, the impact of that is to delay from May of next year to May of 2010 the compliance date. That is the likely timeframe about which we are talking.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second, the amendment would give the Secretary of Homeland Security more flexibility to waive certain requirements of REAL ID, if an aspect of the program proves to be technically difficult to implement. I have talked with some technology experts. Some of them say it can be done. Some of them say this is an enormous task because we are talking about having interlocking databases so that States can check with other States on whether an individual is licensed there. That is a very complex project  because, not surprisingly, each State has its own system. So there are questions about the technology and the feasibility of all of the requirements of the REAL ID Act. We want to give the Secretary some flexibility in that area.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is possible that some of the technological links necessary for REAL ID may not be fully in place at the time that compliance is required. On the other hand, if the technology is there and the systems are up and running, it will be easier for the States to proceed. That is another advantage of the extension in time. The technology is only going to get better and become more effective.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This also gives us more time to address privacy concerns  because there are a lot of questions, if you have people throughout the country working in motor vehicle bureaus who are now going to have access to databases and are going to need training in evaluating the underlying documents, whether they are birth certificates or visas, in determining their validity. So this is a complicated task.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Third, the amendment reconstitutes the committee that we created in 2004, and that was making such good progress in its deliberations before these provisions were repealed by the REAL ID Act. This committee would be required to look at the regulations published by the Department of Homeland Security and to make suggestions for modifications to meet the concerns of States, privacy advocates, and other interested parties. Within 120 days of convening, the committee would report its recommendations  to the Department of Homeland Security and to Congress. So we are not throwing out  the work that has already been done by the Department of Homeland Security. It doesn't make sense to go back to square one, to go back to scratch, as the</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Department of Homeland Security would then either have to make the recommendations recommended by this committee or explain why it chose not to. So we would have much more transparency and accountability in the process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, the committee could recommend to Congress, if they believed that statutory changes are needed to mitigate concerns that could not be addressed by modifications to the regulations. That is an important safeguard as well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The amendment we are offering would give us time, the information that Congress and the Department of Homeland Security need to better implement the recommendations of the &#xD0;9/11 Commission in order to make our driver's licenses secure so that they cannot again be used to facilitate a plot to attack our country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is a real problem. The 9/11 Commission was correct in identifying the ease with which the hijackers were able to secure driver's licenses. But let's come up with not only an effective solution to the problem identified but also a practical one. We don't have to choose one versus the other. We can come up with a cost-effective, efficient, effective way to achieve this goal. This bill does so in a way that does not rewind the clock 3 years but instead keeps us moving to a more secure America.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I look forward to working with my colleagues on both sides of the aisle to address REAL ID and to put us back on the right track to protect our country, to protect our privacy, to protect our liberty, and to do so in a practical way.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, what is the pending business?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The pending amendment is the Collins amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, it is actually a Collins-Alexander amendment, along with several of our colleagues. I am very pleased to note the Senator from Tennessee, who has been such a leader and such an early voice raising concerns about the implications of the REAL ID Act for State governments, is here on the floor. As a former Governor, he has a better appreciation than many of us of the burden this act imposes on the States. So I am very pleased the Senator is here and I yield to him such  time as he may need.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Tennessee, the coauthor of the amendment, is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300002" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I thank the Senator from Maine and I salute the Senator from Maine. She is paying close attention not just to the security of our country but the fact that we need strong States and cities in our country at the same time. She, obviously, is in tune with the people in Maine because they, like people in Tennessee and other States, have taken a look at the so-called REAL ID law and wondered what we are doing up here.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>She has made a very thoughtful and sensible suggestion, which is that we delay for 2 years the implementation of the so-called REAL ID law, and let's make sure we know what we are doing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator Collins, because she is ranking member of the committee that deals with homeland security and a former chairman, and because she served in State government, is more sensitive to this issue than perhaps some of our colleagues. But she understands it is very easy for those of us in Washington to stand up here and come up with a big idea and think it might be a good idea, and then turn it into a law and hold a press conference and take credit for it, and then send the bill to the  Governor and the legislature and say: You pay for it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator Collins is more polite about this than I might be. Nothing used to make me madder when I was Governor than for legislators and Congressmen to do just that: to pass a big bill, take credit for it, and send the bill to the State. Then that same Congressman would usually be back in Tennessee making a Lincoln Day speech or a Jefferson Day speech or a Jackson Day speech about local control and saying how we need strong States and strong cities, but they dumped a big unfunded mandate  on top of us.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So let me see if I can be in support of Senator Collins, who has made a very reasonable, sensible amendment: First, to think about what we are doing with REAL ID and to make sure if we want to continue down this path, we do it in a way that respects the privacy of Americans. We are, after all, for the first time in our history actually creating a national identification card with all the ramifications of that. That is what the REAL ID law did. Second, to make sure that we don't create  an unfunded mandate. The Republican Congress in 1994 was ushered in claiming no more unfunded mandates. The Congressmen stood on the steps over there in the House and said: If we break our promise, throw us out. Well, they threw us out this past election, so why would we persist with unfunded mandates?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is an $11 billion unfunded mandate on State governments over the next 5 years. What does that mean? Higher property taxes, higher tuition costs, less funding for higher education so we can stay competitive with China and India, less money for lower classroom sizes, and less money for rewarding outstanding teachers. That is what unfunded mandates will mean, so we shouldn't do that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Then the third thing that is unfortunate about this REAL ID law that passed is we didn't have the opportunity to say anything about it over here in the Senate. Now, we are not always the wisest people in Washington, DC, but we have half the say. The REAL ID Act came up in the House of Representatives. It was stuffed into the supplemental appropriations bill for Katrina and the troops in Iraq. So of course we had to vote for the bill. We had no chance to amend it, no debate, no hearings, and no  consideration of other alternatives. Yet we impose on every State in this country a total of $11 billion worth of unfunded mandates, and we create for the first time in the history of a liberty-loving nation a national identification card. I would say we wouldn't be doing our job if we didn't stop and think about what we have done. Fortunately, we have time to stop and think about it, because while the law has been passed, it is not implemented yet.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Here is what Senator Collins has done, and I give her great credit for this. For her to introduce this amendment is especially useful because of her position as former chairman of the affected committee and now its ranking member. She has quickly attracted several cosponsors, Republicans and Democrats. She would extend the deadline for compliance with REAL ID to 2 years after final regulations are issued by the Department of Homeland Security.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, from the point of view of a Governor, that makes sense. If I were sitting back in Nashville, I would say: Well, now, Madam Congressman or Mr. Congressman, you are not going to expect me to take 3 or 4 million Tennesseans and run them through the State driver's license offices and find out if they are terrorists or if they are illegally here, or send them back home to grandma's attic and dig up their birth certificates, are you? I mean how many Tennesseans have their birth certificates handy?  How many want to go back to the driver's license office and stand in line? That is a lot of people, 3 or 4 million people, and that is only Tennessee. There are over 196 million people with driver's licenses in the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is another section or two in Senator Collins' amendment. She gives a little more discretion to the Secretary of DHS to waive State deadlines. That is a reasonable approach. She reestablishes the negotiated rulemaking committee that was created as part of the National Intelligence Reform Act of 2004. That means in plain  English that States that have the job of implementing this law will have a chance to come to the Federal Government and  say: Well, in Minnesota, we have longer lines during this part of the year because it snows and shorter lines during that part of the year because there is ice. And in other times of the year people are fishing on their lakes, and so we have some local conditions here. This gives more time to take into consideration the local conditions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Also, it requires figuring out what a fair system of reimbursement is. Here are the figures I have seen: Apparently we have appropriated $40 million for this. The Senator from Maine is nodding her head. Yet, the Governors tell us it is going to cost $11 billion. We have appropriated $40 million. They say it is going to cost $11 billion. We have a 60-vote point of order against unfunded Federal mandates. We couldn't even raise that when this went through like a freight train in the middle of a  Katrina and troops-in-Iraq bill. There would have to be 60 votes in order to impose on the States this kind of financial burden.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So that is basically it. This amendment says let's stop and think about this since this is the first national identification card we have ever had in this country. And since it is a massive unfunded mandate that would have the effect, if the Governors are right, of raising State taxes, raising tuition, cutting the amount of money available for colleges and competitiveness, cutting money for reducing classroom size, and cutting money for State health care plans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Then the third thing is we had no discussion--I don't believe there was a single hearing anywhere in the Senate--about this bill. I am delighted to  have a chance to be a cosponsor of this legislation that Senator Collins has introduced.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I will say one other thing about this idea of a national identification card. I have lived long enough to have changed my mind a few times on important issues. When I was Governor of Tennessee, I vetoed twice the photo identification card I now carry in my billfold because I thought it was an infringement on civil liberties and I didn't think it was anybody's business to have my picture on the identification card. Well, the retailers wanted it for check cashing, and law enforcement people wanted  it so they could catch more criminals. So the legislature overrode me. Plus, when I tried to get into the White House one time as Governor, they wouldn't let me in because I didn't have a photo identification card and I said: Well, I vetoed it, and they didn't think that was a good reason. The Governor of Georgia had to vouch for me, and after that indignity, Tennessee finally got a photo identification card.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have a right in America to be skeptical of national identification cards. We love liberty more than anything in this country, and that could infringe on our liberty. We have seen what happened in South Africa when people carried around passports and they were classified based on race, and their lives, their activities, everything about them was regulated that way. We can think back on Nazi Germany and other totalitarian countries where so much information was on a single card that it gave  the Government a good chance to keep up with every single person.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have changed my mind after 9/11. I believe we need a national identification card of some kind, and we, in fact, have one now. It is a de facto identification card. We call it the driver's license, but it is completely ineffective. It gets stolen. It gets copied. We show it when we go through the line at an airport. For a long time, mine said on the front that it expired in the year 2000, but if you turn it over, it said 2005. Well, at the airport they never turned it over so it is not a very  effective identification card, and that is the impetus for the REAL ID. I understand that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The first thought was let's take all of these 196 million driver's licenses and turn them into identification cards, but that might not be the best thought. There are other options. For example, we might need a work card in the United States. A lot of the impetus for this came from immigration problems. Since many of the immigration problems are the result of people wanting to come here and work, maybe one way to think about identity theft is to say: Let's have a Social Security card that is  biometric and let people apply for that; let people who get new cards get that, and let's have a work card. Or maybe we need a travel card for people who want to travel on airplanes, and they would have a travel card. Maybe we need to expand the number of passports. Twenty-five percent of us have passports. I am not sure what the right answer is. My instinct is that probably a work card would be a good card to have. Maybe we ought to have two or three cards that meet certain Federal requirements,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think it would be better to let Senator Lieberman and Senator Collins and others consider all of these options very carefully. I think it might be best when we get to the immigration bill and we talk about having an employer identification system, because that is going to be an essential part of the comprehensive immigration bill. Well, if that is the case, then we are probably going to need some kind of work card. If that is the case, we might end up with a secure Social  Security card. If that is the case, we might not need REAL ID at all.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So that is an even better reason to adopt the Collins amendment, because between now and the expiration of 2 years, we should pass a comprehensive immigration bill here in Congress. In fact, if we don't, we should all be severely criticized, because it is our job to do it. So I urge my colleagues respectfully to look at the Collins amendment and see it as a reasonable approach. It says: Let's delay 2 years. Let's hold some hearings. Let's ask the States to be more involved in what the cost is.  Let's think about any privacy issues that might result from a de facto national identification card, and let's even make sure, if we are going to have an identification card, that the idea of using driver's licenses is the best way to do it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As my last comment, I would underscore the fact that there are a number of States already considering taking the action Maine has already taken, the Senator's State, in passing a resolution rejecting the REAL ID card. Those are Hawaii, Georgia, Massachusetts, New Mexico, Oklahoma, Vermont, and Washington State. If the REAL ID card were to go into effect in those States in May, next spring, and they didn't have the REAL ID card, according to the law they can't fly on a commercial airplane. Well,  that is going to create a situation I don't think any Member of this Senate wants to see.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I am here to salute the Senator from Maine for being diligent in protecting our liberty and in protecting the rights of State and local governments, and making sure that if we are going to have some kind of more secure card, whether it is a driver's license or a work card, a travel card, or even a passport, that we do it right after we have suitable hearings.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am proud to be a cosponsor of the Collins amendment, and I thank the Senator for yielding time to me.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Maine is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I thank the Senator from Tennessee for his excellent statement. He outlined the issue very well.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I emphasize two points the Senator made. First is the cost. The National Governors Association has estimated that compliance with the requirements of the REAL ID card will impose $11 billion of costs on State governments over the next 5 years. Yet we have appropriated only $40 million to be used toward that cost, and of that amount the Department of Homeland Security has only allocated $6 million, so only a tiny fraction of the expected cost.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The second point I emphasize is the Department of Homeland Security has yet to issue the regulations detailing how States are to comply with the law.  So to expect the States to comply by May of next year with regulations that have yet to be issued is simply unfair and will add another layer of costs because of the short time for compliance. This 2 years will allow a more careful review. It will allow more input by the States when DHS does issue the regulations,  and it will allow us to devise a cost-effective way of achieving a goal all of us have, and that is to make driver's licenses more secure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am very grateful for the insights of the Senator from Tennessee, for his support, and for his very early leadership on this issue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam President, I yield the floor and suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300056" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300056" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, the provisions included in the Commerce Committee title, title 13 of the substitute amendment, reflect the Commerce Committee's relentless efforts to tackle emerging issues and building upon existing security transportation legislation. The provisions included in the Commerce title improve and enhance our security efforts across all modes: rail, truck, motor carrier, pipeline, and aviation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator STEVENS and I, and our colleagues on the Commerce Committee are no strangers to the issue of transportation security. In fact, the Commerce Committee responded and the Congress enacted immediately in the aftermath of the 9/11 attack landmark aviation and maritime security laws.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last year, the Congress took its first step in 4 years, to significantly improve the Nation's transportation security system by enacting the Commerce Committee's SAFE Port Act, which strengthened the security of our Nation's ports and maritime vessels.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While significant in terms of the protections provided to our ports and maritime system, the Congress failed during conference to seize the opportunity to enact comprehensive transportation security legislation that would have addressed many of the gaps in other modes of the transportation system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today we begin to correct that shortcoming with the proposed legislation before us.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Commerce title to the substitute amendment before the Senate addresses transportation security for our rail, motor carrier, and pipeline industries. The economic importance of these three industries can not be overstated.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While 95 percent of the Nation's cargo comes through our ports, our rail system and our motor carriers move these goods from our coasts and borders, through the interior of this country, to their final destinations. Together, these systems are the backbone that sustains our economy.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In terms of rail security, the Nation's 560-plus freight railroads own more than 140,000 miles of track over which nearly 30 million carloads are transported annually. This network transports 42 percent of all domestic intercity freight, the majority of coal used in electricity generation, more than 12 million trailers and containers, and two million carloads of chemicals. Meanwhile, U.S. trucking hauled 9.1 billion tons of freight and employed 5.6 million people in trucking related fields in  2003.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Equally important is the contribution that these modes make in moving passengers throughout our Nation. Approximately 24 million passengers ride Amtrak annually, and there are nearly 3.4 billion passenger and commuter rail trips in this country each year. Similarly, over-the-road buses transport approximately 600 million passengers annually and are the only viable means of public transportation for many people throughout the country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The recent attacks on the passenger trains and transit systems in Madrid, London, and Mumbai all demonstrate that railroads and surface transportation systems are vulnerable targets for terrorists, and are a constant reminder of what can happen in our communities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We must address the risks facing our essential surface and rail transportation systems here at home in a comprehensive and coordinated way before we become the next victim of a successful attack.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Toward this goal, Senator STEVENS and I, along with Senators LAUTENBERG, ROCKEFELLER, KERRY, BOXER, SNOWE, PRYOR, CARPER, DORGAN, HUTCHISON, KLOBUCHAR, CANTWELL, and others, introduced the Surface Transportation and Rail Security Act of 2007, or STARS Act. This bill has 22 cosponsors to date.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The STARS Act incorporates updated versions of provisions within the Rail Security Act of 2004, which the Senate passed by unanimous consent in the 108th Congress, and the Senate version of the SAFE Port Act which we passed in the 109th Congress.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Commerce Committee unanimously reported this bill along with <bill type="s" number="509">S. 509</bill>, the Aviation Security Improvement Act, and <bill type="s" number="385">S. 385</bill>, the Interoperable Emergency Communication Act, on February 13, 2007, and these provisions are included in the substitute amendment before us today as title 13.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The surface and rail provisions in title 13 require the Department of Homeland Security and the Transportation Security Administration to expand existing security initiatives and develop grant programs to assist private-sector surface transportation security efforts. The title authorizes $1.1 billion over fiscal years 2008 through 2011.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The rail title of the substitute amendment requires railroad risk assessments and plans for improving rail security. It also authorizes grants to Amtrak, freight railroads and others to upgrade passenger and freight rail security, undertake research and development, and improve tunnel security.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Additionally, the title encourages the deployment of rail car tracking equipment for high-hazard material shipments, requires railroads to create a railroad worker security-training program, and provides whistleblower protection for rail workers who report security concerns.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The surface transportation security provisions in title 13 of the substitute amendment promotes tracking technology for truck shipments of high-hazard materials and requires new guidance and assessments pertaining to hazardous materials truck routing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The title also establishes programs for reviewing and enforcing hazardous materials and pipeline security plans and requires the TSA to develop pipeline incident recovery plans.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Additionally, the title authorizes the existing grant program for improving intercity bus and bus terminal security.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, the title clarifies, at the TSA's request, the Secretary of Homeland Security's legal authority for initiating an administrative enforcement proceeding for violations of security regulations relating to nonaviation modes of transportation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Regarding aviation security, title 13 addresses all the recommendations in the 9/11 Commission's report, including cargo and baggage screening, explosive detection at airport checkpoints, passenger prescreening, airport access controls, and general aviation security. The title requires the TSA to provide for the screening of all cargo being carried on commercial passenger aircraft within 3 years. The system must allow for a level of screening "comparable" to that of checked baggage screening  and ensure the security of all cargo that is shipped on passenger aircraft.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The aviation provisions in title 13 advance the deployment of electronic Explosive Detection Systems, EDS, at airports across the nation by extending the Aviation Security Capital Fund that is used to integrate such machines into the baggage conveyor process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The title also bolsters the existing grant program through changes in funding allocation requirements requiring a prioritized schedule for such projects that will increase flexibility for funding options.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our legislation recognizes the threat presented by passengers transporting explosives through security checkpoints and promotes key changes to address this risk.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Title 13 requires the TSA to produce a strategic plan to deploy explosive detection equipment at airport checkpoints and fully implement that plan within 1 year of its submission. They must also provide specialized training to the screener workforce in the areas of behavior observation, and explosives detection. To address ongoing problems in developing an advanced passenger  prescreening system, the aviation provisions in title 13 would ensure a system  is in place to coordinate passenger redress for those individuals misidentified against the "no-fly" or "selectee" watchlists. The TSA must also submit a strategic plan to Congress for the testing and implementation of its advanced passenger prescreening system.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To increase General Aviation, GA, security, the title will require a threat assessment program that is standardized and focused on GA facilities. It will further require foreign based GA aircraft entering U.S. airspace to have their passengers checked against appropriate watchlists to determine if there are any potential threats on board.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Title 13 of the substitute amendment includes a number of additional provisions that will take significant steps toward strengthening aviation security generally.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Title 13 will also authorize research and development spending for aviation security technology, remove the arbitrary cap of 45,000 full-time equivalent--FTE--employees currently imposed on the TSA's screener workforce, and mandate security rules for foreign aircraft repair stations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, this title will require the TSA to develop a system by which the Administrator will provide blast-resistant cargo containers to commercial passenger air carriers for use on a random or risk-assessed basis, implement a sterile area access system that will grant flight deck and cabin crews expedited access to secure areas through screening checkpoints, and require a doubling of the DHS's existing dog team capacity used for explosive detection across the Nation's transportation network.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition to transportation security, title 13 also includes the text of <bill type="s" number="385">S. 385</bill>, the Interoperable Emergency Communications Act, which I introduced earlier this year with Senators STEVENS, KERRY, SMITH, and SNOWE. Under the foresight and leadership of Senator STEVENS, during the Deficit Reduction Act, the Commerce Committee created a new $1 billion fund administered by the National Telecommunications and Information Administration--NTIA--to support state and local first  responders in their efforts to talk to one another during emergencies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The interoperable provisions in title 13 provide congressional direction on the implementation of that fund.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since its creation, NTIA has served as the principal telecommunications policy advisor to the Secretary of Commerce and the President, and manages the Federal Government's use of the radio spectrum.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In this capacity, NTIA has historically played an important role in assisting public safety personnel in improving communications interoperability and recognizing that effective solutions involve attention to issues of spectrum and government coordination as well as funding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, our first responders continue to struggle in their efforts to improve the interoperability of their systems. The statutory guidance provided to NTIA in this legislation will help them in these efforts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>First, the provision would make clear that proposals to improve interoperable communications are not solely limited to systems or equipment that utilize new public safety spectrum that will be vacated following the digital television transition.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In a letter to the majority leader earlier this year, Mayor Bloomberg of New York City noted the significant efforts of his city to improve communications interoperability for first responders utilizing systems in other public safety spectrum bands, and urged Congress to eliminate the apparent eligibility restriction in current law. As a result, our provisions make clear that if the project will improve public safety interoperability, it is eligible for funding.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In addition, the provisions provide the NTIA Administrator to direct up to $100 million of these funds for the creation of State and Federal strategic technology reserves of communications equipment that can be readily deployed in the event that terrestrial networks fail in times of disaster.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Recently, an independent panel created by FCC Chairman Kevin Martin to review the impact of Hurricane Katrina on communications networks noted the impact that limited pre-positioning of communications equipment had in slowing the recovery process. As a result, these provisions will help to ensure that our focus on interoperability also considers the importance of communications redundancy and resiliency.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second, the provisions ensure that funding allocations among the several States result in a fair distribution by requiring a base amount of funding--.75 percent--to be distributed to all States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On top of these minimum allocations, the provision would further require that prioritization of these funds be based upon an "all-hazards" approach that recognizes the critical need for effective emergency communications in response to natural disasters, such as tsunami, earthquakes, hurricanes, and tornadoes, in addition to terrorist attacks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, NTIA's administration of the grant fund will not only help to integrate the disparate elements that must be a part of effective interoperability solutions, but will also ensure greater program transparency and oversight. Given the myriad of different grant programs administered by the Department of Homeland Security, it is critical that these funds--specifically allocated by Congress to speed up our efforts to improve communications interoperability for first responders--not get lost  in the shuffle of other disaster and nondisaster grants.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a result, the provisions not only devote NTIA's attention to the success of this program, but also require the inspector general of the Department of Commerce to annually review the administration of this program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The terrorists that seek to do us harm are cunning, dynamic, and most of all, patient. While they have not successfully struck our homeland since September 11, 2001, it does not mean they are not preparing to do so.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>They work 24 hours a day, studying every move we make, looking for some weakness to exploit. It is imperative that we stay ahead of them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We must recruit, train, and deploy a skilled and dedicated security force. We must research and implement the most effective and cutting edge technologies to enhance the capabilities of that security force. And we must provide communications equipment to our first responders that is interoperable and accessible in the immediate aftermath of a disaster.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Simply put, our entire economy relies on a well-functioning, secure transportation system, and we must ensure that the system, and the passengers and cargo that use it, are well protected.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The steps we take in the coming months will impact our safety, security, and one of our most essential freedoms--movement--for years to come. We must commit ourselves to ensuring that our transportation security remains a priority and is as strong and effective as possible.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The provisions before the Senate this week that were reported out of the Commerce Committee make that commitment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have worked over the past several years with our colleagues and with the TSA and DHS and with the FCC and NTIA to address concerns, improve on initial efforts, and plan for the future. Now, it is time to act and to pass these provisions, so we can continue to move forward.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Connecticut is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I thank Senator Inouye for his extraordinary leadership in these matters. The committees have differing jurisdictions, all aimed at supporting homeland security. The Commerce Committee sections we are proud to have put together with the parts that came out of the Homeland Security Committee, as well as parts that came out of the Banking Committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is always an honor and pleasure to work with Senator Inouye. I thank him for the contributions he and Senator Stevens and their committee have made to the overall movement in the Senate to improve our homeland security. I thank the Senator very much.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300056" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I thank the chairman for his kind words.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I yield to the Senator from South Carolina, who has come to the floor to offer an amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from South Carolina is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I thank the managers of this bill for the time and effort they have put into it. It is almost 400 pages long, and it contains numerous provisions. I look forward to working with the Senator from Connecticut, Mr. Lieberman, and the Senator from Maine, Ms. Collins, in the coming days to make this bill better. I call up amendment No. 279.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the amendment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, the amendment I have offered, No. 279, is very simple. It codifies the recent regulations issued by the Department of Homeland Security which bans certain criminals from gaining security access to our seaports. My amendment is needed to protect these regulations from outside groups that may challenge them in court, as well as from future administrations that may repeal or weaken them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My amendment is also bipartisan and should not be controversial. It was unanimously adopted by this body last  year as part of the SAFE Port Act which passed 98 to 0. Unfortunately, it was gutted by the conference committee behind closed doors, and that is why I am offering it again today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As my colleagues know, the Maritime Transportation Security Act requires the Transportation Security Agency, TSA, to develop a biometric security card for port workers at our seaports that can be used to limit access to sensitive areas within a seaport.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The security card is called a transportation worker identification card or, as we sometimes call it, a TWIC.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The law requires that the Secretary issue this card to any individual requesting it unless the Secretary determines that the individual poses a terrorism security risk or if the individual has been convicted of treason, terrorism, sedition, or espionage. To clarify who poses a security risk, the Department of Homeland Security recently issued regulations that bar certain serious felons from receiving these TWICs. Specifically, the regulations permanently bar from our ports criminals convicted  of espionage, sedition, treason, terrorism, crimes involving transportation security, improper transport of hazardous material, unlawful use of an explosive device, bomb threats, murder, violation of the RICO Act, where one of the above crimes is a predicate act, and conspiracy to commit any of these crimes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Department of Homeland Security regulations also bar recent felons--defined as those convicted within the last 7 years or incarcerated in the last 5 years--from gaining access to our ports if they have been convicted of any of the following felonies: assault with intent to murder, kidnapping or hostage-taking, rape or aggravated sexual abuse, unlawful use of a firearm, extortion, fraud, bribery, smuggling, immigration violations, racketeering, robbery, drug dealing, arson, or conspiracy to  commit any of these crimes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These regulations were developed after an extensive process that included consultation with the Department of Justice and Transportation to identify individuals who have a propensity to engage in unlawful activity, specifically activity that places our ports at risk. These regulations governing who can gain access to our seaports are nearly identical to the regulations that govern those who can gain access to our airports as well as those who can transport hazardous material in our country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These prohibitions are crucial because individuals who engage in this type of unlawful activity have a greater likelihood to engage in these acts or in acts that put American ports and American lives at risk. Our law enforcement officials understand this risk. They understand the threat our ports face when traditional criminals, particularly organized criminals, work with terrorists. For example, the FBI recently apprehended a member of the Russian mafia attempting to sell missiles to an FBI  agent who he believed was acting as a middleman for terrorists.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Joseph Billie, Jr., the FBI's top counterterrorism official, recently commented that the FBI is continuing to look at a nexus between organized crime and terrorists, and they are looking at this very aggressively. The threat not only comes from criminals working directly with terrorists, it also comes from criminals who may look the other way when a suspect container comes from a port. Joseph King, a former Customs Service agent and now a professor at the John J. College of Criminal Justice,  outlined the concern very clearly: "It is an invitation to smuggling of all kinds," he said. "Instead of bringing in 50 kilograms of heroin, what would stop them from bringing in 5 kilograms of plutonium?" The nightmare scenario here is where a criminal at one of our ports who may think he is just helping a friend smuggle in drugs inadvertently helps smuggle in a weapon of mass destruction. That is a risk we cannot take.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I offered this amendment last year to address this threat and to ensure that serious felons are kept out of our ports. My amendment codified in statute the then-proposed TWIC regulations. As I said earlier, my amendment was unanimously adopted and was included in the Senate-passed version of the SAFE Port Act that passed 98 to 0. Unfortunately, my amendment was also completely gutted behind closed doors in the conference committee. The provision went from addressing a list of 20 serious felons  to a list of just 4. These 4 felonies are so rare that the conference committee made the provision almost meaningless.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am extremely disappointed by the stealth opposition to this measure. I cannot understand who would oppose banning serious felons from gaining secure access at our American ports. While no Senator has been willing to publicly oppose this measure, the longshoremen's labor union was more than happy to take credit for gutting the provision. Late last year, the International Longshore and Warehouse Union claimed credit for killing the provision in the SAFE Port conference committee. They stated  in their newsletter:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have heard rumors that Senator DeMint is particularly angry with the union's successful lobbying effort to strip his anti-labor provision. He may attempt to amend another piece of legislation, so the union will stay on guard to protect its members' interests.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Apparently, this union has stayed on guard because it was able to get five Senators to object to this vital homeland security measure when I tried to pass it the second time late last year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I wish I could say that the unions would stop at fighting this legislation on the Senate floor, but they are also gearing up to mount a legal battle against Department of Homeland Security regulations. In response to a Wall Street Journal editorial on the subject, the union stated that the TWIC security regulations were " ..... double jeopardy and unconstitutional." This is a clear indication that they have a legal challenge in mind. It seems clear that once longshoremen start applying for  TWIC cards and some members are rejected because they are convicted felons, the labor unions are going to take the Department of Homeland Security to court and try to bog the regulations down in lengthy legal battles. The consequence will be that as we continue to fight this global war on terror, America's ports will be staffed by serious felons who cannot be trusted.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Some of my colleagues may be tempted to come to the defense of the longshoremen. They will say that the individuals in question have paid their debt to society and barring them is gutting our port workforce. They may also claim that the crimes listed in the Department of Homeland Security regulations are somehow not related to homeland security. These objections are just plain wrong.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I don't disagree that convicted felons should be given a second chance. I hope they get back on their feet and become productive members of their communities. What I disagree with is that we should give serious felons a pass, literally and figuratively, to access the most secure areas of America's port infrastructure. When they are fresh out of prison, we should not trust them with the most vulnerable areas of our ports. The stakes here are simply too high.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As for the concern that barring these individuals will empty the ranks of the port workforce, the facts don't  agree. When the Department of Homeland Security issued nearly 350,000 ID cards for hazmat truckdrivers and subjected them to the same background check that is required by my amendment, only 3,100 were rejected. That is less than 1 percent. The fact is, we are talking about an isolated group of serious felons here, and the workforce in the United States is dynamic enough to supply the few thousand longshoremen who may be needed to replace those we let go.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, some may say these felonies do not represent serious crimes. To that, I would ask any of my colleagues to tell me which individual he or she wants working at our ports where security is so important: Murderers? Extortionists? Drug dealers? Bomb makers? I just want to hear the rationale for trusting these criminals with our national security.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The bottom line is this: My amendment applies nearly the same protections to seaports that are already applied at our airports. It will make us safer by keeping individuals who have shown a willingness to break the law outside our ports. This is extremely important. We can spend all the money in our Treasury trying to screen cargo, but if we don't screen the people who  work at our ports, we cannot expect to be safe.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I do wish to thank several people for supporting this important policy. First, I thank the Senator from Maine, Ms. Collins, who was very helpful to me during the debate on the SAFE Port Act last year. I also thank the Senator from Connecticut, Mr. Lieberman, for his support. I should also say that the Senator from Hawaii, Mr. Inouye, was also helpful in getting this provision into the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a bipartisan proposal, and it should not be controversial. Americans expect us to check and verify the nature of the people who work at our seaports, and we have a responsibility to ensure that happens even if it upsets a labor union that feels compelled to protect the jobs of a small group of serious felons. My amendment codifies in statute these important security regulations, and I hope all of my colleagues will support it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I appreciate the opportunity to speak on this important measure, and I will be happy to work with the bill managers to arrange a time to come back to the floor if further debate is needed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank the Chair for this time, and I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Connecticut.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I thank our friend from South Carolina for the amendment he has offered. We worked together when last this subject came before the Senate to bring about a result that I believe was a good one and in the public interest, which was that the Secretary of Homeland Security issued regulations to create an identity card. The card has a marvelous acronym, which doesn't sound as serious as it is. The acronym is TWIC, transportation worker identification card. This is one  of the necessities of the post-9/11 age, that we need to move toward some filter for people working in areas that now have become higher vulnerability areas and are more likely targets for terrorism. Unfortunately, that includes our ports and, obviously, includes our airports as well, which have a separate ID program on which they are working.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I know there is some hope within the Department of Homeland Security that we are moving toward a more common program for a similar background check and card for postal workers at a host of different transportation-related locations to protect them and us from potential terrorist attacks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator DeMint, I gather from his statement--and I appreciate his intentions here--intends by this amendment to codify in law the regulations the Department of Homeland Security has established for these identification cards for workers at our ports. I want to take a look at it. I know Senator Collins does as well. We want to work with Senator DeMint.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Clearly, the intention here is one we all share, which is to do everything we can, within reason and respectful of common sense and constitutional rights, to secure our critical transportation facilities, including our ports. I rise now to simply thank the Senator for offering his amendment, to tell him we will consider it with some thoughtfulness and look forward to working with him as we move toward a vote on this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank the Chair, and I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Georgia.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300021" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, what is the pending business?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The DeMint amendment is the pending business.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300021" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that amendment be set aside and I be allowed to speak on the Collins amendment, No. 277, please.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300021" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise today in support of the amendment offered by my colleague from Maine, Senator Collins, relative to the issue of REAL ID. I was back in my State last week, as most of us were, and I had the opportunity to speak to our legislature and visit with members of both the State house and the State senate in Atlanta, and I cannot tell you the angst and apprehension that I saw among members of my legislature over this issue of REAL ID.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When I got back I did not understand why there would be that much concern about the issue. I was not sure how this thing came about. When I checked with my staff I found out, as Senator Alexander said this morning in his comments, that this was a measure that was stuck into the Katrina appropriations bill that did not go through committee, we did not have debate on it on the floor of this body, and I don't think anybody here understood the real consequences of it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When the 19 hijackers came to this country and carried out the horrific attack on September 11, they were in possession of 63 driver's licenses issued by various States around the country. That should never have happened, and we need to make sure it does not happen again. But the fact is, I don't think anybody understood the consequences of this REAL ID Act as it pertains to that particular issue of driver's licenses.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1994, when I was elected to the House of Representatives, we talked a lot about unfunded mandates. The Presiding Officer was a Member of that body. He remembers well we had a lot of conversations about unfunded mandates coming out of Washington to our State and local officials and organizations that were required to fund those mandates that we passed. There is no bigger unfunded mandate that we have passed lately that is more atrocious than this particular mandate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I applaud Senator Collins for looking at this issue, for deciding that it is a real, practical problem. It is an issue that needs to be dealt with. Her amendment makes a lot of sense. It does not repeal the law. What it does is to say that the law is not going to be implemented until 2 years following the issuance of the regulations. Here we are, with this law supposed to be implemented by our State legislatures this year, and we don't even have the regulations coming out of the Department  of Homeland Security yet. They don't know how to carry out the provisions of this law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I support the Collins amendment, No. 277. I think it makes an awful lot of sense. It allows us to go back in and take a more thorough look at this particular issue and decide how we can accomplish the results that the REAL ID Act wants to accomplish but at the same time not burden our States with a mandate that none of us intended to impose upon them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I do support this amendment. I hope when the time comes it will receive not only passage but significant numbers to support the passage of this amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Maine.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I thank the Senator from Georgia for his support and his excellent comments. This is a carefully drafted amendment. It doesn't rewind the clock in terms of throwing out the work that the Department has done, but it recognizes that it is simply unreasonable to expect States to comply by May of next year with complex and costly regulations that the Department has yet to issue. The Department has yet to issue the detailed guidance that the States need.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It also recognizes that the quality of the final regulations will be improved by the formation of a committee with State officials, privacy advocates, technological experts, and Federal officials sitting down, looking at the regulations, and providing input to the Department on their proposed regulations and also providing that input to us.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The third provision of the amendment would increase the waiver authority that the Secretary can have if it proves that there are technological barriers to complying with certain provisions of the law. I think this is a reasonable approach to a real problem.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, let me say to my colleagues, the estimates for the cost of compliance with this law are as high as $11 billion over the next 5 years. This is a huge unfunded mandate on the States. My hope is through our approach we can come up with more practical, cost-effective means of achieving a goal that all of us share and that is improving the security of driver's licenses that are used for Federal identification purposes, such as boarding an airplane. There is a real need to have a secure driver's  license, but let's do it in a practical, collaborative way, and let's make sure there is adequate time to comply.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank the Senator from Georgia for his support and for his excellent comments.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the Senator from Georgia, Mr. Chambliss, be added as a cosponsor of the Collins amendment, No. 277.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent to speak as in morning business for 20 minutes. I don't think I will use all that time. If I need more time, I will ask for it.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300048" topic="TAXES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, as everybody who follows Congress on a regular basis knows, when you get close to the month of March, we are in budget season. The President sent his budget to the Hill, which he does regularly, the first week of February, about a month ago. So now it is up to the Congress. In the next few days the Senate Budget Committee will be marking up our budget resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For the public at large, don't confuse a budget resolution, which is a discipline for Congress on budgeting, with appropriations bills that actually give the President the authority to spend money. They come along a little bit later in the year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At a minimum, the budget resolution will lay out the fiscal priorities of the next 5 years. As everyone knows, the American people spoke last November and sent a Democratic majority to both Houses of Congress. For the first time in 12 years, Democrats will take the initiative on the Senate budget. As ranking Republican on the Finance Committee, which deals with taxes, trade, Social Security, Medicare, and Medicaid, and also as the senior Republican on the Budget Committee, which is the committee  that sends the budget to the Senate, I am eager to see the direction the new Democratic majority wants to take on fiscal policy for this year, but the budget also has long-term implications of 5 years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are a lot of questions I am waiting to get answered. What will be their plan on pay-go, which means pay as you go? With spending at higher-than-average levels of our economy, what kind of spending discipline will the Democratic majority show? On the revenue side of the ledger, will Democrats look to prevent a tax increase on virtually every American taxpayer a few years down the road, when the present tax policy sunsets, or will the Democratic majority, without a vote, set in motion, then,  the largest Federal tax increase of all time? This is a fact. It will happen. When we have a sunsetting of tax law, it is possible to have a tax increase without Congress voting it. In this particular instance, this would put in place the biggest Federal tax increase ever.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Over the next few days, I want to talk about the tax issues--I want to do it topic by topic--that are going to come up during debate on the process of the budget. There are probably many ways to do it, but this is how I split the general subject into topics: One, the importance of preventing a tax hike on virtually all American taxpaying families and individuals. That is what I want to visit about today. Next is the negative economic consequences of sunsetting the bipartisan tax relief plan that  will be the biggest tax increase in the history of the country without a vote of the people, if we don't do something about it. Then another time, I am going to review Democratic tax increase offset proposals with a specific focus on the limits and problems associated with those tax increases.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Next I will focus on one particular ill-defined but often mentioned offset; that is, reducing the tax gap. Everybody is for reducing the tax gap, and I am working with Senator Baucus to do that. He is chairman of our committee. But there has to be realism brought into that debate, and I hope to provide that realism. Then fifth and last, tax reform and simplification, its necessity and bipartisan opportunities to do so.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These discussions are meant to be about the revenue side of the budget. But before we get into the revenue side of the budget, I want to issue a challenge to my friends on the other side of the aisle. It is a challenge I have made over the last few years. It is in the context of intellectually honest budgeting. It is also in the context of the bipartisan record of the Finance Committee on tax policy over the last few years. That tax policy has been led by this Senator, when I was chairman, and  by Senator Baucus working with me during that period of time, or Senator Baucus, now leading the committee and, hopefully, my always working with him as he worked with me.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That bipartisan record of the Senate Finance Committee shows about $200 billion of revenue raisers from antitax shelter measures and corporate loophole closures, basically doing something about abuse of the Tax Code, unintended by Congress, by people who can hire very sophisticated lawyers to find ways around paying taxes. We have closed $200 billion of those, and it has been bipartisan. So when I hear from self-styled deficit hawks, or from the media, who are sympathetic to those points of view  that we need higher taxes to reduce the deficit, I believe the Finance Committee has anted up in terms of producing revenue raisers without raising general levels of taxation on the American people.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Here is my challenge, and I will ask my friends to listen up. Anyone on the other side who considers themselves a deficit hawk needs to prove it, then, on the spending side. Compared to our committee already raising revenue by $200 billion by closing tax loopholes and tax abuse, show me, then, a spending restraint proposal for deficit reduction. I issued that challenge several years  ago and have issued it repeatedly. No one from the other side has stepped up. We can look and look and look and we won't find such a proposal. All of those liberal think tanks that oppose tooth and nail any kind of tax relief are usually advocates of spending increases, all of this under the guise of fiscal responsibility. We won't find any proposals to restrain spending from these liberal think tanks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If we look at the media sources that are sympathetic to the views of the Democratic leadership or the liberal think tanks, we will find hard-line opposition to tax relief and a lot of tax increase proposals but, likewise, no proposal reining in spending. They will claim the mantle of fiscal responsibility but won't show anything on the spending side other than spending increases. For these folks, when it comes to deficit reduction, there is only one side of the Federal ledger. That is raising  taxes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have a Federal Government that is projected to spend $2.7 trillion for this fiscal year alone and is projected to spend $33.7 trillion over the next 10 years. Yet leadership on the other side of the aisle, the liberal think tanks that back them up, and the media that helps them get their message out so easily and is sympathetic to their views, can't find a dollar of savings on the spending side. To these folks, with all due respect, I want to call them out. They won in November. The Congress  is in their hands. Let's see some credibility on the spending side of the ledger. Show the taxpayers the money. Show me a proposal to restrain spending and put it to deficit reduction. That is a preliminary point.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now I will move to talk about preventing tax hikes. The same group's position on current law tax relief is radically different than its position on spending restraint. Back in 2001 and 2003, Congress approved, and the President signed, legislation that provided across-the-board tax relief to nearly every American taxpayer. The Democratic leadership, liberal think tanks, and sympathetic east coast media criticized tax relief on a couple of grounds. One charge was that the tax relief was a tax  cut for the rich. The other charge was that the bipartisan tax relief was fiscally irresponsible.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Nonpartisan Joint Committee on Taxation distribution tables actually put a lie to that first charge. The record levels of revenue show that the growing economy, the expanding U.S. economy, and economic stimulus from tax relief better the Nation's fiscal situation, bringing in more tax dollars,  not depriving the Federal Treasury of dollars.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This debate on preventing tax increases is often couched only in macroeconomic terms. We will hear what it "costs" to extend bipartisan tax relief. We will hear very big numbers. For instance, the Joint Committee on Taxation projects that the revenue loss from making the bipartisan tax relief permanent is $1.9 trillion over the next 10 years. That is the way the Democratic leadership, liberal think tanks, and sympathetic east coast media will define proposals to prevent a tax hike. We won't  see them talk about the number of families who benefit from the extension of the $1,000 child tax credit. You won't see them talk about the number of married couples who benefit or the average family benefit from marriage penalty relief.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today I am going to take a few minutes and shed some light on the side of the debate about extending bipartisan tax relief. Lord only knows, there is not much light shed on these important facts, because everybody is talking about tax relief for the rich. I will acknowledge the critics' point on the macro cost of extending tax relief. But keep in mind, a liberal's tax relief cost is a conservative's tax hike, when we are talking about extending current law. They are the two sides of the same  taxpayer's coin. I will agree to that number, but call it a $1.9 trillion tax increase.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I am going to follow the Democratic leadership plan and dismantle the bipartisan tax relief package bit by bit. I am also going to challenge the Democratic leadership to show us the money by indicating whether they want to scrap each piece as I move through the package. Which pieces would they scuttle?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I will work through the bipartisan tax legislation piece by piece.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let's start, then, with the basis for the 2001 bipartisan tax relief measure. That is the new 10-percent bracket. The revenue loss for this part of the package is $299 billion over 10 years, according to the Joint Committee on Taxation. The 10-percent bracket is a huge piece of tax relief for low-income people. The 10-percent bracket does that. No wonder 100 million families and individual taxpayers benefit from the 10-percent bracket. I do not think anybody wants to dismantle that piece. But  I want to hear that from the Democratic leadership because that is a compromise of their position of whether the 2001 tax increases ought to sunset.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Where do we go next, then? The marginal tax rate cuts, which include the 10-percent bracket, lose $852 billion over 10 years, according to the Joint Committee on Taxation. That proposal reduces the taxes of approximately 100 million families and individuals across America. It appears some folks think 35 percent is too low of a top rate. Well, guess what. Repealing the marginal rate cuts hits small business--the biggest source of new jobs in this great country of ours--and it hits small business  the hardest.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Treasury Department estimates 33 million small business owners who are taxed on their business income at individual rates benefit from the marginal rate cuts. Repealing these cuts would cause 33 million small business owners to pay a 13-percent penalty. Do the Democratic leaders want to raise taxes on these small business taxpayers, restricting the ability of small business to create jobs?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Treasury also projects that small business gets over 80 percent of the benefits of the cuts in the top two rates. Do we want to raise the tax rates on these people--small businesses for the most part--by 13 percent? Does that make any sense? So to the Democratic leadership, what do you say?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>How about the death tax relief package? The Joint Committee on Taxation scores that package at $499 billion over 10 years. Most of the revenue loss is attributable to increasing the exemption amount and dropping the rate to 45 percent on already taxed property. Is it unreasonable to provide relief from the death tax or should we raise the death tax on small businesses and family farms? That is what will happen if the bipartisan tax relief package is not extended. So to the Democratic leadership,  what is your take on that provision?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Do the opponents want to repeal the proposal to double the child tax credit, which the 2001 bill does? Mr. President, 31.6 million families benefit from the child tax credit, according to the Joint Committee on Taxation. Or how about the refundable piece that helps 16 million kids and their families? That proposal loses $135 billion over 10 years. I do not think we would have a lot of takers on that one. They are going to want to extend that. Democratic leadership, do you agree?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>How about the lower rates on capital gains and dividends? Thirty-three million Americans--a good number of them low-income seniors--benefit from the lower tax rates on capital gains and dividends, according to the Joint Committee on Taxation. Does the Democratic leadership think we should raise taxes on these 33 million Americans benefiting from these lower tax rates? That would be families and individuals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On a side note, in another speech, I will be talking about the worrisome Goldman Sachs economic report on the adverse economic effects of failing to extend lower rates on capital gains--this line right here, as shown on the chart--when it expires.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There are consequences to what Congress does. When you have a booming economy, there could be very detrimental consequences to the country when you take away the incentives that have had this economy exploding like not any time since the early 1990s.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let's take a look at the marriage penalty piece. It is the first marriage penalty relief we delivered in over 30 years. The Joint Committee on Taxation scores this proposal at $52 billion over 10 years, and Treasury estimates that in 2004, nearly 33 million married couples benefited from this tax relief. Again, I do not think many folks would want to raise taxes on people because they decided to be married. I hope the Democratic leadership would agree with that statement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Another proposal is expensing for small businesses; in other words, writing everything off in 1 year instead of stretching it out over 10 years. This is a commonsense, bipartisan proposal and directed specifically to small business--the engine that creates new jobs. According to IRS Statistics of Income, 6.7 million small businesses across the country benefited from this expensing provision in 2004. If we do not make it permanent, small businesses face a tax increase of $19 billion over 10 years  and probably sputtering the engine that creates so many jobs in America. Does the Democratic leadership think small business expensing is an unwise tax policy?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Continuing on through the bipartisan tax relief package, let's take a look at education tax relief. This package, which will help Americans deal with college education costs, scores at $12 billion over 10 years by the Joint Committee on Taxation. IRS Statistics of Income show nearly 16 million families and students benefited from this tax relief in 2004.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In this era of rising higher education costs, should we gut tax benefits for families to send their kids off to college? Does the Democratic leadership think that is the way to go, which would be the way we would go if Congress does nothing and you let this tax law sunset?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, families where both parents work have to deal with childcare expenses. The tax relief package includes enhanced incentives for childcare expenses. Mr. President, 5.9 million families across America benefit, according to the Joint Committee on Taxation. Does the Democratic leadership think we ought to take away these childcare benefits? That is what would happen if the tax cuts of 2001 were sunset. It would happen without a vote of the Congress either.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, I have taken you through about $1.9 trillion of tax relief. It sounds like a lot in abstraction, but it provides relief to every American who pays income tax. I would ask any of those who want to adjust or restructure--and those are words that are used around here about this tax relief package passed in 2001--do you want to adjust it or restructure it? Where would you cut in this package?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Would you hit the 10-percent bracket, driving up the taxes of low-income people? Would you hit small business tax relief and sputter the growth machine, the job machine of America; or the now refundable child tax credit, and hurt low-income people; or the death tax relief; or the marriage penalty relief;  dividends and capital gains relief; education tax relief; or childcare tax relief? I hope not. Because in a recovering economy, with above-average levels  of individual income tax, as a percentage of GDP, even with the tax relief package in place, which areas would you adjust, which areas would you restructure?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Why, then, undo bipartisan--with emphasis upon "bipartisan"--tax cuts that make the Tax Code actually more progressive? Now get that, not regressive; it is more progressive now than before the tax bill of 2001.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As folks on both sides of the aisle say, budgets are about priorities. As the Democratic leadership draws up its budget, we will hear a lot of talk about a big number for extending tax relief. It is a big number. It is the biggest tax increase ever. It is going to affect nearly every American taxpayer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If leadership now in the majority of this body, because of the results of the last election, decides to propose the biggest tax increase in history in the name of deficit reduction, I will be looking for that one, single dollar of spending restraint I never see. Now, maybe we will see it, but I will bet we would not. Only time will tell, and it will be within the next 2 or 3 weeks.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I yield the floor. I do not think I see any colleagues who wish to speak, so I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300078" topic="TAXES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300078" topic="TAXES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent to speak as in morning business.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300078" topic="SPACE STATION SAFETY REPORT">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, there was a space station task force safety report released yesterday which points out a number of hazards as we are now in the process of completing the space station. Remember that we have this multibillion-dollar structure about 300 miles above the Earth, with a crew of three, and eventually it will have more of a complement, of five or six, which will have the ongoing, full-time responsibility of scientific experiments. Right now it is about two football  fields long. During the completion, which will occur over the next 3 years, it will have all the additional appendages, including the international laboratory we need to conduct all of the experiments that we want. Yet the task force that released its report yesterday says there are certain inherent hazards that we have always known about, such as meteorites striking and/or space debris.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The U.S. Air Force catalogs all of the space debris. Therefore, we have the ability, if something really got in the way, to actually maneuver the space station out of the way of that debris--if we know where that debris is. The same is true with weather and reconnaissance satellites. I don't need to say anything about weather satellites here. Everybody knows because it is obvious what technology we have today to see the approaching storms, and if you live on the coast and it is during the summer,  it is all the more important, because of an inbound hurricane, that everybody is prepared.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Well, what is preparing us? It is not only that airplane that is flying into the hurricane, it is those satellites that are constantly tracking the position of that hurricane. Those are threatened by this space debris, which brings me to share with my colleagues: Isn't it interesting that there has almost been a strange silence throughout the world for the last 6 weeks after the Chinese tested their antisatellite missile, which created a debris field that is 100 times more than any debris that  has been created, and because of its altitude, some 500 miles, it is going to be years before all of that debris is pulled back to Earth by the gravitational pull of the Earth?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is that debris field of thousands of particles, as a result of the Chinese rocket destroying a Chinese satellite by hitting it and exploding all of the kinetic energy in parts into the vacuum of space, that now we have a new threat not only to our space station but also to all of our weather satellites and our reconnaissance satellites. So my colleagues can imagine the headache now for the U.S. Air Force of trying to track all of that Chinese debris, much more so I think just from that one  explosion, more debris than all the other debris that is up there. It is going to take several years before it ever comes down because of the altitude where the kinetic energy occurred when the vehicle slammed into the target, which was an old Chinese weather satellite.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So as we are looking at the future of NASA and the completion of the space station and the saving of the Hubble space telescope, which has opened vast vistas of new knowledge to us about the heavens and about the origin of the universe, thanks to the Chinese, as we do this we now have to worry about something that could be lethal to our astronauts and cosmonauts who are onboard the space station.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Some of the things they are talking about in this report released yesterday include some kind of special curtains they put over the windows that would give extra protection to the glass of the space station windows. Others are talking about protective blankets they might put over very sensitive areas of the space station that could be hit by debris. This debris could be coming at a velocity of 10,000 miles per hour because, if it is in a different orbit and suddenly it crosses the orbit of the  space station and hits it--remember, going around the Earth in orbital velocity is 17,500 miles an hour. If that debris hits at right angles, you are going to have a velocity of 17,500 miles an hour. With the space station going at a different orbit, you start to see the kind of kinetic energy that could rain from such a collision. So it complicates it, and it complicates it not only for the American space program but for every space program on planet Earth, and that is the problem.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is what the Chinese have done for us. Yet there has been a suspicious silence of anybody speaking out in the world community about what the Chinese have done in space. There was an intellectual discussion about China having shown they have the capability of targeting an antisatellite to hit a satellite, which is a significant feat. But in the process, they ignored the threats now to all of the human and nonmanned assets that are up there, not just for our country but for every country in  the world that depends on a satellite or a spacecraft of some kind.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is what we are facing. That is what we have to figure a plan for. I hope the Chinese who have had singular success--and this Senator has invited their Chinese astronaut to come here and visit, and he did. This Senator has congratulated them on their space accomplishments. But this time China has done something in accomplishing something technologically that has endangered the other nations of the world with the manned and the unmanned programs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is what is facing us. This is only the first the Chinese have heard from this Senator about how they have endangered the interests of planet Earth.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I yield the floor and suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="SPACE STATION SAFETY REPORT">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="SPACE STATION SAFETY REPORT">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise to speak about two parts of the bill that is before us, the Improving America's Security Act, which is really the attempt by our committee and the Senate to finish the job the 9/11 Commission gave us to protect the security of the American people from terrorist attack and also to adopt for the first time a national all-hazards defense strategy that would set up a system that would not only be aimed at preventing and, if, God forbid, necessary, responding to  a terrorist attack but  also being ready and preparing every level of government to be ready to respond to a natural disaster.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The amendment offered by the Senator from South Carolina is pending. I wanted, in the interim, hoping others will come to the floor to offer other amendments or speak on that pending amendment, to speak about these two parts of the bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The first is about what is one of the most significant changes the bill would make; that is, to establish for the first time a dedicated grant program to assist States and localities in creating interoperable communications systems to be used to protect the American people in time of emergency. The ability of first responders to communicate with one another is fundamental at a time of disaster. Yet time and time again over the years, disasters have occurred, and police, firefighters, and emergency  medical workers are unable to exchange critical information with one another, even indications of their location. Sometimes, as we saw in Katrina, certainly, not only is this a problem of their not being able to communicate with one another, it is a problem of their not being able to communicate at all. There is a painful and tragic cost to this failure to communicate or to interoperate with others in law enforcement, and that is that lives are lost.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is a problem which was intensely made clear to all of us on September 11, 2001 and again during Katrina, but it is not new. In 1982, the record shows, communications difficulties frustrated the recovery efforts in response to the crash of the Air Florida plane right here in Washington, DC. In 1995, again the record shows communications difficulties complicated the response to the terrorist bombing of the Alfred P. Murrah Federal Building in Oklahoma City, OK. In 1999, communications difficulties  again slowed the response to the shootings at Columbine High School near Littleton, CO.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Then came 9/11. The story of the communication breakdown among New York City's first responders is well known. It is well known because it cost the lives of some of the bravest Americans, some on duty and some off duty, who rushed to the aid of their fellow citizens and fellow first responders. But there were other communications breakdowns on September 11, 2001, as well--less well known but also breakdowns that hampered the response at the Pentagon and in Shanksville, PA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>After an in-depth look at the three incidents I have described--the Pentagon, the World Trade Center, and the plane that went down in Pennsylvania on 9/11--the 9/11 Commission wrote:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The occurrence of this problem at three very different sites is strong evidence that compatible and adequate communications among public safety organizations at the local, State, and Federal level remains an important problem.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That was the 9/11 Report which came out in 2004. We are now at the end of February 2007, and that problem remains as real and intense as ever.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Commission recommended expediting and increasing the assignment of radio spectrum for public safety purposes. In 2005, as part of the Deficit Reduction Act, Congress set February 2009 as the deadline for broadcasters to transition to digital signals, which will free up much-needed spectrum for first responders. A lot of us, including myself, believed that delay to February 2009 was too long. The occupant of the chair remembers that well; we stood together on that. But so be it, that is what  it is.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Since that time, Hurricane Katrina devastated the gulf coast, particularly the great city of New Orleans, and reminded us again how much more needs to be done to improve communications operability, to sustain the very operation of an emergency communications system, and interoperability, the ability of different first responders to communicate with one another.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The communications infrastructure in Louisiana and Mississippi at the time of Hurricane Katrina was decimated. Once again, difficulties in communicating among officials and first responders significantly impeded rescue and relief efforts. Mississippi Governor Haley Barbour drove the point home when he said the chief of the National Guard in Mississippi "might as well have been a Civil War general for the first 2 or 3 days" because in order to get information, he had to use runners. His runners  had helicopters instead of horses, but the point was clear. The lack of operable or interoperable communications equipment put first responders in that disaster back about a century and a half.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee, which is proud to claim the Presiding Officer as a member, investigated the preparations for and response to Hurricane Katrina, a 9-month investigation that produced a 700-page report and almost 90 recommendations. We enacted some of those recommendations last fall as part of the Post-Katrina Emergency Management Reform Act. That legislation, which I am proud has largely become law, included ways to improve planning and coordination, establish  a much needed national emergency communications plan, and strengthen technical guidance and assistance to local first responders. The newly created Office of Emergency Communications, which was created therein, will be responsible for carrying out many of those responsibilities. Like many of the homeland security challenges we face, achieving nationwide operability and interoperability of communications will require significant resources, a lot of money. One estimate from our Government several years ago put the figure at $15 billion. Testimony before the Senate Commerce Committee this past month estimated that the cost may be as</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is an important investment, a kind of leverage for the Federal Government to create in partnership with the States and local governments. Of course, part of the reason there is not only financial need but programmatic policy justification for this. The kinds of attacks, the kinds of natural disasters we are talking about, as we saw most painfully in Katrina, have national consequences. The Federal Government needs to be there to make some additional investments on which the State and local  governments will build.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation, <bill type="s" number="4">S. 4</bill>, before the Senate today authorizes $3.5 billion over 5 years, beginning in the coming fiscal year. That is on top of the $1 billion interoperability grant program to be administered by the Department of Commerce during this fiscal year, the result of previous legislation. This is the beginning of moving toward a genuine national system, if we can adopt this and fund it, a call to the States and localities to match that money, each in their own way, so we can build this  survivable network of communications.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Individual States will be able to apply for grants under this new program, which will be administered by FEMA, with assistance from the Office of Emergency Communications. The committee was very anxious, as the Presiding Officer knows, to not only create a fund of money and throw it out there for every local official who had some idea about how to create interoperable communications--all applications will have to be consistent with each State's communications plan and the national emergency communication  plan which is being developed and expanded by the new Office of Emergency Communications. In other words, to get money, you have to prove you are going to fit into a statewide and national plan for interoperability of communications.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Incidentally, the national element of this is pretty obvious. In Katrina, you had a lot of first responders streaming into the gulf coast, and New Orleans particularly, when local first responders were overwhelmed. They were all bringing their own communications systems with them. A similar response occurred--a really moving patriotic response--after 9/11 to New York City, with first responders from all over the country coming in.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What do we want at that point? A Tower of Babel, where people cannot communicate with one another, or the ability, easily, as part of a national communications plan, to do so? Obviously, the latter is what we want.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>States, incidentally, which would be the recipients of this money, would be required to pass at least 80 percent of the grant funding to local and tribal governments. The money could then be used for a range of activities: planning, system design, engineering, training, exercises, procurement, and installation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We also include a minimum amount of funding for each State because interoperability is an all-hazards concern. In other words, we are having a well-intentioned, good-faith debate about homeland security grants and to what extent--as some would say--should they all be distributed based on risk or be distributed with a minimum amount going to each State?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In this case of interoperability of communications, it seems to me the argument is compelling there ought to be some element that gives a minimum to each State because what we are trying to establish is a national emergency communications system that will be ready to respond not just to a potential terrorist attack, but to natural disasters which, obviously, can occur anywhere in the country. In other words, the ability for first responders and other emergency responders to communicate with one  another, either by voice or through data sharing, is necessary regardless of the nature of the emergency.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In short, we owe it to the memory of the firefighters and police officers who gave their lives on 9/11, some of whom lost their lives because of the absence of interoperable communications, and to the commitment of first responders who struggled under such adverse circumstances to do their jobs in the aftermath of Hurricane Katrina, and to first responders and emergency managers today all across our country who are ready to respond in the time of our need to pass this legislation, to provide  the funding necessary for this critical effort, and to move the Nation's first responders toward real 21st century operable and interoperable communications in the face of disaster.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have one more topic I want to discuss at this time. The one I have just talked about--a dedicated fund for interoperable communications--I think is one of the most significant parts of the bill. It is the beginning of a transformational partnership between the Federal, State, local, and tribal governments that I am convinced will have a measurable, significant effect on the security of the American people.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This next topic I want to talk about has to do with a provision in the committee bill which extends employee rights and protections to airport screeners who work for the Transportation Security Administration. Frankly, I do not consider this to be a major part of the bill. To me, it is correcting an inequity that exists in current law. I honestly do not know why anybody would oppose it. I will listen to the arguments, but I want to contrast it with the section I just described, because if the  last 24 hours are any indication, this section may receive more attention than any other section of the bill. The White House has indicated it will veto the bill if this section is in it. I respectfully do not understand that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Colleagues, I know, are preparing to come to the floor to try to strike this section from the bill. I think this section is an act of elemental fairness, granting quite limited employee rights to airport screeners who are now denied--I am using this term beyond its judicial meaning--equal protection that is enjoyed by most every other Federal employee, including most every other Federal employee involved in security.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I hope, one, we do not spend a disproportionate amount of time on this section; and, two, we do not allow it to get in the way of us fulfilling our urgent responsibility to finish the job of enacting the recommendations of the 9/11 Commission, which <bill type="s" number="4">S. 4</bill>, the legislation before us, would do.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I wish to spend a few moments talking about this section of the bill. The fact is, since the Transportation Security Administration was created in 2001, TSA screeners have been denied the same employment rights and protections as almost all of their fellow workers in TSA. In fact, they have been denied the same rights and protections that are enjoyed by most of their fellow employees at the Department of Homeland Security, such as the Border Patrol and Customs and Immigration officers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>TSA screeners--often also known as TSOs, transportation security officers--are familiar to most Americans because we see them at every airport across our country. Thanks, in part, I believe to their hard work and diligence, we have been spared a repeat of September 11, and air travel generally is safer than it was before that day.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>They deserve to be treated equally in their employment rights. It is long past time to provide the same protections to TSA screeners as are enjoyed by their colleagues.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I wish to take just a moment to review the history of how this inequality came to exist. Shortly after the September 11 attacks, Congress federalized the work of passenger and baggage screeners at U.S. airports. TSA was created within the Department of Transportation. It was subject generally to the same personnel rules as the Federal Aviation Administration. Responding to the sense of emergency at the time, however--remember, this was right after 9/11--Congress gave the head of TSA broad authority  to set personnel rules at his own discretion for airport screeners.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 2002, when Congress established the Department of Homeland Security to coordinate and strengthen our defenses against manmade and natural disasters, TSA was removed from the Department of Transportation and put into the Department of Homeland Security.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>At that time, Congress engaged in extensive debate with quite serious partisan and political overtones about how to apply civil service law to employees at the new Department. This was an amalgam of 22 different agencies, almost 180,000 employees, most of whom were coming already with their own  employee rights--their own rights--most particularly, to join a union.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ultimately, and contrary to my own position, Congress authorized the Department of Homeland Security Secretary to waive certain provisions of civil service law which Congress and the President believed were necessary for national security purposes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Meanwhile, since 2001, TSA has declared itself exempt from laws enforcing the most basic employee protections, including the Whistleblower Protection Act, the Rehabilitation Act protecting Federal employees with disabilities, the Federal Sector Labor-Management Relations statute, appeal of adverse personnel actions to the Merit Systems Protection Board, and veterans preference laws.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In each case, the Transportation Security Agency has devised its own version of these fundamental employee protections substantially below the standard that Congress and the President decided were appropriate generally for DHS employees.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So now you have this anomaly because of this unusual statutory history where TSA screeners have a much lower level of employee protection than most of the other employees at the Department of Homeland Security.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is now 5 years after the agency was established, and TSA screeners still lack those basic rights that are available to their colleagues at DHS and throughout the Federal Government. That is exactly the inequity this small provision in this bill, <bill type="s" number="4">S. 4</bill>, aims to overcome.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For example, TSA screeners have no individual right to appeal to the Merit Systems Protection Board when they believe they have been subject to unlawful retaliation for protected whistleblowing activity. OK, this is exactly what we want employees of the Federal Government to do. They are our representatives. We are paying them. If they see something wrong going on, we want them to blow the whistle, and we do not want them to be punished as a result.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But under the current state of the law, TSA screeners do not have any right to an outside appeal when they believe they have been subject to unlawful retaliation because they blew the whistle on something or someone else they saw doing something they thought was wrong.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Second, TSA is not bound and the screeners are not protected by the Rehabilitation Act. So TSA is not bound  to make reasonable accommodations for a disabled screener still able to perform his duties. This is the basic mindset we have overcome in recent decades, that somebody who may be disabled in one way is--if I can make up a word--abled in many other ways and perhaps, therefore, able to carry out the responsibilities of a screener at one of the security  checkpoints we have all gone through. We have all gone through them, so we know there are a number of those functions that could be performed by somebody who may have a disability. But there is no right to appeal if an employee, a screener, thinks they have been discriminated against based on that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>TSOs--that is, screeners--are allowed to join a union, but they cannot collectively bargain as other security forces at DHS and throughout the Federal Government can do. Nor can TSOs claim an unfair labor practice with the independent Federal Labor Relations Authority.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to stress something. Screeners at TSA can join a union. They cannot strike. There is nothing in this small provision in <bill type="s" number="4">S. 4</bill> that will give them the right to strike. There is nothing in this provision that will give them the right to strike. I fear people hearing about this provision may think we want to extend some employee rights to TSA screeners and may think, oh, my God, at a time of crisis these people will just walk off their jobs and strike. It is illegal. They cannot do it. It  is the same limitation that is on Federal employees who have collective bargaining rights generally. It is just that these screeners have much less, many fewer rights than others do. They cannot claim an unfair labor practice with the independent Federal Labor Relations Authority.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Finally, unlike the rest of the Federal Government, TSA limits the veterans preference in hiring and other personnel decisions to veterans who retired from the Armed Services, and denies the preference to those who were honorably discharged. Of course, it is the vast majority of men and women who have served our country in uniform who are honorably discharged as opposed to serving until the time of their retirement. But they do not get any veterans preference in hiring and other personnel decisions  at the TSA.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Is that a big deal? It is if you are a veteran. One of the things this provision in this bill would say is that, the full veterans preference should apply for TSA screeners.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So that is the amendment we adopted, the literal effect of which is to instruct the Secretary of Homeland Security to include TSA screeners, either under the departmentwide human resources management system or under the specialized system that now applies to TSA employees other than the screeners, in the most specific way, which leaves no ground--no gaps for misunderstanding. Although there are people, I fear, who are misunderstanding or misstating it, this amendment simply and directly says  that TSA screeners have to be included under the departmentwide DHS human resources management system, or under the specialized system that applies to TSA employees other than the screeners.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I know critics of this provision are arguing right now that TSA needs flexibility to manage the screener workforce in a way that provides security when, where, and how it is needed, such as when the threat level is raised, or when a new threat becomes evident, or when unexpected problems arise at a particular location so the Administrator of TSA would want to move screeners from one airport to another. This argument is not based on fact. The concerns are misplaced. The committee bill, in this  small section, retains flexibility for the TSA Administrator to promptly redeploy employees, change their assignments, or otherwise respond to problems as they arise. The bill recognizes this is a department which has to have the flexibility, the management flexibility, to respond to emergencies.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is another reason to do this, I believe, apart from equity, and that goes to the effectiveness of the TSA screeners and the Department of Homeland Security employees generally. Personnel management at TSA, the record will show, has been troubled since its inception. The record will show the agency has experienced unusually high rates of attrition--people leaving, unusually high rates of workplace injury, high rates of absenteeism, and other indications of low employee morale. Anybody in  the private sector will tell you if you have high attrition, high workplace injury, absenteeism, and low morale, you have a problem, and the problem is going to mean the service you are intending to provide is not going to be what you want it to be.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would say those problems interfere with establishing and maintaining the core of experienced and professional screeners we need, that the American people need to ensure aviation security. From conversations I have had with screeners, simply taking a step to put them on an equal plane with everybody else in TSA or DHS in terms of their employee rights will go a long way toward creating the kind of morale, devotion to work, and avoidance of workplace injury that will better serve our Nation.  I know the Administrator of TSA, Kip Holley, has recently made some efforts to improve personnel management, but I believe they haven't gone far enough, and this amendment will take them a large step forward.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I want to say finally that when the Homeland Security and Government Affairs Committee marked up the bill, there was apparently a Transportation Security Agency screener by the name of A.J. Castilla who was there in the public section of the room. Later he wrote a note of thanks in which he said:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We TSOs aren't asking for special treatment, merely to be made whole and equal again in the eyes of the law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A.J. Castilla is committed to his job, is as committed as any other employee of the Department of Homeland Security or the Transportation Security Administration, and it is time to give him and every other TSA screener parity with those other Federal employees so that they may better do the critical work we ask and need them to do.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I appreciate the opportunity to speak at some length about these two provisions. Both are, I think, important. One is a dedicated grant program for interoperable communications that, as I said, I think will have a critical effect and I hope we will discuss the positive effect. The second, I am afraid, will be discussed more than it deserves. That provision is fair. It is simple equity. It treats working people with the fairness they deserve, and in fact will improve our security, not hamper it,  as its critics say. I urge my colleagues to look at both carefully, and particularly when an amendment is offered, as I fear it will be, to strike the section that would correct the inequity now suffered by transportation screeners, when it comes to the floor, that my colleagues will come, will listen, and ultimately will vote to reject that amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank the Chair, I yield the floor, and I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="SPACE STATION SAFETY REPORT">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent to set aside the pending amendment and call up amendment No. 269.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, for the moment I am going to object on behalf of Senator Collins who is co-managing the bill with me because no one has looked at the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300043" topic="">
    <paragraph>Thank you very much, Mr. President. The amendment I am seeking to bring up is a bill that has been reported out of the Judiciary Committee, and essentially what it would do is ensure the confirmation of all U.S. attorneys by the Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What happened was that in 2006, an amendment went into the PATRIOT  Act that allowed the administration to appoint an interim U.S. attorney indefinitely without confirmation. In the early part of this year, I believe it was on January 6, I learned that six U.S. attorneys had been called and summarily told they were to resign effective a specific date in January. I was told by the person who gave me the information that there was something suspicious about  that. I didn't know, so I began to look into it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Well, I received a new story today about one of those U.S. attorneys, and if I might, I will read it to this body. It is an article by Marisa Taylor of the McClatchy Newspapers:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The U.S. Attorney from New Mexico who was recently fired by the Bush administration said Wednesday that he believes he was forced out because he refused to rush an indictment in an ongoing probe of local Democrats a month before November's congressional elections.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>David Iglesias said two Members of Congress separately called in mid October to inquire about the timing of an ongoing probe of a kickback scheme and appeared eager for an indictment to be issued on the eve of the elections in order to benefit the Republicans. He refused to name the Members of Congress because he said he feared retaliation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Two months later, on December 7, Iglesias became one of six U.S. Attorneys ordered to step down for what administration officials have termed "performance-related issues." Two other U.S. Attorneys also have been asked to resign.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Iglesias, who received a positive performance review before he was fired, said he suspected he was forced out because of his refusal to be pressured to hand down an indictment on the ongoing probe:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe that because I didn't play ball, so to speak, I was asked to resign, said Iglesias, who officially stepped down on Wednesday.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Iglesias acknowledged that he had no proof that the pressure from the congressional members prompted his forced resignation, but he said the contact in and of itself violated one of the most important tenets of a U.S. Attorney's Office: Don't mix politics with prosecutions. The article goes on.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now this is only one element of this story. The matter has been the subject of a hearing in the Judiciary Committee. Legislation is ready to come before the floor. I have introduced it as an amendment. We approved it in the Judiciary Committee with a bipartisan vote. I think the time has come to do two things. One would be for the Judiciary Committee--and I hope it will, and I believe the chairman of the Subcommittee on Administrative Oversight and The Courts, Senator Schumer, is interested  in doing this--to issue subpoenas to have these U.S. attorneys come before the Committee to answer questions about how their demanded resignations took place.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Generally, a U.S. attorney is appointed for a term of four years, but serves at the pleasure of the President. If he wants to fire them he can. However, U.S. attorneys have very complicated and very difficult cases and I believe they must have some level of independence. The FBI, as we have heard in our oversight hearings, has raised the level of public corruption in their investigations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So if the FBI investigates a case and comes up with the evidence, a U.S. attorney is obviously bound to prosecute that case. How this affects David Iglesias, I don't know. But the fact that these people all had very good performance reviews causes me a great concern. I wish to read from those performance reviews.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The performance review for John McKay of the Western District of Washington says:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>"McKay is an effective, well-regarded and capable leader of the [U.S. attorney's office] and the District's law enforcement community," according to the team of 27 Justice Department officials.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>David Iglesias, about whom I read the news story, of the District of New Mexico, got this performance review:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The [U.S. Attorney] had a highly effective firearms violence initiative and active and effective program to address drug trafficking.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Daniel Bogden, District of Nevada:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>United States Attorney Bogden was highly regarded by the federal judiciary, the law enforcement and civil client agencies, and the staff of the United States Attorney's Office. He was a capable leader of the [office].</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Bud Cummins, who many of us know, in the Eastern District of Arkansas:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The U.S. Attorney had an active, well managed anti-terrorism program ..... The Project Safe Neighborhoods initiatives were being effectively implemented and successfully managed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Carol Lam, Southern District of California, including San Diego, whom I am very familiar with:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Carol Lam was an effective manager and respected leader in the District ..... Appropriate management procedures and practices were in place to ensure a quality written work product.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These are some of the snippets from the reviews. But clearly, the performance of these U.S. attorneys was not a reason to fire them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I truly believe what the Department of Justice intended to do was what they did in the Eastern District of Arkansas--bring in bright, young Republican political operatives to assume these roles to give them a leg up and fire or require the resignation of these U.S. attorneys.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When I began to inquire into it, I asked whether interviews for replacements were taking place within these offices, particularly in San Diego. At that time, no one in the office was being interviewed as a replacement. Since these hearings have begun, individuals within the office have been interviewed. In fact, one has been appointed to fill in for former U.S. Attorney Carol Lam.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I truly believe there was an effort to use this section of the PATRIOT Act reauthorization to bring political operatives into these offices, and I think it is a matter of urgency for us to pass the legislation that was marked up by the Judiciary Committee. Absent that, there is no recourse, other than to issue subpoenas, to have these former U.S. attorneys come before the committee and be able to ask them some hard questions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think when a U.S. attorney who has served, and served well, is summarily dismissed for no real reason, it is a problem. We all know the U.S. attorney in San Diego brought the prosecution of a Member of the House of Representatives who is serving consequential time for major felonies and had subpoenas outstanding for other Members of the House and was summarily told in December that she should resign--in this case--by the end of January. That is not right.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So the only way I know to right the wrong is to restore the law to where it was before the PATRIOT Act reauthorization. That law is this amendment and the amendment is very simple. It simply says that the Attorney General may appoint an interim U.S. attorney to a vacancy for 120 days. After 120 days, if a nominee has not been confirmed by the Senate, the district court in the district where the vacancy exists can make an appointment. This provides the incentive for the administration to move  a nominee. I should say there are 13 vacancies, of which only 3 nominees have presently been sent to the Senate. If you combine those 13 vacancies with the seven new vacancies, then over 20 percent of the U.S. attorney positions could be filled without Senate confirmation if we assume the</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If the law is left as it is, any Attorney General or President could essentially appoint every single U.S. attorney as an interim U.S. attorney, not subject to confirmation. If you consider the work of the U.S. attorneys--the public corruption, the major narcotics cases, the immigration cases, the complicated Federal law they carry out--I think every Member of this body would believe that confirmation by the Senate for every U.S. attorney should be assured. This amendment will carry that forward.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I was shocked to read about David Iglesias. I don't know whether it is accurate. I know it appeared in the news. Based on that, he has said he believes he was forced out for a political reason. There is only one way to find out, and that is for the Judiciary Committee to issue subpoenas, have these U.S. attorneys come before us, and ask a number of hard questions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am hopeful this body will see fit to pass this amendment. It is simple, short, direct, and it solves the problem.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Maine is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, knowing the Senator from California as I do, I am certain a lot of the issues she has raised are serious ones, deserving of  scrutiny. They are, however, under the jurisdiction of the Judiciary Committee and not the Homeland Security Committee. As such, I don't feel that I, at this time, have the expertise or the knowledge to evaluate the amendment that has been filed by the Senator from California. That is why I am objecting  to the amendment. It is not because of its merits but because it is not relevant to this debate. I have not had a chance to look at it, and it is not in the jurisdiction of the Homeland Security Committee.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I will say to my colleagues that the Senator from Connecticut and I have been working very hard in a bipartisan way to try to keep the focus of this bill on issues to improve our homeland security. We were very pleased that, despite the overwhelming importance of the debate on Iraq, there had been an agreement by our leaders to try to keep that debate for the next issue to come before the Senate, rather than having it tied in with this bill. Similarly, the families of the victims of 9/11 have  made a plea to all of us to focus on this bill and to keep extraneous issues off this bill and rather focus on issues the 9/11 Commission raised. That is what we are attempting to do. I have no doubt this is an important issue, an issue that is worthy of debate,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For that reason, my hope is the Senator from California will look at this as an opportunity to educate us on the issue but will not proceed with this amendment because it is not at all relevant to the bill before us.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from New York is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300087" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I rise to follow up on the comments of my friend from California, who has legislation I am proud to cosponsor on the general issue of the fired U.S. attorneys.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, it is said that "where there is smoke there is fire." As we look at the case of the U.S. attorneys, that is more and more likely to be true.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, according to the McClatchy Newspapers, one of the fired U.S. attorneys from New Mexico said that "two Members of Congress separately called in mid-October to inquire about the timing of an ongoing probe of a kickback scheme and appeared eager for an indictment to be issued on the eve of the elections in order to benefit the Republicans."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is a quote in an article by Marisa Taylor of the McClatchy Newspapers. Frankly, it comes as no surprise to me. That is because David Iglesias, the U.S. attorney, told my staff the same thing the day before. He asked, in fact, that he be brought to Washington--was willing, rather, to be brought to Washington, under the power of subpoena, to tell his story. We have inquired of the fired U.S. attorneys. The overwhelming majority of them want to tell more but feel honor-bound not to do it, except  if they were brought under the power of subpoena to Washington.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I join certainly in the request of my colleague from California and others. I have already spoken to Senator Leahy, and we are examining how that can be accomplished. Senator Leahy is very mindful of the fact that the Judiciary Committee doesn't issue subpoenas willy-nilly. But given the fact that some of the U.S. attorneys expressed a desire to testify, and others said they would be willing to testify, and now with these new revelations, the fear many of us had that these  U.S. attorneys were summarily fired not for no reason and not for a good reason but for a bad reason is coming closer to reality.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, we must get to the bottom of this issue. The U.S. attorney is the lead enforcer of the law in his or her jurisdiction. Fortunately, for decades, the U.S. attorneys, almost without exception, have been insulated from the political process, even though they are chosen in part by the political process. So when six were fired in one evening, and when it later became clear in hearings I held that at least one, by the admission of the Deputy Attorney General, was fired for no reason,  and a call from the White House to suggest a replacement who was someone with very little legal experience but someone who had worked for both Karl Rove and the RNC, I believe it was, you can imagine the concern that not only the Senator from California and I had but the concern throughout the country in law enforcement--nonpolitical, simply a desire to protect the integrity of the U.S. attorneys. So we must do two things now.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These new revelations are extremely troubling. They would show politics at its worst--the long hand of the Justice Department reaching out to fire U.S. attorneys who would not do what was politically asked. At least that is a very real suspicion. So we must get to the bottom of this. The only way to do that is to call before us the fired U.S. attorneys and hear their side of the story.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I remind my colleagues that we did have a briefing--the Senator from California was there, the Senator from Rhode Island was there--and then were shown the evaluation reports, the EARS reports, and almost to a person the fired U.S. attorneys received very good evaluations from their peers and from everybody else. If you read those evaluations, you would say: Oh, they will keep that person in office for as long as he or she wants to stay. But instead, they were fired.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In private conversations my staff has had with them, they have grave suspicions as to why--some of them more than grave suspicions. Today, Mr. Iglesias said publicly what he told my staff privately, that he has a very troubling view that he may well have been fired because he refused to bend his U.S. attorney's office to politics of the worst sort.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So there are two imperatives here. One, as I said, is to get to the bottom of this and get to the bottom of it quickly. The second is to pass legislation that restores the appointment of U.S. attorneys away or at least removes it somewhat from the political realm because when the Senate must confirm or when an independent judge must temporarily appoint, there is a check, there is a balance that was removed, unbeknownst to almost all of us, in the PATRIOT Act. The minute that passed, people were  surprised and wondered: Why did it happen? The explanation from the administration didn't quite ring true. Then, on the evening of December 7, when six U.S. attorneys were called at once and fired and not given any reason, suspicions went further. The investigations my subcommittee has had, with the help of our chairman, the Senator from Vermont, and the Senator from California, who has taken a keen interest in this issue and is lead sponsor of the legislation, have gotten worse every day.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As I said at the beginning of my remarks, the expression goes: Where there is smoke, there is fire. Every day, not only is there more smoke in this investigation of the firing of the U.S. attorneys, but there seems to be, unfortunately, a real fire. We will not rest until we get to the bottom of this matter, to see what happened, to see if possibly any rules, regulations, or even laws were broken. By bringing it to light, it will importune this body, the other body, and the White House to pass  legislation so that it cannot happen again.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, in sum, this is serious stuff. When U.S. attorneys are fired for political reasons, fired to stand in the way of justice rather than promote justice, it puts a dagger into the heart of the faith Americans have in their Government and in their system of justice. That faith, fortunately, is long and deep, but if we don't get to the bottom of this, if we don't change the law to make sure it doesn't happen again, we will be weakening permanently our system of justice and the faith  the public has in it.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We will move forward in whatever way we can. Hopefully, we will find it is possible to subpoena these attorneys and subpoena them quickly and then take the necessary action in these cases and prevent future cases from occurring, which justice and the faith the people have in the American system demand.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Rhode Island.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412247" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, the remarks the Senator from California and the Senator from New York  have made today are very well taken, and I rise to express my shared concern with them and my support for their initiative to get to the bottom of what took place. In May of 1994 I had the honor to be sworn in as Rhode Island's U.S. attorney. It was one of the great honors of my life, equivalent to the great honor of being sworn in with you, Mr. President,  into this extraordinary body. I knew when I took that oath that I would be forced to make very hard decisions and that my independence and my integrity would be my strongest allies as I discharged the extraordinarily difficult and powerful responsibilities of a U.S. attorney.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last December, seven U.S. attorneys were fired by the Department of Justice, all on the very same day. That is unprecedented. Never, to my knowledge, in the history of the Department have so many heads of U.S. attorneys rolled all on the same day. These men and women had been confirmed in this great Chamber. By all indications, they were well qualified and performing well in their jobs. Several of them were involved in ongoing public corruption investigations. Yet in this unprecedented step,  this administration showed them all the door. It suggests to us all the question: why might such an extraordinary act have taken place; why were they told their services were no longer required?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Attorney General, Alberto Gonzales, told us this:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What we do is make an evaluation about the performance of individuals, and I have a responsibility to the people in your district that we have the best possible people in these positions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Deputy Attorney General Paul McNulty testified that "turnover in the position of U.S. attorney is  not uncommon."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So the two suggestions that were made were that this was performance related, that a performance evaluation had been done of these individuals and they had not measured up, and that it was just turnover. It is hard to accommodate both of those stories, but when one looks into each of them, it makes even less sense.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The committee, through Senator Schumer and Senator Feinstein, asked to see the Evaluation and Review Staff reports, what is called an EARS evaluation. When I was a U.S. attorney in Rhode Island, I lived through an EARS evaluation. All the local agencies were interviewed by career U.S. attorney services staff, detailed to Rhode Island just for the purpose of doing these evaluations. They happen in every office every 3 years. They are a significant part of the oversight and management  practice of the Department of Justice, and they are extremely thorough.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We asked to see the reports. When it was clear that we were going to ask to see these performance evaluations, the Department began to back down. Mr. McNulty told the committee:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are ready to stipulate that the removal of the U.S. attorneys may or may not be something supported by an EARS report because it may be something performance related that isn't the subject of what the evaluators saw or when they saw it or how it came up, and so forth.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There isn't much that an EARS evaluation doesn't look at, and contrary views began to emerge from the Department very shortly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In an article published February 4, the Washington Post reported that:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>[O]ne administration official, who spoke on the condition of anonymity in discussing personnel issues, said the spate of firings was the result of "pressure from people who make personnel decisions outside of Justice who wanted to make some things happen in those places."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let's look at some of those places. In Arkansas, H.E. Bud Cummins III was a 5-year veteran U.S. attorney serving in Arkansas's Eastern District. Last June, he was asked to resign. The man chosen to replace the well-respected Mr. Cummins was Tim Griffin. Mr. Griffin is 37 years old. He served as Special Assistant to Assistant Attorney General Michael Chertoff in the Criminal Division of the Department of Justice, where he was sent as a detailee to the Arkansas U.S. Attorney's Office.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>What Mr. Griffin lacked in prosecutorial experience, he more than made up for in political experience. Mr. Griffin is a former aide to Presidential adviser Karl Rove. He is also a former Republican National Committee research director. As those of us who have been through this sort of thing know, "research director" is not about looking up old statutes; it is about prying into personal lives of other candidates in order to try to dig up dirt on them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>A more partisan choice could not have been made to replace Mr. Cummins. Remember, Mr. McNulty said:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Department is committed to having the best person possible for discharging the responsibilities of that office at all times in every district.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is just hard to believe that Mr. Tim Griffin was the best person possible, at least not as we ordinarily define those terms. At the end of our Judiciary hearing, Mr. McNulty admitted that Mr. Cummins, the Government's chief prosecutor in Little Rock, Arkansas, was fired to give Mr. Griffin the opportunity to have the appointment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In San Diego, U.S. attorney Carol Lam successfully prosecuted Duke Cunningham, who pled guilty and resigned in 2005. She subpoenaed the House Armed Services, Appropriations, and Intelligence Committees in connection with a probe into Defense Department contracts. Her office indicted Kyle "Dusty" Foggo, the CIA's former Executive Director, and Brent Wilkes, a defense contractor and top Republican fundraiser.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In her district, former Reagan U.S. attorney Peter Nunez--another Republican political appointee familiar with the world of U.S. attorneys because he served there himself; he served from 1982 to 1988--said this:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It's just like nothing I have ever seen before in 35-plus years. To be asked to resign and to be publicly humiliated by leaking this to the press is beyond any bounds of decency and behavior. It shocks me. It is really outrageous.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>San Diego's top-ranking FBI official, Dan Dzwilewski, also commented on Lam's firing. Bear in mind, this is the Director of the FBI office that is operating as lead agency in these public corruption investigations. His quote:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I guarantee politics is involved ..... It will be a huge loss from my perspective.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Other U.S. attorneys, such as David Iglesias of New Mexico and John McKay of Seattle, said they had no idea why they were being asked to step down.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That changed recently. Today was posted a story from which I will quote:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The U.S. attorney from New Mexico who was recently fired by the Bush administration said Wednesday that he believes he was forced out because he refused to rush an indictment in an ongoing probe of local Democrats a month before November's Congressional elections.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>David Iglesias said two members of Congress separately called in mid October to inquire about the timing of an ongoing probe of a kickback scheme and appeared eager for an indictment to be issued on the eve of the elections in order to benefit the Republicans. He refused to name the members of Congress because he said he feared retaliation. .....</paragraph>
    <paragraph>"U.S. Attorney Daniel Bogden, who also stepped down Wednesday after being asked to leave in December" had it recently reported in the Wall Street Journal that the FBI was investigating in his district allegations "whether Nevada Governor Jim Gibbons performed any official acts on behalf of a contract in exchange for gifts or payments. Gibbons, a Republican, has denied any wrongdoing."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Bogden said he hoped that the ongoing case did not have anything to do with his ouster.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is his quote:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>You would like to think that the reason you're put in the position as U.S. attorney is because you are willing to step up to the plate and take on big cases, Bogden said.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It's not a good thing if you begin to wonder whether you'll lose your job if you pursue them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Last month, a Las Vegas newspaper reported:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>a GOP source said ..... the decision to remove U.S. attorneys, primarily in the West, was part of a plan to "give somebody else that experience" to build up the back bench of Republicans by giving them high-profile jobs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These are extremely troubling facts. The New York Times has recently editorialized on this subject and hypothesized three reasons for why these well-qualified attorneys were fired. As the New York Times said, "all political and all disturbing." The first reason: helping friends; the second, candidate recruitment; the third, Presidential politics.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The newspaper concluded that the politicization of Government over the last 6 years has had tragic consequences in New Orleans, in Iraq, and elsewhere, but allowing politics to infect U.S. Attorney's Offices takes it to  a whole new level. Congress should continue to pursue the case of the fired U.S. attorneys vigorously, both to find out what really happened and to make sure that it does not happen again.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I would like to highlight two further concerns that come from my experience as a U.S. attorney. One concern is how this alters the balance between U.S. Attorney's Offices and what we used to call main Justice, and the second concern is the chilling effect on prosecutions of public corruption.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is constant tension between the U.S. attorneys in the field and main Justice. The U.S. attorneys know their districts, they have practiced before those judges, they know their office's capabilities very well, and they have their own local priorities. Of course, the Department of Justice also has its own priorities, its national priorities set by the President, and the tension between those two is healthy and is constant. In getting its message out to the U.S. attorneys, the Department has  a wide array of ways to send its signals and make its wishes known, but to take six or seven well-performing U.S. attorneys and sack them all at once ends that dialogue. It brings the blunt instrument of, not even persuasion any longer, but brute force, to bear.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Now, there can very well be policy differences between the Department of Justice and local offices, but this would be a first for the Department of Justice, to say: You haven't emphasized this enough so we are going to have your head. It will squash the healthy tension between U.S. attorneys and between the Department, and at least in my experience, the greater wisdom of the Department of Justice versus that of all the U.S. attorneys in the field was not such that it justifies this level of force  in emphasis and enforcement and in the demand for conformity with its policy positions.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I submit there is long-term damage to the capabilities of the Department of Justice as this tension is disrupted. We live in a country of checks and balances, and tensions like these are very often the best things for the public we serve when they are allowed to be maintained in a healthy fashion.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The second point I would make is the chilling effect on prosecutions of public corruption. This applies particularly with respect to Ms. Lam in California. In many respects, she had become the leading edge of the Federal Government's sword point on public corruption investigation because of the investigations that I mentioned earlier in my remarks. Her office was leading the biggest public corruption cases in the Nation, with more to come it appears. U.S. Attorney Lam was personally at the helm  of these investigations, and she was well qualified for that role. Her unceremonious expulsion from office will send a shockwave through the offices of her fellow U.S. attorneys, and that shockwave will carry a very unfortunate message because these cases are not easy ones.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Public corruption cases are resource intensive for the office involved. They are extraordinarily challenging. Witnesses are scarce and difficult, significant agent expertise is required, internal procedures governing the investigation itself are complex and onerous, and launching one's office at established political figures is a decision with potentially serious consequences not only for the U.S. attorney but for the career people in that office. Someone who has come through all of that and  moved out onto the leading edge of public corruption investigation for this country, I believe, merits the active support of the Department of Justice not just for the good work done but as a message and a signal to U.S. attorneys around the country that when they step out into that public corruption arena, we will back them up.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The signal to the contrary is a dangerous one. When a U.S. attorney gets fired, and one who was deep into a public corruption investigation and is leading it so well that their termination draws a public rebuke from the FBI chief, antennae will go up across the country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent to have printed in the Record at the conclusion of my remarks a letter that the Attorney General has received from the National Association of Former United States Attorneys.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <narrative>(See exhibit 1.)</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412247" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, the sentence in that letter which strikes me as the most significant is:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are concerned that the role of the United States Attorneys may have been undermined by what may have been political considerations which run counter to the proper administration of justice and the traditions of the Department of Justice.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This is not a good day. This is not the sort of thing that we need to be discussing. This is not the sort of thing that we should be discussing. As Senator Schumer earlier said, there is a lot of smoke in the air right now, and it looks as if there is actually some fire. It is truly incumbent on this body, the body which confirmed these individuals to their offices and which has oversight responsibility with the Department of Justice, to look into what is happening and to reestablish  the procedures to prevent this from happening again.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor, and I thank the Chair.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The National Association of Former United States Attorneys, </paragraph>
    <paragraph>February 14, 2007.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>DEAR ATTORNEY GENERAL GONZALES, We are the President and Executive Director of the National Association of Former United States Attorneys ("NAFUSA"). NAFUSA was founded in March 1979 to promote, defend and further the integrity and the preservation of the litigating authority and independence of the Office of the United States Attorney. Our membership includes United States Attorneys from every administration back to President Kennedy and includes former United States Attorneys from  every state in the union. It is with this mission and with our cumulative experience as United States Attorneys that we write.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are very troubled with recent press accounts concerning the termination of a sizable number of United States Attorneys. Historically, United States Attorneys have had a certain degree of independence because of the unique and integral role the United States Attorneys play in federal law enforcement Among other things, the United States Attorney establishes and maintains working and trusting relationships with key federal, state and local law enforcement agencies. In many respects, while the  United States Attorney is a representative of the Department of Justice in each district, the United States Attorney also brings to bear his or her experience and knowledge of the law enforcement needs of the district in establishing priorities and allocating resources. Most importantly, United States Attorneys have maintained a strong.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are concerned that the role of the United States Attorneys may have been undermined by what may have been political considerations which run counter to the proper administration of justice and the tradition of the Department of Justice. While we certainly recognize that the United States Attorneys serve at the pleasure of the President, we would vigorously oppose any effort by any Attorney General to remove a United States Attorney as a result of political displeasure or for political reward.  Any such effort would undermine the confidence of the federal judiciary, federal and local law enforcement agencies, the public, and the thousands of Assistant United States Attorneys working in those offices.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We do not mean to suggest that we know the reasons for each of the terminations or, for that matter, all of the relevant facts. Indeed, we encourage the Department of Justice and Congress to make as full and as complete a disclosure of the facts surrounding these firings as is permissible. Still, the reported facts are troubling, perhaps unique in the annals of the Department of Justice, and certainly raise questions as to whether political considerations prompted the decision to terminate so  many United States Attorneys. It may well be that legislative attention or a written policy of the Department of Justice is necessary to deal with this and similar situations in the future to afford continuity and protection to United States Attorneys. We will be happy to assist the Department or Congress in any such effort.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sincerely yours,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>&lt;center&gt;ATLEE W. WAMPLER III, &lt;/center&gt;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;President.&lt;/em&gt;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>&lt;center&gt;B. MAHLON BROWN,&lt;/center&gt;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Executive Director. &lt;/em&gt;</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask for regular order in regards to my amendment No. 279. I have a modification of that amendment that I would like to send to the desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator's amendment is pending. He has the right to modify it. The amendment is so modified.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, if I can make a couple of comments about the modification, many will recall that this amendment is focused on our ports and the security of our ports. I think all of us are well aware that as a nation we see that our ports of entry, whether they be in Seattle, New York, or Charleston, SC, could be our most vulnerable points when it comes to smuggling in a weapon of mass destruction. We have committed many resources and lots of technology to try to detect  radiation and other types of weapons that might be smuggled into our country that could hurt Americans and destroy American cities, and we are making some progress. But there is a lot more to be done.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>All the spending, all the technology, all the equipment in the world will make no difference at all if we don't have the right people working in the secure areas of our ports. We need to make sure those people are the most trusted we have, just as we do in our airports. Our responsibility, whether it is homeland security as an administration or we as the Congress, is to make sure these people are screened and that we have the best and the most trusted individuals working in our secure areas.  This is very important.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My amendment focuses on just that subject. It prohibits convicted felons  from working in the secure areas of our ports. This is common sense to most Americans, and I think it is common sense to most in this Senate because when this exact same amendment was offered last year, when we were dealing with port security specifically, everyone voted for this amendment in the Senate. Unfortunately, that amendment was stripped out when we had a conference with  the House.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many of my colleagues have encouraged me to reintroduce this amendment, Republicans and Democrats alike, and that is exactly what I have done. I understand the Senator from Hawaii is considering introducing a modification that would allow the Secretary to eliminate some of these felonies that we have listed in our amendment. Please keep in mind that the listed felonies are the exact same ones that homeland security has listed in the regulation that they have put in force at their agency. So this  amendment puts in law what homeland security has already put into regulation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The importance of putting it in law is that we already suspect this legislation will be contested; that there will be delays, there will be challenges, and we need to make sure that our ports are secure. The modification of my amendment would allow the Secretary to add felonies in the future which may become important but that are not now listed. We think it would be a huge mistake if we put in law something that allowed future administrations to eliminate felonies that are specifically laid  out in regulation and in this amendment I am offering.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If anyone in the Senate would like to eliminate some of the felonies that we have listed, I would encourage them to come to the Senate floor and let's discuss those that they would like to eliminate. Maybe they would like to have some of these folks working in the secure areas of our ports, folks who have committed espionage, sedition, treason, terrorism, crimes involving transportation security, improper transport of hazardous material, unlawful use of an explosive device, bomb threats, or murder.  These are specifically listed. If there are some of these that we think should be eliminated, let's discuss them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Homeland Security has evaluated this and has listed these, just like we have for our airports, to keep our ports secure.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am offering this modification that would allow our Secretary to add felonies but prohibit the elimination of these felonies which we think are so important to our security.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank the Chair for the opportunity to offer this modification, and I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I thank the Senator from South Carolina for his modification. We talked about this briefly. I think he is heading in the right direction. We are taking a look at the amendment as it is offered, and we look forward to working together. I think the purposes are very important.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank the Chair, I yield the floor, and I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent to add Ms. Murkowski, a Senator from Alaska, as a cosponsor to the Collins amendment No. 277.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, speaking of the Collins amendment on REAL ID, cosponsored by Senators Alexander, Mikulski, Carper, Cantwell, Snowe, Chambliss, and Murkowski, I bring to my colleagues' attention the several groups representing Governors, State legislatures, and others who are now speaking in favor of passage of this amendment. In addition, as the Presiding Officer so ably represents the State of New York, there was a Newsday editorial today also endorsing the amendment  with its 2-year delay.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The National Governors Association has also issued a statement that says:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator Collins' bipartisan amendment recognizes the need to give state officials and other interested parties the right to review regulations and suggest modifications.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It goes on to say:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This proposal would provide states a more workable time frame to comply with federal standards, ensure necessary systems are operational and enhance the input states and other stakeholders have in the implementation process.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have also heard from the American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees, a union that is affiliated with the AFL-CIO, which has written a letter as well. It says:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is clear that the states do not have the capacity to comply with the REAL ID Act by the 2008 deadline and that a number of serious concerns related to privacy must be addressed. The Collins amendment provides the opportunity to address these matters.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Similarly, another group with whom we have worked closely is the National Conference of State Legislatures. In fact, it was a high-ranking official of the NCSL who sat next to me on a plane going to Maine some time ago and suggested that what States needed most was a delay in the compliance time. I worked very closely with the NCSL in drafting our amendment. I am very grateful for their advice.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the letters and editorials I have mentioned be printed in the Record so we may share them with our colleagues.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="U.S. SHOULD TAKE TIME TO GET IT RIGHT">
    <paragraph>I thank the Chair.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300056" topic="U.S. SHOULD TAKE TIME TO GET IT RIGHT">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300056" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I rise today to offer an amendment that incorporates Senator DeMint's amendment No. 279 regarding the Transportation Worker Identification Credential, known as TWIC.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am pleased to advise my colleagues of this amendment. It is cosponsored by Senator Stevens, Senator Lieberman, and Senator Murray.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The amendment offered by Senator DeMint codifies in statute the list of permanent and interim disqualifying offenses for individuals applying for a TWIC that the Department of Homeland Security has already codified in final regulations this January.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While I understand Senator DeMint's desire to ensure we do not allow individuals who could pose a terrorism security risk to have access to our ports, Senator DeMint's language restricts the authority of the Secretary to identify, adopt, and modify criminal offenses that may pose a terrorist security threat.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are all aware of the fact the war on terrorism continues to evolve with emerging threats. We need to ensure the Department has the flexibility to adjust their procedures accordingly. I, along with my fellow cosponsors, believe such a responsibility is best left to the intelligence, terrorist, and law enforcement experts at the Department of Homeland Security rather than Members of Congress. Therefore, this amendment preserves the authority of the Secretary to modify the offenses accordingly.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask my colleagues to support our amendment and help ensure we improve the security of our port facilities in a fair and effective manner.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam President, I call up my amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the clerk will report.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300056" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, the clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300022" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300022" topic="U.S. ECONOMIC SOVEREIGNTY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, we are in the middle of an ongoing discussion and debate over our homeland security, and certainly, as all of us know, this remains a matter of grave concern. Homeland security means many things, and it certainly does mean that we fully and appropriately fund our police and our fire. It means we guard our ports and our infrastructure such as our tunnels and bridges, all of which are going to be the subject of the authorization legislation brought forward by the chairman  and ranking member. But it also means we have to remain strong at home and we have to have the economic resources to spend on protecting ourselves.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Yesterday, the Dow Jones Industrial Average plummeted 416 points--the largest single drop since the markets reopened after the September 11 attacks. While our markets were reeling, alarm bells were ringing once again over the irresponsible fiscal and economic policies of this administration that continue to surrender the economic sovereignty of our country to foreign banks, investors, and governments piece by piece.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Yesterday's stock market disruption came on the heels of pessimistic economic news on the homefront and ominous comments about recession by former Fed Reserve Chairman Alan Greenspan. So while it can and will be debated whether yesterday's market fluctuation was a blip or a larger indicator of our economy's vulnerabilities, it is clear that what happened underscores the exposure of our economy to a combination of economic developments in countries such as China and economic policies here at home.  A scare in the Chinese stock market, based on rumors within that country, sent economic reverberations around the world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In terms of our fiscal stability, we are in uncharted waters. Markets, to a certain degree, will always be volatile and, to a great extent, we are fortunate that our domestic markets are deep enough to absorb certain shocks. But there is no precedent in U.S. history for an economy as large as ours to be as heavily in debt to its trading partners as the United States is to countries such as China, Japan, and others.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When it comes to the fiscal recklessness and economic fatalism of the current administration, the writing may not be on the wall, but yesterday the writing was on the "Big Board." In the face of this challenge, the economic policies of the last 6 years have contributed to an erosion of U.S. economic sovereignty and have made us more dependent on the economic decisions of other nations. As I have proposed, and continue to support, we need to take steps to restore fiscal responsibility and sound  economic policies based on the facts, not ideology.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I will continue to support legislative steps to require that the Bush administration address mounting fiscal and trade imbalances.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today I sent letters to Treasury Secretary Hank Paulson and Federal Reserve Chairman Ben Bernanke urging them to address many of our underlying economic vulnerabilities resulting from our debt and deficits.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our Nation has been running record deficits and digging a massive fiscal hole of nearly $8.8 trillion as foreign countries have been buying our debt and in essence becoming our bankers. According to the most recent Treasury statistics, foreign nations now hold more than $2.2 trillion, or 44 percent, of all publicly held U.S. debt. Japan and China alone hold nearly $1 trillion. To put it plainly: 16 percent of our entire economy is being loaned to us by the Central Banks of other nations. I know  other Members of this Chamber, such as Senator Conrad, the chairman of our Budget Committee, share my concern over the implications of this massive foreign debt.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While the foundations of our fiscal house are eroded by our fiscal policies, our failure to pursue smart economic policies has added strain on our economy. Every single year since President Bush took office we have had a record trade deficit. Last year the deficit was $764 billion. One of the ramifications of that trade deficit to foreign interests is the control by foreign interests of more and more of our assets.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>How can we negotiate fair, pro-American trade agreements and ensure foreign countries uphold these agreements when we sit across the negotiating table not only from our competitor but from our banker as well? While ceding our economic sovereignty, we also sow the seeds of economic vulnerability. Precipitous decisions by any country holding our debt could create much graver economic problems than what we saw yesterday.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I believe in smart, pro-American trade, and globalization does hold incredible promise to continue to improve our standard of living and to create economic growth. But for too long, the choices have been painted far too starkly and with a broad political brush. In fact, we can protect our economic interests while promoting trade. We can secure our economic sovereignty while promoting policies that secure our global economic position. Trade does not have to be a zero sum game.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The choice is not between fatalism and protectionism. The choice is between policies that work and policies that are not working. We have to curb these deficits and ensure foreign governments do not own too much of our Government debt. We need a firewall that keeps our economic future more in our own hands.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In years past I have worked with other Members of Congress who share my concerns. For example, during the last session of Congress I supported legislation by Senator Dorgan and then-Congressman Cardin that rings an alarm bell when U.S. foreign-owned debt reaches 25 percent of GDP or the trade deficit reaches 5 percent of GDP. It would require the administration to  develop a plan of action to address these conditions and report their findings  to Congress. At the very least this proposal would compel our Government to deal with these economic issues while they are problems but before they become crises. I believe proposals such as these need to be considered in order to put our economic house in order, as we can too easily be held hostage to the economic policies that are being made not in Washington and not in the markets of New York but in Beijing, Shanghai, Tokyo, and elsewhere.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Yesterday it was the selloff of foreign stocks that had reverberations in U.S. markets. But if China or Japan made a decision to decrease their massive holdings of U.S. dollars, there could be a currency crisis and the United States would have to raise interest rates and invite conditions for a recession. Precipitous decisions by any country holding our debt could create far graver economic consequences than what we witnessed yesterday.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While it is clear we should take reasonable steps now to ensure that the economic problems of today do not become the crises of tomorrow, we are awaiting some action by the administration that gives us a clear signal that we can begin to restore responsibility. This is a long-term problem, but it is one that I think we must respond to. We ignore it at our peril. As we saw yesterday, the United States is interconnected with globalized markets. They are not going to leave anyone out. We will all  be impacted by decisions that we have nothing to do with making, even if they are rumors or quickly reversed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is my hope what happened yesterday, which gave us headlines across the world, will open our eyes to what we need to do to take action to put ourselves in a much more competitive position and to begin to move away from the loss of economic sovereignty we have seen over the last years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Kentucky is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300014" topic="U.S. ECONOMIC SOVEREIGNTY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, what is the pending business?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Inouye amendment to <bill type="s" number="4">S. 4</bill> is pending.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300014" topic="U.S. ECONOMIC SOVEREIGNTY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent to speak as in morning business for 5 minutes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <narrative>(The remarks of Mr. Bunning are printed in today's Record under "Morning Business.")</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="U.S. ECONOMIC SOVEREIGNTY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that at 5:20 today, the Senate proceed to a vote in relation to the Inouye amendment No. 285, to be followed by a vote in relation to the DeMint amendment No. 279, as modified; with the time until then for debate to run concurrently on both amendments, with the time equally divided and controlled between Senators Inouye and DeMint or their designees; that no amendments be in order to either amendment prior to the vote and that there be 2 minutes  of debate equally divided between the votes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="U.S. ECONOMIC SOVEREIGNTY">
    <paragraph>Thank you, Mr. President.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Who yields time? The Senator from Hawaii is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300056" topic="U.S. ECONOMIC SOVEREIGNTY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I concur with the statement just issued, and I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="U.S. ECONOMIC SOVEREIGNTY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I wish to comment on the second-degree amendment that has been offered by my colleague from Hawaii, Senator Inouye.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> All time has expired under the previous agreement.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent----</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, to clarify the unanimous consent request, I believe there were 2 minutes between the votes, am I correct, for debate?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator is correct. The Senator from South Carolina may proceed.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, may I ask the Senator through the Chair, how much time does the Senator from South Carolina need?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="">
    <paragraph>Three or 4 minutes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senator be given 4 minutes to speak.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the Senator. I appreciate the Senator fitting me in. Again, I am speaking on the second degree to my amendment that is related to port security.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As we talked about here several times on the floor, and actually passed last year, it is important that the people who are working at our ports are people we can trust to use the equipment and technology they are given to keep the people of America safe.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The amendment I have offered is consistent with--in fact, it is identical to--the regulations that the Secretary and the homeland defense agency have put together so that we will not have convicted felons working in our ports around this country, so that we know the people who are operating our most secure areas are people who have not proven to be susceptible to crimes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Senator Inouye is offering a second degree to my amendment that would allow the Secretary to change some of these crimes or felony convictions or to modify the rules. The Secretary of Homeland Security has not asked for this. In fact, he is supporting the amendment we have. I cannot imagine any future Secretary or future administration wanting to eliminate some of these felonies. The whole point of having this amendment and putting it into law is so that our agencies are not subject  to lawsuits and constant harassment to change the criteria for working in the secure areas of our ports.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So I appeal to my fellow colleagues, a vote for this second-degree amendment is a vote to gut my amendment. It is a vote to allow in the future any administration or this administration to eliminate certain felonies that would keep convicted criminals from working in our ports. I encourage my colleagues not to vote for this second degree. Vote for my amendment, which everybody in this body has voted for unanimously in the past.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Again, I thank the Senator from Connecticut and Senator Collins for the opportunity to speak.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from Hawaii is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300056" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, the amendment I introduced is not a second-degree amendment. However, it incorporates Senator DeMint's amendment.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It doesn't in any way minimize the matter of security. It just says the Secretary shall have flexibility with changing times. As we all concur, times do change.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Thirdly, in the other areas where security threats are common, such as airports, the Department of Transportation has not asked for anything like this, with no flexibility.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Fourth, if rules are to be made to differ from the present rules as set forth in the DeMint amendment and the Inouye amendment, it will have to go through the rulemaking process. I can assure my colleagues that we will not let felons be in charge of our security.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I thank the Chair.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, may I have an additional 60 seconds?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400105" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the Senator from Hawaii. I need to make an important point. The whole point of my amendment is to put a regulation in law so it cannot be changed and contested. The amendment offered by Senator Inouye basically guts the amendment and eliminates the reason for the amendment. It moves from being a law to something that is subject to the whims of any future administration or Secretary.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our job here is certainly to be fair to workers, but our first priority is to protect the American people. Please, let's not allow convicted felons to work in our ports. Our job is to protect our ports. The second degree completely guts the whole idea of an amendment that makes this law.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on agreeing to amendment No. 285.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask for the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there a sufficient second? There is a sufficient second.</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will call the roll.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>I announce that the Senator from Delaware (Mr. BIDEN), the Senator from South Dakota (Mr. JOHNSON), and the Senator from Rhode Island (Mr. REED) are necessarily absent.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300069" topic="">
    <paragraph>The following Senators were necessarily absent: the Senator from Kansas (Mr. BROWNBACK) and the Senator from Arizona (Mr. MCCAIN).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Are there any other Senators in the Chamber desiring to vote?</chair>
  <narrative>The result was announced--yeas 58, nays 37, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I move to reconsider the vote, and I move to lay that motion on the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The motion to lay on the table was agreed to.</narrative>
  <chair> Under a previous order, there will now be 2 minutes of debate equally divided on the DeMint amendment No. 279.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I am prepared to yield back the time on our side and go right to the vote.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="">
    <paragraph>Let's hear something about the amendment.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>The proponent of the amendment is the Senator from South Carolina, and he has 1 minute to describe it, if he so chooses.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, if the Senator from West Virginia is seeking an explanation of the amendment, I believe I can provide that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The amendment offered by the Senator from South Carolina would give authority to the Secretary of the Department of Homeland Security to add certain advances to the list of disqualifying crimes that would prevent someone from working at our seaports.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300016" topic="">
    <paragraph>I thank the Senator from Maine.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300025" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I yield back the remaining time on this side.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The question is on agreeing to amendment No. 279, as modified.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300067" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask for the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there a sufficient second? There appears to be a sufficient second.</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will call the roll.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>I announce that the Senator from Delaware (Mr. Biden) and the Senator from South Dakota (Mr. Johnson) are necessarily absent.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300069" topic="">
    <paragraph>The following Senators were necessarily absent: the Senator from Kansas (Mr. Brownback) and the Senator from Arizona (Mr. McCain).</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Are there any other Senators in the Chamber desiring to vote?</chair>
  <narrative>The result was announced--yeas 94, nays 2, as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>I move to reconsider the vote and to lay that motion on the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The motion to lay on the table was agreed to.</narrative>
  <chair> The majority leader.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, because of these two votes coming together as they did, there was some confusion. That is why this vote took longer. Everyone should understand, we will not make a habit of this. We have been very strict in enforcing the 20-minute rule, and we will continue to do so.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For the benefit of all Senators, we had a productive day today but, in my opinion, not as productive as it should have been. For Senators who have amendments, tomorrow is Thursday. We are not having votes until 5:30 on Monday night. We are going to have some amendments offered or I am going to get the idea there are not any amendments to offer, and we will have to either move to third reading or move to cloture or something. If Members have amendments, we said this would be an open process. This  is a very important piece of legislation. I hope they are not waiting until the last minute because the last minute may arrive more quickly than they think. It is important legislation. In our cloakroom, we sent out a hotline today to find out what amendments my caucus has. I hope the Republicans will follow up on that so we may have a list of amendments so we know whom to call.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have had a lot of dead time today. If this bill is open to amendment and people have concerns with it, they should offer those amendments.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from New Mexico.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, I call up amendment No. 281 and ask for its immediate consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection to setting aside the pending amendment?</chair>
  <narrative>The clerk will report.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that reading of the amendment be dispensed with.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, this is an amendment I am offering on behalf of myself and Senator Domenici, my colleague. It is to provide funds to local law enforcement agencies along our very substantial borders with Canada and Mexico to assist them with criminal activity, problems of enforcement of the laws, and dealing with criminal activity in those border communities. This is an amendment that sets up a $50 million-a-year grant program. It is an amendment we have passed twice in  the Senate, but it has not become law as yet.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It calls upon the Department of Homeland Security to establish a competitive grant program to assist local law enforcement located along the border or other local law enforcement agencies that are determined by the Homeland Security Department to be heavily impacted, high-impact areas elsewhere in the country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The border with Canada is 5,525 miles long. Our border with Mexico is nearly 2,000 miles long. We have had serious problems on the New Mexico-Mexico border, as has the State of Arizona. In fact, last year the States of Arizona and New Mexico declared states of emergency in order to provide local law enforcement with immediate assistance in dealing with criminal activity along the border. The Federal Government needs to step up and do its part in helping these local law enforcement agencies. This  amendment helps to do that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I hope when the time comes for a vote on the amendment, my colleagues will agree to support it, and we can pass it with a unanimous vote.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The Senator from New Jersey.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="400272" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, the Improving America's Security Act is not only about unfinished business, it is not only about doing what others have failed to do, it is about living up to the responsibilities we have as a Congress and a government to protect our Nation and its people and to do everything possible to prevent what was once unthinkable from happening again.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a Senator from New Jersey, I take that responsibility as a solemn promise to the 700 New Jerseyans who lost their lives on September 11 and their families who survived them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>More than 5 years ago, it became painfully clear that we, as a Nation that believed it was the most secure in the world, were unprotected. In the glimpse of a few minutes and over the course of a few short horrific hours, our Nation and the security we thought we had was changed forever. We entered into the stark reality of a post-September 11 world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On that day, glaring gaps in our security were exploited, lax systems were taken advantage of, and a trusting nation paid the price. Thousands of innocent lives, everyday Americans whom this Nation has grieved every day  since, were lost.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We can never go back to rectify past mistakes that could have prevented that day, but we can work to better secure our Nation moving forward.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We have a roadmap of how to get there. The 9/11 Commission laid out a plan, provided guidance, and delivered 41 specific and wide-ranging recommendations. Yet more than 2 years after the Commission issued those recommendations, many of them remain just that--recommendations that have not been acted on or fully implemented.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This legislation already comes before this body far later than it should. But the fact that it is on the floor of this Chamber just 2 short months into a new Congress speaks boldly of our new leadership and how important finishing the 9/11 Commission's work is to our leadership. I commend both Majority Leader Reid and Chairman Lieberman for making this a top priority for this Congress, as well as Chairman Inouye and Chairman Dodd for their roles in crafting  this legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Many of us have been pushing for a long time to see all 41 recommendations fully implemented and to make significant improvements to our Nation's security that have been under the radar screen for far too long.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As a former Member of the House of Representatives, I fought to see that all 41 recommendations were fully implemented in the 2004 intelligence reform legislation. I was proud to serve as the lead Democratic negotiator in the House on the conference committee that created the final intelligence bill. While that legislation made essential and urgently needed reforms to our Nation's intelligence, unfortunately, it fell far short on implementing all of the recommendations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have also since introduced legislation that ensures that all of these recommendations will be fully implemented and to hold the executive branch accountable for implementing each recommendation. It is my hope that with the bill we are working on now before the Senate, and with the vigorous oversight under the leadership of Chairman Lieberman and Ranking Member COLLINS, we will be able to see all these recommendations enacted and implemented.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It was just over a year ago the 9/11 Public Discourse Project, led by former members of the 9/11 Commission, published its disturbing report card, giving far more Fs than As on the implementation of those 41 recommendations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>There is no excuse left for Congress, the White House, or our Federal agencies for not finishing what is so direly needed: improving the security of our Nation. Yes, we have made some great steps forward. Yes, we have made some significant improvements that have likely saved lives and stopped terrorists in their tracks. But no one--no one--should use the lack of another catastrophic attack on our soil as proof that we have succeeded in fully meeting our goals.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The fact is, so long as we do not heed the advice of the 9/11 Commissioners who spent months examining how we could improve our Nation's security, so long as we do not make dramatic improvements to our security--at our Nation's ports, on our trains and buses, around our chemical plants, and in how we allocate homeland security funding--we continue to leave our Nation at risk.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I cannot imagine talking about the security of our Nation without the 41 recommendations of the 9/11 Commission. The Commission's findings and recommendations are integral to understanding our deepest flaws, the complexity of our intelligence and security networks, the obstacles that lie ahead and, most of all, what needs to be done.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Yet if some in our Government had had their way, there would have been no Commission, there would have been no digging into the secrecy and ineffectiveness of our Nation's security, no poring over thousands upon thousands of documents, no reviewing of every action Federal agencies took or did not take to prevent and respond to the attacks of September 11, no asking of some of the toughest questions our Nation has had to bear.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So once we pass this final legislation, have it signed into law and implemented, we will come to the day--I hope sooner rather than later--when our Nation's security funding is based more on risk, when our ports are fully secure because of 100 percent scanning, when we are making the necessary investments in mass transit security, and when our first responders have a strong emergency communications system that works in interoperable ways, so that those who are sworn to protect us can speak to  each other effectively.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These are only a few of the dimensions in this fight. Unfortunately, this is a fight that would not have taken place without the commitment and strength of the families of the victims of September 11.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>When the loved ones of those who were lost on September 11 have to become full-time advocates, spending every possible hour lobbying Congress, when they have to be the constant reminder for our Government to do its job, we know we have failed them. Many of them are here and have been here today watching this body, waiting to finally see this legislation become law, hoping that all their suffering, their work, and their tireless advocacy will not be in vain.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Let us not only fulfill their wishes but the wishes of all Americans to have a nation as secure as possible for their families and neighbors. Let's work to pass this legislation and make sure it is fully enacted. Let's finally accomplish what should have been finished several years ago.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Madam President, I suggest the absence of a quorum.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will call the roll.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the order for the quorum call be rescinded.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
