<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1195059601" ordinal="52" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <narrative>AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET -- (Senate - November 14, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="14415">S14415</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="COMMITTEE ON BANKING, HOUSING, AND URBAN AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on November 14, 2007, at 10:30 a.m., in order to conduct a hearing entitled "Shareholder Rights and Proxy Access."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="COMMITTEE ON BANKING, HOUSING, AND URBAN AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on November 14, 2007, at 2 p.m., in order to conduct a hearing entitled "Sovereign Wealth Fund Acquisitions and Other Foreign Government Investments in the U.S.: Assessing the Economic and National Security Implications."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, November 14, 2007, at 10 a.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building, in order to conduct a hearing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The hearing will focus on the need to improve the U.S. Global Change Research Program, which is responsible for coordinating and directing Federal climate change research. It will also address the need for improved communication of climate information to decision makers.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND NATURAL RESOURCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, November 14, 2007, at 10 a.m., in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building, in order to conduct a hearing.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the hearing is to receive testimony on the Global Nuclear Energy Partnership as it relates to U.S. policy on nuclear fuel management.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>Mr. HARKIN, Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Finance be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, November 14, 2007, at 10 a.m., in room 215 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building, to hear testimony on "Federal Estate Tax: Uncertainty in Planning Under the Current Law."</chair>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="COMMITTEE ON HEALTH, EDUCATION, LABOR, AND PENSIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions be authorized to meet in executive session during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, November 14, 2007 at 9:30 a.m. in room 430 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="COMMITTEE ON HOMELAND SECURITY AND GOVERNMENTAL AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, November 14, 2007, at 10 a.m. in order to conduct a business meeting to consider pending committee business.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Agenda</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="2324">S. 2324</bill>, Inspector General Reform Act of 2007; <bill type="s" number="2292">S. 2292</bill>, National Bombing Prevention Act of 2007; <bill type="s" number="1667">S. 1667</bill>, a bill to establish a pilot program for the expedited disposal of Federal real property; <bill type="s" number="1000">S. 1000</bill>, Telework Enhancement Act of 2007; <bill type="s" number="2321">S. 2321</bill>, E-Government Reauthorization Act of 2007; <bill type="h" number="390">H.R. 390</bill>, Preservation of Records of Servitude, Emancipation, and Post-Civil War Reconstruction Act; and <bill type="h" number="3571">H.R. 3571</bill>, a bill to amend the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 to permit individuals who have  served as employees of the Office of Compliance to serve as Executive Director, Deputy Executive Director, or General Counsel of the Office, and to permit individuals appointed to such positions to serve one additional term.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Robert D. Jamison, Under Secretary for National Protection and Programs, U.S. Department of Homeland Security; Wiley Ross Ashley III, Assistant  Administrator, Federal Emergency Management Agency, U.S. Department of Homeland Security; and the Honorable Ellen C. Williams, Member, Postal Board of Governors.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="2174">S. 2174</bill>, a bill to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 175 South Monroe Street in Tiffin, Ohio, as the "Paul E. Gillmor Post Office Building;" <bill type="h" number="2089">H.R. 2089</bill>, a bill to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 701 Loyola Avenue in New Orleans, Louisiana, as the "Louisiana Armed Services Veterans Post Office;" <bill type="h" number="3297">H.R. 3297</bill>, a bill to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 950 West Trenton Avenue in Morrisville,  Pennsylvania, as the "Nate DeTample Post Office Building;" <bill type="h" number="3308">H.R. 3308</bill>, a bill to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 216 East Main Street in Atwood, Indiana, as the "Lance Corporal David K. Fribley Post Office;" <bill type="h" number="3530">H.R. 3530</bill>, a bill to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 1400 Highway 41 North in Inverness, Florida, as the "Chief Warrant Officer Aaron Weaver Post Office Building;" <bill type="h" number="2276">H.R. 2276</bill>, a bill to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 203 North Main Street in Vassar, Michigan, as the "Corporal Christopher E. Esckelson Post Office Building;" <bill type="h" number="3325">H.R. 3325</bill>, a bill to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 235 Mountain Road in Suffield, Connecticut, as the "Corporal Stephen R. Bixler Post Office;" <bill type="s" number="2110">S. 2110</bill>, a bill to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 427 North Street in Taft, California, as the "Larry S. Pierce Post Office;" <bill type="h" number="3382">H.R. 3382</bill>, a bill to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 200 North William Street in Goldsboro, North Carolina, as the "Philip</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="COMMITTEE ON VETERANS' AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Veterans' Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, November 14, 2007, in order to conduct a markup of pending legislation. Immediately following the conclusion of the markup, the Committee will conduct a hearing on the nomination of Michael W. Hager, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Secretary of Veterans Affairs, Human Resources and Management. The committee will meet in room SD-562 of  the Dirksen Senate Office Building beginning at 9:30 a.m.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="PERMANENT SUBCOMMITTEE ON INVESTIGATIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations of the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, November 14, 2007, at 2:30 p.m., in order to conduct a hearing entitled, "Medicaid Providers That Cheat on Their Taxes and What Can Be Done About It."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON HUMAN RIGHTS AND THE LAW">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate Committee on the Judiciary, Subcommittee on Human Rights and the Law, be authorized to meet in order to conduct a hearing entitled "No Safe Haven: Accountability for Human Rights Violators in the United States" on Wednesday, November 14, 2007, at 10 a.m. in room SD-266 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Panel I: Sigal P. Mandelker, Deputy Assistant Attorney General, Criminal Division, U.S. Department of Justice, Washington, DC, and Marcy M. Forman, Director of Office of Investigations, Immigration and Customs Enforcement, U.S. Department of Homeland Security, Washington, DC.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Panel II: David Scheffer, Mayer Brown/Robert A. Helman Professor of Law, Northwestern University School of Law, Chicago, IL; Pamela Merchant, Executive Director, Center for Justice and Accountability, San Francisco, CA; and Juan Romagoza Arce, Executive Director, La Cl&#xED;nica del Pueblo, Washington, DC.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
