<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1193155202" ordinal="32" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <narrative>AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET -- (Senate - October 23, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="13269">S13269</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, October 23, 2007, at 10 a.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This hearing will examine the Surface Transportation Board's recent and ongoing efforts related to the commercial regulation of railroads, including rulemakings and recent cases. Witnesses will provide their perspectives on the STB and its effectiveness in balancing the commercial needs of railroads and their customers and will provide an update on the Government Accountability Office 2006 report reviewing the freight railroad industry.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, October 23, 2007, at 2:30 p.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The hearing is on the nomination of Mr. Todd J. Zinser, Inspector General--Designate, United States Department of Commerce; Mr. Robert Clarke Brown, Member of the Board of Directors--Designate, Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority; Mr. Carl B. Kress, Commissioner--Designate, Federal Maritime Commission; and Mr. A. Paul Anderson, Commissioner (Reappointment), Federal Maritime Commission.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENVIRONMENT AND PUBLIC WORKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Environment and Public Works be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, October 23, 2007 at 10 a.m. in room 406 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building in order to hold a hearing entitled, "Examining the human health impacts of global warming."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="COMMITTEE ON HEALTH, EDUCATION, LABOR, AND PENSIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions be authorized to hold a hearing entitled "EEOICPA: Is the Program Claimant Friendly for Our Cold War Heroes?" during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, October 23, 2007 at 10 a.m. in room 430 of the Dirksen Senate office building.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="COMMITTEE ON HOMELAND SECURITY AND GOVERNMENTAL AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Tuesday, October 23, 2007, at 10 a.m. in order to conduct a hearing entitled "Six Years After Anthrax: Are We Better Prepared to Respond to Bioterrorism?"</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300051" topic="SELECT COMMITTEE ON INTELLIGENCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Select  Committee on Intelligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on October 23, 2007 at 2:30 p.m. to hold a closed hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
