<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1186027200" ordinal="32" title="LIFTING HOLD ON NOMINATION OF DENNIS SCHRADER">
  <speaking speaker="300100" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, on June 18, I announced my intention to object to any unanimous consent request for the Senate to take up the nomination of Dennis Schrader to be Deputy Administrator for National Preparedness in the Department of Homeland Security. I did so because, prior to his confirmation as Secretary of the Department of Homeland Security, Michael Chertoff told me in my office that if confirmed, he would move expeditiously to implement the National Emergency Technology Guard--NET  Guard program. Unfortunately, Secretary Chertoff had failed to honor that pledge.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, I received a letter from Secretary Chertoff describing how the Department is moving forward with 12-month NET Guard pilots beginning in September 2007, and how the DHS will be requesting funds to continue the program in its 2009 budget request to the Office of Management and Budget.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Secretary also communicated to me that the Department of Homeland Security will be publicizing NET Guard and seeking involvement from the private sector, a step critical to the success of this vital program.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Department has also set aside funds to run the pilots for the year and convened a working group of subject matter experts to guide the design of NET Guard. These activities and Secretary Chertoff's letter indicate that he is making a good-faith effort to get NET Guard off the ground.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In light of these actions, I will no longer object to any unanimous-consent request for the Senate to take up Mr. Schrader's nomination. I will, however, continue to closely monitor DHS's actions on NET Guard.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that a copy of Secretary Chertoff's letter be printed in the Congressional Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
</record>
