<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1189180801" ordinal="38" title="SUPPORTING THE GOALS AND IDEALS OF NATIONAL OVARIAN CANCER AWARENESS MONTH">
  <narrative>SUPPORTING THE GOALS AND IDEALS OF NATIONAL OVARIAN CANCER AWARENESS MONTH -- (Senate - September 07, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="11280">S11280</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400050" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of <bill type="sr" number="311">S. Res. 311</bill>, submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>A resolution (<bill type="sr" number="311">S. Res. 311</bill>) supporting the goals and ideals of National Ovarian Cancer Awareness Month.</narrative>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the Senate proceeded to consider the resolution.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300093" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, this resolution designates September as "National Ovarian Cancer Awareness Month." I am pleased to be joined by my colleagues, Senators DOLE and CLINTON, to shed some light on this disease.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This year alone, ovarian cancer will be diagnosed in an estimated 20,000 women, and approximately 15,000 more women will die of this disease. Unfortunately, ovarian cancer is usually caught in an advanced stage, meaning there is only a 29 percent survival rate over five years. We must acknowledge these statistics and overcome the challenges of diagnosing this deadly disease.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Earlier this year, I was fortunate to have the opportunity to meet with nine-year survivor Carolyn Benivegna of Novi, Michigan. After being misdiagnosed by a number of doctors, Carolyn finally learned that she had ovarian cancer. However, Carolyn is not letting the cancer run her life. Instead, she has become an advocate for the Survivors Teaching Students program, which aims to enhance medical students' understanding of the symptoms and risk factors of ovarian cancer to facilitate early diagnosis  and detection when they begin practicing medicine. I am proud that both Michigan  State University and Wayne State University are starting Survivors Training Students programs for their medical students.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>While there is no definitive screening test, recent studies have shown common symptoms of ovarian cancer such as bloating, abdominal pain, and difficulty eating. However, we must take active steps to educate the community and medical providers of the newest discoveries in prevention, early diagnosis, and treatment of this disease.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, by recognizing September as National Ovarian Cancer Awareness Month, we can show our support for ovarian cancer survivors and their families and join the fight to conquer this disease.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="400050" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, the motions to reconsider be laid upon the table, and that any statements relating thereto be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution (<bill type="sr" number="311">S. Res. 311</bill>) was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The preamble was agreed to.</chair>
  <chair>The resolution, with its preamble, reads as follows:</chair>
  <chair>
    <bill type="sr" number="311">S. Res. 311</bill>
  </chair>
  <chair>Whereas ovarian cancer is the deadliest of all gynecological cancers, and the reported incidence of ovarian cancer is increasing over time;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas ovarian cancer is the 5th leading cause of cancer deaths among women in the United States;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas all women are at risk for ovarian cancer, and 90 percent of women diagnosed with ovarian cancer do not have a family history that puts them at higher risk;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Pap smear is sensitive and specific to the early detection of cervical cancer, but not to ovarian cancer;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas there is currently no reliable and easy-to-administer screening test used for the early detection of ovarian cancer;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas many people are unaware that the symptoms of ovarian cancer often include bloating, pelvic or abdominal pain, difficulty eating or feeling full quickly, and urinary symptoms, among several other symptoms that are easily confused with other diseases;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas due to the lack of a reliable early screening test, 75 percent of cases of ovarian cancer are detected at an advanced stage, when the 5-year survival rate is only 50 percent, a much lower rate than for many other cancers;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas if ovarian cancer is diagnosed and treated at an early stage before the cancer spreads outside of the ovary, the treatment is potentially less costly, and the survival rate is as high as 90 percent;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas there are factors that are known to reduce the risk for ovarian cancer and play an important role in the prevention of the disease;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas awareness and early recognition of ovarian cancer symptoms are currently the best way to save women's lives;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas the Ovarian Cancer National Alliance, during the month of September, holds a number of events to increase public awareness of ovarian cancer; and&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whereas a National Ovarian Cancer Awareness Month should be designated to increase the awareness of the public regarding the cancer: Now, therefore, be it</chair>
  <chair> Resolved, That the Senate supports the goals and ideals of National Ovarian Cancer Awareness Month.&lt;p/&gt;END&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;</chair>
</record>
