<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1177516815" ordinal="46" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="COMMITTEE ON AGRICULTURE, NUTRITION AND FORESTRY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition and Forestry be authorized to conduct a hearing during the session of the Senate on April 25, 2007 at 9:30 a.m. in SD-106. The title of this committee hearing is, "Challenges and Opportunities Facing American Agriculture Producers Today, Part III."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="COMMITTEE ON COMMERCE, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation be authorized to hold a business meeting during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, April 25, 2007, at 2:30 p.m., in room 253 of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of this meeting will be to consider and approve the following legislation following bills: <bill type="s" number="294">S. 294</bill>, <bill type="s" number="428">S. 428</bill>, <bill type="s" number="924">S. 924</bill>, <bill type="s" number="311">S. 311</bill>, <bill type="s" number="675">S. 675</bill>, <bill type="s" number="1142">S. 1142</bill>, the Identity Theft Prevention Act, and the promotion of Mr. Gribbin, in the United States Coast Guard.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet to conduct a markup on Wednesday, April 25, at 10 a.m. in Dirksen Room 226.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I. Committee Authorization: Authorization of Subpoenas in Connection with Investigation into Replacement of U.S. Attorneys.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>II. Bills: <bill type="s" number="376">S. 376</bill>, Law Enforcement Officers Safety Act of 2007; Leahy, Specter, Grassley, Kyl, Sessions, Cornyn, <bill type="s" number="119">S. 119</bill>, War Profiteering Prevention Act of 2007; Leahy, Feinstein, Feingold, Schumer, Durbin, Cardin, <bill type="s" number="1079">S. 1079</bill>, Star-Spangled Banner and War of 1812 Bicentennial Commission Act; Cardin, Warner, Kennedy, <bill type="s" number="735">S. 735</bill>, Terrorist Hoax Improvements Act of 2007; Kennedy, Kyl, Coleman, Schumer, Leahy, Grassley, Cornyn, <bill type="h" number="740">H.R. 740</bill>, Preventing Harassment through Outbound Number Enforcement (PHONE)  Act of 2007; Scott, Conyers, Forbes, Boucher, Jackson-Lee, Gutierrez, Sherman, <bill type="s" number="221">S. 221</bill>, Fair Contracts for Growers Act of 2007; Grassley, Feingold, Kohl, Leahy, Durbin, <bill type="s" number="495">S. 495</bill>, Personal Data Privacy and Security Act of 2007; Leahy, Specter, Feingold, Schumer, <bill type="s" number="239">S. 239</bill>, Notification of Risk to Personal Data Act of 2007;</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Feinstein, <bill type="s" number="879">S. 879</bill>, No Oil Producing and Exporting Cartels Act of 2007; (Kohl, Specter, Leahy, Grassley, Feingold, Schumer, Coburn, Durbin.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>III. Nominations: Robert Gideon Howard, Jr. to be United States Marshal for the Eastern District of Arkansas; Frederick J. Kapala to be United States District Judge for the Northern District of Illinois; Benjamin Hale Settle to be United States District Judge for the Western District of Washington; John Roberts Hackman to be United States Marshal for the Eastern District of Virginia.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>IV. Resolutions: <bill type="sr" number="125">S. Res. 125</bill>, designating May 18, 2007 as "Endangered Species Day"; Feinstein, Collins, Feingold, Biden, <bill type="sr" number="116">S. Res. 116</bill>, designating May 2007 as "National Autoimmune Disease Awareness Month"; Biden, <bill type="sr" number="146">S. Res. 146</bill>, designating June 20, 2007, as "American Eagle Day"; Alexander, Byrd, Kennedy, Feinstein, <bill type="sr" number="162">S. Res. 162</bill>, commemorating and acknowledging the dedication and sacrifice made by the men and women who have lost their lives while serving as law enforcement officers; Leahy, Specter,  Biden, Grassley, Cornyn, Durbin.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="COMMITTEE ON VETERANS' AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Veterans' Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, April 25, 2007 to hold a hearing on mental health issues. The hearing will take place in room 418 of the Russell Senate Office Building beginning at 2 p.m.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON AIRLAND">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on Airland be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, April 25, 2007, at 10 a.m., in open session to receive testimony on whether the army is properly sized, organized, and equipped to respond to the most likely missions over the next two decades while retaining adequate capability to respond to all contingencies along the spectrum of combat in review of the Defense Authorization request for fiscal  year 2008 and the Future Years Defense Program.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON CLEAN AIR AND NUCLEAR SAFETY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on Clean Air and Nuclear Safety be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, April 25, 2007, at 10 a.m. in room 406 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The agenda to be considered: Oversight Hearing on the Nuclear Regulatory Commission.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON EMERGING THREATS AND CAPABILITIES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on Emerging Threats and Capabilities be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, April 25, 2007, at 2 p.m., to receive testimony on efforts to improve the Department of Defense's language and cultural awareness capabilities.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON STRATEGIC FORCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on Strategic Forces be authorized to meet in open session during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, April 25, 2007, at 3:30 p.m., to receive testimony on Department of Energy atomic energy defense programs in review of the defense authorization request for fiscal year 2008.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="SUBCOMMITTEE ON WATER AND POWER">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Subcommittee on Water and Power be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, April 25, 2007 at 2:30 p.m. in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the hearing is to receive testimony on the following bills: <bill type="s" number="175">S. 175</bill>, to provide for a feasibility study of alternatives to augment the water supplies of the Central Oklahoma Master Conservancy District and cities served by the District; <bill type="s" number="324">S. 324</bill>, to direct the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a study of water resources in the State of New Mexico; <bill type="s" number="542">S. 542</bill>, to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to conduct feasibility studies to address certain water shortages within the Snake,  Boise, and Payette River systems in the State of Idaho, and for other purposes; <bill type="s" number="752">S. 752</bill>, to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to participate in the implementation of the Platte River Recovery Implementation Program for Endangered Species in the Central and Lower Platte River Basin and to modify the Pathfinder Dam and Reservoir; <bill type="s" number="1037">S. 1037</bill>, to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to assist in the planning, design, and construction</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300005" topic="PRIVILEGES OF THE FLOOR">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that Elizabeth Goitein, a detailee from the Department of Justice in Senator Feingold's Judiciary Committee office, be granted floor privileges for the remainder of this session of Congress.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
