<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1190822402" ordinal="53" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <narrative>AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET -- (Senate - September 26, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="12186">S12186</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON BANKING, HOUSING, AND URBAN AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on September 26, 2007, at 9:30 a.m., in order to conduct a hearing entitled on "The Role and Impact of Credit Rating Agencies on the Subprime Credit Markets."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND NATURAL RESOURCES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources be authorized to hold a hearing during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, September 26, 2007, at 10 a.m. in room SD-366 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The purpose of the hearing is to receive testimony on <bill type="s" number="1543">S.1543</bill>, a bill to establish a national geothermal initiative to encourage increased production of energy from geothermal resources by creating a program of geothermal research, development, demonstration and commercial application to support the achievement of a national geothermal energy goal.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENVIRONMENT AND PUBLIC WORKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Environment and Public Works be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, September 26, 2007 at 9:30 a.m. in room 406 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building in order to conduct a hearing entitled, "An Examination of the Impacts of Global Warming on the Chesapeake Bay."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON FINANCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Finance be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, September 26, 2007, at 10 a.m., in room SD-215 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building, to hear testimony on the "Offshore Tax Issues: Reinsurance and Hedge Funds".</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON HOMELAND SECURITY AND GOVERNMENTAL AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs be authorized to meet on Wednesday, September 26, 2007, at 10 a.m. for a business meeting to consider pending committee business.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Agenda</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Honorable Julie L. Myers to be Assistant Secretary, U.S. Department of Homeland Security.</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2654">H.R. 2654</bill>, to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 202 South Dumont Avenue in Woonsocket, South Dakota, as the "Eleanor McGovern Post Office Building;"</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2467">H.R. 2467</bill>, to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 69 Montgomery Street in Jersey City, New Jersey, as the "Frank J. Guarini Post Office Building;"</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2587">H.R. 2587</bill>, to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 555 South 3rd Street Lobby in Memphis, Tennessee, as the "Kenneth T. Whalum, Sr. Post Office Building;"</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2778">H.R. 2778</bill>, to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 3 Quaker Ridge Road in New Rochelle, New York, as the "Robert Merrill Postal Station;"</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2825">H.R. 2825</bill>, to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 326 South Main Street in Princeton, Illinois, as the "Owen Lovejoy Princeton Post Office Building;"</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="3052">H.R. 3052</bill>, to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 954 Wheeling Avenue in Cambridge, Ohio, as the "John Herschel Glenn Jr. Post Office Building;"</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="3106">H.R. 3106</bill>/S. 2023, to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 805 Main Street in Ferdinand, Indiana, as the "Staff Sergeant David L. Nord Post Office;"</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="h" number="2765">H.R. 2765</bill>, to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 44 North Main Street in Hughesville, Pennsylvania, as the "Master Sergeant Sean Michael Thomas Post Office."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet in order to conduct an Executive Nomination hearing on Wednesday, September 26, 2007 at 2:30 p.m. in the Dirksen Senate Office Building room 226.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Michael J. Sullivan to be Director, Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON RULES AND ADMINISTRATION">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Rules and Administration be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Wednesday, September 26, 2007, at 10 a.m. to conduct an executive business meeting to consider on the Nomination of Robert C. Tapella of Virginia, to be Public Printer, Government Printing Office; and the nominations of Steven T. Walther of Nevada, David M. Mason of Virginia, Robert D. Lenhard of Maryland, and Hans von Spakovsky of Georgia  to be members of the Federal Election Commission.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="COMMITTEE ON SMALL BUSINESS AND ENTREPRENEURSHIP">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate in order to conduct a hearing entitled "Improving Internet Access to Help Small Business Compete in a Global Economy," on Wednesday, September 26, 2007, beginning at 10 a.m., in room 428A of the Russell Senate Office Building.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
