<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1169614800" ordinal="14" title="STATE OF THE UNION ADDRESS">
  <speaking speaker="300010" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today I rise to talk about a portion of the President's address last night that I think is extremely important. I have heard from many of my colleagues in this body and on the talk shows that there are serious concerns about the war in Iraq. Primarily, they are saying we need to change our strategy; we shouldn't be involved in a civil war. We should be involving the Iraqis themselves in taking care of the civil war. We ought to be providing more--we ought to ensure the  Iraqi Government cuts the Sunnis in on the oil revenues and makes them full economic partners. We need to bring in the friendly neighbors in the region, those countries that want to see a peaceful and stable Iraq, and we ought to be following the Baker-Hamilton report.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As I listened to the President's speech last night, that is precisely what he did. This is a new strategy we have in Iraq. We have heard in our open Intelligence Committee hearings that now, for the first time, we believe Prime Minister al-Maliki and his Sunni and Kurdish fellow elected leaders believe they can take over and restore order in that country, and they are willing to crack down on the Shia death squads, such as Muqtada al-Sadr. We have seen reports of that in the media. They report  that the neighboring countries are willing now to come in and help with reconstruction, provide job opportunities for young unemployed men to keep them from becoming insurgents or terrorists, and this, they say, is our best chance.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Frankly, for Prime Minister al-Maliki and his government, this is probably their last chance. This is an opportunity where al-Maliki said: If you will provide some additional support as we go in, get our troops up to speed and clear and hold Baghdad, we will take over the country.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is what we need to do to bring a successful conclusion to this war and to draw out our military. We are probably going to have our military in the region for a long time because, as the President said, this is a generational war against radical Islam and the terror they bring.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I wanted to just briefly note a comment. Last night we heard that the military is against the war. Well, there may be some in the military who are against the war, but I can tell my colleagues, I have spent a lot of time listening to Missouri soldiers and marines, people who have been on the ground. I have gotten reports from them continually. I have seen newspaper reports about the people who have come back, the soldiers who have come back.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>For example, one woman has written a book. She served with the Army's 101st Airborne. She lost her husband in the war. She says:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is hard to stay positive about Iraq because of what you see on the news. But I was able to be there and I know what a difference we are making there.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Others, such as 1SG Stephanie Leonard, was moved to tears, saying that they are heroes for helping the Iraqi people. She said:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is not a 24-hour war. We want things to be in a hurry. As soon as the Iraqi police are able to secure their own country, that is when the window begins to open.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>These are just some of the many comments I have seen in print in Missouri and heard people express. They want to see us win. They know they are doing the job. They believe the liberal national media has painted a very unflattering and untrue picture, and that is why our troops think they are not getting a fair shake.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>But in that context, in the context of what the President did, let's talk about  the resolutions which are being discussed. If the President is on the track to respond to all of the ideas about how we ought to change our direction in Iraq--and I believe he is--what will the resolutions do?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Well, proponents of the resolutions say they want to support the troops, but the resolutions don't do that. Clearly, I believe there is an agreement now that we are not going to try to use the congressional power of the purse to cut off funding and force an immediate withdrawal from Iraq because that would be madness. The Director of National Intelligence told our committee:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Precipitous withdrawal could lead to a collapse of the government of that country and a collapse of their security forces because we simply don't think they are ready to take over, to assume full control of their fiscal responsibilities.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To simply withdraw now would have catastrophic effects, and that is a quite widely held view inside of Iraq itself. If we were to cut off funds, the CIA Director said it would lead, No. 1, to increased killing of Iraqi civilians.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>No. 2, the establishment by al-Zawahiri and Osama bin Laden of the base of operations for their war to establish a worldwide caliphate beginning in the Middle East, taking over the areas of Iraq which would be out of control and would bring people in from other countries in a possible civil war.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If we remember, that is what happened in Vietnam. When Congress cut off the purse, we saw our allies slaughtered in Vietnam, and some 2 to 2.5 million people in Cambodia, Laos, and Vietnam were killed. A possible slaughter of people in the Middle East who have supported us would ensue.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>General Maples, the Director of the Defense Intelligence Agency, told our committee 2 weeks ago:</paragraph>
    <paragraph> ..... A failure in Iraq would empower the jihadist movement. It would give that base of operations from which the jihadist movement would extend. And it's consistent with the goals of Al Qaida in Iraq to establish that Islamic state, and then to expand it into the caliphate. I also think that there, of course, will be very significant regional impacts both in terms of stability to other countries--</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent to speak an additional 4 minutes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300049" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, what is the parliamentary situation?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The time for morning business has expired.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300049" topic="">
    <paragraph>The Senator from Missouri is asking for 4 additional minutes?</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300010" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask for 4 additional minutes.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300049" topic="">
    <paragraph>I have no objection to the Senator proceeding.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered. It will be charged against the minority side.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300010" topic="">
    <paragraph>General Maples also told the Senate Intelligence Committee that a withdrawal from Iraq could leave Iraq's vast oil reserves in the hands of jihadists. We can imagine what trouble that would lead to.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If we are not using our power to cut off the funds and force a hasty withdrawal, what are we doing? Are we telling the 21,000 brave men and women who are going to Iraq we are uncomfortable with the dangerous mission they are about to undertake but not offering any alternative? I am sure they will find that very encouraging. They will be delighted to know we don't like what they are doing but they will have to do it anyhow.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If the goal of the resolution is to let the American people know we are uncomfortable with the situation in Iraq, I guess that makes for good politics. But, personally, I think it is wrong and irresponsible. It is irresponsible because if we approve this resolution, the whole world will be listening, including the worst actors in Iraq. We will be telling the Sunni terror cells and the Shia militias that America's political will is wavering.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If the members of al-Qaida in Iraq are finding themselves discouraged by the United States military's relentless pursuit, I am sure they will take comfort from these political gestures. If the Iraqis who support and encourage the Shia death squads are feeling the heat of United States-led and supported operations and are contemplating a compromise that might bring sectarian killing to an end, I am sure they will take comfort from the political gesture to hold on a little longer.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One of the keys to a successful counterinsurgency campaign is to wear down the enemy's resolve. This resolution will do the opposite. It will encourage Sunni terrorists and Shia death squads, letting them know if they hang on longer, the United States will not have the political will to outlast them.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>One of the ironies of the resolution is that it condemns a recommendation that comes from a group the Senate requested in legislation. The Iraq Study Group's report recommended that the Iraqi government:</paragraph>
    <paragraph> ..... accelerate assuming responsibility for Iraqi security by increasing the number and quality of Iraqi Army brigades. While this process is underway, and to facilitate it, the United States should significantly increase the number of U.S. military personnel, including combat troops, imbedded in and supporting Iraqi Army units. As these actions proceed, U.S. combat forces could begin to move out of Iraq.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>So let me make sure I have this right. The Senate demanded the legislation. The Iraq Study Group put together recommendations. The study group came forward and made recommendations and the President had the temerity to accept some of them, and now we are going to vote out a resolution condemning them for accepting those recommendations?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>General Petraeus said this week to the Committee on Armed Services that he needs the 21,000 troops to get the job done. Are we telling him we don't think we should have those troops?</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I have to confess, even as a Senator, I can't tell you exactly what we are trying to say in these resolutions. Are we expressing concern and discomfort with the situation in Iraq? I can't imagine how that would help. But more importantly, I can imagine lots of ways in which it will not help.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Look at the confusion within our Government in 1993 when the military had concerns about congressional intentions over our involvement in Somalia and how they prevented a request for armor that could have saved the lives of American soldiers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is not a perfect analogy, of course, but I think it offers an important warning of the danger of mixed message like the one we will send with this resolution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our commander on the ground in Somalia in 1993, General Montgomery, requested a small unit of tanks and armored vehicles, as a quick reaction force in case our troops got bogged down or surrounded in the dense urban sprawl of Mogadishu, as they eventually did.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Les Aspin, the Secretary of Defense at the time, denied the commander's request. He told the Senate Armed Services Committee that "Congressional concerns about U.S. military involvement in Somalia were a factor in his decision to deny General Montgomery's request for armor."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>General Montgomery also told the Armed Services Committee that he would have used that armor in October 1993 "Blackhawk Down" incident to rescue our troops who were bogged down in urban combat with Somali militia men. General Montgomery said that if he had that armor, "we would have gotten there faster. We would have taken fewer casualties."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>My fear is that, in addition to the message this resolution will send to our enemies about our lack of resolve, it will also send a wrong and confusing message to our military commanders.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Just like we did in Somalia in 1993, we are pretty much saying that while the President should not pull our military out of Iraq, they shouldn't bother asking for what they need to get the job done and protect themselves while they are there.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>General Petraeus raised this very same issue in his testimony this week in front of the Senate Armed Services Committee. He said that he worried about what message this resolution. would send to his soldiers and himself.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If we are going to leave our troops in Iraq, as we should, we should also give them everything they need to protect themselves and get their job done. Just as importantly, we should not leave them with the mistaken impression that they shouldn't bother to ask for what they need.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Congress cannot, and should not micromanage the war in Iraq--the troops in the field like to call that the 8,000 mile screwdriver. If any Senator wants to propose legislation to compel a withdrawal from Iraq, so be it, and let's vote on the matter.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>If not, let's stop trying to micromanage by resolution, suggestion and  gesture, put away the 8,000 mile screwdriver, and give the President's plan a chance to succeed.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Deputy Director of National Intelligence, Tom Fingar, told the Senate Intelligence Committee this week that gains in stability in Iraq could open a window for gains in sectarian reconciliation. I agree, and we have to give the President's plan a chance to succeed if we want to open that window.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent to have two pertinent articles printed in the RECORD.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
</record>
