<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1189094404" ordinal="51" title="AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET">
  <narrative>AUTHORITY FOR COMMITTEES TO MEET -- (Senate - September 06, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="11236">S11236</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300081" topic="COMMITTEE ON ARMED SERVICES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, September 6, at 10 a.m., in open session to receive a report on the findings of the Iraqi Security Forces Independent Assessment Commission.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300081" topic="COMMITTEE ON ARMED SERVICES">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the committee on Armed Services be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, September 6, 2007 at 5 p.m. in Executive Session to continue to receive information relating to the treatment of detainees.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300081" topic="COMMITTEE ON ENVIRONMENT AND PUBLIC WORKS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Environment and Public Works be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, September 6, 2007, at 10 a.m., in room 406 of the Dirksen Senate Office Building in order to conduct a hearing entitled "An Examination of the Potential Human Health, Water Quality, and Other Impacts of the Confined Animal Feeding Operation Industry."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300081" topic="COMMITTEE ON FINANCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Finance be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on Thursday, September 6, 2007, at 10 a.m., in 215 Dirksen Senate Office Building, to hear testimony on "Carried Interest Part III: Pension Issues."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300081" topic="COMMITTEE ON HEALTH, EDUCATION, LABOR, AND PENSIONS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions be authorized to hold a hearing on the Nomination of Charles E.F. Millard, of New York, to be Director of the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation during the session of the Senate on Thursday, September 5, 2007, at 10 a.m. in room 628 of the Dirksen Senate office building.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300081" topic="COMMITTEE ON HOMELAND SECURITY AND GOVERNMENTAL AFFAIRS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs be authorized to meet on Thursday, September 6, 2007, at 1:30 p.m. in order to conduct a hearing entitled "A DHS Status Report: Assessing Challenges and Measuring Progress."</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300081" topic="COMMITTEE ON JUDICIARY">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Committee on the Judiciary be authorized to meet during the Senate in order to conduct a markup on Thursday, September 6, 2007, at 10 a.m. in SD-266.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Agenda</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="s" number="453">S. 453</bill>, Deceptive Practices and Voter Intimidation Prevention Act of 2007 (Obama, Schumer, Leahy, Cardin, Feingold, Feinstein, Kennedy, Whitehouse); <bill type="s" number="1692">S. 1692</bill>, A bill to grant a Federal Charter to Korean War Veterans Association (Cardin, Isakson, Kennedy); <bill type="s" number="1845">S. 1845</bill>, A bill to provide for limitations in certain communications between the Department of Justice and the White House (Whitehouse, Leahy) and <bill type="s" number="772">S.772</bill>, Railroad Antitrust Enforcement Act of 2007 (Kohl, Coleman).</paragraph>
    <paragraph><bill type="sr" number="282">S. Res. 282</bill>, National Polycystic Kidney Disease Awareness Week (Kohl, Hatch) and <bill type="sr" number="134">S. Res. 134</bill>, Adopt a School Library Month (Durbin).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Richard A. Jones to be United States District Judge for the Western District of Washington; Sharion Aycock to be United States District Judge for the Northern District of Mississippi; Jennifer Walker Elrod to be United States Circuit Judge for the Fifth Circuit.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300081" topic="SELECT COMMITTEE ON INTELLIGENCE">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Select Committee on Intelligence be authorized to meet during the session of the Senate on September 6, 2007, at 2:30 p.m. to hold a closed hearing.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
