<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1204909201" ordinal="30" title="ADDITIONAL STATEMENTS">
  <narrative>ADDITIONAL STATEMENTS -- (Senate - March 07, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="1739">S1739</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300070" topic="TRIBUTE TO HOOSIER ESSAY CONTEST WINNERS">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today I share with my colleagues the winners of the 2007-2008 Dick Lugar/Indiana Farm Bureau/Farm Bureau Insurance Companies Youth Essay Contest.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1985, I joined with the Indiana Farm Bureau to sponsor an essay contest for 8th grade students in my home State. The purpose of this contest is to encourage young Hoosiers to recognize and appreciate the importance of Indiana agriculture in their lives and subsequently craft an essay responding to the assigned theme. I, along with my friends at the Indiana Farm Bureau and Farm Bureau Insurance Companies, am pleased with the annual response to this contest and the quality of the essays received  over the years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I congratulate Jansen Hight, of Owen County, and Leah Lahue, of Crawford County, as winners of this year's contest, and I ask that the complete text of their respective essays be printed in the RECORD. Likewise, I would like to have printed in the RECORD the names of all of the district and county winners of the 2007-2008 Dick Lugar/Indiana Farm Bureau/Farm Bureau Insurance Companies Youth Essay Contest.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The material follows.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Energy Aware--Energy Independent</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>(By Jansen Hight)</narrative>
  <narrative>Today our world runs mainly on fossil fuels. Therefore, what are we going to do when all the fossil fuels are gone? This limit of non-renewable fuel resources is why we should start considering the use of alternative energy sources. Some of the best-known alternative fuels include biodiesel, butanol, ethanol, chemically-stored electricity, methane, biomass, hydrogen, natural gas, vegetable oil, and peanut oil (just to name a few).</narrative>
  <narrative>A wide variety of alternative energy sources are being developed to aid our rural economies and our nation's security. With nearly 60 percent of our oil resources coming from other countries, it is important that we develop our own dependable sources of energy. Due to the lack of resources to produce substantial amounts of energy from other sources such as solar and wind power, biofuels are the best resource for Indiana to pursue energy independence.</narrative>
  <narrative>With Indiana being a strong agricultural state, Indiana has the ability to be a leader in the production and use of domestic renewable fuels including biodiesel, ethanol, and fuels made from cellulosic biomass. Regardless of the type of alternative fuels being produced by Indiana farmers, one common advantage these fuels have is they improve our energy resources since they all can be made from sources other than imported petroleum. By using home-grown sources for fuel, this would also increase  the local demand for Indiana soybeans and corn, leading to a better</narrative>
  <narrative>Indiana does have the agricultural resources to be a leader in developing a strong biofuels industry. With the cooperative efforts of biofuel users, petroleum companies, and the government, our Indiana farmers can lead the way for a sustainable energy future that supports rural economies and aids our nation's security.</narrative>
  <narrative>&lt;pre&gt;--&lt;/pre&gt;</narrative>
  <narrative>Untitled</narrative>
  <narrative>(By Leah Lahue)</narrative>
  <narrative>Alternative energy sources include: solar, water, wind, geo-thermal, and bio-fuels. Alternative energy use reduces the dependence on foreign oil, reduces harmful emissions, and uses renewable resources. Protecting our environment and slowing the use of non-renewable petroleum reserves are good choices for everyone.</narrative>
  <narrative>Bio-fuels are produced directly from plants or indirectly from organic industrial, commercial, domestic, or agricultural wastes. Three ways to make bio-fuels are burning dry organic waste, using fast growing trees, and fermenting wet materials. Partly digested cellulose and carbohydrates--animal manure can be burnt in dry form or processed into biogas. Bio-fuel comes from corn, sugarcane, wheat, rice, sorghum, sunflowers, potatoes, and sugar beets. One bushel of corn produces 2.8 gallons of ethanol.  Bio-fuel, a renewable resource, reduces dependence on foreign oil and carbon dioxide emissions. With 20 parts bio-diesel and 80 parts petroleum, bio-diesel is environmentally safer. Critics are concerned that the major use of grain as bio-fuels may increase food prices. Unused croplands and continually improving farm methods can meet increased demands without food price increases. Food prices are driven up more by increased gas prices than prices paid to farmers.</narrative>
  <narrative>Solar energy, waterpower and wind energy are clean, nature-provided alternative energy sources, especially for electricity. Solar energy, collected by solar panels, which may be placed on cars and buildings and in open spaces, can be used for heat and to power batteries and other equipment. Falling water and wind turn turbines and electrical equipment. The energy from the turbines can be stored and used as electricity and as a heat source. Alternative energy sources, especially bio-fuels, are  good choices. Farmers can raise the crops used to produce bio-fuels in mass quantities. Renewable alternative energy sources are generally cleaner, reduce emissions, and reduce our dependence on foreign oil, keeping our financial resources in America.</narrative>
  <narrative>&lt;pre&gt;--&lt;/pre&gt;</narrative>
  <narrative>2007-2008 District Essay Winners</narrative>
  <narrative>Schuyler Awald, Walkerton; Stefanie McGovern, Winamac.</narrative>
  <narrative>Joshua Garcia, Auburn; Jordan Hartleroad, Butler.</narrative>
  <narrative>Ayren Cobb, Otterbein; Chad Griffin, Cutler.</narrative>
  <narrative>Tyler Barnes, Kokomo; Mariah Hornaday, Portland.</narrative>
  <narrative>Ross Smith, Pittsboro; Abby Garner, Covington.</narrative>
  <narrative>Cody Short, Centerville; Rebekah Bales, Lewisville.</narrative>
  <narrative>Sarah Anne Foley, Unionville; Jansen Hight, Spencer.</narrative>
  <narrative>Karina Collins, Columbus; Bret Rosenberger, Brookville.</narrative>
  <narrative>Leah Lahue, Leavenworth; Jacob Newmaster, Elberfeld.</narrative>
  <narrative>Denise Maxie, Austin; Luke Aaron Woolbright, Scottsburg.</narrative>
  <narrative>2006-2007 County Essay Winners</narrative>
  <narrative>Karina Collins, Central Middle School.</narrative>
  <narrative>Kybren Foster and Ayren Cobb, Benton Central Junior High School.</narrative>
  <narrative>Chad Griffin, Carroll Jr./Sr. High School.</narrative>
  <narrative>Dalton Christensen and Brittany Wagoner, Columbia Middle School.</narrative>
  <narrative>Sarah Trotter, Charlestown Middle School.</narrative>
  <narrative>Kole Smith, Clay City Junior High School.</narrative>
  <narrative>Leah Lahue, Crawford County Jr. Sr. High School.</narrative>
  <narrative>Shane Bedford and Jessica Tillman, St. John Lutheran School.</narrative>
  <narrative>Jasmine Duvall, North Decatur Jr. High School.</narrative>
  <narrative>Joshua Garcia, DeKalb Middle School; and Jordon Hartleroad, Eastside Jr. High School.</narrative>
  <narrative>Kirstin Guerrero, Heritage Middle School.</narrative>
  <narrative>William Happel, Our Lady of Perpetual Help School.</narrative>
  <narrative>Bret Rosenberger and Emily Ash, St. Michael School.</narrative>
  <narrative>Jesse Houchin and Jannae Jackson, Linton-Stockton Jr. High School.</narrative>
  <narrative>Joshua Foster and Katie Cheesman, Carmel Middle School.</narrative>
  <narrative>Ross Smith, Smith Academy.</narrative>
  <narrative>Cole Williams and Rebekah Bales, Tri Jr. High School.</narrative>
  <narrative>Tyler Barnes and Leah Naegeli, Northwestern Middle School.</narrative>
  <narrative>Kyle Wischmeier, Lutheran Central Middle School; and Denise Maxie, Crothersville Jr. High School.</narrative>
  <narrative>Garrett Smith and Leslie Smith, Rensselaer Middle School.</narrative>
  <narrative>Aaron Loy and Mariah Hornaday, East Jay Middle School.</narrative>
  <narrative>Hunter Balczo, Our Lady of Grace; and Taylor Hillegonds, Crown Point Christian School.</narrative>
  <narrative>Andrew Klein and Lindsay Rader, Immaculate Heart of Mary School.</narrative>
  <narrative>Cole Shafer and Jylian Vigar, Maconaquah Middle School.</narrative>
  <narrative>Matthew Teach, Tri-North Middle School; and Sarah Anne Foley, home school.</narrative>
  <narrative>Jansen Hight and Sarah Law, Owen Valley Middle School.</narrative>
  <narrative>Maggie Mantel, Crown Point Christian School.</narrative>
  <narrative>Austin Bender and Jordan Wassmer, North Posey Jr. High School.</narrative>
  <narrative>Stefanie McGovern, Eastern Pulaski Middle School.</narrative>
  <narrative>Carlas Bogue and Kailey Gough, Driver Middle School.</narrative>
  <narrative>Dylan Gainey and Emily Dillon, St. Matthew Cathedral School.</narrative>
  <narrative>Luke Woolbright, Scottsburg Middle School.</narrative>
  <narrative>Schuyler Awald and Emily Pucel, Oregon-Davis Jr. High School.</narrative>
  <narrative>Jacob Newmaster, Trinity Lutheran; and Jessica Kelley, St. Joseph School.</narrative>
  <narrative>Brandon Downs and Abby Garner, North Vermillion Jr. High School.</narrative>
  <narrative>Hunter Wells and Madison Kroh, Northfield Jr. High School.</narrative>
  <narrative>Andrew Gill and Emma Donaldson, Evansville Christian School.</narrative>
  <narrative>Cody Short, Centerville Jr. High School; and Elise Armstrong, Seton Catholic Jr. High School.</narrative>
  <narrative>Kent Blazier and Chelsea Sorg, Norwell Middle School.</narrative>
  <narrative>Jacob Brummett and Kaity Faucett, Frontier Jr. High School.</narrative>
</record>
