<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1213977603" ordinal="17" title="HONORING TROOPER DAVID SHAWN BLANTON, JR.">
  <narrative>HONORING TROOPER DAVID SHAWN BLANTON, JR. -- (Senate - June 20, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="5937">S5937</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400054" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today I wish to honor the life of North Carolina State Trooper David Shawn Blanton, Jr., who was tragically killed on June 18 during a routine traffic stop near Canton, NC. David is the 59th North Carolina State Trooper to have been killed in the line of duty.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>David was only 24 years old and was a 2-year veteran of the North Carolina Highway Patrol. He was a native of Sylva, NC, and a 2002 graduate of Smoky Mountain High School where he was a football and wrestling star.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We are all grateful for David's dedication to protecting the citizens of North Carolina. He lived in Cherokee with his wife Michaela, who had just given birth to their son Tye 2 weeks ago.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>David was a member of the Eastern Band of the Cherokee Indian Tribe and the first member of that tribe to serve with the Highway Patrol. In addition to being a State trooper, David volunteered as the Junior Varsity softball coach at Smoky Mountain High School.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Along with his wife Michaela and son Tye, David is survived by his father, David S. Blanton, Sr., mother, Jennifer Blanton, and younger brother, Jesse Blanton.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>David's friends, family, fellow troopers, and the people of North Carolina are mourning this very tragic loss.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I know there are no words I can offer to help comfort Michaela and other members of the Blanton family, but I hope my colleagues in the Senate will join me in keeping them in our thoughts and prayers.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>David gave his life in service to our State, and this ultimate sacrifice should never be forgotten.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I send my deepest condolences to all who had the privilege of knowing this young man who gave his life in service to our State.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
