<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1222444802" ordinal="119" title="CONSOLIDATED SECURITY, DISASTER ASSISTANCE, AND CONTINUING APPROPRIATIONS ACT, 2009">
  <narrative>CONSOLIDATED SECURITY, DISASTER ASSISTANCE, AND CONTINUING APPROPRIATIONS ACT, 2009 -- (Senate - September 26, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="9850">S9850</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412247" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the Chair lay before the Senate a message from the House with respect to <bill type="h" number="2638">H.R. 2638</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>The PRESIDING OFFICER laid before the Senate the following message:</narrative>
  <narrative>Resolved that the House agree to the amendment of the Senate, to the bill, <bill type="h" number="2638">H.R. 2638</bill>, an act making appropriations for the Department of Homeland Security for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2008, and for other purposes, do pass with a House amendment to the Senate amendment.</narrative>
  <narrative>CLOTURE MOTION &lt;p&gt;</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412247" topic="">
    <paragraph>I move to concur in the House amendment to the Senate amendment to <bill type="h" number="2638">H.R. 2638</bill> and I send a cloture motion to the desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The cloture motion having been presented under rule XXII, the Chair directs the clerk to read the motion.</chair>
  <chair>The assistant legislative clerk read as follows:</chair>
  <chair>Cloture Motion</chair>
  <chair>We, the undersigned Senators, in accordance with the provisions of rule XXII of the Standing Rules of the Senate, hereby move to bring to a close debate on the motion to concur in the House amendment to <bill type="h" number="2638">H.R. 2638</bill>, the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act/Continuing Resolution for fiscal year 2009.</chair>
  <chair>Mr. WHITEHOUSE: I ask unanimous consent that the mandatory quorum be waived.</chair>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412247" topic="">
    <paragraph>I now move to concur in the House amendment to the Senate amendment to <bill type="h" number="2638">H.R. 2638</bill> with an amendment which is at the desk.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report.</chair>
  <chair>The assistant legislative clerk read as follows:</chair>
  <chair>The Senator from Rhode Island [Mr. Whitehouse] moves to concur in the House amendment to the Senate amendment to <bill type="h" number="2638">H.R. 2638</bill>, with an amendment numbered 5670.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412247" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the reading of the amendment be dispensed with.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The amendment is as follows:</chair>
  <chair>At the end, add the following:</chair>
  <chair>The provisions of this Act shall become effective 2 days after enactment.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412247" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask for the yeas and nays.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there a sufficient second? There appears to be a sufficient second.</chair>
  <narrative>The yeas and nays were ordered.</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="412247" topic="">
    <paragraph>I have a second-degree amendment at the desk and ask for its consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report.</chair>
  <chair>The assistant legislative clerk read as follows:</chair>
  <chair>The Senator from Rhode Island [Mr. Whitehouse], for Mr. Reid, proposes an amendment numbered 5671 to amendment No. 5670.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412247" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the reading of the amendment be dispensed with.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <chair>The amendment is as follows:</chair>
  <chair>In the amendment, strike "2" and insert "1".</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412247" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent ask that no motion to refer be in order during the pendency of the message.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="412247" topic="">
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the cloture vote occur at 10 a.m. Saturday, September 27.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
