<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1194541202" ordinal="32" title="FREE FLOW OF INFORMATION ACT">
  <narrative>FREE FLOW OF INFORMATION ACT -- (Senate - November 08, 2007)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="14185">S14185</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300065" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, when the Judiciary Committee reported Federal reporters' shield legislation to the floor on October 23, I called on the full Senate to promptly consider and pass this important legislation. The Senate version of the Free Flow of Information Act, <bill type="s" number="2035">S. 2035</bill>, is bipartisan legislation that was favorably reported by the Judiciary Committee on a strong bipartisan vote. The House has already passed legislation on this same subject, <bill type="h" number="2102">H.R. 2102</bill>, with a strong, bipartisan and veto-proof  majority of 398 to 21.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Both of these bipartisan bills are available and waiting for Senate action, and I believe that there are well over 60 votes in favor of passing a shield bill in the Senate. I strongly support the enactment of a Federal shield law for journalists, and I urge the Senate to promptly consider and pass Federal shield legislation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>All of us have an interest in enacting a balanced and meaningful first amendment privilege. According to a newly released study by Privacy International--a privacy, civil liberties and human rights watchdog organization, the United States is one of just a few established democracies around the world that does not have a law to protect journalists from being forced to reveal confidential sources. In fact, according to that study, approximately 100 countries have adopted laws that allow journalists  to honor their promise of confidentiality.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Sadly, the press has become the first stop, rather than the last resort, for our government and private litigants when it comes to seeking information. This is a dangerous trend that can have a chilling effect on the press and the public's right to know.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enacting Federal shield legislation would help to reverse this troubling trend. In fact, proceeding promptly to consideration of this legislation is something I strongly support. Should the Senate take up the bipartisan shield bill that overwhelmingly passed in the House, federal shield legislation could go immediately to the President's desk and be signed into law without delay this year.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senate bill has the support of a bipartisan coalition of Senators, including Senators SPECTER, SCHUMER, LUGAR, DODD, GRAHAM, and myself, who have all united to cosponsor this legislation. In addition, more than 50 news media and journalism organizations support this legislation and the call for Senate action on this historic bill extends to editorial pages across the country, including The New York Times, Arizona Republic, L. A. Times, Salt Lake Tribune, and San Francisco Chronicle,  among others.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The Senate and House bills protect law enforcement interests and safeguard national security. Moreover, both of these bills follow the lead of 33 States and the District of Columbia which have shield laws, and many other States, including Vermont, which recognize a common law reporters' privilege. Tellingly, the Bush administration has not identified a single circumstance where a reporters' privilege has caused harm to national security or to law enforcement, despite the fact that many courts  have recognized such a privilege for years.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Given the overwhelming need and support for a federal shield law to protect the public's right to know, I urge the Senate to promptly consider and pass a Federal shield bill.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that a copy of a support letter from the Media Coalition Supporting the Free Flow of Information Act, which is signed by 67 different news organizations, be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the RECORD, as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>FREE FLOW OF INFORMATION ACT,</narrative>
  <narrative>November 6, 2007.</narrative>
  <narrative>DEAR SENATOR: On behalf of the men and women across the nation who work to bring the American people vital news and information, we, the undersigned media companies and organizations, urge you to support expeditious Senate passage of the Free Flow of Information Act, legislation that is vitally important to the national interest. Protecting confidential sources through federal legislation has broad support on both sides of the aisle, in both houses of Congress, and from state attorneys  general across the nation. Your support is essential to ensure that the American people have access to information about their government and the institutions that affect their daily lives.</narrative>
  <narrative>Democrats and Republicans have united to provide overwhelming support for this legislation. The Senate Judiciary Committee reported <bill type="s" number="2035">S. 2035</bill> by a 15-4 vote on October 4, and the House passed <bill type="h" number="2102">H.R. 2102</bill> by a 398-21 vote on October 16. Both versions of the Free Flow of Information Act are available for immediate floor action on the Senate Business Calendar. As the strength of these votes suggests, Senators and House Members from opposite ends of the political spectrum have joined together to support  the public's right to have essential information and to protect whistleblowers who are sometimes the only way the public can get this information.</narrative>
  <narrative>While the Free Flow of Information Act will protect confidential sources by establishing a uniform standard for obtaining information from reporters in federal court proceedings, it is important to note that both versions of the legislation have been amended to ensure that national security is also protected. While many state laws provide for a more absolute privilege, both versions of this legislation are limited to a qualified privilege with exceptions for acts of terrorism or other significant  harm to national security.</narrative>
  <narrative>With 49 states and the District of Columbia having either common law or codified protection for confidential sources, there is a growing (bipartisan) acknowledgement that enactment of a federal law is imperative. In a recent brief filed with the United States Supreme Court, a group of 34 state attorneys general pointed out that lack of a clear standard of federal protection undermines state law. These state laws have worked successfully for many years, defining those covered by the law and the  limits of that coverage. At the same time, they have protected the public's right to information while still allowing these states to investigate crimes and protect public safety.</narrative>
  <narrative>News organizations prefer to have their sources on the record whenever possible. However, history is replete with examples of news articles critical to the national interest that would have never been written had it not been for the protection of confidential sources. As many of your colleagues have  stressed and state legislatures have recognized, the time is now for the protection of confidential sources, and the safeguarding of the public's right  to know. This issue is too important to remain unresolved as the year and the congressional session draw to a close. We urge you to press for immediate and favorable Senate floor consideration of the Free Flow of Information Act. Thank you.</narrative>
  <narrative>If you have any questions or need additional information, please contact Paul Boyle or Laura Rychak of the Newspaper Association of America at 202-783-4697.</narrative>
  <narrative>Very truly yours,</narrative>
  <narrative>ABC Inc.</narrative>
  <narrative>Advance Publications, Inc.</narrative>
  <narrative>Allbritton Communications Company.</narrative>
  <narrative>American Business Media.</narrative>
  <narrative>American Society of Magazine Editors.</narrative>
  <narrative>American Society of Newspaper Editors.</narrative>
  <narrative>The Associated Press.</narrative>
  <narrative>The Associated Press Managing Editors Association.</narrative>
  <narrative>Association of Alternative Newsweeklies.</narrative>
  <narrative>Association of American Publishers.</narrative>
  <narrative>Association of Capitol Reporters and Editors.</narrative>
  <narrative>Belo Corp.</narrative>
  <narrative>Bloomberg News.</narrative>
  <narrative>Clear Channel.</narrative>
  <narrative>Coalition of Journalists for Open Government.</narrative>
  <narrative>The Copley Press, Inc.</narrative>
  <narrative>Court TV.</narrative>
  <narrative>Cox Television.</narrative>
  <narrative>Cox Newspapers.</narrative>
  <narrative>Cox Enterprises, Inc.</narrative>
  <narrative>Daily News, L.P.</narrative>
  <narrative>First Amendment Coalition of Arizona, Inc.</narrative>
  <narrative>Freedom Communications, Inc.</narrative>
  <narrative>Gannett Co., Inc.</narrative>
  <narrative>Gray Television.</narrative>
  <narrative>Hachette Filipacchi Media U.S., Inc.</narrative>
  <narrative>Hearst Corporation.</narrative>
  <narrative>Lee Enterprises, Inc.</narrative>
  <narrative>Magazine Publishers of America.</narrative>
  <narrative>The McClatchy Company.</narrative>
  <narrative>The McGraw-Hill Companies.</narrative>
  <narrative>Media Law Resource Center.</narrative>
  <narrative>National Association of Broadcasters.</narrative>
  <narrative>National Federation of Press Women.</narrative>
  <narrative>The National Geographic Society.</narrative>
  <narrative>National Newspaper Association.</narrative>
  <narrative>National Press Club.</narrative>
  <narrative>National Press Photographers Association.</narrative>
  <narrative>National Public Radio.</narrative>
  <narrative>NBC Universal.</narrative>
  <narrative>News Corporation.</narrative>
  <narrative>Newspaper Association of America.</narrative>
  <narrative>The Newspaper Guild-CWA.</narrative>
  <narrative>Newsweek.</narrative>
  <narrative>The New York Times Company.</narrative>
  <narrative>North Jersey Media Group Inc.</narrative>
  <narrative>Online News Association.</narrative>
  <narrative>Radio-Television News Directors Association.</narrative>
  <narrative>Raycom Media, Inc.,</narrative>
  <narrative>Reporters Committee for Freedom of the Press.</narrative>
  <narrative>Reuters America LLC.</narrative>
  <narrative>E. W. Scripps.</narrative>
  <narrative>Society of Professional Journalists.</narrative>
  <narrative>Time Inc.</narrative>
  <narrative>Time Warner.</narrative>
  <narrative>Tribune Company.</narrative>
  <narrative>The Walt Disney Company.</narrative>
  <narrative>The Washington Post.</narrative>
  <narrative>U.S. News &amp; World Report.</narrative>
  <narrative>White House News Photographers Association.</narrative>
</record>
