<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1221235202" ordinal="9" title="TRIBUTE TO HONOR FLIGHT">
  <narrative>TRIBUTE TO HONOR FLIGHT -- (Senate - September 12, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="8472">S8472</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300072" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I would like to take a moment to recognize the fourth Honor Flight from Kentucky that took place this week. Honor Flight is a nonprofit organization which transports surviving World War II veterans from around the country to see their memorial free of charge. I have been privileged to have participated in previous flights from Kentucky, and I very much regret that my schedule prevented me from attending this one. I hope to have the opportunity to meet again  soon with the inspiring veterans from my home state on future Honor Flight trips.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>On Wednesday, Honor Flight's Bluegrass Chapter arrived in Washington with 38 World War II veterans from the Commonwealth to see the memorial which they inspired. These brave Americans also paid tribute to one of their fellow Kentuckians who gave his last full measure of devotion in March 1945. 2LT Howard Clifton Enoch, Jr., of Marion, Kentucky, paid the ultimate sacrifice while engaging with enemy aircraft over Germany.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Earlier this year, the Department of Defense honored its promise to account for every one of its men and women, and, more than 60 years later, the remains of Second Lieutenant Enoch were repatriated. He will find his final resting place among other American heroes at Arlington National Cemetery later this month. The son of Lieutenant Enoch, Mr. Howard Enoch III, traveled with the veterans from Kentucky to honor his father, who he never knew. I would like to convey my deepest appreciation to Mr.  Enoch for his father's service and to his family for their sacrifice.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I also wish to express my tremendous gratitude to the 38 Kentucky veterans who were here on Wednesday for having served to protect our great Nation's principles from the enemies of freedom. The inscription on the western corner of their monument--a quote by President Harry S Truman--perhaps best puts into words those sentiments:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Our debt to the heroic men and valiant women in the service of our country can never be repaid. They have earned our undying gratitude. America will never forget their sacrifice.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Indeed, our Nation will never forget their bravery or their sacrifice as it lives on today in the men and women of our armed services who display the same honor and continue to defend the same principles.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I ask unanimous consent that the names of the 38 World War II veterans from the Commonwealth be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <narrative>There being no objection, the material was ordered to be printed in the Record, as follows:</narrative>
  <narrative>In Memory of</narrative>
  <narrative>Howard Clifton Enoch, Jr.</narrative>
  <narrative>World War II Veterans</narrative>
  <narrative>George Arflack; William Atkinson; Harold Ausmus; Ruben Avila; Fredrick Balke; John Beyer; Hubert Wessel; Lorell Roberts; James Smith; Harlan Barton; Raymond Bloemer, Sr.; John Blossom; Fred Bryan; Phillip Chapelle; Eugene Thurman; John Bruggensmith; Leslie Cohen; Clarence Crawford; James "Art" Cutliff.</narrative>
  <narrative>Wayne Tabor; Herman Sasse; Charles Devers; Henry "Don" Donaldson; Matthew Flanagan; Robert Carrico; Robert Hall; Edward Jackey; Clyde Logsdon; Leonard O'Dell; Edward Oechsli; Bernard O'Hare; John O'Keefe; Blond Puckett; Leslie "Dan" Stickler; Charles Tribble; Ernest Spencer; Harold Phillips; Joseph Riney.</narrative>
</record>
