<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1179417651" ordinal="52" title="EXPRESSING SUPPORT FOR NEW POWER-SHARING GOVERNMENT IN NORTHERN IRELAND">
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate now proceed to <bill type="sr" number="209">S. Res. 209</bill>.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300059" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I am delighted to join Senators Dodd, Biden, Collins, Kerry, McCain, Clinton, Leahy, Smith, Schumer and Obama in support of a Senate resolution commending the extraordinary success of achievement last week in the peace process in northern Ireland.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ten days ago, on May 8, I was in Belfast to witness the dawn of a new day in the history of northern Ireland--a day that reaffirmed that peace is possible, even in the face of tragic history.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It was an honor to participate in a White House delegation to Belfast and to join Prime Minister Blair of Great Britain and Prime Minister Ahern of Ireland, who have been powerful forces for peace and reconciliation, as former foes in northern Ireland took the oath of office and agreed to share power on an equal basis.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This success could not have been achieved without the courage and determination of the political leaders of northern Ireland over many years in securing a new way forward and forming a new government that offers hope for a brighter future for all the people of that land and a healing of the terrible wounds of the past.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The courageous example of the people of northern Ireland, who have chosen peace and reconciliation, also offers a lesson of hope to other troubled areas of the world.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The resolution we are introducing expresses the strong support of the United States for the new power-sharing Government. It recognizes the contributions of British and Irish and American leaders whose efforts over the years have been indispensable in to the formation of the new Government and the achievement of lasting peace and stability in northern Ireland.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>May 8 will long be remembered as a historic day for peace in northern Ireland. All friends of Ireland in the United States commend the First Minister of the new Government, Reverend Ian Paisley of the Democratic Unionist Party and the Deputy First Minister, Martin McGuinness of Sinn Fein for coming together in peace to begin this new era of hope for all the people of northern Ireland, and we wish them continuing success in meeting the challenges that lie ahead.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The United States stands ready to support their new Government. I urge my colleagues to support this resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table, and that any statements relating to the resolution be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
