<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1212595202" ordinal="30" title="125TH ANNIVERSARY OF THE FOUNDING OF PIERRE, SOUTH DAKOTA">
  <narrative>125TH ANNIVERSARY OF THE FOUNDING OF PIERRE, SOUTH DAKOTA -- (Senate - June 04, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="5035">S5035</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300058" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I wish today to recognize the 125th anniversary of the founding of one of South Dakota's great cities, Pierre. Pierre is the capital of the State, and the county seat of Hughes County. Pierre boasts a robust economy and exceptional quality of life, and things are only getting better for this dynamic city.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Pierre was founded in July of 1878, preceding the arrival of the Chicago and North Western Railroads 2 years later. Taking its name from the French fur trader, Pierre Chouteau, Pierre was designated the State capital in 1889. Pierre's citizens are justly proud of their city's history, and they have undertaken numerous successful projects designed to preserve and celebrate this heritage.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, Pierre is the major trade center of central South Dakota and enjoys an economy mixed with government, agriculture, and plenty of good hunting and fishing with nearby Oahe Dam. The Capital's many attractions include the Capitol Building, built in 1910, and the Fighting Stallions, World War II, Korean, and Vietnam Memorials.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The 125th anniversary celebrations are to be held June 18-22, and include the 19th Annual Dakota Duck Derby, parade, fireworks, watermelon eating contest, and antique car show. The Anniversary Gala will bring together the current and past mayors of Pierre to reminisce and appreciate the history of the South Dakota capital.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Pierre combines the warmth and friendliness of a small town with the vibrancy associated with larger communities. I am pleased to recognize the achievements of Pierre and to offer my congratulations to the residents of the city on this historic milestone.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
