<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1177948807" ordinal="38" title="SUBMITTED RESOLUTIONS">
  <speaking speaker="300022" topic="SENATE RESOLUTION 176--RECOGNIZING APRIL 30, 2007, AS &quot;NATIONAL HEALTHY SCHOOLS DAY&quot;">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today is National Healthy Schools Day. This day was established to build awareness and promote healthy school environments for our children and school personnel.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>National Healthy Schools Day has been recognized for the past 5 years thanks to the work of the Healthy Schools Network in New York. Many organizations have worked together over the years to raise awareness to the conditions that many of our children and teachers are subjected to on a daily basis. The ongoing work of these organizations is crucial in fostering the development and wellbeing of our Nation's children.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Each day, parents send their children to school with the assumption that their children will spend the day in a safe environment. Many parents do not realize that their children's classrooms could be the very thing that harms them. Alarmingly, over half of our Nation's schools reported that they had at least one environmental hazard. These pollutants can have serious effects on health, such as respiratory problems, and can even interfere with cognitive functioning. Furthermore, children are more  vulnerable to environmental hazards as they proportionally breathe in more air than adults.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is not surprising then that approximately 1 out of 13 school-age children has asthma, which is responsible for more than 14 million missed school days each year as the poor indoor air quality in these schools exacerbates the effects of asthma. However, a recent study sponsored by the American Lung Association and the American Federation of Teachers estimates that a shift from an unhealthy to a healthy school would result in a 25 percent reduction in cases of asthma among students.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>It is imperative that we address these problems. That is why I was the proud sponsor of the Healthy, High-Performance Schools Program in the No Child Left Behind Act (NCLB). By incorporating this legislation into NCLB, Congress acknowledged that environmental factors can be a barrier to academic success.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>We must spread awareness of the health and learning effects that result from unhealthy schools and continue to fight on our children's behalf. I commend those across the nation who are using National Healthy Schools Day to do just that.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
