<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1213632003" ordinal="22" title="125TH ANNIVERSARY OF ETHAN, SOUTH DAKOTA">
  <narrative>125TH ANNIVERSARY OF ETHAN, SOUTH DAKOTA -- (Senate - June 16, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="5654">S5654</bill>]</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300058" topic="">
    <paragraph>Madam President, today I pay tribute to the 125th anniversary of the founding of the city of Ethan, South Dakota. After 125 years, this progressive community will have a chance to reflect on its past and future, and I congratulate the people of Ethan for all that they have accomplished.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The city of Ethan was founded in 1883 as a railroad town named after Ethan Allen of historical fame. Jerome Miles was the primary landowner of Ethan Territory. The first school was built in 1885, followed by the first Catholic and Methodist churches which were both built in 1887.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, Ethan is a growing and developing small town community located in Davison County. Ethan has a population of 312 and is home to numerous colorful characters, including many descendents of the original founders. Ethan features several local businesses, including grain elevators, hotels, banks, restaurants, doctor's offices, churches, a public school, and a beautiful park. Ethan Coop Lumber just celebrated their 100 year anniversary in 2007, and Ethan Public School has been declared a Blue  Ribbon School of Excellence by the U.S. Department of Education.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Ethan will be commemorating its anniversary with a celebration on the weekend of June 13-15. The town plans to hold the Miss Ethan Pageant, a street dance, a parade, and hot air balloon rides. The events of the weekend promise to provide great opportunities to celebrate such a historic milestone.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Even 125 years after its founding, Ethan continues to be a vibrant community. I am proud to honor the accomplishments of the people of Ethan, and congratulate them on this impressive achievement.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
