<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1220976002" ordinal="17" title="NATIONAL DEFENSE AUTHORIZATION ACT FOR FISCAL YEAR 2009--MOTION TO PROCEED">
  <narrative>NATIONAL DEFENSE AUTHORIZATION ACT FOR FISCAL YEAR 2009--MOTION TO PROCEED -- (Senate - September 09, 2008)&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[Page: <bill type="s" number="8159">S8159</bill>]</narrative>
  <chair> Under the previous order, the Senate will resume consideration of the motion to proceed to <bill type="s" number="3001">S. 3001</bill>, which the clerk will report by title.</chair>
  <chair>The bill clerk read as follows:</chair>
  <chair>Motion to proceed to the bill (<bill type="s" number="3001">S. 3001</bill>) to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2009 for military activities of the Department of Defense, for military construction, and for defense activities of the Department of Energy, to prescribe military personnel strengths for such fiscal year, and for other purposes.</chair>
  <chair> The majority leader is recognized.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that all postcloture time be considered expired and that the Senate now proceed to the consideration of Calendar No. 732, which is <bill type="s" number="3001">S. 3001</bill>, the Defense Department authorization bill, and that once the bill is reported, it be considered under the following limitations: that the only first-degree amendments in order be those that are germane to <bill type="s" number="3001">S. 3001</bill> or to <bill type="h" number="5658">H.R. 5658</bill>, and that the first-degree amendments be subject to second-degree amendments which  are germane to the amendment to which it is offered; that there be up to 10 additional amendments which are relevant to <bill type="s" number="3001">S. 3001</bill> or to <bill type="h" number="5658">H.R. 5658</bill> and have been agreed upon by the leaders--the leaders being Senators MCCONNELL and REID--with up to 5 amendments per side; that those 10 relevant amendments also be subject to second-degree amendments which would be relevant to the first-degree amendment to which offered; that upon the disposition of all amendments, the bill be read a third time and the Senate vote on passage of the bill; that upon passage, it then be in order for the Senate to consider en bloc the following calendar items: Nos. 733, 734, and 735; that all after the enacting clause of each bill be stricken and the following divisions of <bill type="s" number="3001">S. 3001</bill>, as passed by the Senate, be inserted as follows: Division A: <bill type="s" number="3002">S. 3002</bill>; Division B: <bill type="s" number="3003">S. 3003</bill>; Division C: <bill type="s" number="3004">S. 3004</bill>; that these bills be read a third time, passed,</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Is there objection?</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300062" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I object, and if I could just take a moment to explain why. As we have been discussing, we would like to proceed to the bill under a regular order. In discussing the proposed amendments we have ready to offer, I think it is clear they are relevant, if not germane. In fact, the first few we have suggested I know are germane.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I think we would be better served to just begin the process of bringing up amendments and having debate and votes on those amendments than trying to get the approvals that would be necessary to agree to this rather cosmic unanimous consent request.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>That is why we object to it at this time, but I assure the majority leader that based upon the amendments we have already indicated we wish to bring forth, I would hope there would be a clear understanding of good faith on both sides that that is the way we intend to proceed. I do appreciate that the majority leader then would presumably set up a parliamentary procedure by which the majority would have to approve the offering of any Republican amendment thereafter, so the majority certainly would  be protected in doing that. It would still be our intention to bring forth the right kind of amendments to deal with this legislation.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Objection is heard.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300082" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, maybe we can do indirectly what we can't do directly. That is, we are going to go through the procedure here to--and when I finish the procedural issues I am going to bring before the Senate, then the two managers, Senator Levin and Senator Warner, will be, in effect, the gatekeepers. They won't be under the control of Senator McConnell or Senator Reid. These two very professional, experienced legislators will move through these amendments  as quickly as they can. We all relish the time we used to move to this bill and other bills to have an old-fashioned legislative battle. I don't think--with all that is going on around the country today, including the Presidential election being in effect and all the other things going on politically--we can do that.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I hope, as I said, we can do indirectly what we can't do directly. It would be good for the country if we could finish this bill this week. It is so important. It has extremely important elements in it, including a pay raise for our troops, a good pay raise for our troops. This bill has things that are done to improve our military that only these two managers of this bill could lead based on their experience. I believe I am right when I say I think this has been--this is the 30th bill Senators</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
