<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1182268804" ordinal="13" title="RECOGNIZING THE HISTORICAL SIGNIFICANCE OF JUNETEENTH INDEPENDENCE DAY">
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Judiciary Committee be discharged from further consideration of <bill type="sr" number="231">S. Res. 231</bill> and the Senate then proceed to its consideration.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will state the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="400064" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today is the 142nd anniversary of Juneteenth, a day when our Nation celebrates the complete abolition of slavery. The Emancipation Proclamation freed slaves beginning January 1, 1863, and brought to an end what Abraham Lincoln called "two hundred and fifty years of unrequited toil." America's Civil War had ended at Appomattox, VA, in April 1865, but it was not until June 19, 1865, 2 months later, and a full 2 1/2  years after the Emancipation Proclamation that the  news finally reached Galveston, TX. That day has become known throughout our Nation as "Juneteenth."</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In communities across the country, Juneteenth is an occasion for all Americans to reflect on a tragic period that shaped our Nation and continues to influence us yet today. For Marylanders, Juneteenth is a time to reflect upon our own history. Slavery existed in Maryland from the State's inception as an English colony. In 1664, slavery was officially sanctioned by law, and it thrived until 1864 when it was abolished with ratification of a new State constitution.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>In 1820, Maryland's population was approximately 400,000, less than one-tenth our current size. The slightly more than 100,000 slaves in Maryland accounted for one-quarter of Maryland's population, while the 39,000 free Black Marylanders accounted for nearly 10 percent. By 1860, the State's overall population had grown considerably, while the number of slaves had declined to about 87,000, or 13 percent, while the number of slaves had free Blacks numbered about 83,000 or 12 percent.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Although Maryland was a slave State, it did not secede from the Union. And the contributions of Marylanders to the Union cause and the abolitionist movement did much to tilt the national balance in favor of freedom. Antislavery activists--Black and White, free and enslaved--took tremendous risks for the cause of freedom. Harriet Tubman, who was born Araminta Ross in Dorchester County, and Frederick Douglass, who was born Frederick Augustus Washington Bailey in Talbot County, were both born into  slavery, put their own lives on the line as courageous crusaders for freedom. Having escaped their own captors, they dedicated their lives to fighting for the emancipation of all slaves. They are true American heroes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>This year, the Maryland General Assembly passed a resolution that I will quote here in part:</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Resolved by the General Assembly of Maryland, That the State of Maryland expresses profound regret for the role that Maryland played in instituting and maintaining slavery and for the discrimination that was slavery's legacy; and be it further</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Resolved, That the State of Maryland commits itself to the formation of a more perfect union among its citizens regardless of color, creed, or race; and be it further</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Resolved, That the State of Maryland recommits itself to the principle that all people are equal and equally endowed with inalienable rights to life, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Today, on the 142nd anniversary of Juneteenth, I wish to commend my former colleagues in the Maryland General Assembly for this resolution, and I urge all my colleagues in the Senate to join me in celebrating Juneteenth and honoring those who made that day possible.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300066" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today we celebrate Juneteenth Independence Day in observance of the date upon which slavery finally came to an end in the United States, June 19, 1865. It was on this date that slaves in the Southwest finally learned of the end of slavery. Although passage of the 13th amendment in January 1865 legally abolished slavery, many African Americans remained in servitude due to the slow dissemination of this news across  the country.  Since that time, 143 years ago, the descendants of slaves have observed this anniversary of emancipation as a remembrance of one of the most tragic periods of our Nation's history. The suffering, degradation, and brutality of slavery cannot be repaired, but the memory can serve to ensure that no such inhumanity is ever perpetrated again on American soil.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Throughout the Nation, we also celebrate the many important achievements of former slaves and their descendants. We do so because in 1926 Dr. Carter G. Woodson, son of former slaves, proposed such a recognition as a way of preserving the history of African Americans and recognizing the enormous contributions of a people of great strength, dignity, faith, and conviction--a people who rendered their achievements for the betterment and advancement of a Nation once lacking in humanity towards them.  Every February, nationwide, we celebrate African American History Month. And, every year on June 19 we celebrate Juneteenth Independence Day.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am happy to join with my colleagues, Senators Durbin, Reid, Obama, Stabenow, Brownback, Kerry, Landrieu, Cardin, Lieberman, McCaskill, Clinton, Leahy, Kennedy, Dodd, Sanders, Menendez, Brown, Pryor, and Lautenberg, in commemorating Juneteenth Independence Day with the submission of <bill type="sr" number="231">S. Res. 231</bill>, which the Senate has just adopted,  in recognition of the end of slavery and to never forget even the worst aspects of our Nation's history.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300038" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, today I am pleased that, <bill type="sr" number="231">S. Res. 231</bill>, a resolution recognizing historic Juneteenth Independence Day, has passed the Senate.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>June 19 is an ordinary day for many Americans, is a significant day for those who know its history. Juneteenth Independence Day celebrates June 19, 1865, when Union soldiers led by MG Gordon Granger arrived in Galveston, TX, with news that the Civil War had ended and that the enslaved were free.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Americans across the United States continue the tradition of celebrating Juneteenth Independence Day as inspiration and encouragement for future generations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>The legislation recognizes the significance of Juneteenth Independence Day and supports its continued celebration as an opportunity for the people of the United States to learn more about the past and to understand more fully the experiences that have shaped our nation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>As Americans, we must remember the lessons learned from slavery. Juneteenth is a day that all Americans, of all races, creeds, and ethnic backgrounds, can celebrate freedom and the end of slavery in the United States.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>I am pleased to recognize historic Juneteenth Independence Day and proud that the Senate has passed this important resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table, and that any statements relating thereto be printed in the Record.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
  <speaking speaker="300076" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I yield the floor.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
</record>
