<?xml version="1.0"?>
<record where="s" when="1177516815" ordinal="48" title="COMMEMORATING THE 400TH ANNIVERSARY OF THE SETTLEMENT OF JAMESTOWN">
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate now proceed to the consideration of <bill type="sr" number="172">S. Res. 172</bill>, which was submitted earlier today.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> The clerk will report the resolution by title.</chair>
  <narrative>The legislative clerk read as follows:</narrative>
  <speaking speaker="300099" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, in a few short weeks, America will commemorate the 400th anniversary of the founding of Jamestown, the first permanent English settlement in the New World. It is an event that I, along with many of my fellow Virginians and Americans, have looked upon with great anticipation.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Jamestown's anniversaries have always been major national patriotic events, and this year will be no different. Visitors and dignitaries from all over the world will converge on the site, where, in 1607, CAP John Smith and his motley crew of Englishmen first stepped ashore to begin life in the New World. Commemorating the Jamestown anniversary allows Americans to not only remember the bravery of Captain Smith's crew and the founding of America but also to celebrate the democratic ideals and institutions  that trace their roots to that remarkable beginning. The rule of law, the entrepreneurial spirit, representative government, and cultural diversity all originated at Jamestown and all continue to have profound effects on America today.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>To recognize the impact of Jamestown and to signal Congress's support for the 400th anniversary of its founding, I introduce today this resolution. It marks the importance of Jamestown to our Nation's history and recognizes its 400th anniversary as a seminal event for the American people. Furthermore, the resolution recognizes the critical role Native Americans played in the colony's survival, notes the democratic ideals first instilled at Jamestown, and reflects on the unique confluence of cultures  that made Jamestown strong and successful. With this resolution, Congress has a chance to officially record for history its support for the commemoration of the 400th anniversary of the founding of Jamestown.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I urge my colleagues to join me in support of this resolution.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <speaking speaker="300009" topic="">
    <paragraph>Mr. President, I ask unanimous consent that the resolution be agreed to, the preamble be agreed to, and the motion to reconsider be laid upon the table.</paragraph>
  </speaking>
  <chair> Without objection, it is so ordered.</chair>
</record>
